so this is the talk about my TV and my
spell about statistical optimizer needs
to optimize for queries and when and how
not to use indexes I'll okay so i work
in my a DB operation as chief architect
melody B and I was working on my spell
code base for like 20 years so I'm
pretty familiar with it but let's start
the talk so what but is exactly why the
need for an optimizer optimizes your
query it needs to know something about
the data and usually in volt instant was
done by optimizing was asking engine
different questions like I don't know
how many arrows does astable have or how
much would cost to do the full table
scan and cost is in some arbitrary cost
units not in microseconds or CPU cycles
or anything so for example how much will
it cost to read thousand values from the
index number three and then you might
even compare this course with the cost
of the full table scan and decide
whether it's cheaper or how many
distinct values are in the index and
then if the index face say ten million
rows and there are 1 million distinct
values then optimizing would assume that
every value is present about ten times
in the index or optimizer could ask how
many rolls care how many index values
lie in the range between say 10,000 and
11,000 and then this then it would ask
the cost to read them and then it would
compare with it for table scan and so on
that works reasonably well well but
there are some issues with that and one
of the problems is instability not all
engine has this values all the time
already they calculate them on the fly
and V for example is doing it using
random index dives and because they are
random they supposedly don't have any
bias on the other hand because they're
random they do not give repeatable
results and this is a test I've done on
DBT three benchmarks on query from DVD
three number two eight eight individuals
involved in this query and
repeat by just by the repeated many
times I have seen four different
execution plans and with a query
execution time ranging from 7 mins to
1.2 hours and for q7 I seen I've seen
seven different plans
the fastest one was executing in 12
minutes and the longest one I've just
waited for few hours and killed a query
because yeah I got impatient so it's not
what you'd prefer to have some might ask
what about energy be persistent
statistics and it does solve the
instability problem in a way that in DB
is still doing the random dives and then
it remembers the result in an internal
table and next time it'll just show you
the same result so there's no
instability always get the same result
and the same execution plan but because
it still started from the random drives
if you're lucky you'll get always the
same execution plan and the query will
always get in 12 minutes if you're
unlike your guys always the same plan
and it'll always be many hours and
timeout
that's and if you don't even know how
many plans are less if you you might
just think that very slow if it always
time us turns out after many hours but
it may be just that you go to bed random
there's another problem is that all
engines they do report statistics in
arbitrary cost units but they are
different for students for different
engines and engines lie about what data
are in the table this is the example I
have a table with three integer columns
and I pop you lated every column with a
random number between 1 0 and 100,000
and repeated 400,000 times and now I do
select how distinct which is honest
exact so a skill calculation to get the
number of distinct values and what do
you think what number I will get here
anybody could guess his own
ok if it was 400,000 roles and numbers
are between 100 0 and 100,000 so it
should be about hundred thousand
distinct values and this is exactly what
I've got but this way it takes a lot of
time to calculate
so usually optimizer relies on some
imprecise estimations that I've done by
the engine so the engine is my eyes on
here and here I asked the engine for the
estimation how many distinct values are
in the index and my eye some estimated
which it's not exact number but it's
within one percent which is good enough
for the optimizer pulling plane in point
of view now I change the table for
InnoDB and we look not was I'm trying to
guess in a DB reports two hundred
thousand disinter alias and if you
remember that the table contains
integers between zero and 100 thousand
that cannot possibly be two hundred
thousand distinct layers in there
but what does it mean for the optimizer
so there are four hundred optimizing
note that there are four hundred
thousand rows in the table and there are
100 distinct red it means that optimizer
would expect every single really to be
present in the table four times if you
look for the specific failure optimizer
would expect to find four rows but in a
DB light the twice as many distinct
values of the actual arts optimizable
thing there are only two rows to be
found the optimizer will be more likely
to prefer an index in an ADB case
because in a debate lies about
statistics and why did why energy B is
doing that well like 15 to 20 years ago
the original InnoDB author back then hey
Kotori he just noticed that for some way
energy B doesn't use the index and he
would like in a deep my skill to the
index like he just added times two and
make the inic twice as more attractive
to the optimizer and he was happy with
that and since there since then because
there are many years past optimized just
kind of adopted and it's probably
embedded in many parts of that you might
the assumption that enemies doing that
and as far as I know they've removed
this time to in my spare age
so the other problem of course that if
you need all these 36 you need an index
in and exists in you need to pay the
price for an index index it takes place
they takes time to be maintained and if
usually not user often if you just need
statistics and index it just too much
price to place too expensive and a
solution so from now on I'll be talking
about money a DB for a while and then
later I'll describe the differences with
my scale and numeira new versions so the
solution was in that was implemented in
many AD be called engine independent
table statistics and it is provide
provides stable precise detailed and
comparable statistics so it's stable
because the T 6 is calculated once and
then stored in position tables it's not
calculated and it every time using some
random drives it's precise because maybe
analyze all the data are not just very
very small percentage of the data so it
gets very good representation of all the
data is and statistics is actually close
to actual data it's detailed because
this engine independent statistic
remembers a lot more information than
just cardinality with just one number so
it can it allows optimizer to know more
about the data and create better
execution plans and it's calculated by
the server not by the engine so it
calculates identical for all engines so
cost estimations are identical and the
comparables optimizer can calculate the
cost for one table on one engine and for
another table in different engine and
then compare them and decide in what
order it's better to execute the query
for example to join now I'm not going to
recite the manual so this is just I'm
just give you a few pointers few
keywords industry either download my
talk later or just make a picture of the
slide and this other words you can later
look up in the manual so very briefly it
is implemented by having new tables in
the my SQL schema where all the
information of a statistic is stored as
a new system variables used type tables
or the tells the optimizer when to use
information
this engine independent statistics it
could be never used or preferable and so
on and this optimize the use condition
selectivity we shall be talking about
for the rest of my talk which tells the
optimizer which exactly parts of the
engine dependent statistics optimizes
allowed to use and there are optional
clauses in the analyze table that can
where you can specify what parts of the
table should be
statistic what for what part of the
table the statistic should be calculated
it could be run for all table of only
some indexes of run some columns but
enough this theory now let's get to the
examples and for the examples I use the
employees database which can be
downloaded from the Jabez github and jet
purpose the guy who's giving talks at
the forum it's not a very big data set
but it's not exactly small either one
had 67 megabytes of data in the
employees table has three hundred
thousand records and sorry table head
like 2.8 million records so let's lower
it it's you download it from the
Jeopardy table then you sort those
source in place the despair which
creates on the table and performs all
the load data to load all the data and
then I enable engine independent table
statistics by setting you start tables
preferably and then I analyze all the
table to collect the statistics there's
no need to specify any optional courses
for the analyzed here because if
statistics is enabled preferably then
analyze will automatically do collect
all the engineerin statistics so you
don't need to modify your application
and you write all the analyzed table
statements you just need to enable
engineering 36 ones and then it'll
automatically work for all of your
application and you can see that it's
not a very big data set because this one
took only less than 10 seconds so how
does this one help to optimize your
choirs so I said optimize use condition
selectivity 1 which tells optimizer not
to use any
and in engineering statistics basically
it only uses the data that were
available before engineer apprentice was
introduced and I want to find all the
managers from all departments in this
example in place database I joined
departments with employees with manager
with titles where title equals manager
and for the purpose of the examples
important to remember that title poem is
not indexed then money DB does something
with the data and returns the result set
in 15 seconds
now I enable optimize use conditions
rule 53 which allows optimized to use
Pro column statistics that is for non
index columns and the same query is
executed under a second this is 16 times
improvement it's not 16% it's not 1.6
times it's 16 times improvement and so
it's pretty remarkable to me and let's
see why that is happen this is a result
of explained extended for the first
query when the optimizer cannot use
perform statistics it is explained
extended so that's column filtered which
tells how many what percentage of the
table optimizer things will pass the
where clause and because there's no data
available for non index columns
automatic doesn't know so he just says
hundred percent everything might pass
the where clause but if we enable if we
allow optimized reuse Pro column
statistics statistics for not indexed
columns then optimizer
knows the cardinality for non in
exponent and minimal amounts non value
phone on index poems and optimizer can
figure out that not all employees are in
fact managers and only about 14% of the
titles will match the where clause and
in this Elizabeth in in this way case
optimize decide to join tables in
different order from full table scan of
the titles table and this gives 16 times
improvement
now before talking about histograms I
want to explain what they aqua fide
histogram is this is not an accurate
histogram it's a usual histogram that
you see everywhere
exactly with
the red line this shows some imaginary
data distribution and this is histogram
for this data distribution under the red
line I've drawn with 5 bars 5 buckets
they all have same have the same width
that's why it's called equal width and
the height of the bar is equal is
proportional to the area under the curve
and this is the height histogram where
all the bars have the same height but
different with that were also five of
them but in this case the area under the
curve is all might be obvious all the
same and why would we want to do this
strange thing instead of normal
histograms because all we remember for a
recall is those five numbers well more
than five but still he said number of
bars to describe a histogram and then
later optimizer needs to use this data
to kind of restore the original data
distribution to understand the original
data distribution and if optimizer would
try to restore the original distribution
based on the accuracy histogram this is
what it would get you see this huge
error in the most interesting part of
the curve where the values are high and
if you try to restore the girl from the
equivocally height histogram the
interesting part of the curve is
described much more precise as errors
much smaller basically a clear-eyed
histogram allows you to describe the
data distribution much more precisely
with a smaller number of winners this is
what my enemy is using for histograms
now let's see if how histograms are
helping to optimize the choirs and for
this one we need an example of some data
with non-uniform distribution one state
let's look at the salary values from the
employee database and we calculate the
midpoint of mid soliders exactly in the
middle between minimum and maximum
salary but the first query it's about
100,000 and now let's see what select
all the employees and their titles from
the salary table with where the salary
was above the midpoint above the 100,000
again in some time after churn some data
returns a result in 18 seconds 19
seconds and but if we enable the use of
histograms by setting optimize use
conditions in PV equals 4 you'll get the
same result three times faster okay
again why is it happening because if you
don't use histograms then oh they're all
all the data that optimising knows about
the table is it not the minimum value
for the sorry no the maximum value for
the server and because we are searching
for everything which is above the
midpoint optimizer can figure out okay
so this is midpoint so about half of the
data should be above midpoint about half
of the data should be below midpoint
namsom optimizer things and indeed if
you see the filtered column is about 50%
let's optimize the thing that half of
the crows will pass there we're close
but that at least half of the rows would
have passed the where clause if the
salads would be distributed uniformly
but in this in place database just
wasn't available you know so it's indeed
very unusual for me and if we enable
histograms optimizer can see that indeed
only less than 5% of salaries fly above
the midpoint in this case optimizer
again joins tables in different order
and give it if a three times feed on the
next interesting feature that was
implemented its sampling so this is a
query which could be realistically used
by I don't know HR department by
analyzing whether there's solid-solid is
a distributed fair or there some people
are getting worse are all stolid is
based on I don't know sex for origin or
whatever but this credit it takes the
average salary per department for all
the people whose last name ends with of
which supposedly could mean people with
Slavic origin as you know those those
kind of like where is you cannot
optimize you can optimize from the
indexical
any
it's a ground for that you cannot get
any original statistics for that some
Tomatoes doesn't know anything about
this and it finds fire fire rose because
grow by Department in five seconds and
if you enable sampling you get the same
result
twelve times faster yes so how does
simply in grow because there's no other
way for optimized to get any reasonable
information about the data
it reads few rows from the table and
applies this like condition and then it
except elates the result to the rest of
the table and indeed without sampling
you can see that filtered poem is one
hundred hundred percent because there's
no histograms no indexes no nothing that
could help optimizer to know anything
about the data and with sampling
optimizer can realize that indeed very
little there are very few rows that
matches that we are close and it
optimizes joins tables in different
order and this is twelve twelve times
speed up everything that I was talking
about now it was implemented in my ad be
ten point all which when J in 2014 so it
was it's quite stable
well in fact ten all is already reach
its end of life so don't use that use at
least an one and in this married
emission or engine independent statistic
remembers the number of rows per table
and the cardinality index and for every
column it remembers number of distinct
rayless minimum and maximum value amount
of nulls average value length for
Strings and this equifax histogram and
sampling also works last year maria a
metal eight all went j they implemented
conceptually similar feature it's called
different is called optimized statistic
in mice girl and they remember amount of
nails your column and but they have to
live two different kinds of histogram
the grave
have Equifax histograms until singleton
histograms and solute on watch rock much
better than a graphite if you have data
with very few
distinct vendors like if you have a sex
column or a column with just no venues
this this case by singleton histograms
broken a graphite basically don't also
if you try to do try to collect
histogram for really really huge table
and my scale starts keeping values to
keep all the data center memory and it
gives significant speed up as compared
to how many debates and all collects mr.
Graham's on the huge tables and in a few
months Merida bitchin for will become J
where this engineer Pence is enabled by
default which is basically the main
reason why I'm giving this talk so if
you start upgrading you should know this
enable what default you don't need to do
anything anymore everything will just
automatically and magically be it'll be
faster and Marilla bitchin for also
collects histogram by sampling by
skipping radius so that analyze table
will be fast and mainly before 10 for
analyze for engine Pacific Statistics
was slow this was the reason why it
wasn't lined up by default and this
feature was mostly implemented as a
google Summer of Code project last year
that's all thank you
have any questions
[Applause]
yes yeah
yeah
I'm talking about this one yes so the
question is about how I compared the
results and execution times for the same
query I it was the same system and I
would just repeated many times I
repeated explained many times I repeated
just select many times in different
order when I was collecting how many
different selects I have indifferent
explains output out I would see in
question does not affect that explained
output and yeah execution time as well I
think after the cache was warmed up so
this shouldn't be taking town after the
Risa
I was already collecting the results
that were stable
I'm sorry I didn't you know
so the question is is that if there any
plans to collect statistics on the fly
we are thinking about that but it will
not be in Marina Beach and form