good morning you all my name is Moses
I'm a software developer from Brazil
last year I relocated to Czechs Republic
to work at Red Hat and I've been toying
with configuration files for the last
year basically so I took what I have
learned last year and what I've been
toying with to show it to you so
configuration it's kind of what we need
to do to our software so it can behave
like differently we don't need always
like a hello world that will execute it
and it will always print hello world in
different situations we might need our
software or service to behave in a
different way so that's why we need to
provide configuration to our software in
the beginning like we are used to like
read values and output values from when
we start learning how to program so
basically we toy with the standard input
and standard output so we can through
the a standard input provide some
information and control about the
behavior of the software but as a
service we might need to like get that
configuration before we also have the
standard error like a different way out
to print stuff to return to the console
and then the first thing we have to tie
with configuration in our applications
is the command-line arguments so in
Python we have art parse which is
included in the standard library and you
can do arc bars you basically have to
define your parcel so I can define my
program here to process some integers
I'm adding one argument called integers
which I can call it and later and
type is int and I'm I can have more than
one number provided a hyper string like
integer for the accumulator and another
argument - - sum which is the
destination is this accumulate and the
action I will store this function sum
but its default value is max
so I have a program that processed some
integers here and it should sum these
integers if I provide - - some otherwise
you just find the maximum number so I
can parse my arcs this will process all
the arcs I've provided to the command
line and I can just print here args
front dot accumulate which is with might
be the max function or the sum function
and I will accumulate the integers
passed here so I will get the list of
numbers as I have a plus arc here so I'm
in my console I can type - H in my
program and I will get usage of my
program I have a minus H for this helper
I have a - - sum which is optional and I
have n or more for my numbers it
processes some integers n is a
positional argument which means like it
has a specific place to be in the
command line to be processed is expected
and the optional arguments they have I
have you the helper and also the - - sum
which is to change the behavior of our
software so it normally finds me the the
biggest number but if I want to change
this behavior to sum all the numbers
then I provide a minus minus sum and it
will behave differently for me so if I
call my program with one two three four
it will find me the biggest one and four
but if I provide a minus minus sum
I get a 10 which is the sum from 1 2 3
and 4 and if I try different values
which are not numbers it crashes and say
is like yeah the usage of the program
you're not using it right the argument n
is a type of int so a is not an int then
you get like type checks on your on your
arguments so we've seen how to use
arguments in the comment line to change
the behavior of a software and arc parse
it provides us with the command-line
arguments and very nice flexibility on
those and also type checking so far
another way to change the behavior of
code of software is through environment
variables and in Python we can use OS
environ so basically what I have to do
is import OS and call OS dot environment
let's say home and we'll print my home
folder or I can try to print my home
brew github API token and it doesn't
show up because the Unicode I put there
didn't get to the PDF sorry it was a
wing not my token actually so it's nice
to to grab information out of the
environment but sometimes we might be
exposing some information that is kind
of sensitive and we have to be careful
about that and what is in our
environment can also be accessed at
dependent on how we put that value in
environment variables it might be
accessed by other applications the third
type is through configuration files it's
nice to have the flexibility to use the
common line so you can like
very fast change how you you're using
some software and then sometimes when
you're in the development process you're
not yet have your configuration fixed so
you kind of tone and then you're always
changing need a specific behavior so
you're not using it all the same
but sometimes configuration files they
can have all that specific configuration
that we know that we need for a specific
case and it's not going to change
sometimes in the comment line we do some
typos and then have to call the command
again and we've config files you have
all your configuration set and you know
that it works and it will not break when
you try to try to run it so python gives
us config parser and this is a example
configuration file i have it is in the
ini format it's composed by sessions so
I have a session called default and I
have another session called bitbucket
and top-secret server these values in
the default session they are shared with
the other sessions so if I try to access
bitbucket
org compression it will if it doesn't
exist here it will fall back to the
default group so to use config parser I
have to load the file so I create my
config parser and then I feed it with my
ini file with a configuration so now I
can access I can see this section so I
had two sections other than the default
one and for if I try to see config a bit
bucket user it will get me the user and
config default compression what is in
the default but I can also try to see
what is in config bitbucket like
everything so if I do this it will I
will see that it merges what is store
in pit bugs but also what was a story in
the default group and then if I try then
I can also get things from the top
secret server which he had this option
to know but this one comes from the
default it could get a no from the
default if I yes from the default it
wasn't not there but then as it
subscribed the value then we can have it
different here well in the argh parse I
had my parser and I could just like dot
and the name of the the argument I was
expecting and with config bars I had
kind of like a dict so I had all to be
like brackets and quotes and everything
and so basically what I brought today to
show it is a mix of arguments
environment and config but I still have
some other stuff to mention about like
you can always have inputs as signals to
your software this is not covered by the
Oslo config which I'm using but this is
another way how you can interact with
the software or application and always
you can also like as an output you can
have an exit code so you can pipe so you
can create scripts with your software
and see what is like if it runs okay or
not
so basically this is all the input you
can get and this is basically the output
you can use of course that might be like
you can interact with other ways like
networking but this kind of the basics
if I had this like in my first semester
or first year I would be like very glad
with my professor so in the last year at
OpenStack I was working in I've been
working in a project called
the config which handles configuration
files and the Oslo is a project inside
OpenStack which mean OpenStack common
libraries so you don't actually need to
be running OpenStack to use these guys
they're kind of like built we just just
over Python itself and then it doesn't
have dependencies to other OpenStack
projects so also config at the beginning
it's a it works with configuration files
but also you can have arguments which
will have priority over the
configuration files so you can have your
config in the configuration files and if
you need any change then you can just
overload them with the arguments and
also in the last semester of last year
there was it was merged a driver so now
we can also get values from the
environment so we have the configuration
files and they can be subscribed
overloaded by environment variables or
and then you can provide argument on the
command line and much more like we have
this new drivers in also config so you
can create your own driver to how you
you you can fetch configuration data
lately I've been working on two drivers
one driver to fetch configuration data
through the network so you can have in
your configuration file keys to a server
so you can have a HTTP connection to the
server so you can fetch the
configuration and then use that
configuration the the second driver I
was working in it it's a castellon
driver for this gastrin library in also
in OpenStack Oslo and
using it you can store configuration
data in let's say hash core vault or
Barbican which is a sick secret manager
for OpenStack in also config we have
like the basic types strings boolean
integers floats list and dicts so we can
do the the same type checks that arc
bars does so then we have this that is
now extensible as well to the to the
configuration files as config parses it
only gives me a dictionary it doesn't do
any validation on the types also very
common in OpenStack are like the
networking types so we have also
validations to to this kind of data and
now I will show like simple so from also
config I mean for t-mike config module
and I have some common options and the
greeting options so in my example I will
build hello world
Paris will be configurable in different
ways so I have the name which is the
name to greet the default is world so it
will print hello world for me at first
and the greetings the default one is
hello is the greeting to be used I can
just say like can change the greeting to
hi and say hi world or I can change to
another language and also I add another
option here like x so how many times I
will repeat repeat the greeting so if I
say like x equal 5 it will say like
hello world hello world whole world
laurel a world in my main function
I create my config object and then here
I can also have some kind of control I'm
registering as a CLI options my common
ops so which is the name to be greeted
here I'm resist registering the
greetings options which was the hello
the greeting and then the times here I'm
registering them differently but I could
just pass the the whole list here with
like hashes register opts with an S in
the end like here the difference is like
this one I'm exposing to the comment
line and this one
it can only be defeat by either
environment variables and the
configuration files so this one will not
be exposed as a command-line option oh
then here I have 4a in range times just
to say like hello world world many times
so I'm getting the times config and then
I'll print formatting the greeting and
the name capitalized and just my main
wire play here so here I have the helper
so also config also provides me with the
helper so I get a usage of my program I
have all the like positional arguments
optional arguments and the greeting
options which was in a section so it
will expose me greeting times but I
didn't expose the the the greeting
itself to be used you can provide here a
configuration file a path to a
configuration file to run use your your
software your program and or else a
folder and then it will read all the
configuration files inside that folder
it also has a default paths where it
will look for the configuration files if
you don't provide them for the common
line so here I have my hello world
basically and it will
me yeah hello world it's like his basic
behavior but I can change it through the
comment line passing a name to be
greeted and then I have Hello Brussels
so I was able to change the behavior of
the program using the command line I can
use the minus 3 argument and it will
print hello Brussels three times and
then I have this configuration file
which in the default section I have the
name Brussels still and the greeting now
I'm changing to hello' and three times
so now if I call my program passing - -
config file my configuration file it
will now behave as what I told it to
behave in the configuration file so now
I don't have to if I put like this file
in like let's say slash EDC slash hello
it would read it automatically but also
I can have the configuration file and
still change it using the command line
so the common line will take precedence
and I will have both the configuration
coming from the coming from the
configuration file and the behavior
coming from the command line
both then the times how many times to
greet and the name to be greeted so this
way you can fine tune your configuration
let's say you want to build a container
with your application but you don't want
to put your configurations file inside
the container so you could just either
run the container and mount the the
configuration file you could run the
container and load the configuration
using environment variables you could
use a driver to fetch a configuration
file
a remote server you could use a driver
to to load sensitive configuration files
like credential database credentials API
tokens to fetch them from services like
from Harsha core vault or other secret
managers and then you can also write
your own driver to fetch configuration
the way you want and that was it I'm
open for questions now you can find the
slides here thank you all
[Applause]
questions okay I can't hear you
I still can't hear you
you can can
oh you asking if I can use the mo or
Jason well not yet I heard some some
rumors on that on the IRC channel we are
in freenode you can go there hang out
with us and but it's doable right now we
like lo the file and then feed it to a
any any parser to kind of mount some
dictionary structure so if you can
replace that class and then provide a a
JSON reader or an email reader and then
you can do that you can read the
configuration out of like any other
format next question okay okay the
question is if I can specify a
configuration file if the if some
specific option cannot be overloaded
is that right okay so so far what I've
seen is that when you're doing the
coding you specify where if you're
reading if you exposing it to the common
lines or not so I know I don't know if
you can like then go to the
configuration and shut that down
yeah basically when you're registering
your option you either registered just
to the configuration file or to the
configuration file and also the the
command line depending on which the way
you registered the option this question
okay
oh okay the environment variables it
works like magic no I'm kidding like it
will fetch the it will try to fetch the
value from the environment after I kind
of go into the to the configuration file
so first it checks that the the command
line if it's registered to the command
line and then we have a specific naming
so it was quite it's quite new the
driver to fetch variables folder for the
environment but right now we have some
prefix to the environment variable that
you can fetch it from there if you go
into the documentation you will find
that information or you can just email
me and I'll point you to it
I haven't toid with the environment
variables that much so I wasn't able to
to put it on the slides yet thanks next
one okay
sorry
oh okay I was indexing them yeah I can
you can provide the whole list if the
method see okay the question is if I can
hear because I I saw like greetings
option 0 and then greetings option 1 I
can provide a whole list like here I'm
providing list and then it is like opt
in the plural so but I can I can also
register just a single option I could
just provide a list the thing is like
I'm this one I'm registering just to the
configuration file but this one I'm
exposing it to the CLI option was just
another way I was trying to show how you
can use it and this is kind of the
section it is in so if I go back to the
configuration file oh now it's here like
this is my what I'm trying to act this
is the the 0 this is the configuration 0
and this is the configuration 1 this is
the the guy I'm accessing like right
here so basically this configuration
file will be like this in the greeting
and the session ok times up you can
either talk to me outside if you have
more questions or contact me with my
email or anything else ok thank you
thank you all
[Applause]