hey folks thanks for coming all here to
my talk and being interested in my maxi
stuff I assume some of you may heard
about that term before in the past
okay so for those of you who don't Max
is a concept that has been populated or
made popular by Vannevar Bush he was a
scientist from the mid 20th century and
he envisioned the device that would let
you to that you organize connect and
share your knowledge back then it was a
microfilm obviously not really feasible
from a hardware point of view but now
we're in the stage where we can do that
and so we started to build what what
what Vannevar wants to build hopefully
so who of you knows these problems
please raise your hands and let them go
let them up if you're still in it okay
okay let them up who knows this problem
when trying to to save stuff and who
have you noticed this problem okay yeah
then you probably like what what I'm
about to show you so the thing is when
we're thinking about our knowledge then
the way our brain stores information is
always contextual to other things so
when you're looking at for example that
article that you saw while browsing in
the back rows of a talk and plus them
you remember some words from the article
you remember the day you remember it was
at an event but these are not the things
we can search for and that's because the
way our software currently structured
doesn't allow the kind of fluid
associative memory to be taking
advantage of that we have right like if
we think about it we use 15 century
tools to organize the kind of 21st
century digital knowledge so we first
had libraries that were very siloed so
you had to go to a library and find a
book
then you had to go to the digital age
yet to go to organization like Facebook
like your knowledge management task
management your Google search everything
is disconnected so it's basically like a
library again but what we think is the
future is connected knowledge and you
may have heard also about an application
called notion before who of you has used
that one person oh it's a really really
great tool because it allows you to
connect knowledge and data they have
objects with each other in a very
customizable way because it is so
connected and what notion is for kind of
wiki's knowledge management in that
regard we want to do for web research so
let me show you how that works in
practice so now I'm reading this article
this is the article by the way about the
Memex the original concept of ours and
what do I remember
I maybe remembered a word recollection
right so I had no chance to find it
again if I just remember that worth I
could rego glitter maybe but that take
takes so much time so what you can do
with Memex is you tie two w-space
into the address bar the browser the
word recollection and then you have all
the results from every website that you
visited with that word in it you can
also save least show me everything after
like 20 minutes ago and filter my time
you've also an overview where you can
for example tag stuff you can sort it
into collections because not needing to
organize those mean you can't obviously
you need to have some sort of
flexibility in terms of how you organize
your knowledge the second issue that the
tool tackles is one of notetaking
so we all know whenever we take notes
about the web stuff we see we have to
copy paste it out we have to use the Web
Clipper and make a snapshot of the page
and Evernote and then write some inline
text and you cannot share it you cannot
reuse it it's it's locked into this data
silo again
so what you can do here is you already
saw the little tooltip you can just
highlight any piece of text and add
notes to it
and another thing that you might also
encounter constantly specifically if
you're into like journalistic or doc
writers for open source projects that
you want to show people specific pieces
of an article and not the whole thing
so right now you need to copy paste out
that specific section and then you need
to copy paste again the URL the other
person needs to do the whole shining
again so what you can do is you can just
highlight any piece and click on the
second button that you saw that's maybe
too low I'm putting it up here so so
here
now hopefully internet works because
yeah oh yeah okay work so now you get a
link that you can share with anyone and
this is what happens you can really
quickly link stuff with just a click so
that's the current state that's actually
my production version that's my private
Memex you can download that already you
go on this website world brain the i/o
if you want to do that I repeat it later
again if you like so really important
this tool is obviously because I'm here
at fast an entirely open source and also
we value data ownership and privacy a
lot so we designed this application to
be offline first and it runs by default
all on your computer no data is sent to
any server except you want to share
stuff then there obviously other people
get specific access to specific sub data
for the linking with hello
Kable I'll try it again okay cool
heart attack moment maybe I should
disable flux or so just so touch it yeah
so all your data is stored locally and
if we make these links we for example
only store the highlighted text the URL
but no I piece who gets it we have we
actually never looked into the database
of those links not before we really
don't want to analyze any of your data
and that's also really important for the
kind of business approach we have
because it's a for-profit project we try
to build a SAS model out of it but we
intentionally don't take venture capital
because we know that if we want once we
do that we would at some point need to
sacrifice your data it's inevitable
because we for this for the sake of
growth that is required to have a
venture backed business we at some point
need to build logins we need to somehow
monetize this huge chunk of data that is
potentially on our servers for the
sharing services so that it's not what
we want to do instead we use a model
that is called Stewart ownership you can
also read about that on our website
which is basically a way of
incentivizing collaborators and
investors with some sort of profit
sharing model that doesn't require us to
grow in order like to grow infinitely in
order to give people a fair share for
the risk they're taking also the the
vision of where we want to go is that
this Memex is just one mimics like it is
really like every person on this planet
has a completely different way of doing
knowledge management everyone uses
different apps that they want to connect
with each other everyone has different
workflows so we really want to enable a
whole ecosystem of Memex devices that
can be adapted to different workflows so
a developer might use the different
dynamics and a student then a journalist
and an entrepreneur and that's also a
reason why we don't take venture capital
is to be able to say hey the ecosystem
can generate 95% plus of the wealth of
the revenue of the users in the
ecosystem and we would still be ok
because we don't need to grow infinitely
in that ecosystem so your
interoperability is at the core of what
we do means you can easily switch to
another mimics and modify it and do
whatever you want you're not locked into
our services on that note what we
launched this week is the ability to
backup and restore your data to any
cloud provider so we have built a little
local server app for all main operating
systems that would allow you to
basically upload the backup - to all
cloud providers that have a local file
system integration so you stay full
complete and full control of your
backups - if you like to do that but
obviously you can also choose Google
Drive right like that's for the majority
we haven't done that yet for priority
reasons we're a relatively small team so
but it's on a road map and when we have
for the syncing for the syncing the kind
of relay because we offer like a
synchronous syncing then we encrypt it
on travel but it will be deleted after
it soon
[Music]
so it's it's possible on the basis of
that we haven't implemented yet but it's
it's thought about to just point to a
server have some authentification and
just say make a append append only
backup block there so that's possible
with a little bit of contribution that's
certainly possible yeah so yeah and then
the next step for us is peer-to-peer
sync between your devices means you can
have yeah you can also use it on mobile
phone what we offer them as a service is
to say for everyone who doesn't want to
run a server or doesn't know how to run
a server we do for them and for everyone
who's who knows that and wants to be
independent they can host your hope on
handshake server signaling server to
make the peer-to-peer sim possible for
that we also developed a library that we
call storix which is a library that
would allow us to gradually replace our
back-end infrastructure so for example
we may think to implement an IP FS
back-end or a dot back-end to make more
distributed sharing possible and so
because we're not sure yet which one of
those to take we have built this kind of
modular database abstraction ecosystem
for JavaScript please check it out and
maybe it's useful to you too which
brings us to another next step that
we're doing and that is collaboration
and so that's also the initial premise
of the talk is how do we actually can be
able to collaborate more in our web
research because right now there are so
many limitations because our data is
also locked up and it's very hard to
reshare information because for one you
need to Riegel it right then you need to
find all your notes that are relevant to
it that you may have left in a chat lock
somewhere or in another notetaking
application or in an email threat and so
it becomes so scattered that it's very
hard to share and so one of the like
these are the three features that we're
focusing on and for example the FIR
one co-creation of collections means
that you can create these folders that
you then can share with other people and
collaborate and curating them this might
be useful for entrepreneurs to do some
customer research or for journalists to
do the story research together so hey
this is all the stuff that I read about
climate change here please
you can look through it and you can also
full-text search through them so that's
part of the publishing collections you
can basically say maybe as a thought
leader term like someone who likes to
share knowledge and who likes to share
thoughts maybe giving them the ability
to say look here's the thousand articles
that are ever read about climate change
and I don't want to just share a list
you can discover what I would have
searched for or liked what I what I
looked at for example by just typing now
what did this guy say about ocean
acidification and then basically being
able to search in this kind of shared
subset of his knowledge or her knowledge
plus all the annotations that this
person has left there and wanted to
share with the community or peer to peer
there is no central central platform
it's really you shared with your people
and your tribe and you find other people
that you want to look into that
like into the knowledge of those other
people too the last point is annotation
threats so having conversations like
really responding to annotations and
highlights that people have made inside
an article to exchange thoughts about
that and be very precise
so yeah I wanted to end to talk a bit
early perfect because I wanted to give
room for they can come to me but then so
the thing is that's also reason why we
build storix
in the beginning we might have to start
a more centralized because it's it's
very difficult to build a federated
system that at the end is useful to
non-technical audiences and so because
our tool is is made for developers but
not exclusively we probably started with
more centralized ways then thinking
about how we make data interoperable so
for example by using a distributed hash
table like Doc does it so that address
ability that might be the technical now
and that address ability becomes
interoperable about the authentication
server might be more centralized so we
need to find we need to figure that out
still I don't have a definite answer but
it's on our it's in our interest to make
the system as interoperable and for the
user as free to move as possible
working together on the same knowledge
you mentioned the collaboration stuff
that's want to do but is that production
no make in the roadmap yes so before
that as far as the students number that
you set up somewhere you make it run and
you send data to it right
is it possible for multiple people to
set up the same server and then they
share everything will be hundred percent
with no potentially yes
now it's mourn right now the version is
more on a single-player focus so
multiplayer with having multiple people
on the same server that would be the
difficulty that we're talking about
because that would mean we have a
mastadon like system where you need to
sign up for a new node to be at to be a
part of that node and that is difficult
in a more decentralized collaboration
[Music]
so what we yes for that use case that
would be a problem right now so it
doesn't it doesn't persist the page but
it's on our roadmap to to make snapshot
impossible and we're going to work with
the Internet Archive
they said they gave their goal that we
basically say with every annotation that
is done in a certain time frame we make
a snapshot at the Internet Archive and
add a link to an alternative snapshot to
the page for that particular annotation
so that in any case you could at least
go back to the Internet Archive and then
afterwards being able to snapshot it for
yourself if you like to but that's the
thing is that this space-wise can get a
bit tricky this year so yeah yeah so it
will certainly come before we do the
collaboration because there it becomes
more important to have a central source
of truth when you're talking about an
article
things to do but incur the above of
searching time or exceed and like to
also live like the presumably reference
can change like you can find the first
reference then another one and then you
wanna change how you think about the
first one all this panel of things you
can help you access oh I'm not sure if I
understood the question how we solved
that search
so what the technology underneath or is
oh we we built a search layer on top of
Exige as that runs in the browser it's a
custom search engine and that right now
we tested about 200,000 articles and it
didn't have like it has a little bit of
flow down but not oh no no I didn't do
anything it every website you visit is
automatically indexed in the background
and yeah if you have a decent fast
computer you don't feel it at all it
myth floor ok and him because he was
yeah to exported it we actually use
hypothesis annotation client so it's
it's the same library it's we don't
export it yet in as an open annotation
data model but it's planned to do so
yeah totally
yeah it's a browser extension but I
haven't tested it on Chrome OS if a
Chrome extension works on Chrome OS it
should work I guess so we haven't just
packaged work yet yep it's Firefox all
browsers that support the web extension