hello everyone my name is Bertrand I
must do this from Turkey in this session
we are going to talk about C POTUS
member management C Python is the major
implementation of Python language and
there are other implementations like pi
pi with their own memory management and
there are implementations like jarton
and ironpython they use their written
language member management for example
jython use games memory management this
talk contains out of implementation
details so you can most find stuff in
ducts might suit you learn nevermind
concepts it will show you behind the
curtain for an example you may think why
you why python doesn't release memory
back to the system or have it finds and
directs cited references all of them has
an answer in behind the curtain you are
going to learn how to control it Python
has an interface for all internal things
like abstract syntax tree they mentioned
parser and the interface for garbage
collector we can control it
there are helper functions like assisted
get reference you can learn of an object
in memory although it seems unnecessary
to learn them Instagram increased their
performance by 10 persons with disabling
or enabling Kesey whenever they need you
are going to handle memory link is fight
them and trace them into source with
understanding of memory management on
location of memory memory measurements
we can examine arrangement in two
sections allocation and de-allocation
before we start
don't forget everything is an object in
Parkton so in that memory everything can
be objects every Python object has to
once the reference count and the other
mask object itself reference count is
the count of total reference made to
that object if you set a to 10 and B to
10 you will increase times reference
count by 2 and if you delete or set a
and V to another object you will
decrease the reference count by 2 if an
object's refer start to reach zero it
will immediately delicated
but there are some cases like object
reference itself and it could detect by
the reference count manager so there is
a GC and there AB type pointer it points
object itself
it contains value of object type of
object name of object every attribute of
an object it is my Mormon model of
cpython in the top layer layer 3 based
python objects and some of internal
stuff in the layer - there's our Python
object or locator it abstracts memory
and manages objects in the layer 1 there
is pythons remember a locator it ensures
there is enough space in heap if not it
requests memory from layer 0 layer 0 is
the mall locator if you didn't change
anything or I'm using a standard Linux
distribution it might be Moloch and in
bottom layers there are physical and low
things we are not talk about item device
objects into sections if an object
bigger than small object threshold it's
called as big if not it called as small
small object result is a static constant
that defined in optimal octave C in C
pattern repository is 512 bytes my
default big objects it's not one of our
concerns Python direct routes big
objects to system allocated with a set
of purpose small objects they managed by
layer two
with three level of abstractions the
first one is blocks they anchor plays
Python objects and proof Poussin Cobb
plays same site looks and their size
four kilobytes same as a mutual member
page and there are arenas they contains
64 proof will obscure solo obstructions
the size of block determined with eight
might align rotation for an example you
have third bite sized object it will put
the 32 by size block and whenever your
object de-allocated Python camp put
another object in the range of size in a
range of 25 to 32 to that same block it
brings optimization and there are size
ideas value it has pulls to contain same
size blocks implementation of blocks
they designed for containing Python
objects they use 8 by 10 I'm notation
for better manage or free blocks and
they mark this free and linked to three
blocks list of their pools
Mandira object alligators tooth day and
hope they stay in size blocks their size
4 kilobytes every pool has a pool header
over at it contains a list of three
blocks next time previous proof the
arena index of memory
besides I Dix of blobs inside and some
memory stuff pulses free block list the
list contains three blocks and whenever
a block freed if you sort that list the
are states of blocks used miss it's
neither empty nor full at this one block
is free and at least one block is
currently owed the full mist
there is not currently available blocks
and the empty means every block is empty
and it will be linked to a free boost
list of the its arena arenas they anchor
plates tools there is the overhead like
tools and that blue blue link list with
next time in a primer in the pools their
size 256 kilobytes the mall locator only
allocate space for arenas and the other
abstractions use space for arenas space
and Python only relates memory back to
the system when all pools is empty in
that arena objects specific there are
some objects which cases that's related
with memory management for example
string tonic partying in Street impact
of strings are immutable seconds of
Unicode
so Python can reference same string
twice instead of creating a new string
in every operation we called string
interning if a string is simple it will
be internet and does have to create
trace twice simple strings are
escalators digits and underscores for
example on the central strings and
disciplines in compiled time so function
calls and constructors doesn't affect
that and there is small integers
it's the optimization for C Python
Python pre allocates integers between
negative 5 to 20 256 there are internal
reference to the integers and it brings
optimizations
garbage collection before we start
talking about garbage collection
don't forget Tom as not variables
it has names Institute and B difference
between names and variables names only
points to an object that lives in heap
variables contain objects failure
reference is the pointer to that object
that lives in heap and reference count
as I mentioned the total references made
to the table jects there is besides and
besides of reference counting it's easy
to find unused objects and it doesn't
require a marking time like in Marcos
sweep but there are bad sites like it
had every partner object contains a
reference count field and it cost or
object coverage it doesn't support for
cited references and it is one of the
reasons of Jill if Jill doesn't exist
and to tread tries to increase and
objects ref and values reference count
it will cause memory leaks and that word
and there is generation GC for cyclic
references parson runs this GC
periodically it used an algorithm called
Marcus sleep cycle preferences are
refers that refers it starts for an
example if you add the list itself the
list reference itself and the various in
cyclists refers to list and part
reference counting can coolant directed
so mark-and-sweep marks every reachable
object and sweeps rest and the reachable
objects get next to the next generation
and the generations help you to help GC
through five psychic references easily
so how to track or manage them Python
has internal stuff like you see GC is a
interface to garbage collector there is
a function here that creates a list and
this append itself
I call it ten times then I called you
see that collect it call it runs Marcus
sleep operation and returns total amount
of collected objects here and before
that I disable automatic EC so it
doesn't start without my command then I
called it and you can see there is ten
objects freed and you can check if an
object record by garbage collector bided
thought atomic atomic types is not going
to be triggered and non-atomic types is
going to beat records if you have ever
written as C extension to passion or use
it C module or you saw a patent
application that consumes more memory
than it needs there might be a memory
relief so in Part III there's a model
came
it's called trace mode look it traces
Maalik operations and helps you to find
memory leaks it is a start function it
takes frames I'm just using my frame
here but if you're a complex code you
can you
can increase that frames amount then I
take a snapshot snapshot contains
relevant information about malach and
you can take more snapshots and compare
searches they can compare then I access
the stats of snapshots and get trace
back
it's the biggest member block and then I
print relevant information about that
trade mark is very cool model and it has
a great API and pattern and there is
debug malach stats
it's a rough interface of trace mahlock
here this is the pythonic interface and
this is the rough interface of m'lip
that is you can call it which sees that
the backlog starts or you can set an
environment variable to something's
there are different pattern member
allocates for example m'lip or primal
log or you can write your own memory
allocated fighters a flexible language
it supports a new member a locators any
questions
thank you for listening
[Applause]