hi good morning my name is Luca dairy
and my colleague Sam Walla will be
talking to
about a DPF in the context of network
traffic monitoring so the idea is to use
and to show you an application of a BPF
to something meaningful we are not
talking about a BPF per se but to use it
in in a word so let's start with a few
few notes about us I'm the founder of
the on top project we've heard this
before when we talk about peer free I'm
also a lecturer at the University of
Pisa somewhere a is a former student of
mine and working with us at M top and
top is an open source project we started
I started in 1998 so very long time ago
it was about monitoring a network
traffic in our in a simple way don't
think about the internet ok the internet
did not really exist as it is today but
it was a totally different world so over
the time we started from analyzing
pockets okay just to display two people
to accelerate in packet capture so
differing we have done many other things
another thing and good contribution I
think to the open source community is a
library called n dpi that allows you to
analyze and dissect a packet payload so
it allows you for Institute to tell you
what is the application protocol of a
certain communication so this is called
n dpi you can find all our open source
code in on github so github.com slash n
top and so this is the place where you
will find our activities let's start
from the very beginning so why why we're
here
talking about network monitoring so when
we talk about network monitoring so this
is a definition coming from techo pedia
so we are talking about the ability in
essence to monitor a computer network to
see what is happening ok so if there is
something wrong and expected so from the
security standpoint from the
configuration miss configuration these
type of things and usually the way to do
that is through packet capture so in
essence we capture packets we analyze
pockets and we report users what is
happening this is why for instance I I
started appearing because it was a way
to accelerate packet capture packet
capture has always been you know the
main problem
we have to receive this data so they
input our pockets so if you talk about
that so look at this picture 2009 so ten
years ago okay this was the picture of
the N top world many years ago so P ring
was there so we had a different way of
polling pockets up by the pocket polar
teen R P and then we have all our
application on top of it okay so here we
are talking about pockets we are talking
about network adapters we are talking
about way to accelerate pocket up and
that we have packet analysis again ten
years ago if you're talking about 2019
able to beat hub you download and open G
so that that is the successor of n top
so the next generation you'll see graph
like this you would see that there is a
peak you would see that there's program
normally here now you will see that
pockets are still for citizen this
morning until now we talked about pocket
xt p d pd k and so on pockets pockets
pockets because pockets are too many so
it's not possible if you handle pockets
easily so you have to put them in a
meaningful fashion so in a ways that you
can understand what is happening usually
the way of doing that is through the
concept of flows so you put together one
after the other pockets with the five
toppled so same protocol same ip source
destination port and so on so this is
the uncompressed version so you with
three pockets this is the compressed
version flow so you see my PC is talking
with that PC over port 80 and all the
pockets of the same command action will
be put together and again people like to
see a peek again there was a pig here
you want to say what's happening you can
see the flow but if you don't trust
flows so you want to go down to pockets
in a top engine you can click it say
give me the pockets so again we're
talking about pocket what's wrong with
pockets I'm not against pocket I for all
my life had done pocket ology so it is
good ok
in particular it is good if you want to
be outside of the cistern you're
monitoring so we are here today at force
them so if I want to see what is
happening in this room I cannot put an
eejit on every single laptop first of
all because it is impossible they have
you have a smartphone you have tablets
you have many things so it's very easy
to look at pocket so capture packets
classify them put them on a web
interface very good and wherever there
are some challenges
what is the wireless encryption in n DPI
we had to struggle fighting against that
not that we have to decode the packet
again deep pocket dispatcher is not
about the coding and the cert in the
packet and extracting you know your data
it is about understanding if you are
talking about Gmail or if you are
connected to your own home application
so we had to press it to decrypt they
did initially you know certificate
exchange to understand what is that
about
however the revitalisation so in the
past
computers were you know connected to the
italy but these days you have seen
psyllium before you will see a big
machine with several containers all
providing a service actually a micro
service and only interacting sometimes
the container moves on another place and
so on so if you look at the pockets
entering or leaving a machine at the end
you will see the same result so you will
see that you're connected to a second
website but you don't understand the
interaction of things happening inside
the same computer this is the main
problem and also when you deal with
pockets you have to handle fragmentation
packet loss retransmission so the pocket
is not the native way of communicating
when you open a socket you say I want to
connect to this part I want to send data
/ whatever you don't know anything about
pockets okay so you don't have to pay
attention to IP artists nothing zero is
the car that is doing for you if you
there is a long time queue it will split
the packet into you know segments and so
on so anyway pockets are nice but they
are not native people don't understand
pockets I mean expert know what they are
about
so years ago I wanted to extend that and
give more information about the system
system introspection I wanted hand the
visualization
I wanted to have also an ability of have
a continuous drill down from a problem
let's say a peak I say what is happening
okay my web server a stock with MySQL
and this was the reason and then you go
to floors we go to pocket so at the end
we are still using the same floor in
paradigm in Pocket paradigm but I want
to see what is happening inside the
system if there is a security issue
today you can see oh I've seen this this
very nasty payload inside my pocket but
you don't know the application that has
sent that payload you don't know who has
to receive the payload you simply have
you know an IDs on IPs that is is
reporting that but you are blind with
respect to what is happening inside the
system so we want to fix this problem so
this is what we are going to talk today
so in 2014 I was very excited because
I'm a good friend of the creative system
about this thing I don't know if you are
familiar with that system was it is
still a kernel module that you can
install on on Linux it looks like a TCP
dump for system events so in essence you
can look at system events you can see
connect closed and received so the idea
was to give an idea so when we have you
know application of containers talking
each other to see ok my HTTP our talk
with MySQL and this is the amount of
data but as a chain it
however this software that again 2014
war was very very nice was designed by
somebody that had pockets in mind pocket
ok this was the idea so use TCP dump
over system this was the problem so we
had so this code is still still still
available we had we integrate that with
you know elasticsearch you can see you
know the nice graph you know top one is
the top processes top top-of-t
ok very nice so I spent a lot of time on
that but it was a fail a failure it was
a very big failure for many reason first
of all it was using too much CPU so if
you have our process that using 10 to 20
percent of the CPU on your box
simply because sis dig was decided with
the pockets in mind so if there is a
system that receives a lot of traffic
you have to analyze a lot of packets and
that is wrong first of all because you
are not in the machine with the pockets
anyway because you know there is a lot
of things to do and second because are
the you monetary feature add extra load
on the system second people don't really
like to install agents okay it's not
it's not always possible like I've said
but again this is still doable but the
main problems that Cystic requires a
carry module and you know many people
buy you know commercial supported by you
knows read add or whatever and these
people say if he stole a camera module
that you are on your own people pseudo
like that it also continues were not
that popular 2014 did you know doc has
started to exist but was not just not a
big problem the time so we were a little
bit ahead of time but the main problem
was the CPU I mean monitoring was too
expensive and this was this was the
problem in essence the Cystic outwards
just to give an example so you suppose
that you want to monitor a TCP
connection you have to track socket you
have to track Santa send receive receive
yeah you have to put them together in
flow similar to flows and you have to
report the information and this is very
CPU expensive because you have to see
analyze every single packet not it not
is there that is the problem so cystic
is too much pocket oriented now I'm
going to need the microphone to do some
work
hi everyone and Somalia and I studied
the application of the PPF to traffic
monitoring with Luca
so I BPF is a very great tool that
enabled us to inject code inside the
kernel and and and have it executed when
a specific target kernel function is
invoked and so these are by attaching IP
difficult to network functionalities we
are able to avoid inspecting the
capturing and analyzing the single
packet but focusing only on the events
we are interested in furthermore because
the code is executed inside the kernel
we can compute matrix and Anna sent it
to user space only they are things that
are needed and avoid sending all the
information can away we can collect the
book and both these feature gives as a
great savings in terms of CPU of CPU
usage furthermore btfo as another key
feature that is that it doesn't need
distillation of another kernel model
that becomes embedded in the modern
linux kernel dashan's so this is very
great things what we had done is inject
the code inside the kernel I set up an
insert a kernel and generate to answer
and send it to user space through a
circle buffer provided by btf so the
structure of events is very simple you
have to Clayton in different in
different ways but provide very simple
information such as the destination or
source port and IP address the protocol
or for example the latency calculated
from inside the kernel so is from the
perspective of the kernel or the
application and not from not from the
external point of view of who captured
their packet another things that we are
providing is their Pido the user ID or
for example the the full path of the of
the executable
or the task name or the occipital or the
process name or for example the time in
which the packet the the event has been
triggered and things like this
so to do this we attach a d-- different
probes diff different we inject code to
we are we attach code to two different
kernel function that are for example the
tcp connector which is figured when the
kernel connects to a remote or local
Austin for example to intercept would
appear events concerning the change in
the state of a socket for example we can
track when a socket is closed and and
and analyze how much bites has been
received or sent through that socket and
other things that we can capture is the
retransmissions events regarding their
representations and and this is it
so together this kind of form of
information what we've done is using a
DPF filter function that is BPA forget
current task to attain the craft the
task the struct associated to each
thread and process and by navigating
through the Constructors we can collect
this kind of information such as the
user or for example desi group and
furthermore by using the the socket that
is provided with the function call for
example when we connect we use the TCP
connect we will provide this argument
the socket that we that we want to use
penalizing the socket we can extract
information regarding the protocol there
or the destination address so to provide
to provide visibility concerning
continuous what we have done is using
the C group that we the the we collected
from inside the kernel to interactive
the doctor demon
with the doctor API and and the other
information concerning the container
this can be done because the C group
identifier that we we found that this
group identifier that we have extracted
from the constructor and sent to your
search base is the same identifier that
doctor used to track containers so once
you have now what we have basically done
is a collective information collected
the C group identifier send it to user
space and accuser space little
interrupted the doctor daemon to collect
information a story and store them in a
cache so we can we have information like
for example the container name or for
how much time has been the container
alive
furthermore we have found that from from
the dirty result of the query we can
obtain information from from kubernetes
such as the port just the pod or the or
the classroom where the container is is
easy and so we have a greater view about
what is going on on the machine you know
in a bigger way concerning kubernetes
kubernetes view so under the hood
these TCP accept has been implemented
very very ray has been implemented very
simply because we have attached a probe
to the to the to the food to to the
return of the function call so when the
function restaurants our code is
executed when our code is executed we
use the socket that is returned and body
function to collect Nana to to to to
collect network information and use the
desta the task structure to to collect
information of the user and concerning
the process so in a very few in a very
similar way you have to actually a
transmission and events concerning so it
closed when when the socket is closed
but for for for the connector it has
been more difficult indeed we have to
use a hash table because this because we
want not only to return information
about the user or the network what we
want to return also the return code of
the function to check if it has failed
or it has been successful so what we
have done is attach a probe when the
function is invoked when the tip when
the TCP connect is invoked collect the
socket that is passed as argument then
the function is executed the controller
a reference to the function and when a
function returns the return code our
could is executed again we check in the
stable where we put the socket and is in
the access
that read identifier we-we-we we get to
this the socket and and track neural
network information beside the return
code and in this way we by putting also
the kernel time we were able to to
measure the latency of the connection
okay so in essence we have integrated a
BPF so with an open G to library called
Leiby BPF flow such that allows us to
avoid you know seeing all these dis
internals of EB PF and just to report to
the port event just to give an idea
these are this is a typical example so
you start EVP a flow this is a helper
allows you to see you know the current
time the process ID what is happening
who's talking to who what is the process
what is the command something like that
so the idea is that we want to make this
library available to - also to everyone
so that you can put your application on
top of it and forget it PF so for you it
will be a source of information so
currently in anent open G this is a
preview of what we have allows you to
see next to the communication also the
user and in the process that is
executing that so you will see this this
this pocket is going to Apache okay oh
this pocket is coming from a chrome
thread and this is for the source and
for the destination of course thanks to
the deposit inspection we can analyze
that this is very important because it
allows us to augment the information so
we have an idea of what users are doing
so what am i doing okay I already turned
a bit so I'm using Dropbox so these are
use my network so not just analyze
pocket but also analyze you know
activities so what what is a certain
user is doing and I don't know if you
have noticed when we have the food part
of the application so in case you you
would have let's say a security
violation you will see any other a
certain pocket is very bad so you know
exactly the process that has created
that pocket and the user in the
container eventually so this is this is
important we have also the ability of
putting all these things together so you
see I know what what a certain process
is doing what what are the process
activities and what are the users doing
inside the container but you know this
is very nice ok we just track you know
some some some events very simple so if
you have a you know gigabit of traffic
we simply see connect the response and
predict update I will have a problem
with UDP inside UDP every packet is
independent so you can hop in a socket
send a packet to to each of those of you
so how do we avoid playing with pockets
again how do we avoid sand to use a
space an event for every single pocket
so at the moment we have user Danny
kernel LRU so that whenever we see Park
at similar pockets from from the same to
the source to the same destination we
just send the event once ok every every
time so let's say for every for every
second for everything circle we see
several pockets so especially if you
have a VPN it say before somebody
mention Open VPN so these are typical
example so we send an event every every
few set and so without doing that so
this is one of the problems that we are
still trying to put algo unfortunately
everybody is talking about EBP having
very positive terms but there are also
some compromise with it the first
problem is that BCC is not what what I
consider are stable you know too
first of all there are some limitation
term of memory loops at these type of
things
you might say so why why is it a problem
it is a problem because whenever you
have to decode the pocket you have to
know you have to go through certain
layers so in fact before if the
presentation of xdp people put a lot of
emphasis about the speed say I'll give
you this but give me this pocket but if
you have to look at the pocket before
making your decision so you have to
decode it if you want to decode it
inside the corner with EBP F you have to
deal with the problem and the limitation
of this type of tools another point for
this is that you know the bcc rules are
changing very often ok so you see people
that are playing with python and they
are happy but if you play with the C API
you know sometime this might change we
have although also some some other
little limitation that I hope that will
be solved in the future so just to wrap
up it is not possible to see the full
path from pockets to activities if there
is something bad happening I will not
say this pocket is bad but I would say
this user with this process has created
the problem that's it thanks to the you
know the container paradigm a thanks to
the fight at our library Quran on the
host not on each container so we have
the ability of monitoring all the
contents of a system and to collect this
metadata and attacked is to do pocket
the load is very little you know with
our tool the load is less than 1% so
it's almost unnoticeable and we have
this information this one showed this
preview you know it will be part of the
next and top ng version version 4 but we
plan to have this dis library available
so that there might be other tools
willing to use it so that for instance
imagine a network probe or an IDs that
want to add this information next to
their to their problems their reporting
thank you very much
[Applause]