all right so let's get started I am
I'm his Chum I work at Kong and I'm also
a maintainer of Lorex the package
manager for the Lua programming language
I've been involved with Lua since 2005
or so so it's been working with Lua for
a long time and I'm here to talk about
minimalism vs types and the long journey
with the about the hard relationship
between like a minimalistic language
like Lua and a desire for types so
minimalism well I love minimalism as all
of us here in this room probably do and
once someone asked me like what do I
like the most about programming when Lua
and the answer that I gave like right
off the bat was that well Lua fits in my
head like I know I feel like I know the
entire language right it's it's like the
whole reference manual is like this one
web page that you can read top to bottom
and like there's no like corners of the
language that I feel that I don't know
it's just like in this it's a very
gratifying since the sensation like
being able to work in a language like
that like as opposed to two huge
languages where there's always like some
kind of constructs or part of the
standard library that you have never
touched so so like this is a classic
example of like a huge language versus
like small language and like for a
reference like the entire Lua reference
manual is about the size of JavaScript
the good parts so it's and the language
is the size of the languages and the
size of their good and bad parts also
kind of match hopefully like that well
it's actually older than JavaScript but
but but yeah like it's it's in many
senses are simple it's similar and some
people who are thinking of the other
side of JavaScript they get surprised
that no there are nothing alike but if
you if you focus on the good parts of
JavaScript then there
rising Alya like so types I also love
types and one thing that I'd like to say
is that programming with types feels
like pair programming with the computer
like like you you program a little bit
and then the compiler comes and say well
well you you missed like you made a type
over here something in something like
that or all you cannot really pass this
to that and all of that so so you get
that you get this nice feedback loop
that's different than running the
program and seeing if it is seen if it
crashes right and so this is like this
is my interesting of types form they're
very practical perspective as a
practitioner as a programmer like and
not just a theoretical like as a like
programming language academic sort of
interest so before we dive into types
just to let's just get our terminology
on the same page like when we when
people often talk talk about type
languages and untyped languages and so
the more accurate terminology would be
like when you talk about untyped you
mean know types at all so that would be
like assembly everything is a byte right
and those are not usually like the types
of languages that like the kinds of
languages that we care and for all the
other ones like there are types like
types exists so string a number of
different things
automatic questions can make this a bit
confusing so said oh no it's not typed
because I can do like string one plus
two and I get a number so now it's
actually like it's just doing an
implicit converse conversion they are
actually different things like brass
presentation he mentioned that all
originally in TCL everything was really
a string and then now everything is
representable string even though there
really are different things so like
modern TCL has types like all of the
other model languages do so people in in
the few in in the theory field they say
like you shouldn't you shouldn't even
talk about untyped if you just talk
about unit types it because when you
don't have time to really have one type
like the type of everything so the
distinction that we usually care when
we're talking about this language is
typed or not like when we formally say
that is that whether it's dynamically
typed or stacked statically typed so
dynamically typed in a nutshell means
that values have types but variables
don't so you can move values that have
it's around and like and they fit any
variable so languages that fall into
this category are like low esteem
airline Python Ruby and so and so on all
of those like all of this typically the
ones that we call scripting languages
and some that we don't but that's it and
statically typed means that values have
types and variables also have types so
if you have an integer and you want to
put in this variable this variable
better be of the integer type because
otherwise it will not accept it so like
C Java go see sharp rust haskell like
all of these other are step checker
instead
to run before like run time that tells
you if your types are okay so for the
purpose of this presentation we will
totally avoid these terms like strongly
typed or weakly typed because they are
very confusing and like everyone seems
to have like a different definition of
what those mean and the better
distinction is really dynamic or static
right so so this is what we care about
but we also care about minimalism and
apparently our all of our favorite
minimalistic languages all fall you know
in the first group like there's Luwin
scheme and like all the only wants to
see also there right so what gives like
what we happens when we put minimalism
and types together right so let me go
through a brief history of the efforts
for typing Lua so back in law workshop
Fabian flirter presented tidal walk
which was based on meta Lua his Lua meta
programming library where he attempted
to do like gradual typing of Lua
programs you could you could partially
add type annotations that would verify
them and all of that in his presentation
like the like the main point of his
presentation was that we all left like
scared off the prospects of how hard
that problem was because he started like
showing like how in the simple cases
this and this work doesn't and then it
starts getting Messier and Messier and
Messier because once you start to
capture the way that that blue
programmers deal with their data
structures right he started to have to
apply heuristics and things like that so
is that scratcher had to say well wait
my type checker is gonna be running
heuristics on the code right so because
when you think of a type checker you
kind of want some certainty and and in
the end like it seems to be like a a
real a really tough problem in other
laughs tough problems is what research
is made of so around that time under
damn Idol was was working with Lua and
types and two years after that he
presented his PhD dissertation on that
was called typed Lua and an optional
type system for for Lua
he worked hard on many of those
complicated problems and he came up with
a super complicated type system that had
like many many pages full of little
Greek letters in the thesis as he just
as he tried to make sense of the whole
thing and he made an implementation that
sound github and that implementation is
a nice prototype of all those ideas but
really it's not ready for primetime in a
sense that you can't really feed
real-world programs in it and like try
to use it as a day-to-day tool because
like the type checker is just too strict
it complains about like lots of lots of
things that you as a little programmer
said now this is right you know but the
the type checker just doesn't understand
and it is a super complicated one so I
got involved back then I was doing my
own PhD at the lab like it's completely
unrelated subject but i guarante along
with the people there and so we decided
to start kind of a side project on that
and two years later around 2017 we start
a project called titan' that would be a
statically typed language that would be
like Lua like but not try to type Lua
but create a new language that will be
selling the type that will be somewhat
like Lua and designed to interact with
Lua and this is still an ongoing project
and it kind of shows that we clearly
like at that point we kind of gave up on
trying to type Lua
and I said like just let's just do
something else and and really Titan
tries to fit more as when you're
programming like in that part see part
Lua like embedded language type of thing
Titan would be more suitable for
replacing the C parts rather than the
Lua part so it's not really the same
thing and at the same time there's like
super hard research questions and on how
to go about this and like some of us
were approaching it from a very
practical standpoint some of us were
pushing from a theoretical standpoint so
at one point the project split off and
like the research branch of it is the
Pauline project in which they're really
going like data structure by data
structure from first principles and
doing the research on that right so
so yet here we are 2019 and we still
don't have a type checker for Lua we
don't have a way of like after that many
years and and so many people like
putting efforts on all that we don't
have a way to use Lua and types together
so what gives why is it so hard alright
so I did some soul searching and
thinking about the whole thing and want
to share like my my thoughts about it so
our first first stab of that at that
question like when you think about it
like and we are here talking about
minimalistic languages and it starts
talking about types types types in it
and how everything is complicated and
from your own history experience dealing
with typed languages and you think about
like I don't know Haskell or rust or C++
you know like languages that has huge
complicated type systems you start
thinking oh they ended up being
complicated languages because the types
mess up everything like with the
minimalism you know they like once you
add like the types in the whole
enchilada with it you know the language
is no longer minimalistic so maybe like
so types make our tiny languages
complicated like is that the problem all
right
my conclusion is that the problem is
kind of the opposite and this can be a
little surprising but when we think
about like our little dynamically typed
languages like Lua and scheme and like
your favorite one you might realize
after you look at it for a while that
they actually have huge type systems and
very complicated type systems and you go
like what yeah yes so if you think about
the type system as being well the set of
rules that describe what are the valid
interaction of values in correct
programs which are the things that a
type checker checks right so essentially
the type checker for those languages
it's in your head like you are the type
checker but but if you take like the C
language and it has a type checker
implemented inside GCC you can look at
the source code and you can see this is
a type checker and this is what it does
those are the rules right so let's open
our heads and look at the type checkers
that we have inside our heads for Lua
what are the rules in there you know
like how complicated like if you were to
write it in
Greek letters in a PhD thesis what Wow
what would that type system look like
for Lua codes that we actually write
nowadays with our tiny Lu a language
that fits in a you know and a 200k Qatar
Bowl no so if you are the type checker
what type system error checking no cuz
this is the kind of work you do like you
do like we have multiple returns and Luo
you do I'll get coordinates for those
two values and you realize like you give
a type error to yourself and say oh I
can do that because yesterday I changed
that function from returning two things
to returning a table so so that line on
the top is not gonna work this is the
kind of doing that you're doing you know
ahead that's why I mean by you are the
type checker right so what are you
checking what are those rules well now
we have to go to the state of the art of
sight systems right because I was
talking about dynamically typed
languages so sorry mo statically typed
language but within the realm of
statically typed typed languages there
are dependently type languages
dependently type languages in like-new
like in in the practical sense category
of languages in which values have types
variables have types but types have
values and types have types right and
and since well since types of values and
values of types right you get into an
endless infinite tower of complexity
there and now and there's a few examples
of languages out there like Idris Agda
there are not that many yet like people
always say like the same three and then
the third one is is actually like a
proof assistant like you know the the
from India right so really but this
is the kind of type system that you have
in your head when you're working with a
dynamically typed language right you
have like a nice function f a and B what
are the types of a and B you know a is
an integer and B is well if a is less
than 200 say 256 then B is a string
otherwise B is an array of strings you
know when we have when we programming
with dynamically typed languages we do
that kind of stuff all the time without
like read even realizing that we are
creating these complex types that have
like depend that the definition of the
type has a dependency that's why it's
called dependent types right on another
value right so just pause for a second
and imagine like how hard would be for
you to write a type checker that would
be able to check that you know like you
would have to go through the flow of
every like possible path that leads to
the first argument and determined that
the integer that was evaluated could
possibly ever be like less or more than
256 and then if you got a table you have
to you know prove that you know yes but
if but once we have a dynamic language
you do come up with those things because
essentially the dynamically typed
language since it imposes no
restrictions it lets you think those
thoughts right so but when you're doing
the work in your head like it's kind of
like it's not that hard you don't
actually do like the flow analysis of
the entire program in your head every
time because suppose you have those
variable variables here red green and
blue in there and there and you know
there are all integers right you know
that oh those if you see something like
this and you know like okay so these are
RGB components they go from 0 to 255 and
then I'm I'm passing an RGB component
there with an array and that's not going
to work because I expect like those
numbers to be within the range and so I
named B strings and not a race so that
so there's probably an error here right
but if the type checker had the
information that red it's only ever
between 0 to 255 you had to specify that
in the type right or then the type
checker would have an easier job would
be actually able to do that right but it
won't once you have the idea of a type
system that has like all of arithmetic
in it right
and by I mean like a type system that
encompasses our Atlantic's it mean like
by the curry howard corresponds it means
like every type system corresponds to a
kind of logic right so I first ordered a
large X second order logic you know and
and and those things right so and by the
way since the 50s we know that
arithmetic says proven undecidable in
logic so if you can have a type system
at a checker that knows all of our if
metics so yeah so we kind of do those
things all the time when we're
programming here like for example you do
something like this like load values
into a table you give them ok and an
error if not okay then well the type of
error is like it's dependent on the type
of okay like if it's a string if ok is
false
right or if it's nil right and then
what's the type of tea you know when you
get there T of one right well it might
have failed in between you know and all
those kinds of things like the floor
analysis get can't could get really
complicated and when you get to that
like in a case like Lua where the table
is the only structure type so when we
say like everything's a table like apart
from the primitives you know strings and
integers and all that it means that a
table is anything so a table it can't be
an array it can be in dictionary and be
a struct can be an object you give me a
dictionary mapping objects to strings or
arrays depending on whether the field of
the key object is true or false you know
and without realizing you start creating
the super complex types you know you can
you start creating those super complex
structures that if you were to type them
those would be the types that they would
have to have so it comes to a matter of
expressiveness right and what I mean
like expressiveness in a programming
language like how expressible it is I
don't I don't mean like really what
language can express because you know
kind of but turing completeness you know
that's oh they're all the same blah blah
blah but really it's like how can you
express it right so in that time in that
sense the dynamically typed language is
super expressive but it's super
expressed in the same way that a blank
sheet of paper is now the paper accepts
everything you know the dynamically
typed language accepts everything and
well it goes boom and you know if you do
something wrong that Bron time all the
other hand the type checker works both
for good like oh thank you for catching
my silly typos and for bad like and you
know like I know that this use of the
variable is safe here why are you
complaining about this right so
essentially the expressiveness is like
the feel of a language like regardless
of the look right so and in Lua you can
have something like this like a table
that stores like named fields like and
also serve as an array like two like
both of them right if I take like if I
do like a small transpiler that's like
took all of the keywords from Java and
turn them into Lua like it was it will
still feel like blue all right
so okay so I'm just going to jump ahead
just going so here for the final section
like hope so in the end like how much of
the language do you change like do you
make this illegal because like it's
either a map or an array right because
you could you can still represent
something like that like in Java right
you just make an object that has like
the name field and then a list you know
put one inside the other so it's like
you have to think those thoughts like in
a different way right so so the the
final point is if you want to make it
feel like lua then the type checker is
super complex you want it feel like 100%
like lower than the type checker is
impossible right because you end up with
undecidable things and if you want to
actually finish writing your type
checker you have to make cuts somewhere
but not in the word somewhere so two
options on where to make your cuts
well first you can cut on program
expressiveness as I said like you don't
allow them to mix an array in the table
and say like Oh in my typed version you
have to do something like that you know
items right or and maybe say oh I cannot
make something that's like sometimes a
nil sometimes a string and a key instead
of doing return X on Y and return nil
and error in the same function if I want
to use those two things in the same
function then we have to do return x and
y which is always like an integer or an
optional integer and the third one would
be like the next free available entry
would have to be like the error message
like those those are simple those ones
are fixable right but I'm just gaming
them as simple examples you know
otherwise you can cut on the correctness
of the type checker so you go from like
the promise that every problem that the
type checker accepts has correct types -
something like oh if I complain then
it's probably like wrong but if I don't
you know if I if I don't complain I'll
give you no guarantee and still it's
hard because you made your the
equivalent logic of your types of your
type checker
it's an unsound logic and when you at
once you add unsound logic you can start
like proving absurd things and when you
go back to the type checker it means
that it will behave in very weird ways
if you're not careful and probably even
if you are so the more sophisticated
type system the deep you are in research
territory everyone has felt like who's
ever tired try to deal with that ended
up
dealing with this so is that all lost
like in the final minutes here
well typescript has proven to be like a
successful like attempt in the industry
I'm doing that and essentially their
choice was to go for usability above all
else it means that the type system is
intentionally unsound and this is not
just a technical thing if you go there
to their bug tracker there's lots of
bugs that are close it by design by
design by design it's not meant to
detect that failure right so what about
Lua I probably have like 30 seconds and
just to give a glimpse of hope well I've
been working on exploring this design
space and playing with it so I decided
to try to write a minimalistic type
checker love Lua in Lua but just like
what's the minimum set of features so
that it could type check itself that
will be like enough to be like a real
program and not there yet well when I
try to run it like on itself it
currently feels with 384 type errors a
week ago it was a lot more so that's
progress the thing is that once you
start fixing it like you fix one thing
that fixes 100 errors and but now it's
like you know it's like Achilles in the
turtle but yeah the idea is to do
something Lua like it's here because
even if then though it's not finished it
wouldn't be fossum if you know I'll talk
about code and it's not open source
so in closing yeah the story will
continue and thank you
[Applause]