so hi this talk is going to be about
monitoring converge infrastructure
containing and running together
containers and virtual machines together
the main course here will be about
metric collection because I can't cover
all of it
so let's start my name is the Anil Quinn
I'm working in red at CES 2016 and I'm a
part of their kubera team so we'll
briefly talk about kubernetes and
metrics collection in kubernetes the
main sources the key sources for metrics
collection we'll see how it comes
together for Matthias to provide us a
full monitoring pipeline solution having
covered that we want to throw in virtual
machines into the mix so we'll briefly
look what Qbert is that brings virtual
machines on top of kubernetes see from
past experience what we have collected
the for virtual machine and matrixes and
see how it all comes together eventually
so we have kubernetes as a start as our
container centric platform Orchestrator
that orchestrates computational nodes
and pods network storage database all of
components that you would like to
monitor in your system and the second
building block here is prometheus
Prometheus was is was originated in
Sound Cloud in 2012 now it's an open
source community it's a monitoring and
alerting system it's a multi-dimensional
label based model it based it's based on
a time series the data which is
comprised of a key key value pairs it
has a very strong a query language
promiscuous prompt QL that analyzes that
time series data and you can see it
really integrates in a natively almost
way with kubernetes Sam the community's
components already has integrated or
have integrated the primitives
a quick view on the model so in a minute
we have the Prometheus server that
scrapes and pooled that
through HTTP endpoints into its server
collects then aggregates that data on
the data you can perform a prompt QL
series in order to analyze it and move
it on aggregate the data and even create
the alerting alerting are pushed to the
alert manager into its clients and you
can also use grow fauna or other API
clients to visualize that data but again
our main focus here is matrix collection
so because Prometheus needs as much as
auto discovery as it can get it needs to
scrape data pull data from matrix
endpoints HTTP endpoints for that it's
very easy to integrate with kubernetes
since it exposes these endpoints on on
API is on HTTP as I said some of the
matrix is already exposed through the
matrix endpoint and some we need to be
added and collected so I'll go over two
or three sources of matrixes in
kubernetes in the community say
architecture the first one of them is
host matrix kubernetes notes so
kubernetes knows didn't have natively
exposing matrix endpoints for that we
they had to write an exporter an
exporter is Prometheus exporter is a
service that collects you all of your
data from your node for that good
example or any other data you need to
expose from your application etc exposes
them on the permittee assay endpoint so
primitives can come discover it and
scrape them out so node node metrics are
scraped from proc and you get all your
familiar house statistics such as node
CPU node CPU for example has like 15
dimensions of matrix type Rossi to you
like either
I await but if you want to analyze for
example how much time the CPU spent on a
node or pair CPU core you can perform a
promise QL
and remove these and get your note CPU
statistics are there are of course
memory memory available you can also
perform queries against the total memory
left there are more advanced matrix then
only note statistic if you look at it in
a kubernetes kind of way for that we
have another component called cube state
metrics which looks at it from the
kubernetes way and also takes into
account memory limits and CPU limits
moving on so in our house we have
containers and containers metrics are
exposed to see advisor see see advisor
provides you data about containers
runtimes such as docker or cryo it is
embedded in the cubelet so cubelet
natively exposes an endpoint to two
slash metrics which is a port for for
Prometheus so we don't need to add
additional exporters to collect that
data so you analyze these metrics and
resources usage and expose them on the
metrics these are also also call the
core metrics for each container and
again much like know just in just in a
container view you have your original
CPU matrix in memory memory actually
this matrix is very advanced it's it's a
in the nimac so you know it gives you
actually the exact memory usage you have
left taking into consideration all other
matrix you have and you have under your
container and of course memory
transmission
another part let's look a bit on the
orchestration parts so I'll talk about
only API Silverhill so because the API
server is the front end for kubernetes
cluster and gets all the calls and
relays them to etcd in controller it's
an important component to monitor for
example you want to create a pod or run
a deployment you want to see and it's
all done through REST API calls so you
want to see you want to see the request
rates and latency how long did it take
for me to complete a request to create
such a deployment for example or how
long did it take even counting the
amount of that and let's say you want to
create a thousand deployments on your
cluster when you create a deployment it
goes on to work use for controllers it
accumulates in cache the the request for
creating objects or deployments and if
your queue gets accumulated and get
stuck it's it's you want to detect that
bottleneck so it's a very important
aspect to monitor because kubernetes
is based on goal so you get
out-of-the-box goal and statistics
garbage collection memories Fez etc and
you also monitored the service process
itself so that was only one component of
course you have metrics collection for
scheduler the kubernetes controller etcd
but I won't get into those now there's a
an add-on called cube state matrix this
add-on you need to deploy as an instance
only one instance in your kubernetes
cluster and it's more its relates more
to not health or utilization
it focuses on counts and status so for
example you want to check what what
status is your pod boding in terms of
scheduling or health not helping the
phase it is in you have the concept of
CPU limits or memory limits we won't
allow a pod to run containers without
any boundaries
to exhaust all of them so I want to
check statistics how how much memory you
have in according to your limits or
before or provide even more advanced
their queries on these statistics there
are a thousand of examples in cube state
metrics I'll talk about for example the
replica sets you have defined a replica
set replica set you want to run a number
of deployments on your cluster and you
want to make sure that these number of
deployments I deployments are running in
Trussell so you want to see if they are
not available how many are there in the
cluster and so on so that was very
briefly about kubernetes components and
sources for metrics collection and now
we want to add virtual machines into the
mix so Qbert Qbert comes to close the
gap between virtual machines and
containers under the same under the same
hood and it converts infrastructure we
want to run also virtual machines also
containers in our in the same platform
and we ask yourself why so this is a
great allegory containers are considered
to be lightweight they're fast to bring
up their natively they have native
performance but virtual machines with
their bulky heavy utility hard Hardware
belt are not going to disappear we'll
have them in the next five or ten years
at at least and we'll still want to
maintain them you can look at an example
for mainframes
it's taken a long time to face house
mainframes they're see they still even
exist so so what can I do with first of
all we want to bring the legacy we want
to run it under the same folder we don't
want to maintain two infrastructures we
don't want to maintain two
infrastructure so we're going to mix and
match and add virtualization on top of
kubernetes that's also getting all the
kubernetes advantages such as scheduling
the storage networking well some
and fixes to manage to do that we are
also in the use of Qbert and running
virtual machines on the kubernetes
cluster you can also enable and run any
of us who want to run on coop on top of
kubernetes
so this is governor this and we added to
the mix some virtual machine components
again I won't go too deep into the
components so on the left you can see
the node in the node we have a pod which
runs a vm via virtual machines runs on
pods you know and you have also side the
containers on that pod to enable
utilization such as they lived it they
also have key components very resembling
kubernetes components like via type i
same as api server to create your
virtual machine CL these pass them on to
you TC d having the built controller
identifying that creating a pod running
a virtual machine on a pod and also
scheduling it to a node once it's
scheduled to a node the virtual machine
gets the nodes assigned and then all the
handling of the vm life cycles moves to
the virtual handler again on top of the
the fork so of course I added something
new
I have monitoring on kubernetes I want
to also monitor virtual machines so I
want to figure out first what to collect
so a quick example from pure
virtualization overt other it uses
collect D to collected matrixes it has
powerful plugins a lot of plugins they
can add 2 to it and run it it it gets
you how statistics database statistics
angel engine stats and more more
important for us right now it's virtual
machine statistics so for virtual
machine statistics we have a wheeled
plugin will again communicates with
library and library gives us the
information about the virtual machine so
of course you are introducing here some
new aspects not necessarily all will be
monitored and adapted to kubernetes but
virtual CPU how much time I get
was running on a CPU memory some
specific related memory matrix like
ballooning or over-commitment
memory management matrixes disk reads
and white flashes for discus for disks
and also network aspects
some of them might merge from the
benefit of kubernetes but we might want
to adjust them to virtual machines but
some will need to add one strong example
I can give you that kubernetes has a
scheduler a very strong catch schedule
but it doesn't have like a tea
scheduling policies we have in
virtualization and we want and we'll
probably add these policy also to the
scheduler so we want to see why our
cluster behaves in such scheduling
matter like let's say hi variable H a
reservation and we also want to monitor
that maybe we'll decide in the future to
change the scheduling policy so it's a
very important aspect so we consistently
similarities and add in a virtual
machine statistics so coming back again
to prometheus and kubernetes we had our
collection node exporters cube
components cubed matrix and of course
we're missing the a collection for
virtual machine virtual machines and
cubed just came in so we need to write a
custom exporter very much like not
exported so for that we need primitives
exporters writing an exponent can be
done in Prometheus client library for us
it was very easy it's mainly in go so
it's very native to write it so that
that exporter will collect your data
from the app matrix it will expose it on
matrix endpoint from kubernetes flash
matrix and it will be available to
scraped by Prometheus server so we'll
add custom X photos for our virtual
machines
and we'll now start pulling other
components so we have the kubernetes
components and now we talked about
virtual machine matrix we talked about
components for video for orchestrating
the virtual machines such as they have
built API in the field controller we
have also processes that running inside
the pod as I said for enabling
virtualization such as library and qmo I
want to complete the picture in a small
note about the whole cluster in order to
deploy Prometheus servers on a
kubernetes cluster we can use very
easily prometheus operator
it's from it's it has two main
functionalities its first of all to
deploy and manage the primitive server
you get also alert manager you can get
also note exporters or other responses
you may define and also important to
watch your components on the cluster so
we added virtual machine and in order to
watch them we have a previous operator
we have an entity called a service
monitor you define the port you define
the objects you want to monitor you add
the corresponding labels for that matter
and if you now create new series it
detects that and start scraping these
these metrics also for virtual machines
in our case
so cubed metrics so I'm taking you back
so we looked at metrics we collect for
kubernetes some came from the cubelet
some came from node and components it is
CD scheduler and controllers and now
adding to our mix we add the very
controller and we have the very PI and
the veiled handler and I and I told you
it's very something the kubernetes
components so if we look back at the API
server we talked about it square
communicating with controller walk use
and performance it's it has native
statistic about goal and and it also
handles the REST API requests and
measures them so very similar we have
the convert will control a walk use we
want to want to go over that and get
statistics about that we have cue Layton
series work duration and number of the
time also the caches that comes from go
race REST API calls again very similar
to the API so low
and now I want to focus specifically on
virtual machine' statistics so the
previous were general components in a
kubernetes cluster here you drill down
into the virtual machine statistics and
matrixes so two major parts virtual
machine matrix which we saw how how and
what we collect in overt in a pure
virtualization environment and processes
so for processor its I'll say it's more
for deployment the developer utility and
less for real cluster and management and
observability and these processes for
example are also scraped from proc like
a node exporter and we get metrics about
them okay so some some important there
information about being metrics we can
see the four pillars of metrics we
collected in Oviatt and usually these
pillars are repeating themselves in all
of the matrix these are not the only
matrix will collect but these these are
the most prominent example so for
example V a V n CPU or CPU time I want
to see my guest CPU how much time they
use memory for example you want to
create a matrix that is composed for
several matrixes how much how much
memory we haven't said how much actual
ballooning was left for the VM itself
our assess the amount of it all
compiling and coming down to to
completing a collect matrix and also
about network on the on the bottom you
can see the pod informatics which I
talked about processes themselves and
you can see a full form of matrix how it
looks in a Prometheus expose format you
have the you have the name of the metric
himself itself which domain or for our
or matter what VM does it monitor you
can add a host or other labels for that
matter also we added the process name
and the type of matrix
this applies to all metrics time all
metrics time when time series format we
want to show here so this is an example
how how it will look on a graph on a
dashboard of course you can also use
cabaña for that matter or other tools
for a very simple example for a VM
running on a pod is CPU usage and memory
usage okay so in conclusion that was a
very fast talk about some some concepts
but the main take here
is that we have we have kubernetes and
primitives we have this whole platform
and framework and solution existing we
have very easy extensibility for that so
for us by adding a new add-on
qubit and virtualization in turn a mix
monitoring that was kind of native and
very supportive and for us we got a
complete monitor instruction and it's
continuing to grow as we speak for
convergence for social infrastructure
but it's it shouldn't be just only for
virtual machine everybody can take it
for another is is himself and if he adds
new components on top of kubernetes on
add-ons or side side application we can
monitor that using the concepts of
primitives exporters and are there many
notions