hello hi welcome to
presentation on Netflix and FreeBSD my
name is Jonathan Looney I am the manager
of a software development group at
Netflix my group maintains and develops
the operating system that runs on the
content caches that stir that served
Netflix is a streaming video and I'm
gonna talk to you a little bit about how
we develop that software and
specifically how we use some open source
software and particularly FreeBSD to
deliver our streaming video to happy
consumers around the world so to start
with I need to tell you that open
connect open connect is Netflix is CDN
open connect is a global efficient and
purpose-built CDN for distributing
Netflix is content it is it is global it
is large it is very fun to work on the
open connect network at our peak we
deliver over 100 terabits per second
around the world and that makes the
engineering challenges very interesting
so 1% differences make a big deal
they're a big deal when you're dealing
with these large scales as I was
preparing for the talk and I was
thinking about this I was realizing that
if we had a 1% change in the number of
TCP segments we transmit so for instance
if we already transmitted a 1% more of
the TCP segments on our network that's
an extra terabit per second at peak that
we're sending out to the Internet and
that's a lot of traffic and that's a big
change and so we work in an environment
where small changes are a big deal and
we also value small improvements
obviously we'd like big ones but every
every little bit of efficiency matters
and so it's a really fun environment to
work and do engineering work the part of
our CDN is our content caches
you could almost say that the backbone
of the open connect network they are
what delivers that hundreds here
for more than hundred terabytes per
second at peak you see here a picture of
the one of our storage appliances from a
few years ago
it's the 40 gigabit per second attached
storage appliance and it has 248
terabytes of storage and a to ru form
factor we also have other varieties of
caches our highest end production one at
the moment
delivers hundreds here or 100 gigabits
it's a hundred gigabits per second
attached and it delivers it can deliver
essentially a full line rate in a one
argued form factor the OCA runs almost
exclusively open source software and two
of the more important things we run are
the operating system is based on FreeBSD
it's a lightly modified version of that
and our web server is a slightly
modified version of nginx or slightly
customized version of nginx this is our
typical traffic profile you'll see that
we have lots of Netflix clients that are
pulling data from our CDN we have a
group that manages the steering for that
so we can steer the Netflix clients to
go to the the right caches for to serve
their content there there are
redundancies built into the system and
controlling the clients is very helpful
because there it gives us the chance to
tell them exactly how they should behave
in various failure scenarios and so we
can build redundancies into the stitch
into the system such that if a single
o-ca fails a single one of our content
caches fails the clients can seamlessly
switch over to other content caches and
that means that if we are testing the
new software and that new software has
some sort of fatal error our clients can
seamlessly switch over to something
running more stable software and
continue to be served without hopefully
without even noticing any difference in
the quality of their video
we also get a lot of data back from
these clients and so getting controlling
the clients it's very helpful because
the clients can tell us or controlling
these applicant applications is very
helpful because the client applications
can tell us exactly what they think
about the quality of the cash that
they're talking to they can tell us
whether they can tell us how fast they
were able to get the video whether they
got it fast enough to satisfy the
streaming needs of the client whether it
was very choppy or smooth things like
that so we can get a lot of good
information from our video applications
and that helps us to make informed
decisions about whether we've made
things better or worse in the software
that we're developing our typical
workload on one of our content caches
looks like a typical web server you've
got a bunch of storage you need to get
data off the storage into memory we then
encrypt it we often encrypt it for
transmission over TLS session and then
we send it out we send it out some mix
now this is not not rocket science in
the sense this is something that many
people have done before and there are
even people who have probably other
people who have done it at the high
speeds we are what the secret sauce if
you will or makes this special is that
we are trying to get high speeds high
efficiency or high speeds out of our
systems with high efficiency so we want
to not only deliver a great experience
to our end users we also want to control
the costs and so we we actually work
very hard to optimize our workload so
that it can fit into relatively
inexpensive parts that you could go buy
off the by off the street there's almost
nothing that we use that you couldn't go
buy from someone if you wanted to we
don't have custom Asics and things like
that floating around and so the the
secret sauce if you will is simply being
able to
get things get things through this
system as fast as possible as cheaply as
possible
and you'll see that there's a couple of
resource constraints we have the first
one is the the disk i/o and the network
i/o all has to go over PCI 8 all over
PCIe and so we have we're constrained to
the number of PCI lanes we have we're
also constrained in the bandwidth those
PCI lanes have and then all the data
coming in and out of memory again we're
constrained by the number of memory
controllers we have number of memory
channels as well as the speed of those
the memory so those are the two main
resource constraints that we fight
against and you can either buy your way
out of that by buying bigger CPUs or you
can try to make things more efficient by
utilizing the resources you have more
more efficiently more intelligently and
we try to focus on the latter
so using FreeBSD and commodity parts we
have we get 90 gigabits per second
steady state out of our latest hundred
gig storage appliance actually I think
all of our hundred gig storage
appliances at this point the latest one
we're using fifty-five percent of the
CPU on a 16 core 2.6 eager Hertz CPU for
those that are interested it's an Intel
Xeon 6122 CPU
there's 16 terabytes nvme in this
appliance and 96 C bytes of RAM in a 1
ru form factor 90 gigabits the reason
I'm quoting the new gigabits per second
number is because that's what we we
shoot for in production we we aim to use
90% of the attachment speed the reason
we aim for 90% is we do have a searing
system the tri-state clients to the
correct caches and if you target 90% you
can do that pretty reliably if you go
above that it gets a lot harder to do
the control loop correctly on top of
that we need some Headroom in case there
are failures in the system
so if a Content cache fails the clients
need someplace else to go to and so we
need a little bit of spare capacity in
the system and the 10% gives us just a
little bit - a little bit of headroom to
absorb clients that are switching away
so we would consider 90 gigabits per
second to be our target for this
platform and we can do that with 55%
roughly 55% CPU usage and here's some
graphs that show that you'll see that
the bandwidth is hovering right around
90 gigabits per second and the CP
utilizations right around 55 and this is
measured within an actual system serving
production traffic this is not a
synthetic benchmark this is what we get
in production so let's talk about the
operating system that runs on these
caches it's a as I said it's a lightly
modified version of FreeBSD for those of
you that are not familiar with FreeBSD
here's the 30 second introduction AT&T
had a UNIX distribution they the
University of california-berkeley got a
license to use that distribution they
created what they called the Berkeley
software distribution and there's a lot
that I'm skipping over but essentially
FreeBSD and net bsd are both descendants
of that codebase and the other there's
lots of other bsd distributions i'm not
trying to cover them exhaustively but
this is where freebsd came from it's not
a linux distribution it's not it's not
really related to linux other than the
fact that linux and unix look similar in
a lot of ways
more or less depending on who you ask
probably the other thing is that freebsd
is a complete software system as opposed
to linux which is a kernel and then the
software distributions turn it into a
full operating system freebsd is a full
operating system so the freebsd release
cycle looks probably like your typical
software release cycle for an open
source project
there there is a head branch which is
the development branch that's where new
features and bug fixes go first and then
there are these release branches that
come off of that every once in a while
and the release branch is called the
stable branch so for instance there was
a stable 11 branch about two years ago I
believe which is the branch that all of
the 11.0 men dot X releases come off of
so all the eleven minor all of the
releases that are part of the eleven
major release all the minor releases
come off of that release branch likewise
the recently was a stable twelve branch
that was created over time of course the
code diverges as you'd expect with you
know a software development model like
this and the new features go into head
and not all of them are back ported
depending on just how stable they are so
a while ago when I first joined Netflix
it was right around the time that we
were running stable ten which was the
the major release before stable eleven
so we were our operating system was
based on stable ten and we had a choice
when stable eleven was released we could
stay on stable ten and get farther
behind or we could switch to stable
eleven or head and we decided to rebase
our code on to stable eleven or pet and
then we had the choice well it basically
stable eleven and head or the same thing
at this point because it's just branched
so which do we want to do we want to go
to the next stable release or do we want
to track head and we decided to track
the development branch and so weary
based on to the development branch and
we began to track that and we did that
for about two years and then stable
twelve came along and we had a choice
valo stable 12 or stay on head and there
was essentially no discussion or debate
everyone loved tracking head so much
that we've continued to do that so it's
worked really well for us
this is sort of what the code
inheritance looks like for those of you
that proposed me that need this mental
model or appreciate the mental model so
FreeBSD heads code bases at the top we
have our internal master branch and
about every five weeks we take a sync
from head to our internal master branch
we develop some more code and then we
branch off our release branches and we
shoot to have a release just about once
every five weeks our typical release
cycle is five weeks of development
followed by five weeks of testing the
five weeks of so there's two releases
included in a given time one in
development one in testing and
deployment we start off with a freebie
emerge from FreeBSD head close to the
start of the development process then we
also throughout the five weeks for doing
feature development and integrating our
features into the master branch with the
other features that have been developed
and of course we're doing continual
testing throughout the five weeks at
right at the five week mark we we make
our release branch and then we begin the
process of doing further testing further
intensive testing on that release before
we deploy it more widely so at this
stage we would be running this release
on approximately what we'd be using
approximately 45 caches to test this
release with a mixture of representative
hardware from the different kinds of
hardware that we support half of those
caches would be running the old
operating system half the new operating
system and we would do a very close
comparison of the performance of the old
operating system versus the new one and
so we look at obvious things like panics
and crashes and so forth but we also
look at the metrics of how the system is
performing it has the CPU utilization
gone up or down are we able to push out
the end with as fast or able to push up
bits as fast have TCP retransmissions
changed noticeably we look at has power
usage changed
noticeably so we look at all of the
metrics you and probably think that we
look at and maybe even a few more
regarding the the system itself we also
look at the metrics the clients give us
so where we the clients can tell us
whether or not they like this new
software and if the clients tell us that
they're experienced getting data from
the new the soft the castrating the new
software is as good as the experience
use it from the cache run in the old
software that's a pretty good indication
that we haven't messed anything up and
if their experience is even better
that's great after we do our dev testing
that we fixed whatever bugs we find it
moves on to a canary testing so we've
deployed at this point to a much larger
set of caches so many more clients are
hitting this and we can again do the
comparison to see if things have gotten
better or worse or stay at about the
same and make sure that matches our
expectations and then finally we go
through about two weeks of deployment in
an emergency which does happen
periodically so for example a security
vulnerability or something like that
we can speed up this process very
greatly but if we have the time to do
this sort of this sort of process we
much prefer to be slow and methodical
then than rushed but if we need to we
can rush out fixes in a hurry so one of
the questions you might be asking is
well just what kind of features do you
need to develop and the features that we
develop are basically aimed at one of
two things the first one is making our
customer experience better or making the
OCS run more efficiently thereby
lowering our costs and we want to do one
of those one of those two things ideally
we want to do both at the same time but
we try we try very very very hard not to
sacrifice customer performance in order
to save money so we try to do both at
the same time and there are things we
can do as software developers to make
the customer exterior
it's better so for example getting bites
off the disk faster is something that
can help the customer experience because
their video starts playing that much
faster and there are things we can do as
software developers that will make that
better better or worse but here's some
examples of some features that either
we've developed internally or sponsored
in the community
the first one is Numa enhancements
freebsd has had numerous support for
many years but it hasn't it hasn't
worked for our particular workflow very
well we've tried it so or at least it
didn't several years ago so we've we've
explored adding or we've been adding
some enhancements to it to make it work
better for everyone but also
particularly for our workflow the next -
a synchronous send file and Colonel TLS
are things that enable us to get higher
speed higher efficiency through the box
by avoiding copy a bunch of context
switches and copying data between
colonel and user space I think other
people are probably or some other people
are probably using DP DK in this space
we aim to keep as much in the kernel as
we can and so kernel TLS and
asynchronous send file are ways that you
can the user space can tell the colonel
please do this for me and then the
kernel takes care of it for the user
space a streaker does send the file you
tell the colonel please send these bytes
from this file over the socket and it
will just do that and it'll only really
tell you if there's a problem the kernel
TLS you give the kernel the right
encryption keys then the kernel will go
do the TLS encryption for you and so you
combine the two together and with one
system call you can send a large chunk
of a file to a user without the user
space having to make further system
calls or do more copies the next two
were PDF allocation enhancements and an
unmapped em buffs those are both ways
that we gained efficiency
by taking bottlenecks out of the system
the PIPA allocations P posture the
physical buffers that handled data on
Hindle or store data when it's coming
off of the disk so they would be buffers
for disk operations there was contention
for a lock which was making the
performance very very bottleneck and so
we we did some work to rewrite that and
be able to get more parallelism during
the PPF allocation process unmapped m
buffs again it was about taking
bottlenecks out of the system someone on
my team managed to find a way that we
could take the same amount of data and
instead of representing it in I think
it's like 64 Network buffers we can now
represent it in one network buffer io
scheduling again we can really make it a
significant impact on users which we get
data off the disk at the right time it
actually really matters what when you
read and write data you don't want to
read it too early you don't want to
write it too early you don't want to
read it or write it too late either so
it really matters and we've done some
work to make sure that we are doing IO
at the right time and doing the right
amount of i/o and so forth and likewise
the same thing applies to trims and
we've also been doing some work to make
sure we send down the right trims at the
right time and also at the right pace
because sometimes just drives don't
behave well when you send down a whole
bunch of trims all at once and so we
we've done some work on scheduling those
as well and then finally we do work in
TCP regularly so there's a whole group
that works just on TCP algorithms and so
forth we've done a lot of work in both
research and development in algorithms
to get TCP to transmit data better
where better would mean again sending
the right bits at the right
for that for that session and we've also
added some logging and debugging
infrastructures so we can tell just
what's going on when things don't work
the way we think they should and that's
been very useful for us and developing
these things and we've shared all this
with the I think we've shared all of
this with the community at this point so
I think that just about all of this is
either upstream or is in the process of
being upstream in some way
tracking head makes it lets us be stay
forward-looking and stay focused on
innovation the the problem that you can
run into when you are tracking the
stable branches is that you continually
have to deal with the problem of my code
doesn't match what everyone else is
developing on upstream and so when there
are bug fixes that occur or new features
that you want you have to figure out how
to get them back into the code that
you're actually running likewise when
you get the new merges from upstream
sometimes you have to redevelop your
features because the the api's have
changed or data structures have changed
and all of a sudden the code you had
doesn't work anymore but by tracking
head were able to stay very very close
to what's going on in the upstream
developing community and instead of
continually redeveloping this stuff
we've already done we can just work on
developing new things that will benefit
us and hopefully benefit other freebsd
users as well my my my hypothesis is
that you downstream users and open
source projects can get stuck in one of
two cycles which I've labeled vicious
and virtuous and this is not entirely
original thought but I think you can
easily get stuck in this vicious cycle
what I call the vicious cycle which
starts with infrequent merges and so if
you're a downstream
the downstream user and I don't mean an
end user in this case I mean a company
like us that's trying to write an
operating system or use a net or either
write an operating system and use an
upstream operating system and customize
it produces or use an upstream
application and customize it for users
that that's the kind of user I'm talking
about and I think this cycle starts with
infrequent merges so when you start with
infrequent merges and this is infrequent
merges of the development code so this
could mean that you are tracking a
stable branch and/or a released branch
and then every year or two you jump to
the next release branch that's innocent
in essence that's an infrequent merge of
the development code and when you start
off with that what happens over time as
you get farther and farther away from
the upstream projects so when you do
actually try to do a merge you have a
lot of conflicts you have regressions
things don't work right and it becomes
very painful and so every time you do
one of those merges it's very painful
and disruptive to the organization the
developers who were developing code
suddenly have to stop developing new
features and go back and make all the
old stuff work again with the new code
and that's not very fun to do as a
developer but it also means that's a
whole bunch of time you're not writing
new features and all that means is that
you are you end up thinking these words
are so painful that you're going to do
them even less frequently and when you
do them less frequently you have even
more merge conflicts and you have more
regressions which means that you have to
spend even more time fixing them all
which means your feature velocity gets
even slower and the whole thing is so
painful that you want to do the merges
even less and at some point maybe you
even stopped taking merges from upstream
and instead you just simply try to
cherry pick back the bug fixes that you
think you need so you can compare that
to what I call the virtuous cycle which
starts with frequent merges of the
developing code so when you're
frequently merging the development code
you're diverging from it less overtime
and that means that each merge is much
easier they'll probably still be
conflicts they're probably still be
regressions but there should be fewer of
them and each merge should be much
easier to handle furthermore because
you're so close to the development
branch it's easier to get things up
streams it takes time it up streaming
things is not just about pushing your
code into the upstream project rather
upstream things first of all you need to
generalize the feature and make it
generally applicable to all the users of
the project on top of that you probably
need to do some code cleanup because
there's probably some rough edges and
then if you are and that's just if
you're running the development branch if
you're right if your code is based off
of a stable branch you need to do the
extra step of then rebasing your code
onto the development branch by running
by running the development branch
internally we're able to skip that last
step so we still need to clean up our
code we still need to generalize it and
there's some that costs extra money for
us but we're willing to do it because we
think it's the right thing to do and all
of that means that we can get our code
up streamed that much easier because we
don't have to rebase it regularly on to
the development branch to get an
upstream and having that code upstream
to means that our diff against the
development branch of the upstream
project is relatively small that lets us
focus more on getting our feature
developing new features so we're to
spending less and less time of dealing
with old features or spending more time
dealing with new features and on top of
that it lets us collaborate effectively
with other people in the upstream
community who are using using this
project because we're most freebsd
developers run freebsd head and because
we we also use head internally we are
able to directly share patches with them
and they can apply the patches they
apply cleanly they get senesce patches
they like they apply cleanly and so we
can collaborate together
we're doing our work and all that means
is that it makes it easy for us to do
more frequent merges in fact we've
gotten to the point where my developers
will sometimes just commit stuff
upstream to the upstream projects rather
than to our repository and we'll just
pull it back in the next upstream sink
that that we do now having said that we
do keep local dips for a few reasons
the first one is should be fairly
obvious it's information covered by MDA
we do occasionally get information from
vendors which helps us to do something
we need to do but it's covered under an
NDA and they will not let us upstream
the code based on that I think we have
something like a hundred lines of code
that fall in this category so it's a
very very very small diff but this does
happen occasionally
we also we also have features which are
still in development or testing we will
sometimes commit features to our tree
for testing purposes and we don't
upstream them usually until we're sure
they actually work and so we'll keep
that local diff until we're sure the
feature works and we've had the chance
to generalize it and that's the third
reason we keep local dips there are
features we have which are too specific
for us there there are things that help
us with our workload but they're not
general enough we have a very specific
workload you know as I showed you we
tried our our whole business is getting
data off of disks into memory encrypting
it in memory sending it down on a NIC
that's what we do and there are other
people that use computers for other
things and they might not what is good
for us might not be good for them on top
of that we have a rather rather
homogeneous environment all of our
caches are Intel 64-bit and there are
people that run other architectures and
again though it's good for us and in
celle 64-bit might not be
four-armed 64-bit or arm 32-bit or risk
RISC processors and so forth so there
are features that need to be generalized
and we will hang on to those internally
until we've had the chance to generalize
them and once we have generalized them
and made sure that they work for
everyone or at least don't make things
worse for anyone else then we will then
we'll go through the process of up
streaming them but it's our intentions
upstream any code that we can I think
that this is one of the great things
about working at Netflix I've worked at
other companies that used open source
software as the basis for their products
and they kept everything inside so they
had lots of local patches that it was
very hard to share outside of the
company Netflix does allow and in fact
encourage the use of open source
software make sense but they also let us
freely contribute our software back and
so the approval process upstream of
feature is essentially it's
automatically approved and that's really
nice so we can get our software up
streamed rather he's rather easily from
the Netflix perspective and we're
willing to pay willing to pay our
developers or give them some amount of
time to go through the process of
upstream in those cleaning up the code
generalizing it making it work for the
broader community because we think
there's value in up streaming what we've
done so we get a couple benefits from
tracking freebsd head the first one is
we get quicker feature iteration as I
mentioned we're not our developers
aren't constantly stuck looking
backwards but rather we can they can
develop looking forwards and they can
they can rapidly develop new features
knowing that they're going to be able to
get them there they're going to develop
them once for us in our code base and
then that's the same code base they'll
be up streaming them into and so they
don't have to think about what's going
to work in stable 10 and then what's
going to work in head and you sort of
develop this features twice they can
just develop them once and just worry
about the one environment we also get
quicker access to new freebsd features
and this is probably the right point to
mention that we're very happy running
freebsd we get great performance at a
freebsd it's very stable and we get
access to lots of really cool features
that people in the freebsd community are
working on and so it's a great benefit
to us that we run that we track heads so
that we can get access to the new
features as soon as they're committed
and so someone commits a new feature
today and it can be running in our
network somewhere between five and
fifteen day five and fifteen weeks from
now typically so we like the fact that
we get quick access to new freebsd
features and we can do cool things by
getting access to those features we also
get quicker bug fixes and this isn't
just because the code gets committed
first to head that's true so freebsd
developers are fixing a bug they'll put
it in a freebsd head and then once
they're sure it works and it's heads and
soak time they'll back port it to older
releases so we get access to the bug
fixes you know a couple weeks earlier
generally running freebsd head but on
top of that we also get quicker bug
fixes because our bug reports come much
closer to when the codes committed so
let's say you're an upstream developer
in the FreeBSD project and you commit
code today it may be two years before
that ends up in a freebsd release used
by the general community once that
happens two years from now someone may
find a bug and report it to you are you
going to remember why you wrote that
code two years ago contrast that with
what happens when we find bugs you
commit the code today
in the next one to five weeks we get the
code in a sink we find a bug and we
report it and that's we report a bug to
you on code you just wrote a few weeks
ago you're much more likely to have the
context in your head and it's likely
that you'll remember why you were at the
code the way you did and you can quickly
help us troubleshoot and fix the bugs on
top of that they're easier to fix
generally because there's not two years
of other stuff built built up that
depends on that bug being there you know
that that sometimes happens over time
people you know they depend on oh they
were lying a bug being there because
it's been there for two years they think
that's just the way things are supposed
to work and you could try to fix a bug
and you end up having to untangle this
rat's nest of dependencies that have
built up by finding the bug sooner and
reporting the bug sooner were able to
generally get fairly quick fixes and
before lots of other dependent stuff is
built up that makes it harder to fix it
also enables collaboration as I
mentioned most freebsd developers run
freebsd head and so we're able to
directly share patches with them and
that's that's good we really like the
fact we can collaborate with other
people in the community and I want to be
clear we're not it's not a one-way
collaboration where we're trying to
figure out what we can get from other
people we really do like collaborating
with people and being able to share the
patches we have the things we're
thinking about and you know also find
out what they're thinking about in ways
that we can work on projects together
perhaps it also minimizes our merged
conflicts as I mentioned sometimes our
developers will even just commit code
directly to the FreeBSD project and
we'll pull it back as part of the next
sync in other cases we it may take us a
little bit a little bit of time to
upstream things but we can upstream them
much more easily because we don't have
to go through that step of rebasing onto
FreeBSD headfirst and so that that
really helps us keep our dip a local dip
low and minimizes the words conflicts
that we have it also amortizes the merge
cost so
if we did if once every two years we
switched rebased our code on to the
latest release that would be a very
painful long difficult merge instead we
spread it out and we do it you know once
every five weeks or so we do a little
bit of that merge and so it's a much
more manageable chunks the diff is much
smaller it's much easier to spot bugs if
we absolutely needed to it's even
possible to go do a binary search
through the code the code that's being
committed to figure out where somewhere
a regression was introduced so we've got
much more manageable diffs it's much
easier to to deal with but overall I
would say we probably spend about as
much time doing our in aggregate we
spent probably spent about as much time
doing our once every five week merge as
we would on the big merge at the end of
the at the end of the the two years but
I think the spreading out is much more
pleasant for everyone freebsd also I
think gets some benefits from what we do
the first one is that they get wide
deployment of their head branch very
early so their head branch is usually a
commit on the head branch is deployed in
our network somewhere between five and
fifteen weeks after it's committed to
the freebsd head and i think it's a
testament to how stable the freebsd head
code is that we can do this it's a very
stable very usable release and we're
able to successfully deploy that code
very quickly on a large number of caches
and they get the benefit of having that
early deployment and that early wide
deployment of their code so that we can
find we can find bugs now obviously we
try to find them before it's deployed
that widely but just in case they
slipped through there their code is
still seeing still seeing use on a large
number of content caches
around the world they also get early
intensive testing of that code we test
the code thoroughly before we deploy it
and again it gets tested in production
and we we also have an incentive to
upstream our code and so we because we
want to minimize your diffs we have a
great incentive to upstream our code and
it's easier for us to do that and so I
think more more of our features end up
in the upstream code base then might
otherwise and I think that's good for
the freebsd community as a whole again
we're not trying to just get our code
into upstream freebsd but we want to
benefit the upstream project by giving
them access to the features we've
developed internally and we think that
that's good for it's good for everyone
so you might have some you might think
of some objections to running
development code so the first one is it
isn't stable right well actually it
really is the freebsd community is
fanatical about keeping head stable and
in fact it may even border on unhealthy
it's there that fanatical about keeping
heads stable which is great I think is
great
it means that you can download and use
FreeBSD head and it it generally just
works really well why should you pay to
find the bugs that others are gonna find
weather testing head well the obvious
problem here is if everyone has this
mindset who's actually going to test
head who's actually going to test the
code and you know someone's gotta
someone has to do that testing and I
think that we're well positioned to do
that testing for at least for our use
case on top of that we would probably
still find some of these bugs anyway two
years down the road when we get the code
but it would be much harder for people
to fix because they would have lost all
that context about why they committed
that code aren't there more security
bugs in development code well actually
no not in our experience I think
almost all if not all of the security
bugs that we've run across to the past
two years have most of them have been in
the stable branches as well and so on
the whole we probably have the same
security bugs in general that the stable
branches have but the people developing
the fixes for those security bugs are
developing them on the head branch and
we get access to those security fixes
that they've developed for the head
branch no one does this well that's not
completely true there are other
companies that do similar things there's
one storage vendor that announced a
couple of years ago that they were going
to try to base their storage appliance
operating system on FreeBSD head you pay
a monthly cost to do merges that's true
we do but as I said in aggregate I think
that it's it's no more than if we waited
and did this once every two years and I
think each one is actually much easier
and much more pleasant for everyone
involved and you get new bugs each month
yes that's true we do get new bugs each
month we also get new features and the
new features are really cool and guess
what if we were running the stable
branches and we did the merge once once
every two years we get new bugs then too
so but we wouldn't be getting new
features during that two year time so I
think that on the whole it's true you
get new bugs each month but it's
manageable it's at a manageable pace
they're a little bit easier to debug and
fix and it's counterbalanced by the new
features we get as well
so in conclusion running freebsd head
has been really really good for Netflix
let's just deliver very large amounts of
data throughout the internet very
efficiently while maintaining a high
degree of feature velocity we've found
freebsd had to be very stable it's
stable enough that we deploy their
commits in our network usually as I said
about five to 15 weeks after they're
committed it lets us deliver a large
amount of traffic very efficiently
and it lets us maintain our development
agenda so we're very happy
using FreeBSD and in fact running using
their head branch as the basis for our
operating systems it looks like I have
about five minutes if anyone has
questions they want to ask
[Applause]
[Music]
all right are there are there any
questions people have all right I see
one right there sat again you know how
much of the Col deze nuts portal back to
FreeBSD how much is not allowed to go
with which features for example what's
that
which features for example which
features as I said our aim is to port
back all the features except for the
ones covered under an NDA at this point
there are a few features particularly in
the tcp area which are not not yet up
streamed but we're in the process of
working through our backlog and up
streaming them as we as we can and and
we're also usually happy to share dips
if we can and so when people write us
and asked for diffs work we're happy to
share them and just we give them the
caveats of this isn't quite ready yet
any other questions why did you choose
this FreeBSD kind of Natalja instead of
relying external your can you repeat the
question was why did you choose FreeBSD
instead of Linux why why previously
instead of Linux okay originally for
what I entered I wasn't there when the
decision was made originally from what I
understand it was all based on the
license so it's based on the BSD license
versus GPL at this point we stick with
it because it has a combination of a
very positive collaborative developing
community a good set of features that
are a nice stable velocity and good
performance for us we have tested Linux
in the past several years and it did it
didn't give us as good performance as
previous state but of course we also
it's not exactly a fair comparison
because we didn't do all the engineering
work on Linux that we've done in
previous date so it's not exactly a fair
comparison but
we clearly would have to do a little bit
of engineering work to be able to switch
to Linux at this point if you wanted to
but the original as I understand that
the original reason was the license but
we're very happy with FreeBSD and I
think we get a lot of benefits from
using it at this point any other
questions yep how many developers
focuses on these in Netflix how many
developers how many in Netflix for this
topic how many developers in isn't
Netflix for this topic how many
developers work on the operating system
so my team has six or eight people
depending on how you count and there's
the team that works on the TCP protocols
and that's I think has four people on it
and there's a couple of other people
that also assist us so all told I would
say probably 16 or so so it's a nice
small manageable team one did ask which
file system of FreeBSD you use is it ufn
so ZFS we use you up best and then I
using SSDs or just hard drives we use
nvme SSD and hard drives we use them in
different systems for different reasons
we have some systems that are meant to
store large amounts of content but serve
it less efficiently and those have hard
drives in them we also have our hundred
gig appliances at the other end of that
we've 100 Gig appliances which are meant
to serve a much smaller selection of
data but serve it very fast and they
would be nvme or SSD for your
development testing a new canary
deployments what is the percentage of
your user base you deploy to for the
canary testing event yes so for the we
do several stages of testing the first
one is to about 45 caches
the next stage is to a larger number I'm
not sure exactly what it is I'm sorry
but it's yeah I'm not sure what the
number is I'm sorry it's another group
that does that at that point we've
handed it off to another group when they
do that that testing so I'm not sure I
don't know that answer I'm sorry
[Applause]