so awesome of you guys to come sit here
well there's so many interesting things
to to see here at the campus so this is
this is why we're here this is because
today we can actually move stuff for the
future and and and we we have there's
lots of things you could you could say
about what the internet is today in fact
you can say stuff like this I guess
people have know the name Tim
berners-lee this is from an interview we
gave last year where he said that
basically we have demonstrated that the
web has failed
instead of served humanity he called it
a large-scale emergent phenomenon which
is anti-human I mean for a positive guy
like Tim berners-lee that is it's it's
it's saddens to to have worse like that
but it it's it's kind of true so this
year we celebrate the 50th anniversary
of going to the moon a 50th anniversary
of the ARPANET and well just as an
interesting historical parallel the guy
on the right or the guy on the left that
he caused this this breakage in the
middle so the one guy is the guy who
made the u.s. go to space but he also
designed to v1 a fee to rocket van -
Braun there a guy designed the atomic
bomb that that basically weren't on the
eeschema and Nagasaki and I really don't
know which one is actually I forgot who
it was and it doesn't really matter
because if you create technology there
for sure yeah it can go either way but
it is something that we have to really
take care of now this brings us to the
next generation intern initiative and I
mean that is going to the moon and then
some it's it's it's huge if you compare
go to the moon 10,000 people for 10
years it's nothing to what fixing the
internet will will mean because we're
it's it's the largest and the biggest
thing that we've ever made as humans and
we have all these people on board and
they're making so much money off of it
some people and it's it's it's this is
the biggest thing that we've ever even
come across so you must be sort of an
insane madman to to want to address that
but it needs to be done because
otherwise we stuck with it for a
thousand years
and that's not a hyperbole I mean craps
takes off for a long long time so we we
started this this effort because well
the European Commission had they have
this responsibility and they have a way
of doing stuff and traditionally this
involves asking somebody to to line out
the problem and look for what the
solutions would be and by sheer
coincidence the foundation that I work
for a small foundation called an L net
which is a were the back in the day we
were the the kernel of the the first
internet in Europe in the 80s we ran
into this call and we got involved were
actually where we were asked to to do
this study and so we did a huge effort
but the big thing about this is is this
is what you would normally come up with
like a problem analysis lots of boxes
that need to be picked and the problem
is that we we saw this this isn't going
to work you if you have all these
separate topics and each of them gets a
little pile of money now solves it then
if you want to fly to the moon you
create you have a thousand people
creating rockets then you have a
thousand people working on fuel and if
the two people never talk or see each
other's requirements because they are
operating independently and have not a
single unified goal it's gonna all
collapse and this is actually the
ecosystem that we aimed them towards
saying this is the operational technical
and ethical community around the
internet so the research networks
they're ice P associations the digital
rights communities the moral guardians
of the Internet the the okhla free and
open source software people the web
standards people these are the people
you should be considering as the target
not some fluffy idea of what
mobile data analytics via the blockchain
would be but something that actually can
run on the on the real internet now
after a long long time we came up with
this this beautiful one-page document
called the NGI vision I'm sure you've
read visions before this one is
particularly beautiful but it's more
because it actually gives you a clearer
direction of where what we want to do if
we want to say that the Internet should
be something that everybody can benefit
from and anybody can innovate on then
that gives you a lot of parameters that
are different from today's Internet
because today you have to work for one
of these big companies in Silicon Valley
if you want to change certain things or
if you want to enable people to do
certain things because well the system
is doesn't actually get all the human
talent out there and it doesn't actually
follow the human values that we have
sometimes just extractive or exploitive
so I encourage to read that ngi that the
useless region and this is interesting
so I don't know how many people have you
ever read the European Commission's
websites but saying stuff like we want
open-source software we want open
hardware design we want access to data
we want standardization we want access
to testing an operational infrastructure
and we want my PR that ensures lasting
impact meaning open and we want
reusability of results so you don't want
to fund big companies that do something
internally or paths and stuff and then
and and go from there
but you want this to be in a tech
Commons and that is of course really
really interesting to see that language
from the from from such an important
actor now last year I was here as well
in the yawn zone and we gave a lightning
talk together with somebody from the
European Parliament somebody from the
European Commission and this was sort of
a first approximation this is this when
we launched the vision and and sort of
Beth attested in front of you now we
fast forward and and well what have we
done in a year now in that year actually
a lot of stuff has shifted in the
background and it's it's it's hard hard
to notice it where you're sitting over
there but this is really important
because what we've done now is there's
actually money out there that people can
that people can apply for that has the
words open source open standards open
hardware on it I myself work run the two
top the green hexagons the other were
two projects are run by other
organizations but it's actually money
you can ask for right now you can go to
to to a website fill out one page of ID
that you have give us some some context
of what you're trying to do and eight
weeks from now you could be well we just
missed the deadline because the deadline
was on Friday so now you have to wait
until April 1st for for this there could
be but it's actually tangibly real for
opportunities for people to do stuff so
like I said we run these these two
topics April 1st is the deadline and and
what we're doing is if you're sitting
your attic and you have this wonderful
idea of how to be you want to be the
next Tim berners-lee and you have a
great idea and you could be you're still
alone you don't have a mega company and
you don't have a funding scheme and you
don't have a tech support and HR
behind you so that's what we're trying
to to emulate so we give in addition to
money will actually help you with
accessibility so making sure that every
web every tool that is made is is also
usable by people with a visual
disability or other disability we make
sure that the licensing is is ok so that
when when when you're
sufferer is finished it doesn't sort of
a but these license are incompatible or
why on earth did you choose the wrong
governance model
we help people with security scans so we
scan their plans and we have real hard
security people looking at it at the
very beginning before you start and at
the very end when you've done stuff and
obviously packaging is something that no
ordinary person likes to well not to
offend people that package I package
myself a lot but it's hard work and if
you're focused on the contents of your
project then packaging is just a
something that takes your mind off
things
so we package everything for the whole
program for all the efforts in exactly
the same way so that there's a simple
way for everybody to look at these
projects and interact with them we make
sure that there's diversity management
so people don't have a an environment
that is hostile to that this community
member of that community because we want
stuff to be inclusive we help people
with localization with community
building with we have people from the
internet architecture board and the
engineer steering group to help people
solve standardization issues that they
may have so all in all this this all
these things are aimed at at supporting
people that do project and if you look
at funding schemes historical its here's
your money we'll see you in two years
Thanks and if it fails don't worry we
don't care because the the traditional
is whenever there's something that comes
out of it it's that the money has been
spent in time and and obviously this is
not where we're trying to reach we are
all intrinsically motivated to actually
get this next generation the Internet
and that's why we're aiming at
supporting the projects and the people
behind them so it's a very simple way of
doing this just want between half a page
and two pages of application will can do
in principle and and there's a stage
approach so you don't have to be perfect
you can just shoot in a crappy idea and
if it flies through yay if it doesn't
fly through you get some some tips on
how to do it the next time or to cut out
some bits and even during the process we
could actually amend stuff we are making
sure that people are consistent
because we found out that people are
always good it's seeing and solving
their own problems and their own itches
but they're not really good at solving
other people's issues so traditionally
with accessibility for instance you have
a lot of people with visual impairments
or blind people or elderly people and
then they would have a little jar of
money at the side saying well all the
project I want to deal with these people
should go there and by the way then the
the other 99.9% of the funding goes to
people who don't really look at it and
for us this is something that we do
consistently the same with localization
with security no security claim should
be done without at least somebody some
third party looking at it and all these
other things like reproducible bills
automated testing all these things are
not a given when you're just a small
project where you're asking for 5,000
euros for somebody or and and you get
time to do something cool you don't
automatically get this stuff but when
you when people help you because they've
done it before
they give you a big boost but there's
two topics privacy and Trust in housing
technologies the first one kind of
speaks for itself
everything that improves the privacy or
trusted users can ask for money so you
can ask for five thousand euros in
moonlight you can just quit your job
and-and-and-and and focus on getting a
new processor architecture out there are
fixing TLS or solving the dns creating
an alternative to DNS but because we
believe that this is a key topic and the
other alternative is how do you find
information on the internet if you're
not going to ask some known party if
you're not going to ask underwhelming
search engine or you're asking / or
Airbnb or booking com
how can we reach the information how can
people have federated or in in
peer-to-peer networks or on on the
normal internet find each other how can
they discover how can we improve
discoverability so that the information
that people have is actually visible and
openly accessible or closed accessible
in
communities we're pretty open to that
because if we're not able to get out of
the deadlock of asking the same person
always and the same persons are getting
more powerful and powerful and big and
bigger all of a sudden our brain will if
we see there's a brain then we have a
large problem of routing it's all routed
through the same neurons and those
neurons are pumping up and getting
bigger and bigger and if you want
technology to be more democratic than
solving search and discovery is
basically so how does it work you ask us
for money we give it to you every first
of every even month so again this is not
just paperwork anymore you can actually
go to to to a Nelnet Donnell / PT or NL
nettleton l / discovery and and look for
those two calls we try to walk the talk
there's also these other calls that are
out there they're done by different
groups they have different ways of
dealing with things so make sure that
you go to ng IDU and you can find a list
of all the open calls there and well
this is basically our job advertisement
you can come and work for the open
Internet and and and and you can work
from home you can work your own hours
you get paid just as well as you would
with a normal company but instead you're
claiming your spot in his in human
history so that's it I guess and I still
have 30 seconds so I can still show this
wonderful slide and ask one question
is there somebody with a question no
there isn't abundantly clear wonderful
so in that case thank you very much and
good luck with the next speaker
you