so hello everyone welcome our next
speaker
Sophia celli and all all happy name and
they're talking about no evidence
communication and implementing in
implementing a protocol of the record
protocol version 4 hello hello thank you
very much
I'm Ola and yes we as you said we're
gonna be talking about OTR version for I
think we might be winning a prize for
the longest title we are actually hear
from an NGO called centro de autonomy at
the guitar in Quito Ecuador so we have
come pretty far and we're super happy to
be here of me and my colleague Sophie ok
hello my name is Sofia and I thought I
said already the title of the
presentation I think we don't need
introduction around that but we also
wanted to talk a little bit about the
English talk a little bit why we need
the secure messaging and why is this a
problem until this day
so for these we first wanted to start
with a quote of one of the most famous
papers in cryptography by Philip rovol
way which is called the moral character
of cryptographic work and he stays most
academic cryptographer seems to think
that I feel is a fun deep and political
neutral game a set of puzzles involving
communicating parties and notional
adversaries this version of who we are
animates a feel whose work is
intellectually impressive or rapidly
produced but also quite inbred and
they're both from real work concerns it
is what cryptography should be like is
this is how we should spend the bulk of
an intellectual capital the reason why
we decided to build this quote here is
because when we are trying to design a
protocol a cryptographic algorithm a
primitive or whatever it is are actually
trying to implement it we oftentimes
forget that we are making this for
real-world users with people who are
going to use it and in sometimes the
reason why we create descriptor graphic
algorithms is because they mean the
difference between the life of or death
of our political activists or
journalists
something that Philip roll away
continues in his paper is that while the
cryptographic community have researched
a lot around all the kinds of ideas they
have a little bit not researched so much
onto the secure messaging sphere and we
think this is something that we should
start thinking in a more crucial way
because one of the reasons why people
use the Internet and use the digital
world is actually to communicate with
each other they use chat bloopers email
and those are all forms of
communications so giving users clients
that are actually not secure is
something that we shouldn't do because
actually that's what people are using
most of the times around this of course
we also wanted to talk about why we need
protocols because of course you can have
a secured shut messaging application but
if you don't stay to the user exactly
what is being used then is no use for
them because they don't know exactly
what kind of software they are being
given and we need protocols because we
need options that actually work we need
to show to the user actually what is
happening what cryptographic algorithm
is venturestein
while it's been used while I was
choosing this way we need further
specification because it's not enough to
say that we use elliptical cryptography
we use a certain algorithm we need to
state exactly how we use that elliptic
curve cryptography how we taking into
account several configurations that
elliptic curve cryptography takes into
account I don't know cofactors if she's
time Anisha side-channel attacks we need
to also state exactly how different
cryptographic algorithms interact with
each other
it's not enough to say that you use the
double ratchet algorithm in your
protocol it should be stated how the
double roger algorithm works without the
can with the other algorithms your
protocol has we also need properties
limitations and requirements of course
we need that because we need to define
to the users exactly what we are giving
them if we're going to give a protocol
that says that we are giving them an
entrance point security then of course
we should have state in what manner were
given this we are going to say to our
user that we're going to give them
deniability properties then we should
have state which kind of deniability
properties and in that word way we
should also tell them the limitations
that our protocol has a sampling node
here before we have the limitation that
we didn't use any post quantum algorithm
because actually any of them post
quantum algorithms that have been
choosing the second round of candidates
but the NIST competition has not been
actually implemented in a worldwide way
so we shouldn't strive to create a
protocol that says this has quantum
algorithm when none of the pulse quantum
algorithm does this right now can be
deployed at a worldwide scale and we
should also stay to them which
requirements do they need in order to
have the protocol we also need protocols
that update existing definition they
because big terms get to better define
sometimes in the cryptographic community
you don't have a pair a term that is
well-defined but years later you will
have it defined so you always need to
update protocols the reason that a
proptosis doesn't mean that is the best
protocol is the last word offer
protocols you just said that it matches
up with existing cryptographic
literature that exists at that point and
of course we need review some
verifications we need ideas from
different place places and we need
implementations this is all related
because we need it when we create a
protocol not to say that I created and
it should be perfect because I created
it should it should have reviews and
verifications from other parties from
different parties from the software
developers from implementers from the
cryptographers from the security experts
etcetera and we need ideas from
different places and this is something
that we try to emphasize the note here
before because it's not enough to say
that we have protocols that oftentimes
always come from the global north we
also need solutions that come from the
global South because if you give in a
software for the whole world and the
whole world also means the global South
this is something that we are so very
proud actually out here before was
mainly developed in Brasil and Equador
and yeah we need implementations because
if you are developing a protocol then of
course you needed to show that it
actually can be implemented so actually
going back to two points that I think I
really want to emphasize and the first
one is that there's this question of
specification is quite interesting I I
don't know if anyone in this room has
spent any time looking at the
specifications that underlie the
applications that are used today for
example typical example would be signal
if anyone tried to implement the signal
specification you will find that
actually exactly this is a real problem
it's actually really hard to implement
signal and as far as I know
most of the people that have tried to
implement signal ends up using one of
the existing implementations because the
specifications that are out there simply
doesn't give enough information to
specify it and another part of this is
the reason why we need the properties
and limitations and requirements really
deeply specified in the specification is
that we want it to be possible for the
academic community to review the work we
have done and if we don't specify what
properties were actually seeking to
achieve if we don't if we're not
specific enough about these things it
will be very hard for the academic
community to look at the work we've done
and tell us hey you actually do this you
actually do what you set out to do and
this is also one of the things that you
will find if you look at the security
audits and reviews of many of the
existing programs and systems out there
such a telegram such as signal and many
other that actually it's hard for the
academic community to contribute because
they can't actually look at the
specifications and see what they're
trying to do half the work that
academics have to do researchers have to
do is to look at the implementations to
see wait okay they say I don't know
forward secrecy here but actually they
mean something completely different and
at the end of the day that makes it much
much harder and the barrier to entry for
review much trickier so we forgot to say
in the introduction we should have
mentioned that we're actually like we're
leading the current team implementing
OTR version 4 as well so we're
representing the full OTR team and we're
implementing it now we've talked about a
bunch of stuff and maybe we should
actually talk a little bit about what
OTR is so OTR is a protocol that stands
for off-the-record messaging it was
created in 2004 by a team of academics
they and Goldberg Nikita Borissov and
Eric Brewer and the idea was that
basically when we're having a
conversation in the real world assuming
that there are no recording devices we
can have a conversation just me and
another person and you and I we know
that we were talking to each other and
we know that the other person said what
they said but there is no way for that
other person to go away and claim to a
third person hey Ola said this and prove
it of course they can say that I
something but they can't actually prove
it however in our current world we have
two different situations we have
situations where plain text is being
thrown around and of course plain text
means that anyone can read it so there
is no privacy in those conversations or
we have situations like with PGP where
we're signing all of our stuff in a way
that means that anyone can forward a
signature to someone else and at that
point it becomes very very hard to deny
that you said anything so the idea of
OTR is actually that we want something
that takes back this middle ground we
want conversations to be like in the
real world instead of making them more
problematic by giving more evidence that
something actually was said so
OTR gives you authenticating meaning
that we know who the other person is
that we're talking to it gives you
encryption so that we know that someone
else can't actually intercept what we're
talking about and the authentication is
done in a deniable way and we're gonna
come back to deniability in a second in
version two there was also another kind
of step forward introduced called the
socialist millionaires protocol that
allows us to actually verify that the
other person is who we think they are by
using another means instead of comparing
fingerprints now comparing fingerprints
is still possible but SP is also another
way of doing authentication now ot or
since OTR is quite old was kind of a
trailblazer and inspired many other
protocols because this idea of combining
authentication with deniability was
quite new at the point at that point in
time and we are now in a situation where
OCR version 3 has existed for roughly
eight or ten years and at that point we
decided a few years ago that version 4
needed to be created for a lot of
reasons we're going to come back to the
reasons why so basically we have three
different parts of this that I've
already talked about we have
authentication in OTR version 3 it's
using an authenticated key exchange
using a variant of something called the
Sigma protocol which is a combination of
signatures and max to be able to do this
deniability with verification I already
mentioned SNP and fingerprint comparison
and finally we have end-to-end
encryption
we're all messages are encrypted but all
messages are also authenticated in a
deniable way okay okay instead of TR in
general one to thirteen so of course
today I wanted to turn forward secrecy
which means that you should be unique is
with encryption of it message yeah which
is break break back well protection
which means that for what secrecy is
quite related to post compromised
security or what was called in the past
work well secrecy which means that even
if you compromise one of the message
keys one of the unique skis that was
used to encrypt a message you will not
be able to decrypt previous or future
messages and why is this important and
why does the academics that created OTA
decided to have it because of course for
example in PGP if you get hold of the
long term secret key then people will be
able to actually decrypt the future and
pass messages and we didn't wanted to
have 13 ogia so we did so a lot of
people decided that there will be exist
unique keys for each message and if you
get hold of one of them that you will
not be able to decrypt past future
messages this is post compromised
secrecy which I already talked about of
course and then of course we have mainly
known about OTA is mainly known about
the other thing called deniability as
soon as all as already said this is a
quite important property and what's
important to have it in a digital world
is because in real conversations you
have this property granted by default no
one can actually said that you said
anything unless you are recorded by
video and audio on most countries not on
all countries but in most countries you
will have to get you will have to accept
that you will be recorded by video about
audio if you're saying something into a
conversation but we don't have this in
the digital world because actually all
over the world when you use the internet
you always recorded some data will exist
that will link you to a certain
conversation and we don't want that so
was basically deniability in the temp
savatya
well it's a common goal for secure
messaging consider as in a web or fork
uses a license and in a specific message
just in the judge must decide whether or
not he believes that Alice actually did
so if all both can provide evidence that
Alice sent the message was just a badly
cryptographic signature of the message
on
as long term key then we said that the
action is not reputable of course it
happens in jpg because you actually
authenticate the message in anyone can
said oh this digital signature is
actually linked to your identity so
whatever you said in this is actually
you we don't want that in no Tia you
know Tia what we want is that you will
have the same identifications you have
in GPG but in a way that you can also
deny it there's different types of the
nobility and this is something we wanted
to update it in no TIA we have only an
offline message and participation
deniability message and participation
the ability are the easiest explained
because that bug actually means that you
can deny having set a message or that
you have dinner you you can deny having
participated into a conversation now
only in a Northland ability then ability
are quite interesting in the sense that
of lending abilities the classical
deniability we knew from past versions
of us here basically means that after
our conversation has happened you can
actually deny having said anything
because anyone could have forged the
transcript afterwards all natively
deniability is a new property that is
quite important in the sense that do
enter conversation someone can actually
someone can actually try to collude with
you you know that you to make someone
says something for you so for example
something that actually happens with
people might like me that come from the
global South is that you will go to a
border and patrol of the border and an
officer of the border will actually ask
you to surrender your phone and unlock
it and what they often do is that
something they open up your chat
application and start messaging with
someone else this is actually colluding
with something you have and you want to
make someone said something that they
otherwise would not say so for example
let's say that I'm an activist and that
the border is surrounding my phone and
they started to talk to other activists
that they can get information about this
other activists or make them say
something so they can get later
prosecuted so actually given on lending
ability means that during that moment
that person actually has during that
moment our proof that he actually can
deny whatever he said during that moment
not after the conversation ended okay
okay so why version 4 right as we've
mentioned already there is a bunch of
stuff in OTR version 3 and everything
we've set up until the deniability stuff
was in version 3
the biggest difference when it comes to
deniability just to make this clear is
that OTR version 3 does not have
participation deniability
and version 3 does not have online
deniability our Sofie just explained
online deniability and it's a little bit
of a strange concept it takes a while
reading through the papers to understand
what it actually means participation
deniability is a little bit easier
basically it just means that you can you
can deny that you said anything specific
but you cannot deny that you had a
conversation so if I've had an OTR
conversation with Sofie using OTR
version 3 there is digital proof that I
actually had that conversation but there
is no digital proof that can't be denied
that I said anything specific now in
some cases this can be important because
in some cases having a conversation with
a specific individual might be dangerous
or might be something that you can be
prosecuted for by itself in certain
regimes so we want all these types of
deniability
we've already talked about forward and
post compromised secrecy these are very
important properties that every single
property like if you don't have a very
specific reason to not have them every
protocol should have them this is
actually really true like forward
secrecy the last five years has become
accepted in most of the world until s
1.3 if I remember correctly actually
deprecates the key exchange modes that
are not forward secure which is great
it's a great step forward but post
compromised security and secrecy is also
an important property we want to create
a higher security level OTR version 3 is
roughly at a level of 80 bits and that's
primarily because of the DSA keys used
that use 1536 bit difficult and key as
the main key and that's simply too low
for comfort at this point so we are
racing the security level quite
significantly to 224 bits we also needed
to update some of the other
cryptographic primitives like we have
like OTR version 3 has sha-1 and
something
using classic diffie-hellman it's using
VSA all of these algorithms are not
really a great fit for 2019 we also have
this a little bit weird situation where
we really want elliptic curves because
elliptic curves are great at the same
time elliptic curves can be not so great
because there are specific okay so
assuming that quantum computers arrive
and assuming that they arrive and it
takes some time in how they progress in
terms of speed of breaking cryptographic
algorithms you can get into this weird
situation where elliptic curves will be
faster to break than diffie-hellman
classic difficult man and the reason for
this is because elliptic curve keys are
significantly smaller than classic
difficult man so assuming that the
progress of creating qubits is slow
enough we actually could be in a
situation where elliptic curves could be
broken five years before classic
diffie-hellman so we have also added for
what we call this like limited quantum
computing transcript description which
kind of helps a little bit for a few
years hopefully assuming some some of
our assumptions are correct and yeah we
also need a new communication model when
OTR was created OTR the first Club
plugin for OTR was created for a chat
client called gyeom I don't know if
anyone remembers it that was the
previous name for pigeon and in 2004
that was kind of like great there were
many protocols and you could run OTR on
top of any one of these protocols all of
these protocols had a few things in
common meaning for example all of them
were in order and in general you could
kind of be okay with everything being
online in our world right now a lot of
people use cell phones and a lot of
people come online and offline all the
time and we have transports that are not
necessarily guaranteeing in order so we
need OTR to support out of order we
needed to support offline conversations
this has some consequences offline
conversations lower some of the security
properties specifically when it comes to
online deniability it's not much but
it's slightly different and if you want
more information
it's all in the specification for that
we also have different modes which means
that for people that really want like
the only the highest secure version of
OTR there is a possibility of
implementing that specific restricted
mode that actually allows that and then
finally OTR has always been has always
been server less OTR version four will
require servers if you want offline
capability for online capability you
don't need servers but for offline of
course you need to trust a server to
some degree actually this is an
interesting situation because obviously
if you're gonna send an offline message
there has to be some kind of server to
store that message we don't really trust
these servers we using a pre key model
that is quite similar to what signal is
doing so the server is only trusted to
store these things and then give them
out when someone is asking for them so
this server is trusted to not be an
asshole and do denial of service but
except for that is not really trusted
because it can't actually do anything
else all of these messages are signed
and and there is no way to actually
attack a user using these pre key
messages okay just leave it about the
design which I will go very fast because
we don't have a lot of time so yeah we
use didn't even Ascenta cated case
change what does this mean this
basically means that you will have a way
in which you authenticate it to each one
of the parties in the conversation the
two parties in the conversation but in a
deniable way we use for these two
primitives that is called exit and exit
eh the one the first one for all line
the second one for offline of course we
use elliptic curve cryptography and we
use eg for for a Goldilocks where we
decided to use that are not done in
Spain since 2:45 one night we decided to
go good to go with my Humber's curve
because yep gave us a higher security
level the one that we needed we use also
a TV here monophysites of 3072 because
as all already said we wanted to also
have like a little bit of extra security
in case that elliptic curve cryptography
gets broken faster in with a quantum
computer we decided to use shake and
also exercise shake as the hash function
exercise encryption algorithm we
the double ratchet algorithm today I
derive the unique message keys for each
message and of course we have already
talked a little bit about this why we
don't didn't want a first quantum
algorithms of course we also have a
thing that is cool the toolkit the
toolkit is basically our toolkit that
actually proves that all of the
deniability properties are actually
happening while we don't want group shot
because we wanted to attain certain
deniability properties and right now all
of the cryptographic literature has not
really attained that inability
properties in a group chat setting so I
just want to expand on a toolkit for one
second you will find a lot of people
talking about deniability and there are
specifications out there to talk about
these properties in the abstract that's
not really good enough the idea of the
toolkit is to give you a command line
tool that will allow you to Forge
messages basically the idea here is that
we don't just say in the specification
hey it's possible to forge messages we
make it so you have a command-line tool
that will allow you to forge messages as
simply as using the tool itself so we
can actually show this is actually true
anyone can do this and by having this
toolkit we're putting it into the real
world that anyone can forge messages and
that this deniability we're talking
about it's not just academic it's real
world and anyone in this room could pick
up the tool kit and forge messages for
anyone else it's great fun okay
we have our implementation super fast of
course we do implementations that we
first you vote here before we did it in
C and of course implementing something
in C has its thoughts we also need doing
the implementation also the design of
the protocol we also collaborate it
alone with all of the cryptographers
with the angle were with me concur with
Mike Humber because we sometimes we
didn't know exactly about some
cryptographic algorithm so we needed
some kind of advice on that as I said we
implemented in C Y and C what most of
the libraries oftentimes the protocols
get implemented in C so later all the
libraries in other programming languages
can actually be implemented by having
the inspiration in C of course work
see has its problem of course you have
the memory handling so we have to be
very very careful with that we used a
lot of compiler flags a lot of address
sanitizers from the LV LLVM foundation
of course we did a static test in client
ID and we use the splint we use blood
green bar grant and various sanitizers
but something that we also try to
incorporate is the idea of the code that
has to be readable because some some
some libraries what happens is that code
is a huge a spaghetti code and we try to
create actually a code that can be
readable and that people can later use
it as inspiration to implement it in
whatever or the programming language
should we jump to the questions yes and
I'm very sorry but we run out of time so
Christian whoa sorry here yes links for
anyone that wants to look at the source
code and I think maybe we would have
time for maybe one or two questions
maybe
do we have benchmarks in terms of like a
peer-to-peer messaging political for
example well okay so first of all we do
have messages for sorry we have
benchmarks in the paper for the akes
because they're the authenticated key
exchange are kind of the most
significant part of this they're much
more costly and and how much time they
take the paper from Nick Unger that
actually establishes these has
benchmarks comparing lots of the
different existing dates in terms of
operational costs in terms of sizes we
know how big the messages are going to
be that's easy to calculate I don't have
that in my head
and in terms of the actual ratcheting
algorithm the ratcheting of each for
each message is quite inexpensive in
general I don't have numbers in my head
right now but it's quite easy to find
out and that's something that we should
definitely do of course we also have the
benchmarks of the library of the
elliptic curve that we use in by
myhumber he already has benchmark from
what I remember and one of the reasons
why you use elliptic curve cryptography
is actually because this is faster than
you say large primes devii herman so by
giving the same security level that we
wanted to attain so it's a little bit
faster for us in that way and we're out
of time
[Applause]