hey guys my name is Bill and McFaul I'm
an engineer at Red Hat I wanted the two
or three Red Hat representatives on Fido
and specifically VPP so I'm gonna talk a
little bit today about northbound
connections of VPP for containers as I
was going through the slide deck I
realized that the title has NFV in it
but I really didn't talk a whole lot
about NFB a lot of the discussions
earlier today if you're in the room
talked about alternatives to DP DK you
know a lot of X D P and E BPF but a lot
of their statements were we're not as
fast as DP DK but we're getting there so
in the context of NF e re the reason a
lot of companies do use DP k for nfe is
because it is fast and in a few use
cases need the high speed and the low
latency so even though I don't discuss a
whole lot of energy within the
discussion the context is plugging in
user space interfaces specifically DP D
K into containers and kubernetes so
luckily I looked at the agenda and saw
that before my talk there was 40 a
minute talk on legato and
Conte PPP because I would not have been
able to do justice to the project as
well as they did so I decided not to add
that to my discussion here I'm gonna
talk about userspace CNI and in
conjunction it requires another CNI
montes both of userspace CNI and
Baltasar upstream by Intel and so I've
been working a little bit on the user
space CNI portion of that and then I'm
going to talk a little bit about the
network service mesh so what is Malta
like I said it's a CNI that was pushed
open source by Intel during puke on and
I think it was around 2017 they formed
the kubernetes network plumbing group it
was a way to standardize how to add
additional interfaces into a container
so they've released the kubernetes
network custom resource definition de
facto standard 1.0 and Moltres is
basically a reference implementation of
that standard so what is Malta's mulches
is a meta plugin kubernetes basically
only wants you to have one CNI so
because it only has one interface on a
pod and so what motus does has allows
you to well notice is the one and only
CNI from kubernetes point of view and
then molten and lets you define custom
resource definitions which are basically
what other information other sea and is
that you want to use then the data
associated with them so coober
kubernetes will call into molt s and the
multiples will circle through its set of
custom resource definitions calling each
CNI and then once they're done it
returns the information they of the
default CNI back to kubernetes and then
it squirrels away and some log files
some information about the other see a
nice results that happened so because it
is outside of kubernetes kubernetes is
not aware of these additional networks
that motus adds in or these additional
interfaces kubernetes is only aware of
the default network
all right so the userspace CNI it was
also pushed upstream by Intel and Intel
and Nokia and Red Hat and now Mellanox
are working on this user space CNI the
user space CNI allows you to insert DP
TK interfaces into a container what this
allows is high speed user interfaces and
it also allows additional layer 2 layer
3 and other tunneling protocols to be
pushed up into the container instead of
limiting the container to just IP
traffic it is leveraging multi sensor
because it is doing that kubernetes is
unaware of the additional interfaces and
networks that are being added to the
container it is currently supports both
EPP and VSD PDK I'm working on the VPP
part and some of the Intel guys are
adding some of the OBS part but I
believe the VPP is more feature-rich and
so we'll be able to add a lot more
features to it going forward from the
VPP side all right so just a little bit
more information about what the user
space is doing it is very early in and
development we don't even have a nice
little logo or image and there's that
when I put my slides together everyone
else had the nice pictures and I didn't
have a logo so it is very early on what
it does when the CNI is called is it
goes in using go API and calls into well
okay sorry it calls his local beef
switch to create the interfaces locally
on your local v host for VPP uses the go
VPP portion of it that was discussed
earlier then the UVs ddk does not have
any go API so they're doing their
something using some go calls into their
OS they're OVS
see a lot but this allows you to create
either a V host user for the OVS or MMI
f4 VPP on the local v host then the C
and I will add the that interface into a
local network based off some input JSON
and currently it's just supporting some
layer two bridging so you can define the
bridge that you want to add the
interface to but going forward it would
be easy to extend that out to other
protocols as needed so once it also will
call into your ipam CLI when CNI and
then take that data can be then passed
up into the container if need be
so once the local visa which is
provisioned the data is in squirrel away
and passed up to the to the pod so the
pod can consume the interface
so a little bit on network service mesh
I have to admit going into this I do not
work on network service mish
one of my colleagues is going to present
the service master portion and he could
not attend so he left it up to me so I'm
going to do my best to describe it but
I'm not sure if I can answer a lot of
questions on it also what I'd like to
say is when service mesh network service
mesh one of the key concepts is it is
data plane agnostic it can work with
multiple data planes however probably
one of the first data planes that will
use this VPP because of all the features
that it has saw we'd like to talk to
into that context but it is data plane
agnostic
another thing about network service
mitch is he's has a strong play in run
containers and kubernetes but kou
Bernays is not required it is just it
does it will be useful going forward in
that but you can run service mesh
without kubernetes if you wanted to
service mesh is service abstraction that
allows you from a cooper names point of
view to plug a pod into a different pod
or pod into an external network much
like I was talking about with multis it
creates these networks outside of the
kubernetes default network so kubernetes
is not aware of the networking that is
spewing it one of the advantages of
network service much is it enables
heterogeneous network configurations
it'll support a large variety of
tunneling protocols and it brings light
multi Springs in multiple payload types
into a container where that the ethernet
IP MPLS or any other filling protocols
you might need for some type of in at
the application one of the most powerful
features is that it allows container app
programmers to go in and do what they do
best as far as the workload and not have
to worry about more complex networking
outside of the container so if your
workload needs to connect or it happens
to connect to a VPN or it happens to
connect to a firewall the app doesn't
have to worry about any of those about
programming it's taken care of outside
of it
so network service mesh I mentioned
earlier is a service distraction but I
mentioned again because it's a key point
of it is it it abstracts out your search
it makes you think of your network as a
service and it also because of the
upfront planning and design it the
networking payloads are not an
afterthought it is the upfront design to
feed these additional layer to MPLS
payloads into a container it plays well
with kubernetes doesn't require any
changes to kubernetes or doesn't affect
the kubernetes default network at all so
for some summary and overview so legato
well you had long discussion on it
before but it allows you to insert user
space interfaces into the default
kubernetes network I mean it'd be quite
sure after hearing the the presentation
but it's it's a large feature-rich set
mult as' and user space CNI and CNI
interfaces outside of the kubernetes
default network allows some separation
of control and data plane or your
container it's very early in development
to your question it doesn't have a lot
of the network policy or the cross pod
configuration is right now very early on
just doing plumbing of the dpk interface
into a container and network service
mesh is a service abstraction it's data
plane independent and also inserts
container networks outside the
kubernetes default network it could
leverage mulches maybe legato going
forward stuff to wait and see if it's
it's possible or needed it also early in
development I think they're trying to
get up to one point
I think they still have some work on
integrating with the data plane is where
that stands
so which dependent which is better I
guess it depends on your use case and
what you're trying to do but all these
levers the high speed and reach rich
feature sets that are in PPP so one
thing I would like to say is the call to
action is a lot of these projects do
need help they need coders if you don't
like the code you like to tell people
what to do they could use some
architects as long as you deal with the
smile and the police and we definitely
need a lot of valid use cases so that
these can be tailored for real-life
situations that was that thank you very
much I have a reference at the end oh
yeah so I mean full disclosure I'm a CNA
developer multi-cell Burr Oak open Jeff
hey how much of this could be replaced
I mean multi-screen and having multiple
interfaces is awesome but for these
users based interfaces some of them
don't even really feel like network
interfaces
so how much of this can be replaced with
like a grenade ease how much of this
fits more into the kubernetes device
plugin bottle versus the cni book so one
of the current things we're working on
with the user space CNI is making a
device plug-in so they can handle Numa
CPU pinning all the above so the
discussion is whether it's going to stay
a become a full device plug-in or
whether we're gonna have a partial
device plug-in but still use some CNI
for I think you should be a little bit
of both leaning more heavily on the
device plug-in but time will tell we're
gonna burst it we're talking through
some of that stuff right now yeah that's
the thing we we also need use cases for
because when seeing I was found started
though the ecosystem was a lot simpler
yeah and coming up with a really good
inter like coming up with a proper
boundary between device plugins in CNI
is still not it's very ad hoc and I
think best practice is about I don't
know yeah I mean the way I've always
been told is the Weisse plug-in is what
you use if you have a limited set of
resources so something that will expire
and you need to use up stuff like your
Numa and your well not necessarily your
Numa but you're getting into your CPU
pinning and how many CPUs do you have
and working to place it so but I could
see it is one of those that walks the
line and where did which was aside
should you mostly fall
I think y'all sorry I talked to you
first
[Applause]