so he was here to talk about give us an
honest introduction thank you everyone
for coming and I am very pleased to be
here so I think this is the this is the
first time that all of these talked
about at at first on so it's quite
exciting and I would like to just give
you some taster about on us and what
honest is maybe it may be a show an
icebreaker would be like how many of you
heard about almost before that's very
good so but I still hope that I can
provide some information and maybe you
can ask questions so I can also learn
from you so I'm actually a lot of
ambassador it's not a big title anything
but that just means that I'm keen on
using this technology and I'm keen on
advocating it to others as well so I'm
going to talk about is is basically just
for this and also for those who know on
us but those who don't know what honor
says and maybe just explain the
architecture briefly and the use cases
hopefully we will have a very very brief
demo one minute and maybe just a few
words about the community and how you
can join if you like active and open
source projects so honest comes from the
background basically it comes in terms
of Sdn so it's traditionally word was
such that there were many devices in the
network I mean it's still there are many
devices in the networks and quite often
these are like closed platforms they
come with their own protocols it's
provided by the bank vendor and even the
the the software that controls the
functionality very often comes from the
vendor survey it's very little
there is very little space for research
open-source developers to actually
customize these devices and these system
so they have to always comply with
whatever the vendors providing so that's
the that's the kind of the background
where as then Scott as demos is born so
there is what we call data plane which
is there's a there were a lot of talks
about how to optimize that part of the
stack but there's also the control plane
and honesty's action in that domain so
this is more concentrating on their on
the control plane itself so yeah it's
just again just summarizing there's the
forwarding Hardware functionality in the
hardware this is coming from the
hardware vendors actually I also work
for hardware vendor company so I'm
coming from that side of the software
stack and then there is a network
operating system and then there are
application on top of that platform
which you know all kinds of applications
can be implemented in a way I would
probably compare it to the Linux kernel
itself that writes was an operating
system because in many ways when you
write drivers for these forwarding
hardware's you actually write write like
a device driver in a different sense but
the philosophies kind of like the same
and then the applications would compare
to user space applications sitting on
the on the top of the Linux kernel so
this is a centralized platform and the
use case is really that in datacenters
there are so many hardware devices and
and applications that need need to be
provided that the the variety and the
matrix of these are so so complex and
there was a need to have like a
centralized platform to manage all this
so in a datacenter I just read two years
ago in a in a book that in a big data
centers that for example Google has
there are 70,000 virtual servers running
so it's it's really huge scale so honest
honest is an open network operating
system so it's very much compared to
the Linux kernel in the networking
domain so it's completely open it's
meant for networking for this use case
it's written in Java that's definitely
different to the little sterno so it's a
bit higher level language and very much
object oriented and all these things the
license is Apache it's open source it's
available on github so you can clone it
yourself to see it there are quarterly
releases so the last one happened
actually just this month the next one
will happen in April
either before exit or after I don't know
so that yeah just the ecosystem briefly
say this is this is very import this
slide is is more just to show how how
much it is used and how many industrial
collaborators that are in this are
investing into this project so it's
definitely another toy project not a
personal repo from someone says actually
backed by many many big giants in the
networking field including Cisco but you
see you see all of these I think even
Intel yeah Intel is also there so so so
so many of these companies are behind
this project there is a very active
board deciding according the service
provider use cases so so this is very
much industry driven driven so briefly
just about the architecture so this is
roughly the architecture of Ono's which
is a basically an operating system for
the networking field so there is a there
is a core which I would compare to the
Linux kernel there you have the core the
actual kernel itself then there is what
we called as the core API as the
southbound core API I would very much
compare this to the driver system in the
Linux kernel so you can write device
drivers for various devices even for one
particular device you can write multiple
drivers for different protocols
then there is what is called sitting on
on top of the distributed core is the
northbound core API and then the ABS but
I think I would just go through
explaining each of them very briefly and
why they are there so obviously the
distributed core is where the where the
abstraction is happening high
availability is happening which is very
important in network systems and
scalability performance the distributed
storage so all the kind of logical
algorithm is is happening inside that so
so that's basically the croft of the
whole thing so the distributed core also
makes sure that the scalable scalability
is good so like I said before in big
data centers like there are so many so
many network devices so it's very
important that these are just pluggable
into the network and and the operating
stay honest is is basically the still up
working so it doesn't matter how many
more devices you connect to it it will
keep working or similarly if you if you
connect servers into the system hosts
then that is also like not a limitation
in the nodes that you can scale up the
network like that so this is just an
example in this case we have various
network network devices at the bottom in
the network and at the top we have
multiple servers multiple hosts and they
are all equal so the these those are
there to provide high availability so in
this case if one if one hosting is is
running at fault that another another
hostile takeover so it's not it's not
going to be a problem for the network at
all so although all the hosts are
running the same code the same yeah the
same release basically say they have
their own internal protocol for
communicating Gowanus takeover
it's a consensus protocol so the next
thing very important in the in the
architecture is northbound interface
because this is where the actual network
services that work applications are
written on top so yeah it provides key
obstructions probably I won't go very
much into the details but I think the
main point for network operators network
or architects is that they can write
applications explaining what the
application the network service should
do as opposed to how so it's it's a way
enormous - what we call intense so it's
really the network operator can express
their intent as opposed to connect this
device to these devices devices no you
just say these n devices connect them
and almost feel a work out what the
intern how the intern should be actually
implemented so the next thing which I
worked actually personally a lot with is
the southbound core API this is where
the network drivers are written but
again it's not network drivers in terms
of the Linux kernel but in some way they
are very similar because there is a
strong abstraction so you can plug in
any device it doesn't matter whether
it's an optical device whether it's an
ethernet device whether it's running
open flow whether it's running SNMP
natkho um so it's it's possible
basically to plug in anything and here
is just a few examples of these so what
I worked on personally is open so in
fact that's how I started this whole
honest thing in fact even before almost
I was in - I was working with open
daylight because almost got only open
source in 2014 I started in 2013 and we
started with open flow and gradually we
got more requests from customers to
support not come from our devices or
SNMP p4z
is
upcoming way of programming devices
basically and you know a couple of other
examples like even like whereas the
Rascon these are very popular for
network providers so these are what they
are all implementing in different ways
sometimes these protocols are not
exactly implemented in the same way by
Wenders this is what drive writing the
driver you know knows means so then we
come to the applications so this is
probably the most interesting part of
the stack for network operators because
this is where various applications can
be written so this is just one example
where on us in the middle it can
function as a as basically as a service
in OpenStack and I haven't mentioned
this but it's it's kind of given these
days that bonus is also providing doctor
containers and doctor images so actually
there are nightly builds so even like
the very new stuff can be expanded to
these and try it out
so gnosis is providing that and in this
way in almost instance or a set of
doctor containers that owners provide
they can be plugged into the OpenStack
word and then it can function as a
service and this is this is practically
how it's done in terms of architecture
so yeah almost provides containers it
can be run in V arms in fact the demo
that I will show that is also using VM
Center and dr. container so this is not
a problem and then some more use cases
it's probably a bit too ready to show
whether I'm not trying to show this on a
verizon basis just to show that there
are so many use cases out there that can
be done with that can be used for the
almost can those can be used for so
there's an interesting project I forgot
to mention that honestly
from the open network foundation and
they are also working on a project
called court where they are basically
into all kinds of things the data
centers providing services for data
centers telecommunication offices so it
you know 5g projects and all kinds of
data center projects and because this is
actually a developer conference just to
show because buying short on time but
basically just to summarize developing
an Una's application is not very
different to basically any other way of
developing applications in other
projects you just clone the code so like
I mentioned on the bit on the first
light it's available on github you
create your application or clone an
existing one and adjust it write your
code in it's written in Java the backend
and the front-end is written in
JavaScript the build system is currently
switched to basil which is a build
system and then again you launch it you
activate the applications it's all based
on OSGi so some of you are familiar with
the Java world it's very common to
activate the activity applications
drivers on the fly without affecting the
running production instance and
obviously you tested you debug and it
release it again so I will just show how
honest looks like when it is used so
this is the one of the northbound
interfaces it's a GUI so this is
actually a network topology and yeah
this is America and this is how the GUI
looks like so you can see here like
there are multiple hosts so they're all
in charge of the whole network so if
there's a failure in one there they will
take over and this is just the green we
have a we have a console based interface
as well I personally use that the best
but it's it's it's just what I prefer
it's not really required and we have the
rest interface so one else has the rest
interface for interacting so
the applications can be written using
the rest interface and then you have the
usual swagger which is the providing the
rest API documentation so it's again
it's generic and I will try to show the
devil if it works there should be a play
button somewhere it's worth yesterday's
I used to be a boxer do you syste button
oh maybe we can just go to the slide and
played their little variant
you stopped paying
it's not laying still
something is not right
okay just played from yeah okay yeah
that's what it was meant to be yeah
okay so that's it so this is the this is
the honest good that is being
demonstrated so there are all kinds of
views in the gate so this is the intent
internship where you have your intense
listy they have ideas type and this is
this is like a simple topology view in
this case it's using optical switches
because that's the background I'm coming
from but it's not limited to optical
technology at all so yeah so you can see
there are several nodes you can see
their IDs and yeah the cable is plugged
out there
yes also there are also flows in the
systems obviously everything that goes
beyond between the elements those are
flows even for optical switches actually
the abstraction of flows I are preserved
yeah so in this case the idea was that
if you remove the past and the topology
will recalculate everything and and it
just shows that the consensus works and
and how the topology changes it's um
maybe it's a bit long so I will just go
to the next slide so the community
community again there is an Ambassador
Program in the nose that's how I got
into it as well my size it's very
accessible the community is very open
very very like very friendly we use
Garrett for code reviews and this is
just a map of contributors all over the
world there's a lot in Europe owes in
America also in the East and yeah just
quickly the takeaway is honestly
honestly is is production-ready that's
the critic it used to get in the past
but now with actual real deployment this
can be proved that it's it's
production-ready
it has a distributed core it's modular
so if you write code in one area if you
don't affect the other code its
high-performance scalable it's easy to
expand it's easy to use from CLI GUI and
rest and yeah it simplifies the network
network it's open source and it has a
great community thank you very much
[Applause]