okay so yes yeah and I don't know what
can we use this was the developer site
and which one is the and the white ones
are the designers okay yes this is yes
okay just I want to introduce the the
interaction part okay so we would have
some introductory questions just to know
the audience and you can use the short
link if you want to vote from your phone
or you can scan it with the QR code and
it's important to know from the room how
many designers there are how many
developers they are and why did you do
this and get the survey we're going to
introduce ourselves so my name is Ducati
Navarro and I'm an interaction designer
for about 10 years for an open-source
project which is extricating ok and I'm
going to ask all right so I'm human I'm
actually in like computer games mostly
right now but before that I did some
work for iOS as well that was more I was
a programmer but you know there's a
little bit of design in all programming
work so i'm berlin i am an interaction
designer and design researcher I've been
doing these for over a decade now and
I've been contributing to free software
for about 7 years now I'm young I'm also
an interaction designer mostly on the
next toad and also some other smaller
open source projects yep hi I'm Donald
Abrams past 18 months I've been I worked
in envisioned on studia doing the enemy
tools right now I'm working for the old
camel foundations Community Manager this
is going to be the hardest part okay so
I'm going to update this okay okay so we
have like 14 developers designers and
some other people which is interesting
because it's interesting being a
designer Romo we have some good
representations just shy developers that
who will vote mostly from their phones
mom okay the next question is if you
have a designer in your project
community and I would like maybe the
panel members to save they have multiple
designers in their community and if they
work for multiple communities well like
I said I'm mostly on the corporate side
kind of computer games are proprietary
so I can save much for open-source and
most of the projects open-source
projects I'm involved in
no no designers mostly because it's like
the graphics kind of things but that
aren't company basically everybody's
responsible for his like we have me my
Astros so if you're a like if you're the
sound guy you're the sound guy you do
everything that is sound related and you
have to work with other people to make
all of that work but there's no you know
person whose desire who's responsible
for the design on the UI side even we
very often have people responsible for
certain parts of the UI but it's not
always necessarily a person who is
responsible for designing all of the UI
and then a separate person responsible
for making the UI usually it's kind of
connected because we have a small team
in every single open-source project I've
contributed to I've been the only
designer yeah I would say in every
open-source project I mean I'm the only
like designer with a design education or
a design
studies background so to say but there's
a bunch of front-end people or even I
would say more and more front-end people
who are also more and more design minded
which is good to see of course or yet
developers who also get more and more
design minded added vision we definitely
had a lot of designers on staff because
but it's been interesting they're
designing for designers and they had a
lot of power there biscuit treated like
product owners to a large degree and
then at Oak Animal Foundation we very
very small so we're contracting our
design right now for the bits that we
need it and we're looking at what more
we need okay and for my case for the
past ten years I've been the only
designer too so that's why we actually
we did this community in order to not be
alone anymore and to get feedback okay
let's see what the project says okay so
this is quite a calibrated I'm curious
to see if we were ever do a panel if
this changes over time and if we have
more more designers involved okay the
next question is what communities do you
think they need designers and okay are
there small may be popular or there
they're optional we are small and I
guess twelve people what I would say is
in our company and our general ideas
that we just don't have the resources to
have a specific designer not so much
because well design is not to work
anyway um not that really but the
problem is that also creates more work
in the sense of like more overhead to
get a result whereas if you just have a
programmer doing the programming then he
just says oh I'm gonna do this and then
just does it that's very quick so we
have a very short iteration process
because of that whereas when you're
designing you have to first design you
have to think of all of the use cases
you have to then implement them and the
end result probably will be much better
but it takes longer to get there
well in my case I've worked in both
streams I contributed to the doctor
project which is Sally Knox foundation
initiative and and there was a massive
project I was still the only designer
and in that case the signer was
considered optional right I was
disposable
and but I also worked in a one-man bands
like the video and the video program
that they use here forced them to
process all the talks and and that's the
one-person project and in that case and
I felt very much valued and you know
that he was really appreciating my work
the maintainer so I think I'm not sure
sighs what it's a factor here yeah I
guess the most true answer I guess that
most people unfortunately would give us
Dee but what is the correct answer is a
so the the especially because a lot of
proprietary projects are Silicon Valley
projects or whatever are co-founded or
led by designers which unfortunately
brings us in a tight spot because we
have to compete with that basically so
yeah that's that's very important that
we look at this a not just as like oh we
have so few resources and I hope that
the jobs board of open-source design can
help with that too yes all these small
tasks or do it in small steps
Sipho more nuanced thought on this so
design is kind of an overloaded term a
lot of times the degree programs are
called visual communications for a
reason because it's another form of
communication
so really you bring a designer and once
it surpasses your average person's
ability to communicate what's happening
so if you're doing like a blockchain
startup and it's a small people those
things are very very difficult to both
communicate and understand and they're
going to be designer much earlier than
something that's more well understood by
the people you're communicating to so
again it's doesn't really the size of
the project is more about the complexity
of what you communicate because you need
an expert that knows how to whittle it
down and balance both copy and and
visual design or or interactive design
in a lot of your cases
yes yes so the results are ok medium
projects so people maybe consider that
you need to be a sizable team in order
to need someone ok
this is more like a marketing slide but
the idea is if you are looking for a
designer as an open source contributed
where would you go to look for one and
the option D is like our open source
design job board where prefer to bridge
the gap besides this and I don't know
how many had the time to to to vote to
vote but the majority say other I'm
curious what that other means but and
maybe I have some bugs in the okay so
this means just paid paid designers not
necessarily somebody that could
volunteer and do it for free ok and the
question is what kind of designer do you
need for your project and this would be
interesting to know how you vote because
there's also lack of education in the
vast areas of design and I don't know
when people looking for a designer if
they know exactly what they want and
designers expect you to have the those
are going and know exactly what you're
requesting about this I guess the the
issue is and maybe billon can or Burnett
and also can say more about this but I
guess that user researcher for example
is not gonna be really answered by
anyone or or it's not really something
that you think about because it's not
something that you see that you think
that you need whereas graphic designer
if you know we need logo or we need some
illustrations here that's obvious but
it's not obvious that you need a user
researcher or
usability engineer also very quickly
mentioned that these are roles not
people I do several of those things for
example so these are roles not much
directly to people necessarily and
another issue is that I put there the
front-end developer and a lot of
communities they expect someone to do
also do the implementation but in our
community we usually we don't do that
people said okay so there are eight
people that's so my question is since I
answered I don't know it's partly
because I'm not sure what what's the
difference between some of those roles
could you explain what's the difference
between interaction designer usability
engineer and UX designer I try and a lot
of it has to do with where in the funnel
it is and so you have people that are
trying to find out more about your users
which are your researchers all the way
and there's a different piece of the
funnel all the way down to the front-end
developer which is actually making it
real and there's different specialties
that are broken down inside I actually
don't know of any good resources on that
explain the difference between each one
and actually there's a lot of arguments
in the design community what when you're
putting out for a role what do you title
it because these things are all very
different I'm gonna be fairly brutal in
here I'm gonna say that out of all those
things a graphic designer tend to be a
different person
a front-end developer tends to be a
different person everything else is what
what did you call it
slang
they are pretty much the same thing and
but we are an industry I think that tend
to make fun make up fancy words actually
I think it's a it's a core element of
the interaction these are in discipline
so the statistics in the math part well
and actually usability engineers very
often will not testicle e significant
studies anyway so depends on the person
and said they want to do all but some
they are specialized and they I don't
know they do just accessibility or bomb
and the next question is for how long
would you need a designer and the
options are one-time periodic full-time
and issue based and this is important
when you want to contribute with
collaborate with somebody because that
person might have a limited time or if
you want them to stay like a couple of
years you may need to phone them in in
some ways
so actually for me right now actually
it'll one time but very specifically I
want to delivered with a small design
system so when they're putting other
pieces allow me to sort of remix it with
some guidelines and that enables me to
did not need necessarily need to period
the periodic I think that's super
important you have been 10 years here
next weekly I was five years senior to
project I think establishing long term
collaborations is actually key the
amount of interaction you have to get
into the project very complex long
period of time but if it's just a logo
design you cannot stay for I I'm one of
the other people so not to designer Emma
theatre director and I wanted to make a
short statement on the political task of
open source design because for me we
have four people working together from
the beginning
to people more coming from design site
and to developers and I think in in a
lot of software the mainstream people
are using what they see is very
different to what's happening on the
technical side and I think for me it's a
really really in political issue to
create design to create a design that
enlight speak about how how the
architecture is working actually because
we need to make more people aware of how
our technical stuff is happening and it
is it is like mostly a design issue and
that's like that's really a statement so
please like talk from the beginning on
get people in there and I didn't know
anything about its the vet developing
process and I had to
a lot but then we had like big
discussions and I said like no I don't
want to have hierarchical software
architecture and then there were a lot
of good ideas because we started in the
beginning and that's like I think the
political issue that's really unclear
for a lot of people that there's like an
Enlightenment that can happen so people
can understand how things are working if
it's like transparent to the
architecture No
so we have options like the design
issues list how many of you do you have
this I mean I will see when the results
are come but it's very important to to
showcase and list them in the issue
tracker is the most easiest because
every developer you are using them
constantly but if you as a digital at
the designer coming through a community
and you don't know exactly what is
needed yeah so what but it's often
missing magazine projects is a or what
is often there in projects and
open-source projects is some kind of
contribution page so how to get involved
as a developer as a translator whatever
else as a writer or something or
marketing but what is often missing is
design even if it's there it's mostly
maybe just a link or something and what
would be really good is to have it some
kind of dedicated like slash design page
for a project where you really have like
specific yeah things like like almost
everything like that like design issues
list just decision makers feedback
conduct deliverables communication
channels and yeah this is also something
that we should maybe list or review on
other projects where we say hey we we
prior a premium
prioritize projects which actually have
a page like that and allow people to be
on board or make it easier for people to
on board design because the format in
which you keep the documentation will I
think decide a lot how you can how
people can contribute right yes just
coming on the industry there's a lot of
work on design systems and being able to
sort of hand them off and I think it's
still relatively in its infancy we have
like three or four big competitors but
in terms of we don't have a standard
deliverable format I think we have a
principle behind it which is like the
Brad frost anatomic design for web and
app but that doesn't even really touch
interactive that mode that well so it's
it's it's happening but I think it's
still and its infancy so like handing it
off is applicable and we're just not
there yet
just text so the next question is that
if you think that money is a factor for
a limited contribution you know yes and
they're also tweeted that somebody said
that most designers are in composited I
deliver that country encourages
contributions and I'm just going to
update to see what you said
and it's true does anyone want to
comment about money I mean it's a this
thing in delicate topic but I wanted to
slide about it because hi my name is
Dave Crossland and I've worked for many
years on Libre fonts type yeah say well
I I'm Dave Crossland I worked for many
years on libre fonts and libre font
design typeface design is a very
specialist area of you know design
graphic design in general it depress to
be able to do it well
and often people have to invest tens of
thousands of euros in you know
profession in university courses to get
to that level and they yeah they're very
often very against the idea that they
would give away work that they worked
for months or years on full-time
nevertheless there are a lot of Libre
fonts which are out there and not only
from Google but also from other
companies where they've seen that it's
more valuable for them to make the font
available under a Libre license than to
restrict it and so I think that the
tweet is interesting that most designers
are not compensated at a general level
compared to software engineers but a lot
of designers are working in very small
studios or freelance compared to
software engineers and that if you
understand the business value
propositions of friis licensing then
potentially you can and good money doing
open design the next question yes so
this is a double session so please relax
because I have like ten more questions
okay the next question is if you think
that the university or industry in
France is the chosen format that
designers use absolutely working at
invision we definitely worked very
strongly with a lot of those programs -
seated in early the Adobe everyone as a
student license for a reason it's to get
to lock them in early and it's just a
great way to get mindshare super early
yeah I was just recently at a design
University and it was yeah it's strange
how the students are like all the hot
like oh did you hear about framer
and well I mean
envision and figma and whatever that's
already old and and and the the new
stuff is like yeah always the always the
latest things and yeah okay so you learn
a new tool like every year or whatever
and it's I mean I would say it
definitely influences it I would also
say it's a pity that that necessarily
happens yeah that there's no kind of
standard that it stays there because I
personally think that pen and paper is
still or
whiteboard or something is really
valuable tools for collaboration I'm
gonna blame the universities in here
like I'm a PhD candidate in the
dishonest school at Northumbria
University and basically what they
provide to their students he said the
view stuff I think they something needs
to change in the mindset of educators as
well but I don't know somebody design
and contributor give them a sketch file
and the developer said I cannot see that
I don't have the tools so what you're
going to do and using open formats like
SVG and exporting them it should be easy
for for everyone okay so the next
question is do you need to be a user
first in order to contribute anyone has
an opinion on this so let's see some
results okay kind of equal no so so I
have a habit wit it says that pretty
much all open-source contributor start
out as users which limit the number of
projects that the designer by big
reasonable expected to want to
contribute to I mean if let's say
designer might use the tools they might
want to contribute to game for inscape
but besides this they would need to
contribute to projects that they haven't
used before so I work a bit with both
design and development so what okay I
work with a little bit of both
okay so I work with a bit of both design
and development but so the questions
like how do designers actually pick
projects that they would like to work on
because like as a developer it's either
your skillset or like a project that
you're attached to but then you're
attached to the project they're not the
skillset like it's either of those so
how do you like this Ines go about
building their preferences maybe they
will pick a project because it has that
list of design issues or they have with
me and it will be easy for them to jump
on board otherwise I don't know maybe
money I wouldn't necessarily say that
you have to be a user first as always
good to be user but as a designer you
should have some sort of ability to step
into people's shoes which is the quality
that you should have as a designer or do
research and really find out what what
the users I do oftentimes being a user
doesn't help but is actually
counterproductive because you're you're
too much actually in your own workflows
and think too much about the way you use
the software yourself so sometimes
really helps to step a long way back I
mean I often do that also with the
project that I work on and really helps
after like one week of really not
looking at it at all then you're like oh
this is absolute and then you
change it so that really helps yeah I
think it doesn't really matter that much
if you are a user first but I think you
definitely needs to need to become a
user afterwards so once you get involved
and they start contributing you have to
understand the software and it's
important that you use it as well I just
think it's really important to balance
the needs of like a first-time early
user and a power user the people that
come in as a user first and they're sort
of optimizing their experiences are
really designing for a power user case
and requires expertise to step back and
really sit there and design for the
first time user and we we did to get to
envision we had two different cycles for
this we had internal tickets W generate
because we would use it for own stuff
and then we'd have the external ones
when we go and talk to new users or
people are using out industry and that
they're having the two cycles really
helped if you spend a lot of time
designing a project you will need to do
is ability test to see the how first
interaction is due so you cannot do it
yourself
users okay so the next question is the
designer needs to learn so I was at this
university as I said and oh okay yeah so
feel feel free to punch me but no they
they should not um I mean I dunno get
and I would say it's it's it's a good
probably but it shouldn't be and like it
starts at the level because those
students for example I showed them
guitar desktop for example which is a
non terminal interface forget but still
the design itself in the wording like
clone push and pull is totally bonkers
like it should be first of all it should
be automatic or it should be called
upload download it should be called save
or something like that it's like these
basic things you can expect from from
the developer here I'm gonna say that
developers need to learn how to use get
first we all have a ton of problems
whether it be a small merge commits like
conflict resolution like we don't know
how to do it so I beyond compare charges
100 bucks to Seattle license is because
it's hard there are a bunch of design
version control systems currently being
developed alpha code I think is one of
them there's a bunch of others it's a
different system in terms of you have
people
you used to do this visually and it's a
lot of times there's also different
version control for copies in terms of
going through approval processes and
different pieces it's a different system
than code no I don't think they should
use get unless they're expected to be
coding HTML along with you all in that
case you're gonna have to learn to use
one of the gooeys hopefully that's well
designed well I did want to say yeah of
course getting stuck the basis of
everything you have to learn it how are
you going to cooperate with no that's I
mean it depends on the format in which
you have your date it's true that if
it's more graphical if it's more like a
wiki style thing where you need to make
comments for things it just wouldn't
make sense the merge conflicts would be
horrible on the other hand so for
example get design wise it's the problem
with it is that it's very poorly
explained to people but it's actually
very easy you just have to think of a
tree of patches it's just a tree of
patches and then all of the commands
modify that tree and I don't think they
have to but they definitely shoot it is
an amazing tool and it's also because
when you're for me what happened was
that when I learned it I wasn't really
learning about gate
I wasn't even learning about version
control I was learning about design as
my design material and that was really
powerful so I think they shoot they
don't have to them at the bottom who
says that most open-source development
happens on github and it should be great
to see that platform expands to support
designs my microd my question is so many
people are here answer true designer
Jean needs to learn it I would like to
ask why designers need to learn it I
understand that they have to understand
the versioning system and but why does
it enhance the collaboration between
designer and
Roper's so it's a question for the
robbers because maybe the when we create
a project with imagery icon I come with
the different size if you can't modify
it is help to be the developer to modify
this it will be more comfortable for the
device designer to modify saying is
going to be faster if a designer does it
okay sorry I think I just I wanted to
say quick note about this and I think
that this is two questions implicitly in
two ones
one is whether we get a specific set of
technologies to do version control and
if designers should use that specific
tool and another one that is very
different and is being answered as well
is whether there should be some version
control for the over with the design so
that we can track back to changes and
relate to that as different user
experience I think that may shed some
light on on this so on the technology
side we have a law called Conway's law
that we use for domain driven design
it's basically your your system ends up
looking like your communication
structure and so the question is how are
you communicating between your designer
and developer if that if that
communication is happening with HTML and
CSS then and that that needs to get a
feature branches and so on then they
need to learn get because I was having
to collaborate and I've had that at
places I've worked since craftsy and
visions so on but if your hand off point
is further off where your front-end
developers are expected to take changes
and mock-ups and get updates and then
turn that in HTML CSS and that's your
hand off point then no they don't need
to learn it so it really depends on what
your communication substrate is and how
you design organization
this remark and it says that design is
not perceived as valuable as code and
people said 13 votes for true and 9 for
false any comments on that if not we go
to the next question
straight up comment if you have an
Oakley design people are going to tell
you about it much faster than that ugly
hack you just wrote I guess it can often
be perceived but then you use some
crappy software and you immediately
appreciate the value of good design
thank you have a bit of a side question
for the panel on this and it may have
something to do with the answers to this
question where do you believe the
ideation process fits into the software
development lifecycle and that's a
question across the board because I
think that might answer a lot of the
reason where when should we start design
and if I say like in the beginning and
then you just repeat so that would be my
answer I mean the answer by the book of
course is at the very beginning but who
does that you know like or where does
that happen in practice is the
especially in open source software
rarely or never one I worry it's this is
a different point I would say live this
specific to this to this thing for the
value ability is that for example on
github because we talked about good
before they have this like punch card
thing
this calendar of contributions and the
problem there is that they count commits
they count issue opens they can't pull
requests don't count anything else what
I do mostly is comments on issues like
design feedback they do not count this
at all so I mean I also do open issues
and I also do commit but if I wouldn't
do that I would be invisible so this is
basically I mean as github says on the
front page built for developers so
that's like the first mistake that is
made yeah this is interesting the answer
by the book is at the beginning I
actually think the ideation process it
should be happening all across because
the idea is you're gonna be learning
you're learning all the time through the
process of designing and developing so
that's your theory ng ideation that
doesn't mean that a specific stages you
might focus more on that than on
building for example or whatever but I
think it should be there all along I
think it's a very wide pipeline and a
lot of ways so I mean in the end the
first thing you have to know is
everything about your user you can what
are their goals what is this going to
achieve for them you have a person is a
product specialist who's listening to a
user researcher determine what the most
opportunity is doing a ton of math with
pas to figure out what looks like and if
your open source project and they it's a
product of passion you're like okay does
this achieve the goal better than all
the other options and that takes a lot
of time and effort energy sometimes
you'll choose a design because it's
easier to communicate and that requires
basically sketching out what the visual
design is going down to sketching and
different pieces it it's it's a
incredibly variable depending on what
product you're building what who your
users are how complex it is if you have
a marketplace versus a single you SAP
like what's going on here so it's
there's not a single standard way to
integrate design and organization but
it's definitely an important piece for
every piece to understand the value of
and again it really depends what you say
design is just from experience I can say
for me it was always from
the very beginning forever constantly
basically I always as a programmer am I
constantly designing actually the
software and that includes both like the
12% team writing computer games and my
single person projects at home that I do
it's always constantly thinking oh I
could do maybe this better or maybe I
could and then I just write down the
idea and then later on I try to you know
read through some of the things I wrote
down okay so the next question is as a
contributor have you ever failed
technically shamed by myself all the
time why did I write so stupid oh that
was me again I think that's a thing
developers do I've seen that answer you
know absolutely since so many developers
I I don't really feel shame I feel I can
say oh gee I did this wrong but I don't
really teaching his heart and like
learning is a basically getting used to
embarrassment and just moving forward
with it and having a culture that
supports basically feeling shamed and
getting better and like using that to
move forward and not make you feel like
you need to stay in your lane and hide
is a different environment and I think
it's important to design organization so
that identifying when the shame is and
then saying okay well if you're gonna
call me on this you need to teach it to
me and let's sit down and actually get
over this because we can't have this
happen over and over again because
that's that's where that's we that's
where the organization should be ashamed
it's also depends on the project so if
you're beginner designer and you might
propose something that is outrageous and
the developer might say no this is will
never be implemented or how did you not
know that this is not implementable and
can
a bit down for designer because he will
lose confidence but I don't say that we
shall we say that oh that's nice that's
beautiful
but yeah and this applies not only for
designers but also for new contributors
new contributors always check first
whether what you're gonna try to do
actually makes sense so just ask what
needs doing like if you come to a
project and you say oh I made this
complete brand new design that for your
project things going to be great
everybody's going to look at you why
[Music]
just a comment on this but as you
mentioned also the open source community
is very focused on kind of technical
elitism and you know you were recognized
by your contribution and I know that
from I wasn't for them some years ago
and there was a similar discussion with
people working on documentation and
translation that are another kind of
contribution and it's very hard to enter
a community and very hard to be
recognized if you're not too developer
basically and so I'm doing some insides
or in some way to to show that the value
that a designer someone works on
documentation can provide to a community
I think it's very important and shifting
a little bit of focus on developers in
developing and code only to something
more broad user experience is something
that just probably in my in my opinion
something that should be valued and
probably put in some way
there's just one thing I want to add to
that as a developer if you can write use
cases for me if you can like basically
make my work easier in any way that's
ridiculously appreciated you cannot
imagine the amount like it won't always
show maybe but it really usually is very
appreciated if you do any kind of work
that organizes work for me in a way so
if it makes my work more efficient more
organized more clear what the issue is
even just going over issues in the back
tracker and to asking users what you
know what's the actual problem here why
is this not working what's your system
stuff like that hugely helps okay so the
next question is should open sore
designers have an engineering background
for me I have an engineering I have a
master in software engineering and
instead of coding I decided to do
interaction design and it was helpful
because I know how to I'm gonna say no
but definitely not and I also think that
designers don't need to have an an
academic design background you know it's
sometimes you learn on the job sometimes
you know I think the academic background
is somehow crap I think it's useful if
you're trying to communicate with
engineers so if you're designing open
source tools for engineers I mean you're
gonna that's basically user research you
have most so I definitely agree with
that
academic part you don't need academics
sometimes even bad for you yeah but now
I like learning in practice on projects
is always better than five minutes
[Laughter]
I didn't want to say that yeah usually
this could have the background so that
you know whether your ideas are easier
to implement or not because if you can
come up with a great design that is just
unfeasible to implement and then it's
kind of wasted effort hello everyone
for this question and for the previous
one a question came to my mind actually
I heard always the communication between
designers and developers but why we
don't talk about analysts for example
for use case diagrams or flaws they can
be also from an engineering background
and I think that the analyst position
would be so helpful for such projects
and so my question is in general are
there also analysts for your during your
projects or you communicate directly to
the developers thank you again depends
on the size of the project if they have
it's already a big project and some of
the analysts work is done by the
interaction designers are at the place
we had the most successful product I've
ever seen we actually used to get them
out of BA so BA would do a lot of the
sales talk and the the number-crunching
and then we would transition the ones
using with humanities backgrounds into
product and design work and we had
extreme success with them they were
literally the best I've ever worked with
in my career business analyst sorry okay
next question is would you trust the
designer to make the best decision for
your project and there is a twit from
Nelson who says that the merit system in
project is based on contribution why
would you trust this new and unknown
person to start making decisions about
how the thing should work
any comments on that definitely depends
on the designer know mostly about
whether I think they are you know
seriously though I would say the design
speaks for itself always so it doesn't
matter who it is if the arguments are
there for why this design is good then
sure but it has to be merit-based it
cannot be oh I like this new material
design and I think it's the best thing
ever so I mean we're now going to switch
everything to material design that
doesn't just useless basically it's a
fashion statement I think it's kind of
ridiculous to think you can even upfront
know what the best decision is all you
can do is make an informed decision and
designers are more than capable of
making a well informed decision and I
would say especially since andreas the
person who wrote the tweet as a designer
also might be like a devil's advocate
question so I don't think he thinks that
it's correct or proper that there is a
merit system in open-source software
yeah I don't know what is actual opinion
is I think trust needs to be earned so
you're a designer you need to earn the
trust of the community and they maybe
they'll believe that George is the best
decision okay the next statement is that
everyone has an opinion design and
there's also tweet commenting that it's
really it's really hard getting buying
from project maintainer it could take
six plus months back and forth to get
the logo designed from my side I always
I also always have opinions but I always
try to hold them back if they are just
opinions so you have to always think of
the bigger project and the whole user
base not just your own use case
I think my leg of the elephant is
awesome if you guys haven't heard about
the the elephant and think it's you know
the wise men with like one person's
touching the trunk and it's like oh it's
a snake one person stop saying the
legate's oh it's the tree no other
places you can touch that very different
experience but at the end of the way
that you know what it is is by everyone
having a piece of it so if you have a
something that serves more than one kind
of user they're gonna each have a lens
into it so for example like there's lots
of stuff out there not designed for me
so I yes I everyone has an opinion but
mostly it's their lens that they have
their experience mmm I mean I would
definitely say everyone has an opinion
you design but it depends how you put
them into words and how you argue them
and how you pack them with research or
with with results or not results but
yeah research or only research
I guess user testing and stuff how it's
how they how they then end up in the
project or how you get value out of them
because anyone can say anything and yeah
it cannot be informed by anything that
makes sense but if you actually do
testing and research which unfortunately
is not often thought about then you can
actually do that okay next question is
with Alex summary but what do you think
is the greatest attribute I know is
design you should have and we're going
to share the results and comment on that
okay so communication skill
oh yeah I would have also I would have
whatever I think are always limited by
what your worst at is there any
correlation between gender and noise
participation and I have some stats
there that in UK it is that from 2014
seventy percent of design students are
female and the participation of a source
of women is three percent and also if
you look at in the room and and the
consider is in our small community there
are more many more females than three
percent is a lot I think just being kind
of honest about IT right now yeah I also
have some stats and the and like there's
been a study a couple of years ago where
they found out that a coat done by women
coat done by women is approved at a
higher rate than men unless the gender
is known and if the gender is knowledge
just goes downhill from there so and to
think that this issue is not systemic is
just to like turn a blind eye into that
so there's definitely a correlation and
we kinda know why that is also speaking
about the numbers as far as I know that
general participation in that developer
community of women is about twelve or
fourteen percent something like this so
three percent yes of course but yeah but
three percent seems lower than
[Music]
but not higher than that depending on
the community in developed like general
development not open-source is 25
percent max so that's already a big
difference but three percent is more
close to the truth lag of total open
source participants results we have to
wonder which jobs did they you know
count in those statistics
I mean we definitely have huge salary
gaps still power gaps I mean you see
different like even when they fix the
pay ratio then unless I fix the bonus
ratio or how mented you you see in
computer science especially has the most
basically you have people leaving the
field that are women and minority at a
higher pace than you're like I come in
so you actually have a survival rate
that drops that's says that there's a
reason they're leaving what that is
there's a lot of research there a lot of
it is bad environments and bad systems
making sure that when you design your
community and you open source product in
your governance to make sure that this
is comfortable and if you're like me
which is a white male American you look
go okay if I want this person you should
maybe what do they need to feel safe
valued and honestly can afford to go and
for different dissipate and those are
going to be different answers depending
on what country are talking about what
gender and what what you look like so
thank you so much for participating and
for answering it for the questions
[Applause]