my name is Chris I work for Twitter this
is a very long presentation but you know
I just show you the second half of it
because that's the interesting part so
I'm assuming everyone in the room knows
what Bayesian optimization is very good
so I don't have to explain it
yes I'm going to skip a lot of slides
here so you guys know what Twitter is
we've run on micro services and we have
a lot of them and so this talk is about
we're using draw to run our mostly and
Scala written services and with and and
by using draw we we save a lot of CPU so
what we also have is something called
I'm not sure if that will come up yeah
so we have something that's called
auto-tune it's basically a framework
that's using the evasion optimization as
a machine learning framework to tune JVM
parameters and so we can pass in to
auto-tune we say Oh tune this parameter
for me and then auto-tune talks to the
Bayesian optimization part which is wet
lap that's there's also an open-source
version of it called spearmint if ever
anyone has ever heard of it
and so then spearmint or wet lab figures
out the next the next you confuse me the
neck the next value of the parameter to
try to explore the space and then find
the optimum via the optimal
configuration so it's a driver auto tune
is to drive it to run these experiments
and people know what growl is so I skip
that you can watch this on youtube if
you want and so these are the parameters
that iTunes
there's there's one called trivial
inlining size so that's the size it's
the default it's ten if a graphic
compiler graph of an inline e is smaller
than ten nodes it just in lines it
without looking at any other data then
there's a maximum in line size so it's
the other end basically if it's bigger
than 300 doesn't inline it and then
there's something called small compared
to low level graph size it's similar to
the second one but it's just a low-level
graph
so don't worry too much about it what it
does but these three parameters are the
ones that affect in lining the most all
right so I did some previous work I have
another talk where I explain how cool
growl is and how much CPU we're saving
and so these are two slides from my
previous talk a look at blue and orange
basically so this one and down here like
just using draw instead of C to running
our our stuff we can reduce parallel GC
cycles by about 3.8 4.2 percent no
actually no yes yeah four one two and
what I did when I ran this a year ago I
think I manually tried to change the
three parameters you just saw to figure
out if we can get better performance out
of it and so what I was able to do by
sitting down an afternoon and trying
this for two three hours I could reduce
it by 1.5 percent and I did the same for
CPU time so basically by just running
raw we can reduce CPU utilization by 13%
which is a lot and saves us a lot of
money and I could squeeze out another 2%
by manually fiddling around with these
but you don't want to do this manually
for every service you want a machine
learning framework to do this for you
right so that's exactly what this is so
this is the configuration but it's a
JSON file that you pass in to Autotune
that's basically the parameter and then
you tell it the range from where to
where it should you know explore the
space you don't really have to specify
that you could i've ran experiments
after this where I just said 1 to 1000
right because it doesn't matter the the
framework will figure out what the right
parameters are I just used a range here
because I wanted it to work for the talk
but I'll probably rerun the experiments
and just set it to 1 to 1000 and let it
figure it out itself so the test setup
is I have dedicated machines there's
nothing else running on them because
crosstalk is a big issue when
when I do this performance evaluations
all instances receive the exact same
requests that's important it's not the
same number of requests it's exact same
request because a tweet could
potentially be one character 280 long
and then that would affect memory
allocation a lot and it would change the
outcome we're running with this version
of growl default tiered setup c1 and
growl so that's there's nothing we
change here so the first experiment is
the tweet service I have to experience
I'm not sure if I can show you the
second one too because of time the tweet
service is basically reading and writing
tweets it's built in on fin naval it's a
framework an open-source framework that
we developed and you can get it on
github if you want it's an extensive RPC
system for the TV am used to construct a
concurrency service blah blah blah I
have no idea what it is but the most
important part is its 92 percent written
in Scala and grog can handle scallop
very well because color allocates a lot
of temporary objects and grows in lining
and escape analysis are just better than
what c2 has and that's why we can reduce
the memory allocation rate reduced UC
cycles reduce CPU utilization and so on
ok so you have to pass in an objective
right in this case it's use of CPU time
and since the auto-tuned framework looks
for a Maxima we invert this one to find
you know the configuration that uses the
least CPU and then you can specify some
constraints in this case it's something
so we run on Aurora in mesas or the
other one in Aurora on mesas and there's
something called when you get throttled
it's basically because you're using too
much CPU then it kills you and so that's
basically our constraint we say if
because if you tuned sometimes you and I
noticed that when I was tuning it
manually that sometimes you specify some
values where the service doesn't even
come up because they're just too wild
and so we have to put in a constraint so
that we know if we win
too far so this is 24 hours of doing an
experiment an experiment what one is
only 30 minutes long it's called an
evaluation and I I picked 30 minutes
because it's long enough for the tweet
service to actually reach a steady state
and I wanted to have a lot of evaluation
so that we see how auto-tune really
works so as you can see this is just
request for a second and it's the same
fall services for the two instances and
this is use of CPU time so the
experiment this blue and the control
which doesn't change is orange and if
blue the blue line is below the orange
one that means we see an improvement and
it's above and it's worse I have the
same graph slightly different here it's
a little easier to see you know every
time when it's below it's better when
it's above it's worse and the result
when this was done looks like this it's
a web page it shows you all the
experiments and then this one's the best
one and you see the objectives is one
point zero eight three eight that means
we could improve CPU utilization by over
eight percent and these are the
parameters you remember you know I said
ten to twenty five this was by default
ten this was default 300 and this was
default 300 so if you use these
parameters then you get eight percent
less CPU and the bottom of the pay of
the table looks like this we have three
ones that violated the constraint with
one that's still in progress when I shut
down the experiment and as you can see
there are these that were worse like
this one's almost five percent worse and
like three percent worse now these these
are charts of the three parameters it's
a I'm showing them it's not perfect
because it's a three dimensional space
we're exploring because we have three
parameters and you know with the n
dimensional if you have whatever
parameters but it can give you a picture
every point in here every data point all
depends on two other parameters so you
know keep that in mind but if you squint
a little bit you can see that there's
actually a trend going up so if you
increase
trivial inlining sighs you you get a
little faster if you if you do more but
at some point that's too much and it's
coming back down and this is maximum in
lining size it's kind of flat and then
this one we do you don't really have to
squint to see what's going on so if you
and that one's by default 300s we would
be in that area and we can improve it by
that much if we you know increase that
value I didn't look at the time how much
tender have left with all the stuff in
the beginning okay so what I what I did
then to verify the result was I took the
parameters the first the top one and ran
a 24-hour experiment I also call it
experiment but basically a verification
experiment I just ran the tweet service
for 24 hours with c2 growl and then Gras
with the auto-tune parameters in red
this is again PS scavenge cycles because
tweet services using parallel GC and as
you've seen earlier in this particular
run it was 3.4 percent less GCS and with
the auto-tune parameters we could
increase that by 3.5 so in total we can
roughly reduce GC cycles for seven
percent and the funny thing here is that
we that auto-tune actually squeeze more
out of it than it did by default and the
same graph yeah it's it's it's basically
the same graph as the one before I'm
just showing this one it's allocated
bytes per tweet and it's very flat over
24 hours and you see the obviously the
exact same improvement here through your
advisor bhun for 7% roughly and this is
user CPU time as you've seen in the
beginning that's about 12% ish in that
particular run well it varies a little
bit and with autotune
we can bring that down and not a 6.2
percent which gets us to 18% less CPU we
have our own data centers we have we own
our own machines but even in the cloud
if here if you can run your business
with 18% less machines it's a lot of
money you don't have to spend and also
you know you save electricity you're
safe on cooling Bob about all that stuff
so we're actually trying to save the
world here right then
this is latency p99 latency for for
tweets and you can see it's it's
certainly growl is certainly better it's
a little hard to tell how much it really
is auto-tune looks like this it's
certainly better but you know again hard
to tell how much it is so what I did was
I was integrating over the over the GC
times of 24 hours and that's that's the
graph of that and as you can see we can
reduce p99 late and C's by 19% but just
using draw and then another 8% by using
the auto-tune parameters so 28% means
you get your tweet 20% faster and you
should tweet that
so I think I have 5 minutes left so I'll
skip this one it's basically the same
with a different service let's just go
through these so you've seen all that
blah blah blah I would say the same
thing
you 7.6% and yeah these graphs you've
seen them before looks similar the run
one point six three point five that's
interesting that just draw reduces it GC
cycles only by one point six percent but
then auto-tune gets another 3.5 out of
it yes it did it did here no here 23 398
646 I can't remember that once before
but yeah they were different scroll
Scroll scroll we've seen this GC cycles
CPU time so if that graph that a service
is also built on top of finding but
certainly not as CPU sensitive I'm not
sure what
but we could only reduce CPU by 5.5 but
just using Gras you know compared to 12
for the tweet service and without a tool
we could reduce that by 7 point 8
percent and I think the reason why this
is actually higher than just drawl it's
the same as the cheese see graph because
we can reduce GC cycles by more and that
automatically means that we don't have
to allocate memory we don't have to Chi
C it and that reduces CPU okay
30% questions yes there's one question
that everyone has correct yeah of course
I did
I couldn't come up here and not have
done that so I picked these three
they're very similar to the other ones
that Groth has its max inline level
growl doesn't have that it's the depth
of inlining that c22 us at 9 it stops so
if if you if you call more than nine
methods it's just not inlining anymore
max in line size 35 the same as T the
the Grob her ammeter basically the only
difference is growl is looking at nodes
in the compiler graph while this 35 is
byte code size there's a funny story
about this you know if you have assert
statements that actually is counted in
that 35 so it's stupid
we never fixed it but Jason
configuration kind of the same 5 to 20
you know I wanted to see we've actually
lessen lining level change it changes
things experiment that's the outcome
same graph that's a result so the best
we could do is 5% and and that's kind of
I think an outlier because we see here
three point eight hundred five three
point three I think that's more deranged
that if I would run the experiment which
I didn't do yet the verification
experiment we would see a rough three
point five percent improvement that
audit even can get out of situ nice
right so auto-tuned does a very good job
but compared to Gras it's just nothing
because this the suite service and we
had what an 18 percent improvement by
using Rob without a tune
and the most we can get here is roughly
let's say because I'm nice 4% so no it's
not no it's not because this is Scala c2
is not tuned for Scala
that's an interesting chart the max in
line level you can see it goes up so 9
is the default right so we're round here
we can certainly it should be probably
17 to be honest and then this graph
flat flat so they don't change a lot
yeah that was it my summary is always
very simple and I always just ask people
please try draw as you saw especially
when you run Scala code you should
certainly try grow it can reduce you
know the the cost of your whatever
you're doing business and I want people
to try it so that we find more bugs and
can make rather better compilers or if
you try to run your pet project or I
don't know you go to work at Monday and
put it in production that would be cool
we do it so if you get a crash that
would be nice file a bug if something
doesn't work as expected or as slower
than C - yeah file a bug if it's better
tweet about it and ask me I would love
to hear it so that was it thank you very
much
any questions yeah so did you run these
experiments only for 24 hours yes okay
because if you look at the parameter
space it would be over dream with the
parameters you showed it could be over
everyone right 3 million configurations
yeah possibly yes the problem is you
didn't see the first half of the
presentation yeah but I know of Asian
optimization is yes so if you know what
it is then you know how it works so it's
also sometimes very fragile so not
really huh okay I mean you saw yeah but
there are a lot of other things out
there like how do you batch this can you
batch it like there's a post by Facebook
where they used the same technique for
their hack compiler I guess was recently
posed okay and they didn't show that you
quite there's quite some informations
needed so I was wondering is it feasible
for everyone like besides Twitter to
like if you have a production workloads
right to try this oh absolutely
so I you I did 40 iterations yeah right
okay that's that's a very good size I'd
have to say if you look at the table the
results table you'll see that the top
you know it kind of your explored the
space enough so that you have a good
result the the goal we're not there yet
but the goal is to have this always on
for every service so that the services
are tuning themselves automatically all
the time and then you can run 30-day
experiments or something right you don't
have to tune it every day
the code is changing yes everyone is
deploying multiple times a week but it's
not that much right only once a month
it's still a hundred times more than you
would manually tune it right you only
tune it manually when someone gets upset
and then he Tunes it and then yeah I
have to sit at Twitter I got there and I
said hey when was the last time you
filmed the parameters for the tweet
service I said three years ago right
that's basically what happened so we
want this always-on and then we can run
and a thirty-day experiments and run it
for one evaluation one full of is there
any intention to make this OSHA tune
ferric open source yes there is
so the problem the wet lab vision
optimization part that probably we can't
open source because we bought that
company and you know complicated but
there's the Spearmint framework which is
open source and then auto-tune we wrote
ourselves our team so yeah we can open
source it it's just at this point it's
not very user-friendly ok I have to I
have to curl chase and files student URL
and then you know and you can only kill
all the experiments you cannot kill one
of them so it's you know it's working
progress but yeah we went to open source
it microphone so there exists about 1000
X X parameters how many can you tune at
once and how do they interact with each
other so how much time do you have right
you can do all of them if you want the
the attitude was written to tune GC
parameters that's why at the time likes
likes we or you know you can as many as
you want okay yeah it's like the space
will be a little bit bigger but yeah you
can do as many as you want yeah repping
up okay that was it ask me later thank
you