so thank you very much for being here
today and thank you the organizer for
giving me a chance to come here and
speak about our project pocket sign
laughs I'm gonna pass this device around
so you can take a look at the device
it's okay miss Adella I prepare some
know so many of the got nervous in so
many people here so my name is a harmful
thing I come I come from Vietnam I'm one
of the contributor of fourth Asia what
in for Asia for Asia is an open source
developer community that made in Asia we
try to get more Asian contributor to
various open source project and our idea
that to foster the collaboration and
create ID and application to improve
people's lives through open technology
the organization started in 2009 these
are some of the project developed my
fault Asia so cinder stuff we mostly
focus on software but why now we are
doing hardware so I want to I would tell
the story in a bit so how do I said so
every year at the fourth asia we
organize one event similar to foster to
get people together on work on projects
in 2014 there was a fourth asia event in
phnom penh that when i met this person
Praveen patel he is a business picture
form from india from a very small town
called belgium it was also his first
time travel outside of of india he came
to 4hr to talk about how to teach
student Titan in his country and he
trotted and said there is truly
challenging in term of
science subject because students ever
get a hole of a device for instance a
noxious cope the whole school only have
one in the lab they basically learn from
theory but it don't have and hang on
and they come to it and say ok see there
any solution out there that could help
the student to understand better how to
work with electronics and and as we a
community we try to foster education and
we we make the commitment to prevention
ok so we will check around to see if
somebody only doing something out there
around the world and we can collaborate
and bring this into school in India
a year later Robin came to earth and
show us something called seal applet so
the seal of that also very small device
like a mini laboratory to measure
electric way and many other functions so
Praveen Toa so is it possible to draw
moated now they have like basic function
but it's not entirely optimized for for
the Polonia so they are so they are that
if the force asia community can help to
extend the device in that time the
device is a closest device and for asia
we only want to release open-source
project
so several months of discussion from the
original syllabus there was a develop
book of in a student electric
electronic student from India working on
this project and we spend several week
to convince in there ok so if you want
the community to help and contribute you
you should open the schematics of the
device and then at one point chill in
agree that he will open the kinetic and
watch everything on github so that
people can collaborate and work on this
project and then after the device is
open that give more people eternity to
look into it then we come and this is
the first version of something that
makes form by the community based on the
sila pledge
the first person of the BS lab has the
form of the arena owner the reason why
we we chose to do it in this form
because we want to make use of the
existing case in the market so you only
view the board and get the case out
there so we produce I think about 200 of
this pockets in lab and to try to
distribute and get feedback from from
the people in 2017
we bring this divide to the CCC and some
people recommended that we should not
mouth different component on to side of
the board but gather have everything on
once I which is can't redo the cost to
20 of 25 percent so we did that in we'd
redesign the board there the second at
the second time and this time we
followed every known maker form again
with the poverty' to use the case and in
the at this time we implement loot
bluetooth and Wi-Fi module and also
enhance some of the thing that you see
on the ball on on the backhand side you
can see the description of the pin and
we also include more for more digital
pins and dry now so this is just a recap
of the development and so far of the BS
lab so it come from to see lab led and
then focus on lap halfway and then
different clients that we built from the
community-based lab that table Android
and web app and right now this is
something that we having I I think that
I forgot in the beginning what is the
new set of this device I've been talking
about it yeah okay so basically it is a
four channel oxygen or scope it's a
combination of the oscilloscope a large
logic analyzer multimeter it also come
with a power source so everything in one
device in
different instrument how you can run the
device you just need a you speak
connector to plug into your phone so we
develop an open-source Android
application that help you to that have
to control the device and it also have
the Python desktop app is it simply
enough yes thank you okay so so
basically that how it looked right now
so if you the application available on
Android and also on Android it's when
you open it you will see a different
function and in feature that you like
that you can play around with this it
the interface of the enroll app how look
like so we just got inspired by the
traditional device and have we try to
make the interface very close to the
real oscilloscope the answers power
source and multimeter a logic analyzer
wave generator and this is something
that I really like about the device even
though I don't have an electronic
background when you open an instrument
at the end there is a button that
indicate documentation so the team
actually enter a the guy how to use the
device into the application so when you
click on it it will show you what a
oscilloscopes and what you can do with
it so this is really optimized for young
student in the video who want to learn
electronics the desktop app it look a
little bit less more than the Android
only one and we also have a number of
people working on it but it's
it seemed that it is like to improve
more after interface and try now this is
the combination of all the
functionalities of the device to sample
right again because I did not explain it
clearly in the beginning another thing
that you can do with the device there's
you can see there are a lot of available
pins that you can utter that you can
insert sensor to measure data one of the
use k is that in the classroom the
student tend to measure the temperature
so this is something that we use
temperature sensor and humidity sensor
for chemistry classes and most of the
sensor that you use with the Adreno it's
also work on the base lab and if
something if you fire a sensor that's
not compatible the firmware is open so
you can actually write in pocket in by
yourself yes this is a little bit about
your software stack of the device it is
a Python library we have a desktop app
and also the end row as I mentioned
earlier all of these technologies that
you can find it on the github of course
Asia and the firmware is also available
there if you want to check it out and
this is a little bit more about the
ratification of the device and for any
oxalá scope to million sample per second
tribes or four meter with programmable
gain it also have a trial bit
programmable voltage sources sources and
[Music]
you can see their logic analyzer for
megahertz and a few other things they
also have the capability to measure
capacitance I think it's a test waveform
generators and they said a little bit
more Pacific about this particular
instrument I think and psi also has
several treble analog inputs with
function 800 meters as I mentioned
earlier and if you're interested visit
Devon the voltage and the current source
up to minus n plus 5/4 where they'd
three three different controllers now a
little bit about the production of the
device and we produces in China in
Suncheon and we also work with the
Fraunhofer Institute in Germany to
produce this device two months ago we
start the first batch and we produce
1000 of those and this which some of the
picture of what happened in China when
you when we meet the producer so I'm
gonna I did not go there but my
colleague when they unfortunately cannot
be here today treatments I speak on his
behalf
so I will share a little bit about the
lesson learn from China if you ever want
to go to sunshine and do some kind of
one of manufacturer for your for your
product so if you when you finally pair
by the elders of supplier and if you
want to produce something they always
ask you for the bone I guess everyone
has already know the views of my video
and it took us a lot of time to to
decide this document and when you have
different components that you want to to
make the device that the supplier will
give you
different supplier give a lot of
different quote so sometimes even
there's more covenant the pride
difference is really big and if you
don't speak Chinese you it's very
difficult to find out why it should make
this an enterprise and they tell us that
if you order the past from the rules or
from the truth it's also have an impact
on the price to to order and then for
instance if you plan to draw out the
product in January in in February
someone coming and because the person
who assembled the product actually do
not have the component themselves they
have to order from another supplier so
you need to do plan with them in a firm
sometimes some come on and only come
like fire Foreman lighthouse or if you
want to come in and try to wait the next
month the price could be four four five
times more expensive and then they also
recommend her to use something that
called dream manufacturer component
anyone knows what is Riemann effect
recombinant yes yes yes exactly it's so
real it's somebody order and then return
and then we reorder again I think you
know yes they call brief furbish
something before this so in China and
the producer we call it pre manufacture
yeah and then another thing that we is
fear and either Myra USP hatered is not
fit into the PCB and we have to you know
we are the only 1000 the final 1000
device but every single day why we need
to have a person there to test
everything so it's really a lot of work
if you just order online and you don't
have anyone actually live in China and
check every single thing it could be
quite costly to produce something
because you're not sure whatever
censored out of the device that could be
workable at the end and then so because
mycology there so we find out as several
female pin hitters were not so de strike
so we have to ask them to do it again
and it's also it's like a lot of efforts
and there are also BS laugh
work due to reflash a problem or some
faulty of the past so right now for the
first 1000 we test everything one by one
yeah but we learn recently there is a
altered a is a better way to test the
mass production product if you look for
bun Nihon test mass production you will
see a very good article that he
explained everything about testing so
for the next batch of a production we're
gonna follow this guy to this guy like
he out like there and we work very
closely to to the verb to the producer
somebody so they don't have the test how
do you say the test case so the
automatic test so but it depends if you
want to go to some very very
professional in my higher ed bird
because your book this boy it customized
so they need to also customize another
board for you to test the entire device
so they took a lot of time to convince
them and hopefully for the next one week
we can have the automatic test case what
is it a picture just a faulty part that
they can there yes so and a few other
thing that we learn don't always go for
the cheapest option because it's my has
some problem and but it's some component
that you think it's not so crucial to to
the function of the device the eighth
Chinese are printed the component that
you can realize instead of some
well-known component and before you go
to China please take a look at the
national holiday for instant right now
is public holiday so they're gonna have
ten days off and if you decided that you
go there that time you're not gonna be
able to meet anyone and again so
we did not learn for the extra charge of
production for instance when they sold
how do I say this
so even though you give them the view of
material already in the beginning and
everything all three upon the side of
the rim and later on today we say that
okay so because it will little bit more
complicated if you want to change a
little bit so so joining their the /
ball we decided okay so maybe this
connector we move it a little bit on the
left hand side so that we have small
space for other pins and because it's
slightly different and what we are doing
in the beginning they said that they
need to charge us extra hour for this
yeah so the best would be to have one or
two already that test and then after
after recital contract but whenever you
want to change the bomb there would be
an extra cost involved what next what
next with the Pakistan lab we actually
been distributed to school in Singapore
and India if now being a pioneer in
Denman high school and ite in Singapore
for for the student and what is missing
right now we we work together with the
teachers on a more tutorial and we also
have our developer to go out and give
workshop to show people actually how to
work with the device if you do have
there the knowledge that you are
developer and happy is it easy for you
but for the student and these are more
detailed guides and tutorials to have
them getting starting with and so the
reason why we are here today because we
hope to get feedback of you I believe
that you only have more knowledge than
me and also export interviewer while you
are here in this
therefore a hardware route so we hope
that you can check out a device and look
at the technology stack and have to give
advice for us how we can make it better
so I will call it to make this device
potable and more affordable for wider
population in Asia and everywhere so if
you have heard that we have a lot of
young student to learn electronics
everything that we do available on the
github of course Asia and the community
the main committee communication channel
of this project is on keto so if you go
to go there they're always like people
on the channel who can answer question
and another thing that we're looking for
at into right now so we need a lot of
help to improve the desktop application
the Android is working well because a
lot of young people in India and
everywhere they like to work on Android
but the desktop is a little bit slow we
have an upgrade too so we wanted to
operate the Python 3.7 a lot of outdated
dependency right now so for me I try to
install on my laptop but it took me I
think one day or so in order to make it
working a lot but it doesn't mean it
would take a one day for everyone at the
moment we do not support iOS the phone
we only have Android but it all we also
hope that we'll be able to have it on
iOS we all decided to work on this but
at one born we we realize that it's
really strictly because Apple really
tried to restrict the divider can
connect it to to their phone and at the
moment we have many people from from
Japan and also from India from Germany
because actually a lot of order in in
Germany that tested if I would did not
have so good preview the people said
that okay so it's not there's something
that not working but compared to a for
mr. 55 euro and compared to something
like 400 something it's a lot but a lot
of work so this is not the best device
but we try whatever we can
so if you make any experiment and and
you have any knowledge would we really
appreciate if you can share your videos
or document online with us and have to
conduct a workshop with Pakistan that we
distributors right now in in Germany's
if you go to the Pakistan lab talk at
all you can order anywhere in Europe and
Singapore we also have distribution
partner interferometric there's swished
client and and in China we with assist
it's a studio and how about so we are
valuable almost many major places the
board right now doesn't come with a
casing but the casing can be printed out
easily with the 3d printer or laser
cutter and beside the chromatic of the
of the casing also available online if
you if just if you just want to to make
their casing yourself and we also talked
to one partner in China to convince them
that they can bring the casing they
don't produce the ball because for a lot
of producers in China it is it already
like to chip for them so if they do it
again the same thing if I do everything
open if you want to produce you can also
do it yourself but is the price they
don't see a profit into doing this yeah
so we have a few left at there for a
sustained on K building if you're
interested to get one of those as I
mentioned already these are our
distribution channels and we're talking
with our friend in Russia Vietnam India
and China and so we also want to
distribute them in these different
places so they transfer party we have a
good network of people everywhere and
who want to support our to Reuters out
to to the market I forgot to mention if
the chip on the device a microchip with
24 and a lot of people came to our route
and said okay so this is not open the
reason the projects talked about three
years ago at that time it was the only
of
and available for us and person who
started the project only choose theirs
to work on now if we want to change it
again have to work on different
companies more tricky for us but for the
next version we hope to we talk with em
and have to be able to to use the open
chip instead it's also all they come
with the Wi-Fi and Bluetooth module but
it's not yet soda the reason why it is
not there yet some of the distributor
they do not agree to have something with
the Wi-Fi module already so if you want
it you can so do it yourself at home
okay the end of my presentation in March
there will be a gathering of Asia we
also have a lot of pieces that are
coming from Europe we have one event
similar to to post them but it happened
in Singapore March 14 to 17 will be our
tenth anniversary if you happen to be
there or if you want to come and connect
with Asian community please join us and
all the information can be found on the
Obi o'clock no I oh we are on Lynn and
github and you can easily find out
anywhere that's it and I'm sorry because
of my accident maybe it's people by
difficulty to understand me but already
try to this week as clearly I can thank
you very much
[Applause]