welcome everyone so I like I would like
to speak to you about the preservation
of numerical algorithms and first I
would like to tell you how I got into
this project like a physicist not a
software developer not a hardware
developer and in my work I use numerical
methods to solve equations of physics it
did happen a couple of times to me that
I was looking for a method to solve a
certain kind of problem it was in a
paper in a scientific journal and they
said that the code is available to
interested people the this the age the
date of these papers varied from the
1970s till now and it happened a couple
of times that I wrote an email to the
address given there or if other papers
there was no email address of course
just mail address but you can google the
name of the person you like an email
great and it bounces back over there is
a web address you go to it and it seems
that the head of that research group who
came up with the algorithm or retired or
moved to another Institute and the next
time they redesign the website the code
was gone so I will talk to you a little
why it might be important to preserve it
if there was a paper about it the
algorithm is there you would think
and numerical mathematics obviously has
a long history far longer than computers
so the mathematical most of the
mathematical background was worked out
before the computer age but how they
describe the algorithms was aimed at
hand computation so their computer was
not an electronic device it was a job
title so when you describe an algorithm
you described it to a person and the
person is of course far more
intelligence than any machine so you
don't have there are a lot of things you
don't have to care about they worked out
lots and lots of algorithms far before
the computer age so for example the
first Fourier transform was invented by
Gauss and reinvented by a number of
people even Lance was invented it before
Cooley and talkie he just did not have a
computer to actually implement and run
it methods to solve differential
equations were worked out by Euler or
Barranca and kutah in the late 19th and
early 20th century but all these
descriptions aimed at human computers
you will expect them to think you can
expect them to realize exceptional
recognized exceptional cases or if
that's it there is a case of loss of
significance you can expect them to
realize that oh I did not calculate
enough digits let's go back fix it
calculate with longer numbers computers
don't do that the computer age started
around my late 1940s and from that on
everyone has to communicate their
algorithms to humans and computers at
the same time and for machines obviously
nothing can be left to the reader the
machine will very diligently follow what
you
program if your program has mistakes or
the tonight an exceptional case what you
will get is garbage in and garbage out
so that's the reason why the if there is
a good computer program that's the most
precise description of an augury and
that's possible at least for that
machine on which T and that compiler if
it's written up computing language where
the author wrote it if there is nothing
left to the reader that that if you get
your algorithm in that form you have the
chance to run it it might solve your
problem or if you have to really
implement it for a modern machine in a
modern language the way the best way to
test if you can trust it is to run your
version run the original version and
compare the results if you come up with
enough test cases then you can be more
and more sure that it works so this
project I got into it I think I did not
tell the answer I was looking for a
certain algorithms Google did did not
find it Google did if there is someone
who is actually trying to preserve
numerical algorithms and I found that
the users of the Arkham programming
language that's mostly used for
statistics have run into the same
problem and they came up with a project
which aims to preserve numerical
algorithms and not just preserve them
but to find they're the ones that are
being used by the our interpreter come
from well and what is the original one
and if there is doubt if it's possible
to run the original one and compare the
results the initial idea for this
project came from from a bug report
that this programming language has a
built-in optimization software for
unconstrained minimization and someone
reported a bug in that code so they
could come up with a function in
multiple variables and see that this
minimizer does not converge it stores
lots and lots of steps and then find
something which is not a minimum and if
you look at the source of this code the
first couple of vines is remarks so
copyright message and that this has been
translated by F to see from a Fortran
version of some code which is not
included you start looking for it you
find many Fortran versions of the code
you want to know if the bug came from
the Fortran ver version from translating
it with f - C - C or from the later
editing's that people did to make it
more look like modern c program so in
such a case you need to find if the
original version of the code is still
available is it in a machine readable
code there is it published in the form
of a printed listing has someone retyped
it or and translated it from multiple
languages and some numerical algorithm a
very long history so somewhere first
written in Fortran might have been
translated to C by F to see them they
might have been edited manually and most
numerical methods were published in - in
one of the two oiled programming
languages either Fortran or Agua 60 in
the case of Agua 60 it was not a very
successful language from a commercial
point of view so there were
for many computers there was no compiler
available even if there was warning
available it might have been not very
efficient so people did often did the
manual translations to other languages
and every time you touch the code it's a
possible source of errors so it would be
very nice if in such cases we could
compare the results with the original
one there are very many programming
languages the first computers were
usually programmed in binary then came
some Auto codes which were made from one
machines then assemblers and the 1957
Fortran was the first programming
language that became quite widespread at
that time it was not standardized but
available for IBM machines and later on
people are wanted to enhance on previous
languages and them came up with newer
ones so Fortran was 1957 the Orgel
effort started in 1958 and that were
later versions basic which is still
popular in retrocomputing started in
1964 at that time on a university a
time-sharing
mainframe and later languages include
Pascal a prpr 1 C C++ Python so there
are so many languages with all code it's
an important questions if we can still
run them on a PC for at least four the
goal of comparing the results or for
actually using the programs or finding
bugs if they were there in the original
one and in the case of numerical
software an additional difficulty my
be that you might not even know what
computer the original program was
written for and computers before 1985 or
some even after that had quite variety
for floating-point numbers so even if
you can run the language you might have
to think about what it means by a real
number and what follows I will have a
still history and motivation a quick
look at the programming languages they
use they use in mathematics or numerical
calculations so the first one is Fortran
was originally the first compiler sent
out to many people were in 1957 and a
lot of people were skeptical of an IBM
or John Becker's first spoke about it
that he wants to come up with a
high-level language where you can
actually type your mathematical formally
and the computer will evaluate it and
understand it and it's readable for
humans not binary not Auto codes or
assembly for one specific language but
in one year in the most computing
centers who had IBM machines in a
questionnaire sent out by IBM they
answered that more than 50% of their new
code is actually written in Fortran it
did huh it was such a great help in the
development process and they also
realized that to reduce the duplicated
effort they can form users groups and
and send their sub programs or programs
to each other and some part of it was
collected by the users group into the
IBM SSP or scientific subroutine package
so this from that one it became fright
spread that people are implemented
numerical methods at different places
they sent it out to each other and users
groups and people working at computing
Center started collecting subroutines
for themselves and while people were at
the same time why people were interested
in using occurred or reusing it as often
as possible the language also developed
and it became standardized in 1966 and
ever since there has been a continued
development so the latest standard came
out last year
and why and this is one of the reasons
why a lot of computing work is still
done in this very old language that the
newer versions of the language always
include a large a very very large part
of the old one as a subset so if you
have a Fortran program from thirty years
ago it's most likely that it's still a
valid Fortran program now at least if it
was a valid program then and this may
have multiple definitions like well it
according to the standard or valid
according to a one compiler on one
machine on a present computer like this
one here you have an almost perfect stop
word so you have not just one but
multiple compilers they are very good at
the standard compliance although other
machines port from original Fortran from
the 50s than the Fortran 66 Fortran 77
they were very conservative languages
they were not a very complicated
language so some computer vendors in
that their own compiler started adding
exceptions the good thing is that G
Fortran support even some
deism like this quite unusual way of
specifying double precision real instead
of spelling out double precision and
besides an actual compiler there is also
a source to source translator available
to see so that's one way of running a
Fortran program but that's also how some
old codes got into newer projects that
someone translated it and ever since
they've been editing the secrets the
other language and in early publication
it has been probably even more often
used than Fortran was Olga was sixty it
was not a language that was invented by
one vent or like Fortran at IBM but by
by a group of experts the ideas started
from to come from the International
algorithmic language in 1958 and then
there was the August 60 report which was
an almost mathematically precise
definition of the language syntax in the
Bacchus novel form which is still used
nowadays to specify a programming
language and later there were some fixes
to ambiguities of that report so the
language has some beautiful properties
like it introduced the blocks the block
structure that makes it much easier to
avoid mistakes that that you would
easily make in Fortran and a lot of
other things which is the reason while
we still refer to some languages that we
use nowadays to belong to the org or
family on the other hand it might have
been an unfortunate decision to not to
include input output in the
standardization of the language they
were they thought that computers are
that whopping so fast and changing so
rapidly that whatever they come up with
a standard for input output would be
hardware dependent and would be quickly
outdated if you compare the input output
of Fortran and C well it's quite similar
so that might have been a bit
pessimistic about the longevity of an
idea and what was even worse that the
language was not supported by IBM which
was the great the biggest computer event
or at that time so it did not get that
widespread also in other languages that
the printed representation of the
language in a book and the Machine
representation in some binary format was
quite different so if you come up with a
printed version it might it's not enough
to type it you have to adapt it to your
compiler or your language and if you
have an old computer code even if it's
preserved in a machine readable form you
might not be able to run it as it is and
it's all often used as a kind of pseudo
code that is more ibly more aimed at
humans still we have support in Linux
which are source translators to see and
there is the name of two translators the
GNU marched and jmf all go of which you
can find on github it's been it has been
written by Yann phone cut right and also
there's an implementer called nice
mathematical software often came in the
form of subroutine libraries so the idea
of a subroutine to separate a part of
the program is quite early from the time
of the first computers there was a first
scientific paper on it written by
Goldstein and 4/9 one in 1948 and three
years after there was the first
published subroutine library in the form
of a book which concur which included
binary
which included the machine code form of
these languages and then people are
started personal collections and users
groups and so and quite shortly after
that there were formal collections like
the American Association for Computing
Machinery in their journal started
publishing an algorithm section
numerical mathematic and other journal
and so there are a couple of other
journals listed there which published
mathematical code and there were also a
number of books which not just taught
people to do numerical analysis they
also included a set of subroutines which
you were expected to be able to use
after it now these languages be
collected algorithm of the ACM they're
the first hundreds were printed in the
journal Inagua sixty later more
languages were allowed to be used like
Fortran pr1 MATLAB and so on and now we
only have the later ones in a machine
readable form and that's more or less
true for other journals so what I list
here might be interesting because that
we can use to test our tool chain if you
can still run that and later subroutine
libraries were also available in
computer readable form like the SSP from
IBM port from Bell Laboratories which
was first published in the the first
part of this library was published in a
journal actually and there was slight AK
Bible by the US National Laboratory
Physical Laboratory cm Lee by the
National Institute of Standards NSWC and
Newmar and commercial libraries so to
see how well these codes are preserved
we actually tried to test some of them I
can we used the ACM algorithm to four of
which the best route finder is the most
complicated to check if our tool chain
is actually good enough they were in a
printed representation not in some
machine representation so it definitely
needed some hand editing to get into a
computer ready ready form and the GNU
marched actually the GNU Mars it was
actually possible to run it order you
could see that when they printed
something in a journal that was not
thinking necessarily directly printed
from the computer readable form but we
have written in a human readable form
where people could easily lose a
semicolon which can result in Agua 60
and the next block completely treated as
a comment and first with every algorithm
I try to run I found a compiler bug but
later on actually it was possible to
just type one and run it what I tested
is this one to a girl is one to four
from the ACM and the numeral from the
numeral I bury I just picked out one
bigger code which evaluates the
exponential integral and then its
dependencies and again after a couple of
compiler bugs fixed by the author it did
run so with all goal
my experience is that there are all go
60 compilers in Linux however they need
they have a small user base so if you
want to run it you have you might need
to build your own Ubuntu package I did
and you
find it in my PPA there is a big
difference between the printed and the
computer representation of alga 60-some
use the recommended aisle bike not
somewhere that you just don't get a main
program and you have to write it to test
the algorithm I think now with a bit of
our back testing and the compilers
outdoors bug-fixing there is good enough
support to compare a code with your your
own implementation I will skip most
report from the experience is there much
better
there is almost perfect compiler support
what you have to do to preserve code is
to check if its standard conforming and
maybe fix it or find the compilers which
is that help you compile order code with
certain kinds of standard violations and
one of the there we did not test single
routines but who were subroutine
libraries which are available so because
Fortran was much more it still is much
more widespread in the community so
there the experiences you can find often
even and what Debian package search and
with minimal changes compare it and in
the case of Sly Tech and the port
library we managed to very quickly get
to the point where all the tests
included with the library actually run
so here preservation mostly means
keeping the source at least to yourself
or convincing authors that before they
give up on a project to publish it not
just on their homepage with the license
but completely as in the case of port a
large part is public domain that you can
find on the internet but the non public
domain parts were still given freely for
nonprofit use
however the web page is not there
anymore
and back to the the project started with
us II mean we found the code many
versions and I implemented the the test
case where the one in our failed in
Fortran with the original version and
that one worked perfectly so the
conclusion is that in this case it is
worse finding the original version of
the code and comparing because then you
can filter you can find that the bug
actually appeared in some later
development so my conclusion is that
there is a lot of legacy mathematical
code there that is still used it is
essential to save the original version
to preserve the algorithmic no knowledge
for comparison and for testing later
developments many of these codes are
very high quality so they were written
in the seventies and eighties by big US
laboratories and universities they were
made public domain for example because
there was government money included
however they are in all programming
languages like Fortran and August 16 and
the tasks to do so is to future-proof
the future prove the codes test your
tool chain especially if it's not a
really widespread language like Fortran
and save the code at least for yourself
and check if there are bugs so thank you
for your attention
[Applause]
on this it lepage sorry so the question
was where we intend to publish this
knowledge and there is a get la page
which includes not just code but it's in
our markup so you have the in the case
of our algorithms it's a a document
where you can actually run the code yes
there is one more question
yes and in this sorry so the question
was that even if we have the code and
the language is correctly implemented
what about hex in the original machines
and so in this big subroutine libraries
luckily these were actually aimed to be
a portable among at least a couple of
computers so so far we have not really
run into ugly hacks some standard
violations so it was quite surprising
that I have found one case of an ugly
hack but it was not really in the code
but what is recommended in its
documentation how you can save memory
where you use it and actually in this
test case it was used so it was a
aliasing Fortran variables and the
modern compiler does a lot of
optimization so it just reorganized the
order of stuff and immediately the tests
did not run but the bug was not in the
original code but in the test and the
documentation
no not really so the codes are
high-quality but they were written in a
way not to demand too much from the
floating-point implementation of but if
you look at the floating point in time
implementation of many at many older
computers they were much worse like IBM
computers sometimes used chopped
hexadecimal instead of rounded binary
[Applause]