okay so I'll start off by letting you
know who I am generally this is a
different audience for me but I'm hoping
that there's some things that we can
share here
so I work for tour projects I work in a
team that is currently form of two
people on monitoring the health of the
the Tor network and performing
privacy-preserving measurement of it
before tour I worked on active internet
measurement in an academic environment
but I've been volunteering with 12
projects since 2015 if you want to
contact me afterwards
it's my email address if you want to
follow me on the very verse that's my
webfinger ID so what is tour I guess
most people have heard of tour maybe
they don't know so much about it tour is
quite a few things it's a community of
people we have a paid staff of
approximately 47 the number keeps going
up with 47 last time I looked we also
have hundreds of volunteer developers
who contribute code and we also have
relay operators that help to run the Tor
network academics and lots of people
involved organizing the the community
locally we're registered in the US as a
nonprofit organization and the the two
main things that really come out of Tor
project open source software that runs
the Tor network and the network itself
which is open for anyone to use
currently there are an estimated average
2 million users per day this is
estimated and I'll I'll get to why we
don't have exact numbers most people
when they're using tor will use tor
browser this is a bundle of firefox and
a tour client set up in such a way that
it's it's easy for users to to use
safely when you are using tor browser
your traffic is
proxied through three relays so with a
VPN there is only one server in the
middle and that server can see either
side knows who you are and where you are
going so they can spy on you just as
your isp could before the first step in
setting up a tor connection is that the
client needs to know where all of those
relays are so it downloads a list of
relays from the directory server and
we're going to call that directory
server dave and i user alice talks to
dave to get a list of the relays that
are available in the second step forms a
circuit through the relays and then
connects finally to the the web server
the alice wants to talk to in this case
bob if alice later decides they want to
talk to Jane they'll form a different
path through these relays and we know a
lot about these relays because the
relays need to be public knowledge for
people to be able to use them we can
count them quite well so over time we
can see how many relays there are that
are announcing themselves and we also
have bridges which are a separate topic
but these are special purpose relays
because we have to connect to the relays
we know their IP addresses and we know
if they have ipv4 or ipv6 addresses so
as we want to get better ipv6 support in
the Tor network we can track this and
see how our network is evolving and
because we have the IP addresses we can
combine those IP addresses with geoip
databases and then that can tell us what
country those relays are in with some
degree of accuracy and recently we we've
written up a blog post about monitoring
the diversity of the Tor network the Tor
network is not very useful if all of the
relays are in the same data center we
also perform active measurement of these
relays so we really analyze these relays
because this is where
put a lot of the trust in the Tor
network it's distributed between
multiple relays but if all of the relays
are malicious the Tor network is not
very useful so we make sure that we're
monitoring this diversity and the relays
come in different sizes so we want to
know are the big relay spread out is it
just a lot of little relays that appear
to be inflating the numbers of
individual relays so when we look at
these two graphs we can see that the
number of relays in Russia okay it's
just over 250 at the moment but when we
look at the top 5 by the actual
bandwidth they're contributing to the
network they drop off and Sweden takes
their place contributing around 4
percent of their capacity so the the Tor
matrix team as I mentioned with two
people and we care about measuring and
analyzing things in the Tor network
there are three or four repetitive
contributors and then occasionally
people will come along with patches or
perform one-off analysis of our data we
use this data for lots of different use
cases one of which is detecting
censorship so if websites are blocked in
a country people may turn to tor in
order to access those websites in other
cases tor itself might be censored and
then we see a drop in tor users and then
we also see as I mentioned the bridges
earlier special-purpose relays that can
be used to circumvent censorship we
would see a rise in those users so we
can interpret the data in that way we
can detect attacks against the network
if we suddenly see a huge rise in the
number of relays then we can suspect
that okay maybe there is something
malicious going on here and we can deal
with that
we can evaluate effects on how
performance changes when we make changes
to the software so we've recently made
changes to an internal scheduler
and the idea there is to reduce
congestion of relays and from our
metrics we can say that we we have a
good idea that this is working and
probably the one of the more important
aspects is being able to take this data
and make the case for a more private and
secure Internet not just from a position
of I think we should do this I think
it's the right thing but here is the
data here are facts that you can argue
with that can't can't easily be disputed
we only handle public non sensitive data
every analysis that we do we have
reviews before we publish them so as you
might imagine the the goals of a privacy
and anonymity Network doesn't lend
itself to easy data gathering and
extensive monitoring of the the network
the research safety board if you're
interested in doing research on tor or
attempting to collect data through tor
it can offer advice on how to do that
safely often this is used by academics
that want to study tour but also the
metrics team has used it on occasion
where we want to get second opinions on
deploying new measurements and what we
try and do is follow three key
principles so data minimization source
aggregation and transparency the first
one of these is quite simple and I think
with GDP our probably is something
people need to think about more even if
you don't have an anonymity Network
having large amounts of data that you're
not you don't have an active use for is
a liability and is something to be
avoided given a data set and given an
infinite amount of time that data sets
going to get leaked the pro
ability is just increasing as you go
along so we want to make sure that we're
collecting as little detail as possible
in order to answer the questions that we
have when we collect data we want to
aggregate it as soon as as soon as we
can to make sure that sensitive data is
existing for as little time as possible
so this means usually in the Tor relays
themselves before they even report
information back to tor metrics they
will be aggregating data and then we
will aggregate the aggregates so this
can also include adding some noise
binning the values all of these things
can help to protect the individual and
then being as transparent as possible
about our processes so that our users
are not surprised when they find out
that we're doing something relay
operators are not surprised and
academics have a chance to say well
that's that's not good maybe you should
think about this so the example that I'm
going to talk about is counting unique
users so users of the Tor network would
not expect that we are storing their IP
address or anything like this they've
come to tour because they they want the
anonymity properties so the easy way the
the traditional web analytics keep a
list of all of the IP addresses count up
the uniques and then you have an idea of
the unique users and then you could do
this with combining with a Geo IP
database you can get unique users per
country and these things we can't do
this so we measure indirectly and in
2010 we produced a technical report on a
number of different ways we could do
this and it comes back to Alice talking
today so because every client needs to
have a complete view of the entire Tor
network
we know the each client will fetch the
directory approximately 10 times a day
so by measuring how many directory
fetches there are we can get an idea of
the number of
current users of the Tor network so
relays don't store IP address as a tool
they count the number of directory
requests and then those directory
requests are reported to a central
location we don't know how long an
average session is so we can't say okay
we had this many unique users but we can
say the concurrently we had this many
users on average we get to see trends
but we don't get the exact number so
here's what our graph looks like at the
moment we have the the average 2 million
concurrent tor users this peak here I
think was an attempted attack and
possibly this one as well often things
happen and we don't have full context
for them but we can see when things are
going wrong and then we can also see
when the things are back to normal
afterwards so this is in a class of
problems called the count distinct
problem and these are our methods from
2010 but since then there's been other
work in this space so one example is
hyper log log I'm not going to explain
this in detail but I'm going to give a
like a high-level overview so imagine
you have a bit field and you initialize
all of these bits to 0 you take an IP
address you take a hash of the IP
address and you look for the position of
the leftmost one so how many zeros were
there at the start of that string you
then say say there's 3 you would set the
third bit in your bit field at the end
you have a series of ones and zeros and
you can get from this to an estimate of
the the total number that there are
because every time you said a bit
there's 50% chance of that bit would be
set given a number of distinct items
that you've seen so there's there's a
very complicated proof in the paper I
don't have time to go through here but
this is one example though it actually
turns out to be fairly accurate estimate
four counting unique things this was
designed for very large datasets where
you don't have enough around to keep
everything in memory it turns out that
we we have a similar variant on this
problem in the even keeping two IP
addresses around in memory for us would
be a very large data set so we use this
to avoid storing even small data sets
private set using cardinality is another
example in this one you can look at
distributed databases and find unique
cants within those unfortunately this
currently requires far too much RAM to
actually do the computation for us to
use this but over time these methods are
evolving and they should become feasible
hopefully soon and then moving on from
just count distinct the aggregation of
counters we have counters such as how
much bandwidth has been used in the Tor
network and we want to aggregate these
but we don't want to release the
individual relay counts so we are
looking at using a method called proof
count the allows us to get the
aggregates total bandwidth used while
keeping the individual real a bandwidth
count secret and then there are similar
schemes to this rapport and Wroclaw from
Google and prio that Mozilla written a
blog post about that a similar
technologies all of the links here in
the slides which are also on the the
page on the FOSDEM schedule so don't
worry about writing these down and then
finally I am working on putting together
some guidelines for performing safe
measurement on the Internet this is
targeted primarily at academics but also
if people wanted to apply this to
analytics platforms or monitoring of
anything that has users and you want to
respect those users privacy then there
could be some techniques in here that
are applicable
okay so that's what I have if there are
any questions question
hey I have a question about how many
users have to be honest so that the
network stays secure and private or
relays okay okay so at the moment when
we're collecting statistics we can see
so we as I show the the active
measurement we know how much bandwidth a
relay can cope with and then we do some
load balancing so we have an idea of
what fraction of traffic should go to
each relay and if one relay is expecting
a certain level of traffic and it has
wildly different statistics to another
relay then we can say ok this one is
cheating there's not really any
incentive to do this other than to mess
up our data and it's it's something we
can detect quite easily but we are also
working on more robust metrics going
forwards to avoid this being a point
where it could be attacked hi thanks for
the presentation so a few days ago I
heard that like basically we should tell
matrix you know that you are between 2
million and 8 million users and you
don't really know in between like what
the real number so can you tell a bit
more about the variance or which method
is more accurate ok so the 8 million
number comes from the proof count paper
and they did a small study where they
look to unique IP addresses so it's
possible that our so they looked at
unique IP addresses over a day we look
at concurrent users so there there are
two different measurements what we can
say is that we know for certain there
are between 2 million and 25 million
unique users per day we're not sure
where in there we fall and 8 million is
a reasonable issue number but also they
measured IP addresses in some countries
use a lot of Nats so it could be more
than 8 billion it's yeah it's tricky but
we see the trends any other questions
there's one down here
your presentation actually implies that
you are able to collect more private
data than you are doing so like it says
that you the only thing preventing from
private user data to be collected is
your the team good will and good
intentions so have I get it wrong or
okay so there are so the question
exactly is that
are there any possibilities for the Tor
project team to collect some private
user data tor project does not run the
relays so we write the code but there
were individual relay operators that run
the relays and if we were to release
code that suddenly started collecting
lots of private data people would
realize and they wouldn't run that code
so there there's a step between the
development and it being deployed i I
think that it's it's possible that other
people could write that code and then
run those relays but if they started to
run enough relays that it looked
suspicious then people would ask
questions so there's a distributed trust
model with the relays and we yeah I'll
also mention at three o'clock there's a
relay operators meetup if you're
interested in running a tour relay I
don't remember the exact room but it's
on the Tor project blog any other
questions
one one more yeah okay last question so
you talk about prayer like
privacy-preserving
monitoring but also a couple of years
ago we learned that like the NSA with
the XK store program was able to monitor
relays and learn exactly which user was
was connecting to two relays to tow
relays so is there also like research on
how to make sure that like auditory user
okay I cannot be targeted I was using it
or relay and never been able to be
monitored yes there is there's lots of
research in this area one of them is
through obfuscation techniques where you
can make your traffic look like
something else so there's there's a lot
of their cool pluggable transports and
they can make your traffic look like all
sorts of things so all right thank you
so I will I'll be outside here if anyone
wants to come and ask any more questions
and I guess believe
[Applause]
[Music]