our next speaker will be like the
boulder is one of the regulars in the
organized and he's going to talk about
something I think we all breath and
that's namely profiling PHP application
so like so yeah profiling PHP
applications first can you hear me in
the back yes okay that's good so first
who if you like slow applications yeah
you can leave now we need we need chairs
is it only about faster execution time
or would we like to use less resources
or is it only as much request as we can
get and usually what happens is we start
profiling when we see this so everything
is on fire your client is on the phone
yeah my site is down and everything is
slow and it breaks and yeah what what's
going on you don't know you have no clue
so that's why we are going to profile
our application but first hi I'm Mike he
said it already so short introduction
I'm on Twitter you can send me things on
Twitter whatever I do some development a
little bit of operations at Studio Emma
we do Magento and pimp core if you want
to know something about it find me
afterwards that's it so first profiling
profiling is the process where we find
the runtime characteristics and measure
the performance and I'll do the
performance analysis for optimization of
our application
is that clear so what information do we
get from this profile where is something
happening where is something slow where
is something using a lot of memory such
things what is well we want to know what
is causing this but what is using it
that's the first thing we know we also
learn how much that's already a very
interesting part of it but then you have
that question why my application is fast
yeah you see if I click it it's fast
yeah but do you have substantial
information to confirm that your
application is fast and what is fast for
you so define fast is 2 seconds fast for
you then yeah okay fine don't profile
but can you handle a burst of traffic so
your marketing department has a has a
great idea and they don't tell you they
will send a great marketing campaign and
then it happens bomb everything down and
then you ask around yeah did somebody do
something oh yeah we sent their mail to
all our customers yeah thanks
so yeah optimizing your application has
benefits in all areas you can imagine
there you get this guy I don't need a
profiler and know what slow are you sure
you're kind of shooting in the dark if
you are yeah you probably can make an
educated guess where something is slow
but if you don't have the numbers for it
it's still a guess so the points of
interest we are going to look at while
we are profiling our execution time so
this is the overall thing we get a
response in two seconds or maybe we like
one second better but we also get the
CPU time spent on your application and
the memory usage also interesting to
have is how much disk IO does my
application cause because this could
really help you if you get a burst or
something what we also have is network
time do we lose a lot of time asking
using external api's or same same with
external delays like is the response
from your database slow or did you just
kill your Redis in some magic way that
is suddenly super slow or other
databases you are trying to use
so now how can we profile our
application with PHP who would do it
with PHP just something in PHP magically
and we'll get something no one yeah
maybe not so you can get some
information you get the time and if you
do requests you can even get it from
your server server superglobal but yeah
you get actually nothing because you've
got it you get it already from another
[Music]
another way so first XD back who knows
you who of you knows that you can
profile with XD back oh that's already
quite a lot so exci burke is an
extension you know it's for PHP usually
we use it for debugging but it also
provides us with profiling it needs a
little bit of configuration to let me to
to make it allow you to profile and you
need an external tool to analyze what it
creates so it creates a cache client
file and then you can visualize it with
some external tool so what I usually use
is enable the profiler write it
somewhere and cache grind out percentage
you that's just a timestamp you could be
smarter about this and get more
information you can find it in a
documentation of exit back and one once
you get those cache client files you can
open it in a tool like Q cache grind or
gate crash grind or whatever blah blah
blah cache grind to there is I think
there is a web-based one also then you
get some information but it's not super
easy to to understand what's going on
you can get some visualization but yeah
there is not really something showing up
as being very slow and there is one
larger drawback with these tools that
they have a maximum there is a limit on
the number of function calls it will
show you so usually you can get it up to
500 function calls but this comes from
Magento this is a very complex PHP
application which has a lot more than
500 function calls so you will probably
not see all the information you want
probably what you need but it's not very
easy so it's hard also exit back is not
really a profiler but it's a debugger
with profiling capabilities so it also
introduces kind of a large overhead it
became better with newer versions but
still it might the result might be a bit
off then I guess the people who knew
exit back also knew XH broth but maybe
there are other people's will also know
that XH broth is out there so XH broth
well these days with PHP 7 we don't no
longer use it as XS proof itself but it
continued in the Tideway is PHP
extension there is another another
open-source extension that has a similar
capabilities but personally I used the
Tideway extension it's also some a
little bit of configuration needed and
you use well in my personal preference X
hu e which is an external tool to
visualize the profiles
so it's very simple the only thing
that's really important here is that you
do the tight waist o to prevent library
on 0 because that's for the tight waist
sauce platform you also include some
prepend where you actually initialize
your profiling and it's not all there
but eventually if you get in the
shutdown function you collect your
information that it gathers from your
application and write it somewhere so
that was the wrong way so then you have
X hu e which is empty in this in the
beginning and once what I also forgot
with XZ Burke is that everything you do
with PHP is profile so you do not have
to do something extra to have a command
line script profile because if it's on
its own if you do command line if you do
request whatever you enable it it's
always on that's for me it's very
interesting so then you get some runs in
it you get an overview and in the
details you already get some information
this slide contains something that might
be interesting because it already has an
indication of a problem so at the end of
representation if I didn't go go deeper
into composer autoload include file ask
me about it
what's the problem
you get your function information annual
so can get a call graph which might be
overwhelming but it's very interesting
so the for me the important thing here
is that it's still a local set up so I
don't need to act any external services
and it profiles everything doesn't look
too fancy but it has most well all the
features you want to to get some some
information out of it
you also have tied weights itself which
is an sas that you can also configure so
it's also they're the same thing you get
an extension you configure it
it needs daemon on your PHP application
to send the information to the platform
the the interesting thing with tight
ways is that it has a 30-day trial that
it offers you all its features so you
really can evaluate what it can do it
looks rather nice it also has a p.m.
functionality that is out of the scope
of this presentation and if you want to
profile something you use an extension
and so it the profiling is on the amount
of you you say I encountered some sort
of problem on this page I now want to
get a profile out of it so you say proof
take take profile and then title is will
will reload this page and give you a
profile in their dashboard gives you
some information about function calls
when what happens and so on and so on so
it's more than a profiler it's fairly
easy to use but yeah it's trial to
paying this really depends on if you
already have have an AP
in place and you only need to profile
locally or you really new into this and
you can benefit from a platform that has
everything so that's the kind of a
choice you have to make and then we also
have black fire which is very similar
and set up to Tideway so it's again the
same it's an extension it's similar it
uses a demon to give to get the
communication done between your
application and their platform the
biggest drawback for me is that it's a
freemium model where they're free
features are not really useful to
evaluate what the power of the platform
is so you actually should start with the
paying version where you see everything
and then decide if you want to continue
with it
so it's exactly the same practically
like with tide ways you click a button
and then it profiles a page don't you
get some information I only have
screenshots from the free version so
it's very easy to use but the drawback
is in the freemium you only have the
wall time and a memory usage if you want
the CPU time if you want see IO if you
want to see Network if you want to see
all the other things you really need to
start paying from day one that's what
you choose so that's for me the biggest
drawback it does not not offer you all
the features to evaluate if you want to
continue with this platform my biggest
suggestion here is pick one and learn it
once you learn the one you have picked
you're probably will encounter things
you don't like about it so you don't
find your way properly in it or it
doesn't offer sufficient information on
something specific you would like to
know and maybe another pot platform
offers it
then it's time to start looking around
for start shopping for you could say but
first you should dive into one to really
know its quirks and how it's gonna
behave on your applications that it's
especially interesting if you already
have in-depth knowledge about your
application you will quickly learn what
is missing in the profile or that you
are using to summarize the the tools
it's like eggsy berg xh probe our local
set up sideways and black fire our SAS
solutions so if you really like the
solutions go for one if you want to keep
it local use XD back or exit probe but
now we still need some idea how we are
going to approach the profiling itself
so what are we going to look for what
are we looking for
first we look for slow things for
example yeah for example the contact
page on a Magento website if you
configure it default it's probably the
slowest page on your site weird isn't it
also what you really want to optimize
for is popular things so if you're an
e-commerce probably your catalog pages
will be hit a lot more than product page
so if you really want to profile to gain
well to be more future-proof you are
going to watch at a popular thing so you
can preemptively optimize them before
someone trashes your site
and application initialization that's
the one we saw at the the earlier slide
where composer autoload include file is
really slow if there is only one
takeaway from this presentation remember
if you see this composer at Lloyds
include file that is really slow just
think op cache memory is too too small
this is not obvious but yeah we search
for it a few hours to find out that
actually what happened was oh composer
wants to add a new a new class so it
includes the file but the op cache
memory is too small so yeah the one that
was already in well many others were in
but the oldest ones were pushed out but
they were used again a little bit later
so it continuously accesses the disk to
get the information instead of its class
definitions coming from up cache this
was a not obvious issue
so and then you go and analyze a profile
first follow the hotspot so usually it's
marked as the more red the slower it is
so usually if you see the red fading
away that's kind of the the point you're
going to start watch and yeah what's
happening here does it do a lot of my
sequel calls or does it so does this
method something really weird like I saw
an example where I don't remember where
I saw it but it was another presentation
where I was like yeah we have an HTTP
client and it does something really
weird and far far away it did something
like I calculate pi to 20,000 numbers
behind the comma yeah if you want it if
you want to do that but yeah that's
weird so it can be weird code so fix
that try again if it's better you're
good so now a little demo from something
we did in real life first I'm going to
start with a more simplified example
is this readable or do I have to zoom it
a bit better zoom yeah oh it's good yeah
so there is some background to it yeah
that's the one so the story here is we
had to create a application where they
said well we're not gonna use euros
we're gonna let our users by some sort
of coins and not not crypto just you
give 60 euros and get one thingy and our
products will all be based on yeah let's
say we take a base value of 60 euros and
everything will be based on that so
usually something we will sell will be
one two or three coins
yeah okay so something was built and it
was like yeah someone wants to buy coins
so we started with yeah the coin value
it's like let's take 100 euros and yeah
we want to be generous and we're gonna
give them to other people so we'll buy
ten
oh that's too fast yeah sorry so no we
want to buy in euros so we want to be
generous so we want to have ten coins to
distribute to other people and that's
pretty okay
so initially if we're going to look at
this so we get here one run and it takes
one second so we get into details keep
in mind this is a very oversimplified
example to show you an easy part into
profile
so what I usually do is yeah I go into
call graph and then it's always too big
and now there is just a cheat in it
where the sleep is now taking most of
the time so it's this is the reference
it takes one second
so our codes we are using is okay at
some point in time there was another
department in that company that said no
we're not gonna do that but the whole
idea of their website was based on the
coins so then they said yeah let's
change that we're gonna use coins of one
year oh and go wild so yeah with a
thousand it's probably okay it's not
really that much doesn't really matter
and then they said yeah but we have a
lot of our own personnel and we want to
give them a budget of 2,000 years or
something for courses on our own
platform so I'm going to buy for 100,000
euros and then distribute him across the
company that's when we started to see
weird things because the platform was
completely not built to have 100,000
coins ordered at once
so it's becoming slow so we know the
reference is one second now we're at 13
seconds to get the ID we started looking
at things in the profile the zoom is
working against me yeah that that didn't
go well yeah that's better
so what we come to see here is we follow
the hot spot and yeah it's probably too
small now so we follow the hot part and
instead of crawling I want you to zoom
thank you yes and it's like yeah store
coins what the hell is this thing doing
it takes 10 seconds probably should make
it better
so if we look at it it's based on an
actual it did happen so demo service
coin service yeah this is actually very
readable so what happened is there was
the ID of yeah we go to the slow one so
we store things and what happened is
yeah just at one coin and the table
contains one coin and per row so we
start to insert 100,000 coins and go
wild in a for each and then do other
stupid things like try to check how many
unspent coins there are so the
combination of these two is really
disastrous so because we didn't
originally create our system to support
really small values it escalated quickly
and here you can see you can easily
follow this paths to find out where
things go wrong and start refactoring
here because we do not actually want to
insert 100,000 rows we want to we don't
really want to do 100,000 queries we
really want to do one query to get all
these things in and it will be a lot
faster so but this is a very obvious
example but we'll get to others later
first we have some popular bottlenecks
so I already said that slow coat really
weird algorithms or spending too much
time on things you don't really want to
spend on that sequel queries what you
also get is in the beginning your site
might be very fast without indexes on
your sequel on your tables eventually
you might see slow down
so use your indexes but don't overuse
them because that might bring you to
other problems what we also see a lot is
disk i/o usually triggering your
application to be slow and usually it's
a combination of something externally is
doing too much disk i/o on your server
your PHP wants to do a lot of disk i/o
and suddenly things go bad so what could
happen is certainly a backup kicks in
and reads a lot of files without Io
limiting or whatever and it causes your
application to go slow
what we also already saw is usually we
have an application and it has a cron
somewhere and the chrome goes wild
because yeah someone did not tell you
they were going to do some marketing
campaign or update everything at once
and once you see swapping because you
have memory issues on your server you
have to think of you have to think about
other problems other things too also
if you want to be fast you need to keep
in mind that not everyone wants to be
fast so what we also encountered in the
past was like yeah we have we have an
API yeah do do whatever what you want
with it but they found it acceptable
they found it acceptable to have a
response time of one second
but if you want to go fast yeah you have
to do something about it and then it
happens everything goes down and it
breaks and there they are the angry
customers so the first thing you have to
do is don't panic if your site goes down
just relax it's not gonna kill not gonna
get any better if you're panicking too
so first just throw in more CPUs if it's
needed throw in more RAM and then see to
block probably some mouses actors so you
probably find some bad BOTS list and
block them and when things start to
normalize then try to find out what
happened and try to find out how you're
gonna improve it then find the slow
parts start profiling and get on with it
so for your production environment it
might be interesting for everyone to
have your monitoring have an application
performance monitoring on it what I find
personally very interesting is to have a
top on it I don't know how many people
know a top yeah but if you have it on
your server you can
when everything is back to normal you
can replicate what happened see when it
started to explode and get some really
useful information to avoid these kind
of issues in the future and if you
really need to you can go and s trace
things if you really want to go deep so
I have one other demo where it's not
exactly obvious that something is slow
this will be there so this is Magento if
there are no there are no products in it
so it's yeah it's empty but doesn't
matter it's gonna show up that something
is slow I already said it it's the the
contact page so if we go to contact it's
gonna be around 1 point something or 2
seconds and if you go look at it
we see like the default was 380
milliseconds and the contact page did
2.7 seconds for a page with only formed
it's weird but if we go into that yeah
there is a lot of stuff going on here
this call graph will take a while
because and it's gonna be intimidating
[Music]
whoops and then it was gone oh it's so
small now yeah so it's back yeah but you
as you can see it there is a lot of red
everywhere and yeah where to start you
will need some inside knowledge of your
application well you will eventually
follow the hot part again and we'll find
out something peculiar I think it's
there somewhere no yeah let's not try to
find in life it doesn't help but
somewhere if you get into this problem
you will find out somewhere that it
renders your page in PHP again that's
kind of an expected behavior because you
thought yeah well I have all my caches
on so you don't have to rerender this
page it's somewhere in cache if you dig
a little bit further you will find out
it has a Magento CAPTCHA and it which is
rendered server-side surprised you
cannot catch this page so it slows down
a lot but for these kind of problems you
also already need a lot of application
knowledge all well inside knowledge
about the application you are using to
find out actually what is going on so
you will eventually recognize a problem
oh it renders the HTML so this is not
what I expected so why does it do it and
eventually you find out it tries it also
it always renders a CAPTCHA you don't
want it to do so you need to find
another solution
so in closing find your slower things
for me my preferred go-to solution is xh
probe and xh ue because we use an APM
and production so we get some starting
points from there and then we only use
profiling locally to really fix the
problem also don't trust profiles from
your application performance monitoring
for example when your system is under
stress so if you have a high load on
your server that that information will
not be useful will not be correct also
what you can take away from this is make
your popular pages cacheable it will
help you a lot and if you can profile
periodically in your development
environment - if you have some reference
you will know that your application
slowed down while adding new features or
for example you had to do a bug fix and
it's suddenly one and a half seconds
instead of one second maybe you have to
reconsider the fix are there questions
yes so the question was have you ever
tried New Relic yes we use that as an
APM in our production environments but
that was out of the scope of exactly
profiling so that's that's also the
reason my preferred go-to solution for
profiling to improve things is xhu II
with x8 profit x8 Yui because we get
some pointers from New Relic where
things are probably slow and if you can
reproduce this locally we can get ahead
and so yeah you get all you get you
already get useful information from New
Relic so you can reduce your search time
in the cold graph where you very already
know from New Relic yeah okay it's about
my sequel queries it's its elastic
search that's that's responding slow
it's something else
so yeah it's useful you have other
competitors of New Relic
I think the auto doc is one and tight
ways
sideways also offers you a minimal set
of APM so yeah it's it's very useful to
have it
the only drawback we've seen lately is
that in really complex applications New
Relic might have too much overhead so we
we switch it on and off like if we
expect a problem we turn it back on
but if we want normal operation we turn
it off because we noticed at some sites
between 15 and 30 percent overhead which
is really big
yeah yeah the more complex your
application becomes the bigger the
penalties of New Relic even though they
are actually a tool that you want to run
in production that you want to have in
production to get this information but
yeah we lately seen it if your
application is really big it might
become no longer really beneficial to
have it yeah
for example yeah
other questions yes yes so the question
was is there a possibility to get this
in continuous integration I summarized
it correctly yes it's possible so that I
didn't mention is like Blackfyre has
this
that you can make it profile during your
continuous integration so you really see
the trend if your application is slowing
down slowing down over time so you can
make it a part of your continuous
integration it it might be very useful
also what I did not mention is there is
a more newer tool which is called PHP
spy but I only tried it briefly and I'm
not sure if it's really that easy to use
for request based profiling but it works
very well for command line tools to
profile those and it gives you a nice
fire graph which is very easy to
interpret
to read and to understand but it's
fairly new so I have to dig into that
deeper more questions no well thank you
and you can give me feedback on joined
in or on Twitter or whatever
[Applause]
[Music]
whoa
you are in real-time preview at the
minute