with your 3d printer I think in the very
very long term yes but you know for the
moment you know certainly not there's
just you know too many people are
looking to try to figure out what the
secret recipe is it provides a
competitive advantage there's a lot of
tension because most of the people who
work in this area are historically
researchers and academics they all know
one another they all go to the same
conferences they frequently went to the
same schools but most of them are
working for pay masters that you know
really would like to keep as much under
the table as possible until it's it's
clear I mean they always ask to publish
and we publish as much as we can we like
to be open but some stuff gets to them I
would buy a metaphor consider you know
the whole you know risk of the movie so
we finally have after what 50 years of
computers an open-source computer design
and even that's not a computer design
that's just the instruction set okay so
it will happen but it will take a
generation or two in my opinion so
obviously in a lot of you I have to use
this yeah great so I agree with Kevin in
terms of where some of the industrial
players are going but a lot of the
advancements in this field are still
happening in industry and there's
actually a lot of open-source software
that goes all the way down even
available today so there's things many
called cue codes which is used for
controlling super nothing qubits and
there's a bunch of groups thank it was
someone here who works on that project
they're not here now there's open source
controls for Dax and adc's depending on
your platform there's Arctic which is
open source project for fast feedback on
ion traps which is another kind of
quantum computing and these things go
like this is like all the way down down
to the metal so I think there's going to
be a proprietary stream and that might
be the leading stream but there's
already sort of open source bases and I
Demian I don't think those are gonna die
out they say I hope they're not
controlling so it might be open source
but still only for a couple of groups
that actually cover
[Music]
and and to some just to follow your
point to some degree the firmware is
only relevant to a very particular
implementation I mean and and and that's
sort of the point I mean what we're
trying to get you know Sirk down to the
lowest level that is useful to people
you know working on machines in the
abstract yeah we got firmware but our
firmers different on every for every
chip and modifications the chip will
need modifications of firmware so open
sourcing that firmware until we actually
start having standard well again Linux
became possible because there were PCs
ok so once there is a Bic what is cheap
quantum platform you know then I think
the open sourcing of the low-level
software all makes sense just that yeah
I think that while the while each piece
of hardware is bespoke and relatively
bespoke to the companies I just
fundamentally agree with that point that
the very second I think that you get
some model where you could reasonably
expect a large number of people to use
it or maybe just even as we start to
scale up and you start to see common
components appear between the different
refrigerators say that are more
accessible than you might see more
standardization of the software but
until that point I don't think I don't
think so other than maybe in very narrow
verticals where some things are useful
and used some open-source components are
used deep in the stack
yeah that's why I was gonna say so in
quantum photonics we're using for a lot
of our equipment off the rack stuff
there a lot of universities and other
scientific labs used so there is a lower
entry to bury a lower barrier to entry
the thing is it will still take time
because we're still standardizing
exactly what architecture will look like
on the quantum photonic chips so I guess
and in the very short term will be doing
optimization based on user submitted
jobs and how can we optimize and make
this process more efficient in the long
term definitely I see a process for once
we've standardized the quantum photonics
the one thing that would be a barrier
though are the detectors so the
measurements at the end of the circuit
so at the moment we're using two very
high quality best in the field first row
number resolution detectors PN RS from
NIST and these don't require super
cooling but they require a degree of
cooling so these aren't as accessible as
the rest of the photonic setup we have
so that's a--that's a little bit very
so actually that's very possible you can
build a quantity of Sonic's chip with
off-the-rack stuff it won't necessarily
be Universal and you won't have access
to all the quantum algorithms the very
basic thing you could build a chip that
does something with the classical
properties of light and then introduced
some quantum properties that way so
there are easier ways to accesses
definitely in quantum photonics and I
think that's the approach will be taking
so we'll have an iterative procedure to
our devices as well I think one point
that is worth noting is like the number
of startups you're seeing in the field
kind of shows that it is possible to
sort of in some sense build a quantum
computer in a hobby sense I mean these
are obviously I have no idea what the
barrier of funding is for these places
because I'm not involved with that side
of the building but you do see that
you're getting more and more of
companies and it's law and research
groups at universities and various
people getting involved with this this
field which still again I mean this
amount of infrastructure goes into that
but it does show that there are it's not
so high that you need you know giant
companies to do the funding right from
the beginning just to say the real cost
the real obstacle isn't cost its
expertise
well the core team that is building the
hardware have invested you know many
many years in in trying to master the
superconducting technology and so we
don't have hardware teams working on
anything else at this point the
algorithms guys on the other hand I mean
the beauty of quantum information theory
is that it doesn't matter what the qubit
is composed on the behavior is the same
and so the algorithm should be
applicable wherever else and I sometimes
joke that if somebody else actually
comes up with a better scheme you know
I'll be faster cheaper more stable you
know Hardware a substrate you know I'll
be the first to say let's move to that
but I try not to say that in front of
John Martinez's team because you know
you would break their hearts
so
I do want to get the others involved but
you know I'll point out that you know I
mean I've worked for IP companies that
you know that used patents as a weapon
Google Trends to try to use them as a
shield there are things that I've
invented and not the quantum field at
Google that we didn't patent but we
filed the paper to prove that I'd
invented it so that nobody else could
because we didn't want to shut it off
from the world I mean Google does that
kind of stuff now are we gonna do that
with key quantum discoveries I do not
know but again historically we're fairly
open but you raise it won't you raise an
excellent point it's it's a good point
and there's there are some things that
other industries have done and some
other things that we could as a
community think about doing so there's
an example is a one thing you can do is
have like a defensive patent consortium
where the stuff that where groups of
startups will pool IP so maybe they each
have a few patents but if they pool
their IP for defense then if anyone they
have access to it if any one of them
gets sued by a large company and other
kinds of consortium models and stuff
like that
I'm not gonna go too far and advocate
for any particular one for our field but
that's it's a thing to think about and
there are some of these groups that are
starting to come together like the
quantum open-source foundation would be
a group that could think about this
there's something called the quantum
economic development consortium in the
US that has mostly big companies and a
lot of startups in it as well Google's
in it too so there's there's some space
for us to think about how to do that in
our in our industry and it's we can
actually act on it it's not something we
just have to talk about so that's good I
guess the only other point I would add
to that is like there is definitely
different types of patents so that
companies focus on so for instance do
you wave where were a lot slower to
patent or to otherwise IP protect like
algorithms because we want we want more
people in the field we want more people
in the ecosystem so you know there's
incentives the same incentives that had
us open source our software in the first
place is the incentives that keep some
that stuff fun protector or otherwise
just defensively patented but as you get
sort of maybe parking back to the first
question as you get sort of further down
the stack the the incentives start to
switch a little bit so
[Music]
I tend to agree with you I think we
sometimes make especially the physics
very hard to access and not very
accessible to people who want to get
involved and want to get engaged so I
think we definitely have to do a better
job doing that I agree with you hundred
percent there's been times where I've
had to learn the other frameworks from
the other companies so especially when I
was doing the Penny Lane forest plugin I
think I started with Pikeville version
1.9 and halfway through Pikeville
version 2 came out where there were lots
of API breakage and I it happened really
faster I didn't really know us but I
pick and sold upgrade and everything
broke so even even from a quantum
researcher it's difficult to keep up and
so I think it's something we definitely
need to improve them
yeah I mean so at least from the US
perspective I mean though we started our
open-source project a little bit later
than I think some of the other folks up
here but I went live maybe about a year
ago and the whole purpose of that was
number one to sort of bring it higher
level and higher level and higher level
so that we could access groups and I
think like the all the projects that are
going on from all these different
companies and groups are starting to
reach a level of maturity that you can
you at least you're not going to version
3.0 and then 4.0 every week you're you
know at least have months in between
these things and that gives you just
enough stability that you can reasonably
start reaching up higher in the API and
then I think the other point is that
part of the reason that at least for us
that we went into the open source space
is because we want just more people in
the ecosystem asking more questions
making more connections because then the
my best case scenario is someday
someone's gonna ask a question on Stack
Overflow and someone else will answer it
without us ever having to have been
involved right yeah yeah so so I mean I
think that just getting getting more
people in the ecosystem creates that
connective tissue that then lets the
next people who come in have a little
bit of a softer landing and and you can
sort of build up from there another
thing to remember is that a lot of these
packages a lot of them are really about
quantum gates and quantum computing but
a lot of them have the classical
software in them there are there web
frameworks in them there are api's in
them and all of these things also need
to work really well and could be made
better so as a web developer I think
there's a lot of ways that you could
contribute because a lot of people who
are developing the physics code are good
at the physics but not at the web
development this would be actually a
very very useful way to to contribute
on the back he's been raising his hands
several times yeah that's a good
question
if you come to tomorrow I think there's
a lot there's some other ones that the
people so come check out those talks a
plug for those I can tell you about why
we ended up with Python at Righetti
there's some list but why that was the
interface we chose it was based on the
target audience that we thought would be
using this so typically people who are a
little bit more mathematical programmers
may be a little bit more scientific
programming they know vectors so that's
ml people and Python is kind of a lingua
franca for that initial group and it has
a lot of other reasons that it's good
easy to prototype in so that's why we
ended up with Python on the front end
but there's tons of reasons why in the
long term it's almost certainly not
going to be Python
we might have real quantum programming
languages at some point like all of
these are kind of like embedded cue
sharp from Microsoft has won a check out
that's kind of actually but but that is
that's already got a lot of barriers
barriers to entry that's kind of like
maybe the hardest way to do it it's
multi-paradigm already
it's like based on the f-sharp so so I
think there's there's at some point room
for proper a quantum programming I think
another reason that Python is attractive
is that you know it has some of these
tools coming in like scythe on and it
has pretty good C++ bindings in the
first place so I think most of the
stacks here are all sort of Python
interfaces but have some C core or at
least some part of it so you know when
you're when you're doing these sorts of
things you you want to both address the
first point which is make it easy to
access but then you want to also give it
performance and so at least for us that
cost-benefit analysis is resulted in
having writing it in Python prototyping
it in Python having it let out live out
there for a little while and then start
knocking down the typed all poles by
converting the the intensive parts into
C and so when you actually look at the
total execution time of sort of an
average job I think again on a lot of
these stacks what you'll see is that it
actually spends a lot more time in C
code than in Python and can I just add
to that that one other reason we went
with Python I mean there's two smaller
reasons in that because we're working
with very
the hardware team is also kind of
prototyping a bit as well
so pythons a good language for
prototyping and on top of that we found
that python is just really easy to
install so we have more complicated
packages where we have C extensions we
have C++ extensions and we have Fortran
extensions and with Python we can have a
pipeline where we build the binaries for
all the operating systems and Python
versions we want to target and for the
user all they have to do is pip install
and they don't even have to worry about
dependencies
yeah in in Google's case we had a
certain amount of experience with
programmatic interfaces to the various
REST API is for the cloud services and
in many cases we started out with
publishing in Java and what we found is
you know everybody is saying ok job is
really nice but couldn't you give us
something that's like oh Python and and
so you know so that was already sort of
a trend we knew that people that users
of cloud computing in general seem to
like to use it for the aforementioned
reasons it's easy to use you get quick
feedback it's not this very long compile
debug cycle and then you know very
significantly of course we did
tensorflow and yes there are tensorflow
bindings for other languages but nobody
ever talks about them right it's all
being done in python because of that
dominance in the data science space and
keep in mind that the official name for
the Google quantum team is the AI lab so
there's that
okay
that point is a really good languages is
always a fun topic right so in quantum
computing debugging is is tough because
if you have n qubits and you want to
print the state you're gonna end up with
two to the n complex numbers so if you
one hundred qubits you put no print
statements so your debug feels a little
weird and so that that makes me think
that in the longer term we're going to
need languages which have sort of more
formal they have to have actual type
systems so that we can use this as a way
to control formally what we're doing
when we can't do normal print debug
flows so that's another reason to think
that we'll move a little bit and it's
worse than that because you can't do a
great point restart right yes yeah so
debugging is a big
so I definitely that ease of use is good
most people who program program on
multiple platforms so making it easier
to do that is important there are things
that are the way to make that easier
that I think is a good one is this
transfer transpilation stuff so there's
like a chasm a quill converter and these
kind of transport and the reason I think
that's better
rather than standardizing is it's a
little early to think about this field
standardizing we still need to come up
with a lot of creative different ideas
you know we aren't at a stage where
people are running quantum computations
and they're much faster they're much
better and we know what the patterns are
and we know how to do quantum
programming like we don't know how to do
any of these things so having more
diversity in approaches is I think
important and so I'd actually careful
about about early standardization but
translation definitely
just just to respond to that point I
mean you know this comes up that you
know just about every conference and you
know and I will echo the point that it's
a bit early to think about
standardization but you you can think of
you know standardization sort of as a
horizontal and a vertical axis here and
as much as do we actually want to have a
common low level language maybe at some
point do we want to have a standard high
level and we yeah maybe at some point
but ultimately again we're talking open
source here so ultimately what's going
to happen is that they're going to be
you know library api's that are
relatively high level that do things
that are useful for people that are
going to get where the implementations
underneath maybe actually
device-specific
and you you link in a very large sense
of the term with the one that's required
I think that's the sort of thing that
will evolve but it's it's early early
days we don't know what's most efficient
can I just add on the when we were
developing Penny Lane we we had the idea
as a qml framework but what we noticed
after developing and having people use
it was that sometimes you would use it
even though you didn't want to access
any of the gradients of the qml features
and sometimes even I when I have a
Strawberry Fields program I'll just do
in Penny Lane because it's faster and
allows me to quickly swap it out and try
QAS case or something it's not a a
proper high-level abstract replacement
because you still can't control any of
the lower-level Hardware optimizations
you're still constrained into this queue
node encapsulation where you have to
work with expectation values but playing
around with that has got me excited to
the future where eventually there will
be this high level library that allows
you to mix and match and change devices
I think because the d-wave architectures
is so different than a lot of the other
architectures here it's sort of hard for
us to talk about standardization in the
same way but maybe I'll put a slightly
different slant on it which is like one
plug for sanitization I'd like to see is
standardization of benchmarks because
right now it's very much the Wild West
for a different different companies
doing different benchmark and I think
that can be both a good thing and a bad
thing for everybody but having some some
more standard targets that then can be
compared what I think really helped the
field yeah what's the quantum missed
that's them these kind of standard tests
have done a ton for machine learning I
guess maybe I'll take the really easy
answer which is like in the same way I
mean in a analogous way to the way that
like machine learning has sort of
touched on everyone's lives in the sense
that it was like sort of it's it's a
really factor of a bunch of other old
concept that suddenly if you put them in
the right way and sort of put the right
hardware behind them you can get a lot
of a lot of benefit from that I think
sort of the dream of the quantum is is
to have sort of a similar effect where
it's like it in some way touches very
lightly on on everybody's lives but
probably at least in no time that I'm
imagining are you gonna have it on your
wrist because you know just the way the
hardware is designed so I see it as
being potentially in the future like
everywhere but also kind of a level or
two abstracted away from from the
average use case but I'd love to hear
actually other people's will again when
you say benefitting you know the man in
the street okay and I I don't take you
to be asking is the man that Street
going to be carrying around a quantum
cellphone okay
I mean I give us a gives us enough
centuries and people will of course have
something like that
but no in the near term where I think
it's going to have an impact and again I
did not talk very much about the
applications I was really much more
interested in explaining how the system
works and how that influences the design
of the language that we open sourced but
if you look at applications that are
seriously being investigated now is for
example with quantum superposition you
can do a much better job of global
optimization of for example traffic
management for public transit or for
taxis if you use waze waze will tell you
where the traffic is but Waze creates
its own traffic jams because
Durex everybody - what is that at a
given moment the optimal path what you
actually need to do is you need to
distribute the traffic in some
intelligent way where you're not
creating new traffic jams and that's a
hard problem and there are quantum
algorithms that will tend to get there
and so people like Volkswagen are
investing in looking at it for things
like that's just one example there are
others so there's sometimes people talk
about a big application space for
quantum computers being the quantum
simulation which sounds like it's very
esoteric but what it actually means is
designing molecules with computers so we
design planes on computers now not if
not in wind tunnels and it's that's why
we've been able to go from the Wright
brothers to jets so fast but the
molecular equivalent is still throw a
bunch of PhDs at it you know if you know
anyone get a PhD in chemistry they might
have spent their entire PhD figuring how
to make a couple molecules but in the
long run if we can use computers to help
design molecules then the man on the
street may have organic batteries solar
cells that are much more efficient
impacts on making fertilizer cheaper
stuff the stuff that we design with
quantum computers I think is going to be
a very very impactful in the long run
so even if so
that's a great point and there's more
even beyond at when tanks work there's
actually several kind of other examples
there was a contrastive diverted
riverssance algorithm yeah yeah it's a
new racing one yeah it's a really good
point
I mean just to echo something I said
earlier like I think just having a
community that we can grow getting more
people in the ecosystem on all of the
platforms some of the platforms trying
comparing the platforms using you know
doing web development doing you know
anything really just getting more smart
people doing more things on all these
systems I think would help all of us
because then that creates that sort of
competition an idea isn't generating and
just all the energy that we need to to
do the amount of work because you know
one of the things about working at one
of these companies that I think is most
fun is like there's so many ideas
there's so many there's so much
low-hanging fruit there so many things
to try that you know we could have ten
times as many employees and we wouldn't
be able to try it just on the software
side right so so having more smart
people in the yuko system trying those
things can can only really be a benefit
to the field as a whole yeah I agree and
I also think it's it's really useful and
really important to have a sort of
central area that people can refer to
and see all these different quantum
software projects it was one there are
awesome lists on Facebook this is one of
the first places that instead of just
listing it also discussed the different
projects and said you know these ones
have been they're not active anymore
these ones are still active these ones
have decent documentation I think that's
a very important thing so we can get an
overview of the quantum software
ecosystem especially if users who are in
you too or don't have a quantum
background because a lot of the
documentation there really exists was
written by physicists and it's something
we can improve upon and something like
the cue OSF can definitely help with
that I particularly agree with with that
last point there are things to be done I
don't think it's critical yet simply
because the the size of the community
the number of people who are actually
doing development is relatively small it
would be a total exaggeration to say
that they all still know each other but
it's it's a pretty small group and as
things the more things scale the more
signal noise ratio degrades and the more
points of coordination clarification
documentation standardization become
deeper and try to understand very well
how these qubits actually work and
interact understand
on the other hand there's this other
approach that treating some way I can
black box and trying like here and there
and see what happens and then in the
meantime like you know getting a better
feel of how it works
reading paper checking it out and you
know like joining this Victorian
practice
starting from like a higher higher point
and it has like it's easier this way for
many people who are not theoretical
physicists so my question is do we have
any thoughts about it and how like
looping promoting this high-level
approach is is a good thing and how to
actually explain people to people that
you don't understand research yeah I
think I think that's a great point most
of us don't understand these machines
all the way down to the physics of the
transistors right and it's kind of
contrasting maybe like a bottom-up
approach which is what people learn in
physics of like here's linear algebra as
opposed to a problem first approach I
think this might be something that the
open source foundation could could help
with they could have a list of you know
problems of like here's a way to get
started little challenges opening eye
puts out it was a request for research
challenges that could be smaller ones
that a little bit educational of like
you know start trying to implement this
trying to solve this problem I think
that would be a good a good thing to
have
[Applause]