so okay good to go yeah yeah I'm going
to see jokes from my side
hi i'm gabriela Falasca and i want to
talk you to talk with you about the
caching strategies flow for progress you
about okay you know that this is the
chrome that I know when when you are
offline offline is a problem for the
information flush sorry okay
for the information flush in of our
application because you don't have the
data now I will show you how to automate
the data also for offline news from last
week Google Play as I noted that
progressive web app can be uploaded on
the store and so you can East and
progressive web app directly from Google
Play Store is a good thing what is a
progress you are but you know okay
progressive buff is a lively the from of
web application and native application
okay is a web application that you can
install on your mobile device and it has
looked like look and feel of the ver
native application okay if you have an
existing web application if you want to
migrate it to progress your but you have
to follow this step you have to make
sure that your application follow the
HTTPS protocol you have to think about
the caching that is the object of this
talk you have to to implementer and Adam
Adam home screen button for the mobile
visualization you have to use all API II
you need
and joy okay let's see a recap for
service a drank rendering web source
client server side rendering okay
server-side rendering is the most of a
website are also in server-side
rendering so you the browser make a
request to the server and server returns
completes that page and after the page
loads or remote assets ssj as images and
every action on the page causes the the
for reload of the browser table okay
in client-side rendering the server the
server retards only a block template
okay and after to JSU you have to fetch
the data and show to the user but the
pro is that every action on the page are
allowed only the part of the code where
were actually triggered okay if you are
to cache to cache things in a
server-side rendering you can cache CSS
JavaScript or asset and the static page
okay in in clients in a client-side
rendering application you can cache CSS
JavaScript and play to images and the
yuka cache the data are received from
the network for offline use if you have
a simple data you can use a cache API
but if your that has a bit complex you
you can use indexed DB and you can
manage the offline streeter through
JavaScript in this model or checking
navigator dot offline flag or there is a
solution Evan basic in JavaScript you
can catch the offline and
events okay you know serviceworker there
are a piece of code that sit between the
application at the networker and the
serviceworker can cache things can
intercept all the facts requests and you
can use particular api's such are web a
lower payment or I don't know okay what
you can do with several worker caching
things register for push notification
use various API I just see and other
things that okay this is the first
strategy for caching things in progress
you above you have to to create your app
fall of the schema you have to separate
the application shell so the all the
scaffolding all the scaffolding part of
the application from the dynamic content
okay in this model when you start the
application you can cash immediately the
application shell and after you you can
get the content dynamically okay let's
start with the real caching strategies
let's start talking about to the went to
cash resources okay this is the first
approach you can cash reserve sister
honestl okay when when a serviceworker
is transmitted this trigger understand
event and in the callback of this event
you can is easier for caching the all
the dependencies of the application so
javascript CSS images and and the other
order data you can consider statically
for your application okay
another event is a activator when you
update your service worker and the the
new service worker is a is activated the
odd one is not working anymore
so you can catch the activating event of
new service worker and use this event
for puja the old data
push the old service worker data and you
can manage emigration schema for your
index at the beach ok for for caching
resources you can use also user
interaction so you you say Ridley there
same for align buttons on the click of
the button I cache the data the proper
data so as you can see the the cache API
is not only available only in
serviceworker but you can use also in
the regular page another another
strategy is caching that or network
response is a good good a good approach
for not big data big data because for a
moment you have two instance of the data
as you see response that clone so if you
fetch very bigger data it could be
problem of memory because the the way it
is doubled for a moment ok you can cache
things also impose messenger you don't
push notification yeah okay and which
submits work and you can you can
register for a push notification service
and if you want you can you can store
data in cash
with a push notification when the app is
closed it but
the device to receive the notification
and we start to to caching the data of
the notification this is a new API but
in this moment is not standard the
background sync API in JavaScript for
some service workers you can start a
sink a background sync update of the
data and during this update you can
catch the the things you are updated but
sync API is not a w3c standard in the in
this moment ok this is a cool approach
is the approach use it for example for
the whatsapp avatar are you sure
when a user changes Avatara you continue
to see the old one for a bunch of time
and after the
the other launch of the application the
update ok I should with a user did that
by having care in cash but I recovered
the new data from the network for the
next time easy deal for if you have data
that you don't need the last update ok
ok now let's see how to respond to
requests with you can see when use a
cached data or when use the network data
or let's see also hybrid approach ok
this is the simplest I have a fetcher
okay I'm at the faction for all not get
requester so foreign to me submission
you can catch the the request because
you have to send data to the server and
for noget request you can do anything
another this is the most usee the
strategy ok
this is the standard strategy and all
over all other strategies can be
exception from these who I am a fetch
okay I have the result yes this is the
result no I got the result okay I made
the request on the network this is the
old approach of the of the social
network of all social network okay I try
to recover the the latest data but is
the network fails I'll show you the cash
the caching data and now this is the new
approach the code is splitted into slide
because he is longer this decoder you
you have to use in the application page
and this is the good of the service
worker okay
and in this strategy you show media Tony
to the user the cache data and after
show the data you can recover the latest
data on the network and show and put it
in the same feed of the user okay so
this is the code of the service worker
either for Continental of this
frequently such as social media team
lines okay other strategies but less
user this CAPTCHA network race and
generic fallback genetics for back is
the classical error page so I sorry
and the fashion autocracy is extremely
particular situation you can use it only
if you are sure that device were is
installed at the Apple are very slowly
discuss arches okay so I start
contemporary the cache coal and network
Allah and I use the the first result
the result of the of the winner of the
race okay oh let's see re-establish
worker that okay you see the code okay
now you you can read okay these are
service worker for a pokedex you know
the Pokedex Pokemon okay
honest and event I am I carried the the
main chunk of my application is our
react application okay the main chunk of
the application German JavaScript
I fetched the list of the Pokemon
because the Pokemon are there and I
assured the Pokemon images okay I create
a function for generate an array of
images you'll and I'll cash it and after
i intercepted the fetcher I use it the
different strategies for for many cases
but only for learning purposes because
our are not the optimal strategies for
for these cases okay if I want to see an
ability of a Pokemon I use the network
cash fallback approach okay and if I
want to see the move of the Pokemon I
use the network only I use this because
I can show you the difference between
cash call and network holder okay and
for other cola-cola I use the network
cash for back approach okay let's see
the application oh okay so
if i refresh the page you can see this
is all pokemon images okay if I open a
new Ola and I see the the request timing
is a zero millisecond because they have
already in my cache the same is for the
color of the pokemons list zero
millisecond and is so bulbous our okay
and if you want to to see the detail if
I if I want see an ability I have to
recover the data from the network okay
and the timing is the request is lowly
then the others okay if I return to the
oh my and i refresh exist eternally okay
so I finished have you got a question
[Applause]
I've been doing a little bit of work
with pwace and one question that keeps
going back from other people involved in
the project is what happens if the app
is not connected for a period of time
because you can't guarantee that the
caches are gonna be kept so fishy so you
can't guarantee that the cache gets
maintained persisted for a long period
of time it might get flushed yes how do
you what sort of strategies have you got
for that if you're not going to be
connected to a network so the example I
can give is people out on a shipping
boat they've got their app they do some
work using that there might be away from
sure for a couple of days okay so the
cache is purty Center but there are
limited space okay and some browser as
to when the this limit is reach other
start to flush all the data and Safari
polish the cache randomly randomly start
to the cache polish so there are new
strategies that you've come across to
help case that Franz using other parts
of Web API is maybe to maintain this
there are there any particular
strategies that you've come across to
help with that situation you have to
study your case that's what we go to is
wondering okay okay
sorry about the previous question I am
one of the strategies maybe the
persistent data Matt you can you can ask
for this mercy sorry yes sorry grace
yes I was thinking about the previous
question maybe I can just add there's a
persist a P I all right not available
everywhere but anyway that's not my
question my question is what day again
was the strategy to update the
application itself
so when enters a new version of the
application right yeah so how to deal
with that so I install it with the
serviceworker and then how to inform the
user yeah when we sell new serviceworker
you can catch the activity activate
event of new service worker and you can
clear the cool data and update your data
yeah but how do I know that I need to
delete my my old version of the
application and I want the new one to
check the new version this depend of so
the cache is virtual ated okay so you
can use a different cache for any
version of the application and on
activity event you can put the older
cache and use also the the new with the
new serviceworker
okay the question
yeah thanks it's not a question with the
addition you don't have to implement the
whole caching strategies at first they
are a lot of tutorials out there okay
and secondly they are libraries for that
out there yeah one of them is for
instance work box yes very good library
you probably know it but the other
others don't so yeah yeah what box but I
I want to show without it because
there's no sense but I think is
important when you that you say it is to
know that concept yeah yeah absolutely
what's the question
no okay thank you okay
[Applause]