we're gonna go really fast today who's
seen it in my talks before anyone oh
there's some people cool cool good to go
all right hi I'm James hi everyone thank
you for coming it's a full crowd did you
put the full sign sure let more peace
let more people in the FASTA there's
room in the sides yeah so so we let some
more people in quickly
quickly let them in let them in so Who
am I I'm a hacker I work on config
management stuff I write a technical
blog called the technical blog of James
who've seen my blog just raise your hand
if you haven't just raised your hand so
I seem really popular is that Richard
Jones is he here that Richard
anyways I work on I used to work in
physiology or I studied as a
physiologist so if you have any
cardiology questions just let me know
and big in the DevOps stuff I was
working in DevOps and all the tools were
just just this everything was on fire
and terrible and you know people like we
had all these servers but now we have V
M so let's manage some VMs but then like
oh no that we just have more of these
machines and it's a big disaster and now
there's all these fancy pieces of
software to deal with these things like
I won't name it names and the real
question is do we want to really use
these giant and flexible monoliths
to manage our VMs do we don't be shy so
this is the answer to that as far as I'm
concerned this is my nope guy just like
I don't know some people might enjoy
those pieces of software for me it was
not what I was looking for and that's
fine you use the things you want to use
but I wanted to see if I could do this
in a better way so a long story short I
reluctantly sat down start writing some
code we have a project called MGMT I've
got this lovely logo thank you
and MGMT has two main parts there's the
engine and the language the engine is
basically what actually does the work
and the language I'm going to talk about
a bit too so in the engine just really
quickly I'm gonna go very fast so if I'm
going too fast hopefully you can slow
down the video at the end and watch
everything so the the engine actually
has two parts so the engine has three
main design points the graph of
resources that it runs it runs in
parallel there are event-driven and it
works as a distributed system so
basically for this sort of thing we have
these DAGs these resource graphs and
each blue block is work that we want to
have done and the black arrows represent
the dependency between each thing that
we want to do and if you can see this
red line here is something called a
topological sort where we just basically
decide we're going to do this and then
that and so on but an MGMT instead of
wasting a lot of time the way most other
tools do they actually paralyze this so
everything on the Left can actually be
run at everything on the right and so
even one a once this is done we can do
these two resources and so on does that
make sense
pretty basic stuff and that's useful if
we're working on really big complex
systems that have a lot of things going
at the same time we want them to be able
to run in parallel and each box each of
those blue boxes those resources are
actually
event-driven so I can actually show you
a quick example of this we have all
sorts of resources including our vert
resource so I'm just going to sit down
to do some demo so don't worry I'm still
here don't be afraid I'm just gonna run
this first demo here and basically it's
very simple show you the code it's very
very simple we basically just declare
dillio you can't see it there but we
declare this vert resource and we give
it some properties so one CPU memory
that we want it to be running and so on
and so let's just run this and see what
happens so we're going to run this over
here and if we run verse list can
everyone see is that big enough on the
right so you can see that MGMT started
up this VM right here it's running but
here's the cool thing everything is
reactive so if I averse if I just
destroy the the VM you can see mgmg says
hey you were supposed to have that
running so it automatically starts it
back up and you can see it's running
again so you can destroy it comes right
back up cool you can even I think you
can even under fine it which is another
vm thing oops
and you know that one you can because
it's transient but yeah so you just do
bad things to it and MGMT will fix the
state make sense so that's just the
basics we're gonna want to do some
fancier stuff yeah yeah all right cool
all right so just one check so now we
can actually kill it and it's going to
go away so so this is actually what I
think is config management but this is
really another technology as well does
anyone know what I'm
getting at I think this is monitoring
right so traditionally system ins would
like set up all this infrastructure well
you have to set up monitoring detect
what's happening this way kind of merges
the two in the same in the same bunch of
work so hopefully you don't have to
replicate too much work so now I'm going
to switch very quickly and talk about
the language so this is sort of the
design principle for the language you
want to express things that are very
very complicated in very very safe ways
hopefully so a safe language once we
were powerful so we use something called
a reactive language and we want the
language to also be very easy to reason
about so our language is that DSL so
it's a domain-specific language which
means the language is useful for
infrastructure automation but it's not
useful for general purpose programming
it's designed for this use case and
because it's very specific to this use
case it has some special magic powers
that other languages would find it very
hard to write so here's a demo I'm going
to show you just to show you the example
so we have this date time function which
is in the language and we add the output
of that to this a year variable and then
over here there's like this I your
variable is a bunch of numbers
multiplied together and then we put that
into a struct with this load function
which then takes this value and goes in
here and this is all super weird and
then all of these we build this big
string and then stick it into this file
what is going on here does anyone know
looks a little confusing so let's run
this code just to see what happens so
I'm gonna run that code here on the left
and again that whole thing just produced
a file and I'm just going to actually
just oops
you run this watch command to show you
the output of that file in real time so
you can see what's happening and you can
see that the output of the file is
changing all the time
right and here's why these variables and
these functions this function here this
date/time doesn't return the date/time
it returns a stream of the date/time
values so every second this actually
changes it's the number of seconds since
1970 right so this changes every second
which means this variable changes every
second which means this variable changes
and so on the load valuable the load
value comes from the kernel the kernel
decides that the load is they recomputed
every five seconds so that will change
and all of this stuff gets output into
the string and then the engine gets
these resources that it builds and it
happens in this particular graph that
those resources are changing every
second which is the file contents and
that's what we see so we can see this
ticking away and that's changing in real
time it's everyone follow that and just
to make this a little bit more fun I
have actually this vu function and what
the view function is actually doing is
actually listening on my real laptop
microphone right now and sampling the
sound and if you look it's printing out
a little graph to express that so if
we're very quiet see it goes up and if
you want to test this I'm gonna be
really quiet when I point at you oh and
here you make a lot of noise are you
ready there you go
so again any value any sort of string
you can build all sorts of inputs that
are changing over time it's really up to
you to be creative and I kind of use
this example a lot because it's a bit of
a joke but you could have this in your
server room building your real-time
infrastructure if the volume is too loud
for some number of seconds maybe people
are having a fight so you could
automatically set all your file systems
as read-only so the system means don't
break things yeah random things like
that whatever you want that's the idea
that makes sense about the reactive you
want to see more demos or you had enough
yeah okay let's gonna make this a little
bit more complicated so magic CPUs so
here's what I'm going to do first what
we can do is I have I showed you hide
that vert resource right so I have
another one and I'm gonna start up
MGMT on my local laptop and I just want
to make sure I start up the right one so
you start up MGMT and what it's gonna do
is I'm gonna run verse list so it
started up MGMT some vm and let's
actually log into that vm now normally
when you have a VM start up it's already
even started up that was fast
normally my password is password
normally when you have a VM start up you
might want it to automatically start
MGMT and then run itself inside the VM
as well but because I want you to see
the log as what's happening I'm actually
going to run MGMT in the terminal so you
can actually see what's happening
instead of do
automatically and to way I do that I
just have same thing she's gonna run
MGMT I just have a little script that
runs it up so what I have here on the
Left I have MGMT running on my host
which declared the state of one VM to be
running and then inside that VM on the
right I have just a console of what's
happening and here's the fun part here's
what I mean to do I'm gonna tell you the
trick
nothing it show you happening so the VM
resource remember it's declarative so I
say I want this number of CPUs this much
RAM and so on but if I tell MGMT that
that value should be 2 instead of 1 for
the number of CPUs MGMT will notice that
the user requested a different value and
in the case of virtual CPUs it will hot
plug or hot unplug the CPU count in that
running vm so in real time in seconds
you can hot plug or hot unplug by just
changing the number and to get that
number I have a little text file that
MGMT is watching so just the way I had a
sound microphone input in this case I
have a little CPU count text file that
just says a number and MGMT is taking
the value the integer from that file as
the input now that's part one so when
this value changes it hot plugs on hot
unplugs cpu in the vm MGMT is also
running and MGMT also can use the cpu
count as a function so there's a
function called cpu count and it reads
how many CPUs there are and so I'm just
gonna hide this over here and open up a
new window I have a little display CPUs
shell script and it's just looping and
it's doing two things one it's running
LS CPU so you can see how many CPUs the
kernels are sporting the other thing is
it's editing a file to put in the number
of CPUs this could be doing something
fancier but it's just for simple so I'm
gonna ask it the hot plug is CPU or hot
unplug it'll change the CPUs and on the
right it should react very quickly and
respond that make sense
let's hope that you receive this works
ok so I'm just gonna echo say one CPU
count and boom it's done see that we
change it to 2 goes to 2 could go to 4
if we wanted so very quickly it responds
and
instantly we see four CPUs that cool you
want to do it faster faster or you've
had enough you guys are a shy audience
who's shy just raise your hand so we
know where you are anybody all right so
I actually can do this faster so I made
a little crappy shell script over here
and all it does is the shell script when
I press plus or minus it just echoes to
that file 1 2 3 or 4 just so you can see
how fast it goes so I'll move this over
here and just as I press 1 you can see
basically in in in virtually a second it
goes up and that fast is that cool that
virtualization can VMware do this I
don't remember if that's a feature or
not and so what apart from cool demos
maybe that's to ego II but like the
reason this is useful is because imagine
you have some big hosts running a whole
bunch of stuff and you just squish all
those VMs together because most people
have their crappy website about their
cat that never gets visited until that
one day when there's a lot of traffic so
then the load goes up so you dynamically
see that the load is going up so you add
more virtual CPUs and inside the thing
you schedule more services to start and
deal with that load and do all sorts of
stuff like that
is that cool that's the point you have a
quick question search that can't be use
for what fencing I don't know yeah yeah
wait wait wait I have more demos so I'll
show you I think no sir I got a lot of
demos so quickly we can do everything
actually we haven't implemented it for
RAM because it's really hard if you will
help I'll help you right at the RAM
support it's trickier the CPUs work
really great the RAM is like a bit
sketchy and there's some bugs but it's
doable so you want to see some more
demos I have some more cool so I'm just
gonna shut this down you actually have
to kill MGMT before you shut it down
otherwise it will just start it up again
right so you shut that down so I showed
you some magic D demo stuff this I'm
gonna skip so really quickly what I'm
not going to show your demo is this
language this FRP language can actually
look at the historical values that a
variable had so I know what the load is
today but I also know what the load was
five seconds ago or 10 sec
ago or whatever so what is this lovely
photo of anybody screaming out
it's a thermostat this is my parents
thermostat in Canada you see it's in the
correct international units of Celsius
I found a prettier picture for some sort
of weird us through I don't know what
the units are but I think they have
their house far too hot just for clarity
and this thermostat has an interesting
property does anyone know what it is
I found the hecklers anyone know what
the property is the property is called
hysteresis and what hysteresis is is
basically when you let's say you want to
have your house heated to 20 Celsius the
temperature is gonna go up and the
moment it hits 20 Celsius oh it's gonna
click off but then it drops down 0.1
degrees and it clicks back on and then
back off and back on and back off and if
it was doing this rapid oscillation you
would hear all its clicking and it
potentially break your furnace and it's
not good so what hysteresis lets you do
is when you hit a threshold you can
delay some time or distance before you
click back on and we're gonna show you
how that's useful let's see a demo come
on do I want here you want to see a demo
ok the end of the day I'm tired I'm
sorry so where's that demo what was it
demo so I have this demo so I'm gonna
run the demo on the left it's running I
can show you the code if you want all
the codes all and get so you can try
these demos at home on your own laptops
and just to sort of show what's going on
I'm gonna run this watch command on the
right so it's basically just every half
a second it's adding some text file and
then running echo just to put a new line
and then it's running verse which is the
VM list command with libvirt listing
over and over again makes sense so you
can see what's running we got two VMs
running one and two and MGMT is running
here and what I've done you can see
right here I'm printing out the system
load in that text file and I'm also
showing you a threshold of 1.5 so when
the threshold gets above 1.5 I've told
it to shut down one of the VMS and then
only when the threshold stays below 1.5
for 10 seconds will it start up that VM
again that make sense
and we'll talk about why this is useful
after so I'm just gonna move this down
here so watch
so I'm just gonna just artificially
increase the load just to sort of show
you that something is happening and
watch the value go up it's going up
pretty fast
so watch the second hits 1.5 there's
actually a bug in this so I hope I
didn't hit the bug there we go see is
hit 1.7 and you see how MGMT to the
second VM shut down you see that
so watch so the load is still high now
watch what happens when it goes below
1.5 nothing's gonna happen for 10
seconds hopefully so it's a 1.6 it's
dropping 1.6 1.500 so not quite or so so
5 seconds I don't know where the
rounding error is okay so in five
seconds four three two one and there we
go and it start it right back up is that
cool
you like that you can clap if you want
okay so obviously the implications are
pretty obvious you have a whole bunch of
load on a whole bunch of machines you
reschedule them somewhere else and so on
and and like trying to buy the VMware
plug-in to do this would be like a
million dollars and who knows how it
works so the whole point of having this
light flexible language is that you can
build these dynamic systems in real time
to do what you want and say you're one
of those scared people that doesn't want
to touch code first of all you're crazy
but second all you don't have to someone
else could build a module for your
company that does the use cases of a
bunch of things so instead of building
this huge kubernetes or OpenStack
monolith or whatever someone would just
build a small MGMT module that's
customized for the you know a whole
bunch of use cases and if you want those
use cases it's a month of work for some
developer to build the thing for you and
a different month for a different kind
of product and so on so you fast dynamic
right I think that's how software should
be so I have more stuff to show you
unless you're fed up you want to see
more
that's better that was better this is
FOSDEM everybody okay so history says so
some interesting nerd properties on the
language and engine the language is
something called an FRP I'm not a genius
at FRPs so I'm kind of making it up as I
go along but the cool thing is the
language and theory shouldn't crash but
it actually can because like a runtime
errors like a hardware failure or
something like that but technically
we're trying to eliminate all sorts of
errors at runtime but even if there was
a runtime error in the language the
language is actually pushing a stream of
graphs to the engine that does the work
so worst-case in there there at the end
worst case scenario the engine would
just be sitting there without a new
graph for a while so not perfect
remember how the code was out of order a
little strange but that's actually cuz
the code is that graph like in the graph
dag sense of the form so you could write
code that's out of order and will still
work properly you probably shouldn't do
this because you would be insane but
just a weird sort of quick about the
language we had a lot of safety
properties into this because we don't
want you to blow away a data center
because you made a bug so variables are
immutable so if you did x equals 5 and
then x equals 7
this would be a compile time error right
there's no nil variables in the language
so you cannot set something that's like
a null pointer exception or anything bad
like that I talked about hysteresis
there's different kinds and you can use
this to make all sorts of complex
decisions hysteresis is useful because
it's a real life thing that we like you
know think about like imagine like oh
I'm gonna open this door or the door
handle is hot huh ok I'm not going to
touch it again right away right your
brain has all these ideas something's
not working now you think about it it's
a real life thing reactive variables
super useful eventually we could have
probably also model error scenarios as
reactive variables I don't really want
to talk about that because it's kind of
niche but I'm talking at a really much
more technical niche conference in two
days so there's gonna be stuff about
that if you're interested and if you're
into graphs our import module system is
actually a dag and there's this new
system I just built to do all the module
writing so you could actually build
these huge standalone components it
worked out really elegantly I'm very
proud of it and all upstream so if you
want to take a look
excuse me so there's a lot of stuff
still to do how much time do I have
mister timekeeper six minutes so I don't
have time to show you another demo
unfortunately but I'll just tell you a
bit more about the tool so we still need
stuff to do it's still new in the
project it's not really on the
borderline of being production writing
you can probably start using this for a
lot of simple use cases even just doing
a small VM automation project something
that you couldn't do with your
traditional tools play with this we have
an AC we have an Amazon ec2 resource if
you want to manage VM in the cloud thing
wherever that is so same sort of stuff
if someone deletes your ec2 instance it
will bring it right back you can shuffle
them around we have a scheduler that
works in real time so you could actually
move VMs from cloud to other cloud or
from ec2 to you know some other guys
cloud if you want to so think about all
these things new features still a lot of
stuff to do there's some bugs and things
we need to there's some code quality
stuff that I think it's probably fine
but it probably needs a little bit of
love and this is all about this is all
about you how can you help you can use
this test it patch it share with your
friends document it start on github if
you're into that kind of thing you can
write a blog post about it even if you
don't code like this was cool you can
tweet it if you have tweeter you can
discuss it with people in the hallways
hey that purple idea guys pretty cool
hack on it just hack on this stuff right
it's code it's out there I left a job at
a reasonably cool tech company to sort
of live off my savings and do this and
I'm trying to keep it all free software
and that's the goal but if I don't have
people sending patches or sending me
money eventually I'll have to stop or
make a proprietary and that sort of
sucks we don't have funding and just
like graph of my money going downward so
I have a patreon just for fun that's me
and like finding a hacker it's very sexy
so if you want to feel sexy send me some
money that's cool let's just recap you
can't hear the audio but it's Arthur
Benjamin putting the cap back on his pen
it's a really bad joke I reuse all my
jokes so I'm sorry about that
IRC MGMT config on freenode we hang out
talk about nerdy things there's a
tweeter account and a mailing list
hosted by my former employer there's a
technical blog of James you all know
about it now so you can check that out
RSS and
house I'm purple idea on IRC and tweeter
and so on
and if you some crazy person accepted
all of my FOSDEM talks except for the
main track stuff so I'm giving a talk
tomorrow these are some talks I gave
earlier today because everyone just
accepted the talks and it was kind of
absurd so I'm gonna talk about the same
sort of thing but with container
scheduling so I'm gonna do a schedge
willing demo so you can actually
schedule containers very easily you
don't have to have a whole container
thingy and then there's a small
lightning talk which you might not find
interesting
right after FOSDEM on the 4th I'm at
config management camp where I'm gonna
give a really hard talk and then a
really really hard talk and also Felix
Frank did some cool work and MGM - who's
gonna be presenting as well so that's
free if you can come if you can get a
spot like it should come and on the last
day on the sixth again 30 minutes way
I'm holding a hackathon so all day will
be writing MGMT code playing with it
diving in new users experience users
everybody's gonna be there hacking away
it's free so if you can come feel free
to feedback if you like this talk please
find in FOSDEM organizer and the yellow
shirts and go up to them and be like hey
like James's talk purple idea looks
really cool and if everyone goes up to
them they'll be awesome if you can't go
to the schedule page on the website
there's a secret link if you click on
the talk at the bottom submit feedback
this is real go click on it and say hey
his talk was awesome and then maybe
they'll be like hey we should have them
for a main track talk but then you got a
free hotel and that's awesome
so I'm almost out of time I have some
very expensive stickers I will give you
if you promise to use them and stick
them on your laptops then you can have a
cool laptop like mine so if you want a
sticker I'll be just over here outside
and I'll give you one and that's really
that thank you very much
so I have I have like a few minutes wait
wait wait 2 min if you want a question
or two I will find it I think the famous
if you haven't met him Richard Jones is
in the audience he's a famous hacker
that makes all the plumbing stuff like
all the vertic all these things aren't
possible I didn't write all the things
underneath MGMT so guys like him do
great work to make anything possible the
system D people and so on so father
Richard does he's shy but he's he's a
genius and he helped me on the FRP path
so yeah questions any questions I can
take yeah so the question is which
hypervisors are supported so we actually
wrap libvirt so anything that libvirt
supports theoretically works I only test
with like qmu stuff and like KVM like
the core Linux stuff it's known to work
with others but I don't really know
technically it also works with LXE but
I've never really tried it um and if you
have a bug like submit it it's probably
going to be a liver bug yeah how do you
measure it sorry yeah
so the event-driven there's to basically
event stuff the resources each resource
the question was about events basically
so the resources themselves have events
to know when their state changes which
is so that the engine can change the
state or run the state whatever the
second source of events is in the
language so those functions like date
time and so on those suck in events from
something so anything you want to have
events from needs somewhere to get it so
in the case of levert the libvirt daemon
actually is watching the state of each
vm and that's where it gets its
information from that answer your
question
the load the load comes from the kernel
so the kernel has a thing know look at
the code it's amazing it just pops out a
new value every five seconds I don't
think it's pulling but pretty sure I'll
check but yeah any value you want
there's there's almost nowhere that
we're actually pulling I have to go but
I'll be right here if you have any more
questions and come up and I'll give you
a sticker thank you so much
[Applause]