yeah so I was saying I'm the one between
the end of the event and the beer and
I'm as as you probably very tired by the
event because there have been a lot of
sessions so my goal here is to make a
point around the red fish standard and
how many of you have heard about red
fish using it okay great so my name is
Bruno connect I'm working for a hardware
manufacturer company which I will not
necessary name here because I'm on my
own for the travel so you will guess
during the subscribe I've been involved
values open-source projects in the last
25 years and I'm interested in red fish
around the Python projects that we have
been doing in a small team of people
first I would like to just to remind
some definitions around what what we are
dealing with so everybody is aware of
what the rest api is yes okay an API is
clear it could be it could not be just
rest it could be POSIX it could be
explained oh it could be whatever
library defines a an interface between
two environments JSON is clear for
everybody as well I guess structured
format great Oh data okay so this is
something Microsoft had come with as a
protocol to enable the creation and
conception of first epi I'm not a huge
specialist of data but it's using
combination with the rest of the other
three protocols to create red fish so
red fish is not an openness to industry
standard which is providing
specification schema and a set of tools
these days to help you with regards to
server where machine management I would
say it started on the server side and
the goal is to if you are coming out
with a notion of BMC so an onboard chip
on the on your machine which allows you
to do which is completely Sorority from
your operating system your veteran
environment
gives you access through cellular
network port to another operating system
running there and giving you information
and ways to manage your server out of
man so this is what the BMC is doing and
having a lot of started in the past try
to help you manage at scale a fleet of
servers and typically you used to have
something called smash for example which
was a command-line interface tool
created by the DM TFS the same guy who
are creating redfish Rajesh's is there
because mash did not really succeed with
a way of smash in the room okay one with
used smash in the room okay so that's
why so it was pretty complex it was
really not standardized across vendors
so it was really difficult to deal with
and you have you had to learn a new a
new interface each time you were
changing from how to manufacturer which
was not very nice
so that's not one of the goal for a fish
red fish is really there to help
different manufacturers to agree on a
hardware representation of your machine
and an API sustaining that Hardware
representation so that you can have
access to the same hardware components
in different manufacturers servers the
same way so it's using as we were
mentioning earlier
it's a restful api it's based on on json
and it's also using data for some
representation the goal is to have a
much better hardware support at what was
provided before so the ancestry with
fred fish was IPMI which had a certain
number of drawbacks especially it was
not really secure it was pretty
cumbersome to use and it did not provide
a lot of hardware information on complex
hardware set up complex hardware setup
could be a blade system with chassis
where you want to have address you want
to address multiple servers inside a
single enclosure having a single
management interface or multi node
platforms so one manufacturer and I know
of which is HPE
has a machine called moonshot in which
you have cartridges which can have
embedded management board as well as a
chassis management ball and each
capstreet can have multiple CPUs
multiple systems on it so the red fish
tunnel was created to support all type
of hardware design not just an observer
two processors ram memory disk NIC etc
etc the goal is really to be able to
have a model which is suitable for more
complex platform and you may know that
some manufacturers are working on memory
centric type of computing these days and
we will have a couple of years we will
have machines which will be made of pool
of memory somewhere full of compute in
other places CP used different type of
CPUs and very high speed interconnect
between the CPUs and the memories and
the disks if several disk or yeah full
of large very large pool of memories and
so the right fishtronaut should be able
to support those new type of design of
systems that will happen in the coming
years so it really has been architected
that way of course when you gather I
don't know ten different how the
manufacturers around the table and you
say to them ok let's talk and make a
standard it's pretty difficult to each
one wants to have the best support for
is own however many hardware service
harbors platforms
so the standard evolved slowly because
they really agreed on a subset which was
pretty small at the start of certain
center a number of features that you
have in a machine and everybody was in
agreement on how those features should
be described and should be accessed and
as time passes they were adding more and
more features so that more complex
architecture were recognized and in
common between different manufacturers
however you always have some so the
marketing departments in in
company calls that added value and
sometimes you can call that crap but it
depends on the on your point of view but
anyway a lot of have a manufacturer have
some features that are not standardized
because it's something which
differentiates them from another harbour
manufacturer but they still want to be
able to access to it so the best example
in history is probably SNMP SNMP was
working like that you had to stand on me
buoy and you had public information with
your IDs and you are able to access to
certain number of information completely
and it's not that away from one
manufacturer to another but for example
our fans in our servers were accessed in
what we called private meet so we had a
certain number under which all the three
was our profit yeah IP and was described
and you give access to the people to the
information with that information for
the fan was different from a server from
Dell started from Lenovo server from
someone else away or whatever so we read
fish had to propose the same type of
mechanism and they created the notion of
om schema to be able for manufacturer to
store some information that for their
own information that they are not in
agreement to standardize yet either
because not all the manufacturer has the
same feature and so the other don't want
to expose in a standard something they
don't have because that them at a
disadvantage or because it's something
that the other don't have it and have
not developed or not interested in and
you want to keep it on your side so
hopefully after the first times there
will be a red fish red fish page because
I was supposed to make that slide based
on Wikipedia as a previous page because
I think it's a very good source of
information but there is no Wikipedia
page for red fish yet so I've written
what I had in mind on one template and I
will propose that when I'm in the train
back to my country and hopefully next
week we will have a red fish page which
will explain a bit what I explained to
you here
so the stomach is not completely new
it's four years old standard which has
been published
orogeny so mostly what we you had were
as a jason and the OData schemas to
describe the resources which are
available and a very light mock-up was
was made to elute developer to test
redfish even if they didn't had access
to hardware support addressed efficient
implementation because when we started
the startup was there but there were
very few hardware manufacturers who had
added that feature in their BMC nowadays
it's very different there are a lot of
manufacturer warp which are providing
support for the redfish with minimum
firmware version depending on on the
manufacturers I put here some of the
major one in terms of numbers of several
souls
feel free to so I also put that in the
wiki page Wikipedia page feel free to
add when if you are dealing with a
manufacturer you know that it's
supporting redfish feel free to add to
the information so you have mock-ups you
have real hardware you can play with it
that's pretty interesting a lot of
documentation has been published as well
as my paper facts etc on this URL so the
DMT F dot org website under the
standards at standard area they have a
redfish and three point in which you
will find all this information and you
can download all that so latest version
is 2018 dot three which has been
published in 2019 don't ask me why it's
not on 19.1 I don't know that's the way
it is so so having I think seven or
eight revision of the standard still
since the beginning you have release
notes which each time describe what has
been changed between the latest version
of the standard and the newer version of
the standard since the 1.0 version
originally it's mostly edition so has
not been any big change in the way the
standard has been has been designed
compared to your own
9 where it was a bit different okay so
what can you do with redfish so
typically you can do what you do with a
PMI sterically so you can have a lot of
deformation about southern health
temperature fans identification setting
forth information typically an inventory
on on the how the platform as much as
your bmc's able to provide to you though
about something like for the items that
you can get and the Mongols 400 items
25% or items you can modify through red
fish as well because you have the you
use the rest api interface so you can
get information but you can also pass
information to the redfish api and have
configuration items modified on the fly
you also have actions that you can pass
on the server around power management
around the boot order around some
thresholds for the power around llt and
logs and you can also deal with the BMC
itself with its network settings and
user accounts for authentication on on
the system through the BMC so the MTF is
providing quite a large set of tools to
deal with as examples I will say on how
to deal with the redfish interface so
that we can take that software as a
reference point and include that in the
either in your programming programming
environments so mostly what they're
providing is C bindings and Python
bindings there are some CLI tools and
there are more and more tools available
not all of them are working for all of
the redfish implementation so I don't
take part here but I'm trying to make
some of those tools work on my HPE
reference hardware and as souls I've
been developed by Dell sometimes there
are some differences in the way you
interact with redfish and specially the
set up the access to the saturate fished
as v1 interfaces a bit difference but
globally once you have
as that hurdle the rest is working
really really fine so you have the
possibility to do simulator as we can
for example if you have a real hardware
server you can capture the redfish
implementation of that server and put it
in a simulator and then run it as a
software appliance so it's pretty
interesting if you want to do tests
without having access to the hardware
which is also nice when we were speaking
about channel CI and the possibility to
do automatic testing that's one of the
feature which is pretty interesting what
else so constantly with a group of
people we started with Python by fusion
initiative I have another slide on that
a couple of years ago I've been in last
year so I've not been able to work on it
I hopefully will restart that this year
so once that guy didn't want to wait
till we fix some of the issues he
identifies as he created another Python
library called sushi there is also
another Python library in the end on the
red 50 MTF so everybody is in love with
Python these days I'm missing my Perl
bindings that's why I as there is a
comma here and I need to do something
for that but there is no reason it's
just rest API so it's easy to do
bindings in other languages that such as
go or whatever language you like the
only major application which has yet
already a redfish driver is probably the
OpenStack ironic bare-metal deployment
project I don't know of any other tool
which has integrated a redfish support
to do two Matic inventory or automatic
deployment for example based on the type
of systems you could have you can have a
lot of IDs using this type of tools I
will ever go into it so so data model
looks like this one but I won't pass too
much time on it what I will do is more
go on to directly the
so like one
[Music]
they're with me once it on
so I will just explore the markup for a
simple rack-mounted servers so this is
on the DM TF directly is at the MTF
website so not on swing very quickly so
they provide a certain number of of
mock-up for simple rack-mounted servers
or OCP machines they have blade systems
okay interesting
hmm
and so when you explore the data model
it looks like that so you have your
entry points which are so this all Z all
that stuff I don't know why we are in
need I need to discuss with the driver
because I don't really understand why we
are in need of that instead of just
playing Jason and you can have fields
directly and you can have of course
collections available so here we have a
single system but you can have the
notion of chassis so for example if you
go on there on the blade here you would
have more stuff you have the manager
which corresponds to the BMC so for
example if you look at the manager it
was just one BMC on the server and if
you go on the on the BMC so this is this
one it's not a real physical server is
just a fact one to show what type of
fields you can get and and you will see
that you have for example the NIC itself
of the BMC that you can query and
finally when you have passed the three
enough you can find the MAC addresses
for example of the BMC so if you want to
do DHCP configuration so not force of
BMC because you need to have access to
the Big C first so that's not really the
most useful part but if you go on the on
the system side of course and you have
just one system you will find exactly
the same type of information for the
photo MBD mix inside the system so for
example you see you have a TPM one to
two component inside that servers you
have a certain number of information on
the on the naming of the asset number on
the bios version which can help you
derive an upgrade strategy if you have
the fleet of servers and you want all
the server to have the same thing i'm a
version that's the type of stuff you can
do with it and again you can pass the
bios processors memory internet
interfaces so here i have to mix in my
server and again I have my MAC addresses
IP addresses here in that case so the
MAC address or harbour MAC address so
you can have a affect my advice you can
have a physical one and you can override
the physical one by another one if you
want so
here is a way to pass the information
and all that is accessible through the
REST API so here's it's just a nice
looking visualization system for it
okay let me just go back so for those of
you who are fan of pythons there is work
we've done around Python wet fish with a
couple of people initially around up
instead we use Python requests tortilla
to map in fact the the data model of
redfish in in-memory and being able to
pass it very very easily our goal and
that still work in progress we have a
markup close out but that's it would
require a bit more development the
interest for me of redfish is really
around activities so I'm part of
solution center we host 400 servers we
do models for different type of
customers and we are rebuilding the data
center all the time we move servers we
move part in the servers because we have
to build something which corresponds to
the customer request and the idea is to
say okay how can we automate the
management of those changes in
relationship we are CMDB so we have a
CMDB but each time you change your ram
from one server to another your CMDB is
wrong except if you do manual easy
operation inside the CMDB which is very
time-consuming and stupid job so the
idea is to really use while it's not
stupid for the people doing it but it's
you can use your time in a better way
and drink beers that cause them for
example but so the idea is really to say
okay if I could crema how how the
platform so that this part of the
inventory is always up-to-date and
pushed into my CMDB that would be great
so what we want to do is have a data
model of for our servers in the data
center which are looking like the
redfish one because we don't want to
reinvent anything and we want to map
that data model to the CMDB data another
we have and the same DB we are using is
an open source one called I top and so
the data a little item is a parameter so
you can change the data mother's or
where you want so we can vary
easily mapped to day tomorrow and each
time we modify something on the hardware
side pull information through which
redfish call in to the CMDB and the CMDB
is working by raising information which
you have changed but keeping all the
rest of the information which have not
changed so it's pretty easy to use and
that would allow us really to improve
the time that people pass on maintaining
that CMDB and just maintain the
information that only humans can
maintain not machines so that's one of
the area where redfish could be very
useful in my opinion another area could
be on the deployment so if there are Red
Hat people in the room for anaconda for
example on well you could have a look at
redfish to try to grab our information
from the redfish schema and detect
automatically a certain member of our
information that leads to device names
or holo setups that could be easier to
do using redfish directly in the
possible ways in it's interesting part
is that you do the redfish call and
whatever the nature of the server you
get then normally you should have
something which drives a decision which
could be the same for all manufacturers
so that's really the type of IDs you can
have around that so if you want its own
pit if you want to look at it as its
that's one version available you can
also look at the DMT F stuff as well I'm
working on the markup to automate the
test of our our client with regards to
the DMT F markup so that it works
correctly any question
yes yes your first
oh sorry CMDB is a configuration
management database so this is a place
where you are managing your assets in
your in your IT infrastructure which
could be not just computers it could be
copiers it could be phones it could be
buildings it could be whatever you want
in in the CMDB we have you can also
manage for example service level
agreements providers point of contacts
etc and you can have a measure of impact
so for example imagine you unplug a
power cord in your data center because
you need to do electrical maintenance on
an area you can say ok gel CMDB tell me
if i unplug that what is the impact on
my infrastructure so what will be the
services at the end which are touched if
I remove a plug on my on my wall so
that's the type of service a good CMDB
is able to to give to you and so some of
the CMDB is up to date the more precious
it is for managing your environment and
the more to mission you can put in it
the best is because that information is
correct it's coming directly from the
hardware you had one
sometimes okay so with regard to
security customers should never put a
PMC on the Internet
that's clear change customer now teach
to your customer teach to your customers
is really really a bad idea it will not
improve with IOT devices which are also
sometimes on the internet and all sort
of pmc somewhere I understand
so redshift protocol is HTTPS so you
need a notification mechanism to be able
to log on to the system so it's as
secure as your authentication schema is
from as you mentioned is an update for
example of that of version of BMC
firmware and and that's true and that's
I mean the BMC is should be managed like
a standard system so people should pass
their update on a regular base so should
automate that if possible this issue I
mean that's part of the CI environment
for managing it's as an operating system
you are upgrading your operating system
you have a workflow you have a approval
for a grade you have tests etc you do
you should do exactly the same for
management of the BMC's on your servers
because that's as critical as the rest
even if it's not on the Internet
[Music]
so comment is that their problems we'll
see software implementation on BMC so
the software stack use on BMC the fact
that it becomes obsolete and the fact
that it could be shared with some first
sneaked of the server see access to the
BMC I would say make test with your
hardware manufacturer before buying
hardware and includes test all the BMC
as part of your evaluation of the
platform there are good providers that
don't do that anymore that may use to do
that in the past but don't do that
anymore but I agree it's I mean redish
has not to solve those security issues
per se it's it's a way to do secure
management because it's unscripted and
it has an authentication mechanism
compared to ipmi which was really poor
or SNMP which is also a certain number
of other problems so it does not solve
the hunger in the world but it's all
some of the problem