hello everyone I'm really happy to see
you here this morning I'll talk about
reto sherry said the centralized
platform a retro sure we we have many
things implemented but this is
decentralized in a censorship and spam
resistant in a way that still guarantee
reality it's both an animus and
authenticated when you need one thing or
the other it's it's full of of crypto
inside so when when probably later you
will have a lot of question of for which
service what kind of encryption it use
and keeps working even if the internet
break so for example if you are in a
isolated part of Amazonia you could use
retro sure to communicate between
different tribes for one not that far
away you want from the other but you
could so a researcher is a friend to
friend network so basically this is the
local view that are not as of of the
network is basically in is friends and
if this friend give access to the
Friends of friends
still it can communicate also with
people that did that doesn't know where
they are located in the network and so
you can reach in any any participant of
the of the network let's let's run
through different mechanism one of them
is started routing so when you try to
establish communication with someone
that is far away from you the
information gets opened from node to
node 2 up to the destination node and
the node in the middle does not with the
origin of the message and doesn't know
with the actual destination and doesn't
know the content of the destination they
just know the last op before them and
the first op after them
and this is suitable for trust for any
kind of content being it lightweight
like text messages or EVs file or
whatever another system to expand the
communication beyond the the trusted
friends circle is the is general
exchange system is an a synchronous
messaging are synchronous information
propagation system so you can propagate
information toward nodes that are not
connected at the same time with you in
the network benefiting from the from the
friend to friend network so if there is
just one friend of you online that
information will be propagated to that
friend and then you for example go
offline because your electricity
finished and that friend will propagate
that that information to the next one
and and so on and as as it this this
mechanism is redundant and provides
storage is not very suitable for every
payload so for example if you transfer a
time series of off sensor that of four
gigabyte GCS is not the right tool this
is the turtle routing but you could use
this system to inform the order that the
data is available at your not for
example another things that we recently
added this deep search that through
taking advantage of a paean search
engine I'm really retro sure not that
index is it's data and metadata it's
content so when when you search on the
radar Network the the search band can
can investigate inside the content of of
course it's it's anonymous incidence
Allah addresses relies and so on
so we have this long-standing QT GUI you
probably saw this some time ago if
you'll reduce rather is an example
of file search there is no there is no
server boo index the file is every node
index its own files and and when
search request is made it every not
answer with the result if they have some
otherwise they don't and this is a
services we call channels it's used to
publish organize content through general
exchange system so for example you can
see those video are Creative Commons and
they are sorted because they are a
serious so you can access the world
series of those of those video with the
description a preview and then you can
download them from the or stream them
through the turtle to the turtle routine
so from the software tthe point of views
writer sherry scruff cross-platform as
independent core and user interface is
exist extensible through C++ in the
offer and API it sustainable through
JSON API extensible with runtime
laudable plugin so you for example you
can prepare your dot so
plug-in and the load it at runtime if
you need to action even more retro sure
and that's zero cost automatic
serialization and deserialization
framework it means that when you define
a new data type it's very easy to make
that datatype transmittable over network
or storable or visible to the json api
this is the the architecture of of the
json api so from one side you have
return share service or also the
readership GUI super did but let's use
register service inside it has a use
Liberator shell and rest bed and C++
side api is exposed through to http to
for example another hub that want to use
the decentralization and Krita graphic
features and anonymity feature of
writers that are already implemented to
expose a new a new kind of service
so the c++ ad json api are always
coherent because the json api is
generated from
starting from the C++ API so you will
never have a C++ API and JSON API will
be always feature pair you you will not
be penalized to be using JSON API
instead of C++ and also the types of
data you see in C++ are the same in
Jason because they are because of the
automatic serialization system they are
directly converted to JSON objects and
the other advantage it is that we write
just one documentation and it's valid
for the C++ API json api nor whatever
language you want to use so what
happened
this is method from the suppliers plus
API in the class login helper we have
this methodist get location this is a
method to return all your available
profile on that note as you can see it
the return type is void but it take as a
parameter a vector of locations and in
the in the documentation of the method
there is a description it's it's flagged
as exported on JSON API and also you can
you can see there is the parable
occasion is flooded as B as an output
parameter so you don't need to provide
that parameter when you called it method
but that parameter will be used to give
you the output and so ended and that is
a pointer to all the global instance of
that class less login helper so as you
can see that the type of the parameter
is a vector of locations okay
so let's explore this this type the type
location is defined like that this
relation is it inherited from Russ
serializable and inside of those members
location ID as PGP ID location name and
PGP name and then with this in this
method that's called serial process
those made those members are ready are
registered for serialization it means
that those members will be 100%
accessible from Jason and also from
beaner and so on and send the ball over
network and so on so what happens if we
want to access that method from from the
JSON API for example from from the shell
so there is the API they all wear the
API is listening that is on our machine
and then with the plain card call we
just call the method
it's a rest login alter and get location
and what JQ is just to practically in
the JSON output but you can avoid that
if you want and this is the output as
you can see we get the array of
locations and inside the array there is
a location that has an ID an ID a PGP ID
location name and the PGP name so your
experience using the JSON API is
completely coherent with the experience
of a developer using the C++ API
so let's the API of course is
authenticated otherwise any any program
running on your computer or your phone
that is more easy you have fishy finks a
stolid could access the API and stole
your favorite data so the cause most of
the calls of the API are authenticated
and you as you see you can you have API
token to access it and again you can
pass parameter through again with card
you just pass the parameter formatted in
Jason you are passing for example you we
are asking to the API to get an invite
for a friend to invite a friend and we
are passing the ID of the location of
the I invite through the JSON string and
and then just call the method address
appears get rate or share invite and as
the output we just get this this big
this big string that is just a basically
I'm the invitation so as as you know
Jason and HTTP we are pretty well
supported on almost any decent language
nowadays so you can do very very similar
thing from
you can do it from JavaScript on our web
page that's that's a an extract from our
experimental web interface for retro
sure and as you can see here this is the
the call to the JSON API it's just is
just an API request here the part of the
method and here we are pass we are
passing the JSON for the parameter we
are passing to the major and so you can
do almost with same easiness from from
any language it's always HTTP in JSON
and it's well-documented
very important so this is an example of
a chat application and experimental chat
application development of using
rhetoric JSON API for Android the DOS
those little faces are a very easy way
to have an approximative way of
verifying the fingerprint of the user so
it's very user friendly or so for people
that have no idea of Krita graphic
signature and so on they can just tell
to themselves the color they see in the
face and they almost verified their
fingerprint this is a new app that's
called repo repo dot IO that use JSON
API to create a service to share culture
and and curate and store and preserve
culture in the it's mainly used in place
where there is no very not good internet
connection so it take advantage of
community networks or when it's possible
register always use the local connection
instead of using internet by local I
don't mean just your Wi-Fi and your own
if you have you participate in a
community network like Fred funk or Biff
Annette or whatever all the other all
the nodes reachable inside the community
network that maybe all the nodes of your
city and so on or keep being reachable
inside graduation it doesn't need the NS
and so on and if someone
- took a picture of the of the solar of
the lunar eclipse in in January and
share it on the repo do and someone also
this picture of this spider and this
another example of size of report that
is an an app that use JSON retro share
JSON API so Yara this reducer is a free
software for a free society you are
welcome to contribute even on your spare
time or you can apply to for for some
grants to work on it for example to NLL
net like we did or someone Summer of
Code and and we will be happy to review
your pull request and assertive or
suggest modification if they are needed
and thanks if you have questions you're
welcome
of course leadership may may be used
also through tall and e to pee and other
anonymize network city list from high
the question is how do you manage to
make two notes to talk to each other
when they are netted I mean when the
Chumash scene are behind a nut
how do you do that okay the question was
how do you manage to have a connection
to a person that is behind the knot so
retro should implement values not hole
punching strategies so it it's always
trying to to punch hole through the nuts
so you may even take a direct connection
to someone behind the nut but if it's
not the case
it used the friends or friends that use
the front of your network to route
through to get to the other person that
is behind the nut so fully you always
get some trust note that is not behind
the nut and that will be instant
connection or otherwise you will have
will have this natural punching process
and also also a leadership support
connection through tour that has very
good mechanism to punch through nuts and
also its support ipv6 that doesn't have
all those problem with nuts because it
usually doesn't is not provide through
not but through public eye piece so is
the JSON API available for Androids or
does it use C++ and Jane ie or other
interfaces so the JSON API is available
on Android so does this application that
you saw
a screenshot all of Android phones and
there is the retro share service running
on Android and the app running on
Android too so the service is C++ but
it's compiled to native code then there
is a Android package that you istel and
then you can
well whatever app that does is talking
now tries by on the retro search service
can use the JSON API okay this is me
again the question is how do you manage
if no do you have the possibilities do
you have a multi device I mean can you
repeat I didn't understand do you have
the abilities to have a multi device
[Music]
yeah you can have multiple device they
they can share usually the PGP key so
your friend can recognize you but you
have different SSL key so they are
actual difference not but they are they
are capable of authenticated at the same
profile yeah you keep your friends
action yeah across device well if you
lose the device you're sorry so it said
if you lose your device you can rebuild
your network of course you can do you we
suggest to keep backup of your profile
but in case well the the PG peace
process is protected with with the
password so you can use a good password
but in case you are concerned and Eve
you are a bit paranoid but we suggest
create if you lose your device someone
may may may try to brute force your PGP
key N and take it so in that case
depending on your security needs you
could decide to restore it from a backup
or or create a new profile and tell to
your friend that your profile changed
no well if you do the backup yes if not
you you don't have your your content
back yeah well if you can subscribe to
forums and the things that you were
participating
before and your friends will pass you
again in the content but it's depend on
the service for your file probably you
have to look for them again and and so
on any more questions
so in case you lose your key there is
some way to ensure that your keys not
use militia they it well you
it's a PGP key so you can relocate it so
you could publish that the revocation
but then it's up to your friend to
update the PGP key database and and know
that he is relegated otherwise it's like
like any credit cryptographic key it
could they couldn't continue to be used
yeah you can publish its file actually
so there is not implemented yeah it
could be implemented yes yeah another
question do you think one more over
there
it would be possible if you keep it up
I'm sorry say if you have multiple
device it's possible to synchronize the
data between them it's possible actually
some services like forum if you are
subscribed from two devices the UC model
Mazda say it's possible but it's not
implemented yet in fact we have a
proposal for if you want apply for for
the Summer of Code or some other grants
to implement synchronization occur
across devices so we wait for for our
poll requests and and we'll be happy to
review it if there was no more question
you know of course the you can install
okay do you have some mechanism that you
can install the retro circle on a VPS
and then have your device yep running
just the graphical interface the answer
is yes you could just install the retro
service on any machine and then access
it through the JSON API thank you very
much if you have more questions feel
free to contact him free the valve and
also please for every talk you will
attend in fosston if you could leave a
constructive feedback on the website for
speakers and for room organizers it
would be great thank you