okay hello everyone so I appreciate that
you are here that late time my name is
sell stock off and I'm the author of our
spawn day open source spawn filtering
system and also I'm free busy developer
for more than 20 years in this talk I
will talk about one particular
integration of our spawn day in and
actually it's about integration of our
spawn day in freebsd email this talk
won't be about performance of our spawn
day because this release doesn't process
more than one millions of messages per
day and I consider this volume is very
low so I don't care about performance at
home so the the tasks whoa how to build
spam filtering because nobody likes spam
and especially nobody like spam in
mailing lists and because mailing lists
are the main source of information and
you hate to archives like spam messages
and so on and so forth so that's quite
important task and here are some
explanation about what was difficult so
let's start about this talk about
talking about the architecture FreeBSD
male so there are a couple of mixes and
I'll draw some sort of flows of mail
here so we have free fall we're all
developer account sleep and there are
also Alice's so email comes to M x1 and
it integrates with free fall to operate
a local email and then we have mailman
which operates WiMAX one and the mixture
is used for outbound spam for server for
outbound yes
[Applause]
spam is low then mx1 interoperates with
the mix to the next two can send back
and deliver us identifications for mx1
free fall can send email WiMAX to my
Imam can send emails to free fall for
local users and that's that was my
opinion about all the system so luckily
we have we had some sort of help of the
postmasters in particular forum calendar
and Kiril ponomaryov and they actually
built our spawn day in these complicated
mail flows I did just small adjustments
actually so the main problems of the
email architecture is that we have very
complicated man flows so there are many
release many aliases so lots of users
prefer to use something like Gmail
instead of using of local clients and
actually it complicates situation and
also email has very non-trivial circuits
so in some cases I could see like 16
received headers and for a single
message because it constantly ping-pong
between different relays and there are
lots of legacy decisions because freebsd
mail is almost as old as freebsd so lots
of decisions are from 90s when we had
something like UCP so the decision to
filter spam and some other stuff was to
add our spondee because I'm pretty busy
developer and I'm the author of our
Sunday and I suggested postmasters to
try this project because it's free and
open-source and to resolve our issues so
that some something about responding so
it has web interface that's not freebies
delay that's just by random relay and
internally it's represented as a
complicated system of different layers
it integrates with empty using Milton in
our case so they use POSIX and hence
we use milk in our consideration we
don't you separate proxy layer we
combine proxy in scum layer so it's it's
operating it operates in South can mold
and internally it uses different things
and actually all of them with the
exception of bias are used for now so we
use even neural networks I'll talk about
it a bit later because it's a bit tricky
topic so what problems we've tried to
resolve is ask from them so the first
one is actually spamming the mailing
list they don't like spam nobody likes
from another problem which was also
quite important was that we break became
signatures when they pass all member and
we wanted to do some sort of controlling
overall mail flows because we had
completely no understanding about how
mail those and how to make it better no
not this one so my personal motivation
was B was mainly to reduce amount of
spam in my mail client and actually
that's some of samples of messages that
have constantly received from FreeBSD
mailing lists and what's more important
I couldn't filter them because my
profile of a spawned a my own responded
local was so that actually mailing my
mails from FreeBSD lists are usually
trusted so the vast majority of emails
from FreeBSD lists are actually ham and
they're they have very low scope low
negative score and also FreeBSD relays
are listed in some of Dana's whitelist
so basically it simple is impossible to
use any are bills and other stuff
because they're hidden beyond their
freebies literally that's why I
constantly asked about let's let's
install responded let's install respond
and try to do something better because
my filter can filter these emails and
your filter cannot so now I still
receive some spam from freebies list
because actually we
currently quite cautious about rejecting
email but what you can see that there is
special symbol called spam flag it means
that they're really on freebsd marked
this message has junk and actually
respond they can recognize this and then
treat this email separately so this
email wasn't my junk folder luckily and
actually that's quite good so in in
future we plan to reduce project score
and to increase probably junk score to
filter more emails because currently
there's the profile of our today's
statistics so the vast majority of
emails are ham but actually these
statistics is a bit skewed because
basically our mailing lists on each
email that comes to mailing list we have
like 200 1000 of emails that are coming
out and actually because of this
complicated schema we we see this
messages many times and since we send
these emails to all our subscribers we
actually have situation when we might
multiply one hand message and send it
many times
obviously if message has been rejected
we don't send it to subscribers and
that's why this profile is a bit
difficult to understand because
basically it's not true that the vast
majority of emails are spam so sir
ah-hem because we have lots of spam but
due to this multiplication effects from
mailing lists we don't see this in this
stuff another problem of this statistic
is actually using of neural networks
because for neural networks they assume
that your traffic is somehow balanced so
it learns the model using half of
samples spam and half of samples of ham
and in this situation neural network is
also not very useful so this is also
quite a complicated topic
the plans for future are to improve
neural network in the way to reduce
number of the same training vectors
because currently just pushes everything
so if a message has high enough negative
score it just tells that let's learn
arithmetic from it actually that's not
quite a good decision especially for
this profile of traffic so we have
improved the situation with spam but
there are obviously areas to improve it
better now I'll talk about it a bit
later another problem that we resolved
this family is actually to sign messages
because in many cases we have the
following situation we have something
like Gmail or other Center and this
Center signs their messages using their
private key mailing lists are usually
modifying messages so they are adding
some sort of disclaimers
oh that these messages has been
delivered by some mailing list blah blah
blah
and that actually breaks the Kim
signatures what's worse is actually that
Gmail in particular rewrites sender
sorry sighing sender and sender is the
special email header that is always
rewritten by mailman and actually all
messages from Gmail have broken the Kim
signatures and this situation is not
very good because many users don't like
when their they receive messages that
are from some sort of untrusted sources
because you don't see anything good from
that so the trivial solution is actually
to add another team signature and
actually a spondee is used for this as
well obviously there are some obvious
solutions like open the Kim but in our
case we have responded so why not use it
for the Kim submission the Kim sign and
in this case all emails that are come
that come from FreeBSD are digitally
silent my freebies general
it makes some users happy actually there
is one thing here so currently we sign
all emails even if we decide that this
email is junk
we still sign it I think that should be
fixed at some point to not sign messages
that are not trusted and not edited that
I'll consider it as spam because it
doesn't make any sense to science spam
another technique is actually to use arc
so unlike dickham arc provides the way
how to organize chains of trust in
emails so in not show it looks like that
actually add special header actually
there are three headers and it surely
increase the special counter so
basically unlike the Kim's signature you
don't know when this relations are this
cygnus you can obviously much something
like something like received headers but
usually the received headers are not
sign it but the Kim for obvious reasons
because they are well they can be added
in any order for arc there are some
centers that are using arc in particular
Gmail then Yahoo and as far as I
remember Microsoft and Office 3 365 and
what's more important that all these
providers who are using arc they also
recognize arc so basically if you have
this became signature broken the message
still can be verified because there is
some transitory for instance through
busy relay that tells that this email
was successful before I modified it so
the idea here is that you can have
message and you can modify it because
you are like trust actually and you can
tell another lace that the initial
message has had like valid signature and
another lace if they trust you obviously
they can tell that ok I trust FreeBSD
and I know that rubies they won't lie
about the initial signature and I can
I can improve our sending experience by
adding this signature so that's how it
works
that is email that has been passed from
my domain to FreeBSD list and then it
was received by Gmail so Gmail actually
signed it one more time and in this case
you see that the I equal to means that
there is their third early on the way
and also there are authentication
results so you can see that the body
fresh from the originator is not
verified because it was broken by a
mailman but the are clarification and
became verification afterwards who was
successful and actually it helps to
interoperate with email services
providers and it probably helps to
improve delivery basically so what are
issues is signing the main problem again
is that we can see messages many times
so in some cases we can see some a
single message on mix one like three or
four times yes and accordingly we need
to enable and disable signing and checks
because we have seen this message and
that that's not done actually that we
should not sign spam so if we decide
that this message is spawned we should
stop the signing process and proceeded
without signatures because well it's
stupid so that's how it's it's resolved
in responding so there is a small
snippet so all configuration is stored
in local D folder so we don't modify any
venule configurations that's the
recommended way how to configure our
spondee because all the time when i have
bug reports in many cases users are just
modifying vanilla config and don't know
how to
deal with that great and that's the way
how it should be done so here we just
defined some rules and enable and
disable some symbols according to their
path when we see this message so for
instance we don't add multiple the Kym
signatures that's quite important
because otherwise if we see this message
multiple times if you add multiple
signatures from the same domain the one
of these signatures won't be valid
that's the idea that's not true for arc
by the way yes
that's not missing the Kim's signature I
mean yes I know but the question here is
that from the perspective of ESP it
depends because invalid the Kim's
signature means that your Demark
verification if you have some sort of
democracy can be totally failed and if
you have no the Kim's signature
well I've implemented many Demark I've
implemented the marker nurse from D and
I know that well RFC tells treated in
this way but actually sometimes it
shouldn't be treated in this way because
basically if you receive message these
broken the Kim's signature or without
the Kim's signature from people oh yeah
you're right so I'm just telling that
the same thing that you know was sorry
but in this case it just ensures that
you don't have two signatures because
one of that signatures will be valid and
another will be not valid arc works in
this situation but the Kim doesn't so
now so what about what we want to do
actually because well currently we have
very we have working prototype but there
are still ways how to improve it so
first of all we have a big pain point
now so there is a special script on
freefall that sends email for developers
and unfortunately these scripts adds
this disclaimer just after motive
message and as far as you see it's my
message in my message you cannot do it
because in my message you need to
improve to insert the Sigma Sheen's
inside of mine parts and actually if you
have multi-part alternative parts you
need to insert the signature into both
text and HTML and that's actually not
easy because there are many situations
when you need to insert the signature in
the right place and that's why I've
decided that it could be a good transfer
from there because I can modifiers from
day so let's again some work-in-progress
project that can modify message and it
knows about multi-part messages it can
insert signatures for text for HTML
parts it knows how to deal with the
sense it knows how to deal with 7-bit
encoding it knows how to deal with
quoted-printable UTF and so on and so
forth so it's pretty much sophisticated
it also kind of the right subject
because in some cases you need to do
this so literally it can do things that
are typically done in male form but this
list is special it's not done in male
man so that's what we want to do and
also we think about including here
became signatures as well so every
mailing list should be signed so this
part is also missing now so we don't use
boys and statistics and that's actually
bad because basically it's good to have
personal bias for our users we have lots
of developers who are good enough and
who are eager to train their spam filter
and who can do the spam filtering better
unfortunately it won't work for
everybody because all people have
different preferences and the generic
idea is actually quite simple so we plan
to have art like generic bias that will
be used for everybody's with some sort
of generic training purposes
and on top of it there should be some
sort of personalized statistics it's
it's it can be implemented in the
respondus so it stores everything in
Redis and it can actually check first of
all one thing and then another and
adjust things according to the to users
preferences so that's one of the biggest
plan that we have also we want to
present better statistics because this
one is from my spam trap it's not from
FreeBSD but we want to have something
similar for FreeBSD to view how many
messages we received to you how many
things we are sending to view popularity
of mailing lists and so on and so forth
so this is done by a project called
click house and this is both from it
called redish so basically it also works
almost out of the box the only specific
for bsd is actually that this system is
linux more linux oriented so probably it
will require some sort of many or
modifications it is written and go but I
suppose it should look
click house itself has been ported to
FreeBSD so if you want corner and
database with lots of analytical
features and very high performance
instruments or each you can check like
house its Porter to FreeBSD also you can
do some sort of analytics so it's if you
like
so actually that's all it was we're a
short talk about how they integrate
respond day in FreeBSD my goal was not
to describe lots of things about our
spondee because I can talk about this
for very long time and in this
particular presentation I wanted to
explain this
practical implementation so if you have
any questions so we can just use these
aliases as Mariners from there as map so
it's possible to read it as fresh and
then well like so we can just add
additional LSS for learning that's how
it's done so basically you can just tell
something like learn spam there's some
specific key that is available for
developers and we would just accept this
message and learn as spam for him for
just for him yes that's that's a
complicated question because basically
we have false positives all spam
filtering system has false positives and
if you reject that he won't see it and
in many cases unfortunately there are
too many broken centers who won't react
to the SMS and that's actually real life
and very is actually to sign it and to
leave it on users consideration probably
we do some sort of statistical mistakes
so we can relearn this message as ham
and we are done if you reject it we
cannot do anything
the only alternative to this is somehow
current illness but containing
personally supports containing but
postfix requires additional demon as far
as I remember to do containing so that's
why we just add flag and tell our users
that just use this flag to mark this
messages as spam in you see rules
that's all that's possible yes that's
possible but we plan to reduce reject
score but we don't want to reduce it
like to gray level so there will be
there will be definitely some sort of
gray zone obviously we are trying to
reduce this gray zone as well but
currently we have two hijacked right
threshold if you reduce reject threshold
this problem should be resolved because
nobody would reduce reputation for gray
mail that's great
so what does so internally respond this
text is decoded so this code is
operating with decoded parts and
actually for text parts it's recommended
to use quoted-printable in any case so
that's general recommendation and those
from the justin calls and
quoted-printable forgetting about the
original encoding why do so because
first of all if we have a bit encoding
it doesn't make any sense because many
relays doesn't support a bit encoding by
default so they don't announce it and
what should we do actually with 8-bit
encoding sending it via this race so
8-bit is not an option
base 64 is done by some well I would
have said broken esps but actually many
people are sending text in base64 but
actually it adds lots of overhead so the
only sane solution from my point to you
is just to encode everything in
quoted-printable and furthermore it
encodes everything in either f8 so if
the original according was like
something like we ate that - our it
should record at utf-8 that's limitation
but unfortunately I don't have to
support all these Zoo open callings
because some open coatings are
absolutely brain-damaged to tell the
truth
yes it will record it you there but it
works for Jeff eight so that's the point
of the point here actually in G be
something and chief G's you can encode
periodic lattice as well so they're full
único compatible but again that's what
I'm talking about
well it depends but the only solution
for this problem for this particular
problem is actually arc I don't see any
resolution about how to fix broke and
Demark when you have to do it because of
like standards for instance you need to
write this gdpr node I think everybody
knows about that but you have to do it
and you have to break change a sender or
hain't Rob yes that's not option but
send rewriting is actually is something
that also quite difficult to implement
properly doable doable but
[Applause]