Thanks
hello my name is Anne my name is Andrea
Frisco and I will talk about Russ vmm
and how can that help you into building
your own custom vmm so this is my first
time at FOSDEM well actually my second
time giving a presentation and I heard
that the first thing that you have to do
is introduce yourself if in case you are
wondering this is a failed attempt at
reproducing my github profile page I'm
super excited about open source this is
my current focus at Amazon where I am a
software development engineer I'm a
maintainer at firecracker and also
contributor at trust human but before
getting into details about what either
of these things are let me start with a
simple analogy so let's say that we want
to build a motorcycle the first step is
to gather the requirements and getting a
pretty clear idea of what we want to
build next we will just break it into
tasks and thinking about the components
that we need from our motorcycle but
then we so realize that this is actually
going to take a lot of time so can we
use something that already exists and
the answer is yes because I wouldn't
have asked the question otherwise so we
can use a car everybody is using the car
we know that a car is great people have
used it in other projects as well so it
must be perfect for our use keys now the
car is too complex so we just start
removing the components that we do not
need and we soon face a serious problem
so the car the motorcycle will fell down
so we have to add some weight to balance
it which means that we patch it a bit
next we argue at the end of our project
and we compare what we want you to build
with what we actually built and we are
not really satisfied with the result so
even though the car was super great our
motorcycle
is not ideal now we naturally ask
ourselves is there a better way to build
this and of course there is now we can
build this from scratch but that takes a
lot of time so moving to the technical
side of the talk this is similar to what
Cruz VM did about two years ago instead
of using an existing vmm they decided to
build their own vmm as a lightweight
their memory turning rust Christian runs
on top of KVM and it is used for
providing application isolation in
chromium OS moving a bit in time about
more than one year ago we decided to
build fire cracker we also wanted the
lightweight vmm that can boot very fast
and that it that has a low memory
footprint and that is because we want to
build fire cracker for short lift and
multi-tenant workloads now fire cracker
was also supposed to run on top of KVM
and we started our design process and we
analyzed the options that we have we
decided to go with rust because it's a
system language it's a language that
offers memory safety concurrency safety
and also it has performance that is
similar to modern C++ now after some
digging we discovered cross VM and we
decided to start our work from there now
even if firecracker was developed
what started as a fork of cross VM the
project's almost instantly diverged and
that is because they have really
different customer use cases so Chris VM
as I said is providing Linux it's
providing isolation for Linux
application in chromium OS which means
that you could potentially run for
example Photoshop in your Chromebook and
for running Photoshop it would actually
make a whole lot of difference in having
features like GPU and PCI now fire
cracker is used for some other things so
it is powering
AWS forget and the AWS lambda and it is
is run its it is running in the cloud
environment at scale which means that we
added features that could make us
operate it easily like metrics but we
also have rate limiting for block
devices and for network devices and we
also have a feature by which the guest
can query information about the micro VM
that is running in which is mmds now
they are different we talked about it
but still there are some common
visualization components so because they
are both built on top of k vm they have
dkv MAPI wrappers they have block device
and network device so they have a
similar implementation of the
specification and because they are both
like 2 8 micro vm micro VMS well the
events they have a minimal kernel loader
and there are some other components as
well so basically if we are going back
to the analogy with which I started the
presentation we are now having two
motorcycles but if somebody wants to
build a third motorcycle there is no
good way to do that so basically they
would have to either for one of the
projects or start from scratch and
actually this is where raske Menn comes
into place and one of the reason why it
exists res vmm is an open-source project
it started about two months ago it's
very fresh and it is a place for sharing
common visualization components if
you're wondering why would you actually
want that well the first obvious reason
is that it would be actually very easy
for a firecracker in cross VM to share
common virtualization code but since we
are here and I can ask you why would you
actually care about that because maybe
you wouldn't unless you were working
from one of the project and now the
answer is you should care about it
because brass vmm is going to do much
more so we trus vmm you can create your
custom via MEMS and that is because it
is thought with modularity and testing
in mind so for example let's say that
you want to build a VM M that is before
kubernetes that means that this VM is
going to be fully compatible with the
runtime interface and also it will have
features like memory hot plug and CPU
hot plug and host file system sharing
which is something that for example in
firecracker we don't have a really good
use case to add it so far there are some
people that are involved or we aren't
many people this is a call for you to
get involved as well people have
contributed code people have
participated in discussions we have a
feedback process by which we are adding
components into Rizvi mmm so people have
also provided reviews if you want to
help it is as simple as becoming a rusty
mmm member on github you just have to
open a new issue in the community
repository then if you want to
participate in the discussions there is
an email list and if you have an idea
about the component that could be a good
fit for res vmm you can write it then
then open a review requests and people
will look at it now you might get a talk
is over but it's not
and there are two reasons for that
so one is try just tidy the slides two
days ago
and the other reason is that we are
going to talk about what's next so what
is in the future there are some
discussions ongoing about the adding the
host user user space implementation for
the host in norrisville then there are
also some discussions around porting qme
components which I actually find the
very interesting but the feature is not
set in stone and it is an ideal time for
you to come and decide with us the talk
is still not over and we are going to
go over an example of a vmm that you can
build with components of raspbian and
this this light is actually here because
with the current stage of rusty mm you
can't really build anything because we
don't have enough crates there or
components so we are going to build a
minimal vietnam it's not exactly minimal
it is more to prove a point of the
structure of rusty mm so our V mm is
going to run on top of KVM so we will
have need some KVM wrappers then we will
need a kernel loader a block device for
our root filesystem and the user
interface the first thing that we are
going to do is write DV mm user
interface this is basically the place
where an external client let's call it
is going to configure the VM that wants
to that that wants to run now next we
are going to look at the future Rizvi mm
component so before getting into details
about what these things are
let's talk a bit about structure each
box on the right side of the screen it's
a crate or a package in rust packages
are called crate so that was my first
slide sharing crates virtualization
crate now each crate can have 0 1 or
many modules and this is for example the
vertical devices which has a block
device a net desoky and serial each
structure in a module now there is an
interesting feature about that rust
there is an interesting thing that rust
helps us with now instead of for example
you want to use just the block device
and instead of importing all the code
you can import only the block device by
using features which basically means
that it's actually just a conditional
compiling now let's get them one by one
so
eeehm bindings is actually
auto-generated code with binding it is a
Russ foreign function interface to the
KDM headers but these are not very
useful by by themselves because it's
basically just defines and structures
now on top of that we can build the KVM
wrapper which actually has
implementation wrappers over ioctl
scabiei maya CTLs which can help us in
doing stuff like opening def KVM
creating the VM also creating V CPUs and
so on next we have vertical bindings
which are similar to KVM only that they
are auto-generating for from vertol
headers and we have the implementation
for the Verta specification in de verte
i/o devices that i talked about earlier
next we have a kernel loader the kernel
loader is minimal it just loads the
kernel image in the guest memory a rate
limiter that can be applied on the
vertices to limit operation per second
and the bandwidth and also the B host
user now we said that our VM M is going
to be minimal so we are just going to
select some of these and because these
components are actually independent in
some in some way we can't just dump them
into our VM m and everything works we
will have to also add a vm m blue that
is basically responsible for interacting
with the VMS and also making the
connection to the vm m user interface so
people can actually start VMS with our
minimal vm m now there is only one thing
to do
we have to profit and that was all this
is really the end of the talk the first
link you have is the rest vm m
organization on github next if you click
the link on this slide the second link
it will take you to the SUBSCRIBE page
for the rest vmm email
and the last one is my my email address
so if have any questions that you do not
want to ask now you can send me an email
and I will be more than happy to help
you thank you yeah so the question was
if on the first do you mean this one so
the question was whether these crates
are already available on crate i/o so
the thing is that the only thing that we
actually have in respira
now is the crate KVM bindings this is
already available on free tayo as well
and we are using it in firecrackers so
it's it's working all the others we have
to we have to add them we so the
follow-up question was if we reserved
the names no we didn't and the answer
was vicious yeah so the question was if
we have plan to if we plan to add armed
support so we started with KVM bindings
it has support for arm so the bindings
are generated for arm as well and the
plan is actually for the crazy that I'm
adding there to have support for both
x86 and arm and I'm actually working
with one of my colleagues to do this for
DK VM wrappers
what okay so I don't have a the question
is if we are going to add support for
other architectures as well if I can't
do that by myself obviously because I'm
a 26 and don't you actually know all
those architectures by name yes yeah
this is different so well because you
can conditionally conditionally compile
everything that means that you can add
support for many platforms and it should
be okay for most people because if they
don't want your code they will just not
pull it in yeah it is a common
foundation we are oh oh so the question
was if this is a common foundation and
if we are working it cross Veeam so I
just want to make something clear this
is not fire cracker so this is not a
product owned by a company in it's not a
product of its own it's really just a
place to share common virtualization
components between many VMs so we can
build them in the same word in the same
way yeah the question is if we can't
create non rust rust vmm on top of it
and I've don't really know how to answer
that question probably for languages
that allow you to call code that is not
rust maybe I I really don't know how to
answer that sorry
so the question was if we are going to
replace cream.you components with
components from Rossi mmm and there is
actually some discussion about it on the
recipe mmm email list you should join it
as well so you can participate in the
discussion so I think that that's the
plan yep
that's it
[Applause]