hi man my name is Russell Agarwal I work
for Citrix on Zen and Zen sir and I'm
going to be talking about implementing
secure B's there is no audio so I'm
going to be talking about secure boot on
Zen so I'll briefly go into some
background about it and why it's useful
so secure boot is basically a way of
preventing malware from running at boot
so the worst kind of the worst thing
that can happen is malware sort of
affects the bootloader or operating
system kernel image and once it's got to
that point you can basically in the
system I mean this could happen from
like a rogue update or something so
there are a number of ways that it could
happen but one way of preventing it is
to use secure boot so it's the firmware
basically has a way of trust working out
where the image is trusted or not and
preventing you from booting untrusted
images so this works well if you've got
real hardware and but if you've got a VM
in the cloud for example like running
Xen unfortunately it doesn't support
security at the moment so what can you
do about it
so just on some background secure boots
is actually part of the UEFI
specification just added in version 2.3
that one and this is basically a
replacement for the bios which the firm
eight sort of starts the operating
system and provide some services to it
so the first thing to notice is that
well if we're running if we want to use
secure boot then we need to be using uef
our guests luckily is then does support
you if our guests are ready so there's
nothing for us to do
it makes use of ivmf which is kind of
like the build of the tiyanak or
open-source ufr implementation tailored
for virtual machines not the way that
UEFI starts kernel or bootloader is kind
of different from if you used to buy us
a super-earth bios basically it chooses
a disk to boot and starts executing from
the MBR at the beginning of the disk
with UEFI
the firmware knows how to understand GPT
partition tables and fat file systems
and so it's configured to boot a
particular file of a particular file
system and this is sort of quite a lot
like how an operating system would start
some executable that it knows about now
when you turn on secure boot there's an
extra step basically before executing
that file it verifies whether the file
is trusted and can be executed so how
does this work so hardware has nvram
which is kind of like non-volatile
storage separate from the main disk and
these store UEFI variables which are
kind of like key value pairs and some of
them are contained certificates there
are a number of them and I won't go into
the details of what they mean but
essentially the bootloader or kernel
that you executing needs have been
signed by one of these so-called trusted
certificates and therefore if the kernel
is replaced with something else the
firmware will refuse to start it because
it hasn't been signed properly the
certificate databases themselves can be
populated in a number of ways one of
them which is probably the most common
is just that the factory installed the
certificates are loaded into the NVRAM
and it just works because the laptop of
whatever comes preloaded with an
operating system and so if you're
running Windows it'll come with the
Microsoft certificates and if you want
you can update the certificates in the
database so these databases are called
authenticated variables and they require
to update it you make a sort of runtime
call called set variable but this update
needs to be signed by specifically one
of the certificates that's already in
the database and so more wire can't sort
of click it's it can't trick itself into
being trusted by inserting its own
certificates in the database unless it
concerned the update in which case it
could sign the bootloader anyway the
third way is typically there's like a
platform specific reset method so on
real hardware you would say press f2
during boot and with physical access
reset the certificates too or clear them
for a VM typically the way I implemented
it on Xen was just then the hypervisor
or specifically dom0 there'd be some
button that you can press or command to
run and you can clear the database for a
VM so if you look at how this is
implemented on real Hardware kind of the
most important thing is that the code to
updates that's all the set variable code
which handle and firmware which handles
updating those certificate databases
needs to be protected from being sort of
interfered with because if malware could
interfere with this code and some are
circumvent the checks then it would be
possible to just insert your own
certificates or if it could write
directly to the
then it's a problem so there needs to be
aware of protecting the code that's
running but it's kind of just yeah it
runs on the same CPU that's executing
the other code which you know it could
be some sort of rogue device driver
that's running as part of the operating
system so it needs to be a way of sort
of defining an extra level of privilege
or execution context and on x86
processors this already exists in the
form of something called system
management mode or SMM for short so this
is kind of something that's you can jump
into and execute code from a special
section of Ram called SM Ram which is
hidden from the rest of the system so
the sort of security sensitive part of
the firmware is placed in that sm ram
and the NVRAM is configured in a way
that it can only be written from within
an SM M so making a variable updates
then requires doing an SMI and then
there are traps into this system
management mode and in theory it's
secure at least in theory
so KVM has implemented secure boot
the way the approach that they took kind
of it virtualizes what real Hardware
does so qmu emulates some flash memory
which is the envy ram and KVM emulates
system management mode for guests and it
kind of implements or reuses parts of
the IANA core firmware for the SMI
handling and the way that it jumps into
the sort of SMM parts of the firmware
and so there's a interesting talk by
Apollo
about implementing this and KVM sir
I won't get into too many details cuz
I'll probably get them wrong so how
should this be implemented on then on
Zen so they're kind of lots of
vulnerabilities against SMM mode because
it's kind of tricky the way that it's
implemented and so they're lots of ways
of attacking it yeah all sorts of cache
attacks and the previous talk I
mentioned about implementing it on KVM
also details some of these attacks in
additions and does not have any support
for emulating SMM so implementing it
would require well could introduce more
bugs at least until they I and out
thirdly the using emulated flash kind of
limits the flexibility of how variables
are stored because the code that writes
the rights of the flash is stored in its
well it's part of the firme which runs
inside the guest so this is kind of okay
for regular hardware but from VMs we
want to be more flexible because you
want to be able to import vm's export VM
migrate them from two different hosts so
it'd be useful if you could have
something that was a bit more flexible
so with virtualization there are kind of
already two distinct privilege levels or
execution context you know broadly
speaking the guest and the hypervisor
so using SMM is but not really needed to
create this boundary or separation so
what we propose is to run a demon in
dom0 which what was then would be dom0
essentially part of the hypervisor that
implements the variable services outside
of outside of the guest itself and then
add a new module to ovm F which
implements the variable services by
essentially proxying them to the demon
that's running in dom0
so they're about four or five different
variable services that it does this for
so this means that the guest does not
have direct access to the code so it
doesn't need to make use of the special
SM Ram it doesn't have direct as to the
access to the storage so that isn't
anything specifically needed for the
flash emulation and it means that the
variable storage can easily easily be
abstracted into different backends so
you could use an SQLite database or
zappy database or just flat files kind
of whatever you need to use to get the
situation done so I'll just talk about
how this works in a little bit more
detail with an example so let's suppose
that operating system wants to make a
update to a one of the certificate
databases by adding a new certificate so
it would do this by calling the set
variable call which is a runtime service
it's sort of a bit like a system call to
the firmware or an sort of indirect
function call and it would send the new
data and sort of assigned authentication
descriptor which is needs to be signed
by one of the existing certificates in
the database so this goes into the proxy
module in ivmf which we write called
which we call Zen variable and it finds
the set variable handler there and so
that basically has some memory which had
set aside and it's serializes the
function called parameters into this
separate memory and then makes an i/o
port right
and to a well-known port number with the
address of that memory
this causes the demon in Don's area to
wake up which we called Vasco D and it
so so it handles the IO port right from
the guest that's basically unser
realises the the function call that's or
it Maps the memory from the guest uncie
realizes the contents of it and works
out which command to run in this case
it's the set variable 1 so it calls the
state variable function and this then
proceeds with the regular behavior of
state variable and all the various
authentication checks and if it's a
successful call which in this case let's
say it is then it stores it in the zappy
database which could be anywhere for
example it could be on a another host
even once this has happened the response
is then written back into the memory map
buffer and so it BEF our success just a
simple status code for this that returns
from the i/o port right which then
causes the guest to continue executing
and Xen variable module basically uncie
realises the uncie realizes the response
and returns back to the operating system
so there's kind of a clear separation
between what happens in the half of oz'
and what happens in the guest which
makes it quite easy to analyze from a
security perspective
so just to yeah go for that so we wrote
a demon called fast or T which
implements this and at the moment
there's a single back-end which is the
zappy database which is used on
XenServer but it's kind of written in a
way that makes it easy to use other
backends and then there's a ov EMF
module called Zen
which implements this sort of proxy and
but we've got it working on Zen at the
moment and so you can implement secure
it built and tested with both Linux and
Windows guests I believe it could be
used with KVM without too much
difficulty due to the fact that I mean
nothing in it is rarely is then specific
so this could be a different approach
yes mmm it's also not really a platform
specific implementation so SMM is kind
of tied to the x86 platform as far as I
understand
whereas this okay it uses an i/o port
right but that the same sort of approach
should be used on any platform so I've
got a demo video which I didn't want to
do it live since it seemed a bit risky
but so what I'm going to do here is
start a VM this is running on XenServer
and it's booting up and you EFR and at
the bottom writers they console.log for
fast OD which is essentially logging the
runtime service request that vast OD is
handling on behalf of the guest so you
can see various get and set variable
commands I'm just going to check that
the kernel reports that it has been
booted securely so Linux reports that
secure boot is enabled I think it's a
bit small to see the back bit the video
is online if you want to look at it
afterwards so what I'm going to try here
is modifying the bootloader what's the
firmware execute and in a way that would
not ordinarily cause it to what it
should still boot afterwards but because
the signature is different it's going to
well the firmware should refuse to boot
so I've just written FOSDEM 2019 to
the very first string in the program
then the vm's
then restarted and if all goes well the
firmware will stop and not beat the
operating system so this is a trivial
example but it kind of shows what
yeah if Norway tried to somehow patch
the kernel and it's not very clear but
that's the UVF our way of showing that
it didn't be which is not exactly the
greatest user experience but it's
possible to then run the command
manually or execute the bootloader
manually and you can see it says
security violation which means that a
secure boot is doing its job so that
just leaves when will it be available
unfortunately it's not yet been publicly
released and so we intend to release it
shortly and it'll be announced on the
Zen mailing list so if you're interested
please look out for it there and that's
the end of what I've got to say are
there any questions
the question was how does it relate to
chemo and how does it work with emu and
stub domain so at least as we've
implemented it it's a separate demon
that's completely separate 4qe from
Kimmi
so then has support for they call irx
servers which and you can have them in
separate programs essentially so it's
kind of not related at all and if Q
isn't a stub domain then this demon
could be anywhere else including in a
stub domain as well yes
yes so the question was have working
code for the certificate and
authentication stuff
the answers yes so the demo that I
showed was kind of all all working so I
can just repeat what she said yeah yeah
yeah that's implemented so I didn't
didn't have a demo of that because it's
I mean not really much to demo
you mean the implementing time I mean
it's it's kind of a few thousand lines I
don't think it's not super intense to
write kind of also developed a test
fairly extensive test suite for it
because it is quite complicated yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah so I mean that is
kind of the disadvantage of this
approach is that it has to duplicate
some of the code that's already been
implemented in ivmf but I mean it's not
it's a few thousand lines of C code so
it's not yeah
well I mean it it Maps the memory but
then copies it out of the it copies it
out of the memory that it's not before
it uses it so I don't know what you mean
about how how else would it get it if it
didn't matter yes ma'am
so Kristen was basically house sick the
question is how is the security of a
study handled because it's running in
Dawn's area so it's kind of an extra
attack surface so at least for how we've
implemented it on XenServer specifically
it runs kind of sort of it with no
privileges in a sort of container
environment and so even if you could
escape into dom0 should well it should
be contained yeah and you can't really
escape out of that extra Jail kind of
thing it's Kristin at the back yes that
would be so the Kristin was can you run
the Dom's aribert in a stub domain so
that would be the answers yes that would
be another approach to reduce what
removing any potential security risk of
running it so yeah either within a jail
or cut some kind of stub domain it's a
separate innocent is there one bastardy
for every domain the answers yes
it's the separate instance kind of like
the way you get a separate team you for
each domain so times up you can find me
afterwards if you want to ask any other
questions thank you
you