okay and okay so maybe this should we
have been the part of a retro computing
track because it goes as bad as far back
as 1968 when these draw might send a
memo talking about I'll go to his bad
and why we should avoid it and the memo
was then redistributed by any Kasparov
under the name go to consider harmful
and that's all like the original floors
of the consider harmful price ok so
what's wrong with the go-to in the first
place do you have to get some context
like you can put it in different ways
but this particular way of putting it is
I've shamelessly stole from from
National Smith wrote a nice nice blog
post about it and it goes like this like
this is a program in 4matic which is the
predecessor of COBOL and it's an
unstructured language so as you see
there are no loops and nothing it's not
it's not even a invent it and you see a
lot of jumps there so you look at a
program and you have know why you like
what's going on and then you start
drawing like arrows like how the control
flow looks like and it's like this so
you look at it and you have no idea
what's going on so what's wrong with
that
you have different like constructs like
if for whatever and go to and some of
them are good some of them are bad and
how the hub should be know like which
ones are good and which ones are bad and
one thing one way of thinking about it
is let's say the contract is good if the
control flow starts in the top and then
it ends up in the bottom and if you look
at all those contracts contracts like
all of them have you have is nice
property that it just goes from the top
to the bottom if you do if block it can
do if
our Lord else part but eventually
they'll arrive in the bottom and same
for for or function call or just
sequential sequence of commands but not
so far go to four four go to it just
jump somewhere and it never returns it
never reaches the bottom of the of the
codebook so we like to believe that the
functions are black boxes maybe we call
a function and the function will
eventually returns like nice and then
easy easy to reason about so we have a
main function it called function foo
which then calls function bar but
eventually it will return from bar and a
return foo and it's also nice for for
encapsulation because main doesn't have
to know that holds bar because like you
change the implementation it called
something else you don't care it's still
written heiress back but try to use a go
to somewhere and suddenly the does not
know that's not longer a case right it
just somewhere in the nested function
you jump somewhere else never to return
and now here we have developer Bob who's
like very cautious he doesn't use an
egotist
but he happens to use the library
written by by Alice who is very cautious
as well she doesn't use any go-to but
she uses a library written by Colleen
who is Carlos and who uses go-to
and suddenly Bob is heard by that
because like Dao inside the dependency
three just flow control flow
just somewhere else and Bob's function
function called foo - foo never returns
like all the assumptions he had about
his code unbroken so this is kind of
it's not only like bad design it's bad
design pass pass because it's transitive
like it takes only one dependency in
your whole dependency tree and you're
screwed so so what I was talking about
was the old kind of go to that probably
not many people here really remember
that we're like the big bad go to which
could jump around the codebase like from
a function to a different function and
you don't see those anymore right there
so and but it's actually not that the
long long ago when I started programming
in 1984 I've got Sinclair ZX Spectrum
and it had like built-in basic and it
actually looks very much like the flow
Matic code I've shown before there go to
solar over on the place and it just said
you jumped around so you don't see this
anymore
but what we have now is this kind of
thing domesticate if you go to which you
can jump only inside a function right so
that's the go-to in C oh my good
you can jump inside a function but
there's no way to jump out so it's still
bad but it's it's at least no transitive
right so the cone of the Corinne that
the developer of a nested nasty
dependency can really break your
overflow okay so now that I've explained
the hole I could go to think like from
50 years ago what does it have to do
with modern programming thing and I'm
coming from the network in background
time or author of 0 mq and I've made
several networking libraries and the
problem that occurs all the time is how
to handle a synchronous calls basically
alright so so this is what you have one
wire that there is a byte saying that
the the following field is going to be
13 bytes long and then you have the
actual data and how are we going to
process that
so the old-school way of doing that was
like classic unix way where you launch
and process for each connection and the
process were not nice and sequential and
it just read this write that and that
was it but then people realize that the
launching process per connection is
probably not good thing because it's
slow and things a lot of resources so we
have to do better and so the fred's verb
and know the interesting thing is about
Fred's is you can't really fire find out
like who invented an but they're
probably the person was like too ashamed
okay so so what we have to deal with
nowadays is this kind of thing we have
this asking function which loops like a
function but it's not not really a
function of it because you would expect
it to do whatever is inside the block
and then return as a normal function but
it doesn't if the returns immediately
and then at some later point the dicing
part is is done so if you just look at
these men naively as if this was a
normal function you would expect it
should print one and then to bring free
and then between five and four and two
but actually what you have is one two
and that's this part is executed three
four and then five so it's very and yeah
and it gets even worse in JavaScript
there basically that those functions are
anonymous and nested inside the code and
this looks like a normal stress fracture
code but it's it executes in very
different ways so the the layout of the
program has basically nothing to do with
the order of execution right so what
what you see here is 1 3 5 4 2 was
printed out is 1 2 3 4 5
I guess well okay the other option to do
it in a plastic state machines very very
remember like a what state you are in
and variable and well this is at least
explicit about what God is doing so you
go you are in this state so you switch
to a different state you grow launch a
sinkhole and at some later point the
function schools again with the reading
done message and other part of the same
machine is executed but you know you
look at his coat rack it's terrible and
this is the one slide but if you look at
the real implementation it's like pages
at page
of this kind of stuff no nobody can
really electro spit to that first side
so then enter go enter a Google rank so
the nice thing about going is that it
introduced
co-routines as a firm was first class
citizen and you are back to the old
unique style programming where a very
basic elantra process for each
connection and it's nice and sequential
except it's not the process is the core
routine which means it's cheap my god
this tag is at the beginning like two
kilobytes and the context which is
pretty quick like 20 nanoseconds or
something so okay so it seems that we
are done but what's wrong with the go to
we've go contract watching of Quran T
coroutine you see it kind of looks like
the old go because it's in one way it
just continues but in the background
somehow the control flow just jumps away
some different function it's it's very
similar to go in a way so and you have
the same problem as the VB had before so
once again Bob launches the core routine
from Alice's library the vigilance is a
call from calling library and calling
them does go and launch is a core
routine which is running in the
background and the core returns to to
Bob's code and Bob things okay the the
barfing is done but they're sexually
currently running a background and bob
has no idea
so it's transitive again like if any of
your dependencies launch is a go routine
in the background you have the old
program from fifty years ago we've you
know this viral to go that big bad go to
so how easy is it to fix so one would
say okay let's make let's make a routine
scope right so we have a scope if you
launch a quarantine and we're going to
be get to the end of the scope the
quarantine will be canceled and that's
it except that that doesn't really work
because mmm look here it is the class
cold enough wrinkles we have a server
except connections and each connection
is handled by a handler which is a
separate coroutine but if it was
canceled at the end of the block
well it would be actually canceled
immediately and ah nothing would happen
so that's not good enough
so what we really need is like two
different different kind of scopes one
is like the normal scope and one is like
extent the better scope which cancels
order coroutines that the wrong that
were launched inside it all right so
this is in C this is this is code using
a library that I wrote called video and
basically you see that the two scopes
here there is a faint
bundle it's a bundle of coroutines you
initialize it there in in the vial
you allow any any number of core
routines inside it and once you want to
shut down your server or something you
jump out of the loop here with the break
and you close the bundle and that
cancels all the core qualities so it's
kind of you see it's indented like no
nicely structured so there are several
languages that implement it is like this
is in Python library court trial bit
which does the pretty similar thing
except these nicest so you open nothing
the corner nursery which is the same as
the bundle in previous example and yeah
you basically do the same thing you
launch routines and once you get out of
the blow of the Dead block or the
co-routines are canceled so is that it
is that is it easy so there are there
are some open problems here it says we
are not the other like for example that
there is a difference between how little
handles the termination and outre all
have this determination what Rio does is
you story or nursery you launch freako
routines and when you get to an the
block waits waits till all of them are
finished and whatever finish it just
continues and if there is an error in
any of them you just write an exception
and when the exception reads reaches
this point it cancels all the other
coroutines and and then it continues
lib deal that does it differently so
there you open a bundle you run some
threads and at some point you say closed
bundle and at that point the coroutines
are closed so so the the difference
really is that in this case you have
work I kind of like main thread which is
in control a lot of threads in the
article other case like all of them are
created equal and and there's no like
the controller and the control
so which way is better you say it's
pretty hard to tell because in the trial
version you have this nice error
propagation where you throw an error and
the error gets to the color of coroutine
and and it bubbles up until it error
which is main but the problem there is
if that happens then it kind of looks
like that one of the one of the core
routines can cancel its siblings and
even its parents and it's very like
unstructured way of doing stuff so
that's not nice about it so it would be
nice to know like better we can combine
the two approaches that we would have
nice error handling and kind of nice and
conflation there co-routine kind of
cancels parents okay so some other
problems that are still unsolved will
partially so how would we go how will
you handle timeouts so one way is to use
something like it's going complex but we
have an object on which you can call I
cancel the panel function and it will
occur it will cancel after a door is no
you can parse it manually to each
function who knows better great spirits
that's a hard problem so for example you
want to shout out a server and you say
okay I am giving you like five seconds
to finish or whatever stuff you are
doing to close the connections decently
and then shut out so we don't have a
good story for that okay I'm sorry
how the admin foot yeah timer started a
bit late
Thanks so thank you very much for this
all
[Applause]