thank you sorry about the the wine there
I don't know what's going on I'm going
to talk about TCL as a minimalist
language in the sense that as a language
it sort of has no syntax or not no
syntax but no keywords and a minimalist
syntax that lets you inject your own
commands and in fact the things that
ship out of the box are the same sorts
of commands that you can make yourself
and so you can make it be whatever you
need to be and this is the long lever
with an easy grip because you can make
it feel however you like and then do
whatever you want so I've got enough
slides to show I've got some
demonstrations to show I'll talk briefly
a little bit about the history of it and
then get into a couple of the features
and specifically get into tweaking some
of those features to show what you can
do with it first of all I guess how many
people are already familiar with TCL as
a as a language small maybe less than
half how many people program with the C
API Julie three get into some see just a
heads up but it's it's good it's fun
first of all so TCL was started was
launched into the world in about 1987
and what brought it there was the
inventors frustration working with
command languages leading up to that so
what he did was design integrated
circuits and built tooling for the work
for the integrated circuit work and they
had specific tools that they wanted to
build and commands to drive their tools
and every time that they were doing
their work ad hoc they would build the
control languages that they want and end
up building something that was slightly
different
time after time and compatible time
after time and ad hoc from time to time
on sabbatical from his work at the UC
Berkeley
he it occurred to him why not write a
standard kind of a thing to do this that
would be a simple kind of a shim that
you can inject into whatever the tool
the specific work the things that
they're interested in and have a
standard library that would do that at
the time this was before the wide
distribution of gooeys as far as tools
go so people were typing all of their
commands and this was the conception of
TCL it was launched on the world in 1988
so developed conceptually in 87 and
launched in 88 so at about this time
Perl one was out Python I think still
had about six years to come
ruby was still in the future bash was in
the future so often I think that TCL is
lumped in with languages as a scripting
language which is fair its interactive
it's got a read eval print loop it's got
the quick sort of prototyping I guess
that people associate with a scripting
language
so you could say Ruby Perl Python TCL as
far as languages but it is unique in the
sense that it doesn't have any keywords
and it's built to be injected into a
thing that is more interesting than what
it is and then it provides kind of a
substrate to have the interesting thing
that you're working on
put commands into it and then make them
available so for example what it would
do is give you things like looping
constructs and decision and variable
assignment and and simple things like
that so you can have a tool that does an
interesting thing and leave driving that
tool to something else this is all very
abstract but we'll let's not not
abstract but we'll get into some
specific examples later on one of the
things that is interesting about TCL is
that it's what's called homo iconic
which means that the icon is the
representation of what it works with
which is to say that in this case code
is
is code you'll be familiar with this
from lisps for example where it runs as
lists and it parses lists and so we can
omit a thing and run that thing
TCL is the same way but it uses strings
indeed it used to be pure string run as
a language so it would be shooting
strings or arrays of characters around
as the method of its operation that's
different now but conceptually it's the
same thing everything is representable
as a string so what that means is that
commands emit strings and strings are
the things that you run so you can have
the emitted part of a command as a
runnable thing
the commands are also I was thinking
about it in the sense that it's kind of
like a socket pair in the sense to try
to figure out what a command is where
with a socket for example you've got an
IP and you've got a port or a pair
another IP and another port and that is
a unique identifier between two machines
and there's no other thing that is like
that as well with the commands they have
a name but they also have a little piece
of data that comes along with them they
also have an implementation that could
be separate from the name and in this
sense it's almost like the Magritte
painting Cecina paws and deep where you
you you you might wonder what what it's
doing or what's going on and indeed you
can take like the standard commands and
rename them or delete them because there
are no keywords in TCL so it is a
substrate that runs a thing and that's
it so it provides a substrate it ships a
bunch of commands but you don't need to
use them and indeed a lot of people
rewrite some example looping structures
you have wiles and fours or for each two
run across a list and it does the
obvious thing you can say for X in list
of things do some stuff and it will
properly do those things iterate over it
but I've written things for example that
would take a JSON blob as a command and
iterate over all of the the peer nodes
or recurse down the children no nodes as
a structure a looping structure right so
the json parser you can take any minimal
c version of it and quickly write a nice
little interface to TCL for it and turn
it into a first-class looping kind of a
thing within TCL because what a command
in and TCL is really really basic what
I'll do I think is launched a couple
demos and so I'll show you some the
loops and command evocations and we can
show some substitution as well how a
command can have its output be another
command and run that and rewrite some
looping and do a little bit of
introspection as well which is another
good thing as as simple as what the
substrate for TCL is it has really great
facilities for introspection which is to
say you can tell you what it knows and
as far as commands go for example and
within each command you can say of what
type are you which may sound interesting
because TCL is often one of its
mattresses everything is a string which
means that it parses strings and it
omits strings strings are generally
considered type less and and duck typing
for example where you just instantiate a
variable and have it do the right thing
or do something I guess
is both attractive and can also be a
cause for consternation or a write
errors for example if you're trying to
work with something as an integer and
you feed it something goes not an editor
and internally interestingly I think we
might touch on it there definitely are
types in TCL but everything is still
representable as a string so it's the
[Music]
kind of default default marshaling
method maybe I should have left that off
method so the strings come and go
there are inferences that you can make
with the types as well but let me load
up some code and show off some of this
some type stuff that I was talking about
so what I've got here is some C code
I've got 400 lines 425 lines and this
I'm gonna load it into a default TCL
interpreter which I can launch like this
and for example with the introspection I
can do something like this and get a
list of the things that it knows these
are the things that ship out of the box
so it's tell socket subs to open
etcetera etcetera the code that I've got
over here I can load that up as a module
and what that looks like is package
require and I called this one number
like because I was working with some
numerical stuff as an initial example so
this module is loaded now and if I go
back over here what I've got is a a
command that's called number like and
then one so this is my own registered
command and somewhere in that list it's
going to show up what does it do though
it is identity I've got another one that
is the same and what is interesting
about this is that from here this is the
prototype and this is the actual code
for it this is the that one command is
registered here I've got two sub
commands that it will take and this is
the like I said TCL doesn't have any key
words it's got a few simple parsing
rules I won't get into them there are 12
of them once you know those 12 you know
everything that there is to know
so I've got a sub command here that will
do add and delete
it tells you what it wants it does the
obvious thing these are also composable
so what I can do is this three gets
returned as a thing but I could say
number like to add number like one add
three let's number like to add number
like one add three and it does the right
thing I'm gonna do this and load up
something else
I've got with respect to the
introspection this series of commands
here make one XYZ and a let's you
instead of having C code to make a
command what I've got is a command that
makes commands so this one was cold make
one so this right here takes an argument
and takes two arguments actually it
takes the name of whatever you want to
give it and a base value this is another
number emitting kind of a thing and it
will create the command right here and
it gets injected into the interpreter
and it's instantly a first-class kind of
an object so here I can make four of
them and what I'm going to do actually
is edit this a bit
so you can see here there are the
commands that we just created here X Y &
Z but aside from that with the commands
they let themselves be introspected as
well so I know from a command what it's
backing see structure or see code is and
that is the the signature of the the see
function that it gets called with and I
can also determine what a specific piece
of client data like discrete specific
information belongs with each command so
for example if I've got a thing that
emits a number the number that it is
emitting is going to be carried with it
in memory and between with those two
different things the the backing
function and the unique client data that
it has I can identify things that are of
a type so example I've got a command
called like me and what it does is loads
it takes two arguments it takes a
reference command and a list of
candidate commands which are the things
that it wants to compare is anything in
this list the same as the first
reference piece so
if I run it I've made commands here that
are X Y Z and a there of a class of
commands that just emit numbers if I run
like me and I see which things are like
X X Y Z and a are all of the same kind
of command so they're all like X and I
run that against info commands which is
a list of everything that the
interpreter knows about what it does is
properly identifies what those commands
are it you might notice that X itself is
missing and that is the case mmm right
here we with the commands there's
information that is associated with the
commands and I chest to see is the
backing procedure for any command that
we're testing in the list the same as
what the reference command is if it is
we're going to move on and do some more
testing here we're going to filter out
other commands and so we're going to say
if the object data the special piece of
memory that's associated with the
command is not the same as what we're
testing against then that means that
it's not the exact same command because
if the special memory is the same
between the reference command and the
one that's in the candidate list that
means that the special command is in the
candidate list and we don't need to say
that it's like itself so we if it's not
the same then we go and append the list
of the element from the list that we're
testing because it passed two tests it's
the same kind of thing but it's got a
different memory so this is just an
example of the command sitting on the
substrate and
sure yeah no that's got it we've let
syrup pretty quickly but you know no
there any questions comments practically
speaking it's often hidden in in
enterprise networks its office very
often buried and f5s and 810 network
edge appliances it's used with storage
companies as well 3par and he let
Packard use it for their work in the
industry it's also used with with
computing like competing design so
cadence and Mentor Graphics for example
everything that's in your computer has
been touched by TCL with electronic cad
often used in prototyping as well it's
and and the joke is that it's it's easy
to prototype so things often get whipped
up in TCL and then work well enough that
they just get rolled into production as
well so it also drove the orc army and
the Lord of the Rings so if you enjoyed
that you enjoy to seal
yes I do and the way that I came to it
to begin with was as oh the question is
whether or not I enjoy writing things in
TCL I think it's it's fine it starts out
it's I find it very legible and then I
think that the worry is that it's going
to be like using Duplo blocks or crayons
later on because it seems so easy to use
but you're going to outgrow it but the
good thing about the malleability of it
is that you can extend it as you feel
fit and I came to it out of pearl which
is a pearl and so very very strict full
of special signals and and variables and
things like that that are you have to
know some of the the deeper inner
workings and I find that the TCL is
enough of a blank slate with a few rules
that once you know those it doesn't get
in your way at all but it's sufficiently
malleable but it's that it's interesting
I've used it to do system administration
for like hundreds or thousands of
machines at a time to like do network
connections and and pull databases and
and turn those things into commands and
make it do something interesting
[Applause]