do you hear me clear very clear okay
great so I am yes pronounce I'm going to
bring you this talk about from Tesla
hacking to freedom evey freedom if he
projects so quite excited to be here
honestly it's been about 18 years that I
come to FOSDEM
I have missed a few years I have to
admit I have submitted quite a few talks
and this is my first talk at for them
[Applause]
thank you guys I'm so proud to be here
and to be able to present this to you
because obviously you are also the
people who I admire so much and probably
the reason why I didn't get any talk
earlier it's just because I have the
habit of wearing a shirt like this and
everybody thinks I'm stupid good I am
just reliance I'm founded of Linux
Belgium we do make money with free and
open-source software training and
consultancy purely open-source we don't
sell any record subscription or things
like that we try to focus on what's the
heart of our community and I'm very
interested in if he since Tesla and
obviously I always thanks to you guys
the entire community is what as made as
possible for me and yeah I'm humbled by
it thank you
so first of all I'm a Tesla customer I'm
not a test a supplier or employee and
there's some disclaimers of course with
hacking cars they are relatively big and
you can run people over with them and
things like that but of course there are
other tools which are tasers well like a
knife which can be used for perfectly
peaceful purposes as well
so it's also a little bit uncertain what
level of endorsement is both officially
and unofficially by Tesla we are quite
optimistic but there are some rumors but
more about that later probably how many
of you is there somebody here who has a
Tesla
who's the test owner okay quite a few
data owners great hopefully some
contributors okay other people who have
a reservation who don't have a test not
yet but who are looking for one
yay cheers to that we will have some
work support freedom a key to that the
core I'm working on my model eggs nice
rolling dwarfs alia Falcon wing doors I
have to say is fantastic for sale by the
way do no way replacing it with the
Model S once you drive electric there is
no going yak going back it's really
fantastic to drive not doing any
pollution neither you can easily I think
if you plan a little bit you can drive a
thousand kilometres without having to
wait I don't like waiting in the gas
station you have to fill up the car if
to wait there a few minutes I don't like
waiting and with the car you have to
charge but if it's charged us very
quickly at one on the 20 kilowatts and
if you combine it with a toilet break I
do have to pee a lot or if you take a
lunch break it's completely full pee
break
just one on the skilling meters charge
quickly and lunch it's completely full
or dinner so 1,000 kilometres without
having to Waits and otherwise it's just
full when you start at home so you never
have to go to the petrol station just
plug it in at night and walk away
for Tesla it's important to accelerate
the world's transition to sustainable
energy that's their mission something of
course which is very nice to say self
contributed a little bit to that saved
over 16 tonne of co2 and after that all
the other pollution of our atmosphere
over the last one and a half years so
the problem of course that for many
electric cars are still too expensive
this is hopefully something which is
changing right now for 40 thousand euro
you get a guillotine euro or a corner
Electric coronation leaf which are
already very nice cars and which can get
you everywhere you want that's why it's
still a bit higher it's announced that
they will reduce prices and things will
happen this year and early next year
that prices will trickle down also the
other car manufactures are going to
launch more electric cars so just be a
little bit patience if you don't have
money for it yet just don't buy a new
internal combustion engine car because
it will have a lifetime of 30 years and
better if you really can't afford it
just buy a second-hand car good so
coming to the mission of freedom Evi
so why is this tesla hacking in which
played around with the system is
evolving now into an open-source project
well it is clear that's the future of
mobility which has been stuck in the
dark ages for so long with analog and
proprietary technologies is now
completely digital and running on Linux
and because it runs on Linux we have it
full fully under our control well maybe
there is for example also this project
called automotive create Linux from the
Linux Foundation and this is fantastic
it allows car manufacturers to run Linux
on their cars to build Linux for our
cars and to more easily build that based
upon the Yocto project now if it means
that you've got a lot of freedom but if
it's completely locked down into a box
which you cannot touch what kind of
freedom is that so it's all about
control cars are the symbol of freedom
for many car manufacturers I was never
that much of his car geek but if you
look at all the commercials it's nice
landscapes and cars driving through its
symbol of freedom but if these symbols
of freedom are constantly connected to
the Internet's can be parked can be used
as surveillance mass surveillance
weapons against the public it's not that
great of course so there are some
disadvantages some dangers about the new
technology as well and obviously we
think that Tesla is doing the right job
but not all car manufacturers will play
nice and it's not because we trust the
company now that it will prove to be so
in the future I've seen on the on the
stage of ausdom also Facebook a long
time ago when there were just a small
company very enthusiastic about their
new technologies now people would
probably be more critical about what
they are doing with respect to privacy
saying goes to Google saying goes for
Apple so what will evolve in the future
we don't know unless we have control
ourselves over our own vehicles so it's
about that and obviously also to add
some nice features to it as well
so we have some founding principles
first of all freedom Evie needs to
enable maximum functionality of your car
while preserving the original software
if you bring your car in for service
the car guide the car technician he
doesn't know anything about open source
or freedom or privacy and software
rights you might want to educate them
but they're more concerned about getting
your car working and and obviously so so
they should not be confronted with our
own experimentations on our car so I
think it's important for the freedom if
you project that it is easily to disable
easy to install and that it preserves
also the original software so that
basically as a user you are trusting the
manufacturer and the open source project
of which you can verify the code your
source code yourself and you're not
trusting anything else so that's a
little bit of the founding principles
also lastly I think it's important to
avoid conflicts with manufacturers Tesla
for example they sometimes sell software
enable features new version of the model
Dixon no more or less has a 100
kilowatts hour battery but it's not
fully accessible unless you pay an extra
price using software using roots of root
or privileges freedom easy project codes
enable that but of course that's not the
ID we want to respect the business model
of this company if it's possible to
enhance the performance and they don't
sell such a package obviously it is nice
to do so you have to find the right way
there and I think it's important not to
do any abuse one of the new features for
Tesla which I will introduce with
freedom if he today is hotspot mode and
it uses the Tesla network to get
internet connection and in car we see
experience in your
obviously it can cure costs for Tesla of
this bandwidth so for that we are also
building that it keeps track of the
amount of volume so they could possibly
bill it we don't want to abuse the
system we just make it want to make it
more useful our son is really you loves
it so we have to make some design
decisions three design decisions are
made first one is that we have one
script slash facts that freedom if he
start which is launched by the car as
the root user from a persistent storage
location so these two things are a
requirement for running freedom if he on
any car you need to have root access
hopefully and a persistent location to
put a script so and of course the car
needs to run Linux because will run the
entire freedom if he projects as a
chroot addition to the system so it is a
bash script we chose for basket because
bash or ash is available on most
embedded Linux systems and so also on
the cars running Linux then it uses the
USB stick most cars F USB stick USB port
for charging and in the case of the
Tesla's it is not only used for charging
is also direct connects directly to the
central display of the car and on this
USB stick there is a root filesystem
containing Ubuntu what's important to
realize is that power management can at
any time disable the USB stick normally
not while driving but if you park the
car that can go on power saving modes
and then the USB stick is no longer
there so we need to manage
that why did we choose Ubuntu and this
is a dangerous thing to say here in
force them because obviously we have
some nice contributors to Debian and to
arch and to other exciting Linux
distributions in this room and for to
those guys I'm sorry we have to pick one
and obviously Ubuntu is a nice choice
because nvidia tegra for a bundle was
already available you can just update
install ten thousands of packages
compared to the choctaw where we need to
cross compile everything and fiddle with
recipes it's just you know a lot easier
so please don't be sad for the other
guys and obviously it doesn't
necessarily need to be that it just
happens to be this way so with respect
to the automotive grade Linux it is not
impossible that freedom if we will also
evolve as a layer towards octal and in
this way can also be easily integrated
with that but that's probably two three
steps ahead
oh yeah and maybe a little bit of
criticism towards octo if you want to
run your code with the GUI and you know
dependencies like chromium for example
you end up with something which is the
same size of a bunch oh come on guys you
can do better than that
so maybe good advertisements for Ubuntu
I don't know I try to change every two
years Linux distribution running on my
own laptop to just do you know running
my gyro right now okay so a lot of
design decisions the third design
decision is how to configure everything
we want to do with freedom easy well
through web interface and obviously we
could have chosen something lightweight
but yeah we went for nginx on PHP fpm
and looked the other day and it's only
consumed about ten megabytes of RAM it
has two gigabytes of RAM it's not the
most optimal run wise but it's high
performance and low overhead so why not
it's not written in stone we can change
that if we like so with respect to the
functionality we have bundled
functionality together in so called
freedom if he apps problem name maybe
but what's important for that is that
they have a proper activation when the
USB stick is detected time when the USB
stick is lost the entire root filesystem
is gone well maybe there are still some
processes dangling so we need to
properly deactivate them as well so
maybe also some things need to be
periodically run so all that kind of
functionality is provided out of the
activation of freedom Evi
so let's have a look at how it all comes
together
[Music]
electric vehicles our future of mobility
we are adding a layer of freedom
enabling freedom movie is as simple as
wasting one line of code to your Tesla
here don't select it we go to our root
channel come on Tesla paste installation
script full run that will vary v it's
not running a seizure not yet installed
if it's the correct car to download and
install the freedom of e start script
and installed inside the home tab that's
all it does it says freedom Evie
installs have fun after that we only
need to insert a USB stick when the
stick is inserted within the minute
treatment even detect that it's there
train movie is configurable to all web
interface
and yet you will detect that it's there
read movie is configurable to OLAP
interface IP address of machine see all
the different modes the software good so
I have a second movie coming up late
which explains a little bit more so here
we have a little bit more technical
details about our Tesla Tesla is
basically a computer network which just
happens to have a big battery and some
wheels so the instrument cluster which
is the display behind the steering wheel
here as this IP address we have the big
screen which is over here which is a 17
inch screen it is actually a display
which is rotated on a sides so the video
day graph has as far as I know it no
possibility of from the video driver
rotating it and that's probably the
reason why the cute application which is
constantly visible written by Tesla if
actually on its sides so and that's also
probably the reason why they are stuck
with cute 4 because cute 5 obviously has
contributed a lot of nice features
compared to cute for but one of the
disadvantages with cute 5 is that which
cute for you could just say rotate 90
degrees and with good 5 you have to
basically turn all the way
so I presume that that's the reason why
they do it like that the disadvantage
with that is of course that if we use
the X display directly and we send an X
term on it it will be visible on its
side so actually I wanted to put that
into another movie but yeah time
constraints so and this of course also
means that if you want to visualize
stuff directly to the exert ourselves we
need to make sure that it's rotated or
that it's an application which supports
90 degrees rotation the general software
based framework in the kernel for
turning 90 degrees and 180 and something
that would be nice
just saying that okay good gateway 102
103 if you like it in the open source
roads don't complain just do it
so I know I know autopilot so I'll go
over the systems one by one there is
also the uplink which is connected to
the USB and bluetooth and whiffy which
is connected basically to the USB over
the central display so this is the
instrument cluster this is the back of
the instrument cluster if you if you
open up the car I not never opened up a
car before but luckily the Tesla is
relatively easy to open up
it's also only one screw driver you need
it's the same screws everywhere that is
really a good job it's the instrument
cluster behind the steering wheel has a
leaked SSH key so if you have access to
the internal network you can get access
to that so it's a boots or squash it has
compressed read-only file system but the
slash for partition is writable and
persistent across the boot so it is put
stuff
there it's very similar than what's on
the central display the things like
steering wheel buttons are attached to
this instrument cluster and input is
sent over the internet it's actually a
good way to know if your internet
connection is working just use the
scroll wheel nothing happens with your
internet which doesn't work
the guys from Tesla service were
actually quite surprised that I knew
that because of course I filled with it
I put a switch in there in between and
things like that so settings are stored
in SQL 3 sqlite3 database and there's
also comments to view those comments LVS
you can also change all these parameters
and variables stored in there in a
persistent and non-persistent way
instrument cluster be careful when you
remove it the connector as a click
mechanism it's very easy once you know
it but otherwise difficult to to use at
sha a few years ago italian friends
helped me with that first time then the
central display so 192 168 dot ninety
dot 100 it's an nvidia tegra quad core
system now on the newer cars
Intel based systems and so we currently
don't support that yet we feel such a
car and you have root access to it we
can try to port freedom easy to it
I'm sure only that that difficult I will
have to just make another file system
image of probably a boon to an Intel
compatible than or whatever you like
it's your car good so it runs the cute
based web browser which most people
don't really like it's not that great so
being able to use use that for the
duration of freedom if he is of course a
nice application because most people
don't use it for some anything else
anyway so okay then I will see an end
map of the system obviously there is a
lot of interest to be able to get
through to access and we'll come back
back to that in later there is also the
parrot USB connected bluetooth with E
and LTE module which is own IP addresses
can be accessed through telnet it's only
physically accessible from the central
unit and it's a very small
microcontroller
but it runs a built root filesystem then
there is not divides a gateway running
free Actos and which is attached to the
canvases so to control basically most
vehicle functions there are six canvases
typically used in automotive industry
attached to the Gateway it used to
contain password which you could extract
from the SD card located inside the cid
but it's no longer the case whenever
there are easy ways to get routes Tesla
fixes it and obviously that's a good
thing because there is also the
potential for abuse but we'll come back
to that autopilot 2.0 has its own IP
address it's basically the the most
powerful system in the car obviously
there is a new version of the autopilots
which will come out this year out of
pilots 3.0 which contains a sock
developed by test for themselves it's
quite amazing it will enable about 100
times as fast processing of you look
only once images from the 8 cameras on
the system so but this generation it's
Nvidia px 2 base
- Denver course for RA 57th and one
Pascal GPU to do the heavy lifting for
the image analyzes and to assist in
getting people where they want without a
lot of effort so how do we get root I
get the question a lot
now the freedom IV project is not about
how to get route it's pretty basic aliy
a prerequisite okay but how to get
through it so getting on to the physical
Internet network is the first step so it
has a factory connector you can
basically try to fill and figure it out
by yourself
but there are also pre mates over
expensive cables you can find on eBay
but Arcadia they're called Tesla service
access cables and they also fit in a
connector we below the steering below
the central display here now the port
below the central display is locked by
Tesla Ethernet it's locked and it can be
activated by a tool which Tesla service
uses it's called toolkit this sends a
cryptographic token to unlock the sport
some people don't like that because
there's known that people who steal
Tesla's can also have toolkit so if they
then enable the port breaker wind or
enable the ports plug it in a fruit
disable the alarm start the car
then it can happen very quickly that
it's assisted in stealing a car so also
one of the things we want to add to
freedom of e is just to disable that
security token it's called sets and we
can just kill the process and yeah then
it doesn't work obviously we might want
to turn it back one when we go to the
Tesla service center
or we can add some GPS positioning can
easily query where the car is even get
the address and things like that and
he'll fence it so it's only possible to
do that there's no service location
that's I could do that but okay we're
doing a lot of things which does like
good do but they have other priorities I
think so which data paths exist to get
routes well through the internet
obviously all these cars are connected
to the internet must be certainly a way
to get into that but maybe it's a bit
difficult maybe only singularity capable
APA ice will be able to intrude to all
Tesla cars I don't know it's nightmare
of Elon Musk that all cars in the world
would be hacked and directly sent to the
same location from creating cows in
traffic things like that
it's a risk yes because of obviously
Tesla can access all the cars it only
takes one malicious person at Tesla to
do that other possibility is through
your Android app you can steer the car
with your toes under tap you can set the
air-conditioning
what's so functionality of your app and
obviously there's also a data path which
is heavily protected of course
motherships no test.com is basically the
central points where all these things go
through all the cars connect - aside
from that we have for internal Ethernet
network which means we have a physical
connection at our central display behind
our instrument cluster and also go to
our outer pilots which is fairly easily
accessible now getting physical access
to the Internet network you would resume
ok than we are having root that's not
the case so it's very
protected and Cambyses might be another
way of access Tesla is a very good
citizen with respect to security
whenever there is a problem security
wise they fix it immediately
not only that they well what is the
problem of course well if somebody can
get routes to somebody else's car there
is a possibility for abuse it is
possible to help stealing Tesla's it is
possible to fake the mileage it is
possible to fake thin numbers and trim
levels of the car you can control to
control the cars and and things like
that remotely so yeah obviously there is
a danger of abuse and this is a good
thing of course that Tesla is
immediately addressing these issues when
they come to be also Tesla has a bug
bounty program this means if you find a
way to route your Tesla you can of
course share it with everybody to be
able to install freedom IV but if you
tell it to Tesla they will give you
money and it will fix it right away so
it's a difficult situation for freedom
Fe with the model 3 they even have upped
the game so now with the bound to own
contest in Vancouver which will happen
in March they have really said ok if you
can route our car in these different
ways or access or even just to a denial
of service attack on our autopilot
system we give you fixed shift we give
you $50,000 ok it's hard to compete with
that not only that if you're the first
one to do one of those things you get
this Moultrie for free as well
so yeah hmm
there is a guy who has posted that he
has roots on his model tree and he is
running Ubuntu as well on it and I see a
shorted environment so but still it's
not actionable for any of these prices
because he D solders to de MMC put some
changes in there and put it back which
is of course better to do not everybody
will want to do that of course and it
might fall to your warranty a little bit
but only for the device I'm not the rest
of the car of course but there are some
unaligned interest between Tesla and us
and as a whole maybe offenders at all so
they will fix it right away so it's of
course great that I fixed it but it's
not that great if it's the only way to
gain access to your own car it's your
car come on when I bought my Tesla first
I sent an email to do well on musk and I
said I'm turning 40 please give me root
on my own car
turns out he doesn't read email so much
and I should have made me send it over
Twitter there was somebody on the Tesla
Motors Club forum who was so kind to to
assist me there first for the EC and
then using a undocumented exploit so
most great that he wanted to share that
with me yeah so I I hope that there is
not right now an official way to ask
root access for your own freaking car
but I hope it will change quickly and
and there is a security researchers
program with Tesla in which Tesla also
say that if you are analyzing the
security and you break your car it's no
problem
we'll just reinstall it for you without
any cost I think that's a great thing to
do they even say we can do it multiple
times that's nice so I do think they are
doing the right thing I hope they will
do it as well for route and I understand
that there are cautious about it but
come on we're all grown-ups here
and why not flag cars like that and
these people are buying a second-hand
car that they know ok this car has been
routed maybe maybe the trim level is
wrong maybe people filled with it
decrease the price or me because this
was freedom day ok of the price I don't
know
but important is of course that Tesla is
a trendsetter for the industry and what
Tesla is going to do now will also
impact what other vendors will do later
on and that's also the reason why I go
through the efforts of starting this
project right now why I think it's
important that we make this step right
now of being able to open source our
cars because it's the beginning of the
new era of electric cars and now it's
probably the last iterations of course I
would say I don't know after that we'll
be tunnels and flying I guess okay so
how to get routes from someone who has a
root method from a Tesla service
technician or third-party repair center
obviously these people they have roots
they you have access to the tool get the
toolbox program from Tesla so if they
just give you access or just use the
comment line to have this one comment
paste it it's already there and this
script is very simple you can look at it
script yourself it will just see if the
USB stick is not there okay it stops it
exits it doesn't do anything anymore
in the current iterations it runs out of
crontab because fast fulcrum is on var
and writable was an easy way maybe on
the intelligent cars you have to turn it
into a demon or something else we'll
have to see if we get access to those
cars also for other cars non Tesla cars
they might have different ways of
getting things started but yeah I hope
we'll be able to find that out quickly
and that's all else fails yeah
desoldering or resoling emm say it's not
that hard it's always a way so what have
we puts already inside freedom evey
[Music]
freedom means you are certain that your
privacy is guaranteed normally in a
marketing like way where you cannot
verify them it actually happens but by
looking at the codes and disabling the
GSM connection turning off Rafi this is
cloak mode I get a warning message cloak
mode disables out the planets GPS mushy
and 342 makes you invisible for tracking
by the vehicle and mobile phone poles
mapping music streaming stops working
and it could be abused and depend to
drive to enable LTE DC so that features
didn't make it yet the pin to drive to
disable so I hope you able to add that
Tiffany I get a warning message to makes
you invisible for tracking by the
vehicle performance mapping music
streaming stops working
that could be abused and depend to try
to enable LT cloaking disables the USB
3g connection to get when we turn clock
mode off again
if we turn clock moves off again we'll
take a little bit of seconds and then we
see he gets animal again so the message
is that it gets animals
it takes five seconds for the interface
to recognize that the USB device is back
online and then get back or get a
connection to the Internet
showing your freedom gives you easy
access to developer and factory modes
which can be enabled at the touch of a
button the developer a factory modes who
restores the cute application running on
our display when you look at the top for
display we see that blue developer
flexed is added to our T of Tesla this
is Tesla provided functionality we now
touch this button then you'll get the CD
there's a Help remote inside developer
modes we get a nice overview of the
different packs in our car there's the
chorus currently plugged in we see what
the car battery management system is
actually doing developer mode also shows
us when the car was first built so
February 1st 2017 in this case there is
a special thermal mode inside developer
mode introduced as an overview of all
the important temperature metrics in the
system go out of developer mode and by
the exit button
system again when even musk announced
two years ago that hotspot mode was
coming to Tesla cars from a simple
software upgrade everybody was thrilled
[Music]
with hotspot now if you can just add
this antenna to a car and turn it into a
in college vehicle first research D must
be if you adapter now ready to go the
freedom easy app keeps track of data
usage so that's like them properly bill
used of their network if they want to do
so something sniffing a label with 3G
don't make a lot of sense when we find
mode change the core of your display we
understand me an abstract italic way if
one day you decide you want to live
without freedom II complete removal is a
sample as well in your script
[Music]
thank you thank you so here is the hit
up project it's completely accessible
there are already some my contributors
and and last night also a friend of mine
from Hungary
great Tesla Hackett also installed it on
his scars and had it gave me the test
and quite a few typos were already fixed
letters as a result so we burned all
this functionality which we can just
enable in the web interface in what we
call apps and we see here in the master
branch there is the slash freedom if he
so we put everything on the USB stick
the root filesystem in a directory
freedom IV and there we have other
extracts recalled apps this directory
called apps contains symbolic links to
apps in progress or apps available the
web interface only allows us to create
symlinks basically two apps available
out of this abstractly and only those
same links will be active and it also
means that when the USB stick is
detected to the application is started
by running a activation script out of it
so it's just the scale shell script
which can start a service also the
freedom of these star scripts will copy
the deactivation script through the root
filesystem just to the temp directory in
RAM so that if the USB stick needs to be
is the sorry is removed that it can
still run this deactivation scripts to
kill dangling processes then there is
also a description that sheets on file
and this initiation file is basically
the name of the program and some more
description everything which is visible
in the web interface also it can contain
hidden
the marking the fact that it's hidden
means that it's not visible in the web
interface also the freedom easy core
itself is implemented the web interface
is implemented as an app you can easily
copy stuff from it and then we have some
directories every minute every hour
every 5 minutes every day to implement
some kind of grunt applied behavior as
the script freedom if you start forints
every minute it will look in those
directories if relevant and run whatever
it's in there in the periodic way so
here we see the example of the
descriptions of JSON and by the way this
directory 0 template up in the apps in
progress that actually you can just copy
that there's nothing going on in there
just some explanation I can copy the
directory for your own application if
you want to create birthday mode working
on it a little bit you can easily do
that
so you see three entries in the
description that she stays on the name
of the app the description and if it's
visible or not but so in the apps we see
that which current things are enabled so
yeah if you want to update freedom of
you just hit pool on the root filesystem
which will basically put some things in
there for far away freedom iffy and also
the flash freedom IV directory so what
are the current problems and things
which are to do well some things in the
movie were not really there yet so the
two disabled for cloaking modes we
disabled right now the LTE modem but
Leif is not yet disabled it's easy to
disable it just that to edit but there's
also no pin to drive it's not being
asked so ya would prefer that's in there
it's not easy just the interface which
needs to be built for that we had some
more plans for making movies of
of things which are already in there
like that man is in there maybe you're
not that form of lab mean I know it
doesn't work great on the web browser
anyway but it might be interesting when
your wife is driving just to be able to
install so much other things without
having to pulled out your laptop a blue
post movie was also planned thank you to
my wife by the way for allowing me to do
this I weren't Warner and when there is
a possibility that one of the displays
is going to reboot the car still drives
when the system's reboot this may be
hard to know the speed but so also the
proper hot spots traffic accounting it's
not in there yet just not enough time
for that
but shouldn't be too hard to implement
it should be properly done because of
course the car switches between Vicki
and LTE 3G all the time so we don't want
to pay for our own beefy connection so
some other things yeah the hotspot mode
works - SSH shock tunnel right now
probably some iptables
problems unbox I've worked on that a
little bit try to get Android working on
the platform unbox is more geared
towards running on Intel
so my easier on the newer cars to get
that running would be nice of course to
be able to run Spotify things like that
on your car completes a bit with adds
functionality basically compared to the
Tesla things also car logo edition I
have changed from some images in the car
I overlay them using bind mounting so I
don't really change the actual files and
this means that it gets to see like that
I like it a lot I think lots of people
will like it - to be able to put their
own logos their names whatever on their
cars so I want to make an app for that
as well so it can be easily done
okay also I would like deeper reverse
the other day crashed into a car behind
me blame the fact that the car didn't
deeper when I was reversing my weapon to
face for reverse SSH tunnel is not
finished yet airplay over whiffy am
player to a few movies we can also check
if the car is driving or not easily for
safety reasons compilation of route
browser like the one from Tesla to
similar limitations some cleanup variety
tables button widget sometimes receives
two events often if too so it might be
the problem with the widget or not we
need to troubleshoot it a little bit all
Tesla friendly our friendly is less la
seems to be quite alright I don't have a
lot of time so I don't think it for its
warranty what I what you are doing here
obviously don't break anything if I
break something I also tell that lying I
don't claim warranty I wanted to pay
just a few euros because I broke the
plastic cover myself very reasonable
okay I need to help please contribute if
there are any questions I might have a
minute or so left
yes
okay so the question is if we perform a
software update on the car will freedom
if he still work yes so for now yes so
basically it relies on the fact that we
have full access and persistent storage
as long as that not being touched its
keeps on working obviously we need to
remain cautious it is possible that they
might break stuff and we need to work
around it so we will always say what the
latest support is releases there is a
rumor that 2010 19.2 might break some
stuff and we'll see how to deal with
that if that's really true