howdy everyone I'm gonna start with the
obligatory disclaimers I'm a lawyer I'm
not your lawyer and this is going to be
mostly focused on US law in fact
entirely focused on US law and I'm not
commenting about anything else
so with all that out of the way I want
to talk about patent exhaustion now a
lot of times when people are talking
about the interaction of patents and
free software they really look at
licensing they say does this particular
license have a have a patent grant or is
there an implied patent license
associated with open-source this has
been the subject of almost all of the
discussion and surprisingly exhaustion
wilde has occasionally been mentioned
isn't really the focus of any of any
analysis I was going I was going through
and helping collect all of the primary
materials and I realized that the
Supreme Court of the United States has
recently had a number of very important
decisions regarding patent we're
carrying patent exhaustion and I decided
to look at these and see in what way did
they enter interact with free software
and I was surprised I've been doing this
for a very long time and I was surprised
and so I bet you will be too now one
thing occasionally people who are
motivated to say so will say something
like I'll I'll get to that in a second
so one what people will say that that
patent exhaustion doesn't really exist
this is a quote from an article that was
put that was published a little earlier
late last year I've bolded the the quote
permitting one software to be strip you
dat under an OSS license that conveys no
patent rights involves neither the
selling of a product nor the licensing
of patent does not implicate patent
exhaustion that all due respect this is
a pile of crap I'm going to go through
and I'm going to hit you with lots and
lots of case law in each case in each
case I'm going to I'm going to be
quoting the quotes that you will see are
all from the appropriate cases but now
I'm going to say for those who for those
who are not intimately familiar with
patent law what's the difference between
a patent license and patent exhaustion
and we're going to get into this because
there's some there are some distinctions
that are going to become important a
little later but you can think of a
patent in patent law a patent says that
there are rights that people have to
make something to use something to sell
something to import whatever the patent
says a the patent holder is the only
person who is allowed to do take those
certain actions those are the reserved
rights under patent law it is a transfer
when you give someone a license you are
giving them permission or at least
partial permission to take one of those
actions and you're promising you won't
sue them because of it now the
difference is patent exhaustion happens
is as soon as you take advantage of one
of those one of those reserved rights
under patent law as soon as you sell
something as soon as you pass it on as
soon as you make a product as soon as
you put something into the stream of
Commerce there's a doctrine that says
you're only allowed to profit once from
your patent and so when you've put it
into the string of commerce your patent
is quote-unquote exhausted and you can't
sue anybody who's downstream of the
authorized licensed licensed creator or
seller or distributor for patents for
example many of you have phones or
computers or whatever can you imagine if
you bought those and then let's say that
people came to you and said hey you know
what you also need to license my patents
or else I'm going to sue you and you
would say well that's bollocks and you
would be right because that you have as
soon as you paid them or even as soon as
someone was paid upstream of you they
received their reward and they're not
allowed to try and sue everything every
single person all the way down the line
to the end-user they can only take out
that they can only extract a payment
once in the entire chain of Commerce
clear as mud probably not but I want to
I want to talk about this the thing is
that patent exhaustion is not a license
a license is a transfer of rights it is
actually relatively narrow it is based
upon the reserved rights under under
patent law exhaustion takes place any
place that you put something and in an
authorized way into the stream of
Commerce so if you learn one thing today
the most important thing is a lot of
patent exhaustion is not patent
licensing they're completely different
and in some ways patent exhaustion is
much bigger so what are we going to be
talking about we're going to be talking
about some particular cases particular
cases these are the cases that I'm going
to have quotes from I will summarize
just briefly what each one one of these
was about quanta computer versus LG
electronics there was there was somebody
who was licensed to
create to create software to put
together I think was LG had licensed
licensed Intel you can use our patents
but you can't use them with any non
Intel chips
quanto went ahead and and built a
computer with Intel and non Intel chips
they got sued the the Supreme Court said
you know what even though you told you
told them this is you only gave them
this license for Intel versus non Intel
chips you know what patent exhaustion
you can't you can't try and you're
already licensed Intel they quanta got
it from Intel you can only apply it once
exhaustion impression products versus
Lexmark this was one that just came down
recently this was an interesting one
first of all it took but it took place
overseas at least in part so it was
about the territoriality of patent law
the second one is you know that Lexmark
they sell those compute those printers
and they really really want you to buy
their expensive ink and so they had this
idea that we're going to sell sell you a
one-time-only ink ink cartridge that if
you don't return it to us you're you
don't return it to us you're committing
patent infringement and so some people
bought it and refilled it and sold it
and they got sued the Supreme Court said
no patent exhaustion life scan Scotland
this is an interesting one has nothing
to do with technology or well someone to
do with technology but it was about like
blood draws and things like that what's
interesting about this one is they were
arguing about the meaning of sale this
is this has been talked about in terms
of the sale of a patented product in
this one they were giving things away
court said nope doesn't matter how you
could put in stream of Commerce
exhaustion cascades computer innovation
this was the only one that's actually
directly related to free software
Cascades had licensed Google for a
certainty for certain uses of their
patents in the dalvik virtual machine
cascades then went and sued some people
who took the Android Open Source project
and built their operating systems
systems with it the court said no
exception and finally Intel Intel this
was about the ability to have made and
there is a trick on this one that I'll
leave till later so I'm going to hit you
with a bunch of principles number one
what's the most important thing to learn
exhaustion is not licensing this is what
I was talking about in terms of
everybody has these inherent rights to
inherent rights to do these things we
have the right to give make you sell
those are natural rights in our system
the only reason that those are
restricted is all is because we have
this artificial limitation based upon
the patent but this in this case this
anytime you take one of those actions
and put it in the stream of Commerce it
is you have exhausted your rights it is
a limitation on the the on the scope of
the patent grant it is completely gone
as it says there's no more exclusionary
right to right left to enforce what's
the next principle well
oh why is patent exhaustion not
licensing and this is I think a very key
element when you're thinking about free
software licenses are about rights
exhaustion is about goods now you may
think hey free software I'm getting a
license I'm getting rights but when you
are given those rights in association
with the source code you're with a good
because those rights are attached to a
good
that's why exhaustion starts to apply
so again licenses are rights exhaustion
has to do with goods now I'm going to
take for a moment the perspective of
some some very large patent holders and
they say they don't like this and
they're gonna say well what are some
things we could do to get around this
because you know that's what lawyers are
paid for let's get around this this is
inconvenient so what if we said I am NOT
going to I'm going to say you're not
allowed to do to to to give it to
somebody else without telling them that
you're infringing on my rights
well the Supreme Court said no it
doesn't matter
a it doesn't matter even if you tell
them hey I've got patents on this and
you are exotic and I'm still going to
come after you as long as you have made
a sale you've exhausted the patent
rights it whom they said well what if I
particularly like I gave them notice I
said you really really you can't do this
well wait no nope oh sorry wrong one
okay
what if I said well this is a good my
Canton is on a method for those who
don't know their patents two different
types of things methods systems you know
compositions of matter but if they said
mine thing is a method even though I
gave you a good the method it's really
when your end user runs the software
that my patent is enforce know that
again that doesn't work Supreme Court
said if you're some the thing that
you're doing encompasses and performs
the method it's all the basic it's all
basically the same thing and when you're
thinking in the context of free software
the only time
patents are really going to apply is
when the pet the software does the
patented thing or else why are we
talking about it at all
well what if we said something like I am
going to write my patent claims so that
you need to put it on a computer and I'm
only giving you the source code haha I
didn't give you all the stuff you can't
do the method you don't have the system
I saw my patent rights Supreme Court
says this is the notice one sorry I
don't have my thing so I don't remember
exactly which order I'm gonna go ahead
okay well we'll do it in the order that
I did I put it this is this is the one
we're in the Intel Agreement Intel had
to pass forward to this this notice that
said we still have patent rights Supreme
Court said no you're still exhausted
this is this the court made a
particularly strong opinion about this
there have been people who have tried to
do this in the context of Foss in
particular there was a Xerox PARC
license which they took the BSD license
and they said this is the copyright
element of this license by the way there
is no patent license granted associated
with this those who wish to grant a
patent grant listed your name at the
bottom you can find this you can find
this out there do you know what even if
you explicitly say I am NOT giving you a
patent grant but you still put something
in the stream of Commerce well hey it's
still exhausted now this gets to this
life can't live scan Scotland case what
if they said it's free software and you
can see from the quote that I put up
earlier earlier they said what you think
that this would apply to free software I
mean this there's no sale going on here
well in life scan Scotland the court was
particularly unimpressed by this
argument he said you can give something
away and that's exhaust and that
exhausts our patent what you're
basically doing is saying even though
we've talked in general about sale what
we're really talking about is entering
the stream of Commerce that means you
put it into someone's hands in an
authorized fashion at that point it's
exhausted and what's more if you don't
you have the right to choose what sort a
reward you get for giving it to somebody
and if the ward you want is $0 you can't
back and say we didn't charge enough and
so we want to be able to enforce our we
want to sue you for more money and in
fact if you think about Jacobson be cat
sir the court there said there is an
economic benefit associated with getting
your name out and having people use your
code and so you are people the courts
have recognized an economic benefit
that's the quid pro quo that people
receive for them receiving your code
you've been paid if you choose to
release something under open source
software you can't say it's not a sale
so no exhaustion this is the this is the
one where this is the Cascades case
where it applied to to Google and the
Android Open Source Project now it
wasn't that it wasn't that Google in
particular was selling these things they
were simply they made something free
software and other people were taking it
and building on it and doing the things
that they would with free software they
tried to say say well this was they had
a little piece in their license
agreement this is Google you can only
use this for Google products and
Cascades tried to argue look this is a
Samsung product this is an LG LG product
these are other people's products it's
outside the scope of the license court
said no remember as soon as you put
something in the stream of Commerce it's
exhausted it's gone so it doesn't matter
that Android and the Android Open Source
project it it came from an authorized
producer therefore the fact that they
chose not to charge money for it well it
doesn't matter they got it from an
authorized person they can do what they
want the patent is exhaustive
this is the one that I was getting to
about this idea of what if I didn't
include all the if I said you need a
computer or you need this to do this in
the context of a computer system or a
network or something like that well the
court has come up against people trying
to make that argument before and again
they were unimpressed because they said
really you're selling these chips this
was in the context of these computer
ships that were meant to be combined
with other chips they said the only use
for these chips is to connect them
together and put them in a computer so
you can't say well that last non
inventive little piece of putting it in
a computer is really what is is keeping
this patent from being sun exhaustion
they not said no as long as the thing
that you are putting out there
substantially embodies these patent
claims it is exhausted even if the
contemplated even if the contemplated
effort requires you to to put it in a
system or put it on a computer or do any
of those other things this was
interesting as they said well what if
there's some other way in which you
could use this and the court said that's
a good point if you have something that
is truly dual use then then it is
possible that it can be put out there
without exhausting the patent but in
this case the thing that you were giving
was had no real other use and again if
you think about in the context of free
software if you've got some sort of
piece of it that where they say this
embodies these claims well then it's not
them about the use of those the software
is the whole it is those specific lines
that they're saying this does our thing
and if these lines
don't really have any particular other
reason other than to embody this
algorithm well then that is that is
exhausting
what if they said wow geez I'm running
out of arguments here what if we I don't
know what if we told them they had to
disable it court said no sorry I got
very excited about this the court said
no you can't disable it because disabled
code has no use therefore you can't say
that you've sold them something useful
except that it only it only is uninjured
it'ss able all the pieces that have used
that give it that that use so this is
really starting to look pretty pretty
all-encompassing now here is the kicker
this is the one where I said there's a
twist this was an interesting case in
which in which hewlett-packard was given
a license - to make - they were given a
license to be a foundry for some certain
chips that you know they were they were
able to manufacture them and sell them
to other people another company another
company that did not have a license to
the IP so Intel gave them HP this
license some other company you OSI said
hey we've designed this chip that does
the same thing as Intel's chip can you
manufacture it for us HP was like sure
they took the design they manufactured
sold it back and they gave it to him the
the quartz HP Intel students said you
LSI is not an authorized person to have
designed this thing they could not be
they are not a patent licensee
exhaustion doesn't apply to them because
we have never ever in our life talked
with ul si the court said it doesn't
matter because it passed through the
hands of a company that was authorized
under a patent license now when you
think about this what does this mean
oh by the way what if we did it outside
the country I had still exhausted so
what if we the court also said there is
there's this idea of you only can allow
it under contract which means that in
theory you could have a contract that
would have some some results that people
people did certain things but in the
context of a free software free software
license you've given them the contract
it's a free software license and it says
you can do anything that you want so I
only got about five minutes left but I
want to talk about a scenario imagine
that we had I'm this isn't true this is
all made up but I'm going to use some
real names just so that you can so it's
a little more concrete imagine that
Qualcomm Qualcomm made a chip that
happened to read that happened to embody
a patent that was owned by 18 T now it
wasn't the AT&T in Qualcomm had a deal
it was just they happened to have
invented or used you know the same thing
that happens all the time somebody
decides well that somebody's realizes
that this chip is embedded in all these
phones and so they happen to go to an 18
t store and they don't want the phones
for you know to to join in
in to go with 18t service they want to
crack them open and take these chips
their qualcomm chips so they crack them
open they open it up and they go to a
festival that come to Fossum they set up
an alternative thing and it turns out
that they can make a business out of
creating a competitor to 18t because
they took these chips AT&T finds their
patent and Sue's who wins well first and
says your patents are exhausted 18 say
it says look we didn't you know we
didn't like license you said I bought it
at an AT&T store Oh
Qualcomm didn't have a license doesn't
matter I got it from you turns out the
analysis is no different if it is a
piece of software that passes through
someone's hands now let me give one big
caveat to all this Court's art can are
frequently going to try and avoid
surprising outcomes and like I said this
is where it got surprising to me so it
could be that a court says I'm gonna
pair this back and I'm not really good
even though I see your point I'm not
gonna allow this but we have in the in
the free software community this idea of
having mirrors and distributions and
these days we've got distributed
distributed source control where
everyone is throwing around copies of
the source code willy-nilly turns out
that for example if someone has mirrored
a copy of a Linux distribution with its
thousands and thousands of patents by
this analysis they Pat it passed through
their hands and they became an
authorized distributor of it under all
of their patents makes it so that
someone like Microsoft who just bought
github
[Music]
yes turns out that if we go out and we
find patent code distributions that have
passed through Samsung's hands and
Intel's hands and 18 T's hands and
everybody's even incidentally we have we
can do an n way merge on all of these
because it's all the same code we're
just like figuratively merging all these
patent rights and creating sort of
public fact that all this code is
exhausted with regard to everybody with
who's who with regard to everybody whom
it has passed through
so I have a question and you talked
about exhaustion yeah geez so exhaustion
as you described it and that was my
understanding is is based on goods as in
the physical objects is there Authority
for this proposition that exhaustion can
apply due to to suffer electronic
distribution of where is it good and if
you want for example one of the one of
the cases was about Android exhaustion
in and it wasn't included in a phone or
in some little object it was
specifically the dalvik virtual machine
right and it was just downloaded it was
it wasn't that is correct it body did a
physical thing that's correct
that was Cascades computer innovation
versus Samsung I think in the back
sorry I'm still a bit confused about the
concept of exhaustion so does it mean
that if you have a patent and you
license it to me does that mean I have
the right to use your code and and then
distributed with a copyleft license
depends on it means that if I have a
patent and I license it to you then you
can distribute it to your neighbor and I
can't sue your neighbor I can't see you
because I've given you a license and I
can't sue your neighbor because the
patent is exhausted
someone this is why to design patents in
the US I've not done the analysis with
regard to design there's a person way in
the back
who's had his hand up for a little while
I saw your question Philippe we'll get
back to you so there's one case you
didn't address here that I think you
need to if you're gonna do this analysis
which is the bowman monsanto
self-replicating seed cases yep I think
that's very relevant to the problem of
once the article has been distributed
and exhausted there's a subsequent
replication I agree so I that that one
causes problems with chains of
distribution I think at least as far as
people are so that is a great point and
here's why I think it's in opposite the
reason why is because that was in
particular about a self-replicating item
but in this case you have to look at the
context of what exact that that could
create a problem in other contexts but
particularly in the free software
context this the software has been
passed on with an explicit right to make
and to distribute and to patent to pass
on the rights for others to make in
distribute
it is a licensed target means that the
first part it means that the party who
receives it under the open-source
license the scope of their license
included the right to make the Monsanto
said we may have given you a license to
use but we didn't give you a license to
make therefore the self-replication you
can't do in this case to add yeah okay
one last question
so a pathetically hypothetical example
say I have a patent for a video codec so
and someone in my company redistributes
some piece of software with ffmpeg which
happens to have an implementation of
this codec and just makes the code
available like that that would exhaust
my patent to anyone which has received
ffmpeg if if someone who is an
authorised licensee of FM MPEG passes it
on with rights for other people to under
the and if an authorized licensee of the
patent this is it on with the rights
that our company with every open source
right license I would say that yes that
gets exhausted so for example by the way
for H 2.65 and ABC if you can find a
copy of ffmpeg under GPL from Samsung
they're caught there and members of two
of the patent pools okay I was just
gonna say find somebody who's a member
of MPLA that happens to redistribute
Linux or something fantastic thank you
[Applause]