right so I'm gonna talk about
a bill of materials editor that I'm
working on for kids mr. org so kiss mr.
OGG is a project sharing platform where
you pretty much at this stage you put
stuff in a git repository somewhere and
send me a link or send me a pull request
and gear up to add your project and the
idea is to have this a repository of of
easily replicable designs so on a kid's
face page you have the way to is to see
what the what the PCB would look like
and you can download the Gerber files or
have it's got links here to go to Eisler
or PCB way to have it made and a lot of
spent a lot of time on these tools to
automate the the parts ordering process
so there's buttons on there too which
uses a browser extension called the
one-click building materials browser
extension to automatically add
components to retailer shopping carts so
the the problem with this is obviously
it's quite hard to for people to
properly document their bill of
materials and actually even a lot of the
projects on gear up on Kidspace already
they don't have business materials that
are purchasable because it hasn't been
fully documented so it's quite a I guess
the frustrating process for people to go
through this so I've been working on
this editor tool right now it's a
standalone kind of application web
application
the idea is to integrate this into kits
base so that you when you press edit a
project edit the pillow materials on
kids base this would be it would be
there's something similar to this so I'm
just going to show you like the workflow
in this just looks out of date there we
go this is the new one
so the idea really here is you can you
can open your existing color material
and it would and you can even import a a
CAD PCB already so we're going to try
that so this is the PCB from the ruler
currently this means it's thinking and
create and you can see right so you can
import there and it's it it grabs tries
to grab the descriptions of your project
you can then look at this and maybe
reduce this down a bit really this is a
1206 1k resistor and then it's going to
understand that actually so then you can
go to digi-key and see whether you want
to buy that one you can select it you
can select specific parts here and you
can even even for these when it's when
it's basic one is when this is green
it's pretty sure that it knows that you
want this part so I've been working on
doing this Auto filling so we're able to
select all these parts for you there
this magic one means it's like this is
already a part that you've selected so
it's really sure that you you want this
power number in here so what's how am i
doing on time five minutes ago I should
have stopped what five minutes five
minutes to go I can go back to the demo
I'm just gonna finish off like because
this is a software developer conference
talked a bit about the tack just how
this is made so these are the kind of
features currently you can import the
bomb and you can import the Chi CAD PCB
and quickly select parts and then you
can download a CSV file which you can
then use to add a Kidspace project or
you know you can keep it for yourself
you the the the plan with this obviously
is to integrate it into kit space to
have more cat imports for all the
different CAD files and kind of grab the
Bill of Materials information from there
and help you make a proper Vilnius here
as out of that we want really better
price information like price summaries
and being able to reduce the bill of
materials by price to optimize for price
or to optimize for what retailers you
prefer or anything like that if we need
my accurate price information to do that
I've almost finished this part to then
go from here from the have a button here
to kind of reduce the bomb billow
materials to your preferred retailer and
then use the one-click dealer materials
browser extension to to buy the parts so
you can easily from your bill of
materials making process go to your
shopping cart so nope so the
architecture is fairly boring I'm gonna
I'm kind of a language nerd and for this
for all this kid space stuff are just a
kind of so far I stick to JavaScript and
like modern established working ways in
JavaScript so it's a kind of as the most
most a lot of stuff is on the client
side and this application is kind of
almost like a standalone I this is like
it's statically its to static hosting
and then the server side is just
currently a single application that just
kind of hooks into other api's and gets
the information it used to do some
scraping as well I've just stopped out
but I could again also use scraping
techniques to get the information into
there and the reason it's not just using
up to par API because they
there's some improvements on the stock
information the price information that
we can get from other places octopod is
a great API but it's not perfect so
plants I'd like I said really boring
stack kind of modern using react are
using semantic UI which is like good for
the user interface it allows me to not
worry so much about how things look and
I'm fairly happy with this the kind of
default style styling for semantic UI so
I don't spend a whole lot of time on how
that looks so the server side more
JavaScript nodejs and the reason for
this or the that I keep using javascript
is that I can develop libraries that I
can either use on the front end or on
the server side and I can pull them in
and use them on both sides one of these
libraries is is the electro grammar
which I've mentioned in an in talk last
year at first term which is a I don't
think we have time for this API demo
electro grammar is a is a JavaScript
library to Paris eloquent electronic
components descriptions and this is
where really what makes this tool more
usable than just to straight up the
standard octopod search or API access
one time one minute so I've just started
like trying to finance this project a
bit more because I spend a lot of time
on this so I've just opened a open
collective so if you start using these
tools and you find them useful please
consider supporting these projects
there's other people obviously my
cousins the whole thing on kids face
with how the Gerber's the gerber preview
of your board that was an amazing
project called PCB stack-up by my
cousins who has done an amazing job
with it David Skirvin has helped me on
electro grammar and yeah I'm hoping
we're gonna get more contributors so I
think this kind of collective way of
receiving donations would work for this
maybe we have time for one question if
you would we are with where we are I
wouldn't say we're duplicating a
standard we're making it we're using the
existing standards and the existing
language that engineers use but we're
making it like a simple interface for
understanding that language or I I guess
I didn't understand your question fully
what applies for you so you just update
and you can recognize it when you update
a file you can graduate upon tables for
you well I guess the answers like the
jeddak's standards and the other
standards for how to hard how do you
describe components and we're trying to
use all of that we're trying to use all
of that so that you can just write that
name and then we under like the the the
parser understands what you mean
you