okay I'm Hannah - Cisco system and I'm
going to present to you a small project
that we created to test our routers in
our feature on the router
it's called 2x and actually it was my
first journey in the open-source because
my friend asked
told me try to open source it don't put
it in your drawer and this is the result
okay so I'm going to talk about traffic
generation how we are doing it in Cisco
to test our routers and it's all based
on software okay today there is a DP DK
library and I will talk about that so
because I have very very short time I
will talk about stateless and advanced
stateful mode of the traffic generator
let me start with the result the result
after we open source the traffic
generation it seems that many has the
same problem many needed traffic
generator to test the routers so for
example many open source started to your
TX like opening a VDP decay if you want
a fight or Cisco internally and many
time in Cisco and Intel and Mellanox and
rather small this is say from analytical
our documentation you can see that it's
growing about 1,000 users actively and
this is the mode of operation because
there are many type of modes that you
need to test the need to be modes of
operation from the traffic generation
for example you don't need realistic
traffic to test a switch right because
there is only a switching of packet of
simple lookup but when you want to test
snow the doing inspection and
normalization and dpi and you need to
create a realistic traffic something
that with layer 7 that simulate client
server and application if
really to evaluate the performance of
the of the gear that you want to test so
there are in general two modes of
operation stateless and stateful with
more one of them I will talk about
advanced eight fool and I will talk
about stateless okay the problem that we
try to solve again is to estimate the
performance of stateful features on the
router stateful feature on the router
behaving in a weird way you know for
every flow we open the context we cache
the clients cache the server try to
normalize the traffic and so forth and
by bumping a UDP packet in short packet
it we won't get any reasonable number
it's not it's not it won't give us
anything but because of that we need to
generate realistic taxes realistic
traffic the problem is that realistic
traffic really cost really expensive
like 500k 450 gig or 100 gig and it's
not flexible and this is the reason that
we open source this so what is t-rex
t-rex is a software it's an application
it is a Linux application in sit on top
of DP DK and it's exposed a free way of
off mode that I've already talked about
and using that it can come with a
container and it's scalable everything
is about scale and virtualization this
is how you know I perceive it it's
really really fast everything is from
bottom up is scale and this is the slide
I'm using in Europe there is another
slide for the US okay let's talk about
stateless stateless is a way to generate
traffic to test switches it composed the
building block is
is a stream we call it a stream and you
can add more stream remove swim and the
API is json-rpc and we created a Python
that simplify the way that you can walk
with it so there is a server side you
install the to excel and then you
interact with it with the client moves
the Python you add stream remove stream
get statistics started to remove and
everything else there is a nice GUI that
works on top of this API on JSON RPC API
and let's see what is stream which is
the traffic mix that we are using so you
can build a profile that built from
streams in this example there is three
streams the blue one the green one and
the yellow one so the blue one is a
packet that I can generate using Scapa
anyone knows copy okay so you can build
a packet a template of a packet and then
you can build a program that change the
packet over time for example I I want to
create a range of salt IP to destination
IP and then I can choose the mode the
the right the the blue one is continuous
just bump the packet in specific right
the green one is a burst of packet let's
say I want only three packet and the
yellow one is the multi burst with inter
packet gap inter burst gap and I can
connect them I can create a program
let's say when the green one finished
starved the yellow one and then point to
another stream it's like a program that
you can build on pipe using Python let's
see how simple it is before that so this
is the architecture the eye level
architecture there is a server there is
an RPC using JSON RPC there is a data
path that I talk later on that is
scalable with if the number of scope as
you add more cause you will get linear
scale with the performance which is
really high and then come the Python
that encapsulate all the JSON RPC in
nice API and there is a Java API for
someone Ericsson is supporting that and
there is a GUI and there is a console
there is the API okay you just brought
wrapping everything for the users so we
separated the definition of the profile
from what to do with the profile this is
a definition of the profile I define
this day Lord of a profile of stateless
we defined really a simple continuous
but continuous stream with this
definition Ethernet of the IP over UDP
over 10 axis okay this is the packet
there will be a different type of packet
from different direction from one
direction it will be 1600 one to 4800
one and the other direction into the
opposite this way we can create be
directional traffic so this is the
profile and then we can manipulate the
profile load it so there is a console
that you can start the profile oh the
profile get statistic about the profile
and so forth and there is the API this
is the API impact on that we run
everything
so in this way we are connecting to the
clock to the server and then reset
everything restore all the statistics
add the stream that I showed already
clear the statistic start the traffic
and here I can multiplied and say that
the traffic that I want is five mega
packet per second for the duration of 10
seconds and then I can wait after I wait
I can get the statistics how much
bracket well how many drops how many
packets were sent and so forth okay so
really really simple API and qyx do the
hard work to separate what you asked it
what we're asking to multiple Co it's by
magic that under you don't need to
separate their profile so this is the
the thing that we do for you this is the
performance visits on the XL 7:10 on one
core you can see that we can reach to 13
13 mega packet per second in one quo and
it's linear scale so it's all about the
performance
so let's bet let's talk about stateful
stateful is more for feature that
inspect the traffic like dpi like snort
like firewalls like NAT they need to
generate stateful traffic in this
example TX can act like a server or like
a client and generate traffic on top of
TCP stack that we wrote the reason that
we wrote the TCP stack is that if you
will take a TCP stack from Linux it
won't scale it won't it will scale to 1
million packet per second and we needed
much more we needed 10 million 40
million active flow generating 200 gig
and this is how we did we took a BSD
native BSD stock and we changing in a
way that it would be multi Co every
instance of this every thread instance
had in separate stack and we did through
the API for the control plane separated
the application to each code and we
manager from the perspective of the user
you see one box that do one thing ok so
there is a layer of emulation of
application on top of the TCP stack on
top of DP DK and everything is
event-driven
every call as an event you even look no
thread nothing no locks no interaction
between them it's only a messaging
between the core and by that we can
reach really high scale this is an
example for the emulation layer ok the
clients for example do a request and
then write for response and then can do
a delay of random and then send another
request wait for response and close the
server-side do the opposite you wait for
the request
and response and so forth okay this is
just them at their low world of the
lower level microcode that we have in
the emulation layer let me show you a
real profile remember the profile of the
stateless it was Python it's talk it's
talk about streams here we are talking
about application on top of TCP stack so
in this example and we have a utility
that can take a pickup file convert it
to the instruction that they the
emulation layer understand and then
replay it on top of the TCP stack from
the client to the server and so forth
and by that reaching millions of levels
millions of client talking to each other
and exercise the device on the test with
millions of flows I will show
performance so just to drive in what we
are doing inside so from amulet from
simulation point of view from the client
side we are simulating creating a socket
connect once we got the syn synack we
are writing a buffer to the TCP stack
and then reading this is an example of
write and then read and then we close
the flow from the server side we don't
open all the flow or the server side of
time because we cannot do that like
let's say we have a medium server we
won't do the bind and socket because we
might not need all of them so we have a
special API to them because we rewrote
the TCP stack from BSD we had a lazy
allocation once we get a packet to a
server we dynamically simulate
everything like it created the socket
bind listen and then start the program
but you don't need to do that right this
is internal you just need to define what
you want to do to provide the pickup and
we will do it for you and get all the
statistics with this example is to
template there is taunt of stone of
statistics statistic is the God here
right we cannot miss even one packet so
you can take a JSON of all the counters
from the TCP stack from the flow table
start from UDP and from other layers of
the traffic generator I want to touch
really one point of the complexity what
we did finish the real engine by the way
of the car that I showed this before so
let's see what is the problem with scale
with TCP with this one flow of participe
okay in the transmit side you have a
sliding window let's say 32k 64k it is
how the M buff and buff is the layer
inside the kernel that manage the
pointer inside the packet which is how a
packet look like okay it's knit 32k in
the worst case if we need ten millions
flow let's do the math 10 million slow x
32 k it's about close to half a gig of
memory but we cannot have half a gig of
memory for ten millions flow we support
40 million flows okay so what we did is
we changed the api of the stack instead
of pushing the data to the stack the
stack is asking us asking the data from
us
from the upper layer and by that we are
saving a lot of memory see we can use
for 10 million flow only dot one gig of
memory and you don't need to do anything
you just need to write to use one of the
the profiles that already have and you
change it a bit and we will do it for
you the same problem happened in the RX
ID when there is a drop there is a
windows that try to accumulate
everything ok and just to show you the
last comparison we compare Ingenix with
t-rex to t-rex client and server and the
performance is facto 100 faster and from
memory perspective is free order of
magnitude that's it
you
[Applause]