and next up we have Brian Burke I'm just
going to talk about to go garbage
collector run of applause
hello well thank you for coming along so
late
who who has tuned a garbage collector
okay not too many people okay so I was
wondering who would show up to this talk
anyway let's I'm gonna talk about tuning
the gold garbage collector all of the
settings you can use to do that with
that's a joke that nobody got okay
we'll get there we'll get there so first
of all let me introduce myself my name
is Bryan Boram you can follow me on
Twitter and ask any questions you like
afterwards that way I work for a company
called weave works we do like DevOps
tools continuous deployment stuff like
that
I like making code go faster it's like a
video game for me so that's kind of why
that's the that's where I'm coming from
when I when I want to tune the garbage
collector
oh I need to stay here I need to not
walk sorry I could I can walk around
here it's too far no yeah so let me let
me tell you about my terrible life so
the first the first UNIX machines are
programmed had four megabytes of RAM and
I used to we had a server with sixteen I
used to sneak on to the server to do my
compiles because I didn't have enough
RAM and fast forward at weave works we
run the SAS this cloud system on Amazon
we we had these 32 gig machines a couple
years ago and we prepaid a year and we
spent basically a whole year running out
of RAM on 32 gig machines and tuning it
and and then finally the prepay ran out
and we went to 64 gig machines and their
room I'm certainly much more relaxed now
so yeah so so we care about the garbage
because you know if you don't take out
the garbage it fills up and your life is
a mess and so on and so on so I this
these are some slides from a talk I did
last year I might just skip through
those in the interests of time basically
the point I was making is is you every
time you garbage collect it kind of runs
all the way through memory than your
process so you have stuff in cache can
we can I move the mouse around yeah the
cache is over here so the cache has got
stuff in it and then after the garbage
collector runs it's kind of it's kind of
run through your whole the whole memory
space looking at stuff and basically
emptied your cache and it slows down
your program in ways that you might not
expect you know certainly it's garbage
collection slows you down more than just
the time it spends garbage collecting
because it interferes with the cache
behavior of the machine so this is
another picture to try and make the same
point
stuff you have on the stack it's very
easy to clean up you know when you when
you finished using something on the
stack we just go zip just move the stack
pointer it's all gone stuff on the heap
the garbage collector has to go all the
way through it looking carefully and and
saying is this thing still in use can we
find it from somewhere else and so
that's my like introduction to the
theory of garbage collection so we need
to worry about it it's going on all the
time and you're in the go runtime we we
are impacted by it whether we notice or
not so let's look at the options to tune
the garbage collector
these are all the options you get to
tune the garbage collector in Java yeah
okay they're not all these are these are
all the ones I could find in like 20
minutes of googling yeah let's let's
look at the list of options you get to
tune the garbage collector in go you
ready there is one option I signed up to
do a 30-minute talk about one option 25
minutes okay
and actually the timer is not running so
who knows who knows how long this takes
you can get good yeah okay so let's look
I'm gonna hopefully do a live demo if
the live demo doesn't work I have screen
captures so I'm running a client-server
micro service set up as my demo the
server is a thing called pod info from
my colleague Stephan the client is from
Jana doggin who was here this morning
but it's not here now in there my client
is the thing called hey that just just
like generates HTTP load so let me see
if I can get my demo going okay so so
the first set up is a a big server
process a big server process that has
some kind of large amount of data in
memory that basically sits there all the
time like a cache of results or you know
some data set that it's processing or or
something like that
and I have simulated this by
I scrolled it up too far yeah I I put
actually added that option to Stefan's
program I just allocated half a gigabyte
of memory just in a byte slice this I
could probably try and make a bit bigger
hey they go so what I want to point out
is the this is the easiest like garbage
collection in action I am I'm hitting it
with like five requests a second so it's
it's not really doing very much it's
using basically nearly zero CPU but the
memory is going up and up and up and
then back down again up and up and up
bang down again everybody really got
that so this is garbage collection in
action you good thank you and this is
the default behavior of the goal garbage
collector is it will it will clean
everything up as much as it can and then
the next time it garbage click collects
will be at twice that value okay so the
III hogged half a gigabyte of memory in
my program my programs not doing
anything it's just like returning some
string saying it's alive or something
like that but the the program as a whole
is using an extra half a gigabyte of
memory over and above what I allocated
because that's the behavior of the go
garbage collector and that so that
setting go GC is a percentage and the
default percentage is a hundred percent
so it gets a hundred percent bigger and
then it collects so I mean the way I got
to learn about this actually the this I
found this setting in the prometheus
system Prometheus is a good example of a
program that sits there very large in
memory and the Prometheus authors tuned
the go GC value down so let's just try
and do that I'm going to put the
microphone down and take for a second
okay so I'm terminating my server so I'm
gonna run the same server I'm typing
one-handed so that I would probably use
ctrl Keys and things go GC equals 50 oh
I typed I typed good GC with a small
letter so let me just ctrl see that and
do it again
thank you very much mr. microphone stand
so I'm running pod info inside a
container that has nothing to do with
the demo I'm monitoring it using
Prometheus that again has nothing to do
with the demo and I'm visualizing it
using graph on ax which is drawing these
charts
who knew Griffin I could do white as
well as black right yeah like they go
the you learn you learned something else
so so what I've done I left the load
generator going and I changed go GC to
50 right here okay and so what is going
to take a few seconds just to flow
through on the chart but what we can see
is it's now garbage collecting closer to
the to the the kind of baseline right
and in fact what it should kind of
steady out at the 750 level so this is
this is a trick you can use you just set
that environment variable go GC if if
the situation you're in is your program
naturally has a huge amount of memory I
mean you know our Prometheus server sit
at 20 gigabytes in fact we run we've
works runs a hosted Prometheus as a
service and we actually we have this
thing called cortex which is like a
multi-tenant Prometheus and those
servers we have like a bunch of them
that sit at 20 gigabytes so we do not
want to spend an extra 20 gigabytes of
RAM just just doing that just kind of
letting the garbage collector chill out
so we use this variable in production
tuned down for the processes that have a
big stable memory base load okay and my
chart you know my charts kind of working
I did one earlier they just find that
the back to slides so a large stable
data sir yeah so if you turn it to 50
the garbage collector lets it go 50
bigger and and everyone's happy
what's the next one high GC rate small
heap okay let's try and let's try and
emulate that so shut down that server
yeah go on just trying on that server
we're gonna not hog the memory and we're
gonna leave go GC on the default okay
and then we were running hey like five a
second
I'm gonna run so this command is 10
concurrent threads doing 20 seconds so
200 a second and it's going to run it's
gonna run for two minutes so let's take
a look at the charts oops right so just
for clarity I have I have totally
changed my perspective the first example
was even though I'm running the same
program I'm in a different pretend now
the the first case I was pretending I
had a program that ran with a really big
stable data set so now I've moved to
pretending I'm working with a program
that uses very little memory like
something like a reverse proxy it turns
out we have one of them at work as well
and so what we observe let's rather than
let it run the full two minutes let me
put the the pre-canned stuff up on the
screen
the the CPU sorry the heap the heat was
like tiny like four megabytes or
something like that and I hit it with
these two hundred requests a second and
it went up to like ten megabytes the CPU
usage went way up the garbage collection
rate went way up you know before I was
showing you is garbage collecting like
once a minute now it's garbage
collecting 60 times a second so we can
go in the opposite direction we can
raise Gogi see we can say dear mr. Gore
garbage collector I would like you to
use more memory just like chill chill
out man and use more memory so this is
go G C equals 200 I could run the live
demo but you probably get bored go G C
equals 200 so now we're letting the
program use twice as much heap right we
can kind of see that sawtooth effect
here it's it's kind of leveling out at
about 10 it's still not using very much
more memory but if you if you compare to
the previous slide it's garbage
collecting half as often so like you
know I told you my life story I my whole
machine had four megabytes to begin with
but now we have we use 32 big machines
or whatever we can spend more memory
than 10 megabytes so so let's set go G C
equals a thousand there are we go so now
we're using you know it's a tiny tiny
demo program but we're using like 30
megabytes of memory here the go this is
the point where I ran it you can barely
see you can barely see that GT rate went
to about 5 or something like that and
the latency is lower they just skip back
let me let me use this thing so that was
the original one the latency was like 10
milliseconds and the latency just by
setting the GC
just to use like 50 mag instead of for
latency came down like a third so in in
certainly in my production life getting
getting your latency down by third this
is a pretty damn good result so that is
the second thing you can do with go GC
so first thing you can do is set it down
second thing you can do is set it up is
there anything else you can do with it
Brian you have a question it's a
percentage go GC is a percentage the
question was what is the unit of go GC
and it is a percentage of the minimum
heap size so when it garbage collected
in this example it collected all the way
down to about four megabytes times a
thousand percent is forty megabytes so
that's where it gets up to about about
here somewhere as forty megabytes right
yeah so it's a percentage relative to
the minimum size so I'll give you a link
at the end there's a really really good
presentation that goes through the the
like five-year history last five year
history of the go garbage collector and
all the reasons why they did things and
the background and so on and one of
their aims is to make this thing kind of
self tuning and self adaptive that's why
everything is relative that's why it
doesn't look like the java page so this
is a relative measure but there we go
so go GC set it to ten times the
original and my latency went down by
third my CPU usage went down to you know
about two-thirds the the GC rate went
down by factor of ten so that's that's a
pretty good result so I the there's a
there's another thing you can kind of
see it in this picture as well when the
load went away we
actually get all the way up to 40
megabytes right and in in this example
you can barely see it this is when it
was like ticking over on the on the 500
Meg case so it turns out there is
another setting for the go garbage
collector but it's not a setting that
you're allowed to set the goal garbage
collector will run every two minutes if
it has otherwise not run and so that's
useful if you like did something very
intensively in your program and then
stopped your program just wait it for
input then you know by the rules of
garbage collect when you hit a limit it
would like never run the garbage
collector and so your program would sit
there hogging all the memory in your
machine so they run it every two minutes
two times ten to the nine nanoseconds
every two minutes and they will actually
free the memory back to the operating
system if you're no longer using it in
in that scenario so so that's this this
sawtooth which I didn't actually know
about until I did these slides I didn't
know there was a two minute max on the
garbage collector it is it is a variable
but it's an unexploited variable in the
4300 line file that I had to read to
find it okay one last trick there is one
more thing you can do with go GC you can
set it to the word off so why would you
do that you would do that if you had a
truly infinite amount of RAM that's know
nobody has an infinite amount of RAM
okay but it turns out basically there's
there's a certain set of programs that
just will terminate before they've used
a huge amount of RAM so let me see do I
want to do the demo no I'm scared
at the pre-canned version so I just I
built the pot in full program that that
I'm using for the demo and it builds in
like seven seven and a third seconds on
my laptop if I turn off garbage
collection it builds in five and a half
seconds and this is a four year old
macbook so you know I don't have
infinite RAM yeah I think the the
compilation of that program which like
vendors kubernetes libraries and stuff
like that you know it's not a not a
trivial program the the compilation runs
in 50 50 Meg of RAM or something like
that it just does not need to garbage
collect and it sounds a little trick you
can try you can turn off garbage
collection in your compilations or if
you have some other kind of batch you
know batch operation and written and go
that just runs for a bit and then
terminates you can just turn the garbage
collector off and you might get a speed
benefit or you might get a crash I you
know this is open source no no
guarantees
okay fantastic picture from Ashlee
McNamara there we might get more go
garbage collector settings to tweak in
the future we might approach the Java
page over time so there are two that you
can read about clearly talked about one
is set max-heap because you know this
thing about I'll just go twice as big as
I was last time you know at some point
it goes back oh this is this was my life
right for most of the last year our
processes would crash in production and
so just telling the garbage collector
like yeah I love your sawtooth but just
don't go above 20 gigabytes oh you know
whatever whatever number you pick so
what that does is it trades performance
for safety right because if you actually
need that much memory you you're
sawtooth is going to get faster and
faster and faster until eventually the
program does nothing because it's just
garbage collecting all the time
but that so this is in an experimental
branch of the goal run time that I
couldn't actually find but I can I can
read about it and you can google it you
can find all that stuff on the other
side there is also I think accepted
support for a minimum heap size so this
is this is basically the same thing as I
did with setting go GC very high saying
look I want you to use more memory but
it's like a safer way to do it because
the the multiplier has that dangerous
effect that the sawtooth might get out
of hand so good go GC min I think that
will show up that's a that's so much
simpler change to the runtime so
probably show up fast faster sooner okay
I am done with my talk
[Applause]
questions
No okay couple of Link's open question
yeah do I do I run with the mic thank
you so what about GC x r GC x strictly
linearly dependent with the amount of
ram that needs to be wiped
or is there a sweet spot between GC x
and them okay so I think you're you're
asking about the time the garbage
collector takes to run and and I was so
number one that I will say the the
impact of garbage collection on
performance is way bigger than the time
the garbage collector takes to run so so
that go over the last few revisions move
to a largely garbage collecting in the
background so the actual time it stops
your program for is is under most
circumstances tiny tiny tiny their edge
cases that whole slide about the like
the cash and so on garbage collection
will slug your program will really slow
it down in ways that are really hard to
understand you know it's it's just this
fact that it's trolling through
everything in your program so so there
is no metric you can other than other
than the end result like my latency went
down by a third so that was the impact
that GC was having on my program there
is no measurement of GC time that will
add up to a third and I so you know
sorry that I do this a lot and that is
absolutely my finding there's there is
no simple relationship between anything
and anything you've got to kind of try
the different values and see what hum
comes out okay out of time thank you
very much
you