I'm gonna talk about VR map which is
bringing OpenStreetMap data so it's
actually using the real book data is one
thing I would like to know is how many
people here are this treatment users at
least okay how many of you have dirty
with the overpass API so very few okay
it's any any one thing to my talk
yesterday okay it's gonna be very
similar I will talk a little bit more
about the Open Street Map parts of this
but it will be very similar it's the six
lights this lights are up it's sliced up
and on et / post of 2019 I did not get
around yet to put it on the main page of
slice cavity they will be there link
there I think tomorrow or something as
soon as I get to it I'm Robert Kaiser
I'm
speakers people from the Cairo and I've
also an Open Street Map contributor in
happening for for a long time mostly in
Austria also pretty active in the
Austrian mistreatment community so what
is this talk about mainly what I want to
tell me about is the cross device nature
of those technologies of web PR or red X
are the ease of use of the library I'm
using which is a free which makes it
really easy to get stuck in Internet we
are and the ability to use of this
rhythmic data in for this audience
specifically also a few tricks and doing
data for disabilities age
so first what is wrap it with XR or red
VR it's virtual when we are special
really become with map technologies XR
is average is mixed reality this is a
pretty moocher
standards everything ended at the w3c
there's a Reiki group or - and the
proposed standard for medics are the TR
parts of that are still somewhat in flux
the VR parts of that are pretty stable
now and multiple browsers actually have
implementations for it with bases on web
GL Web Audio and for the controllers on
the game played in panic api's it can be
used on full VR headsets of course both
the three degrees of freedom ones like
this one and the six degrees of freedom
that give you full immersion so you can
also walk in the sea with those who
cannot return around and um for the
desktop devices for the PC connected
devices like the HTC vive in the oculus
rift Firefox in release on Windows
already supports that we are completely
to just plug in your HDMI for whatever
launch the VR tools launch Firefox and
enter the VR from the browser with HTML
technologies on make I think it's in
beta right now it was set back to
nightly at some point and then back into
beta again
it's me but they're helping the few
complications with the drivers only
that's the driver the drivers for the
HTC vive are still experimental in the
graphic stack so it's not there yet but
it's in breaks for the oculus rift
there's no drivers for for making Linux
as soon as Facebook but if they stopped
all development on that completeness
make your own thing out of it but that
said the the default oculus browser on
the go and the Samsung internet browser
for the their Samsung devices those also
implement where we are and this person
no microsoft test them some support in
the edge for the blue lens and it won't
know the real estate so there is
implementations in few browsers of
course for for those standalone handsets
there is Firefox reality which also
supports it which is a browser for the
span of assets
the our map itself is a demo I did with
life of mistreatment data from the
overpass API that's why I asked before
it's usable in 2d mode even outside of
the VR devices so you can actually use
your phone or your tablet or your PC and
look into this as well I will in the
next slide or in next minutes show you
the same thing here in the projector
just need to be bold but when you go
into the our device where you have
controllers where you have a headset you
can immerse yourself into it it's using
the Mozilla Ifrit library I'll be coming
back to that and it's a very simple
thing it only has about 80 lines of HTML
most of which are the starting dialogue
which we will see and about 300 lines of
JavaScript and quite a bit of that is
cool I'll actually show you because it
makes a few decisions about defaults for
for stuff that comes from Sweetman but
the code is not very difficult
it's made for people like you to take it
and make something of yourself so let's
take a look at the theme on itself when
you when you launch it this is the start
catalog and that's that's what I said
take takes up quite a bit effect of
those 80 lines of HTML and most of it is
explanations including of course the
OpenStreetMap okay right and you have a
few presets of where we can go those are
presets that have at least something
that that looks decent you can actually
enter coordinates and this before in the
Catherine if at the rear is someone if
it was oh wow this is actually this
place where I'm at home everybody seems
to do where is at home so did I because
this first preset is what what you see
the back there is actually in front of
the door of the building I'm living this
is very rude to it and already went
there to not bore you with flying around
too much so this is the view of very
neat back there is currently if you
wonder so this is a view around of part
of this area
I'm not loading more than this area
right now in this demo expect the code
is made in a way that it should be
- dynamically old more but for a demo I
was like let's not go into the
performance aspects of when you have too
much loaded I want to be able to show
this off and we want to take more out of
it
it's not easy these are hard to figure
out one thing that's nice here and
that's why I like the example of this
area is that in the end we could import
some data for it for the trees
old trees in in public area listen man
have been open government index and
being parted that into OpenStreetMap and
so we know the height of the trees we
know the circumference leaves and so on
and we know the diameter of the crown
that is and the circumference of the
track so I can use all that I still used
a very simple model for trees but still
you get different sized trees and that's
that's pretty nice in in that you
preview picture I have to do you see
that for me the leaf trees I have a
different way of displaying that
movement so because we have that data as
well and open treatment has the taste
for it which is nice so yeah that with
the EWS keys you can fly around in the
scene you see there is
in there those trees have I did have no
further text those are just some
defaults and it is you have different
heights of the buildings as well which
[Music]
usually you know mistreatment you don't
have a lot of heights of buildings you
have some but then if you have the
amount of levels building hairs you can
do a pretty good estimate that didn't
have a few things I'll show you a bit of
that of how I get to two high swing
I don't know much in this area I walked
around with the sheet just put in out
with printed out of the treatment data
and just wrote this is six stories this
is 5 this is 4 this is 1 and so we get a
pretty nice picture of realistic view so
that that's the demo it looks the
principle so to make that code simple I
had to start with a few simplifications
and one of them was that the world is
flat actually it's flat in two ways in
this demo for one thing there's no
curvature over it that makes it much
easier in terms of calculations and for
the other thing there's no hills and
valleys but before the flat flat very
supported series 2 is too much
I actually had to respect the latitude
and the curvature of earth because I'm
using the ground tiles from Rakata
protection and those change size based
on latitude and so the coordinate system
inside the VR space is in meters so I
needed the size and meters of those
ground times those round tiles are I'm
just using from the default method eight
tiles that OpenStreetMap renders I'm
using it via a tile cash operating
myself to not over text in suite map
service the trees and buildings though
I'm taking directly from the overpass
API so that's really life data if you
change it in OpenStreetMap you can add
the tree few minutes later you actually
have it in this database fun
there is a camera control Isetta that
the library has some defaults but if you
want the controller's to work right you
need to put some setup in there and to
enable this flying navigation
that as well and it's filled with the
a-frame library so the apron library I
just mentioned that second time and now
I really should tell you what it is
it's Mozilla library that makes it
really really easy to create VR sites
basically you include a JavaScript file
at the top of your HTML file and then
you write some text those are not in
HTML standard but the library interprets
them and make something out on the
outside you put in a scene tag and then
everything in there is used in Ryan
dirt-eater VR space like in a sphere and
a cube and a cylinder they playing the
planes are tiles on the floor of course
this here is not the cold and I'm using
this in an example and I'll show you in
a minute
how this example is and you can even do
animation of things by just putting an
animation inside something and then this
is something is animated with those
properties and you just use standard
HTML with expected properties on those
things so you have a position you have
the radius that sky with the color is
just a sphere that has the inside
painted with that color and if you put a
sky SRC equals something then you
actually have this image that you put in
SOC projected on the inside of that
sphere you can very easily get a texture
on it this one for a 360 degree
so you only need to know HTML
Littlefinger br6 that's pretty nice to
show you how this example looks I
probably need to reload because it's
loading yeah and nice so it's a little
bit bigger that's the scene you just saw
described and dakotas it's small but
it's still up here it's to see the
default even has the the scrolling with
the keys is the keys and you saw the
animation with the tag and the cube is
just rotating this we didn't even write
any JavaScript it is it's routine that's
nice well underneath it it has the three
J's library which is a heavy JavaScript
thing but it's abstracted enough that we
do things so this is if you look at the
stuff slides the Edit view link is so
that what
you planned you can dynamically try out
stuff there as well
so if you want to you get can go in here
and see which one
this here this - yeah I can I can change
that
let's leave this year old not it's not
intimating at all because it's any
meeting pass hero and make let's make
this 360 and that's going to different
next and that can exchange to colors and
whatever in that didn't ease it's pretty
nice
you can learn more about a frame and a
friend got a ol he also has a few other
samples there but I wanted to get back
to to my vehicle
shortly looking to index.html but I'm
into that more in the Mozilla room and
you can look into it yourself as well I
want to get more to them than Street
mail things here that has to start
dialogue and this camera controller
thing Matt GS is the main javascript
file that that loads all all the stuff
and does the fetch from overpass
conversions is boring but it's necessary
because you have a lot of coordinates
conversions in their position limit is a
different component I wrote that and
it's a very nice example for how you
write a different component I mean this
yes
they will not do that today to have more
time for the OpenStreetMap parts I had
the problem when I was flying it could
fly through the ground so I said let's
do it right and write something that
prohibits me from going through the
ground and that's this it's a very nice
example of how to easily do the
component and then I have tiles trees
and buildings chairs that
fixing the tiles in the ground and the
trees and it's on github at my relation
to /vr half you will see that you're out
later and with that I'll look let's look
at the code then we come back to what we
learned so yeah this is the from
yesterday that's the component the one
thing that's interesting in the
component is there's a tick function in
there you just write one function and
that's cool that every time you display
updates
that's and basically on everything I set
back the coordinates if it's outside of
my constraints it's very easy so let's
go back here and take the shirt look
into index.html this has a lot of
importance of scripts this is the main a
frame and then have a few additional
components there is a components index
every mile rate can find a few things
they can easily plug in and make it
easier and without running stuff without
JavaScript Etzel date or dialogue and
then here we have the EC that still fits
on one screen a entity is basically the
div of a frame so it's the container
that it can be anything and can't
contain it and actually an a cube or
something is just a specialized a and so
the ground this is a workaround but the
met entity has a container for tiles and
the container for items which is recent
buildings and here's the camera rake a
component enables and other attributes
here so you have movement controls that
are you allowed to you beautifly and
here I'm putting in my that my own
component that you saw four minutes
their position limit equals with those
parameters that the y mean zero is the
really important one that I can not go
Lord I did not mention the coordinate
system
I said let's see why me just if it was
was an actual thing so if you stand in
the VRC then X is horizontal
why is vertical and sees the component
that goes towards you or away so that's
why wiving is zero and
I will not go into the mix-ins here but
you have a head that's 1.6 meters
there's a little brown which is feels
pretty natural for most people to have
the head but around that above the
ground and then you have a left-handed
right hand for the controllers and if
those those controllers if any of those
things is is present so it's it's not
that hard to understand to take a bit of
time to look at it I know it's a bit
fast now to just have something it's not
and then I want to take a bit of a look
so the tiles are pretty simple but
the tree so yeah anyone who has worked
with overpass here's the stuff that
looks familiar to those who have work
here I'm having the overpass query the
bounding box string is calculated from
whatever it is played in otherwise it
just those whole nodes with natural
equals three who has actually edited
OpenStreetMap yeah so those of you
natural equals three will be something
you have heard about it's and the the
system of notes ways and relations we
have heard about
for the others that the the data model
of open segment is you have points that
are notes that have coordinates the
definitions of nodes that are ways and
you can have relations that's just omit
reference to any object and any of those
can have a value tags so natural equals
trees is attack and that set tells me
that's a tree it's very easy to
understand in this case there are some
some that are not that easy authorities
in the bench that convert that to Chia
Jason because that's easy to process
afterwards and then here dynamically
creating and you'll see I'm just
creating HTML and enhancements so if you
ever created stuff with JavaScript if
you ever created elements with
JavaScript that's basically how you did
it if you did not use any abstraction
layer you can actually use all kinds of
abstractions like angular key
some chick Mary already Evert with this
as well and then I'm setting all kinds
of stuff here
I'm pretty much getting to and very
shortly looking to the buildings that's
a bit more difficult because I had to
find out before Heights so actually if
there is a height equals something right
I'm using the if there's a building
levels on it
I'm actually using that and calculating
times or have a meters by per level
variable which is said here so I
estimate every level is about three
meters which is pretty okay
your feelings are usually
and even before and if I don't have that
it gets here but there's sometimes
there's building equals like Chios or a
cabin or something like that or carport
I can safely assume those are one level
high those will not be higher than
that's usually and then I have some
special defaults like howls I'm
estimating is two levels at Papa as well
as apart the transformer tower I'm
estimating is ten levels now is 10
meters high in the water tower I'm
estimating is 20 meters just to have
something that looks somewhat realistic
and under construction I'm even giving
you the building's a different color
and if I don't have all that I'm going
back to a default and then I have even
have some specialty in there there will
not because of time is not care very
small buildings I even go to work so
it's not too hard
I hope it's not too hard so what we've
seen here is how across the customized
nature of those technologies when we are
pecs are you so I did two demos here you
have to believe me right now that it's
working in in the headset but we can
actually take a look at it afterwards in
this one it's a fuse of a frame I showed
that quite a bit and the ability to use
of this treatment data and a bit of how
you're using the OpenStreetMap data if
anyone's interested in should show your
you can look it up how which query I'm
using for the buildings and there's a
few improvements that can you get down
there but what I would really encourage
you to do is to look at the code make it
your own
those are two examples where people have
done that one was for finding the right
position of an actual
model of a building within a scene and
then you can use don't let right
position and put it back into a street
map so it's defined how those buildings
should be placed when being rendered
somewhere and always in real someone
actually made something very can ride
along the train line and see everything
that's right and with that I'm at the
end if you have any questions I'm happy
for those and if you want to look at it
yourself so the color is just a
correlate to something that I'm using
that I do not have the more extended
thing with building parts in it but the
whole building human color you actually
have that interest would support using a
photograph of the building as a texture
[Music]
you would need to program to some
programming to set the SSRC in whatever
in the it's a bit hard because it would
just protect it on around it so you will
probably need to do some manipulation
but I think it should be doable
well then we have to come to the end of
this day in this room please some
kindness for next year how to program