so I'm going to talk about VR map which
is webmix are with real-world data from
OpenStreetMap my name is Robert Kaiser
the if you want to look up the slides
they're already out fit my slides page
so right a slice of Cairo da/dt slash
post them 2019 if you just go to this
lie its Chi right T peaches will not be
in the index yet I still need to do that
usually do that right before the talk
but had some slight issue starting here
so I thought I haven't had a slide above
me here apparently I don't I'm most
other tech speaker and also a Mozilla
rep so community representative and I've
been with the Mozilla community for a
very long time I'm a big fan also a big
fan of the OpenStreetMap project and so
some time ago I said there could be some
things where I can bring those things
together and this is what came out of it
the objectives of of this talk are as
you can see cross-device nature of the
technology web we are or web X are
another objective is easy feed to show
you the ease of use of the a-frame
framework that Mozilla has been
developing for those technologies for
web the Arabic WebEx are and the third
is using Open Street Map data and the
ability to use Open Street Map data for
things like this so what is web PR or
WebEx are it's basically that VR is a
sub group of WebEx our device the WebEx
our device API XR is short for mixed
reality which encompasses both
augmented reality are in virtual reality
VR and everything in between
so that's an open standard that's being
developed right now in the w3c and it's
virtual and augmented reality with web
technologies directly in the browser one
thing that's interesting there is so for
one thing it's building on a few
technologies that we had before
WebGL for one thing the controller API
the gamepad API for the control area and
web audio but a few things in addition
and the one browser that even supports
it in release versions right now is
Firefox in on Windows you just need to
plug in an oculus CO or HTC wife into
your Windows machine startup Firefox and
you can enter web PR scenes in right
from the browser in your headset that
said in the standalone headsets like the
oculus go I have here and it already
says one of the browsers that supports
it
Firefox reality is the Mozilla browser
for the standalone headsets and also
from what I just recently heard in HTC
headsets it will be supported across the
lines it will even give you default
browser on the oculus go to the default
browser even supports web we are as well
and Samsung internet supports it as well
so it's pretty widely supported across
browsers in for the standalone handsets
and on on desktops for Windows Chrome
has an experimental mode that's in
experimental versions and I think
Microsoft has something
working for the hololens that i have not
seen that breaking but holos event is
also a bit constraint in what it what it
can do
and as a head on the slide for mac and
linux the story is a bit more difficult
for mac we're in the process of enabling
it I think it's not in release yet but
it may be in beta at the moment for
Linux it's very experiment because even
the drivers for the HTC vive are
experimental
there are no Mac or Linux drivers for
oculus because Facebook killed those off
when they bought oculus so they are map
itself is a demo for where we are with
life OpenStreetMap data as i already
mentioned and it works on any modern
browser in 2d mode the good thing with
those technologies web we are and
Bewick's are is they scale down pretty
well where they can so you can use it in
2d mode for example in your normal
browser and where we have a headset and
controllers it uses those as well it's
using mozilla iframe i'll come back to
that later and currently it's about 88
lines of HTML a lot of which is a
boilerplate for an intro dialogue and
about 600 lines of JavaScript a lot of
which is very simple ifs for a few
special cases as well so it's pretty
simple code it's intended for you to
grab it and make your own thing out of
it so I kept it as simple as I could
so let's go into the demo because I'm
talking about it all the time and I'll
need to look at at the screen for that
bit I think I'll turn my back to some
people so this this is how it reads you
that's the intro dialogue that's what
actually made
a lot of the HTML and you have a
selection of some preset places in the
default one I went to to some place here
is already so you see what's what's in
there there's basically three kinds of
things in there you have on the ground
you have a display of a normal map piece
that's just the the bitmap tiles from
OpenStreetMap then you have trees and in
F buildings the trees were my first
selection to do something because
they're on a point so it's easy to find
one point to render something on the
buildings are a bit more complex because
they have multiple points and complex
shapes nice thing in this piece here is
that we even have trees with different
heights and shapes because in this case
OpenStreetMap actually has the data of
the heights of the trees the crown
diameters and even the trunk
[Music]
circumference I think it is and so we
can actually render this and we can know
we only have leaf trees here broadleaf
trees here if we have needle leaf trees
here Iran very different sample as well
that looks more like a fir tree or
something so that's information we can
all use and of course of course the
height of of the buildings we can use in
some cases so with the ASD Keys you use
the W keys you can actually fly around
in the scene here and
[Music]
you see the the buildings have different
heights actually there's there's a few
where you see very harshly a different
heights there are in OpenStreetMap
sometimes you have the actual height for
the building sometimes you have the
number of storeys then I estimate from
the number of storeys what the height of
the building may be and otherwise I'm
using a default yes if you want after my
talk you can you can look at it in in a
headset as well that's main reason I
have it with me here let's go a bit back
to to how this all works
I need to find the talk again here and
actually in the in the preview you had
there so where's my mouse here should
have jumped back the slider they can do
it this way so so in the preview picture
here you see some some needle lift trees
as well I clicked instead of okay so
some basics here the one one main thing
here I had to go into is to make things
simple I decided the world is flat in
this example and actually in two ways so
there's no hills and valleys and
additionally I ignore the curvature of
Earth but before all the Flat Earth
supporters rejoice too much there's I
actually had to take the curvature of
Earth into account because the tiles I'm
using at the base have different size
depending on the latitude and I had to
respect that because in the VR system
all measures are in meters so I had to
actually calculate the size of the tiles
based on the Mercator projection I will
not go into the details what what
mattnic
rendering is that's default rendering of
OpenStreetMap you see there if you want
to hear a bit more details about the
OpenStreetMap expects of this i'm at the
end of tomorrow I'm giving a talking
about the same thing in the geospatial
room I will go into more of the
OpenStreetMap details right now I will
go in a bit more into the VR where we
are aspects of it so as I said there's
trees and buildings those come from the
overpass API which is the usual API for
Open Street Map and there's a camera and
controller setup that is in the HT a
frame scene and as I said it's built
with a frame so let's actually get into
what a frame is a frame is a library
that makes it really easy to write VR
scenes this is not what I have in my
code this is an example that's pretty
much the hello world example with a
small in addition everything in a frame
you put into inside an a scene
tag you include the JavaScript library
at the top of your HTML file then you
use this a scene tag and then you put
some other HTML like text into it for
example a sphere a cube cylinder
airplane the sky is just what you see
around you it's basically a big marble
where the inside is painted with the
color or if you put SRC equals an image
the inside is painted with this image as
a texture and then you give it positions
rotations and you can even do animations
so what you see in the cube here is I'm
putting an animation inside the cube and
that makes the cube animated which is
really nice because that usually needs
quite a bit of JavaScript and if I know
now where I loaded this
yeah here this is this is the same
example that you saw rendered with the
animated cube and you can pan around
here and I think there's no controls on
there so you cannot yeah
there's our controls on it by default so
you can actually move around in this as
well so that's the default that that
Efrain gives you if you go to the slides
to edit to use ik is exactly what i just
showed you and so the code itself is
structured pretty simply the index.html
has to javascript includes and and this
scene setup and the intro dialogue and
then there's map GS that that handles
the overall stuff like loading or
everything congressional thing but the
most complex thing because it handles
all the coordinate conversions that you
need in there efficient limit is a
different component it's pretty nice to
to see how a basic different component
looks because other in the first version
I could fly through the floor and that's
not that nice so I wrote the component
that actually prohibits flying through
the floor and this can actually really
meet even more in taos trees buildings
GS are for drawing those three types of
objects it's on github cairo 80 / vr map
so that's here there there is a readme
and stuff but that's not that
interesting the position limit I said is
an afferent components of it well let's
first I think we still have a minute or
two so let's go back here and
looking to the index.html so we have a
lot of JavaScript includes some apron
components and the rest is my JavaScript
and here we have the AC here's the a
scene starting and it has a background
color that's skylight and the ground we
can pretty much ignore that's a
workaround for for the for one of the
navigation components there's an a
entities the container it's basically
the diff of a frame a entity is the most
neutral thing and you can stuff anything
in there so the map has two things in
there 4,000 and items items are trees
and buildings those will be filled in by
JavaScript and the camera rig defines
things like where is the user where it's
looking where are his controllers in
which types of controllers are supported
how is can the user move things like
that so the movement controls has to fly
in it that means you can fly through the
scene that's that's one of the
components I'm loading earlier that
allows this and abstract sits all the
way from me then there is an entity ID
equals head with a position 1.6 meters
above the floor so the coordinate system
is is X Y and the Z is is going away
from you or towards you so the second
component being 1.6 Y of 1.6 means it's
1.6 meters above the floor which looks
pretty natural for most people for where
the head is even if you're a bit larger
or a bit smaller it looks pretty natural
so it's a good default and then you have
the stuff the two hands for the
controller is if you have
I will not go into the mixings
because we don't have that much time
right now but this is a pretty nice
example to play with and find out how
those things work I will put do one look
into this position limit as well because
it's a very very nice easy component so
I'm not sure if you saw in the
index.html the the camera rig says
position limit equals and then it has X
min zero and it has an x max as well but
the X means zero is the important one
why me sorry
now X Y means zero which means the
minimum Y component of the coordinate is
zero so you cannot go through the floor
and this component define that defines
those xmin xmax ymin ymax and it's same
for C and tick means a function that is
called
at every update of the rendering and so
at every update of the rendering which I
look if our current position is over it
violates the constraints and if it does
we set it back to the constraint very
simple but this way we can implement
this component and in in this HTML code
just write position limit and whatever
we need and it handles that so it's a
very nice abstraction and that that's
all it has it just has it for every of
one of those components I will not go
into more of the code because the time
is coming to an end here so let's recap
the cross device nature of web we are in
web web XR is something we've seen we
can use it in 2d mode as you solve and
I'm was presenting it you can use it
here with one control or you can use it
with the two controller fully immersive
headsets as well
ease of use of a frame you saw in a few
steps how we how you can easily get
stuff in we are done with a frame and
you saw a little bit of how
OpenStreetMap data can can be used there
if you as I said if you want more
tomorrow I'll be talking more about the
OpenStreetMap aspects there I'll be
cutting the other code pieces very very
short instead
otherwise it will be very similar so
last thing here is make it your own
there's two examples here toon 3d EMR
where someone made something to place
models in inside the scenes done with my
with my sample it might be our map
sample to find out which coordinates you
need to put to the to the object to have
it correctly positioned when we link
that model in OpenStreetMap so if you
careful graphically push it where it
needs to to go in then it extracts the
coordinates and gives you the correct
line to put into OpenStreetMap and osm
rail enables you to drive with with a
plane with a rail along a rail line and
see everything rendering around that's
that's two two examples
and with that I'm closing up I'm not
sure if we have much room for questions
but yes we do
and so the example I said we are make
RIT and the github you saw as well
maybe so much higher level yes I'm
arrived as soon as possible
hi I'm just wondering can you adapt this
technology to show elevation so for
example can you make the ground show
Hills using srtm data or anything like
that
does the a-frame allow you to have
variable height ground I think there's
no component for it yet but it bases on
three chairs I think it did not I did
not mention that yet which is a very
basic library that can do a lot of
things and mozilla actually is investing
a lot into 3GS right now to improve it
and with 3GS you can definitely render
very complex shapes as well so I think
you should be able to render that data
with three chests and then just put it
into an a-frame component very similar
to what I'm doing with the buildings in
this sample where I'm also constructing
in three tiers shape and then just
exposing it as an a-frame object
okay fine thanks any other question No
okay I'm arriving and as I said before
if anyone wants to see the full we are
you can do so here okay thank you so
much