can you build all these things because
after this table I want you to realize
that it doesn't matter it really doesn't
matter what you do because what you're
gonna have to do it's just to build the
component and and share that with your
team right it doesn't matter so let's
stop that war right away so um quick
agenda because we only have 25 minutes
and basically this talk it's designed
for a good hour because and then we go a
little bit into demos so I'm gonna speed
it up because I want you to see a bit
more the code part but I'm gonna brush a
little bit things about web component
showing you how old it is and then a bit
hard new it is right now so you we're
gonna go through all these this element
this element of the agenda
the most important part will be the
specifications and we're going to focus
only on custom element and shadow Dom
okay so and then a quick reference on
the framework world I just asked
question right now we saw kind of react
one angular sake and if you third and
once again that's part of that that line
right here but that war should end and
right now that's that's the point so
what is the web component someone want
to answer but doesn't have the mic right
I'm gonna answer for you and so before
before we even dive the question is
actually what is a component if I say
you know what is a component you raise
your hand so there is a part of the room
that doesn't know what is a component
and what is Wikipedia tell us it's
basically a components a piece of
software that is encapsulated extensible
composable and reusable some people call
that in software engineering a clear
module it has it has a behavior and then
it gives you an interface to interact
with right
and there are few keywords right there
you can see encapsulated extensive all
comfortable reasonable those are the
four keywords and this thing has been
around before the web even started if
you think about it but we haven't used
this concept in the front of the front
end engine front engineering
okay component for the web let's dive a
little bit into that so if you want to
build a component a few years ago you
know I know some people see that and
they feel like oh I've been doing that
it's ok it's ok that worked and then you
get basically angularjs that came with
directive it was amazing and then you
get all these new frameworks view react
I didn't put angular because there were
no space and I had already angularjs
there right so um you have those options
you had these options in the past and
now when you you go back to this
definition you realize that all of them
they were actually approaching component
that way ok so if you take this
framework what is the component for each
of these framework I know the react
people are bad to say everything is a
component right react right we're good
everything is a component about UGS no
you don't have component there right no
I'm kidding but you should have
component everywhere so the the main
part here is the fact that regardless of
the framework that you use the idea of a
web component is like it should be able
a component without being web component
first it the interoperability is the
most the most important part of what
we're trying to do ok so now we move
from component to web component
well component we pick wikipedia says a
lot of stuff about it right so I'm not
gonna read that for you I'll give you
two seconds we're good now I'm gonna
highlight part of that definition that
makes sense to all of us so what
component we have HTML and um
specification yeah it is just a
specification what does that mean means
if you were to implement a framework
that respect us those specification
you're good to go then it helps you
build a set of reasonable widget this is
also something really important widget
within component we think reusable we
done that all the time even though we
have already tons of framework or
component library we keep rebuilding
them all the time because we want we
think ah no that one wasn't good I'm
gonna do that my way because my way is
better and we hand up rebuilding widget
over and over those are web component
without being web component without
being called web component okay but most
important part is the fact that software
engineering has been around before the
web was and that's basically the same
idea of component based software
engineering that we that is brought to
front-end development okay so if I give
you this and I ask you how would you
build that in well I say jQuery you guys
feel like it's possible right you've
been doing that before we have to Pierre
you were doing it okay I know I'm saying
I'm old but we all we all did that at
some point okay this is a web component
but if I show you the code base of this
and Adam I ask you to to pinpoint web
component you will be like what are you
talking about
right that's not a web component that is
just HTML CSS and tons of stuff and I
don't even know where is the navbar beam
okay
I like putting comments you can see it
right there but we can do better we can
do better what if we were to write that
this way
now we we have something cleaner already
we know we have a nav bar and that nav
bar should represent just that that is
the component there is something about
that component that is not right someone
can tell me empty well okay so someone
got it right it is a component and it
has and clearly a behavior so when you
render that then it shows you that
navbar but there is no way to interact
with them okay so but it still served
the fact that we have something we can
reuse but yeah we won't be able to
change CSS and stuff like that
so that thing translate to this okay so
which technology would you use to build
this okay just for the screen
someone said JavaScript which is which
is obvious and hopefully we're in the
JavaScript dev room and very well thank
you for your answer okay let's let's
push yeah
really the question like doesn't matter
or does he it doesn't matter and it
shouldn't matter so let me dive a little
bit into the specification quickly
specification for things custom element
shadow Dom HTML template and HTML import
we're good you don't know any of this I
have a resources web page just for you
because we have 25 minutes but one of
them the most important part here it's
probably the custom element and
shatterdome okay those are the two
things I want you to pay attention to so
how many people do javascript in a room
everyone we agree on that before we even
started let's say HTML are you guys
doing JavaScript
how about CSS now you're alone not to do
CSS when you do JavaScript but not HTML
we get so look in just one question I
can prove you your own web component
developer because that's all you need to
be a web component forget about those
react angular and UGS that all you need
to build you a web component and yes if
you use things like polymer frameworks
and stuff right you using this thing out
of the box without any fanciness or
things like that to make your your could
look react or view GS ish so um my point
with these slides is just to show you
that before we dive into any framework
while are you all web component
developer so let's build web component
so how do you build custom element if
you can't read this good raise your hand
and we're gonna have you can't read it
okay we're gonna have a 101 at the end
yeah it's my goal to teach people
JavaScript so if you if you don't if you
can't read that talk to me at the end I
have a class that extend an HTML element
there is no transpiler here or any of
this it's just JavaScript row JavaScript
your browser supports that then I have
Windows custom elements define AB
selector and then I just passed the
class that define that object that
element and then I can use that this way
in my app and voila we have a web
component that was difficult right
but I'm still available after the talk
you don't get that part okay so a few
points extent HTML element custom
elements define and then using it in the
browser look if we have that as the base
the fundamental to build web component
why can't you do that in view GS or
react or angular sure you can you can
literally reuse all these things and
have your web your your view and react
component to be web component ready so
I'm gonna dive a little bit further when
you have the class you get this
lifecycle hooks that helps you interact
with the component when it enters the
page and one is leaves the page well
feels like in react we have something
called component someone said did not
you're right and then component will and
mount those are here we're not inventing
stuff we just were using the same
mechanism that exists out there okay and
then you can you have this lifecycle and
you can even go further for example here
I want to track that attribute disabled
attribute I'm just using a class I'm
just my half of the observable attribute
and then I'm tracking this disabled
thing here and then when it's disabled
okay it just returned the get when I
will not put the attribute I just read
as attribute and this here refers to the
element on the page so far so good
okay and you can see how I use it right
there just past disabled there and then
I have my component working so there are
a few others the things you can add on
top of custom element the fact that you
can extend native component you have an
image you can just say I'm extending an
image and I'm hiding my own features on
top of it
people you've been doing that already if
you use angular directive and things
like that you take a component and you
start adding more property on it you've
been doing that already
observing change to attribute well
bindings you've been doing that as well
already with your frameworks Fogarty Web
Apps that it's a long story short but
it's a long story but literally
progressive web apps with web component
you you you kind of get that okay today
it's kind of free just to get this
behavior with the web component and the
other two things are not really the most
important part here but custom element
is one of the fourth and it's probably
the most important part of them then
shadow dom anyone shadow dom like like
you want to say something about it and i
will just repeat that you wanted to say
what
[Music]
you get you got that there yeah very
good
so I don't have to repeat that but just
a long story short if you see the
shatterdome will look something like
this so you get your HTML don't but
really pay attention to that HTML is up
here and then this is the entry point
the closing point and then I have my
component that we're going to build in a
few minutes and then I have this shadow
route here so basically there I get a
kind of dome within the dome okay the
dome dome we dim the dome so the one of
the main rule here is the fact that your
CSS star will be encapsulated within
that dome here so the the linking
process saying like you have a CSS file
that is general and when you put it on
the top don't do that and then you
expect it to pass all the CSS down the
page don't do that but obviously with
shadow DOM and this is something you
don't get anymore
and it's good because it helps you think
in terms of component okay so let me
just go back here quickly shadow Dom
self-contained scope CSS possibility to
write a more declarative code it helps
you focus on just CSS in one one
component right so if you if you use
those rules you start building more
focused component so the other two HTML
template and HTML import I put that in
the resources because we only have 25
minutes so now and actually only 10
minutes left look platform supports
where are we it's green do it every day
from now but I need to show you quickly
how you will do it but it's green yeah
don't look don't look here right but
it's green
okay that they're doing it okay that
part is really important before we dive
a little bit into a bit of code so and
benefit I'm just gonna put them right
here interoperability lifespan
portability portability is really
important you can reuse that and and mix
them everywhere you want dos slide
you're gonna have them so I need to push
a little bit so the framework war look
the greener you are here the closer you
you you your heart to the standards
so polymer sketchy as xTag and there are
other order of web from web framework
friendly framework out there that are
already doing it angular is the most
advanced on the of this tree does he
give you already tools that you go
directly to web component react is a bit
red ish but I'm gonna show you a way to
get it a bit greener than that so move
on here so I think I only have like
eight minute maybe less than that let me
jump into the demo cause I feel like you
are we gonna miss on something so this
is this is an angular app you see a
component here that's an angular app I
want you just you to recognize some bit
of code that is used here
remember the create custom element we
saw before and then we have custom
element define these this thing here and
then you will hand up with this pop-up
element that you can now use in your
code as just a tag pop-up element okay
I'm gonna show you how you will use that
in in a in occurred in another app in a
few seconds but I want you to to see
this one and this one yet
yeah component reactor so this one will
be much easier to digest so I have a
simple example right here so it's not to
react related it's literally JavaScript
yeah it's react but I get the a tool
here a named Pierre module called react
web component is not really well
maintained but it was already doing the
job before even every everyone thought
about it at some point so you have this
component but instead of instead of
saying I'm gonna start the project using
I'm gonna mount it in the dome I'm just
building it can you can use it I'm just
gonna put the team maybe write it better
yeah so react web component create I'm
inside a react app this is a small
component he just does hello first them
right and then I have my component what
do I do with that
I go inside my index.html and I just put
my component there but that's a small
app there is a literally a small app if
I if I run that you will be like that's
that's that's so simple but he does
already the job like you get a component
out of that and your component hand up
being you expect to something yeah I was
trying to do this one and web component
react yeah this one and let's do that
again
thanks for your help so push ok so um
this is a small app but I'm gonna show
you with the bigger app how I can turn
an entire app into a web component and
reuse that somewhere else
so look hello first time I know you're
disappointed but it's there it does the
job but look
this this literally this is the code
that took us there if you keep the same
the same idea and we kill that that app
and open a beautiful app that we built
just for you so a few hours ago we
thought like Netflix wasn't doing a
great job of shipping us movies so we
decided to rebuild it I'm not kidding it
was a true thing
and then if you go inside these are
clicks up I'm gonna go back here have my
app in here this is the entry point of
my app as you can see I'm just like a
react web create I get the app and then
I turn that into my a clicks component
okay so if I go here and I run that that
app because I still have three minute I
should be able to see something that
looks pretty cool yep coming
yeah I just killed some stuff here so
let me bring that back so someone said I
just need to import yeah from yeah no
two minute so and it's called react okay
let me look at my computer and that will
be much better we are done and I think I
should just do that this way and then
keep it this way so again perfect people
love you so let's go back here and then
we should have
thank you very much well we have we have
some problem no worries and still have
two minutes so let's make sure that this
works so so down it's gonna be fine
so if we say react ohm what he wants you
want is saying that yeah indeed you need
to tell him like instead of doing that
let me put it a deep here thank you sir
and then you say I D should be good now
if we go back here yeah that thing works
so the the style style is broken but
that's because I turned that into a web
component so I kind of reverse the thing
and the style got broken but look what
is happening here I'm tired I'm I need
this thing to run the app so if we take
it if you remove that part and then I go
back here just say use this instead and
go back inside my app look my app is
literally this huge component it's this
this component with all the logic here
he knows where to get the data and stuff
like that so if I go back here and then
make sure that I run my app the import
thank you
except that there is another one
this is this is what happened when you
do life cutting but this thing here
there is just a web component that's it
so if you take if you take that code I'm
just I just turn that into a web company