well welcome good morning and apologies
for not being there in person and I
suppose most nights okay
can you see this like in as long as I
don't hear anything I assume it's a yes
even though not in person and thanks for
getting up early to listen to this it's
four years since I last gave a talk
across there and at a time I see oh boy
I trust in open source and a lot has
happened in the meet I'm so give you a
bit of an update and it talked about
where the community side so this thing
represents one of the more exciting
things that has happened with SEO for
you know this is a yeah no it's not Oh
God
okay okay for some reason stop sharing
I'll share game your screen sharing you
should and now you should see the slide
yeah go straight okay so this is one of
the things that happened recently what
you see here is a Boeing helicopter
flying and it's not just flying its
final Panama City
this is pilot on board for safety
reasons because they don't get FAA
approval for flying it without it but
it's actually fine called the
autonomously this is say in around
Arizona and of course the exciting thing
about it is flying on a CL for what's
even more interesting is some of the
history here
so this is a military-grade system it's
actually a defense system and you should
think it's reasonably secure but turns
out that professional pen testers took
about two weeks to complete it and then
they could completely control the
flooding could have crashed into or
divert it at whatever and this was the
starting point in the Java hackers
program which started which ran for
about five years finished about a year
ago and we did with our colleagues there
is convert the system and to a sea of
formated secure so in total there were
four vehicles there were two ground
vehicles and that to breathe air
vehicles each of them had a research
platform I've just thrown where we
ripped out all the electronics and
replaced all the software and this US
Army robotics reference platform and
then the military vehicles which is
following up on the selling of the
Ottoman stocks and we did with our
partners were real fitting these systems
for security by putting them on SEO for
and doing some of the architecting of
the system then in the end we kept the
echos hours they will say they know
where they did a in-flight attack that
in the past would have completely
compromised the system and it was
completely protected
specifically we gave them with access to
a virtual machine running Linux on the
system the original system had
everything running on Linux and the
attacker could completely compromised
the Linux VM but it couldn't break our
deal affect the rest of the system so
that so much as motivation a rough
outline of my talk is quick intro to a
cell for a technical update on a number
of the things that happened in the last
few years and this is the part of the
talk and then at the end I'll talk about
the status of fear the community and
ecosystem so for those who haven't heard
about SEO for its a microkernel and it's
arguably the world's most secure and
safe operating system one is perfectly
unique a power that it has secured
portable security enforcement and I'll
talk about on the next slide what that
means it's also at least as fast the
open literature is concerned the only
protective mode operating system with a
complete and sound analysis of
worst-case timing behavior so that super
existed for doing hard real-time they
need to take new McSweeney Kalinina
real-time with us trusted and untrusted
components insights all that it's the
world's fastest microkernel we never
compromise with performance and of
course that's the reason I mean it's
open source and it's been open source
support for nine years ago
so the security the story is summarized
in this slide where say proof here
this means mathematical formal
mathematical proof that is checked by a
Miss machine tape so we have high-level
security cognitive properties
confidentiality integrity availability
enforcement and we have proof that an
abstract model of the kernel which is
formulated in a mathematical logic is
able to enforce these security
properties and then we have a further
proof that the C code that implements
the kernel is a what's called a
refinement of this abstract model so
it's a correct implementation of this
law so that specifically this means the
under the semantics of the C language
the kernel cannot behave in a way that's
not captured by the model and then
there's a further step that shows that
the binary cover that buns on the actual
silicon is a correct translation of the
C so that means we don't have the trust
of C compiler we can't just use standard
untrusted and untrusted BTCC to compile
and then run the tool chain that's
dismissive
translations quick for pretty good
advertising there's a few exclusions all
are
work in progress we're working on fixing
all of them colonel initialization is
not verified that some privileged saved
in particularly I mean user not yet to
verify the de same degree of detail as
everything else that's very close to
being fixed we have a high performance
Nordica version that's not verified and
we don't have any stuff verification
story about tiny channels that not like
any ice security-oriented operating
system SEO forests uses capabilities as
for to represent access lives in the
system and so these are basically opaque
pointers that reference an object and
lights convey to it and any kernel
operation you type in boldly store be
authorized by having such a capability
so these are capabilities in the
classical object capability for master
computing the tutor has known them for
forty years they're quite different from
the what the Linux box called
capabilities which are chemical this and
[Music]
strangest of them accidentally eat again
accidentally the power cool
okay I just need nah okay okay hopefully
you can see the slides again full screen
if not me yeah okay good okay so this is
say that the in a very high level called
your face here for there's much more to
it in particular its resource management
more model which is quite unique but
that's all the establish so if you don't
know a summary of recent things we've
done with it and one of the most
significant ones is support for mix
criticality real-time scheduling what
does that mean so in many particular
cyber-physical systems any sort of
real-time system where you have
non-trivial complexity you have this
integration challenge of mix criticality
that some components are highly critical
and you need to be sure that they get
toward that they operate correctly under
all circumstances and then there's
untrustworthy components so a very high
obstructed view of this UAV as a control
loop which is highly critical because
that's what pieces they fly and stops it
from crashing and then there's other
components for example those networks
and so there's a network driver that
talks for the ground station for example
or the communication and obviously that
one is not critical if the communication
stops working then this thing will just
light relay or to a waypoint or
hopefully has something safe not cheap
to fly it home or something
the challenge here is the controller
will be very slow at once of the order
advanced annealing time scale so would
of Tindall under threats the network
driver of course is really fast if
networks like to be serviced within sort
of microsecond time scales
and that means that this network driver
needs to be able to interrupt the
controller witches can't wait for the
controller to finish its 20 millisecond
execution because it lose lot of network
packets so you have to be able for this
less critical components to grant the
critical ones but still guarantee enough
time for the critical component store do
it shop was from safety of your system
so that that's the quality of next
critical systems what makes it
challenging is active sharing involved
so typically in our UAV there instead of
the vehicle controlled it tells the
deeper where the flight or so it has to
access waypoints these waypoints they
get updated by the navigation system for
example based on what the media
processing tells the system or updated
from the ground station and so the true
the trusted and young lets faster parts
share this critical data and the legal
control needs to be accessed
please be able to access data that is
consistent even while the navigation
system they updated and you need to do
that on on the same system a simple way
to even make something like that is by
what's called a resource server so we
have the the two components that use
this and Waypoint data to control the
critical controller and the less
critical navigation system and the
Waypoint data is EB B capsulated in a
server which can be invoked from those
spies and that we gain from system you
might invoke the client to update my
clients and the control system may
invoke the server to beat the way pots
so it's all fine and if long as to
survive stable enough and fast enough
that maybe not a big deal
the problem is particularly this server
has some longer running operations then
we need to count the time properly
because otherwise the navigation system
which is argued before might be running
at higher priority
just boss the critical system by sending
lots of requests for server so we need
to ensure that if time is isn't handed
properly and in the new version of a C
or four we do we use capabilities like
for every access control that the system
we introduced capabilities for the right
to use OSS of time so a classical threat
will have quality and a time slice in
the new SEO for we have authority and
the shielding context capability which
is capability to a shave lean object
which is encapsulate the rights to
access the CPU so it has a period and a
budget and the semantics is that over
any time T you cannot use more than C of
the policies or so the ratio of C 2 T is
C the bandwidth of CPU this policies
allowed to consume and there can be for
example what terms one so in this case
in three time units it may use up to two
years of to turn to the bandwidth or
something that runs for a longer time
like our control loop has 14,000 time
units it's allowed to use 250 and if
things are right you can you can see
that you can combine those in your
fourth gate that time the system the
whole point is the system enforces that
something is not allowed to run over to
suction and that way we can guarantee
time to lower priority processes which
is exactly what we need for these things
critically system so and the way this is
done is by being able to oral shielding
context so in the case of our resource
silver if they decline invokes the
server it prizes among its rippling
context the service and running on the
time jiggling context and the server and
gets charge of the client when to serve
our finish its job to shim the context
occurrence of Clyde and it now has
server time charge through it and
therefore we can prevents this client to
advance the server and force something
else or miss its deadline
there's a paper what's in here is this
last year and took a lot of this makes a
zero for the first ever real time system
with capabilities for time there's
concurrent work at Washington George
Washington University but there hasn't
been a system like that before so the
first time we integrated CPU time with a
capability system the second thing I
want to talk about is what we call
security enforcement my architecture and
there's a start speed used on this
Boeing helicopter the idea here is that
in SEO for backup a microkernels they
have a very low-level interface a CEO
for its particular table and then you
need to deal with a lot of these objects
and capabilities in order to do anything
this here is a representation of the
second most trivial example you can buy
or even to an SEO for so the most
trivial one would be a hello world
program that just says hello world and
then stops the most the second most
pre-built thing is you have to process
and they communicate by sending messages
between a chess or represents this
really trivial example we have over 50
kernel objects that we need to worry
about and that's just for this trivial
example this is a simple system but no
longer quite as trivial each point
represents an object and the capability
and you can see there's hundreds of
thousands of that just for a relatively
simple system so that's not a good
abstraction level to reason about in the
system so instead we have any component
middleware or anchors that's not
particularly unique for example T know
there's a in many ways much more general
component middleware but can get some
assurance story which you don't pick
with others so in this case we have in
this campus world we have components
that are represented by boxes and
connectors that are represented by lines
between those boxes and there's three
different types the end
whether you have sickness
message-passing semaphore like signaling
or shared data and sort of the the top
two boxes and the RPC clinic they
between basically represents this second
most trivial example I talked about
before so much more high level
representation and the beauty of this
and the spanker system is that we can
provably reason about the system
behavior on this angus representation
and it takes corrective mapped onto SEO
for so the way it is that oddness
demonstrate that it's a business example
this is a highly abstracted view of our
UAV architecture and it has some
untrusted stuff in a Linux virtual
machine and the one of the core security
properties of the system is that Linux
is only able to talk to the rest of the
system by using encrypted traffic so
only by the scripta library and we can
do that by saying ok it's not connected
to anything else in the system except
this one line that goes to crypto
therefore we know that if you can't if
we can trust this crypto component then
we can ensure that Linux and interfere
with the rest of this so this is our
highly simplified package view of the
system and in order to build the actual
system of course we have implementations
of this component store each of these
boxes as a implementation of Stevie
clean C so there's a driver multiple
drivers the virtual machine etc and of
course I get some compiler linked
together what is missing here is the
so-called glue code which is the
operating system calls that enable these
combinations so where do the message
passing specifically and what this blue
code needs to look like it's completely
specified by this architecture view so
we can generate this glue code which is
a game that's not particularly returned
so of any idea of compiling us it's been
around for centuries but in our ok
we have proved that the glucose sk
generator is correct in the sense that
if you invoke a compound a function in
the component then this is semantically
equivalent to just directly involving
this this function in the same address
space so that's sort of a very strong
correctness property of the school code
but we also think is from this canvas
representation we can generate the low
level SEO for representation so they in
terms of SEO for objects and
capabilities that's represented in a
formalism called Cathy Ellicott capable
of description language and again we
generate this automatically from the
canvas you and again this generation is
provably correct and that means when we
have the system in this this low level
if this low level rivers diagram
represents the actual ASL flow system
then we know that we can reason about
the system according to the styling of
their diagram by this boxes and lives
for at the center of campus campus all
of us and the final step is how do we
get the system in the state we also
generate the initialization code that
gets the system into that shape so we
have a automatically generated code
which is the English it passed in the
system which will create all these
objects distributed capabilities and
then we know the system is in a state
that's correctly represented by this
anchors representation on top and that
means we can now do all the reasoning
above the properties of the system in
this cactus operation for some
limitations at the moment not all the
proof stories are completely complete
yet but this is ongoing work that's
funded by another alpha program and it
will be finished within the next year's
then it will be very interesting there
was an articulated communication of the
ACM to start October that describes that
and then there's also tools
where this fixed height or a formalism
called architecture analysis and
description language which is an
international standard and that's used a
lot in the avionics industry and there's
a clip space tools etc which - and the
home language is designed for doing
safety cases and there's analysis tools
and all those stuff and you can use that
framework and generate the canvas
levitate patient from that one although
that generation is not going to be
correct and it's unlikely to happen in
near future
when these tools are provided by
Rockwell Collins they're all open source
so that was the second thing that's sort
of relevant we're still for in recent
developments and the third one is okay
we have the verified kernel but of
course the whole system is more than a
kernel even the trusted computing base
of the system is much more than the
kernel so typically you have some
critical components there may be some
devices you need to where you need to
trust the drivers you may need to have a
trusted file system you have so your
control code etc and all these if they
need to be trusted ideally they really
should be very hard and of course 11
person years of most what we invested in
verifying the kernel I'm all these
components of the order of thousands or
tens of thousands of lines of code and
11 person years for 10,000 lines of code
and it stands when traffic lis that
doesn't sound like a particular
attractive way of doing things it was
okay for the kernel but for doing things
on top you own better productivity and
this is where we developing the coaching
framework so coaching stands for covered
include cogeneration and it is a
language framework for building high
assurance components on top of a co 4
and it is a programming language it's a
functional programming language that's
either memory safe but not managed and
it's called a linear type system
synchros it's very similar to rust in
many ways because I like rust it's got a
formally well defined semantics
and we compile it into C which is not
particular exciting but the more
interesting part is when we compile it
to see the compiler spits out
proof that the C is correct against a
component stake which the compiler also
generates and then we know okay we have
a correct implementation translation of
this coachin into C which means that as
long as we trust compile like this can
reason about the correctness of our code
at the level of the cultured semantics
and we know that the seed translation
will will maintain that semantics like
the bus the language is restricted that
you can't program everything at it it's
it's intentionally to really complete so
we need to complement it without start
datatypes so these are things like force
file systems we have abstract data types
or the mainly red black trees and sympa
and the idea is these need to be
manually verified so in the end you have
an overall high-level abstract
specification of the complete
functionality of this component you have
these abstract data types which can be
verified independently and your years
they are highly reusable and then you're
left manually verifying the culture code
which is much easier than verifying C
code because of the properties of
Coaching language the fact that its type
and memory safe that it's pretty
functional and so that's the key for
increasing the productivity of
verification and we've done some case
studies a number of file systems and
there's a PayPal account that's about
three years old now but that describes
it and what we found is that okay
productivity stories not too bad so we
get a possible of verified code in terms
of dollars per line of code that's a
power defect of two next thing will be
what our cost is your form
the copy verification story for SEO for
was about three or four times as
expensive as the earlier pistachio
microkernel which was earlier l4
microkernel that was developed in a very
similar common
thanks by people the university folks
who sort of had experience with
microkernel settle so it's quite a
comparable system so I say before with
its complete verification was about the
fact that for more expensive than this
earlier system that had no verification
story at all so that means if we get the
cost down by effect of true we are
competitive with non assurance
traditional engineered code and it seems
like with our coaching of college we
already got half of that gap we got
effect of two and the fact that the
reason it's not more has a lot to do
with the way potion the initial version
of coaching was done it was very
restrictive that you get forced to do a
lot of fun boring repetitive stuff etc
and this is what we're working on at the
moment and so the with the ultimate game
of having something that really allows
you to write systems components and
verify them at a cost that's comparable
to classical unverified C code so
another interesting aspect is that ok
when you have this coach and
implementation presumably ideally you
want to verify that but you can actually
play a trade-off of dependability versus
cost we could for example say ok it's
safe language and therefore that reduces
the number of bucks already
significantly and maybe for something
that's not ultra vehicle that might
actually be enough and then you have you
just need to write the code and your
I've already code that you know it is
going to be paid out that beaker but C
code if it was making do it then only
couldn't do automatic testing in
particular this called property based
listing which is something that comes
out of the Haskell world where you have
a formal specification of your
functionality and it generates a cases
automatically from that and in
particularly the exercises the
interesting bits so all the cases it
simple and it has been turns out is a
very effective tool
for any code pretty much correct very
quickly and of course you can do model
checking and then finally you can do the
full functional correctness proof by
theorem proving as we done it with SEO
for so there's a hierarchy of increasing
insurance but also increasing costs that
you can pick your point but one of the
interesting aspects of that is that this
poverty based testing has an interesting
compatibility with our full functional
corinthis groups in the sense that it
uses it requires a formal specification
and a formal specification can be reused
with a full-frontal correctness proof so
that means you can use a checking for
properties space tasting for actually
developing and loop up in your spec who
specs head boxes what and it's much easy
to verify against the correct stake than
an e correct one because any anybody in
the spec will send you down some red
hole which you need to take out out for
a while so starting with a more or less
correct spec is a big win but also very
fine correct code is much easier than
verifying buggy code and so eliminating
most of the box with quality based
testing before you start verification
also reduces cost so there's a whole
bunch of trade-offs that can be played
and this is all only at the beginning
but we've already made a lot of progress
in the last two years particular of the
last year in increasing the
expressiveness of the language to make
it easier to use reduce the number of
times of code you need to write for the
implementing some functionality we're
putting some of this oil like code int
or syntactic sugar in the leg language
and we are applying it to other
components so in the past we use it for
the many file systems we know starting
to use Cochin for device drivers and
network stacks and that's by the way all
supported by industry funding so I'm
happy to see that there's a fair amount
of interest in industry for using this
technology they've got one particular
application Ares autonomous cars
nothing to do with DARPA it's a
california-based company doing
autonomous driving heads and they're
working with us for using this coaching
technology to get in some of their
critical components verified so they
have pretty crumby system with a for a
v8 course that run the machine learning
and sensor fusion and all that stuff and
then they have and that's running in
that SMP Linux and then underneath with
this SEO for and then the critical
components are cooled out running
natively on their co 4 and with a
minimal trusted computing base with the
idea of verifying that trusted computing
base in particular verified providing
the privacy coaching they verified them
and of course the system has redundancy
as well so this is some of the I think
really exciting developments that are
have been happening around or happening
around SEO for it's sort of I guess that
may take away here is SEO for really is
the cutting edge of operating system
design and development so it's really
driving innovation and there's more and
more deployments that help us supporting
real world cases and driving innovation
through dot okay now so what many of you
folks are probably quite interested is
sort of what's the story about the
ecosystem and they generalize your whole
community there's some good and some bad
news
so the good news is the community is
growing the available mailing list is
very active there's heavy support from
US government they set up a u.s. SEO for
center of excellence which is basically
an organization where companies can go
and get help with developing systems on
polyphagia for obesity DARPA the
services or support particular offense
work but it's not the only defense is an
SEO for based
system has gone through high assurance
evaluation and be it's been certified
for defenders and is actually in use in
the UK and Australia defense but it's
also to me particularly important aspect
there is we're getting out of the just a
defense space into our safety critical
systems and this is reflected in the
amount of commercial funding we get in
for SEO for so this one companies some
big some small some very big putting
real dollar on the table to help us
develop the SEO for open source system
and the framework surrounded and pretty
much all this work that we take funding
for is open source work occasionally we
would fight for example a propriety
driver or for specific purpose for a
customer but the the bulk of fee money
that comes to us goes straight into
developing the open source system SEO
for itself as well as things that are on
top and it's really into none of areas
so there's some some of the companies
there talking to our building things for
because your control system to stop
protect them from cyberattacks
autonomous cars already mentioned and
there's people building frameworks for
eye assurance medical devices so a lot
of safety critical systems work so
that's a good news the bad news is
really the present state of the
ecosystem which is not where I would
really like to see it and I really
thought this would develop faster at the
moment the whole system is very tiny you
have not a lot of actually usable
components so unlike l 4e for example
which has a fairly mature and rich
ecosystem the SEO for one is still very
much in its beginning the components
around that people are way out but it's
only documented how to find some of them
are supported most
and this is something we really need to
change there's definitely a shortage of
tools so we would like to see people
developing more tools the Center of
Excellence is doing some of that but we
really like to see a open source
community doing this and part of that is
really because we are to blame for that
we are community engaged in it's just
insufficient we generally very
responsive to people putting issues
asking questions on the mailing list but
we're not really practical and the main
reason is not ill-will it's just we've
been too busy with we've been always
very stretched without people hiring
really good kernel OS developers it's
hard and we've been recruiting for years
and with varying success just recently
it's been pretty good we hired a number
of people but basically just getting
enough people in as a bottleneck and
it's creative taking an egg problem
right if you have if if we can make more
views of the community then obviously
that solves all of these problems but in
order to bootstrap that we need to
invest and engage with the community
etcetera and which has been too busy in
the past Buddha but that's really
changing so this is a high priority
thing for us we just over the last two
months added two full-time OS engineers
and a bunch of student panels and you
will see in the next few months a real
change there happening with the way we
engage for the community and there's a
it becoming more activity the CEO is of
course one important bit of the
community because they are their job is
to contribute tools etc but we want to
have a real sort of open source
developer community around that and we
both takes takes to help that developing
much better and that includes of course
on our side really just about
documenting much more what's there and
you said as a way to encourage community
members such as adopt components and
support them except by a continuance of
course and part of that of course is
keeping the developers
contributors more visibility etcetera so
we're working all that and we hope the
suggestions and we're definitely taking
steps to improving the transparency of
the whole thing I'm it's been noted a
few times that the whole SEO for
development is not very transparent and
that's unfortunately true but we're
really changing that so once that we've
already taken a few probably developer
mailing list you would have seen that we
started an RFC project process so in
future any major changes will be going
through this community consultation
process and it's a way for the community
obviously to engage as well and make
suggests so that's already in place and
a few other things that are not yet in
place but we are working on them it is
opening up our JIRA for working on
platform issues that's a bit of a tricky
one because there's lots of stuff in
here from some of them 10 years old so
the staff thing there is we first or
eight projects that are online
yes yeah my last fight so yeah so that
needs some cleanup because there's
confidential stuff in there and some
stuff that could be embarrassing it's a
plus so that will take a bit to get go
through but it's happening we also
created a discourse group which will be
opened up very soon it already exists
but it's not yet had but a
non-sustainable will announce it open in
the next month or so and there is a
public road map or this horribly
outdated about about three years we'll
update that and be more active in
mechanicus so please talk to us if you
interested and we really want engaging
with the community much better in the
future that we have the house and it's
the last I think
if then let me punish al so I can
hopefully see
yeah okay I got that 3500 it's not our
space right we are software experience
on Hardware experts obviously hardware
is the thing that keeps me alive at
night awake at night I we understand how
the mix of persevere we don't we can't
be no control of the hardware and we
know the hard ways that there's a lot of
activities happening in that space or
take me around risk five which of course
the open architecture encourages that
and there is so probably three or four
objects around the world that are
working on verifying risk five processor
implementations which is really exciting
but it will take a while to get there
but yeah I mean you're totally right
harvester the big problem and for
example stick that nail down demonstrate
so overthink this hardware it's done so
I hope people really get the activate on
the hardware side if there's any more
questions saying email
[Applause]