thank you as always there's always
inaccuracies that's my fault
it's it's now 30 years at IBM so I was
born back in a decade where people call
this baby boomers and I originally
studied applied physics and electronic
engineering and also computer science
back in the days when there wasn't
computer science one of the very first
degrees offered in computer science and
I did a PhD in information theory
information theories basically it's
group theory number theory a lot of kind
of abstract and convoluted mathematics
and little did I realized way back then
that actually 35 years later so I did my
PhD 35 years ago 35 years later I would
have a Renaissance based on what I
studied and all the stuff I learned back
then because actually with that armed
with those tools you pretty you you're
pretty well armed to understand or at
least to attempt to understand because
nobody really understands it quantum
physics quantum mechanics and quantum
computing so I'm going to talk about
IBM's quantum computing platform
including things like whisky it the IBM
quantum experience and hopefully open
some doors make you think about about
what iBM is doing in this space and of
course the appeal to everybody to
contribute to work with us so let's see
if this works so the I guess the the
fundamental question is have we reached
and this is this is our IBM quantum cat
the quantum cat he's thankfully alive
and not in superposition and certainly
not dead have we reached the limits of
classical computation so let's have a
look
yes I've been practicing this I can see
your are you're impressed this is this
this is 30 years working for IBM
practicing with Microsoft is anybody
from Microsoft here Mika's love-hate
it's good for some things but let's see
what happens I can hear the the intake
of breath here like how did he do that
it's quantum so this is this is this is
everybody's contemporary view of quantum
computing for those of you who are
observant you've seen me before I was
starting to step here here doing some
stuff so I was quickly writing my foils
I just pulled these literally about
about three minutes old off Twitter I
thought that was quite nice so we have
you know we are we have the picture of
the chandelier and it's cold and it's
even more cold and down at the bottom
it's really really incredibly cold and
then we have some means of mapping some
real-world problem on to probably a
Hamiltonian probably using the Ising
model and nobody understands what the
hell it's all about but it seems to work
and of course between this and British
I'm allowed to be humorous or at least
I'm allowed to attempt to be humorous
between this level and and reality there
was a kind of mapping and some some
details we need to understand
if we take a look at quantum algorithms
in general and we've heard some talks
today about different approaches how we
might actually use quantum computing but
fundamentally we've got to actually
understand a lot about how contemporary
current algorithms work what their
limitations are and how quantum
computing might might be able to improve
that or bridge that gap is there anybody
here with a background in theoretical
computer science okay so I'm thankfully
for the rest of you and thankfully for
me because the theoretical computer
scientists will be able to pick holes in
it I'm not going to go into a complete
derivation of the bqp hierarchy class
derivation but it really in order to
understand quantum computing or the
advantages potential advantages of
quantum computing you need to understand
a little at least a little bit about
theoretical computer science and
algorithmic performance in particular as
we'll see later one concept which is
quite key is the idea of a quantum
computer providing a super a polynomial
speed-up okay it might be an exponential
speed-up it might be something else it
might be super exponential but it's at
least super polynomial and we'll see
well why that's important in a few
minutes this is a foil which does not
display also not okay so if we look at
the class of algorithms which we are
attempting to to address with quantum
computing we have so-called easy
problems does anybody know how we
classify or name those easy problems
anybody got a an idea
polynomial you've for those of you for
the computer scientists close your ears
for the rest of you these are so-called
polynomial time algorithms so there are
algorithms which are a polynomial in the
size of the input whatever that means
you know so classically multiplying two
numbers together is polynomial just in
order to do that I have I need a number
of operations which is a which is a
multiple of the size of the two numbers
I'm trying to multiply together we all
know we've all heard or we should have
all heard of Shor's algorithm who hasn't
heard of Shor's algorithm and a couple
of people
ok Shor's algorithm is a quantum it's an
algorithm which can be run on a
universal quantum computer which
provides a super exponential a super
polynomial speed-up of factoring numbers
so multiplying numbers is polynomial
determining if if a number is prime does
anybody know what that is it's
polynomial factoring a number an
arbitrary number into its prime factors
is no it's not pulling arielle that's
all that's the whole basis of
cryptography or at least most public key
cryptography relies on the fact that
that is a non super polynomial and
Shor's algorithm unfortunately can
factor in polynomial time there's a
there's a kind of a small gotcha with
shorts algorithm so for let's say
realistic numbers realistic realistic
size numbers you almost certainly going
to need tens or hundreds of millions of
qubits currently the the best universal
qubits the best we can achieve is less
than a hundred so we're a long way away
yet but maybe one day that will become
feasible the original use case for
quantum computing was to simulate
quantum mechanics that's also
an easy problem we somebody earlier
talked about how you can map in
particular optimization problems using
the variational quantum eigen solver
onto a hamiltonian equation Hamiltonian
equations are things you can relatively
easily solve or at least observe with a
quantum computer so there are some ways
to approach specific problems but in
general we're looking for hard problems
now typically these are problems in the
area of algebraic and number theoretic
problems also optimization problems and
the optimization problem one is of one
of the most interesting ones and if I
look at the if I look at the space of
developers startups people who are
actively working on and with and
especially with quantum computing on our
api's there's a lot of companies in
there in the finance space because if
you look at hedging or portfolio
analysis or economic prediction these
are all fundamentally optimization
problems so there's this you know this
this idea that when quantum computing
when we get to quantum advantage
suddenly problems in a financial space
or logistics which are intractable today
will become tractable and I'm sure that
will happen and a result of that will be
complete change in business business
models and how these how these branches
how these industries work machine
learning I'll talk a little bit about
that in a second
and of course simulating quantum
mechanics for chemistry which is the
area where we expect quantum advantage
to occur earliest just to illustrate
this I don't have anybody's seen this I
merely must apologize for HDMI and my my
this is OK
26s look quick so the question is the
question was okay
the IBM Blue Gene queue now a
supercomputer it can this stuff you
can't read it's saying so for a 512 bit
number how long would blue gene need to
factor that and the answer which you can
clearly see here is 26,000 years okay oh
it looks better how long would it need
for a thousand 24-bit number anybody
want to hazard a guess
exactly
take Shor's algorithm that's the
speed-up so that's super a polynomial
speed-up the small qualifier of this is
that you need a fault-tolerant quantum
computer with around somewhere 20-30
hundred million cubits so we're still
not there yet how do we actually program
a quantum computer now there are a
variety of approaches but fundamentally
it comes down to mapping in some way
your problem on to an interference
pattern which is in this interference
pattern you set it up on your cubed
there are two mechanisms for doing that
set up there's a superposition and
entanglement
so superposition we've seen the Bloch
sphere where you put a initialized qubit
into a superposition of two states an
entanglement is where I make two
different qubits into one system one
quantum mechanical system and the real
challenge is given a real-world problem
for example inverter matrix
how can I map that into a bunch of these
types of operations there was a question
somebody asked earlier about
different types of Hamiltonians who was
it somebody set up here yes you asked me
about new Hamiltonians right now we we
have the superposition Hadamard
transform and the sea not transform
those are things you can more or less
easily implement in hardware but
obviously there's a lot of people
working on I would say higher-level
fundamental Hamiltonian operations which
would were they to exist would also
result in speed-up in algorithms so we
take we take a superposition of all the
states this is actually this bit as a
lie because in order to visualize
multiple qubits with entanglement using
the Bloch sphere it quickly becomes a
problem that's only understandable by
pangalactic transformational hyper
beings I'm allowed to say that here
because you're developers and I can
assume that some of you at least have
read Hitchhiker's Guide to the galaxy
who hasn't so for the video there is
about three people put their hand up on
all the rest of Reddit so you know what
the mice are right the mice and the okay
so only the mice can understand the
hyper potentional hyperdimensional blah
sphere mapping there is a way to do it
with two qubits but it's extremely
convoluted and not really very intuitive
basically we have a way of entangling
the qubits and and making out of a for
example 20 cubic quantum computer
effectively one one consistent quantum
system and then the magic happens where
we basically collapse the wave function
we observe and out pops the results
every quantum computing program and I
don't know if that people really
understand that which is why I'm going
to emphasize it again
every quantum computing program is
actually a circuit so it's initializing
a bunch of bits performing some
preparatory operations on those qubits
and then observing there's no feedback
feedback is forbidden so reversibility
and no cloning to Bridgette principle
operation principles of quantum
computing and the output of this quantum
program is non-deterministic it's
fundamentally non-deterministic that
means when you perform your experiment
two times three times four times five
times you never guarantee you always get
the same result if you're lucky and your
algorithm is robust in non determinism
then you'll you get a very very clear
statistical correlation showing you one
particular result
then you've assuming your algorithm
algorithm is designed well you know okay
that's the answer
there are also inherently in all quantum
computers because even though as we saw
the quantum computer is very cold and
it's in under high vacuum and there's
very little electromagnetic radiation
impacting on it it's still not perfect
so every operation on a qubit whether it
means putting it into superposition or
entangling it or even reading it out
also introduces by its very nature
because it's an interaction introduces
additional errors and now in fact that's
one of the major challenges in actually
building real universal quantum
computers is to manage and handle those
errors and keep them as low as possible
when we talk about the power of a
quantum computer it's not just important
to talk about the number of qubits
because you know what would two hundred
qubits what benefit would be if the
individual qubit error rate completely
dominates any calculation otherwise the
two hundred qubits would be useless I
need to have a corresponding error rate
which is
correspondingly low in order to be able
to actually make use of that so there's
always a trade-off between error rates
error rates in English in fundamental
operations in entanglement operations in
readout operations the coherence time of
a quantum program which also of course
determines how many how errors can add
up how errors are combined and the
number of qubits at IBM we talk about
the quantum volume which is a measure of
number of qubits and the error rate also
if considerable interest is the
coherence time because that determines
the maximum amount of time you have your
quantum program and coherence times if
the order of tens or maybe a hundred of
microseconds normal when you think about
it back in the day when when Deutsch
Fineman and Deutsch were thinking about
the principle of a quantum computer and
that we might need such things I can
vaguely remember it I was doing my PhD
early 80s and I can remember this stuff
about you know the idea of a quantum
quantum bits and I've not looked it up I
maybe I have to do that but I seem to
remember that way back then the first
attempts where her coherence times were
measured in femtoseconds so now we're in
tens or maybe even hundreds of
microseconds so we're a long way it
doesn't sound like a lot but it's
actually significant to a development so
historically quantum quantum computing
was the domain of quantum si the quantum
scientists physicists chemists we're now
at the phase where we're quantum ready
and we see this IBM are our competitors
I don't like the word our in German
midget writer the people in the market
in the quantum computing market with us
we all see a very very big uptake great
interest in quantum computing and right
now it's the challenge is to understand
how to program quantum computers to
demonstrate as early as possible quantum
advantage and there is significant
economic and business interest and
impact on doing that and at some point
in the hopefully not so different just
in the future we will be in the phase of
quantum advantage so
this is a model or a mock-up or actually
might be a photo of the one that
actually built I figure does anybody
know this of course your developers
hackers you know it so this is Charles
Babbage's computing machine that's one
component of it it was never built
because back in 1823 I think or 1833
they did not have the metal ology
metallurgical skills to produce gear
wheels of sufficient strength and
accuracy it's I don't think it's a
Turing machine but it's pretty damn
close it's no it's a Turing machine but
it's Anna
it's a Turing machine but I don't think
it's a fun Neumann architecture it's but
it's very close so it has a CPU has
registers it has the idea of memory a
mechanical von Neumann machine from 1823
so am i I'm English I'm British and I've
been living in Germany for 30 years so
one day after brexit I literally want to
offer breaks that I applied for German
citizenship so I'm now German and
British so when my Germans German fellow
Germans they all say well Conrad Sousa
invented the computer and I pull this
out and say no sorry all the best ideas
that come from British people which
which which raises a very pertinent
question about what he'll breakfast is
here I am in the center of the center of
what was this this would be there this
would be the was in Star Wars the no the
Star TV day this deed
Death Star so were supposed to be the
Death Star with with the EU Commission
I'm very Pro Europe by the way I think
this anyway so and this is this is where
we are right now so there are several of
these an undisclosed number sitting at a
couple of locations I've been with
locations you may have seen in the press
at CES a couple of weeks ago we
announced the first I would say
commercially available quantum computing
system so that's significant because
that means we are moving from a pure
research model into a model where we
actually going to work with we work with
customers on developing applications and
we use for our for our qubits we use
these babies here superconducting
Josephson junctions there are several
other approaches some of which are
actually in current use some of which
are currently only of theoretical
interest because we haven't thanks
Noah's actually observed them
specifically the entangle on approach if
anybody's not heard of entangle Yuans go
google it afterwards
it's entangle ions if we actually show
that they exist and are able to use them
they will represent a very very
interesting technology for the basis for
quantum computing the key point here is
that the underlying technology the
methods of mapping quantum programs onto
a specific technology and the method of
mapping applications on to quantum
programs these three levels we want to
see these decoupled from each other so
search initiatives is open quasi m-- for
the layer between the quantum assembly
language in the hardware open standards
for how you actually control and control
and operate a physical quantum computer
and also standards for how compilers are
built
that's all open source I'll show you in
a minute how to get get access to it
there's SDKs and api's coming out of
your ears on on github but we're so the
the important point here to note is this
number here any electrical engineers or
electronics engineers here yeah so you
know yeah Boltzmann's constant every
particularly microwave frequencies you
have equivalent temperature and noise
floors and all that sort of stuff so
before I came up here I was down at the
amateur radio bench down there and
because I'm a radio amateur as well so
talking to the guys about moonbounce and
that sort of stuff
so this is all this is all very
important when you're working at
microwave frequencies low noise and that
I'm actually one of them one of the
reasons why the quantum computer has to
be so cold is that you need the noise
the environmental noise around the
qubits to be lower than the value the
equivalent temperature value of the 1 or
0 and there we go
so hundred micrometers is is here
this device is I guess a few nanometers
does anybody know if I have a gate
physical gate on a chip where the size
of let's say 10 nanometers anybody know
how many silicon atoms are in though
I'm looking through the electronic
surges hmm hmm no it's more it's a it's
it's about it's about 50 or 60 but it's
still a sufficiently small number of
electrons I have atoms that you observe
you don't observe your your gate is
almost dominated by quantum effects
especially at room temperature which is
why Moore's law is basically at least
the scaling of gate size is is breaking
down the die size expansion is also kind
of hits implements so that's what one
looks like
or at least an IBM one if you remember
the photos from Righetti and d-wave
they're quantum computers look
astounding astoundingly similar there's
that's not chance that's kind of the way
you have to do it the interesting thing
I always found fascinating was this see
these little stripes here and you can't
see you down here this is sort of big
block of thing here and some stripes
here it goes all the way to the top so
the whole thing is cooled with helium
for helium four is the common isotope of
helium helium four has a boiling point
of I think somebody probably gonna
correct me about three point five Kelvin
as an isotope of helium called helium
three has one Neutron less it's boiling
point is around 2.7 Kelvin you use the
difference in a refrigerator to
basically freeze down to 15 1015
millikelvin interestingly the amount of
helium-3 on earth is is rather
restricted and it doesn't occur very
often spontaneously so there's a which
has put the helium-3 in the fridge you
don't let it leak it's expensive
so we saw one of these pictures earlier
15 milli Calvin down in the bottom a
bunch of microwave electronics what
actually happens inside there input
output modules a whole bunch of control
electronics here what you're seeing
there is a photo of one of the research
machines obviously in a commercial
quantum computer a lot of that's going
to be miniaturized and I'm sure at some
point in the future you'll have pizza
carton control electronics for your
quantum computer for those of you who
work in in in computer centers or in in
computing delivery you know that pizza
carton this is the affectionate term for
that the CPUs and memory and disk things
you put into a 19-inch racks they're
called pizza cartons so I'm sure that
would be a piece of carton to control
electronics at some point and then of
course compilers api's SDKs and cloud
access and HTTP wrappers and all that
sort of stuff and so the idea is that we
were going to replace this with this in
a certain just actually in a certain way
and I was that where was I I was in
Berlin yesterday Potsdam that they has a
Plattner Institute and they have a
Museum of computers there so some very
very old pcs yeah so backs and pdp-11
all this sort of thing and these the
really really old computers you won't
remember it I do but to initialize the
computer to boot a computer you had to
physically enter the the actual first
memory locations by hand it's actually
very very very good analogy for how we
initialize and set up qubits you have to
do it manually but a lot of people
working on quantum memory and quantum
sensors I'm sure that problem will at
some point in the future also if not go
away at least be mitigated improved
so
this is this is the bit where you roll
your eyes because it was going so well
before now he's not doing it so the key
thing is I need to get the little here
we go there we go now I already do this
oops okay here we go
so what is how is IBM how is IBM working
with quantum so there is a a whole bunch
of stuff on on github
there are various api's but what we've
what we've said is that basically a
couple of couple of toys and giveaways
and there's an app for the for iOS there
was even a board game called tangley on
which is actually quite fun and
undergoing revisions and we've developed
a model cue keyboard I'm not quite sure
what the point is but it's selling like
hotcakes if you if you don't like to
paterno books if you are the strange
kind of person that doesn't like view
does anybody here doesn't like using
Jupiter I knew it's going to be you so
you're obviously one of these people who
insists on using Microsoft vs code yes
we've got you covered
so if we look at the this separation so
quiz kick terror is basically it's the
gate level so in quiz kotero you can do
ahead of my transform you can do a see
not transform you can do XYZ so you can
do the direct manipulations so it's very
very low level quantum computing it's
really simple to install pipe install a
quiz kit that's it
you need an API key there is I'll show
you how to do that in a second then we
have something called quiz kit aqua and
chriskate aqua is interesting because
nobody's really addressed kind of
address that but what what would it be
like if I had for example in Python an
API call which said calculate calculate
binding energy
and I give it out brackets I give it my
API key and then I say hydrogen lithium
hydrogen close brackets so where's the
quantum computing I don't care now I'm
just maybe I'm using the quantum
computer as a back end
maybe I'm using a quantum computers
simulator maybe I'm using a classical
supercomputer maybe if it's only
hydrogen lithium hydrogen I'm using my
laptop but if it's uh if it's a caffeine
molecule I'm using the quantum computer
so for IBM it's clear to us that the
level at which you ultimately use
quantum computing
you're not gonna you're not going to
have to take care of though there are
actually qubits down there or not and
that's the the level we work with with
with chriskate aqua we also have
chriskate air which is also open source
publicly available this is a for access
to and working with a quantum simulator
there are there is a open source
publicly available quantum simulator out
there you can use that there is a iBM
has a variant of this that's behind err
there is also Chris gate Ignace Chris
get Ignace is part or at least parts of
it are in quiz kits terror Chris get
Ignace and you get the analogy Ignace is
like the you know them the magma and hot
rocks underneath the Earth's crust so
Chris get Ignace is all about
manipulating and working with actual
individual qubits and the technology
itself so it's below the waterline or
below the crust of the planet we have a
number of publicly available quantum
computers Tokyo isn't publicly available
Pope Tokyo is only available to our
customers however Melbourne and the
other quantum computers are publicly
available you can go on the quiz kit
website you can see the I just did the
screen shot about about an hour ago so
you can see the current operate
in frequency so if you remember
beforehand the 240 millikelvin the
equivalent is equivalent nose
temperature of a 5 gigahertz signal
we're operating at 4.9 gigahertz you can
see the the related timings for for
Tokyo so coherence times you can see
gait errors and readout errors and we
make that all publicly available we've a
open about that why are we open about
that because that actually determines
the performance or it determines whether
your quantum computer is your quantum
algorithm your quantum program is
actually in a work or not in fact the
compiler that sits between Chris gate
Aqua and Chris gates terror you can tell
it I don't really care which physical
machine you use just give me the one
with the slur the shortest queue or give
me the one with the lowest error if you
look at the actual this is the topology
here so this is this basically says that
qubit zero one can be entangled with
each other but zero and six can't no
they can't so that where there's a
connection there's entanglement
possibility interestingly this one here
it looks totally different from this one
so Mel Bourne is a kind of it's like a
very very linear Tokyo is a mesh it
wouldn't it be nice if you're at least
at the application level the compiler
took care of that and said well just
give me your just give me your topology
and I will map it to whatever is
available so we also do that go on to
github please it's all open source hack
it you prove it
it's an it's just being recorded so I
hope
nobody from IBM sees this but we
actually we've had a lot of input from
people outside IBM who've made some of
the software significantly better okay
you're all developers I'm allowed to say
that
nobody's gonna hoist my petard for that
one so you can see up here there's a
hundred and seventy seven repositories
in total working with and on and related
to Chris kit and around 2k commits so we
have some people out there working very
actively with this on developing this
software and using it but actually
developing the the API itself if you
want to if you want to sign up then and
you're a student or a faculty member or
a PhD student or whatever at any
accredited academic institution please
go via on the hub sign in there if
you're not in that category so if you're
working developer earning real money
with a real job then just go onto the
quiz kit org it's all free we also have
some interesting interesting
collaboration possibilities for
developers for startups if you want to
talk about that just let me know and I
would say with that how many minutes
have I got left one
okay so at that point I have got about
another 300 foils seriously I do have
another 300 foils but they go into go
into things like machine learning
optimization in some detail but I think
that's enough at least initially just
give you a feel for where IBM is and
I'll take some questions so the question
was you heard of or seeing something
about a comment that all quantum
computing problems will be what was it
yeah I I'm familiar with this this is
the the noise beats everything principle
unfortunately I'm I'm not into that
enough to be able to comment on whether
on the validity of it or let me speaking
as an engineer I understand the argument
however back in the nineteen nineteen
sixties when I first took a soldering
iron into my into my hand and I look at
the size of integrated circuits back
then and the performance the Intel 4040
which was the first 4-bit microcomputer
on a on a on a chip with a clock
frequency of I think sixty kilohertz
and the performance figures and noise
figures and capabilities and compare
that with the couple of billion
transistors on this I wouldn't want to
bet on noise I mean always a noise it's
always a problem now you can't get away
from it but I think where we are
currently with the noise ceiling we're
going to push that way way back so there
was another question hold on
yes well of course well the question is
you wanted to ask about quantum volume
and what's the quantum volume of our
current chips like Tokyo the best in the
market of course no yeah we think we
think we think we're among the best
no I mean the the what what quantum
volume is exactly there is a formula and
you could think about you know like
qubit equivalent or noise equivalents
ultimately it's it's the idea is just to
have an awareness of it's not just the
number of qubits yeah you can you could
make a chip right now with a with lots
and lots of qubits but it's be useless
because noise would dominate you need to
do both so hold on before the question
here there was a question back there
can I talk about Chris could aqua and
how the chemistry API was implemented
yeah that's a three-day intensive course
at university basically basically if
you're right now if you're developing
quantum algorithms you have four maybe
five ways to do it the ones always been
mentioned is using Oracle's so can I
decompose my problem into such a simple
fundamental building block that I can
reproduce it Scott Aaronson the the the
father of computational complexity
theory would would you know would be
shooting me right now for claiming that
the second way is can I can I adapt my
problem to a Hamiltonian of some kind we
already saw that with those ody video
using that but Righetti everybody's
using that using the variational quantum
eigen solver take my problem and map it
to a Hamiltonian the third way Peter
shor kind of did it without realizing it
is there's this really really really
nice nice nice thing and if you're no
electronics engineer or communications
engineer it's that's the point where you
have launched on
enlightenment is that the the Fourier
transform which is in the real world
sucks computationally and the quantum
computer is a thing of beauty it's fast
and it's simple so if you take the
hidden subgroup problem which says I've
got a group of things are the two two
subgroups which are isomorphic which map
one to one to each other it's a
combinatorial problem basically to
answer that you've got up you've got to
look at every possible subgroup so for a
group of size n it's two to the end
computational steps the quantum Fourier
transform you just you just do a Fourier
transform of it and you say suck all the
isomorphic subgroups appear as like
frequencies when you do a normal Fourier
transform that technique you can use
that to these to do phase estimation
with phase estimation and rb2 rotations
you can do the h HL algorithm
you can do matrix inversion so you take
a Gaussian elimination which is n cubed
and turn it into h HL which is log n
there are a few other techniques
somebody standing up which means I got a
schüttler
hello if you want to talk about that if
you want to learn about that you're
gonna work on that sign up there's a
there is a slack channel there's a whole
bunch of idea as Emma's on the slack
channel we're very happy to talk to you
if I got a stop now I'm around today and
I'm around tomorrow so just hit me of
you
if you've got questions or you want to
know more
[Applause]