are we wrong the next talk is what are
you our users could be controlling into
your kubernetes cluster by Julio Garcia
welcome okay thank you okay
[Applause]
lot of people today sorry about my
accent first and then let's try to make
this quick and something interesting the
idea is to tell you a little bit how we
use file code to detect what your users
are abusing inquisitor l in your
communities cluster okay
so first of all let me introduce a
little bit what is Falco Falco is a
behavioral activity monitor that allows
you to this detect suspicious activity
based on a set of rules that you can
write okay we do that using tapping in
the kernel module and listening to the
Siskel's there and keep during that with
put powerful expressions we have full
support for adding context to that
syscall from the orchestrator and for
the containers and process of a of the
system and we have a system for
notification very flexible that you can
output that until occasions out to the
standard log to the syslog to work who's
with to whatever you want okay and
furgus open source of course we recently
changed to apache license but it was
opened from the beginning and we are
really willing that everybody helps out
with a better write better rules or make
improvement for the - okay another thing
that we are really excited about is that
falco has recently joined the club that
it could be computing foundation the
sandbox level project but the idea is to
bring it up and make it a more mature
tool there the idea is to improve from
tense acuity for cloud native platforms
right now into the tech on normal
behavior there in containers and host
and an Allen teen the orchestrators
activity okay
a quick example of how falco works in
the upper part you have Falco running in
the lower part there are we are doing
bad things in a container we are
executing a second unit we are touching
sensitive files we are trying to copy
the server 5 the password file we are
trying to modify files under the Beanery
folder and all of this is being notified
by Falco in the upper part you can see
ok so this is the normal use of Falco
Reyna a little bit talk about their
internal architecture right now to
explain how we improve this and modify
it to allow the the auditing of the
orchestrator events ok what Falco does
internally in the architecture is that
he it up in the system tree in the event
system ellen trinkles
ok take that system call and take it to
the user space as more information about
the process the docker container word is
tranny in the orchestrator I'm generate
an event call object
determine collage it goes through the
rail engine that has a lot of Falco
rules are configured by the user and try
to match much mass mattress pad Court
rules against the event call event
object call and if there is a match then
goes to the output and notify in
whatever means you have configured Falco
to do that ok
how is a Falco drool
I don't know you see well I think so so
for example this is a simple rule that
notify you if the somebody tries to
write below the binary ok so as you can
see we have the condition where we go to
the role ending goes to the system call
event and check the event type of the
system that this is call and if you sow
no pain a ghost
go ahead with the condition check-in
checks the directory that is being
executed that open call and then if
there is a match goes to the output and
get some more information from the from
the event to give more information in
the output of the Falco rule for example
this
that right the have tried to execute
that the the command light that that was
execute was executed and they the binary
that was at additive okay
so with this in mind the idea was to try
to reduce all these for doing the same
with the l detail so we want to reduce
the the conditions they were the field
the expressions that we have there the
output even the channels where we write
the rules okay so let's see how we did
that first of all let's talk a little
bit about the kubernetes of it events
this is a this is a thing that is only
from kubernetes nothing to do with falco
it was added in 1.11 and provides a
chronological set of records that
documented the change in a cluster okay
its record is edition object and you
have to enable this it doesn't crime
enabled by default and you can select
what do you want to be notified about
you can be you can say oh yeah I only
want to be notified about deletes I only
want to be notify about Melissa case
Yost or about creates or whatever and
then all that can go to a lock back end
that can be a la hora what hook in Falco
we configured our workgroup for for that
mean so this is the this is a a
kubernetes all determined addition it
was simplified a little bit because
there isn't even more stuff there but
this is to so you can see more or less
what kind of information came from the
from the kubernetes to to the tool that
you configure to well Dale determines
you can see that we have the birth in
this case was a delete the user that
secured that delete the status or the
timestamp when this was secured and
unique ID for example and even then in
the annotations we have the
authorization that allow this Sakina
and other stuff so a lot of information
to to to be filter and to be useful for
detecting things how do we integrate
this with with Falco first of all we
create an animal good server inside the
inside Falco and make them I'm prepared
to listen only for post request as
simple attitude by HTTP then we
configure the kubernetes a little and
the policy and anawa hook directly to
the embedded with self
so whenever are a new kubernetes all
determine what innovated was posted to
the embedded web server and there it was
part set another a little bit more
information and insert that in the rule
engine like the cisco Levin's were okay
this runs in parallel and with another
set of valve Falco rules but we have
they're running the two systems at the
same time and the outputs are the same a
little more information about how they
do that we create a hinari Kevin
interface so we have the common part in
one of the objects we create we create
an kubernetes of the dev an object and
then we insert that directly there is a
JSON object and create a DJ some
pointers to track values from there okay
so the ideas that we have in that event
we have all the information that the
kubernetes has passed that pass us and
we can work with it and now another
thing that we have to do is to identify
the Falco rules so some of them are only
for the sis cards and another one for
the kubernetes all determines because
they are different okay so we have a new
a new property to the Falco rules that
is the source talking a little bit more
about the do some pointers is a really
easy wave do you know XPath is that
really easy way to navigate a JSON and
go and take different values inside it
so we can the idea of doing it so he
sees that you can write that in the file
court rules whenever you're writing I am
preparing one of the custom pools that
you want to write for example more
complex example of the different
pointers using directly one of the how
did kubernetes of deterrence as you can
see really easy you can access the bear
you can access insight to two levels or
more or even arise or whatever
so the syntax a little bit when you are
you see now right in the governmental
rules allows you to use a mediation
pointer to access any part of the JSON
of the kubernetes of it event we have
created some macros to facilitate the
access for for example the birth the
username the third set of suppressors
can be can be excessive easily and you
can see all these right in the last the
last command for Falco that is the same
life like Falco does does help for so
Falco does does least equals kubernetes
of it gives you all this information
directly from the command line a little
bit more or a Falco rule more complex
and complete they prepare for the
kubernetes LD turbines here we have a
rule that allow us to notify a warning
about some complete map that contains
the word password or AWS FS key or AWS
is three FS key
so whenever some user we we create a
config map with some sensitive data we
will be notified okay talking a little
bit more about the Falco rules as you
can see we have markers that we can use
and lists okay and indeed case in this
case for example we can start we start
with a macro for detecting that the
compute map has does provide anything
else okay yeah I mean we can can be much
more complex but with this release
enough we have another Mac referred to
check-in if this is a complete map and
another one to check that we have to
read a modify over that próxima okay and
in the condition as you can see we try
to check three of them and whenever we
check that the three of them has been
fulfilled we go to the output and we
check for example and we return to the
user that is taking Falco rules for
example the username that tried to do
that and what the complete map that he
was trying to create okay
and a little bit of them or now I'm
going to show you a little bit how these
works in real life if nothing is broken
here it will have I have Falco running
okay in a mini queue connected to a mini
cube plus there's no communicable
cluster and here I'm going to try to
execute some some things let me show you
first what I'm going to try to create
for example I'm going to try to create a
simple confuse map with my secret key my
access key for AWS here let me then try
to do that okay and as you can see here
I have been notified about that a
complete mess has been created and this
will be working better
let me try to check demo effect this
will have to be more information there
okay because I am stupid I cannot write
correctly now that's now now yes okay
sorry okay yeah we we have the warning
about the config map that we the
complete mark with a private credential
was creative as you can see we have the
information about the using that try to
create that they complete map all the
information about the complete map and
and everything ok so more things more
interesting things that we can detect
with Falco for example let me create a
normal deployment for indeed this is
really something really easy as you can
see here with our endings and everything
we are notified about the that the
premium has been created nothing special
but now if I try to let me do this if I
try to exit in the path and then this
the problem
what I wrote okay because I don't have
okay but I was working then you notify
me that I try but I didn't correctly
succeed because the Maha was not pull
because I don't have internet connection
now probably so but yeah but you can see
I was I was notified anyway because I
tried and the under seclusion worse than
even it was not successful so they
connected
okay morphine's for example if you I can
create I create a service account this
is usually normally a problem and and
you try to be into being that service
account to the cluster admin to get nice
collection of privilege or whatever and
you are notified about that there was a
cluster all beamed into clusters mean
about that and and you can then act at
all these and one that you said or react
about that another one for example is
that okay this is an over like a really
permissive cluster role create that I
have here that allow was to attend your
screws and with and uncreate then across
federal Wyndham for my user okay so let
me create this
and now we should see here that there is
a warming here about the clustered role
was created with the Google car so we
can check something so so special about
it like or too much permissions to a
secret fees or things like that but the
and at the end for example and a little
example about the clustered roles is
like the spot exec this project SEC
permission for example you can also
notify out about something so much more
specific like if you try to give police
accuse of permissions to a cluster role
you have to do you are notified to a lot
it just like you see here ok so let me
return now today so nothing more
specific you have here you have here all
day all the links about the website we
have a public slack for sis D there is
no specific is locked yet for Falco but
you can join there and there is a
channel specific for falco where people
questions and and there are several
developers from the tools there that can
answer probably better than me we have
some blog posts about it spinning how it
works
and now you can you can join us in the
github repo to to help improve this and
write more roots and that's all
questions
[Applause]
the notifications you showed were just
log messages running in Falco do you
have ways of exporting it out other yeah
we do can you can configure that in the
Falco Reapers planes there are several
possibilities you can send that to our
hook and then react to a door to concern
that to uh notify our server place a
server less función and then react based
on that what ever do one build on top of
that is is really easy we are going to
be in grant next week doing that
workshop and we will be so we hope to do
that sadly on how to with Google s I
think release over there so we will be
doing that Wednesday afternoon in
inventing after complete management but
it's easy to do extended better that
modification channel and send it was
luck or to whatever place one any other
questions so as I understand since the
Falco uses cystic under the hood yeah
and a cystic recently introduced support
of EBP F so now we don't need to add the
kernel module right
is it like production ready is it stable
alright right now we are posting it
internally about we it even reach even
QA yet it's the developers are testing
it but we didn't have the time to to the
tested properly yet but it's in the
works and probably will still be I think
it's for this year for the eyes will be
ready thanks not ready
that's our questions thank you thank you
[Applause]