okay
last talk of the day I'm gonna have mass
and took to us about writing CNI and I
use it ice oops well mister I'm sorry
sorry I thought we had working
hello my name is Martin I'm working for
Red Hat I'm taking care of the
networking side of the overit and cube
URIs projects and today I will tell you
about how to write a CNI and we'll
quickly implement basic CNI plugin
I will try to make it as simple as
possible so please bear with any
simplifications that I will make I'll
probably make quite a few of them okay
in the demo I'll first go
I will first have two slides about
containers and network namespaces will
briefly talk about what a CN is and then
we'll go over to the live demo Hey
what is a container it's a combination
of some C groups for meter metering and
limiting some storage and a set of
namespaces the namespaces are to keep
things private to the container so we
have some protest namespaces mount
namespaces and what's most important to
us in this presentation the network
namespaces how many of you are using
network names places or are familiar
with that not everyone they stopped by
default in a Linux instance the whole
networking stack is short so you can see
all the network interfaces the routing
tables all other resources some network
namespaces change that a network
namespace is
a private network stack so you have your
own set of network interfaces your own
private routing tables IP tables
everything separate
you can have you can the network
interfaces they are private to a network
namespace so as in this example you can
for example move and network interface
to a different namespace a very common
scenario that we will use is to employ
virtual Ethernet Paris to communicate
between the tonight between any two
namespaces so let's now go over to what
happens when a container is created in
terms of networking when a content
container is created the network runtime
creates a network named space for our
container this is a simplification for a
kubernetes for example we have a network
namespace for a pod but let's ignore it
for now and after the network is the
container is created our network
namespace is created at this stage the
network name network namespace is not
yet connected anywhere it doesn't have
any network interfaces probably besides
the loopback interface and at this stage
the container runtime has to implement
the networking most container interface
container runtimes use a plug-in
architecture in rocket or kubernetes CNI
is used so CNI is just a specification
that defines the interface between the
container runtime and the network
implementation CNI is short for
container network interface it is a
simple specification between the
container runtime and the network
implementation the main part of course
is the specification but it's not only
this
see and I also have a few plugins basic
plug-in sub supported by the community
it also has some additional libraries
that make the that make writing of
plugins easier like it has a skeleton
that you can use to just populate
important bits and it's part of CNC F
which is also part which is also home to
kubernetes how does it work when the
container is created the network name
space is created the container runtime
looks for a network configuration file
inside the network configuration file it
finds the information on how to find the
networking plug-in using this
information it invokes the cni plug-in
and network configuration is done let's
look at the cni plugin invocation the
plug-in receives two pieces of
information one is the network
configuration file this is exactly the
same file which was used by the
container run time to find the cni
plugin the other piece of information is
the runtime information this is the
information about the container which is
being created the network configuration
at JSON file
it's streamed into the cni plugin in its
standard input the runtime information
it's a set of environment variables such
as container ID or a network namespace
and this is this is passed into the
container as a set of environm
environmentally the cni plug-in
configures the network it has to do
several items one is it has to insert a
network in taste interface into the
network name phase second it has to do I
P address management so it has to give
an IP address to that interface it has
to configure the routing it has it also
has to modify the networking on the host
in such a manner that the container is
reachable from all other containers on
the cluster after it's done
it returns result to the container
runtime the result is in the JSON format
and it's streamed to the container
runtime in the plugins standard output
let's look at an example of the network
configuration file there are actually
only three mandatory parameters CNI
version this is the version of the cni
specification that we implement name and
type type is important here type is it
is actually the name of the plug-in
binary which we will involve so if we
are using demo our binary has to be also
to be named demo there are also some
additional optional parameters like IBM
DNS and the file can also contain any
number of additional parameters not
useful for the container runtime but
it's also passed to to the plug-in and
actually in the demo we will make use of
this the runtime information CNI comment
this is an variable that tells us what
the container runtime wants the plug-in
to do we have four values add delete
track and version adds it obviously
means we are adding a container delete
we are deleting a container check its
track if the network configuration is
okay and version this just returns the
supported versions a container ID pretty
obvious Network not earnest this is the
network namespace I have named this is
the name of the network interface which
the container runtime expects us to
create CNI path this is the path to the
cni plugins directory and CNI arcs this
is just some additional
information that the container runtime
wants to pass to us in kubernetes for
example you can find the pod name that
is being created in here CNI result this
is the CNI result for adding for adding
a container we have the CNI version a
list of created interfaces IP routes and
DNS information we'll go over that in
more detail in the demo so let us now go
over to the demo first
I will briefly talk about what I will do
when we start the demo our container and
our network namespace will already be
created first we will write a simple
network configuration file the second
step just to make it a little bit easier
we'll use named network namespaces what
we will get from kubernetes is an
unnamed network namespace just for the
sake of making it easier we'll create a
named one next we'll create a bridge to
which we will connect and we'll add
we'll add an IP address to it we'll
create a virtual Ethernet para will move
one one end of the period to our bridge
and we'll move the other end to our
network namespace remember that
container run time gives us the name of
the of the interface is expect to be
inserted into the namespace so next step
we will rename it will configure the
connection we'll add the IP will
configure routing and this is it okay
during the live demo I will coat the
plug-in and I will make some titles I
don't plan to make any but still I will
make some so let's make it a group
if you spot any typos let me know right
away and to make it worthwhile I have
some swag to give away I have some heads
and some lighters which are also I can
turn off I mean bottle openers so if you
want to grab some spot a typo okay
this is my host it's a kubernetes setup
all-in-one sure I thought it's already
big is it okay now
okay let's first go to our configuration
directory it is CCNA and this is the
directory where we will find our network
configuration now does anybody know what
property kubernetes uses to identity
our configuration file yes you don't
count
okay okay I see no other answers I mean
other people knowing this and this is
the correct answer no such property we
can only specify the directory where
config 0 but it's only yes please
grab some swag after the meeting we can
only specify the directory kubernetes
we'll look at all the files in
alphabetical order and it will pick the
first one
so let's modify the one that will
specify our our plugin notice is it
second one alphabetically so it will not
be used yet we have the version we have
the name my demo plug-in and we have the
type let's call it demo and as I said we
can have any number of additional
attributes here we won't we want to
connect to a bridge so I will add a
variable through this let's call it demo
BR and we want to connect to it we want
to be able to to set up the routing so
let's also pass in the Gateway and make
it an o1 no typos okay I will not rename
the second file yet or delete it we
don't have our plug-in yet so let's
first write this by the way we don't
have the bridge either so let's create
it now and let's give it an IP address
all right and we'll go over to the
directory or with the plugins our
plug-in is called demo it's slightly
pre-populated to avoid typos I will
explain the already existing items as I
go along so what we want to do first we
want to grab our network configuration
file from standard input we'll do that
by just looking at death yesterday in
just to make it a bit more readable our
comments next we want to rate our custom
attributes okay
oh wait wait wait and we can Center it
does it work
okay story for this I didn't see that
it's that it's not visible okay next
what we want to do is retrieve our
custom variables so what we need is our
bridge and our gateway excuse me
comments don't count but please grab
your property after the demo anyway I
will run out of swag if you wait so we
have our network configuration in the
conf variable this is JSON
so let's retrieve the bridge parameters
so we will we will F or echo conf and
we'll pass it to J cube JQ is a
command-line utility for parsing JSON
very handy if you don't know it - r is
for raw values and we want to get great
let me just repeat that and the second
one we want to get if Gateway next step
we will as I said we want to use a named
namespace it will be easier to code so
choose a name for our namespace and this
name obviously it should be something
unique
so we'll just go with the container ID
here see an icon the inner ID CNI
container ID is the environment variable
set by the container runtime and next
open to save time I will choose the
simplest IP address management method
available and by that I mean I will
hard-coded if you want to use it in
production don't do this it will not
work I mean it will only work for the
first container we only have ten minutes
left so let's speed up now we have an if
we inspect the cni comment we want if
it's add it means we are adding a
container so the next step should be to
create our namespace you can create a
name network name space by creating a
link to the namespace the namespace is
given to us in the cni net and as
variable and we created in vara run net
NS
and we already have a name for it that's
the NS name variable
now usually we won't have the directory
by default so let's just create it too
and this should create our namespace
next step next step would be to create
our Vesper we can do that do this by IP
link IDI vas we'll name the end of the
Vesper that we'll put in our into our
root namespace red fruit and the other
end vas ns I type first pure name if you
are not familiar with that we are it's
opening at the name of one end of the
Vesper we indicate the type and we say
that the pure name the other end should
be named with an S and now we'll handle
verse wrote what we want to do we want
to edit to our bridge I'm feeling that
first root master and we have our bridge
name in the bridge variable what we want
to do next we want to set it to up and
let's just set the bridge to up to I
can't remember if I did it great up next
step we have to take care of our the
other end of the Vesper Oh we'll have to
move it to the namespace so we do that
by saying IP link set the device name
not an S and we have our own namespace
and last name let me just check if this
is how we named the variable yes oh yeah
I wanted to you can get some of this
work even so you're a CNI maintainer
I wanted to write what we are doing so
move
vasin s29 space now we want to rename it
we want to rename it to whatever the
container run time is expecting so we'll
do that by saying first we have to set
the device to down IP link set of NS
down note that we have already moved the
interface to our namespace so we cannot
just do IP link set because that does
things in our root namespace we have to
tell the IP tool that we are using a
different name space and we do that by
IP not earnest with the namespace name
so one once it's down we can rename it
of course we have to do it in the
namespace again that
nice name and we rename it to CNI AF
name and we want to bring it up again we
have to use the new name now now IPAM
usually item is more complicated than
this
and let's add some routing
fold the and we have the gateways
variable now we are we are almost done
now we have to now we have to return the
result back to our container run time to
do this we'll need two more values will
need to retrieve the Mac of the Edit
interface and the interface index I
pre-populated to avoid typos I couldn't
arrange enough slack in the project this
is the template for our output we have
the cni version we have the interfaces
we only add one so we have the name Mac
and sandbox sandbox is just network name
face so it's a repetition of the cni not
honest variable which we have received
eyepiece node interface is the interface
index note that this is an integer value
so no quotes here it's a little bit
misleading but the elemental maintainer
can answer the questions about this
after the session so we use print just
to populate the values this is the
interface name the Mac network namespace
I'm trying to speed up a little bit
because we are running out of time we
return the result by just echoing it to
standard output and we are almost done
now because you haven't spotted all the
typos because it was so quiet what we
might want to do we want to do to add
some logging so we'll just redirect our
error stream to a file not to death
d MODOK we also might want to echo earth
to echo
we might want to echo the action which
the CNI wants us to perform so
[Music]
and because it will be useful later on I
will also echo the output
below we can find some actions that we
will do during a delete we just want to
clean up the namespaces and the Wester
let's save it and let's try to run it
before we run it we need to swap the
configuration files so let's just move
this one to a different name so
alphabetically our receive first so
let's start a pod
I'll create kubernetes deployment with
local image
I mean local from a local repository and
the moment of truth get pod and it says
container creating so we probably made a
typo we already had that I had a shebang
for a log
and it says network is unreachable Amol
let me just say if them
let's delete the deployment clean is
just script that I wrote to clean the
the environment so that we start off
with a clean with a clean one and points
up let's just and it's running no not
yet
please give me one more minute let's
just try if we can ping it we are
offline so it's yes if we have