hello everyone this is a talk about xcp
ng so this is more the story behind the
project and not technical talk but
anyway the title is building an open
source and chunky patronization platform
so first I'm Oliver I'm the CEO and
founder of eights company doing open
source since 2012 and I'm a sysadmin
performer since I mean doing a lot of
Linux BSD and Zen stuff also I'm the
founder of Zen Orchestra XE PNG project
you can find us on Twitter and here the
website of XC PNG project so first to be
sure we are talking about the right
thing the title was about a chunky and
open source virtualization platform so
what does it mean so it means that a
veteran's Asian platform is not just the
hypervisor it's the hypervisor but also
the network stack the storage sack and
an API so in the case of XE PNG it's
basically Zen as the main engine and
open the switch for the network's mappy
which is the storage stack inside XC PNG
and finally zappy which is the api for
for it on top of that you can put as an
orchestra which is basically a web
solution to manage the platform when I
said turnkey turnkey means that you just
have to download the ISO and install it
on your hardware so it means you don't
have to make some specific configuration
to have your Zen running you just you
know download put an e on the stick put
on the hardware install it and that just
works plus you got everything that you
need through the API so it could be
using the clients like the CLI or a web
UI anyway every command is going through
the API so it means for example if you
want to create a network you don't have
to do that manually
Isis h2 the box and create you know a
network using obvious no need to that
you just tell the API I want a network
from my VM
and finally when I said open source well
we know what open source min but I want
to just tell it's not about only the
license its gplv2 that's cool but it's
also something that having a really
really nice community and nice I mean by
that a lot of people coming from
everywhere and working on the projects
not just you know giving feedback but
also improving the documentation etc and
finally it's also about the governance
of the projects when I mean open source
I mean also that all repo all the dark
and the developments it's completely
publicly accessible so that's for me
really important it's not just a matter
of the license so this is just a view of
a dashboard so you can represent what
does it mean so this is web UI Zen like
Easter on top of XC PNG so classical
stuff you know like overt or proxmox
whatever so a bit of history for people
here doesn't know as any detail so it's
not new it was in fact the first open
source hypervisor released back in 2003
and then six weeks why the company are
doing Zen called Zen source and Citrix
decided to launch something called Zen
server which is basically a veteran
platform it was closed source at the
time and then a bit later switch we
decided to focus more on desktop
virtualization so it means the product
that are using XenServer on top but more
you know for people accessing to their
desktop Windows desktop from a remote
location and it means that Citrix is
more focusing on that and not more more
on server virtualization one year later
the first time the first release of xcp
was done and basically it was the open
source version of XenServer and xcp
means Zen cloud project so you start to
know about xcp so you can imagine why
it's xep energy because it's xep new
generation few years later XenServer was
open sourced so it means the end of the
xep project because it was the open
think that now everything is open-source
no problem and this is when we started
to work on Zen orchestra to give you
some some timing in 2017 situated to
remove some really cool feature inside
the XenServer so they decide to remove
for example live storage migration and
and that kind of stuff and all big
features not in the hypervisor itself
because the design is fully open source
but in the platform won't be open source
in the end so we decided just a few
times later to start the xcp project
it's the energy project to remove all
those restriction and to do a lot more
than just a fork so you can ask the
question why we are doing that because
you know it sounds a bit 2008 - for
catalyzation platform everyone is
talking about the cloud and containers
etc etc but on the field you know if you
are not Netflix or a very large company
like that everyone is still using the
translation and people want to have
something that works that's ideally
open-source and that can scale so well
our reasons to do that we are multiple
first XenServer was a great tool really
a grateful because it was a real chunky
platform but now we know the the future
is a bit closed source sadly there
wasn't any developer community outside
Citrix walls because it's it's more a
commercial project for Citrix also
Citrix had other priorities and you know
working with the server of its relation
world so it makes sense for them you
know to have other priorities not a
problem but at the problem with that is
there is no convergence between people
want to make server virtualization and
people want to make desktop
virtualization also not all components
were open to contribution you know when
you're really is it's GPL compliant you
reuse a tarball but you don't have you
know the master branch so it's really
hard to contribute from some project
inside it so we we saw a great
opportunity to open everything and to
allow people to work on that and we
proved the project also for us as a
company
working on zanuck Ezra it's a good
opportunity to grow these an ecosystem
you know by not just having one platform
but another one which is more open and
also be able to answer people needs not
just on the management side but also on
the layer which is on the bottom of
Zeena bistra because now we can you know
having a common objective with both
software to go into the right direction
to improve for example some performances
that are really important for us and
also fix all bugs etc etc but doing a
fork of a platform is like a
distro okay so it's not really easy just
to show you this is basically XenServer
or XC PNG platform in in that square so
it means you've got a lot of components
so we are not every component
see it wouldn't have make sense to fork
then or Linux because they are fully
open source but the goal is to be able
to take the stuff to understand how it
works and to build that in a more open
fashion in short okay but to do that you
really need to understand which
component is talking to other components
etc so the interactions between all
those components this is one of the
challenge so to recap the three parts
the 3 main challenges that we have to to
overcome the first one and maybe the
most important one at least first is to
get a good community working with us so
it means not to be only you know a small
company doing some stuff in our corner
but to be able to gather people around
projects and to have people starting to
do contribution and that kind of stuff
so we weren't you know the only company
doing that so this is one of the
challenge the other one is as you may
see in the technical challenge technical
challenge is we need to be able to folk
that and truly something that works ok
so it's not just not getting the whole
stuff we need to understand how it works
and we need to also be able to
demonstrate how it works and to improve
it to fix bugs and also for people using
XenServer maybe to be able to migrate to
our solution and finally to is the
adaption for Zen you
for example people who never had any
experience with then so it should be
easy for them to use XC PNG and the last
challenge is to have a really open
projects open aiming methods to get an
open governance for example to be inside
the foundation or also the last part is
to be continued to work for a long
period of time so it means we need to
have under cooperates parts a support
business model so we can continue to pay
a developers team to work in to improve
the product so I did it work
I have some answers the first answers is
well we did a Kickstarter last year and
the first objective was about only 6,000
euros so it was a low bar but we
estimated that we could take too many
risks with that so we will try you know
with to see if there is some interest in
the community about doing that and for
this first goal the objective was to
really is a kind of prototype and we led
all the goals but without thinking that
we will reach all of them and finally in
less than 24 hours so it's February to
March
okay so it's one month and in less than
24 hours we got the first goal and then
in continued and we've seen that a lot
of people were interested in fact you
have a really chunky or an open-source
virtualization platform and in the end
even companies became sponsors by
sending us money not by with the the
Kickstarter platform but by sending
checks or wire transfers so in the end
it was more than this amount and then it
started and it started really fast
because we didn't first fork in April
basically exactly the same thing then
XenServer but without you know the
future restriction but then for the next
releases we we've been able to add new
features for example we have been able
in October to also follow the pace of
Citrix prisons and server and be able to
sign our our rpms to add software read
support during installation to add new
features so it's really a fast
face cycle so today regarding the
community and the project challenge that
we had in the previous slides we've got
a lot of people who build a really
really vibrant community of people using
it a lot of active users on the forum so
active I mean by that people with more
than one post got a lot of posts a lot
of threads everyday got a lot of unique
downloads so it's really a good sign
that people are trying the product are
talking about the product plus it's
still really easy to break from working
XenServer it means it won't erase your
VMs it will just you know like an
upgrade in fact so we will do both and
you will be on X C PNG and it works we
are now a member of Zen security pre
disclosure list so it means before the
public knows knows about some security
features we are you know like Amazon or
the big cloud providers they have in
average 15 days to to fix some problems
so we are inside that so that's really
helpful to be able to to fix problems
really fast before it's public we are
working to be inside a foundation so
it's not official so I can tell a lot
more about that but we are working on
that to really have an open governance
and not you know be the only company
behind that we want to do together other
people around it
and also as I said no license or future
restrictions so about the technical side
so as I said we we did a lot of stuff in
one year so we already for example fixed
bugs in the upstream in the upstream I
made for example in XenServer we
discovered some bugs and we fixed them
or we helped Citrix developers to find
the root cause of some problems so it
was really really cool
we got a testing repo that's really nice
because it means for people who want to
try some maybe cutting-edge features or
you know like support of storage that
weren't existing before without taking
risk to put that into production so you
can let the community to work with that
so that's really really helpful
we got cloud stack compatibility and
finally we embed the set standard
compression inside XC PNG basically
it's not girly the compression algorithm
made by Facebook which allows us to
compress faster and better than the
existing algorithm in XenServer which is
using gzip so we've got a comparison of
backup time in gray light gray without
compression then in dark you get a JZ
compression and in red with that
standard compression so we did a lot of
performance improvement for making the
backup of VM for example when you export
the VM it's compressed we then started
it's really really faster up to six
times faster than JZ
so it means in less than one year we
were able to to add really cool features
in a short amount of time so what's next
so this year we want to have more
firepower and to do that we are growing
the team working on that so we target to
have up to six people working on it we
are working with some research labs and
universities so we found that a
reasonable amount of papers were done in
France about Zen so that's really
interesting to work with a local
university knowing Zen itself so it can
lead to interesting stuff and which I'll
get a team about twenty people for the
end of the year which you count all the
researcher and the engineers and the
contractor again it's a joint effort
regarding the research and development
we got a lot of topics to cover because
as I said there is a lot of room for
improvements and that's really great you
can see that we want to improve on any
sides of a virtualization platform so we
are targeting improvement in the storage
side on the network side and compute
side and to do that with some
universities so you have publication
that's really great because you have
also benchmarks you have the data so you
can see the the improvements that's have
been done into the research so it's very
very very a lot of different stuff but
to give you a quick example of one field
that we are working this year is to
improve the nvme drive obtain drive if
you don't notice right those are three D
X points memory from Intel which is
really really reefer
a lot of high ups but the problem is the
legacy storage designed for
vectorization platform we're made when
HDD where they're so high latency and
not really a lot of high ups but then if
you decide to create a specific layer
which is thinner than the original one
you can maybe reach almost the bare
metal eye ups of the hardware so you
need to do a lot of improvement to to go
there but that's that's doable I mean we
got an architecture and we know the
general direction when we go we need to
go but now this year we need to go
through the next phase which is a proof
of concept and some benchmarks and then
if it goes well then it will be
implemented and again pushed upstream
because the goal is to push everything
upstream also because as I said it's a
distro in the end like a debian or
whatever we need to improve the thing so
in X a PNG like in XenServer the dumb
zero the privileged Amin is based on
CentOS so we need to have a platform
like cozy to automate the RPM build
process Kochi is used by fedora we need
to also make some automatic QA and CI so
if we add for example a patch of
something that's ideally your platform
should be able to tell everything is
great it's built it works automatically
so this will help the project to have
more contribution because every time
someone adds something automatically it
will be tests also the great thing about
it it's that you can have nightly builds
for people who want to test really
really cutting-edge stuff there's that
very stuff so to improve the mirror
management when someone will become what
should become a mirror for download XE
PNG there's a lot of project are doing I
think we will use a project done by used
by the people behind the VLC projects
okay so we can use really interesting
open source projects to help us about
that so also other features but I will
you know enter to to deep inside the
details
so and to recap also regarding these
anarchist aside it's a management
platform but more than that you can do
backup resource delegation so it's not
cloud stack or OpenStack okay but still
it helps you manage your infrastructure
up to let's say two or three thousand
VMs and then if you have a large
infrastructure maybe probably cloud
stack up and stack will be better but
anyway we want to integrate more
features between the two the two
software because this allows us to to
create really interesting connection and
to also innovate on both interaction
between between the two software so we
are working with both as an orchestra
team but also the XE PNG team working
together on the ideas to push both
projects into the right direction so how
to help well we we got a really nice
community so if you want to to just try
it download it and then if you have any
problems to talk with people there also
we are hiring so if you are interesting
to work on system development like um
you or as N or that kind of stuff even
the kernel or if you are using or
developing you know KML because the API
is in oak animal we're interesting so
just come to see me after the talk as a
company there is a lot of interesting
programs if not you will make research
and developments at the European level
also just in the end using it will be
helpful because more people using it
more hardware will be tests so it can
work for your I would say medium desktop
machine up to your server inside data
center but it was built in mind to run
into let's say servers into a data
center so as you seen there's a lot of
stuff coming and the we did a lot with a
small team and having a larger team will
be really interesting and we hope to to
build a lot of new features and exciting
features for for this year so stay tuned
on the XP dot ng dot org website you get
all the other new stuff and that's at
12 question go ahead yep for now it's
okay what's the difference now with a
sense of a project right now we tend to
limit the fort because we are pushing
upstream everything that we are adding
so for example for the Zetas City stuff
we added that into the upstream because
most of the tools inside XenServer are
open source so we can push you know for
the API zappy on the github etc so we we
try to maintain the smallest fork as
possible but drive innovation and maybe
to to to use our innovation faster than
the Citrix cycle which is different than
ours because we don't have the same you
know priorities India yeah yeah merging
features faster and and and yeah to be
more flexible than then XenServer
release cycle yeah yeah there
so so what what do you mean is does it
work with cloud sack or sorry I didn't
hear the the OpenStack yeah we don't
have open stock support right now
because you know OpenStack can work with
XenServer on the bottom cloud stack to
the people like glass stack already
helped to make it compatible with it but
not yet at OpenStack I don't know the
current status add up and sack right now
but maybe you shouldn't being some
developers it's it's the same API so
it's not really complicated to adapt to
it it's just you know changing the name
a string basically to to have the
support of its because it's exactly the
same API other questions yeah okay so
what the main driver for the XE PNG
project right now it's weights the
company behind it but for example on the
Windows stuff like the Windows client
and the drive heavy drivers it was
someone from the community so the goal
to be inside a foundation is to be able
not to be the only company driving the
project we have a lot of people working
on it we don't have a lot of people on
into it and we are we have professional
supports on it but it doesn't mean we'll
be the only company to to to provide
improvement inside it and and the goal
is to have more companies to you know to
work with us for example we have some
people who would like to have for
example the V excellence reports because
they are using a big data center and
they are ready to work with us to
improve that so it's not just something
by white company if we don't want to be
the only company behind that in the end
yes
but the crux long stairs the advantage
if you just want to run one suburb with
virtualization you're already getting
why and everything sedation
[Music]
okay okay so the question is the ability
to use only for smaller use cases for
one server because for example proxmark
Scott's web UI bundled directly with the
installation so you just for one machine
it makes sense you have everything
bundled it's not the case for XE PNG but
yeah you can deploy as anarchist
relatively easily if you just want a
basic UI we got a virtual appliance
that's just really to download and to
and to use if you want to install it
from the source yes you need a VM to Moo
to make it work but bundling a web UI
directly inside it could be problematic
for something that's made to be working
clusters in pools so we are thinking
about that but there is no trivial
solution to deliver something like that
right now yes makes sort so we make what
with web UI
okay so the question is maybe to create
a flavor of XC PNG with a web UI bundle
inside it this is some stuff that we are
discussed about already so we are
thinking about about this oh and by the
way we got stickers if you want at the
end of the talk just thinking about this
right now okay that's it thanks a lot
you