so hello everyone I am Eric I work at
kelabra the graphics team and I will be
talking about a not really hardware
enablement project I had an accident
yesterday and or not and hit my head so
I've moved mr. and I will as a
result probably go a little bit slow and
might we might not make it to the end of
this presentation but yeah so that's me
so yeah the goal the goal here in
general is to implement OpenGL on top of
Vulcan to make a simpler graphics touch
in the future of the Linux system so
there's a few other attempts at this out
there that already exists I think
silicon has made something called glove
it only implements OpenGL ES 2.0 and the
CLA requires a copyright assignment
there so which can be tricky for some
companies to work with Google has angle
they again also implement only OpenGL ES
and there's something called VK GL which
targets opengl 3 core profile so it's
not gonna do
legacy opengl versions no fixed function
or anything like that and this is a
pretty slow-moving project it's
sparetime project for a single developer
and it has a really long way to go
before it can be very useful so for
solving this there's nothing really out
there that fits as well so
- the wrong way
No yeah so I guess that's what these
slides I'm sorry for that yeah so why we
want to solve this is that OpenGL is a
requirement for supporting desktop
applications it's it's a pretty pretty
dated API it's been around since 1992
and the hardware has changed a lot since
then and so has the software world so
there's a lot of things that's OpenGL
isn't so well suited for my work came
out of virtualization so be able being
able to use GPUs in virtual environments
I'm working up Virgil and Mesa for this
and there's some problems with that but
that were trying to circumvent but I am
seeing if this vendor works or not yeah
Volken is also kind of becoming more and
more proven in technology and and it's
pretty clear that it's becoming the
dominant graphics API going forward
which means that OpenGL has a little bit
of a less bright future and it's better
for the graphics community if we can all
kind of work on one API rather than
multiple ones but as I said we still
need to support all applications that
that use OpenGL currently yeah and
there's some other use cases that can be
enabled by this work for instance mobile
platforms that support Vulcan can get
full OpenGL support which they don't
currently have so my solution to this is
called zinc it's an it's a NASA gallium
driver that takes the gallium API calls
and translate them into Vulcan it's
currently what I would call an early
kind of out of tree prototypes stage the
driver works reasonably well it supports
opengl 3.0 on both rad
and envy so the open source in Mesa MD
and Intel drivers we haven't tested much
on anything else some people try to get
it working on and they die but there
were some difficulties with the lack of
DRI to they've early has jumped on this
and started contributing a lot of really
cool features the driver is written and
uh pretty kind of like naive
happy-go-lucky approach to kind of see
what could possibly go wrong and uh
turns out it works a lot better than I
feared
and yeah I can run a lot of games and
other demos applications with a pretty
usable performance and I'm not going to
talk much about performance because
we're haven't focused that much about
that and that but for some simple
benchmarks I get roughly half of what I
965 provides and that's with some pretty
not great stalls that we're doing kind
of to place the windows system yes ok
currently I'm taking a little bit of a
step back and kind of re-engineering it
a little bit because a bunch of the
early assigned decisions I've made were
turned out to be mistakes and so I'm
trying to like build a smaller feature
version of it that I can upstream in my
sound and kind of build the more of the
features on top of that again yeah so
it's a it's a galvan driver for those
who don't know my son guy Loomis on
opened it's a system that takes OpenGL
calls and kind of translate lets them
into a more low-level API and yeah
sync will kind of take that and
translate that to Vulcan and communicate
what's on Window System is this this is
the software windows system which is not
good where they have a hardware like
yeah
the amoeba bastes thing as well and
there's a rough overview of how I draw
calls kind of or the data flow of the
driver so there's for instance a
compiler that feeds a program cache and
there's a pipeline cache that takes in
render passes and creates frame buffers
and feeds that into command buffers yeah
so we're doing the shader worked with a
neuro which is an SSA bastes compiler I
are in Mesa I translate that into super
V which is the Vulcan shader IR I chose
to go that direction rather than
something like TJ's I mostly because SSH
SSI is or seem to be a great fit it
turns out to be a little bit harder than
I thought because of some annoying
differences in how they treat some of
the fundamental SSA constructs it's
written as a reusable module hopefully
like similar to that we currently have a
spur v2 no so it's kind of written in a
somewhat similar fashion and I'm hoping
that well that maybe we can make an
entry GLSL all the way to spur V
compiler and that's it's this isn't the
high like an important goal but there's
it seems neat to be able to do that
without pulling in other compilers for
maybe we need to pre compile from
traders for instance it does not
generate awesome codes seems to the
Vulcan drivers and desktop kind of make
up for the bad code regenerate by
optimizing it afterwards but I fear that
this is not gonna fly on mobile mobile
drivers are probably less eager to spend
CPU time on icing the code first
yeah so I'm gonna talk a little bit now
about the different difficulties we met
some of these have solutions some of
them have ugly hacks and yeah yeah so
control flow we don't support it pretty
pretty bad this is one of the kind of
like big ticket things that needs to be
fixed I think before I can upstream it
it's yeah I have some prototype but that
kind of crashes and burns in some cases
it's trickier than it sounds and the
reason for this is these SSA differences
that I talked about in our jumps can
appear from anywhere inside a basic book
which is a very creative way of defining
a basic block I think so so for instance
I am err jumpin return break continue
this can all bit and some intrinsics
also have implied control flow
modifications like this card in an
interview all of this terminate the
basic block and that means that
addressing finals gets pretty hairy it's
probably not super duper hard to to
solve but I think I'm gonna have to like
except not a direct translation here
first I'd like to do something a little
bit favor I haven't haven't really spent
much thought about this effort kind of
hitting this wall
yeah another problem is that the SSA
values of NARAS type ty plus they're
basically just a bucket of bits which
means that we currently just bit cast
everything into if I'm from you and this
creates a lot of needless instructions
in a lot of cases and yeah it's not not
great there's some externus event o has
been nice enough to create a prototype
for looking kind of scanning past that
finds out which cast can be removed and
kind of replaced the different SSA
values with typed versions it doesn't
work for all of the stuff but it's it
doesn't meet its kind of problem needs
to do better than nothing
they're still yeah some constants are
still problematic with that but you
probably probably extend it I haven't
tested this pass yet of time
restrictions yeah then another thing
that needs to be solved but we're not
doing of Awesomeness
how to bind a shaded resources to to the
shaders and and for those who don't know
Vulcan the the way you address resources
or bind them is through descriptor sets
so we have a set of like you can have an
descriptor sets and they have kind of
indexed resources in side of them we
currently just push all of this into one
big descriptor set which is a pretty
easy approach but it's might not be
great from performance point of view
especially the Vulcan spec suggests that
this is not a good idea
we stole that idea from the xvk and it
seems to work okay but some points we
should probably look into doing this a
bit more properly
and I think making a descriptive per
stage
appreciated stage makes this easier and
we will get much smaller indices there
and that seems seems good yeah and then
we also need to have as you draw in it
we need to deal with the descriptor sets
currently watch what we do is we create
a huge descriptor set pool and just
allocate from there until the allocation
fails then we flush the the GPU and wait
for the GPU to finish and reset the pool
that's all obviously not not a great
idea and it causes some validation
errors and some framerate hiccups so
it's probably better to have multiple
smaller pools and keep track of how many
how many descriptors we've used from
there and you know use some fences to
automatically wait if the next thing
wasn't finished yet so on the GPU
yeah we for those who don't know what
pipeline objects are there an object in
Vulcan that encapsulate frame pretty
much all the draw States these are
relatively expensive to create so so we
try to catch them and keep them around
for the next time try to use the same
dress that we currently just do that
kind of naive length put them in the
hashmap
but in the future we want to move to
doing in building an optimized version
of this eagerly and then kind of a
background thread that creates of most
pipelines instead this is what dxv care
does and it seems to work well for them
if I know that Intel driver people is
listening it would be great if you guys
started respecting the disabled my
session but this plan yeah anyway so
this is this whole thing is similar to
variant caching and it's yeah it's it's
not really a big question what to do
here
yeah and we need to also deal with image
layouts which is one of the big
differences with OpenGL for those who
doesn't know quite what that is that
it's kind of like a it's a hint to the
driver what or what you're gonna do with
a with an image so you can for instance
be set in a state where you can only do
rendering to it or you can only do
texture infer from it and generally
speaking these optimizations or this
might have some of my sessions on the
other level where they're faster at
being exists we just use the big hammer
called layout general and translate to
that as early as we can and just keep
them there there every operation is
allowed but that performance isn't
necessarily great it's this is not a big
problem for us yet mainly because we're
mostly CPU limited rather than GPU
limited of course depends on the
application but it has some nasty
implications with
with rice in us with multiple complexed
where the problem is that the resource
has has different like the resources can
be shared and the context is the only
one who kind of sees when the transition
happens so we need to insert some
fencing or something there to make that
sure we're not doing that I haven't
tried anything that does multiple
contexts this in context yet yeah
in addition this angle is doing some
really cool work of building something
called a frame graph which is like a
kind of build a timeline of what's
happening with things and then measuring
things so you can do move your image
transversus early as possible which is
supposedly better for performance I can
imagine we can do like just steal their
ideas there and something but this I
think comes down the line a bit from
whether or not no yeah and so uniforms
is also kind of a little bit different
in OpenGL you can have like freestanding
like default default uniforms that or a
default uniform block and then gallium
this is a little bit yeah it's the they
look different from the IR and stuff
like that we basically just do a shader
a compiler pass that transforms them
into into a uniform book there's already
some stuff and gallant to do this by
default but we can't use that for some
technical reasons yep
there's some difficulties here it's not
really but interesting I'm gonna just
prefer yeah and then one other issue is
that we're we're depending for some
opengl 3.0 features to fly that will
depend on some ext extensions and stuff
like VK ext transform transform feedback
I'm not so sure we can rely on that
forever and probably not at all
I'm oh well
so we need to rethink some of these
solutions I kind of can envision some of
this stuff being done with a giant
computer that inline all different sizes
that is apart from the fragment shader
into and kind of build some queues
basically every implement the GPU
pipeline compute shader people some
people have done this before with CUDA
and it's pretty successful so so it is
some option but there's maybe it's
better to do some more targeted smaller
things for simple features where we
maybe not fully support the spec but or
get applications running we'll see ya
this other extensions been back that has
the same same problem so yeah we're
currently supporting opengl 3.0 but
there's a little bit of an Asterix there
there are some features we're not
missing most of these are fixed function
kind of details polygons world is
different in Vulcan and OpenGL where and
OpenGL you can specify different polygon
mode for front and back faces and on
Vulcan you can only support one suppose
for one so we just currently issue a
warning if if they're different and use
the font from face state for that I
haven't seen any applications failed
with it this but as we test more
applications I'm sure there's some CAD
applications that aren't gonna render
correctly there's several emulation
paths we can try something like drawing
all the back faces first and then all
the front faces kind of assume they're
ordering isn't important we can write
out the primitives to buffer and like to
stream it out and yes a geometry shader
- yeah construct triangles afterwards
maybe I don't know it's a pretty low low
priority they should fix texture borders
are a little bit different in OpenGL you
can have arbitrary texture borders and
colors and in Vulcan there's three
different ones you can have transparent
black opaque black and opaque
we just hard coded as transparent black
all the time and I have only seen
synthetic tests give any problems but
it's totally possible to do this by
injecting some shader codes it's not
actually that bad to do that but not
awesome yeah if needed we could
implement like a some extension to
support more modes but I doubt it's
going to be important yeah point size
was you you can either OpenGL you can
either write the GL point size outputs
and the vertex shader or you can set fix
the front plate size for the whole joke
all we need to like have some in Vulcan
you can only write the vertex shader we
haven't done any forwarding there if
that's state it's kind of boring code to
write but it's relatively easy and I
think also some of the other drivers
that are working to be up streams gonna
need something similar so maybe we can
work with them on a shared solution yeah
alpha testing it's this in theory very
simple to implement but it requires
requires control flow which we don't
support yeah so it's a difficult role
for it should this will go very quickly
so currently mr. put opengl 2.1 like
it's the lowest sets of features we
kinship support requires vulcan 1.0 and
a bunch of different physical device
features which we don't test first so
probably well before we land this driver
but maybe with an override or something
so you can run things even if
if it's not perfect yeah
opengl 3.0 requires two more xt
extensions
those are both enabled in red V and V so
on both of those drivers we get 3.0 I
had some slides about about future
versions but I decided to cut them there
in the slide deck if someone wants to
download it and read some more it
basically goes through which Vulcan
features we're going to require four all
the way up to 4.6 yeah so in the future
there's a bunch of more stuff to be done
the biggest problem is that the compiler
is not as great as it could be I'm not
really a compiler guy so if someone who
knows compilers would like to help out
that would be awesome yeah and then it's
like fixing rendering issues and
applications and upstream meaning there
so yeah and after that it's like
correcting away on the your OpenGL
versions currently I'm kind of the
bottleneck here and I'm really really
sorry about that for anyone who wants to
contribute and I would be very willing
to have a discussion on fixing that
somehow
so yeah any questions two minutes so one
or two questions I guess
so I think I think if I were to to have
a crack at this myself I think I would
have gone the other way around and
gotten mess out there on that cause I
think there are like builds like to see
I should check some stuff in my so for
now cause I think it works and something
very similar to think I think would be
needed but that outfits metal instead
there are some people have yes Moulton
VK is interesting but I think layering
emulation on top of emulation is so way
to insanity I like if someone will also
try it out they're like they're free to
and you know if they report some bugs
that's that's great there I will you
know have a look at that but I don't
have a Mac I'm not gonna give this a try
alright and more questions
we're hiring