here we go
uh thank you for joining uh the talk uh
i'm uh
i'm a lead scientist at imperva in the
last 21 years i've been innovating on
security and algorithms and
their intersection i enjoy the game of
analyzing threats
and designing mitigation i love math and
i love
all sorts of algorithms and i love
building security technology
and uh in my spare time i love hiking
biking
uh trail running and traveling around
the world uh
alone or uh with my family and this is
another one of
my hobbies and i'm i'm really
disappointed at this time i don't have a
chance to
to go physically to texas and i really
hope that in the
in the next year we'll meet uh face to
face and i can uh
enjoy uh texas a good texas stakes
i will start with a brief introduction
of
ai and the ai threat landscape
i will continue with talking about data
poisoning which is one of the
of the main threats on on artificial
intelligence systems
then i'll continue with explaining the
challenge of data poisoning uh in the
world of uh web security
uh how this uh uh threat is being um
is effective in in this area and what
are the possible mitigations
uh then i will go into uh explaining uh
about a solution to do a robust learning
that is uh safe towards uh
data poisoning uh on a stream data
meaning without
keeping all the data and running it in
batch processing
uh which is very important in in many
many applications
and i will end with a summary and
conclusions
we are uh in the ai era and no doubt
about that
uh artificial intelligence is is
everywhere
uh it is uh it is uh
it involves every probably almost every
aspect
of our life and the ai era is also the
data error because data
like the new gold or the new fuel uh the
thing that
that fuels uh artificial intelligence
system uh
helps them to work and do what they can
do
and uh both the ai era and the data era
are responsible
they have amazing contribution on the
on on many different domains however
this contribution uh comes with several
caveats
which we usually ignore or at least
underestimate to some extent uh and and
this talk will uh we'll speak about uh
about some of these
most of you are probably familiar with
the gartner hype cycle
for new technologies uh and i think you
can
you can think about an equivalent
security lifecycle for new technologies
when you have a new technology and and
that was the case for web that was the
case for mobile that was the case for
uh for iot then at the beginning uh
people experts uh pioneers developed the
technology without
too much thinking about uh security
uh they are excited with the with the
new opportunities that are
unlocked and then at some point someone
discovers that this
system is technology behaves in an odd
way when
a particular input is being fed to it uh
and you have a vulnerability and then
another one and another one
and at some point there are so many
vulnerabilities that people start asking
themselves whether
um this technology can can be ever used
in a safe manner and then we get to this
uh valley to the to the bottom
uh in the point where domain experts
and security researchers start to join
forces to develop
a terminology to develop a methodology
and to give names to attacks and to
start the designing mitigation and then
we get to a stage of a healthy
development where
uh the main threats on this technology
are understood
and are to some extent mitigated uh
and uh we get to this sort of a plateau
this is
not not very static because we know in
the security
we always have new vulnerabilities and
new mitigations
uh for them but uh but we get to a
stable solution where technology can be
used uh
safely and uh and and ai is no different
than other technologies in that sense it
has no exception
uh ai also have vulnerabilities and
we'll speak about some of these in the
next couple of slides
what you see here is a typical machine
learning system a
very very generic one uh there is
a training data so in the training phase
we build a model from a training data or
training set
um and this model can be a
classification model regression model or
it can be other things in depends on the
other problem we want to solve
uh and then uh this model is um
stabilizing is converging and once
seeing an inputs data
in a phase that is called the inference
data this inputs data
an image is now being classified as a
category dog
uh it's that sort of a prediction
in some cases then this this result the
outcome of the model
goes into an evaluation and and then
it's evaluation whether it was good or
bad is being fed
in the feedback loop to back the model
in order to either to
uh to enhance it or maybe to just uh if
the model that we are building is um
is coming to uh uh to represent
in a dynamic environment then we want
the model to keep uh
keep being aligned with the uh with this
environment and
and continue to uh to evolve uh
when you look at this system from an
attacker's perspective
then uh first you know the
when you think of an internal attacker
or an external attacker that's found his
way in
using some i don't know somehow a rce or
any other
attack vector then then the sky's the
limit you can do everything he can
tamper with the model it can steal the
model
you can extract it and can modify every
particular
decision the model has made however
even when the attacker is not an insider
when he is
working from outside then still there's
plenty of things the attacker
can still do uh one of them
is a collection of um of attacks called
uh sometimes
evasion or adversarial examples or ai
deception
where the attacker actually creates data
points that
confuse that make the algorithm making
correct mistakes
most of you probably are familiar i've
seen at least once
this example of stop sign when you add a
couple of stickers to it
and then the ai engine of an autonomous
vehicle he looks at this uh
[Music]
stop sign and it looks for him like a
speed limit site
which of course can have uh a
devastating uh consequences
uh and in i think that in every
situation where someone tried to create
such data points that
that uh that full the um machine
learning model
is success successful with with very
little effort
because we are in designs we know that
whenever you build something
without thinking about what will happen
when the adversary will come
and then your adversary counts then uh
uh
the adversary's work is it is very easy
um the second uh uh
threat is a training data poisoning and
machine learning uh
models uh are based on data
uh and this data usually on on big data
usually it comes
from outside from external sources that
are not always
uh trustworthy uh
and uh if the attacker has some control
over the data then he can carry out uh
something that is called the data
poisoning
attack and we speak uh in in depth about
this uh
this kind of attack later on another
slightly more esoteric threat uh is a
training data leakage
when you build the model from training
data then
some of the training data is actually
leaking
into the model is there implicitly and
in some cases there are ways to uh to
extract this data
and if you use the sensitive data for
the training
which is fairly typical because
training is sometimes it used with a pii
health record so it depends exactly on
what is the problem that you're trying
to solve uh
then this is a thread that you should
you should take care of and make sure
that you are
immune again against it
uh but as i said we will zoom into uh
data poisoning
so uh what is data poisoning and how uh
does it work
uh on the left side you see uh a typical
machine learning model it
it is a clear classifier it tries to
find
the best line that separates between the
red
triangles and the blue circles
and uh the the thing
is that if you take a single point and
move it
into different locations then the the
optimal separator will be completely
different
so even if you have um if you're
changing a very few
uh data points in some cases
it can have significant impact on the uh
on the model that is going to be
generated and on the right side you can
see uh
a more uh significance the example
where the attacker actually uh
tries to do something deliberately and
he will put
all these uh uh it is a batch of uh
of red dots uh which will make the model
uh be completely perpendicular to the
original model and
practically useless for uh separating uh
at the red
from the uh from the blue which is
exactly what the attacker was aiming to
obtain uh now the
the threat of data poisoning you know
the terminology i
i think it is fairly new i only uh heard
about it a couple of years ago
uh however uh this is not a new threat
data poisoning um a threat i think it is
um almost as old as as the internet
because
i i'm sure that like myself when you
enter tripadvisor
and you see now you want to uh to pick a
hotel you see
a positive or a five-star review then
probably like myself you ask yourself
okay
is this a real review or a fake review
uh
because trip advisor like many other
travel sites or actually any side
that use a rating system they count on
data that is coming from outside
and uh data is coming from what's up
outside
it can be subject to uh to malicious uh
circumvention uh and this is the case
for travel sites it
is the case for um i don't know and film
rating sites
it is the case for e-commerce sites and
everything that everything that
has a rating system uh is subject to uh
data poisoning
uh and these sites are aware of that
they do they take
some at least some measures to try to
mitigate
the threat and to uh to minimize or
to make the life harder for the
attackers to uh to impact
uh the actual rating
uh here you see an example of uh data
poisoning in the wild
and the attack here is a model skewing
attack um
sometimes called also a backdoor
the attack occurred in the end of 2017
on gmail spam filter uh
actually this is not surprising that one
of the battlefield for data poisoning is
uh
is a spam because this is i think one of
the of the first domains where
machine learning models prove themselves
very effective against
adversaries and for the sake of this
discussion let's say
let's say they called some spam
providers adversaries
and what the attackers did they wanted
to uh
to make the model think that their
emails
are legitimate so uh they fed the model
with massive amounts of uh
of spam like emails and they label of
them
as benign and their intention was of
course that
uh the model we learn all the
the keywords the structures that are
within
uh these messages that you will learn
that
it will learn that these structures and
keywords are actually representing
legitimate emails and when they will
have the actual spam
uh then this uh then
it will go under the radar of the model
uh but
uh uh google research team had detected
it and
and analyzed the and this is uh and
this um this chart came from
google research uh another example again
uh of uh of spam filters is um
an availability attack so if the
previous attack you can think about
a bit of a sort of a backdoor because
the attackers wanted
to have backdoors within the model that
will allow them to do something later
so this was in is an availability attack
the victim here
is uh actually this is not an attack
this is a research on the potential
attack uh the victim here is
a spam based spam filter and the idea
was to pollute the the spam dictionary
means legitimate words
because they knew that this this is an
open source spam
and spam filter they knew that it works
uh that it is based on
keywords of a bayesian network that is
based on detecting keywords that are uh
correlated somehow to spam or to
legitimate uh emails and they created a
large batch of
um of uh uh
of messages that were built from
legitimate words
probably very popular awards uh
and they uh and they classified these as
a spam
and in this case they wanted to make the
the staff filter detect more
legitimate messages as a spam and
indeed on the right side you can see the
the results
having uh one control over one percent
of the of the messages
it was sufficient to make the model
classify eighty percent of the total of
the total legitimate messages as spam
or to detect to classify 95 percent
of the total legitimate messages as
unsure uh both of them
make this model practically uh uh
completely unusable
uh for any uh for any uh usage
so probably like myself at the beginning
you see these examples and you say okay
so um we gave the attacker
significant power we gave him the power
to provide us data
and to tell us also also what is the
meaning of this data to do the labeling
so if we only could get rid of the uh
of giving the attacker the power to
label then
we'll be good right wrong
because another variant of a data
poisoning attack
which is called a clean label attack
actually works when the attacker
is response is giving you the data but
it doesn't have any influence about the
labeling process
and the way it works the the victim here
is an image classification system
and uh what the attacker does he wants
uh
this model to classify these images
of fish you see on the top uh to
classify them
as dogs and the way the attacker
achieves that
uh he takes an image of a dog and now he
adds to this image an
invisible noise invisible for for me
visible for you invisible
for the trusted person that is
responsible for doing the trusted
labeling
so he adds this invisible noise to the
image this invisible noise includes
patterns that somehow are correlated to
the
the top image of the fish uh and what
will happen
next that the trusted labeler
will see a dog will classify this image
as a dog
uh and the model will get this as a dog
and when this model we see uh this image
of a fish it would classify
classify it as a dog and this uh
attack works with a very very high uh uh
success rate
um you see this uh in this graphing that
the blue side you see that the
confidence of the of the model when
seeing images of
fish and classifying them as a dog is
more than 95
uh same thing on the bottom when the
attacker wants to classify images of
dogs
as fish uh this attack is uh extremely
uh
successful and the and the main thing
here
is that uh actually this attack works
even when uh
this service provider actually uh
hire some uh trusted people to make the
uh the labeling uh but still the attack
is
effective so uh
that's we talked about the threats so
let's uh talk a little bit about the
mitigation
uh there are two mitigation approaches
which are
well they are straightforward um the
first one
is let's filter suspicious data we get a
lot of data that we
do the training with uh now we can
filter uh
data that looks suspicious uh it can be
data coming from
maybe the data itself is suspicious
maybe it comes from
suspicious suspicious origins maybe ip
addresses that we suspect for some
reason
uh suspicious user suspicious uh client
maybe we can uh filter out all the data
that comes from
from bots etc
another approach uh another mitigation
approach is to
do the data sampling for the data that
is used for the training
to make it in a in a fault tolerant way
uh
to try to limit the impact of data
points that are arriving from a single
entity
again entity can be a user it can be ip
address uh can be things like that
uh and again if you think about the
booking.com for example
and i think that you cannot you can't do
rating
without having uh i committed a a
transaction
an actual transaction uh and uh
i'm sure that if you go to i don't know
amazon and you want to uh
to give a rating to a particular product
and you know you you push a
3 000 um
five-star rating rates uh
rating rates uh rates within one minute
from
the same ap and the same user then we
probably you will get
blocked so again this is a a
a pretty straightforward not always very
easy to carry out because
we know that uh if we see messages from
different types then
they still can come from the same source
but
it is what it is uh other uh mitigation
approaches
uh less effective uh are
detection approaches uh like uh diff
tracking
uh to keep uh measuring the distance
from uh a new model from the previous
model and assume that
if you see that the new model is very
very different from previous model then
uh prob then you can conclude that you
are under data poisoning attack
and you can use a reliable benchmark to
build the golden data sets that
you know for sure what should be the
result of the model for this data set
and if it makes different uh predictions
then
you can conclude that you are under
attack
uh but but again these are um
when the model comes to uh represent
as changing a dynamic environment then
uh
these detections are are less effective
because
you expect the model to change and you
don't know what is the
the right prediction uh for a golden
data set
and of course there is a security by
obscurity you can
assume that the attackers don't care
about you and you can assume that they
don't know exactly how you work
uh what is the model what is your model
doing what is the type of the model
and uh and even if they want to attack
they will not know exactly how to do
that
uh a good deck with that we are in b
side we know that the security
biosecurity
uh very rarely proves itself as an
effective
mitigations against practically
anything so
let me summarize uh what we got so far
so data presenting a significant threat
on learning mechanisms uh this threat is
critical when you use data from
untrusted sources
another uh important um condition is
that
the the output of the model the
prediction of the model is significant
for someone and i hope for you that
every model that you are working with
has a um is making predictions that are
significant for someone
uh and there is no silver bullet
mitigation there is a collection of uh
uh of uh mitigations that uh can be used
uh to
throttle the attackers um uh
but not necessarily to to stop them at
once
again and this threat is effective in
any place where you have an adversary so
every time you have travel sites or
any site that uses rating definitely
cyber security
uh services um are subject because
you have adversaries and the data uh
next generation
uh anti viruses they actually use data
that not always they
they know where it comes or not always
they uh they can trust it
so the threat is effective in many many
cases
next i will uh try to look at the data
posing threat in the light of um
when it comes to a web security uh what
you see on the top
is a typical web security setup
there is a web application or api
and there is a waft web application
firewall that protects
uh the the application from outsider
threats
aka the internet usually
web application firewalls working by
using a combination
of two security approaches
just a second
uh there is the negative security model
which assumes that everything is good
all the traffic we see is good except
for
things that we know for sure that are
bad usually when we have a matching
pattern matching with some rule
and the other model is a positive
security model where
um where the wealth assumes that
everything is bad
for what you knows for sure is good
usually based on looking at the traffic
for some time and
learning what are building a baseline
profile
for how this traffic uh looks like and
uh block
or alert on a deviation from this
profile
this is practically what we call a
anomaly detection and the difference
each of these models have
a pros and cons um the negative security
model is uh
is more accurate it's false positives
but it requires ongoing update because
it is not effective against
zero days uh but the main
important thing for the sake of our
discussion today
is that uh when i'm when i'm saying that
um uh the positive security model means
that the what
learns a baseline profile from traffic
then you should
now know that we have all the
ingredients of a data poisoning
threat being fulfilled being realized
because data comes from outside and of
course attackers want
uh to make the wife make mistakes so
no doubt that this is a situation is a
is a good
place for data poisoning
uh so again for the sake of this
discussion uh let's assume that the
the web or api traffic profile looks
essentially like that
and you have objects which are the red
items here you can
think of them as parameters uh query
string parameters body parameters you
can also think of
of a cookie as a sort of a parameter
and each parameter each object is
contained
in uh in a container which can be a url
uh url and method maybe a host and url
or global parameter can be different
combinations of a host url
and method and each one of them
has a traffic profile which
is the representation of all the values
that are permissible to go through this
this object through this parameter
and the features of this profile usually
it makes sense to use features that
have some web security meaning uh
because they are somehow correlated to
the way we understand the web attacks
so it makes sense to learn the type of
the parameter
at the multiplicity whether it can come
only once or multiple times within a
single request
optional or mandatory uh if it is a
number
then what are the typical sizes uh if it
is a string then
what is the length of uh uh the
potential length
uh range of this uh of the value
uh and what are the uh the permissible
characters for this uh parameter all of
these are things that
can be correlated with uh different web
attacks and it makes sense to uh to
learn them uh and in order to do
uh uh the learning in a robust manner
um again this is a typical way to
achieve that so the first uh phase
you can do uh cleaning which is the
first mitigation
to filter all the suspicious traffic
that you can think of so
if you have events uh requests that
you were classified by some uh
engine as suspicious or malicious then
you can throw them away
if you have uh requests from ips that
you have some reason to think that they
are suspicious or malicious then
again you can uh everything is good
okay um
if you know that these ips generate a
malicious traffic and again
uh you can also when you have an attack
on a site you can take all the batch off
that
request during this attack and throw
them away because you
you can assume that some of the attack
was missed and
uh and you can in some cases it makes
sense all to throw away data
coming from uh from bots uh
then uh the second uh filtering is to
try to do this um
um this uh uh
threshold learning to learn things only
if you
see them coming not from a single
entity but maybe from a collection of
different ip addresses or
other network domains different user
agents different
geolocation countries different
identified clients
uh and even if you want to prevent
yourself to avoid learning from
from a burst of requests coming at the
same time
then you can uh can require that
you learn things only when you see them
along several days or at least several
hours and again you can
play with the different uh attributes
and put a threshold that
makes sense for your application on
any of these uh now
however this threshold learning is it's
very easy to uh to carry out in
in batch processing uh however
if you want to do base processing you
you need now to to buffer all the data
that you've seen along the
uh the learning period it can be a day
it can be a week it could be months
depending on
what exactly you know how you set the
learning period which in many cases will
be
impractical or at least very expensive
and there is a need to
to find a way to do this in a more uh
memory efficient
uh way uh and and at least in imperva we
try to do everything we can
in a streaming fact in a streaming
friendly fashion uh
in a way that uh we don't have to keep
to to keep
huge buffers that keep all uh all the
data that we can do
uh uh use the more efficient uh
structures
uh in order in order to uh present the
string friendly
uh solution that we developed for um
for a robust learning i will take you to
a completely different
world uh this this is by the way a
completely uh
fictitious uh story uh this is not a
it's not a really research that we
carried out important to say that
in fact i don't have a dog i have a cat
so
i have no uh uh i'm not biased towards
any uh dog food that ran so we want to
uh
to do some kind of a competition between
two uh dog food
brands pedigree and theo so we do
sort of uh of a poll and between
different users
and uh we got uh you seen the uh
yellow text you can see the results and
we got the 12
likes for a theo brand and six likes
for a pedigree brand uh however we are
afraid of uh data poisoning uh
we don't want to give too much uh power
to a single brand or a single uh
uh city uh and then we set the threshold
of at least
three cities and at least their three uh
dog breeds in order to
to accept the fact that the theo is a
tasteful
um is a tasty uh food
uh and when we do this threshold
learning then only pedigree which has
the six slides uh
it passes and the reason for that as you
can see here
that uh for tio there
there is no sun bernard that they gave
him a positive
uh tastiness indication only pomeranian
and german shepherd
uh however for uh pedigree
uh we have a quite balanced uh voting we
have uh
two votes from three cities and uh three
uh
uh dog breeds and then we're good and
the reason for this
uh for this sort of anomaly uh for this
phenomenon
is that uh the
the data that we have you can see that
all the uh new yorkers that have
pomeranian
they really like theo and there are
uh quite many of these because our data
is biased
towards uh new yorkers that have
pomeranians
and this is exactly the thing that we
wanted to avoid we didn't want to
to let this bias in our data
to impact our decision so
how do we do the learning on this data
so uh first we have a pedigree is an
object this object there is a fact
that we want to learn whether pedigree
is tasty or not
and we define the threshold learning
which is on two attributes
city and breed for each one we put a
threshold of three
and for each one of these we actually
maintain
we keep a set of all the cities from
which
we've seen a tasting authentication for
a pedigree
and we have the same structure for theo
and the same
for other facts like whether this dog
food brand is
nutritious and at the beginning we see
no data so we are convinced at
nothing we don't believe at anything we
wait for data to start being convinced
data coming in and now looking at the
data
we see that uh pedigree tastiness now
have
um tastiness indications from three
cities and
from three dog breeds and now we know
that we're good uh we passed the city
threshold
we passed a brief threshold and
therefore we now accept
that pedigree is tasty on the other hand
for teal we have only two cities and
only two
dark breeds and therefore it didn't pass
any of the tests and
we don't believe that the ethio is tasty
so uh what we learned in this
uh thing in this example that we can
learn a boolean facts
whether an object x in this case this is
dog food brand
it has a property why which is whether
or not it is tasty this is a boolean
fact
uh and you probably understood that the
memory consumption
here is proportional to several several
parameters
and to the number of the objects of
course to the properties
or the facts that we want to learn about
every object
and to the number of attributes and also
for the thresholds because we need to uh
to keep all the cities from which we've
seen uh
this testing authentications until until
we pass the test and then we can throw
them away but
uh we can until we pass the test we need
to keep them
but the thing that we wanted to achieve
is that it is independent of the size
of the uh of the data itself uh
so it makes this algorithm this
implementation
of threshold learning uh memory
efficient and can be used in the
streaming uh situations and environments
uh so we have this model of boolean
facts
how this model can be used in when we
want to
to build the web's uh profile or api
profile and to uh
and to enforce it later so actually it
is very
straightforward when we see a data point
a request then we can extract
for a given fact whether fact x was seen
within this uh request we collect all
these
fact accessing and then we try to learn
uh whether uh this fact x
passes all the threshold tests that we
that we have
and if it passes all the thresholds then
uh we can define it as allowed
and it can be now part of the profile
if it is not allowed meaning that at
least
there was one threshold it hadn't passed
then uh
we have a different flag within the
profile which is fact x
prohibited uh so
think of uh of a web profile as a
collection of
fact x allowed in fact x prohibited for
different
uh facts uh during the inference we
when when you see and you request
you take uh you extract all the fact x
seen
from this request and and now you do you
enforce
by looking at fact x there is in this
request
that is corresponding to fact x
prohibited
and when you have a match then you have
a contradiction to the profile
and you can now declare a violation uh
so this is how the enforcement can work
and it is pretty straightforward
so the boolean facts approach uh works
well with
uh with the web or api profiles
uh but uh is this enough meaning
we can do boolean facts but what can you
express with boolean facts
so let's start with the object and
containers
we talked about url hosts and parameters
cookies
so in fact these are uh goes along
pretty
easily with boolean facts because um if
you want to learn that the
particular query string parameter x
uh is uh belongs to urly
with uh method get or post or or
or that uh then the nature of this piece
of information is boolean
uh so this is pretty uh straightforward
and it is the same
if uh which urls you have and which
cookies belong to url and which methods
are available for
a particular url it it goes
fairly easily uh however
you want to answer also questions like
what about things like
data types ranges character sets etc
uh so if we look now on
the type of a parameter then you you
need to do sort of um in in data science
it is called one hot encoding
and you divide uh for each of the uh of
the categories of the parameter for uh
parameter types
and numeric string a none if it is
representing a non-existent value or
bullion
so you have an num type allowed flag
and a non-num type allowed flag they are
different
um and you have also corresponding uh
the actually the
the opposite one and so i either have a
num type allows for this parameter in
the profile or
a num type prohibited in the profile
uh and you uh you have one from each uh
from each of these pairs so how you use
them
and suppose you want to have in the
profile to express the facts a
particular parameter is a string
and then you learn that a string type is
allowed for values for this profile
uh but you know you don't learn uh you
fail to learn that
num numeric type is allowed and
therefore you have that numeric type is
prohibited
and if you only see strings then you you
cannot
learn that non-str values are allowed
so you will learn that non-str types are
prohibited
and then when we see x equal 23
then it is prohibited and we have a
violation
if you have uh if the type is a mail
address and you have um
a regular expression that represents
mail address then again
i i believe that from the first example
you understand that the more important
uh flags are not the green ones but the
red ones
so you will if you only see email
addresses then
you have in the profile a non-male
regular expression
prohibited even if you've seen one or
two times
things that are not compatible with the
regular expression they probably didn't
pass the thresholds and
and then when you see now abc for
example in this value of this parameter
which have non-male regular expression
then it contradicts
uh this non-male regular expression
prohibited
flag and again you have a violation
whether mandatory or optional the
parameter is mandatory or optional
so it can be addressed with a missing
prohibited or missing
allowed flags when you want to
[Music]
express the fact that a parameter can or
cannot have
a no value then do the same with the
non-type allowed or
not and non-non-type allowed allowed or
prohibited
when you want to express the fact that
multiplicity is allowed for a parameter
then again you can do it in in the same
way you use
multiple occurrences allowed or
prohibited
when you want to handle a character set
then again
you can build flags that are
corresponding with a set with character
sets like a base s64
or for particular characters for example
if you uh
you want to say that um to express the
fact that
alpha numeric is okay and the colon and
semicolon are okay but any other special
character is forbidden uh
then you will have str type allow the
alphanumeric type allowed
but special characters prohibited for
the different special characters
except for the ones that uh that we've
seen
so um when you want to learn
uh numeric features and then you need to
do
uh more sort of a trick to the
discretization of
the of the range uh into uh several
uh ranges so uh if you're uh
in the learning you you want to learn
that to include in the profile the fact
that
the parameter length is between 34 and
it's 345 characters
then you have to define in advance
threshold like 50 and 500 and
to learn uh boolean flags boolean facts
like
uh whether the parameter value can be
greater than
500 or greater than 50 and greater than
or lower than 10 and uh that can help
you to uh to
express this thing uh but
i i i don't get deep into the details so
however it is done but i want to
convince you that
it can be done so we talked about uh
uh about a profile uh
about the features of a profile let me
uh try to explain
uh how the boolean framework the boolean
effects framework can be used for more
complicated models like decision trees
on the right side you see a very simple
decision tree and this is one of the
one of the machine learning models that
are more popular
and you have their two features whether
a particular animal breathes air
and whether an animal lay eggs and each
of them is the bullion
and when you see an animal then the
decision tree says that you go yes no
breathe air
lay x and you uh in the leaves you have
the the classes the different decisions
and the potential decision and this is a
very simple
uh model uh and usually it is used in uh
something it's called an ensemble when
you have a collection of models
uh that are uh work together one
type of ensemble is ensemble is begging
when you build many models independently
and then
you do some kind of a voting or
averaging of the the prediction of the
models
another approach is uh called boosting
when you actually you you don't build
the different models independently but
you
uh you build the models in a way that
corrects
the uh the mistakes of
the previous of the previous model and
then you
you have a collection of models that
together provide a a
good result so how can we use the
boolean framework in this
situation uh let me first explain uh
what you see here in this decision
stream
uh so if we look at uh
at this node at battle with a smaller
equal 1.65
then 48 samples from the training data
reached this uh this node uh
47 of them had the green class
and one had the purple class uh
and the decision if we should spawn the
the one that has the uh the most
examples which is uh uh the the green
class
versicolor uh so for the for building
the tree uh the boolean framework cannot
cannot help you but
there are ways to build a trees in in a
streaming
a manner but
the the boolean framework can help you
to
do validation of the tree and the way to
do that is
you can add the sub leaves to each of
the leaves
uh you can also add a sublease to
to the notes and all these uh fab leaves
are actually
um if we have here in
in the most left
leaf we had only uh the green cloth
then we'll have a sub leaf for the green
class if we have a nodes that have
uh two classes it will have two sublimes
representing
uh both of them and now we go
and we use the threshold learning and
the boolean facts to
validate uh these sub leads
[Music]
so you can see here uh for example for a
decent note with the 47 and one uh
you have 47 data points uh
that were had the green class so
probably
let's assume that they passed all the
thresholds however you had only one
data point for uh for the purple class
so
probably didn't pass the threshold so
you learn
only nodes and branches
and leaves that are a pass all these
deaths and now the tree that you're
getting
is actually a subtree of the original
tree
uh there is a some caveat here that
before beforehand we only had one
decision per sample
now we have situations exactly for
example
uh if we reach this point uh
then we have nothing that is validated
so there is no decision for the model
and if we reach this point for example
the tree was
only truncated at this area at this
level and this point has two decisions
so we need to handle
this situation but there are many ways
to do that
uh so this is a way for uh to do the
validation of
the trip uh what can we do when it comes
to ensembles
so when it comes to bagging actually
this is straightforward when we have the
models that are set we can now validate
the trees and
in fact it is even easier because the
problem that we had of no decision or
multiple decisions
uh when you do an averaging or voting
then you can say okay when i have no
decision then
i have no vote when i have two decisions
the
permissible decisions then i give two
votes one for the first class and the
second for the second class
uh so it actually may make sense
uh for uh boosting uh and samples it is
less straightforward to use because when
i say
three validation this is not exactly
validation uh it is beyond that it is uh
uh also actually changing the the tree
and since we have a path
of optimizations here then if you change
the tree then you need to make sure that
um that you will not impact the rest of
uh
of the chain so it might be useful also
for this area but uh
i uh it is probably uh more complicated
to uh to obtain that uh this is a
good um direction for a researcher
i believe so uh let's sum up
um later poisoning is a significant
threat or learning mechanism
uh it is uh it is there whenever you
do something meaningful based on data
from untrusted
sources with or without a trusted
labeling and threshold-based learning
may provide an adequate
robust learning solution uh the boolean
facts framework that i presented
provides a streaming friendly
implementation for threshold-based
learning
and many features of uh when you build a
profile
can be expressed with boolean facts even
if it
seems that a limited model it is not
that limited
uh it can be uh it can work also for
uh for numeric uh and for uh a
categorized uh
features and a traditional learning of
trees and forests is partially possible
with boolean in fact i showed you how
you can uh
you cannot build a tree uh in this
manner but you can do validation of the
tree
to make sure that your tree is a full
tournament
and that's it thank you for listening
and now we have a couple of minutes for
questions
um
i can't hear anyone
so
um
you
so
dropping out um video issues so i'm
gonna go ahead and end this broadcast
now
um thank you for coming thank you for
presenting um if
you can make sure to stick around in the
track one
uh breakout session in discord to look
for questions from our attendees
but beyond that um
we do have a question from ryan coming
in which is interesting information
more of a statement again again um so
please go ahead and jump into the
discord room and i'll go ahead and close
this session out
okay so i'm in a track one breakout
yes okay awesome
hi there i'm melissa miller and i'm a
hacker
i'm also a security researcher and an
advocate for hacking is not a crime
and i'd like to share with you what
being a hacker means to me
because you see since i was a
young young child i've always been a
hacker
i was the kid that liked to take my toys
apart
to figure out how they worked and to see
if i could make them work better
when i turned 12 years old i got a job i
saved up enough money and i bought
myself
my own computer and on that computer
i wiped it clean started from scratch
figured out how to build it from the
ground up
learned programming so that i could
write my own software to run on my
computer
i learned modem communications and
serial communications
so that i could figure out how these
online services that i like to use
were working and so when i got into my
career
i took a lot of different twists and
turns
i started off as a penetration tester i
moved into consulting i worked at high
executive levels
building massive application security
programs across
large enterprise organizations
i work for product companies and
resellers
but through it all the one thing that
stuck with me was this identity
of being a hacker now we hear the word
hacker thrown about in the media and
it's usually connected with some type of
criminal activity
but being a hacker does not mean being a
criminal
being a hacker is all about this innate
curiosity this passion to understand how
things work
and to see how we can make them work
differently better create
new things i'm reminded of a quote from
a keynote given by
jason street one of my colleagues in
which he said
hackers are inventors and creators
not criminals and freaks and that's the
reality
hackers are people who want to make
technology better we want to make it do
cool new things we want to understand
how it works
so that we can innovate we can make
things better
and we can make our lives all the more
exciting
through technology so i hope you'll join
with me
and with hacking is not a crime to
spread the message
that hacking and being a hacker
is not a crime we're not criminals
we're artisan inventors thank you so
[Music]
much
you