good afternoon b-side san antonio i hope
you guys are having a great
event today i am presenting mr felipe
perez and he is going to do a walk
through
of identifying security holes during the
development process
as well as do practical demonstration of
how a developer can use
sas tool for static analysis and code
vulnerability
execution in source code byte code and
binary and identifying security holes
during the development process
uh he will be analyzing many languages
such as java python ruby going so on and
so forth and searching for
key link leaks and security flaws in all
files of your project
as well as your get hit story he's a
very busy principal security engineer
and security researcher at sup
innovation global researcher manage
manager at
hacker security he's a staff at defcon
group
in sao paulo brazil he's talked in
security events all over the world
and he is the founder and instructor of
the course malware analysis
fundamentals hacker set company online
course so be sure to check that out
also remember to hop on discord right
after to talk with our sponsors
and community organizations if you have
any questions for felipe
please go to track one in the weeds
breakout room and felipe also wants to
say hello to all of you guys so
have a great event
hi thank you thank you for these
presentations thank you so much
and uh my name is felipe pierce again
and i'm talking from brazil now here
from my office by the way my office is
in my balcony as you can see
behind me you know he is at night here
in brazil at
you know it's six at six
pm not six pm yeah six pm sorry
and um yes let's talk about during this
in the end of this event about the
secure development right so
here my home page it's very simple
homepage just to
just to see some information about me
you know in the um
hear my presentations again i am yeah
that doesn't matter
that who am i but here the most
important is i'm advocate of the
hacks not a crime uh project i think you
heard about that during this event and
i'm a part of the
devcon groups here in south all the
staff teams you know you know i'm
supported fcom groups they're the right
team village
too right so here you can see some open
source project
that i have here in supernovation my
company here in brazil
and uh here's another presentations that
i have
been doing the during this year in the
last year
and we have here in english in spanish
in portuguese or everyone
we have here some you know talks and
here we have some articles
that i wrote in the fantastic magazine
hackney and
you know a forensic magazine in other
places
right so today we're going to talk about
the the very interesting talk that i
like by the way
and about the secure development because
this is a very interesting
important process when you build
something right of course related to a
software
or when you have some code because in
the end of the day
we have you produce some code you you
know you build some code
and you can produce it and you can
compile this right it turn this up you
know
turning this this code that has a binary
or you know you can create a
uh some apps using in a mobile
environment or you can use in a web
application but
the first you need to create this code
right and um
here it's important to understand the
difference between you know where
what is fast and dust right so just a
few explanations about that you know i
i pick up this information from the sign
off site
it's um i think it's a company
responsible to produce some sas or last
product i don't know exactly
but just a reference to you to see
because i think it's important to
explain the difference between you know
and uh here the difference sustains uh a
white block security test
it's related when you analyze the
applications
before or not before uh actually as
before before
to produce this right so actually the
tester
has access to the underlying framework
design and implementation
the application here is important the
application is tested from the
inside out right so uh you don't publish
this applications yet right so
on the other hand in the black box
security testing in this case is a dust
right so the application is tested from
the outside
right so you need to publish the url and
after that you can execute the test
application inside by name application
security test just to understand the
difference between right
so another uh difference is related to a
requires required
search code sas doesn't require a
deployed application you know
on the other hand on that solutions
requires a running application which
means
thus doesn't require the search code or
binary
analyzes by executing the application it
means you need to publish the
applications you have the url
of course and after that you can execute
this test in this case
dust right in this case sast
is different you you're not your
analysis
is uh if in the search code right
so here another interesting difference
right so when you talk about assessed
find these vulnerabilities early in the
stlc
you know it's a software development
life cycle this economy right
so this can can be executed as soon as
cold
is teammate feature completely right
but on the other hand in this case it's
finds lunar reads
toward the end of the sdlc
you know you have that this life cycle
when you talk about the
the software software development right
so vulnerabilities can be discovered
after development cycle is completed
right
so another difference less expensive to
fix vulnerability
in fast mode right since this
variabilities are
found early in the sdlc it's easier and
faster to remediate them right because
you remember you don't you you don't
publish
yet you know the applications right
it's more expensive to fix
vulnerabilities in this case in the desk
why it's very simple because since
vulnerabilities are founded toward the
end of the sd lc
it means after you publish your
application right you need to remediate
this
it's very complicated because if you you
see the attacker or you know
find some vulnerabilities the the fix
needs to be
emergency release you need to create
some release
emergency right so another point is
can is can't discovery run time and
environment related to issues
it means since the tool is kind of
statistical
it can't cover runtime vulnerability
because
you analyze the code but in this case
you have a published
you know you already published the um
applications right so and the end of
this explanation
by the way typically supports all kind
of softwares
example including web applications as i
mentioned
web servers and think lines client and
think
clients right and the dust wave
typically scans
only apps like web applications and web
services right so
that is not usable for other types of
software this is just a simple
definitions right guys so
another point is here is you understand
about this explanation right
sas is a statistical application
security testing
and today i will explain more about the
open source
of the open source project right about
the orosec
is currently a sas project that you can
execute in your code right
or in your environment you're you know
and binary something like that
again this is the last two as i
mentioned right it's dynamic application
to keep the test
it's too recommended to find the
vulnerabilities externally
visible right as i mentioned okay and
here we have another interesting
yest interactive application security
test you can
mix at both of them right so east is the
combination of the statistic and dynamic
past
modules right and it has better results
why because of course it's better
because you can test both of them
before and after the applications
uh to be published right and here
is the interesting point yesterday has
an option to perform it together with a
security analyst
you need to have in this ca usually this
guy
then it's called by application security
guy right
because this guy can be using this
um type of the you know analysis to run
it is the best type to test in terms of
the false positive rate
due to the human interactions right
because of these
you can reduce the false positive right
but in my opinion in philippi opinion i
think it's better you
if you have if you need to choose for
example a false positive or false
negative
in my perspective from my perspective
it's better when you have false
positives because
you need to analyze it and you can see
what this
what happened in your environment right
but when you have the false negative
you have a problem because something
wrong
it's happening in your environment you
know and you you you don't
see during the scanning or another
platform that you have right so okay
i've explained the difference between
the sas
and dust and us just to understand so
now i would like to explain more about
the
auros sec right so the name is called
aurus sec you can
write this in in google for example and
you can see
more information about that right so
uh our sec is on open source tools again
you can click here using the github or
here or sec.ko
or take you take a look there's some
videos about me
okay nice let's return here so you can
click here to see the documentations
and take a look at this in portuguese
and english right
so identity five vulnerabilities simple
and fast
right so again our second is an open
source
tools so because of this i'm present
this for you because
i really appreciate if you can do some
you know pull requests in this
tools because this uh project
uh it was created to
the security inside of the security team
from zoop but
to give this project to the community
right so this is a very important your
help for me
and not for me for this project actually
right so
our section open source 2 that performs
a statistical code analysis
here it's some keys to identify security
flows during the development
process right so here's some tools some
languages
and tools there that um autosec analyze
like you know chart
java kotlin pattern and like another
different
terraform your kubernetes right so okay
here is here is the web page okay i can
click here
the documentations and here i have some
interesting information so some simple
overview
about this project right so again here
some interesting thing that i like it's
open source project
and here another point here check out
all the support
language and availables tools here it's
very interesting guys because
you can see here all those languages and
tools supported by aurosec you can see
here the python
and take a look at this here is the
engines
responsible to to find some
vulnerabilities inside the
environment if you if you click here
instant grab for example take a look
what happened here
it's very simple the explanation about
how the same graph
works it means you have this um
another project inside the or sex
exactly it's not a framework but almost
a framework right because you have here
many different engines as you can see
here like a golang for example in golang
you have a gosak and sangrat
it's two different engines right and uh
but here is the difference take a look
at that so you have here you
are sec java it's another engine but
not but it's open source you know it's
open source
engine but this engine it's uh created
by
the our sec team so take a look at this
you can see
different engines inside the same
project you know you can see
there for example like a rsec
kotlin same grab and or sec java
different
engines towards right so from my
perspective it's very interesting
because
if for example stingrap don't detect the
vulnerability you can
maybe to be detected by or sec java it's
very
very cool right so okay let's return
here the
overview where can you use the rsac
locally right so our sec has an
intuitive cli
made for developer where it's possible
to perform a loophole analysis
this is the first idea when we created
an rsec
okay and below you can see another
difference
uh locals where you can use
like a c c i c d pipeline an id
and e a actually um
extension here it's the key both of
these functions
it was creates it was suggested by the
community right so because of this
it's very important your pull request
right so
you can use in the cicd pipelining and
you can use it uh
in by vs code for for example right so
here below you can some pictures but but
i will explain in the
in live here and take a look at this
orsac
analysis types it's very important
things right so the other side
performance three types of analysis
right the first is assessed
as i mentioned in the beginning because
of this explained difference between
soft and dust
and he asked right and here is another
interesting key
uh our sec analyze and can collect the
leaks
right so the leaks checks the source
code for a possible leaks
of credentials private keys or harded
coded password
you know for for example if you are a
developer or if you know
any development developer and usually
sometimes the developer
put or forgot or you know um
[Music]
takes the uh some private keys inside
the code
or some had coded password inside
the code in a guitar platform for
example uh
if you are a fantastic now you know and
you are hearing me now probably
when you realize that when you perform
some uh recognization steps
in a pentagon penetration test you
usually when you execute this
step you like to use to see
the github if you can find some you know
credentials of this some target that you
are doing the fantastic right
so it's a first step that we're going to
recognize in this
recognization steps right and the leaks
it's very interesting because if the
developer forgot some keys inside like
you know aws key or azure key
or gcp or ever you can discover this
in this engine right using this some
motorcycle leaks
engines actually another point is
independence audits right so you analyze
a project's dependence to check whenever
it's
ina take a look at this third
part libraries because you know when you
create
when you produce something you know when
you create some apps sometimes you need
to import
another different library right so it's
very
important if you it should have
important actually
if you have some uh tools to execute
some analysis in your code right if you
see
if this library it was vulnerable or not
right so here's the important things
okay
so i think you understand now about what
is our sex so now i made this
overview about this is that i will be
installing
i will be starting now the or sec you
can install it
in different ways right so here the
requirements i need to have the docker
and it installed in my machine i always
put this in my linux
platform here in my linux machine right
so here i have the
my my cli right so
by the way i have here my this is my
project
actually let me delete this
because you need to use it after okay so
take a look this i have here our second
what i have here inside of this project
by the way i have here
my some codes vulnerable right so go and
go laying java
and cosplay node and ph php
okay felipe i would like to do this demo
after your presentation
no worries you can see here these
informations in my github here
not here it's here okay philip
86 or
dash or other sec dash damn sorry
and here all those codes vulnerable
right so go lane
slash api and here we have different
um codes vulnerable right so here it's
my github if you'd like to see something
you have many repositories and
informations about me
too right so uh here it's a very
interesting if you
remember here it's like it helped from
this project right you can afford the
project you can
you know uh suggest some improvements
right so it's here
and here if you'd like to make another
different task
you have here one folder called
example as you can see here if you click
here you can
find many others example of the
vulnerable
code right so just suggest you if you'd
like to
works right if you can practice your in
this way
okay let me install their site here let
me return the documentations here
not here let me close here it's okay
installations process okay twist our sex
cli or macos in linux
you can execute this okay i will cop
this as you can see
copy and i pass here let me
pass selection here and as you can see
it's very simple
some curl with some you know flags here
in the url url to install to call the
script
and call the bash and request the last
latest version right so i click enter
and after that i will download the rsac
in my environment
and of course this is my user don't have
some privilege to access
i think it's more safe right
okay oh something wrong because i always
forgot my password i don't know if you
forgot your password but i always forgot
my password okay
our sec was downloaded and take a look
at this very cool
move it to local bean
it's easier to manipulate the
information okay or a sec
oops
or sack i don't know the comments
dash help yes and click enter take a
look this this is a cli
simple cli you can use in two ways right
right so the autosac
using the flags and other stack using a
comma right so
here is available comments for now just
for now because we can improve that
right of course generate
generate of core uh or cycle
configurations
help i use it now here
have about the any comment right and
start
means start there are sex cli inversion
actual actual version install of the
rsac so i can execute this
autosack just confirm the version
the version okay
make sure it's the verse the verse two
dot one dot zero
okay so i see here that i can use the
start here to start our sex cli
okay perfect so that music with this
or sec start start what
i don't know let me again
help take a look this many different
flags here so i
this is the use usage
usage and here you can use the eight
examples right
so uh take a look this is starter
sec analysis in the current path it
means if
i don't put any uh flags
they are psychic view as it could in the
exactly
currently currently uh current path
right so it means in this case in this
path
right in this folder or project whatever
right
so okay another example of course we
have many examples
but i just talked about something some
uh flags
in this case uh the a right so it's at
authorization strings the authorization
talk from the rsac
api for example after you perform your
scan in your code you can send all these
codes or none though this codes
or these uh all those one arrays founded
in your code to send to their site
manager because we have a manager
to manage this whenever it's just not a
code right the vulnerabilities
found right so it's very important to
just to clarify
okay another point is related to this
dash o in this case it's output format
right output that format string the
format for the output to be sewn
shown options were in the text in s t
dot
json and take a look at this the sonar
cube
you know maybe you are you are making a
question to you so philippe i like to
use this on my cube in my environment
i work with typesec you know i'm i am a
psych guy and uh my company we
we use that we use um solar cube
but sonar cube looks in your quality of
your software
and of course they have some you know
a security settings in the configuration
some settings in the in the in this one
archival you know exactly
how deeply is the the place called
deciding this configuration
but or sec it was created to
to the community right for a community
but
for a security team
thought uh it was uh thought
in security great way right so it's very
important
to clarify because it's um you know you
can
use both of them the the tools the sonar
cube to see the quality
in our site to see the security
right and another interesting uh flag
here it's
it's here dash e
right because it's in this case written
award the returning airport is the
option to check
if you can return exit to one
it means for example if i would like to
put this in my pipeline for example to
see that that's this life cycle do you
remember that explaining that this
that's dlc
okay i can put this in my youtube
reaction for example
if i receive this as if one for example
i if
found some vulnerability you know it's
uh
i can set for example here take a look
the explanation if i found
vulnerabilities i can break
you know i can break my uh pipeline
because
my code was vulnerable right so i just
set the
uh dash e equal true
because if is true in this case
it means the code it was vulnerable
right so it's like if i put here false
in this case it is zero in this case the
pipeline can go on right so that's very
important
okay perfect you you explain
i think i explained something so take a
look at this i have
uh four three four no five five folders
here
and i use include so now the rsac start
and i can i just click enter here take a
look this the folder selector
is it's my my folder here
and or sac dash demo proceed
yes oh no and yes if i pulled for
example
uh dash p i need to set the the real
path
right for example if i would like to
scan
to perform this scanning another path i
just put dash
p equal and i need to select the path
right so i can uh
execute this way right so i just click
enter and
now when we started the rsac
is coming in my project in this case
this is the name of this project right
so guys if you have any questions you
can send in its channel i think
if i am correctly and uh i'm totally
available
to talk during this scanning because it
but it's fast it's very fast here as you
can see
so if you see here the oroseki created
some dock or sec uh file just to
uh during this study right and after
that the
the file is delete deleted
um okay our second and the analysis with
is that
and why because we found some
vulnerabilities right with the
following results uh we starting this
time
right and finishing this time so i think
it's uh
30 minutes 30 i think 30 minutes right
so
let's see the logs very important so you
can see here the language
it's java and here's the in here the
severity
right so but philippia what
what is the the savage that you have
inside of the other side here
nice question you can see here for
example in a
glossary you can see here the
explanation of it means the security
brexit in the
project in and can cause some damage yes
of course we
are in the security event of course if
you found some whoever it's
it's it's maybe call can cause some
damage right into the system or the
organization
or sec can identify six types of the
security brush it's very interesting
it's almost the same it's it's a similar
it's very similar when you
think about the the my tree not nitrogen
and cve for example
if you are uh if you would like to
reduce some cveig
it's usually using the same uh almost
the same
meaning right so we have the first the
critical high medium
low info it means it's a warning no you
know you don't
it's not classified by low or you know
medium it's just an info warning
and maybe you won't know what what that
means no no it's a zero they know it's
not a
zero day of course but probably the
aging don't
you know identify what it is exactly
it's not an info
it's not uh it's not clear it's not a ah
you know a good code but it's
maybe you know it's i know it's not a
zero day
okay just to clarify that right so
that's really returning here in this
case it's high
take a look that this is for my
my site it's very interesting so the
line two column seven
in the code security tools or sec
engine in this case for java confidency
it's
low and here guys you can see the real
file right in this case take a look this
is the
the main project right when i execute
this
scanning or sec dash demo but
here you can find this is the
our sec real is performance this is
cunning all those fires to try and find
some
honorable code inside these project
and he found the app
doc java right code vulnerable import
java
dot until doc randall right why because
in details it's insecure
randall number generate but okay i would
like to see more information about this
vulnerability right so the apps use
any secure random number generate for
more information check out
the cve 30 uh
330 okay and you can click here
if you'd like to see more information
about that because you can
close here okay you can see this
information is not definition by
philippe peters or supernovations or
whatever
it's definitions it's based on the c w
e common weakness enumerations right so
as you can see here the
weakness ide and take a look this it's a
good good good
library to learn not library i don't
know it's the correct name but you know
it's
not library it's a good resource to
learn
more about the security right because
you can hear the parent off
of another vulnerabilities like a
interface entropy for example
and you can clock click here and you can
read more about that
right so you can improve your
knowledgement in security stuffs
right it's very important but these
vulnerability is related at my code
right as we see here in my cli right so
all those explanations here the type is
vulnerability
and here the reference hash it means
we have the reference of this
vunderability
right so it's pretty cool uh
here another it's javascript it's the
same case it's high or sec java
and here below another another language
it's go in this case
right the severity is median line is 23
column seven and take a look at the
security tool is different in this case
it's a gold stack do you remember
goldsack
it's another interesting open source
project to um using that we have inside
the rsac right so
as you can see here the correct file
you to go inside of this path
right and as you can see here the name
is
that it takes off this uh vulnerable
code
is use of weak cryptography
primitive right and uh
in the end of this log take a look this
in these analysis
and a total of the five possible
vulnerabilities were found
and we classify it then it right so
it's a five and you execute this
inside your environment okay but let's
suppose that you
works with um um
[Music]
uh results to the code yes code right
like me
here and here as you can see we have our
sac dash demo it's the same folder right
so i have here
all those codes write and go lang
and java and node.js and php so i can
basically write
here and i have here the extension to
downloading side of my vs code right so
here it's very very useful to use
because you just to click here and
start analysis as you can see here hold
on our sec started to announce in your
code as you can see here
let me close here okay and if you see
here our sex
oops security analysis running it's
running during our talk
our conversation which means it's
running some uh
analysis during these conversations okay
so first of all is a good mystery in the
cli so now i'm excluding the orsak in a
vs code
so you can use in both of them too to
see the
environment so okay let's see here the
first folder java
and take a look this if i just put in my
mouse
above this you can see the explanation
again
you know as you can see here but you can
click here you take a look at this
the real cold guy is the real code here
here is the code vulnerable if i put my
my
just in my mouse here you can see the
insecure
randall number generator right
again here you can see the explanation
the apps uses an insecure
random number generator for more
information
oops check out the cve 330 again
here you can find the information let's
see here another
here injection another here's the
process right so
let me put here using a shell
interpreter when executing eos comments
arbitrary eos common injections gonna
beat where
one more likely when a shell is exponent
rather than a new process so here you
can
found you can find here
the explanation about this um
this vulnerability right so again guys
you can see difference many different
explanations about this one update so
you can imagine if you are a developer
you produce your code you have your code
by the way i have some similar
presentations in my
in there not my zoop channel in this
youtube channel but in portuguese
presentation i probably i will produ are
you
you know i you do a demo similar when i
create my
web page this web page here and i create
this
this web page using you know uh awesome
statistics page i create this and after
that i execute this
uh or sec to analyze to as a good
summary as if
this web page it was vulnerable or not
so i can maybe in the future
to present this to yourself right uh to
to you to understand more about this
in the real quote because here it's just
a a few
uh you know lines about the code it's
not a
completely code written many like here
here it's another
uh interesting because if you remember
here it's uh
in this case it's a a medium because
it's you know
as i mentioned it's a um
a weak clear cryptographic primary
primitive and here you can see
the total code right but it's a small
code actually
okay i explain more about the you know
the cli the vs code
but let's see here another interesting
thing let's suppose
that you have some uh
pipeline is a good in your environment
take a look this we have here the github
actions and as you can see here it's i
don't have any
job as i put in here and or ever right
so
i hit but i hear i have here my code
right
in my environment and i can let's
suppose that i can publish this
in the github but i can publish this
of course not vulnerable perfect okay so
let's return here to the documentations
where is the documentation it's here
okay in a cli extension
id that i explained to you right so
using the
ivs code but here if you see in the cli
installation here
other way is to execute this in uh
via image docker right to run this
command
and another point is installing
installation via pipeline
this type of this installation assures
that a safe
in the deliver of your project in
production right so here this is
important
since your sec is added to your pipeline
so let's suppose that i have i have here
my pipeline and it
i you as i could they are setting my
code before
to put this in production right so we
tested
we tested uh our second github reactions
aws code built in another circle ci
and jenks and azure dev spotlight in
github ci city right so
ball and all and all those uh pipeline
you have here the
uh command as you can see here so but
let me turn here let me close this this
and this this another example here in
this okay
so let me turn here we if what i need to
uh to try as i put something inside the
github box let me click here i need to
set this workflow
i need to have this workflow actually
inside of my environment right i have
here there are sec
demo slash dot github i need to create
this workflow but
i have i need to have the main file
called dot eml right not main but
i can put whatever name i want right and
i just put
here main in this case i can put you
know besides or you know
uh horosek or whatever
and here is the standard information
that i need to put here
okay let me turn here not here github
actions
and okay if i need to create something
i have here the github and workflow so
what i need to create here
the or sec not our second can put
whatever name
again eml right
and i have here in the documentations
this command let me copy here
i will copy and i will pass here so i
will
call this workflow the names uh security
pipeline
this job actually and this this job will
execute this
ram this command actually the crow
as you can see here the same co the same
command that i
execute in the beginning right
to download our sec after that the
the command call the or sec start write
to as i could to start our sec
dash p to set the path right in this
case
either the root path downward path but
the the path that
this environment have has right
and dash e in this case is true do you
remember that i explained it to you
when we have true in this case why we
receive the award exit one in this case
i will break my pipeline right so
i just save here this or prosec
doc eml here and i need to
write what what what i need to do
i need to let me see
it works here okay
it works because i'm using ssh
access okay so github add
a new for a new file right so i will
commit
this information because i have here
this new file in my environment i need
to commit this
remotely to github right or second demo
one file change it right so in this case
exactly for that i
have been created right so i need to
push
this informations to original master
okay okay so let me click here i need to
put my password and
let's see okay heads up
it was i think it works let me return
here
in my github actions i will click here
you take a look what happened
wow we have a security pipeline works
here for us
okay security demo the name of this flow
the workflow right if i click here
i can see my job right so i'm as i put
in this
uh
actions or using this you know the
similar my pipeline right
so let me click here and take a look at
this i will set up the job
here you know setting the talk and the
permissions and okay
using the checkout code run something to
understand the environment
and what take a look what happened here
let me see here what happened
in the end of this scanning as i
mentioned to you
i think it's small okay
take a look at this process completed
with exit
called one in this case my code is
vulnerable as you can see here and by
the way i receive hearing my phone
the message from github right because i
have a problem in my code
and take a look this in this case i have
seven
possible vulnerabilities the same uh
scanning executed in my cli
and let's see here this information take
a look at this
run the scan it means as i could the
curl
right base cutting after that
execute this or sec start start dash
p and dash e
through if my code is vulnerable
my pipeline it was
break broke right so that's very cool
because you can put or sack in your
pipeline
right so okay felipe as i could in the
three ways
and a cli and vs code and
and using a github actions but you have
a another one
you have here the web applications it
means we have a manager
to manage all these vulnerabilities
right so
and take a look it's very simple to
execute this are you using
install with a docker compose this is
the requirements in your environment
docker compose stocker
and linux it's very very simple just to
get copy here get cloning
in the or sec environment right so let
me hit turn here
now you pass here git cloning
okay okay quit cloning
and uh url basically this is our site
platform
from supernov superit it's a it's a
negative club okay i will execute this
and i will download
this this rsac platform cd or sec
dash platform enter
and after that just make install very
very difficult and after that boom
the service are all those services and
dockers
it will be works right it's very simple
if you return it here in the
in the documentation it's very simple
enter the folder
you have clone it as i made
run the command making style in order to
have all
web applications because you need to
have some
dockers in your environment right so you
use it with is
in your environment of course i have
it's uh already exists because i
i have some i have doing i've been doing
this presentations in other events
and after that access our sex services
just copy
here it's a just a for demo
yeah so you can using
in your environment
as you prefer right so we have here our
sec web page
you you can go there and you can copy
this
please if you using your environment
change the password please it's very
important to change this the full
password
you know if you don't change
it's a misconfiguration right so okay
so okay let me go to this workspace
let me delete this because i present
this
yesterday i think something happened
expected i have try again but it works
let me click
here enter and okay
so when you uh connect in this in your
sec
this is the the real uh web page let me
connect again here
just to show you when you
copy here nice
i closed here copy them
look how you this the local page
i will copy here
and i will pass here okay
and now you cop this
and i will pass here and i will sing it
and here
this is the webpage when i was when i
will be
logged right so i need to add the
workspace
i can call it from this site for example
and i will add this workspace
sorry now you add here
besides i can put some description but
i don't need to put now i need to click
here and take a look at this
i need to i can use the token to
identify add
token the
besides and after that i just click in
save
and i can copy this okay
and after that i can just as i could
this
uh again so i can return here
and go towards seki demo
and i can click here or seki
start and here i can set do you
remember dash a equals
and i passed here the
okay
i just need to pass here
and after that all those vulnerabilities
we will be
send sent to this manager as you can see
here
okay and take a look at this this is a
good
point because if you have a good team
with many developers
you can see for example during the week
during the day
or during a month for example uh
what kind of language it has more
vulnerable codes for example for it is
for example javascript
uh the manager can generate some can
suggest some training with
a secure development to a job for
example right
and it's very interesting let me click
here in workspace
in this case not here it's here
workspace
and as you can see one developer it's me
one repository
and here we can find all vulnerabilities
hi
the language javascript javascript
and here you can find other informations
like you know javascript high low
and i need to do some improvements in my
front change as you can see here
right and if you click here in
vulnerabilities um
not here here actually we have some
problem here in mind
probably my environment it was uh
with some problems some air horse
because as you can see here i used
it's another database in other
presentations but it means you know
it's very simple all those
vulnerabilities this one are abilities
it was it is some this
bits are sent are sent to this
uh space and after that you can
manage it in this case severity you can
see the severity
and you can see here all the what is the
stats for example if you uh
pass if you send your team and you your
team
uh made the improvement of this code you
can put the correct it
right so if he is a false positive you
can click here
and after that if you risk accept you
and usually when you have here the
vulnerabilities this is
the correct stats right so
here i finish my presentation guys again
thank you so much um
i don't know if you have some question
let me close here my video
and i finished my presentations here
again i hope
this um presentation
it will be helpful for you and here i
can see you
more and managing my
and again if you have any questions
please feel free
yes thank you for your demonstration
felipe uh uh you presented a great sas
tool today horosek
um it was a pleasure and it was nice
meeting you today um
remember to hop on discord right after
if you want to
talk to our sponsors and community
organizers also felipe would love to say
hi to you guys afterwards so just meet
him in the track one
in the weeds breakout room thank you for
attending san antonio besides everybody
and i hope you guys have a great evening
thank you felipe thank you bye
[Music]
do
you