hello
um christopher davie um i'll be doing an
intro to reverse engineering with uh
deidre i like to call this talk
taming the dragon um so first off a
little bit about me
i'm an avid ctf player i've played in my
defcon finals
qualified for other like very large ctf
events
with nasa rejects um went to utsa
and enjoy doing crypto reverse
engineering and like phone challenges
for fun
um so let's do a little bit into like
what is reverse engineering
um in this context i'm talking purely
software reverse engineering
there's another component where you do
hardware reverse engineering that's
outside the scope of what i'm going to
talk about today
but we'll talk about binary reverse
engineering
generally taking some compiled code from
the machine code you lift it up to some
form of an assembly language
and then from there you can mess around
with it and you have tools that allow
you to go
up to higher level languages
so it can be useful for figuring out how
things work from malware
to ctfs i do it a lot for vulnerability
research and reverse engineering
um that's generally some of the things
that you can use it for
also just like figuring out how
something works or
trying to debug a component of something
so in reverse engineering you generally
have the two
common mindsets you have static analysis
and dynamic analysis
um for the purpose of this talk we're
primarily going to focus on static
analysis with egypt
and from there you're usually you're
disassembling so you're taking that
byte code that machine code you then
lift it to assembly and then you have
another step with fija and ida called
the decompilation step which will take
their assembly port it to some type of
an il
so with dijo you'd be going slay to p
code and then from there go to like a c
like syntax
so the process of static analysis is
examining code without executing the
program
and this provides an understanding of
code structure and program flow
but it is limited right so you're gonna
lose a lot of contextual understanding
from like relative jumps from
uh registers that you're not able to
probe without
having a dynamic system you won't know
which branching paths you go down unless
you actually run it
and so
while static analysis can be limited it
is still very
useful and very necessary trait for the
reverse engineering toolkit
uh the damage analysis is usually you
execute
the binary through some form of
restitution usually
uh in the reverse engineering spectrum
you have some type of debugger
attached to it and i believe these go
hand in hand with static analysis
because you can utilize what you're
learning from both ends
to see which paths you want to go down
in the dynamic slide
or what values or what things you want
to set
when reversing and getting your
understanding from the static analysis
side
oh this node is actually outdated
they just recently in the beta
for uh dj 10 added the debugger
and i do have a slide talking about that
um everybody's actually pretty
interesting
it reminds me of red sink which was
a tool for ida that would allow you to
like integrate with like
uh wendy bug and some other things
um the next thing that i'd like to talk
about though is like a plan of attack so
generally when you are reversing some
type of binary
you have to start somewhere so i know
some people do a top-down
approach so they'll start from the like
program entry and work all the way down
through it and try to like
document up anything that they see or
like fix anything up that they see while
scrolling down through the
uh assembly this can be very difficult
for people
new to iris engineering because you get
lost in the weeds here
and may not always be necessary
depending on what type of version you're
trying to do
you can do it at a high level so
looking at the different function
entries and then go from there
and skim the functions to identify
common ones
you can go from common system calls and
function calls and then trace the
program to find interesting things
this is a very like common tactic used
with like vulnerability research and
that
you want to spend as little time as
possible reversing the entirety of the
program
you want to find where you have
um input coming from the user or coming
from
over the socket or whatever controlled
input that you may have
in order to see what types of things you
can um
mess with and so on so that's very
common for that
and then guided usually um
it's like if you have dynamic analysis
so you can trace the execution flow from
dynamic side and then use that to see
the paths that you take
and that one i think is probably the
easiest for beginners to get a
understanding of because you have
something that's already ran through and
executed the binary so you can kind of
step through that trace and figure out
what's going on there
uh some common pitfalls in reverse
engineering
is going too deep into the rabbit hole
you can have a
ton of different like functions that do
like very complex things but those
complex things may not be
what you're interested in this happens a
lot in debugging where people
will initially get lost in some of the
life sys calls or
so on start debugging code that's a
little bit lower than what they actually
want to be executing in
um you should also get into a pitfall of
reversing functions that aren't
reachable this happens a lot in static
analysis
where um you don't know
whether or not that code is going to be
reachable
for what you're doing it may be like
a very um
unused section that like only gets hit
with like different startup parameters
and so on so
uh it can be hard to know what to
reverse but you can also get stock
reversing functions that
um aren't very useful
um running into decompile or like
disassembly issues so
that's something that can be very
frustrating um
and i run into that with dj like either
the
function is too large or the function
has
like very strange things that causes the
decompilers to quit out
and same thing where the disassembly
kind of just doesn't track the
uh function you have to fix it up in
order for anything to actually
be analyzed and then not saving your
database is a common pitfall because
i've had
power outages i've had other things
where
not having to save your database can
throw a lot of work and research time
out the window
so a simple overview of what a
disassembler
or like edger does is it'll convert
machine code up to assembly recognize
the
start and end of functions recognize
jump
calls to functions uh it'll help you
find strings
and like data sections uh it'll remember
like any user labels and comments so you
can type in your own comments to
start to make a
like binary that you're versus more
readable more understandable
and generally has a graph of program
flow
all right so i've been talking about
guitar a lot but what is deidra
so it's a software reverse engineering
tool
with version management and decompilers
and
also now includes a debugger
um it has a public repo on github with
active contributions and maintainers
and it is multi-platform so i'm using it
today
on osx but it's going to run on linux os
x windows or any type of environment
that
has java 11 supported
as to the supported architecture so this
is a uh list from rob joyce uh
rob was one of the like initial people
who spearheaded um
publicizing guitar and also um
was the main face in promoting diedra
but they have all sorts of different uh
supported architectures
and these supported architectures
generally have an associated
decompiler and this is very nice because
for a lot of these architectures tools
like ida
um did not have a way to lift them
without doing um
either your own custom lifting of it or
having a financial in some other way so
there's definitely
improved reverse engineering of earl
and has made uh life a lot easier for
people working in
um some of these various architectures
um
yeah so to download pedra so there are
two websites there's the
uh nsa's um
uh repo on github and then there's
teacher sre.org
right now you have the stable version
which i believe is 9.2.4
and then the beta version which is 10.00
and the beta version is what i'm going
to be doing for some of my
uh demos at the end of the presentation
uh so like the general like
understanding of the layout you have
um things broken down into different
areas you have
uh docs which have cheat sheets which
have
presentations to like get yourself or
get you um
acclimated to like some of the minutiae
of
deidra um but for running it you have
user run and need to run.bat
so dj run is going to be the linux
utility or osx utility
just script that um opens the
java and then same thing with the bad
script which will run on windows
um the trainings are really interesting
uh
they have instructor notes to give your
to like um be more familiar with the
content that's going on in the
presentation so they can be a really
good learning
environment um i looked through the beta
today and i didn't see anything in the
advanced or intermediate that had
uh presentations or documentation there
on the debugger so the divider is still
reading some of the other documentation
and kind of figuring it out on your own
right now
um some useful plugins that i think are
pretty cool for
youtube right now are dragon dance so
it's like lighthouse for aedra
lighthouse is a tool that would take
like
dynamic traces of the
binary and then use that to visualize
and manipulate the code coverage that
you get when executing
so it'll like highlight the different
fields
or basic blocks that you see to
kind of get an understanding of where
you've progressed in the binary at a
dynamic side and
replicate that over on the static side
um this just has a uh it's a dj
community page
and it has a ton of plugins and cpu
other like cpu extensions that may not
be
directly supported by deidra but
community support
have created so i think there are some
for like
the uh like game boy and so on that are
up there
and then there's uh daenerys which
allows for execution
of ida strips and uddra and also allows
you to port your digit scripts over to
ida which has been really nice
uh one thing not listed here is that
edra also has
tools to convert your binary database
from ida to dija and from dija to ida
noting that you will lose some of the
comments and markups that you
have but some of the structure like if
you have to
manipulate the like program entry
or if you have different like header
sections that you have to
mess with like if you're doing firmware
those things will be saved and
propagated into the other
analysis tool
so some useful features so themes and
configurations
um you can see here that i have like a
little um
dark mode light so it's using the metal
theme and then inverts the colors to
make it look like dark mode
i was going to use this for some of my
demos however
i believe it makes it a little bit
unreadable for
like presentation wise so i'm going to
probably just use the light mode theme
um there's version tracking so version
tracking in
the uh giga server and that's probably
one of the most powerful things
with each apart from having
um lifters and decompilers for
architectures that other
tools don't support is the um server
collaboration
so i believe for ioda like rpi sec
should say um
ctf team out of the school rpi
up in new york they have their own
develop system to do collaboration ida
but they never released it and never
publicized it
um so barring that there's no like
collaborative way to do reversing other
than
everybody just sharing their databases
across with
each other so it was really difficult to
manage who did what
and also transferring those changes was
a bit tedious
so dja come support it with a djs server
which you can set up and then you can
commit up
your analysis changes to
the server to allow other people to view
that and also
commit their own changes so it's very
good as a teaching tool
i think it is stellar to use in like the
university
sphere and is also very good for
collaborative
large reversing efforts on
either like large uh binaries or things
that are very complex that have multiple
engineers working on them
um it has binary diffing however
um i still prefer bindif which bindif
um i believe has some support for
um deidre now but i know it has support
for ida bindif is a
utility that will diff
two separate binaries if you have like a
newer versions let's say
windows team out with a patch for
something you want to figure out what
that patch has
you can use the binary difference to
you the difference between that um i
haven't been the biggest fan of
the guitra provided binary differing
tool but it still is nice
uh as a nice to have and modi is
something that i'll show you
in uh while doing the demo
um so i kind of ranted a bit about um
the server uh collaboration but it's
actually like really easy to set up
um you basically just need a centralized
server and then it's running
out of the same utilities that you run
for like each of run
so you just have a server component it
runs
that stuff just needs java setup
and you can easily get the server
running there
and then have other people be able to
access that
um i thought about having a dj server
that people could
use and play with
during the talk however um
neutral has like authentication and
there is an
authenticated mode but i didn't
necessarily want to do that because then
people could like mess things up so i
decided to miss that idea
but um the server collaboration is very
useful for lots of different things so
you can track like commit changes
kind of similar to like using github for
changes to
uh reversing engineering a binary
you can review changes by others and you
also see that version history and revert
back to those changes and it's very
useful for ctfs where you're
um doing things very like quickly and
need to share those uh
binaries very quickly so you could have
people like reversing different
functions and then collaborate to see
where they are on different things very
useful for mentoring and
group malware reversing efforts group of
vulnerability researching efforts and so
on
um so when you first start off with uh
deidra you're gonna
have like um you know start it up and
you'll get this type of view
so you have like a tool chest and you
don't have an active project so you need
to create a new project
um and with that new project
so you create projects you can create a
shared or unshared project
shared projects are going to be pushed
up to a server if you have a server
um from there once you create
a project my project is called test
then you can then start to upload your
binary so for this example
i'm uploading or importing um
my os x ls binary
up into deidra to try to reverse
engineer that
once you have a binary that's imported
you'll double check the binary
it'll pop up with a a few different
window panes but then it'll ask you
saying hey this binary hasn't been
analyzed would you like to analyze it
and you'll have a bunch of different
settings if you're just starting
off with dedra i would say probably
don't
mess with the different um
analyzers i would like look through them
and like some of them might be useful
for like the different
niche things that you're working with um
so for instance
like i know there are some plugins
for analysis for like game boy and so on
so you might want to like use
those strips but maybe run them as one
offs rather than
run it in like the batch mode of like
running all these scripts at one time
um tool options so uh with feature you
can
modify the tool to do a bunch of
different things you can change the
color scheme
and you can also change um how different
things like lay out
on the tool so for instance
uh one thing that i like to modify when
i'm using guidra is
usually eliminate unreachable code is
checked
as i do a lot of vulnerability research
and it might be nice for
once you have a bug to know what
different
chains or like um code that you can
utilize
to execute in other areas so
um while i may think that it's
unreachable you may be able to make it
unreachable so i like to
or you may be able to make it reachable
so i like to
uncheck that field um it adds a little
bit more
to what you're going to see with fija
and this can
sometimes lead you back into that rabbit
hole of reversing things that aren't
reachable
but i generally would rather see it than
not
from my perspective
you can also go through and modify your
key bindings
i like to fix up some of the key
bindings to make them similar to ida
just because that's what i'm
more used to and accustomed to when
doing reversing
um and also just adding other
like key bindings to make things make
your life easier
for different um tools that you have or
like the different components and
different views that you have in egypt
uh another thing that i like to disable
and this is really hard to read and why
i decided not to do
the dark mode from here but you can see
like the check boxes really aren't
usable
but for the disassembly options
i like to turn off
markup inferred variable references and
so what this is doing is saying
if you have a variable that's named in
the decompilation side
so in the c side it tries to assign the
registers over on the disassembly those
same names
and for my purposes that generally is
more confusing than helpful
i like to be able to see what registers
are being used especially with
the different parameters and like uh
software function
um like kali caller conventions
so i prefer to like actually be able to
see
the um registers there
and i'll show you an example of that in
a second
um there's also some common key bondings
that you can look at
and after i finish this talk i'm going
to go through and upload my slides and
some test binaries for people to mess
with if they're interested
but there's like several uh different
common key findings there's actually
um several gists out there of like
applying um all of like ida's
um tooling interface so
like the key command t bindings for that
over to dja to make your
transition a little bit easier um now
we're going to talk about some of the
views
so there's the graph view um it is my
perspective that the graph
view for djira is not my favorite
um if i were to work on something only
from a graph view perspective
i believe ida is far superior in that
and binary ninja
as firearm superior and the view that
you get for graph view
i just feel like eucharist is a little
bit funky
but you know dj makes up for it and how
its
general workflow is intended to be used
is more from the
decompilation than from the graph view
um but with the graph you can
apply markup so you can apply coloring
this is very useful when doing
like traces so you can um
uh colorify things in the graph to say
hey we took
this branch we went down this code path
and so on so it can make your life a
little bit easier um
with where which functions you've either
gone down dynamically or which functions
you've
reversed and or which portions of the
luncheon you reverse and which portions
you haven't
um now the decompiler i'd say the
decompiler is the like bread and butter
and what most people end up using
when using um hydra
um i like to think of it as a cheap mode
in a sense
i'm very used to using um
ida to go through the disassembly and
having to read a lot of the
assembly to understand things so having
a decompiler is definitely nice
and is definitely an aid
in which you can comment up all these
different variables
add your own
mnemonic names in order to
make it more understandable and more
readable for
your reverse engineering needs
there's an example of uh doing the
markup so
this is just a mim copy you have your
dest your source
and then the size so yeah
you can also patch a binary so
say that you have i don't know my
um example this
that applies to most people say that you
uh like want to cheat in the video game
or you want to like apply a patch to
software because it's being annoying or
something
you can apply patches to like say not
take a jump or
so on so it does have the ability to
patch a binary
and type in the
various instructions that you'd want to
add there it'll fix it up and
write that machine code for you but then
you having to like
manually like set it the binary
uh now talk a little bit about p code so
slay and p code are
some of the intermediate views and
intermediate languages that hedra
uses taking the
micropro the machine code popping it up
to an assembly and then from there
pop the name up to see so it'll go
through these il
or intermediate uh language or
intermediate representation
uh views before being pushed up to that
c like syntax
you can also go in uh
i'll show it in a second but you can
enable p code so that you can see
what the p code is for the
given function you're looking at and an
understanding of the p code is very
useful
because you'll be using that a lot if
you're doing any
scripting or automation with uh draw
um then you have the strip manager so
um this is just like all the different
strips that are already available
but if you add in any of your own strips
or what i like to do generally
is go in and edit one of these strips
that has
some of what i need but not all of it
i'll create a new one copy it off that
and then
uh edit that to do um what i'm looking
to do
but um these and it'd be nice to like go
through here and see if there are any
scripts that might be useful
for the reversing case that you're using
definitely more of a power user than a
very basic user type functionality
next is the data type editing structure
so um
i think this is probably one of the more
like stronger use cases for
ditra and applying it to the
decompilation so you can have these like
very large like c
like structures that have tons of data
in them and you can create those
structures
and edit those structures and dedra
and then apply that to what you're
seeing in the
binary so that deidra recognizes that
and is able to say ah yes this is this
structure these are how they're
referencing it and so on
just to like pretty up the uh
decompilation and make it look nicer
but also to um you can apply this across
all uh functions so that
uh it tracks and traces uh to know like
what this
um type of the
um thing might be um that's another
thing just in the data type
editing um you can if you know there are
custom types for the structure so say
it's some
well-known um ieee standard
and you're reversing that you see these
structures that relate to those things
you can start to apply those structures
and those data types
and then apply that across the binary in
order to have a
greater understanding of what's going on
i think this is like a very powerful
um side of what that makes like feature
very useful
and then we'll talk about the debugging
side so deabody is still in beta
i believe they're planning to release uh
teacher 10
sometime this month either like mid to
late this month
um so then i think you'll get more
documentation and maybe have some
presentation slides
uh with an introduction to the
[Music]
debugger but the debugger is very
similar in my opinion to
like red sync so it allows you to
integrate in with like
windy bug or allows you to integrate in
with gdb
in order to have some type of debugging
like native debugging capabilities
with um the
binary that you're using some of the
interesting things though that they've
added or
um they added like time travel s
debugging
through emulation to say um
i want to step back through what i was
just executing
um and it allows you to do that through
keeping track and state of the
registers noting that time travel
debugging
is not flawless so that is to say that
there are some things that may be
lost so like let's say that you
are modifying files or you have mutexes
or you have locks
um it may change state when trying to go
back through things
um and so on if or those things may not
like
be properly set so um
the timeless slide debugging isn't
perfect but it is still very
interesting and useful uh functionality
and definitely something like really
neat
that i thought they added um also just
like having the
stack and like the ability to trace and
like set
watch points within deidre and then also
have the
um disassembly and also decompilation
available it's like really neat and
useful um
i won't be showing a
uh demo of the debugging side of things
today
but it is something that i plan to use
more
and work with more um they might
somewhat reset and release um
but yeah cool
demo time so i have um
dj already open um i'm gonna
create a new project just to show you
the workflow
but um so you can create a non-shared
project or a shared project
so non-shared being local shared project
meaning you're going to need to have a
feature server running
that you can connect in with um
otherwise you're going to create a
non-shared project so that's what we do
here
and finish
all right so now we have a project right
but we don't have any binaries added in
here yet
so there are two ways that you can add
in binaries you can either
add them in through getting i uh which
is import
you can also do file import file
uh you can also like um go through and
drag and
drop so say i have a program over here
i can drag it in and see what type of
file it is so this particular file is
the
mips um video neon 32-bit
binary and the form of an elf
so we can go ahead and import that
so what it's doing here just loading
that binary into the
system it's not doing any of the
analysis just yet
um and do
similar things so once i get more
processes
and certain things are going to be a
little bit slower than others so
um for instance this is mips it's going
to take a little bit longer
than say your it's 86 or x64
um and so on uh
i found that like analyzing velvet or
like any
apks is like very
time intensive so i'll show you how to
import
the uh apks but i won't go through
actually analyzing them because it takes
a very long time
but here we can see um so i'll prompt
you with uh do you want to analyze the
binary we'll say yes
and then we'll just go through with the
general um things
sorry i can't really tell if this is
readable so
if the speaker wants to pop up then i'm
sorry if the
other anyone wants to pop up and say
it's not readable let me know
um i'm used to doing this on like a
large projector
yeah so while it goes through the
analysis they'll kind of talk through
the different components
so you have your program tree here um
which talks about your different
sections
of the uh program so you have your like
global offset table here your bss
your s data should have your data your
text section and so on um
over here you have your symbol tree so
this will talk about your imports
so this will show all the different um
imports that you have so whether they're
windows for linux this is a linux miner
it's an elf
um so it's going to have like libsy.so
and then it's doing some crypto here um
and then it's a it has like standard c
plus plus library as well
um we can see what functions are
exported so this would be useful if
you're looking at like a dll or like a
um
some type of shared object um because
then you have a lot of like
uh program exports but um generally
speaking
for the types of binaries that you might
be reverse engineering especially when
you're a beginner you may not be looking
at the shared objects or those dlls
so you're going to be looking more at
the functions tab
one thing that's interesting
is that um deidre will
kind of take full uh like your
[Music]
functions and like apply them into files
for things that are similar
uh which i think is interesting but not
always like nice
um for some of the uh things that i want
to like look at
but um you can see these are all your
like different sys calls or like
function calls here
um you can see these are all your like
unnamed functions
and then you can see some of the other
different things um
so generally you're gonna look for
your main um if it's a stripped binary
it might be underscore underscore let's
see
start name um or entry
or so on so depending on like the type
of binary you're going to have different
like program entries but this one has a
defined main
um that we can look at and see like over
here
so this side we have the disassembly
so you can see the different
components and if you open this tab here
so this shows all of the different
sections um and right now
you can see i have highlighted the
operands um
over here you can see the fights here
you can see the
mnemonic and then
so on so if you wanted to like enable
code you can enable that and see what
the p
code looks like for all of the different
instructions
over here but it does add a lot of bloat
so we go ahead and disable that field
and then we also want like post comment
and eol comments
um your comments like adding comments in
here
are very nice when you're reversing to
say hey
i figured out what this does or what
this is doing and so on and then over
here you can do the same thing so now
you're
um i'm going through the
decompilations you can see there's the
function call that has
two parameters i can label one of the
parameters to be a new name
and it'll um replicate across here
um another thing that i kind of wanted
to show were the
tool options so when you go into full
options you have a ton of different
options
um i don't know how to say like
go to here if you want to like do these
things like it's so varied
but if we go back to um this little view
right here
if you highlight like the different
sections and see if this gets
highlighted
so like ah okay it's in the operands
field that i want to like uh look at
something so
go to listing fields and that'll be all
of the uh
different fields for here and then you
can go to
operands field and this is the um
thing that i was mentioning turning off
before was the markup inferred variable
references
i prefer to see the um
[Music]
different like registers rather than the
pseudonames that deidra automatically
applies or that i may apply
when looking at the disassembly um
other things that are interesting so the
function called
uh graph so this our function fault tree
um just to see like what uh incoming
upcoming calls go to these can be nice
to see like track your way up
or track your way down for different
things um
this button right here is how you open
the script manager and so we can do all
the different scripts
uh and then window
if you want to see the function graph
yeah um and then here you can like
scroll around and so on
um i still think so i use i'm using a
laptop right now
using a touchpad um but for dedra i
still think that you need a
mouse in order to like use it uh
correctly
just by virtue of like if you want to
say highlight all uses of a variable and
the
[Music]
assembly or highlight all uses of a
register or something like that in
the assembly you have the middle plate
you can refine that and the keybindings
but i believe it
uh generally for their purposes is
assumed
that you have um
a mouse um so for this instance we're
not going to say
for your instances you may want to save
it
and then i'll show you also opening a uh
apk
so import we
have this little like
uh hello world apk it's literally the
simplest
apk that you want so you have different
ways that you can
open it you can open it as a single file
that's not going to work batched
not going to work either or it's a file
system so i like to open it as a file
system
and then you can browse it to see ah
here's the
uh dex that i want to analyze it so then
you can
open this and then import that dex then
you can import it as a single file
you see that it's a uh dalvik executable
so this is the java byte code
and then go through and import that i
would go through do it but it takes
a very long time to do those things so
um i'm running kind of light on time so
i'm gonna
put the demo now and kind of go into my
mean section
um for those of you who may have seen
one of my presentations before or know
me
i always have memes in my slides so
these are some of my favorite ones
related to
idra um basically when deidre was
released
there's a lot of like back and forth
between ida and future
like guidry cost somewhere in the range
of like three grand
so like 15 grand if you're looking for
like all versions and all different
types of things
um and so on so i just like to leave the
memes up for a bit uh this is probably
my favorite one from the baba group
of uh kind of making fun of ferdari
users uh
unfortunately
hello i'm philip wiley the founder of
the pawn school project
homeschool project was founded in june
as a way to offer free education based
on penetration testing
and ethical
meetings back in 2018 uh
hello i'm philip wiley the founder of
the pawn school project
palm school project was founded in june
as a way to offer free education based
on penetration testing
and ethical hacking to the public more
specifically the dallas fort worth area
this was created out of my passion to
educate others
when i was before i started teaching i
did a lot of mentoring which
kind of inspired me to go into teaching
and you know i was teaching ethical
hacking at dallas college and some of my
students towards the end of the semester
the first semester was asking
why where could they take more classes
because they're interested in taking it
but
most people had you know a small budget
for training so
my idea was to get together like on the
weekends and and do some
some little workshops some little
hands-on training to help them further
their education
so i've decided to go a step further and
started the pawn school project or palm
school for short
uh the home school project hosts two
meetings per month
they started out physical meetings back
in 2018
uh 2019 i started offering the dallas
meeting streamed so that way it opened
up to
people around the globe to be able to
consume this content and help them
and when the pandemic hit we end up
going virtual with both of the meetings
offering two meetings per month and we
expanded past
offensive security into defensive
security even we had talks on
uh becoming a cso as well as
talks on uh becoming a sock analyst
another thing unique to home school is
at least
far is the area that that i live in
where phone school was founded in the
dallas fort worth area
is this this meetup was more friendly to
new new people trying to get into the
industry
and we try to take more of an
educational approach so not only does
phone school stream
uh monthly meetings i also teach
pen testing and web app pen testing
workshops at different conferences for
different colleges
and for different uh cyber security
groups
so if you're interested in checking us
out go to pwnschool.com
and there's a link to our slack channel
as well as meetup for our scheduled
meetings
and i hope to see you at home school
meeting sometime soon
[Music]
thanks
do
[Music]
you