so this talk is about using burp suite
specifically around using plugins that
are available to increase your
efficiency during testing and we'll also
get into a little bit of do-it-yourself
so we'll write go walk through a plugin
written in Python
so the real quick
obligatory about me slide my name is
Brad bellman I work for secure works I'm
an application pen tester so I use burp
suite every day when working first time
my family actually came and seen one of
the talks so we got some gaps in what
burp does for us I mean don't get me
wrong I love it it's awesome it's my
favorite tool to use when I'm testing
there's a few gaps that we're gonna fill
in using plugins we're talking about
beefing up the scanner we're going to
talk about adding some passive detection
things that you can do we're gonna look
at a few specific tasks using some
plugins and then we're gonna get into a
little bit of writing your own so I'm
gonna start out just walking through
some of the basics I'm sure that a lot
of you probably use burp and are
familiar with it some of you probably
not so we're just gonna walk through a
couple of the basics real quick first
off when you're using plugins make sure
you understand what they are I see a lot
of people like hey I read this
description it sounds really cool it's
the new thing that just came out or
whatever cuz there's you know a decent
mount of plugins that are that come up
for this now
you want to understand what they're
doing they're on github so you can
actually go and look and read a little
bit of code and see what they're doing
at least the the Store apps are on
github
anyway and again if you're not familiar
with burp it's got an extender it's got
a store so there's a look at what the
store looks like I hope you can kind of
see that in the back but it's got a list
of plugins descriptions author names
there's a link to where it is all you
got to do is just select it install it
as long as everything goes well it will
install and you can start using the
plug-in immediately so I meant
some of some of burps gaps the big one
that that we're going to talk about is
having full visibility into the other
requests and responses in all the
different tools so like the proxy
history and intruder and repeater it's
not really a big deal because you can
see all those right but things like the
scanner spider if you're running macros
and something starts breaking especially
in scanner it's difficult to
troubleshoot when you're not 100% sure
of what it's actually sending to the
application so that's the big one we're
gonna talk about it also doesn't give
you an easy way outside the plugins to
really add any scanner checks so we're
gonna look at adding scanner checks for
you so we're gonna talk about those
passive checks just really easy simple
ways to add those in and then we're
going to look at some decoders and file
format viewers so first off I put this
one first because it's by far my
favorite plug-in it's awesome for like I
mentioned troubleshooting macros things
like that
it's called logger plus plus it's from
NCC group here's a real quick look at
part of the configuration of it but what
I what I wanted to call here was you can
check the different tools that you want
to be able to see so you don't
necessarily need to run it against all
tools but you know I really liked it
first scanner and every now and then
sequencer and things like that because
you can go back through and look that's
a whole lot of different things you can
do with it too like searching and
highlighting and exporting and reg X's
and things like that so here's kind of
what it looks like when you're when
you're actually running something you
just have it's really basic interface of
on the left you can see you know the
number of the requests coming by which
tool it's in what you're scanning and
gassed and you see method path all that
stuff so it's really nice I also like to
use it keep an eye on things so as I'm
running anything automated so I'll run
automated tools like nikto and things
like that superb as well and it's really
nice as you're watching it you'll see
the requests go through
and it's kind of nice to keep an eye on
things because you can spot a lot of
differences in responses so you know as
it's checking things thrown a lot of
things at the application application
obviously will respond in different ways
sometimes there's you can spot kind of
interesting behavior that the tool
doesn't necessarily tell you about but
it's just something you can see in the
in the results so here's an example so
you can see the response length there is
the same throughout and all of a sudden
one of them is a little bit different so
not saying that that's you know some
sort of a vulnerability is some kind of
finding everything that's definitely
something that's interesting that the
application did and I'd really like to
see you know what that difference was
and take a look and see why that was
different all the others are the same
and all of a sudden one is different so
the pros and cons of it the the biggest
the additional insight it's really nice
for troubleshooting searching all those
things the cons it doesn't save
automatically so Burke now will save
projects and things automatically this
doesn't save any of that stuff so if you
want to keep findings that you have out
of logger plus plus you can export them
to CSV and you can do an auto save to
CSV it's kind of a pain and the other
thing is you only see the entries in the
logger after there's a response or a
timeout so if you send something and
it's sitting there you know the
applications not responding or anything
you have to sit there and wait for a
timeout or if it eventually a
centre-back response you can't see the
request that was sent because it it
pairs them together and then pushes them
into the interface so I want to talk
about beefing up the scanner a little
bit there's a lot of really good
plug-ins that are really easy to install
and do a lot of really useful things for
you not like to use the scanner piece as
a second set of eyes so you know as
you're going through and doing a lot of
manual testings scanner is really nice
to find easier automatable things like
you know cross-site scripting and things
like that so it's a really nice second
set eyes on things but there's a lot
that we can add to it and like I said
low-hanging fruit and tedious stuff
you know I want I want automated every
time and the main goal obviously being
you want to focus on the application
logic because that's really where you
know you add your value is is testing
out logic and things like that not
necessarily looking for cross-site
scripting and things so the first one is
called active scan plus plus it's
written by one of the one of the people
that worked for ports wigger which is
who puts out Bert and adds a lot of
really useful additional scan attacks
like xxe and other XML attacks I'm I
don't know if you guys have seen but the
new wasp
top-10 actually lists xxe as one of them
now I personally don't agree with that
being in the top ten and regardless here
feelings you know that's that's been a
little bit of an interesting subject but
that's one thing that you've gone may is
is checks for that suspicious input
transforms we will actually look at a
few of those there's several other tools
that do something similar and then the
older stuff too so like shell-shocked
and things that you know aren't really
necessarily out there a lot anymore but
something you still need to look for
because every now and then you know
you'll see something like that so
there's no GUI component to it all it
does is just add adds checks into the
scanner so it'll queue them up as you're
scanning some additional things host
header attacks the the input
transformation so things like seeing if
that gets evaluated so seven times seven
you know things like that and we'll look
at an example so this is from a recent
engagement that I was on where it
actually fingerprinted
I don't know Hawaii but it's saying hey
I found something that looks like
server-side templating section and if
actually fingerprinted out to be
velocity which is an Apache product and
the way it did it is you can see the
payload so it's syntax and velocity
actually
and using that getting response where
that was actually evaluated it said hey
I think this is velocity turned out to
be right and that was actually a really
interesting attack if you saw talk that
Jarrod McLaren and I did at skier Iowa
we actually walked through part of that
where this turned out to be a sellable
situation through the application so
another one additional scanner checks so
adding dom-based cross-site scripting
and things like that you want to be a
little bit leery of that you'll get a
ton of hits on that most of them are not
exploitable I've seen you know
engagements where all have five thousand
findings of dom-based cross-site
scripting know it it's a little bit it's
a little bit verbose than that it's
airing on the side of caution you'll get
a lot of false positives it does things
like really simple checks like missing
security headers like you know CSP
policy and things like that also it's
for HTTP to HTTPS redirection and
another one is j2ee scan so this doesn't
another one where it's a lot of pass
CDEs a lot of stuff you don't
necessarily want to be spending time
manually looking for it'll do for you
and you can see a lot of different
examples there some Java based stuff
like struts and Grails JBoss that sort
of thing and ton of other things too
once again this one doesn't have a good
component it's just adding on to the
skin so this is again this is another
recent engagement where this caught
something I definitely did not go into
this engagement saying hey I'm gonna
find this og NL console
it was just not even on my radar
something to look for in that
application but there it was
so that console lets you evaluate
expression language statements and that
ended up being a very fruitful one as
well so the pros it's really easy to add
a lot of automated testing into the
scanner
there's one that does have a GUI tab
most not I put that as a pro because as
you start adding some of these some
plugins and things for though you use
burp you see a lot of tabs there at the
top and it's it becomes a pain to try to
find which one you're using and stuff so
I don't necessarily like to see the tabs
I mean obviously they're useful for a
lot of cases but I'd prefer to not see
them in some of those the con the only
con really being that it's gonna add
time your skin obviously I mean you're
adding to it so of course this is a
somewhat more recent I mean it's been
out for a little while it's very
interesting one called back slash
powered scanner James kettle again one
of the ports burger guys it doesn't
necessarily look for you know a tax
string here measure the response see
what it is it's looking more for hey I'm
gonna throw something kind of
interesting like I'm gonna throw in
different keywords or I'm going to
escape different special characters and
things and see the differences so that's
the the suspicious input transformations
it's just you know really really simple
example is it's going to use a backslash
to escape you know a double quote and
then I will run the same thing just
without escaping it and see the
differences in the application the
theory being if it if it reacts
differently to a non escaped character
than it does to an escape character
that's obviously something that's being
processed by the application maybe
something important to the application
and is something that is is worth
looking into so he did a really really
good white paper on the whole theory of
it and and how he was able to optimize
it and everything else so it's a it's an
easy one to find if you want to go out
there and just search for the white
paper on backslash powered scanner so
it's like I said it shows you the
interesting results to point you towards
a potential issue so this is really one
of those things or it's pointing to hey
I saw something that is kind of odd I
don't know what it is but you need to go
check it so it always requires manual
verification so here's an example
so I mentioned keywords in this case it
took one of the parameters and it's
using null and
I changed it to and zll so it's just one
letter difference but the null keyword
changed the application response so you
can see content length is much different
so obviously null is something important
to the application doesn't necessarily
mean that it's vulnerable to anything
but it's definitely an interesting
little bit of behavior that you want to
go check out and sometimes it does lead
to something so this has a little add a
little menu into burp and this is
defaults I've never really had any
reason to mess with the defaults it
works well for me so pros and cons again
con being some of the results you'll see
it's not always very useful you'll see
things that you know you'll see a
different response and things like that
and you'll go and look like oh okay
obviously that's gonna have a different
response I don't know why it's reporting
that it happens it's not so bad again
easy additional automated tests that you
can throw in and look for different
things that you may not have thought to
look for and it's the the really
powerful thing about it is that third
one there is sometimes it'll find things
that other techniques will miss so the
next one is scan manual insertion point
so this is just a really really simple
one you can add it in and it just adds a
little option for you in one of the
menus so as you're looking at say a
request in any one of the tools it could
be the proxy or a repeater or whatever
you can just highlight it right click
and say scan this so here's an example
you can see here where I've highlighted
the big string there in the post body
right and then I just right-click and
you scan manual insertion point which is
really nice I know a lot of people talk
about they're sending something to
intruder and then do scanning that way
this saves the step as long as it's only
a parameter that you want to send to the
scanner and so it's simple to use saves
you the steps the only downside you can
only do one section at a time
and remembering it's there I've had a
lot of times where I go through and send
a intruder or whatever and get into the
scanner just to remember like oh I
coulda just right-clicked and said go
alright so let's talk about something
other than the scare so pdfs is
something that i've personally come
across in a ton of assessments right and
you'll see something like this where
it's you know it's a PDF I mean it's
really obviously a PDF right you don't
necessarily know what the PDF is and
just by glancing at that at the text
there so what we want to do is go from
this so it's just to look at the raw
request there to that so what it'll do
is they'll add this little extra tab
here I know what it is I can look at
that really quickly and say oh I know
exactly that is so maybe you have
sensitive information or whatever you
know whatever you happen to be looking
for in the assessment so really similar
EXIF tool scanner which is really nice
so it'll scan any of the supported file
formats and look for metadata for you
so looking at that same PDF we just used
in the previous example another tab for
metadata you can go or and say hey
author or all this stuff you know you
you can look for things like that using
folk of the advantage here is if I'm
doing an assessment where I am
authenticated I can now look at you know
across metadata of things really quickly
in an authenticated State with things
like search engines and Foca and search
diggity and some of those other tools
and I don't be able to find this
obviously because it's in the
authenticated portion of the application
so the nice thing about it is you don't
have to go through and look through the
metadata of all the files if it finds
anything it will just throw up an issue
for you and say hey I found
and PDF and you can just go click on
that it'll list if you if you looked at
you know a thousand PDFs and they all
had metadata it will list them all out
for you you can go through and look at
them there and it'll auto attack so if
you already have XF tool in your path
it'll find that for you and just use
that and if not it'll extract to a temp
file and use it that way so you can
literally just install it and go you
don't have to worry about it setting a
path or anything like that and it has
this little this little tab here so you
can by default it will ignore HTML JSON
things like that that are not gonna have
metadata it's gonna collect so it
doesn't mess with looking through those
and and you know giving you a
performance hit essentially and then you
can turn off things to you like ignore
access tool version things like that
they don't necessarily want to see in
each one of those so the pros and cons
of those I mean I don't there's no rule
of cons that I can think of in using
those I do like to easily look at PDFs
when I come across them and see what
they are quick insight into the metadata
and searching all that automatically and
then giving you the heads-up of hey I
found some metadata here's a list of
everything I found really really nice so
move on to the passive detection so the
first one that I like to use for this is
called retire j/s so this is looking at
javascript dependencies for you and
comparing them against a database and
saying hey I just passively saw as you
were loading this page it was using this
bit of jQuery and it's an old version
and it's vulnerable and vulnerable to
these known things so I'll give you the
version it saw it'll give you links to
CVEs and things like that which is is
awesome for you know finding that stuff
for you don't necessarily want to be
looking through all the GS files of
everything you get there's a lot of jazz
heavy applications out there now
so there's an example so in this one too
and again I didn't have to go out there
and look for that it found it for me as
I was just mapping the application
popped it out here and hey it's known
vulnerable to these things so you know
jQuery a lot of times no and vulnerable
to cross-site scripting things like that
but it will tell you exactly exactly the
issues that are known so next one to
stop for a vulnerability scanner so this
is by a group called boners they have a
website with an API so this plugin uses
that API and again it's just passively
watching versions of things that it's
that it's viewing as you're just mapping
the application or whatever you're doing
and I'll go through user API and say hey
I found this version of Apache or is or
whatever and ping the API and then come
back and say hey that particular version
of this again is known vulnerability to
these sorts of things so the the one
downside is you know especially when you
deal with someone like iOS it'll report
a whole bunch of you know known CDs for
is 7.5 or whatever your your target may
very well be patched against those
things you know so it's it's really up
to you at that point to determine
whether or not they're in a patch state
or not but but it's really nice for for
quickly finding those things so here's
an example in this case it found iOS 7
and then you can see you know a list of
CDs things like that in this case and
again you know it's it's nice because as
you're going through obviously you're
gonna probably fingerprint it and you
might even see in the headers of the
response - hey it's iOS 7 you know easy
to find but this gives you a nice list
and says hey here's everything in known
vulnerability and you can go
and look for things interesting that
aren't aren't like you know
denial-of-service and things that you
might want to try and engage meant
obviously yeah there are some not so
common applications I don't have a
screenshot of it but it has a tab of a
lot of different technologies and things
that it will check for so yeah I asked
Apaches things like that are obviously
in there but some of the lesser-known
things even some obscure CMS systems and
things like that will be in there so the
one one thing about it is just you have
to remember that's passive it's not
actively fingerprinting anything for you
it's seen versions come across in
headers or you know in a file or
whatever and reporting that for you it's
not actively doing anything to find
these for you and so there's a there's
just a quick example there you know put
an issue in on on the target tab just
like some of the others and say here's
everything I found so as you go through
you know you may find other versions of
software than didn't detect but at least
you know what it did and did not find
for you all right so another one is
error message checks so I like this one
it uses reg X this check for verbose
error messages and things like that and
it'll also create an entry just like
just like the last one you saw up saying
hey I saw this match this reject matched
on this request and you can go through
and look and see if it you know what the
error message was so there's there's an
example it's nice that it actually gives
you the the regex is that it matches on
and you'll get some false positives
because you will have you know error
handling and things like that in
JavaScript files that sometimes will
trigger on this it's not a verbose error
message it's revealing anything to you
and you know in some of those cases so
you do get some false positives but I
like it because
it's checking for verbose error messages
and some of the tools you're running
like the scanner you know it was one
even even the spider sometimes I've had
that come across something that's
spitting out a verbose error message so
things that you may or may not have
spotted otherwise and so there's there's
a look at the configuration for it these
are all built in and you can put in
regex match just you know whatever
whatever regex you want and and create
those if you want it also lets you turn
on and off for different tools so by
default these are the tools that's
looking at so pros I like to I like to
turn it on in most everything just
passively checking so it's not you know
a big massive resource hit or anything
like that easy way to find those then
just go in our target issues here's the
list easy to miss you know verbose error
messages and some of those are really
easy to spot and then con being the
false pause that i mentioned that you
sometimes will see in some of the
javascript files alright so i want to
just go to a couple of specific tasks
using some plugins so this is one of my
favorite favorites here it's called
authorize and what it is is you can make
identical requests under different users
so you can have user 1 user 2 so two
different users making the same request
so if i'm browsing as user 1 and user 2
can get to some of the same resources
that live under user ones profile i may
have you know a horizontal privileged
escalation there or you can also set it
up so i'm browsing as an admin and it
will make requests as an unprivileged
user and an anonymous user and as you go
through and map out the admin portion
sometimes you'll find and it sounds it
sounds kind of simple sometimes but
you'll find that some of the admin
screens a lower privileged user can get
to just by no
the URL and just going to it right so
forced browsing so if you have an admin
user you can map out all the admin
functions under that user as this tool
is uh is sending the same exact request
just basically replacing the cookies
with the ones used for the lower
privileged and you can very easily then
spot where you have some horizontal and
vertical escalations so here's here's
what it looks like by default it's just
turned off and you feed it cookies so
what I like to do is use two browsers
I'll think one browser and log in is a
low privileged user and I'll take the
other and login as an admin or just
another user and point them both through
burp and you can use the button down
here to grab the cookies so you feed of
the cookies of the user that you want it
to make the request uh right and then
you just go and browse then in the using
the browser of the admin or the other
user and so you can see the the buttons
red once you're ready once you have it
all set up you just click the button
turns it on and then you start browsing
and here's what you get is side by side
comparison of every request that you've
made using two actually
there so that's the length that they get
so it just does a comparison and you can
see here where it starts to to highlight
its it says I don't know if you can read
it but it says authorize authorization
bypass so you can see this first one
here the original session had a length
of 690 the second one had an accession
of 679 the United said 8 828 so it's got
it's got a little bit of variable so
that one may or may not be a false false
positive but if you start to look down
here at the bottom don't start to line
up and actually in this engagement I
took this from was against a medical
records application and I he was using
this and found where they go and
generate reports and so the requests I'm
making here I blacked out sorry you
can't see him the requests are hitting
this this reporting engine and it spits
out a PDF and what I found using this
pretty pretty quickly was a whole whole
bunch of medical records that you know
the the first user should see they're an
admin and they they can see they can get
to everywhere the the second user
absolutely should not be able to see
that I'm talking you know 50,000 plus
this is a staging environment and they
had 50,000 records or so second user
shouldnt have been able to see any of
that except their own it can see all of
them what was really interesting though
is you know us down there
anonymously if i know the URL and i can
i can find that you know how its
spitting out reports they were all just
named by a six digit number so
anonymously i can find that and oh hey
now i can just start iterating through
and i just found all the medical records
in this application anonymously
so pros just mentioned it's it's really
nice to quickly test large portions of
the application for those types of of
authorization issues really easy to spot
the differences from that screenshot you
saw
it'll you know highlight it for you and
authorization bypass so it's really easy
to spot it's really nice to be able to
do the anonymous testing at the same
time I did not in that application even
remotely expect that that the anonymous
would work obviously as something as a
tester you always want to test anyway
but it gives you the opportunity then to
test not only for the escalations but
the anonymous portion as well so you're
kind of kind of you know doing two birds
with one stone at that point and then
the cons I you know I pointed out that
one it was within its margin of error or
the difference that it was looking for
in the request so the first one wasn't
wasn't a a true detection it was just
close enough that it detected and said
hey authorization bypass actually wasn't
so you do have some false positives that
you want to go through and make sure
that you verify that that it is that is
a real detection so another specific
tasks session timeout tests so this
plug-in will allow you to just do
exactly what it's what it's telling you
is test for session timeout some
applications you know fall out a PCI
that it has specific rules for win
sessions timeout and things like that so
in some cases knowing you know down to
the minute when it's timing out and
things for you know compliance reasons
is is important so what you can do is
you basically just feed it a string to
look for that says hey your session time
don't you know however the application
lets you know your session timed out
some will say your session timed out
some old redirect you to the login
screen you know things like that so what
I typically do with this is as I'm
testing I'll leave a session open over
lunch or something come back and see how
it responded to being locked out or
timed out and then later on you know
later that day or maybe even on that
lunch the next day I'll use this plugin
so here's a look at it so top lemare
string to match so in this case really
simple example your sessions time bill I
want to report when it finds that and
then the next two are you know I don't I
don't want it to obviously send a
request to every minute and then
increment at two minutes things like
that it'll take forever so you're
setting here I want it to start at
fifteen minutes it'll send it'll send a
request and see if it's timed out and
down there the interval then is do you
want it to check every minute at that
point do you want to so gets to fifteen
minutes it sends a request waits sixteen
minutes and it'll send a request away 17
minutes and send a request and see if
it's timed out that way so down below
then I I didn't have I didn't grab a
screenshot when I was using this you
know you know real session so it's just
a really quick test I tells you down
there that's complete knows no timeout
detected obviously if it's in a real
scenario you know at times I'll tell hey
timed out here's the here's the time
length it when it timed out so pros it's
easy to test when you're when you're
doing something else doing lunch you
know things like that you're still
getting something done there and testing
cons don't forget to click start before
you walk away I've done that on more
than one occasion and it's frustrating
alright so the next one is called
parameter and this is this is an
interesting one because it'll basically
look across all the parameters that are
in scope so you know you go to your
target an application you put it in
scope
it'll analyze all those parameters for
you and give you a really nice little
overview of all the parameters that
found and an example value of here's
here's what was in it and it will even
do a little bit of analysis for you and
say hey this looks like it was a base64
encoded value or this is just an ASCII
string or this is
Skol you you know that's things like
that and I like to use it not not just
for the analysis portion of it I like to
use it as a list of okay here's my
parameters did I make sure I went in and
manually tested each one of these that I
thought fuzz every single one of these
so there's a look at it
so in this case you can see up here
where you know if you say things like
that you don't want to analyze so this
is that's those are set by default so if
you use you know looking at you have a
ton of you state it doesn't analyze
things like that and you can add to that
as well but then the the middle section
here you can see where I keep walking
across the different columns their
format so you know first one it only saw
it in numeric format it's just just
integers next one you know 69% of the
time it was a word things like that it
also tells you was it reflected was it
decodable so it all tries hey I saw his
basics for encoded to be able to decode
it sure things like that and then the
final over here is here's an example
value of one of the ones I saw so if you
want to really dial in on one of these
so the one I have highlighted here is
just D units you can see that's what the
example is down below and showing you
values and you can look and see all the
different unique values for it as well
so not just the example one that it has
a top here's all the unique values that
it found as well so you can if you you
know you find something interesting with
this this particular parameter you can
go through and look at all the unique
values that this that the tool pulled
out for you and then over here you got
that you're you know you're familiar
requests and response tabs to look at in
the button in the middle there's kind of
nice you can highlight the value then
and go find it in
in your proxy history as well all right
so we just covered a lot of plugins in
in the store that are you know free and
available to use at this point does
anybody have any questions I do I really
considered putting in this I just at
this point I had so many plugins and I
wasn't really sure I'd be doing for time
so yeah I did co2 is another great one I
could you know I could talk up here for
another hour on plugins I like to use
yeah it's so versatile yeah yep so the
plugins she mentioned is co2 and it yeah
it does so many different things like I
can't even go through all of them and
top my head here but go ahead some of
them do some of them you need the
professional Edition when you go into
the store it will tell you whether or
not it requires professional you know
I'm not sure that none of the plugins
that I know of in the store are paid so
I don't I don't know where the
distinction is of hey this one can be
using the free and this one can be use
in professional yeah and that would make
that make sense
yeah so if you're talking specifically
about the boners plug-in through some
volt scanners gonna be way better this
is just hey I saw this come across and I
happen to know there's CDs for it
I guess it depends on your goals if if
you have the opportunity to use the
traditional Bowlin scanner you'll get
better results with it for sure so yeah
if you have the opportunity I would
still I would still go that route Nick
personally no I haven't I do you know I
have seen there's plugins that are made
available outside of the store so I mean
just like anything else let's say you
use caution just like you know loading
an unknown Metasploit module or anything
like that you know it hope you trust the
the person that's providing it but no I
haven't seen an actual malicious one
myself personally have you just curious
any other questions all right so we've
got about 15 minutes left I just want to
move into writing your own plugins
because every now and then you know the
need arises for having your own
customized plugin having the flexibility
of being able to write your own is
absolutely you know just awesome and and
a huge time saver so if you didn't know
burp exposes an API it's got some
documentation that we'll look at in a
little bit
it supports Java so burp itself is
written in Java you can do plugins in
Java because that's native to it
you can do python using jython which is
just an interpreter that takes your
Python code and translates it into Java
bytecode or I can use JRuby which is
similar the example I want to walk
through I I'm you know I'm not a Java
developer by any means I can kind of fit
on my way through it I use Python quite
a bit though so our example is gonna use
Python so here's a really quick look at
setting up the environment for that up
top here is if you're writing in Java
you can point it at a location of
different jar files that you need loaded
with it and really similar Python will
do the same where that second optional
optional input here is here's modules
that may or may not be available to burp
as we're running so you can include them
into a directory and say hey as you're
running my plugin here's the other
modules you'll need but the really
important thing is that first part there
you need to have installed - for this to
work obviously and this is just telling
it hey here's here's where that Jai
thought interpreter is so that's that's
that's what my the value is there is the
interpreter installed in my laptop here
yep that's a that's a great point some
of the ones in the store are also
written in Python or Ruby and you have
to to get those to work properly you
would also have to set those so I
mentioned some of the documentation
here's a quick look when you're in the
extender tab and it's it's got some
documentation that you can look through
then as you're developing if you need a
reference you know it's just right there
in the API or in the documentation here
so the examples that I'm gonna walk
through in just a little bit it's using
PyCharm Community Edition if anybody's
interested in what what those are and
you can see an example down here when
you can't really see the interface or
anything but that's what the screenshots
are using and then the example plugin
I'm going to talk about is it's going to
be it's gonna have a GUI tab and it's a
token generator so this one in
particular was for a target where we
were testing an API and you had to have
a specific token in the header and it
was time-based so it'd be good for 15
minutes and then you have to regenerate
and plug all those in well that really
sucks when you got a really long running
you know intruder session or something
like that uh the might may possibly go
over for games or even scan or two that
might go over that time limit and all of
a sudden it stops working
so what we wanted to do is take take the
plug-in and take the request and just
Auto generate these for us and just plug
them in so that's what this is and I
included some of the code here so you
kind of see what it is
the main thing being it's looking for a
public key a pipe a time stamp a pipe
and then a hash value so that's that's
basically what we're gonna write here so
up top for the imports so I mentioned
this is a Python specific IDE that is
using so you can see up here you know
the squiggly lines it's complaining
saying I have no idea what that is
that's an unresolved reference that's
just because obviously it doesn't know
about the modules and burp and things
like that some of the
the standard Python line race you can
see some of the job ID burp stuff though
it doesn't know about
so it's complaining saying hey I've no
no idea about these that's okay
because once once JA it's running within
the the burp environment those things
are available to it just the ID itself
just doesn't know so we have to start
out with extending the or creating the
burp extender class and so this is all I
mean fairly easy to walk through so
we're creating a class we're giving it
the different things so I've herb
extender is required some of the others
are optional so we're creating a GUI for
this so I tab is that GUI tab that we're
going to create and things like that I
the HTTP listener is it gives us access
sent to the requests and things through
burp and then you can see we're
registering callbacks callbacks is
something that Bert makes available for
really common functions that you're
going to want to do that makes you know
really easy for you then and we'll get a
we'll get a look at some of those in
just a bit or actually there's an
example here at the bottom that
extension name is one of the callbacks
so I just gave it a generic name of API
token gen so this part is building the
GUI now I mentioned that you know I
don't do a ton with Java and I certainly
don't build gooeys so this part was a
little bit clunky to me at first but
basically what we're doing is we're
setting up different panels and once we
get into the GUI portion you'll see
we're setting up panels we're defining
all those things I need to feed it a
public key and a private key so you can
see things like that so that's what this
all this is here so we're gonna put in a
Save button I don't want to put those in
every time I'm running you know if I
shut down burp and I come back the next
day I don't have to put those back in
every time so create a button it's gonna
save the the values that we enter
and then all the all the panels and
things that we've defined and this is
just bringing all of it back together
now so we're actually building some of
the rows defining those us we're
defining panels and things that all
these different GUI aspects live under
once we have the UI set up so this is
just a little bit of extra components of
the of the tab so we're looking
specifically at the GUI tab that we're
going to create now is gonna be in Bert
so caption token generator doing
component and we're looking at the main
panel so once we click on that tab
that's what we want to see is that main
panel so this one this is the part
that's actually doing the work that of
finding where we want to put our token
into our response or request I'm sorry
it's going to find where we want it so I
mentioned an API so it's all XML based
there was a note in the XML where we
want to feed that so what this is doing
then is is taking the same process HTTP
message so we can use that and say you
know I only want this to work on the
intruder portion or scanner or whatever
in this case it's going across to all of
us we didn't actually use it the next
part is messages requests so we we want
to act on the requests we don't
obviously need to inject anything to the
response that does make any sense
so we're looking at message is requests
and then that last one there is passing
in the actual message information and in
the first if there's is that logic then
of if it's not a request
just passed on we don't need to process
it any further in our plugin
so the block down there then is we have
that request available to us and we want
to pick apart interesting things then
like the first line there is getting the
request the second line is is looking at
bytes and then you can see it's getting
the body offset so we specifically want
to process the the body portion so we're
getting the offset so we can use that
later and then when once you see tree
that's that's a Python library then
that's going to actually process the XML
for us and what we specifically wanted
to find is so what we're telling it is
this is you know once we generate the
token here's what we're gonna plug it in
essentially and then once we do that
create a new body so we've plugged in
we're creating then a new body that
we're gonna replace that original
request with with this new one with our
token in it so we we'd already defined
the button and everything before all
that this is actually the the logic
behind that so basically the button was
there to say once I am i plug in my
public and private keys and click Save
it's going to save it that way I don't
have to put them in every single time so
this is at the end of the script here
then and you already saw this is what's
actually generating the token so it's
that the public key pipe timestamp thing
that we already looked at this is the
actual logic to compute that using a
fresh timestamp and so we have a actual
valid value then based on the public or
the private key so that we're
essentially authenticated then once we
have
because we've shown that hey we have
access to the private key so down there
it's just returning that token into that
into the function before what was
finding that portion in the XML plugging
that in creates our new body and that's
what burp then sends onto the
application so then each request we
don't have to generate that it just
automatically does it so the results
then here's the GUI all the different
portions so we talked about the
different rows and the main panel and
all that all that was to basically get
two input boxes in a button here but
essentially it's I plug in that public
key private key say that and now I can
do all my testing all that's just done
automatically for me then I don't have
to worry about generating tokens as we
go so that's the that's the DIY portion
is anybody have any additional questions
around that all right well thank you
very much oh we got one
yeah that's a great point if you can't
do bug it because the the IDE doesn't
know about those thing it'll just crash
right away and say hey I can't import
this so the way you end up debugging
that is by importing it into burp and
looking at errors if it's painful it is
painful I don't know of a better way to
do it at this point
Java I'm sure it probably would be I
honestly just don't have enough
experience with it to to give you a good
answer there but yeah Python it's a
little bit of a pain it's it's kind of
painful too yeah yeah it is
that's a great question one great point
any other questions
all right well thank you everybody
really appreciate it
[Applause]