all right good morning everyone my name
is Brad Duncan I worked for Palo Alto
Networks unit 42 and I'm here to talk to
you about malware distribution trends a
little about myself I've run the for
those that don't know I run the malware
traffic analysis dotnet web site plenty
of examples of infection traffic from
malware and actual malware samples if
you're actually going to get copies of
the malware from the site beware this is
live stuff and you don't want to
accidentally detonate it on some windows
host that you're using and I also tweet
quite frequently at malware underscore
traffic usually just the stuff that I'm
posting on the blog
occasionally I'll tweet about something
like b-sides I were going on today and
then every once in a while just some
really off-the-wall joke that makes you
think I'm socially retarded disclaimer
on this I run into a lot of commodity
malware stuff that's not apt stuff
that's not specifically targeted that's
kind of a different era area that we're
looking at here what I'm discussing is
the stuff that is mass distribution the
stuff that goes out indiscriminately
that's not really necessarily targeted
that's weird okay that's not necessarily
targeted but you could very well get it
if we're talking malicious spam a lot of
this stuff gets hit by your you know
through the spam filters which we'll
never see it now the spam filters are
definitely a good way to get malware
samples that would otherwise hit your
organization and if you've got access to
that if you actually work a security job
where you have access to emails and the
spam q check through it you might be
surprised there there's some good stuff
through there but the stuff I'm going to
talk about hopefully all
limited to early April 2018 so hopefully
it's timely things can and do quickly
change for example two months ago at
besides Tampa I gave a talk on how
ransomware was really on the on the
downturn there was a serious and there
still kind of is a serious lower levels
of ransomware at that time this year
then there was a time before then it was
like it couldn't get away from
ransomware but now as we go into April
I'm seeing a lot more ransomware than I
was seeing in January of this year so
things can and they do quickly change
and personal bias like I said I tend to
look at the commodity stuff and they're
definitely that's only part of the
picture when you're talking about a
specific malware threat to your to
yourself or your organization so for
today's talk we're going to look at the
types of malware distribution methods
I'm gonna go over tech support scams
briefly those fake antivirus alerts that
come up through your web browser because
we're seeing a lot more of those now
than we did about a year ago and
prevention strategies what you guys can
do to help prevent getting caught by
malware so in wide scale distribution we
most often find information stealers and
back doors
the sneaky malware that you don't know
is running on your computer malware
downloaders that can download any one of
those types of malware x' cryptocurrency
miners are a big thing that has really
taken off in the past few months and
ransomware so what do you guys think
it's the most press coverage out of all
those four categories that I have up
there yeah now if I had a explosion
sound effect they put it there with this
particular graphic because ransomware is
a very relatable story on a human level
you've got stuff and some criminals are
holding it for ransom that that speaks
to everybody however it tends to
the very nature of news stories you want
to get a hook to grab somebody's
attention right so you're going to kind
of play it to try and hook a readers
interest and so my personal opinion is
that we tend to play up ransomware in
the open media a lot more than it is you
know as far as the thread is concerned
there are other things out there that
you should also be worried about but the
press generally tends to focus on
ransomware because it's a good story
well we all know about ransomware I
think by this point everybody knows what
ransomware is you you know get it
through your browsing the web or you get
an email and you're a faceless white
couple with a computer and you have to
pay money to a faceless criminal that is
for some reason still wearing a mask so
it's it's a fairly standard I think we
all know what ransomware is by now so
we've seen a lot of high profile stories
in the past couple of years the most
recent one was in March the city of
Atlanta got hit by ransomware
they didn't specify what type it was I
think they're they think it's Sam Sam or
Sam so ransomware and just earlier this
week one of the reporters at WS TB TV
and it w SB TV in Atlanta reported that
they shelled out nearly 2.7 million
dollars as a way to you know following
the ransomware incident that probably
has a lot more to deal with than just
the ransomware I'm sure there was some
endemic system problems in the city of
Atlanta and you know it's a good number
to throw out there once again it's a
hook to catch your interest if you
actually look at the details how much of
that is specifically going to the
ransomware case it's a good question the
Department of Health and Human Services
so far this year at least eight cyber
attacks employing Sam Sam or Sam so
ransom
they reported that have targeted
healthcare and government organizations
in this case it really is targeted
because with Sam Sam or Sampson
ransomware your point of entry as a
server so you're trying to find a
vulnerable server that you can exploit
through automation so if you have a
server exposed to the internet and
you're not fully patched or fully
up-to-date there's a vulnerability you
can you can imagine that it will sooner
or later be exploited and if you're the
city of Atlanta or one of the other
organizations commercial or government
that have been hit in the past few years
by ransomware it is because generally
because you didn't have your servers
fully patched and up to date
now bitcoin is the general payment that
we have that we see for ransomware and
if you look at the price in 2017 there
were some wild fluctuations for longest
time Bitcoin was generally lower than
$1,000 per per Bitcoin the exchange rate
and as the year went on the last few
months of last year it really shot up it
was very volatile the prices so that is
probably one of the reasons that we saw
a decline in ransomware there just was
no stability and saying okay send me
this amount of Bitcoin because a day or
two later the Bitcoin value will have
fluctuated so rapidly that you're either
getting far less than you originally
asked for or far more depending on the
day
fortunately since as we've gone into
2018 it's kind of stabilized and it was
funny when I see that you know reports
of Bitcoin that has dropped to like six
thousand dollars for US dollars per
Bitcoin they say it's a crash I'm
thinking for the longest time
Bitcoin wasn't even approaching that
level yes sir and so it's correct the
question here was when I was talking
mentioned earlier about servers exposed
to the Internet which a that it's not
necessarily spearfishing that it's not
necessarily some of the other methods
that these organizations that we hear
about that have gotten infected with
ransomware and I said generally for the
most part that's not to say that that
that that is the only vector and I'll
get into that here in a few minutes so
it's just that and it's not something I
go into the great detail here because I
don't have examples of that if you're an
organization and you have a server that
gets compromised you're you're generally
not going to share all that infirmity
tales on how it got compromised out with
the general public so it's a it really
is kind of hard to get more detailed
information on that I can tell you about
you know spear fishing or just fishing
in general you can get examples of that
fairly easily one of the types of
malware that propagates that will that
we'll see a lot of we first saw this
happen last year in the spring or summer
was when wanna cry or when a krypter
came out and it's has been reported as
spreading during via SMB the SMB
protocol Microsoft's SMB protocol
through what is called the eternal blue
exploit which is when the hacking team
was a hacked one of their
I'm sorry not the acting team it's I
believe the NSA exploit right so somehow
the criminals had gotten a hold of that
and we're we're able to implement it
into this ransomware now the interesting
thing about one a cry is while it was
big news last year when we first saw it
we're definitely still seeing samples of
that on a daily basis so as a researcher
of Palo Alto Networks I've got access to
virustotal intelligence which apparently
if your your company is not paying for
it is very expensive so I'm fortunate
enough to look through that and I can
actually search through there on
anything with want to cry in the
description or the virustotal detections
on the antivirus vendors and anything
that is first seen since April first so
when I look through that seam they
stopped counting at a thousand so more
than a thousand samples new file hashes
that have come through here I'm not sure
what's been tweaked but we're seeing
stuff that is at least identified by
some of the antivirus vendors as one a
cry and just looking at the general size
and the types of files it seems to fall
in line with what I've seen before now
also as a my employer has to call
autofocus and as a security researcher I
got access to that and I can look at the
same thing in this case I'm looking at
anything that we have tagged as some
sort of ransomware and I'm pulling for
anything that was first seen after April
1st at 12 a.m. 26,000 samples that we're
seeing of ransomware so it is really a
lot more now than we saw back in January
which is I think less than half that so
the samples that are tagged want to cry
of one equipped er that we have
identified a Palo Alto Networks 2500 and
then again crab honeybee how many people
have not heard of gang crap at this
point
and I'll go through that here
momentarily and then Gann crab is a new
family of ransomware that started
appearing back in January but the
majority of ransomware samples not the
vast majority but just the majority over
half of that is one a Corrupter Organa
crab now gand crab is interesting again
crab when it encrypts your files
it adds dot crab is a file extension and
gand is slang in India for but I believe
so I tend to refer it personally as but
crab ransomware but everybody else calls
at gain crab but so you infect a host
which I did on Thursday evening and all
the encrypted files are appended with
dot crab it throws up the decryption
instructions and it throws up a window
to tor so you can download the tor
browser because everything if you had
the tor browser installed it it sitting
on your desktop it was encrypted
so $1,500 us and the interesting thing
about gain crab when it asks for that
money is that it asks you to pay for it
in a cryptocurrency called - now - is
and that was a big news when it came out
it was like okay there's a big move away
from Bitcoin everybody's moving to - now
you know there was one only one family
of ransomware to my knowledge that uses
- specifically as a crypto currency for
your ransom payment and so three hundred
and fifty dollars for one - and one
thousand five hundred dollars now you
can still pay in Bitcoin all right
you can pay in Bitcoin but you've got a
15% service charge
so you're paying what is it
1,650 dollars
I'm sorry that's 10% but anyway you're
paying about $1,700 or so so ultimately
ransomware is still out there and it is
doing a little bit of an uptick since I
saw this law back in December in January
an interesting thing here is yesterday
yesterday afternoon this week and
ransomware was reporting about a
ransomware called thug B or pub G made
you play players on a non-magical
battleground in order to decrypt your
files it's a joke a joke ransomware I
always find those interesting but even
with the media attention on ransomware
we still see the vast majority of stuff
that we run across is not ransomware is
information stealers is malware
downloaders and cryptocurrency miners
which were largely reported the
beginning of the year and now our fairly
commonplace we still see them
I generally don't run into them much on
the mass distribution side on the stuff
that I end up looking at but how does
malware get from the criminal to us
email the web social media and attackers
breach networks or servers and drop the
malware I'm not going to talk about that
fourth one because as I explained
earlier I generally don't have any of
the technical details of the information
on that stuff
social media I've got a story that I'll
share with you but mostly we're we're
looking at email in the web for mass
distribution of malware not apt style
attacks and email is the most common
method hands down that criminals used to
distribute malware by volume it doesn't
mean that the email actually makes it to
the intended recipients but for example
how many people for like their Gmail or
Yahoo or whatever you use and do you get
the pill spam you know viagra cialis for
some reason that stuff just gets to you
that just means that your email is on a
list all right your email is on the list
and it gets spread around and so if your
email is on a list and it's spread
around to the pharmaceutical spammers it
could very well end up in the hands of
people that are actually trying to send
malware out there if you got a gmail
account you will probably probably not
see any actual or malware because they
generally have a good way of a good
method of filtering filtering for
malware we got Yahoo maybe a little less
so we got AOL god help you so these
emails contain archives with malware
executables which is very common and
very easily blocked microsoft office
documents Word PowerPoint Excel
rich text files that exploit Microsoft
Office is a big thing that we started
seeing a couple years back and a
significant percentage not a definitely
not of majority by far but a significant
percentage of the stuff that I see out
there is some type of RTF attachment to
emails or a link to an RTF document that
will exploit a vulnerability in
Microsoft Office normally these have
been patched
why don't you know for months but these
guys are still sending out these emails
in the hopes of capturing some unpatched
Windows XP machine or something another
favorite is archives with any of those
file types so for example Java archives
so you've got a jar file and you
double-click it and it does its thing
it's backdoors your computer using Java
and then there are just as often links
to malware
right so you got to you know show an
example here but you you have an email
that says you know look at this invoice
click here you go there and download the
file and then you open it and it's a
it's a decoy and you're infected so my
favorite one of the link type malware's
is campaigns mal spam campaigns is
what's called hinder or channet ur or
portal this is a malware that uses
macros in a Word document to infect your
computer and macros is pretty common
because you're you're trusting the user
to a average users inclination to click
through warnings to get to what they
want to see I'm not talking about
anybody here in this room or hopefully
anybody watching the video here I'm
talking about the general user and I
think we all know a few of them and have
run into a I had one guy tell me you
know me I'm a clicker guy but so this
was back on Wednesday of this previous
week from the Hanson or campaign you got
a link and there are a number of domains
that they'll have there and so you got
in this case one six six four six comm
question mark there's a string of
characters equals another string of
characters and that second string of
characters is it represents it an
encoding that I haven't figured out yet
and nobody I've talked to is quite
figured out yet is encoding it
represents the recipient's email address
so if you click on that link the server
that sends you the mount where it also
records okay this is the email address
of whoever you know click that link so
they're actually keeping track of who
downloads there there
we're but
yeah you you click on the link and says
hey here's your invoice and there's a
number of templates that they'll use in
these documents that basically tell you
hey in order to view the content you
know enable macros and here's how you do
it because by default Microsoft Office
will not enable macros however you know
certain people organisations may have
disabled that in which case these
directions are pretty much meaningless
but for most people you'll see some sort
of of message that says hey enable your
macros and see the content and of course
you don't see the content you don't see
it at all it just has the same messaging
you figure well ok I'll close it but
you're getting infected behind the
scenes the old macros have been disabled
and every once in a while you'll get
you'll get a link or you'll get an
attachment that says it's a document
it's actually a rich text file with some
support code and usually these are
exploiting things that have already been
patched with Microsoft Office so for
example if you're running Windows 10 and
you got a good set up to where you know
you're getting those patches whether you
want them or not with Windows 10 you're
getting patched for Microsoft Office and
the various operating system components
that they've found vulnerabilities and
but these are the general CBE's that I'm
seeing for the vulnerabilities that are
being exploited by these Word documents
at least according to virustotal when
they tag them there's a what is it the
Microsoft equation editor vulnerability
that's a 20-18 CVE but I always forget
what that is because people don't call
it by the CVE they called the equation
editor vulnerability
be consistent for crying out loud
here's another one from earlier this
week this one I believe is Brazilian
mouth spam and so it has a zip archive
attachment and that zip archive
attachment is whatsapp except the
misspelled what's app if you notice
right there so you know that generally
is a red flag if you will another red
flag when you open that archive open
that zip file you get something that's
not VBS now what is the default setting
for file extensions for windows yeah you
hide them so at best people are going to
see in the default configuration that
are going to see dot PDF and they'll
think even though the icon is clearly
not a PDF icon they'll double click it
and if you look at the code it's highly
office gated JavaScript code and it will
download malware I forget what the case
was in this instance but I just need an
example for today's presentation on that
type of malware that type of
distribution method which I see quite
frequently I just didn't have any easy
examples from this past week however I
did find some examples of mal spam
pushing gand
crab ransomware I'm sorry this is not
gang crab this is a difference from the
knickers botnet campaign which is a very
long running campaign that uses various
methods so in this case and this way
from earlier this month the cinders were
all spoofed so after the ad sign was
your recipients email domain right so if
you're you know if this went to somebody
at Palo Alto networks and somehow made
it to the recipient it would be Emily
2018 at Palo Alto Networks
komm photo from Emily photo from Lea the
attachment names are all some sort of
supposed image and if you look at these
emails and this is common for the
nickers botnet is they will have a very
standard template or in this case no
matches message text at all it was kind
of weird
so you open this up and you find that
it's an actual URL file now the
interesting thing about URL files if you
look at them in Microsoft Windows
it doesn't even give you the option of
looking at the file extension no matter
what your settings are you're not seeing
that dot URL you're just seeing that Sh
20:18 no 404 or BBD baa
so the certainly the average person who
is looking at this on Microsoft Windows
is not going to see the the code inside
and not going to understand that this is
actually a URL that will point to
somewhere on the internet now if you
look here the URL is not HTTP for web
traffic its file colon backslash
backslash so what protocol is that SMB
you're right what port 445 TCP port 445
so that is generally what you're going
to see and the interesting thing about
this is I checked on Thursday night when
I was putting the finishing touches on
this show and I went in Windows host in
my lab environment I was able to find
those VBS files sitting on the server 60
of them 60 of them in that directory in
the stream directory there's another one
on the server and if you guys are
curious you could if you've got a
Windows host you want to check it out
yeah you can find 60 examples of malware
probably right now as I'm speaking if
you're watching the video probably
hopefully it'll be offline
that so I went through and most of the
follow-up domains because basically
you've got that URL file it's pulling
the VBS file from a server over SMB and
then you run that VBS file and it will
again grab through HTTP the actual
malware binary so I checked a few of
them out on Thursday night and you know
no luck no luck no like wait here's one
and so taxi heavy Cu is a site that's a
legitimate but compromised from what I
can tell and it was hosting malware as
of Thursday evening when I checked so I
think if anybody wants to grab a copy of
the malware you might still be able to
do it by using that URL so I ran this in
my test environment I got a post
infection traffic ninety two point fifty
three point seventy seven point one
eighty four port 80 HTTP post infection
traffic - RORO double dot I am and the
characteristics of this traffic were
matched Quandt loader which is what the
nickers botnet was pushing now Quandt
loader is just a malware downloader
backdoors into your computer and will
download some additional mat work and
know it's a couple letters changed it's
not quite loaded it's squanch loader at
least that's what they call it on planet
squanch ultimately there are many
different files types of files used by
criminals to install malware and
malicious spam with links is harder to
to catch by intrusion detection systems
across the board at least that's been my
experience it's a lot easier if you got
that malware in the email you can
generally block it if you just got a
link to something it's a little
harder and sometimes that will slip past
systems and some types of malware have
defense systems that will act
differently if you're analyzing so if it
knows it's being analyzed now I've been
tricked by this before because
especially if I'm on the road I'll
generally use my laptop and one of my
environments is VMware and I run one
time but got caught by the malware is
called be tip which I don't see anymore
but I was seeing a lot last year and it
actually acted differently in most cases
the malware just won't run if it detects
it's being analyzed but in some cases
like in the case of B DEP last year I
was getting completely different traffic
so it really threw me off so you got to
be careful of that distribution through
social media how many people here do not
have any sort of social media account
whoo one two three
Lord you guys had the outliers it is
social media generally like email you'll
generally see what's called what I tend
to think of as mass distribution but
well with a lot of social media
platforms you got to somehow connect
with somebody you can't just spam stuff
out there like you can through email
right so in the case of Skype you have
to be connected to somebody on skype
before they can send you something
that's a link to malware in which case
it's pretty common
it generally tends to be female names
I'm sure the criminals are not female or
they could be I don't want to be sexist
but you'll get something usually
something like hey here's a picture of
me I do I
okay or I just got a new hairdo or or
something that is just so vastly
stereotypical baiting to click a link
you know for for some lonely lonely guy
I guess
and nope I'm sorry that wasn't mine my
bad
so in this case once again the default
for Windows is to hide the file
extensions so you're not going to see
that SCR which is a screen saver which
basically is just another executable
right and this isn't even a screensaver
this is a this is just a executable file
with the dot SCR file extension that's
hidden on the default settings and
windows so you double collect that what
we're saying where's my picture how am I
gonna know if her hairstyle is better or
not I don't even know the woman she just
friended me an hour ago but with social
media because you've got to connect with
people somehow generally social media
tends to be a little more targeted than
regular mass distribution methods and so
I've got a interesting story about this
back in 2016 in August 2016 when we were
seeing a lot of ransomware there was a
lot of news coverage that was just
annoying me and served to your point
earlier there was some hospitals that
got hit by I think it was lucky
ransomware
and which is doesn't is isn't in the
scene now but that is generally spread
through emails and I believe in one
article they had mentioned something
like a spray-and-pray attack right well
they sprayed out there and I'm thinking
it's not an attack right you've got you
got hit with ransomware because you were
unaware enough to to double click on a
link it was something that you did it's
not something that the criminal did any
differently it's something that you did
different well you did unknowingly
unaware so I was saying stop calling it
ransomware attack start calling it
an incident because in cybersecurity in
this field the word incident has serious
connotations however for a lot of people
that think an incident it's just
something that happens so I got a lot of
blowback from this I got a lot of
comments and one of the comments was
from somebody that tagged themselves as
Sarah the enthusiast who wrote a very
well reasoned response that I thought
and said that that and you know this is
the Internet so I don't know if this
person is actually named Sarah or not
but he or she or he whoever it is said
that I think this type of malware is
becoming so increasingly popular that
even the careful list careful Internet
users can be tricked into downloading
and opening a link so this person was
the victim of a ransomware attack two
days before she or he wrote this and the
hoax was so elaborate because this
person thought there was so much trouble
that they went to to get her to download
and click this file so long the short
story is Sarah the enthusiast is a
freelance writer got contacted about a
writing assignment on freelancer comm as
part of the process connected with a
Skype account of a person that she
researched and thought okay this is
legitimate Skype account and it was but
it was compromised it was being used by
criminal to rope in people right so
Sarah Lee enthusiast is thinking oh
that's a lot of effort to get me to
click on something but I'm sure the
person who had compromised this Skype
account was trying to fool more than one
person right so as part of the process
Sarah the enthusiast gets a bunch of
files PDF files company guidelines the
the writing assignment guidelines and
something that's an exe file
now Sara's no dummy so Sara actually not
realizing that the Skype account was
compromised contacts the Skype account
and says hey I see this is a malware I'm
sorry this isn't executable
this is kind of weird you're not trying
to infect me are you haha and of course
the criminal behind the Skype account
said hey this is just part of a new new
format that we're using and so Sara the
enthusiasts double clicked on that
executable and got infected with
ransomware and I say this luckily got
infected with ransomware because it
could be far worse could be an
information steal it could be a banking
Trojan which in my personal opinion is
worse because they're able to steal all
your passwords if this is a
straightforward ransom or all they're
doing is encrypting files on your
machine however you do have to make the
assumption that oh they're probably if
they infected my machine they could very
well have taken my passwords and login
account credentials but I'd like to
share that story because how many of us
in this room think that you know it'd
just be too much trouble for somebody to
target us in that fashion now
understanding it's not really
necessarily targeting but going through
a bunch of work to get us to click
double click in a Windows environment on
an executable file we probably don't
think we're that important but we don't
have to be as long as you can scale your
operations up any one of us can be a
target of those criminals as long as
they can scale their operations up so
for distributing malware through the web
there are generally two types of methods
there are the unexpected webpages or
pop-up windows all right in that case
you actually have to do something to to
click or install something to be
infected and then there are exploit kits
which are I gave a talk about exploit
kits
here besides Iowa last year and had
mentioned then they were on the wane and
that certainly has held true so here's
an example of a campaign that I had seen
and I'd documented on my blog just some
technical some peak apps and some
malware samples and malwarebytes
actually did a good write-up on this
relatively recently I forget exactly
what they called it but so in this case
you got a compromised website and there
has injected code and it redirects you
to to this fake Flash Player if you use
an Internet Explorer and of course
you'll get plenty of warnings that this
type of file is not something you want
to double-click but you know me I'm a
clicker you look at the code of the file
that you download it's highly obfuscated
javascript in this case run by Windows
scripting host and it's designed to
check your computer and I never was able
to infect a host in a virtual
environment with this I actually had to
go through a physical environment
because it had some checks that were
making sure that whoever double-click
that file was not was not in a virtual
environment if you're running Chrome
you'll actually from the hitting the
same website and going through the same
process you won't have flash because
Crump doesn't use flash so you get the
same same type of file different file
name using Firefox says hey you're using
an older version of Firefox even though
I wasn't and then it tells it gives you
the same type of file now when I first
tried this out all of those file names
are the same exact file hash however
about a couple weeks later when I
checked it again they were all different
file hashes slightly different and it is
relatively easy for
criminals when they're doing stuff when
they're compiling their malware it's
easy to kind of put a little bit of
randomize the process just enough to add
a couple spaces here a couple of
characters there and make your file hash
different which is why earlier when I
was saying that Palo Alto Networks on
that query that I didn't know my company
tool though I saw 26 thousand more than
26 thousand samples of ransomware you
know that just means 26 thousand
different file hashes a lot of those
were pretty much the same thing just
every single time you downloaded it it
was a new file hash but it did the same
exact thing but exploit kids which once
again I did talk about here last year is
a way to infect your computer behind the
scenes so basically you're just doing
regular web browsing and you hit a in
most cases nowadays that's ad traffic
some banner ad has some injected code it
directs you to a to a exploit kit server
behind the scene and it will send code
it will check to see if your browser
based components are invulnerable and
infect your computer here is a my
standard definition for excellent kids
the web servers that use exploits to
take vulnerabilities and browser based
applications right so it has to be a
browser-based application so if you're
using Java if you're using flash if you
use an Internet Explorer does anybody
still using Internet Explorer
I'm not saying it doesn't happen is
anybody by choice using internet but so
interestingly enough Java and PDF those
are big
2010 called they want their exploits
back and you just don't see this stuff
as much anymore Flash Player is
generally the only Flash Player and
Internet Explorer are the two that
generally get exploited by what remains
in the exploit kids scene and this is
literally what you're talking about as
far as the infection chain you've got a
normal website this could be CNN this
could be the New York Times this could
be any high profile web site that buys
ad traffic and I should say that that
gets paid to air at traffic and then the
banner ads which are not as as
thoroughly vetted as content on the site
itself actually has the stuff you'll
have a gate it's just another server
that kind of keeps an eye on things and
you know tries to make sure that you're
not coming from the same ip address
multiple times you know your security
researcher or something like that it's a
good way to avoid it but exploit kids
are really on the wane so when I talked
about it in April of last year we had
seen markedly lower levels than the year
before and now it's probably about a
tenth of that now now I have never been
able to use any of the current exploit
kits to infect a Windows 10 host even
even running Internet Explorer which you
can do on Windows 10 Microsoft edge and
I know it can be done I know it has been
done I just personally haven't been able
to do it and good guide Chrome it's they
really keep on top of things as far as
making sure that exploit kits tile
infections where it's happening behind
the scenes without your knowledge is not
happening right --chrome will still
happily let you you know pop up those
windows and say hey install this Chrome
update because your Chrome is out of
date but X what kits are because of that
you know many people use groan and yeah
that sort of stuff is on the wane so in
addition to malware what some criminals
have done is instead of directing you to
download and install a fake flash update
or something they'll say hey you've got
your computer is infected so while you
you get on one of these and it happens
the same way it's the same chain instead
of going to an exploit kit you're
basically going to a page that has this
faked update and you can't close your
browser unless you go your task manager
and you kill that particular process so
it's easy enough to get out of there
every once in a while my wife will run
across these I'm like you got to stop
browsing to these to these gambling
sites
she doesn't gamble I'm just kidding
honey so that I'm sorry you know this
this is in chrome right so chrome
doesn't stop this sort of stuff in
generally I say chrome doesn't stop this
sort of stuff but in my lab environment
I specifically you know change the
settings in chrome so it isn't blocking
suspicious websites so I I revised that
my environment doesn't block those so if
you go to Windows that the same thing
you get a slightly different looking
thing with Internet Explorer and you'll
get a window that pops up you'll try and
close the window and it will not close
it will just pop back up and once again
you got to go into task manager to to
kill that process if you're going at the
same website through Firefox it will
actually ask you for username and
password
I'm astounded
why would nono but anyway if anybody
feels curious enough it's not going to
hurt your computer it's just going to
lock your browser up and you'll have to
kill that process you could probably go
to this URL right now if you're curious
once again for the official record I
don't recommend it
prevention strategies how do we stop
this stuff from getting to us or for the
people that we are responsible for
protecting not really a prevention
strategy you're talking about regular
backups so if you do get hit and this
this could be ransomware but any type of
decent disaster recovery plan because
you could get hit by a tornado here in
Iowa and you can lose all your stuff if
you don't have your stuff your your
critical data backed up you'll never
recover it whether it's ransomware or
whether it's some other sort of disaster
Apache systems keep your systems patched
and up-to-date as far as the software
now this is kind of common sense and for
the home user we generally don't have to
worry about that but sometimes in an
enterprise environment you're still
forced to use Internet Explorer or you
know use a now to date version of Java
you know because a particular mission
critical application requires it
training and awareness if you don't
understand the types of threats you face
if you don't know what a phishing email
is you'll probably click on it and be
tricked so how many people have been
fished by your company to test and see
if you recognize it it's kind of common
there they're a good ways of doing it
there are bad ways the bad way is to
make you feel like an idiot if you
actually click the link and that's not
what it's all about it's about trying to
raise your awareness browsing
restrictions if you like porn if you
like online gambling you even like
illegal file sharing and you
to the internet for that stuff you're
probably going to run into some shady
websites that may direct you to malware
so if you restrict yourself from
browsing that stuff you'll be much much
better situation if you're in a company
and you've got some sort of web
filtering you would hopefully be
filtering out at least those three
categories of web traffic and then
security solutions so if you are if
you're not looking at what's happening
in your network you will never know if
you have been compromised or in some
cases when you were compromised and it's
pretty much it
we've covered the types of malware
distributional methods tech support
scams and prevention strategies and I'm
not going to waste time here with
questions however I will be around if
anybody does have any questions
afterwards I'll be more than happy to
answer them thank you very much
[Applause]