[Music]
again
is
and thank you very much you may be in
greece thank you
thank you appreciate it i gotta move the
dog out of the way for a minute let me
get to my
presentation screen it's hard to move a
200 pound dog out of the way sometimes
all right well good morning everybody um
firstly
i apologize my spanish and my
spanish especially my spanish for chile
is
a little rusty so this will be in
english so i hope that is okay
secondly every now and again you might
see a large great dane coming in about
eye level for more treats
but let's see if we can get on with the
slides and have some fun
um we're just going to talk about the
state
of the industry the state of security
we're also going to have a general
conversation about just some fun things
that we can do
in the industry as we move through the
industry as we walk through you heard
ava
talk just now about the electronic
frontier foundation
and the amazing work that they are doing
um and i
have thankfully been on the receiving
end of some of their work
i am one of those people that they have
dug out of a large hole
so without further ado
let's have a conversation so we're going
to talk about about security and we're
going to talk a little bit about the uh
the mcu so a little bit of fun with
thanos and his clicking fingers
uh but before we do that we will have a
little bit of a public service
announcement as i would like to call it
uh for those of you that were looking
for a fun light
pep talk and a hoorah for the industry
this is not going to be that talk uh you
have been warned this is going to be a
very blunt conversation
about the state of the industry what is
going on in the industry and what we
need to do about it
um so for those of you that know me my
squirrel moment is over
and we're gonna have a little bit of a
conversation with the agenda so we're
going to talk about what is going on
with the security industry
not just in north america but europe
obviously south america
and other areas around we're also going
to talk about why we need to change
how we're approaching the industry why
we need to have a different look at
things
and we'll probably break a few things
along the way and kind of go from there
uh the hairy thing that is in front of
you my beard is not as colored as it
normally is for that as i apologize
my background is obviously as a
researcher a father to both two-legged
ones i have my daughter upstairs asleep
because it is early in the morning for
here
i got the four-legged ones running
around a geek and then yes
the hacker and i wear that very very
proudly
so let's have a conversation uh let's
talk about why are we failing so
and we'll have the conversation about
why i think we're failing but if we're
failing let's talk about the humans this
is nothing to do with technology
this has got nothing to do with any of
the procedures this is about the humans
ourselves and when i talk about the
humans ourselves let's take ourselves
back to the early days when we were kids
when we had parents or guardians or
somebody was looking after us
when we first started and when we first
started not even in the industry
the first time we came into the kitchen
the parents what did they say to us they
said
don't touch the kettle it's hot don't
touch the stove it's on
and what did we do we touched it we put
our hand out
and we got burnt and then later on in
life oops i've missed the later on in
life later on in life
we did this we all thought this was a
good idea we all as
kids were like ah this will be wonderful
until we ended up
wrapping ourselves around a tree and as
adults
this is us not just us in the industry
but these are the very people that we're
trying to look at and look after
so if we think about that and then we
think about our work
on the work that we're doing this is
every single red team engagement
i've been doing this now for the best
part of 40 years minus jumping out of
airplanes for the military
and i'm not on one occasion have we been
unable to actually break into something
every single time
we can get in so this really is the
state of our industry on this one
so then we have to take a step back and
go well we've thrown technology at it
for so many years
will technology fix it and the question
on will technology fix it and here's a
little bit of the answer unfortunately
for this one
we take a look at the amount of
passwords that we have we take a look at
where we're going on passwords
and this password one two three four
five six
is still the number one password that we
deal with not only is one through six
the number password but if you decide
you fancy having a little bit of fun
with the us congress you can put all
ones into some of the user accounts to
still get in although
for those of you that are following us
politics i think it was
make america great again 2020
exclamation
got you into a bunch of the twitter
feeds and everything so
you know we as a society and we as
people are
charging down the way of technology yet
we're still facing these levels of
passwords
so welcome to information security
wonderful big gate amazing big walls and
easy ways round absolutely everything
and then for those of you that that have
a little bit of fun with some english
and british writers and some british
humor on this one
we have the conversation from douglas
adams which is any time that the
civilization gets to a point where it
has to put instructions
on the inside of toothpicks this is
where we have to have a bit of a change
and then we have to look at the very
people that we are trying to protect so
again our industry is all about
protecting people or it should be all
about protecting people
and when we have to put signs like this
up
around the zoos or around other areas
then we really have to take a step back
and go hmm
we should change our approach we should
look at doing something different
in this industry but if you
listen to the very people in our
industry everybody's charging off down
this well i've got
cyber and if you look at it from the
perspective of the attackers so the
adversaries the attackers
the the folks that are actually breaking
in and not legitimately breaking in
if you look at the how organized how
well put together they are the
technologies that they have the tools
that they have
to move the screen just a little bit so
you can actually see what's going on
just a bit
you look at the tools and the technology
that they have and the time that they
have and the patients that they have
they have as it shows a much bigger and
a much more effective toolbox
than anybody on the defensive side which
typically means from the attackers
perspective
it's easy hunting and it's easy fishing
so then you know we take a couple of
examples from this there were a number
of us that got brought into
uh beginning of this year it was a
capture the flag it was an invite only
capture the flag
and we basically were given a target it
was a fully patched windows 10
environment with endpoint detection on
it
all sorts of software and all sorts of
detection stuff on it and a whole bunch
of other things in front of
it and it was sitting on top of the
virtual machine
we knew going into it what we would be
facing how would we facing it
and as you can see you can read the
stats as well as i can once we got into
the system
it was 68 seconds to break past the
windows 10 environment bypass the
endpoint detection system and take
control of their metal
it was too easy and so that was the
state of technology then and it hasn't
really moved on from now
so then we have to go back in history
and look at how nortons cannot obviously
protect you even then
so then we look at the defensive teams
we have to take a look at where we have
been
we take a look at the the people on the
blue team side of the fence the purple
team side of the fence
and where they are today and quite
honestly it's not pretty as it says in
here
arguably less tools or even if they have
all the tools
they're not using them effectively
they're actually still some of them are
still chasing for more technology some
of them have
time to implement them properly and not
only do we have to worry about the tools
but we also have to put policies
procedures
and controls in place so we have to
justify exactly what we're doing
and then also typically we're doing with
politics we're having to worry about
various other things and often with less
resources
so um this unfortunately is where we
come to when it comes to the defensive
side of the world
now for those of you that believe your
vendors
and you believe them without questioning
the vendor apparently keeps telling us
we're going to be secure
the vendor keeps using hooded images and
to tell us that they can keep you
100 secure that they have anti-hacking
solutions
and we aren't going to question them
something we'll talk about in a little
bit
so here is what i say you do to your
vendors that keep telling you that they
can keep you secure
now we are going to need a few more
cartridges because
this is the state of the security market
so again if you put yourself in the
shoes
of the very people we're trying to
protect they have
all of these companies that they're now
trying to figure out
who can do the right thing for me who
can do the right end point or the right
technology or the right defensive system
or the right intelligence platform
and the companies themselves aren't
helping the situation because everyone
every single one of them
keeps saying hey we can all do
everything perfectly and so
part of our challenge and part of the
work we need to do in this industry
is sort this bloody mess out more
effectively
now let's have a conversation about our
industry
this is what i do not like our business
is booming
we have a lot going on there's money
flowing in and unfortunately it keeps
moving
which means we keep rewarding the bad
behavior
we are spending more and more money i
mean it's crazy the amount of money that
we've spent in this industry
last year alone 124 billion us dollars
was spent in the industry now
some of it was for legacy systems some
of it was for
you know software and hardware and
systems that we have to maintain and
that we have inherited et cetera et
cetera but a lot of it unfortunately has
been spent on newer technology which
means in theory we should be winning
but unfortunately we're not even close
to winning
so this is where we're expecting to see
damages hit by 2021 now i've seen some
stuff throwing around in the newspaper
which is oh we're already here and we've
already done it and
i'm still not entirely certain i'd love
to see some more material behind this
but if we take a look at the statistics
that we have in
our industry now and this is a mix from
like ponymon the feds from the verizon
report
uh ibm and a couple of other reports all
put together
the amount of time it takes us to even
detect
that somebody is inside a system
averages out about 197 days it's all
over the place
it's everywhere from like 90 days up to
a thousand plus days you know if you're
yahoo or somebody
we're not good at doing anything on this
one then recovering so when you
know that you found me inside your
environment
then it's going to take you another two
months to actually get me the hell out
of your environment
for those of you that know me part of my
background is doing research and a lot
of work in the deception space
so i do a lot to work in that one which
actually starts to affect those top two
figures
quite significantly then we look at the
amount of companies that are being
fished the amount of companies that have
had a breach
the cost of the breaches i mean those
numbers are again all over the place
part of the problem in our industry is
we don't even have a clear set of
numbers to go against we keep talking
about all these numbers but we don't
actually have one good set to go against
which is a problem
the worst one for me is the fact that
we're losing so much data
that's a global number so 22 million
records a day is a global number so
you know all over the world as far as
i'm concerned and those numbers are
fairly significant unfortunately
if you tally up and you add up
the top 30 breaches that we have had
globally
it's almost double the earth's
population so if nothing else we're
extremely
thorough at making sure that we lose
everybody's data
twice and then we look at when we fail
then we look at even how we managed to
make a profit even when we fail so
i've sold you equipment and i've taken
your money
and then i've taken your money to
maintain it and manage it i've taken
your money to penetrate test it and to
assess it
i've taken more money to put policies
and controls around it
and then when the whole thing fails and
you get ransomwared
i take even more money from you to try
to fix them around somewhere and repay
repave in the first place
we're terrible how the hell
do we succeed
this is the state of our industry
it's not good
if you want to add extra things into
here as well for those of you that are
science fiction fans
this sums it up perfectly we're erratic
conflicted and disorganized we lack
harmony
and cohesion and greatness it will be
and currently
is our undoing now on top of this
just to add a little bit more on top of
this we have alert fatigue
you guys can read the statistics as well
as i can so we have put
technology into the hands of the people
that we're meant to protect
that they can't effectively manage
we've put technology into the hands i
mean i've done it we were on a
penetration test
not that long ago and we'd gotten in and
we were sitting there
and the managed service provider hadn't
noticed that we were there
so we started to make some more noise we
started to like ramp up the noise
and they saw us and they categorized as
something so like okay we're going to
really make some noise we fired up
something called
angry ip scanner angry ip scanner for
those of you that don't know what it is
it's basically it's it's a scanning
software it basically looks at every
single port or specific ports across the
network and it does it
loud and proud it's like standing in the
middle of a library
with a loudspeaker yelling at the top of
your voice somebody's going to pay
attention
they did after they tuned the system
down
they then said oh it's it's a bad
network card don't worry about it we'll
fix it in a couple of days and we were
like
we give up and so this is where we have
the problems even in our entry when we
put the tools
that should be doing the detection we
haven't tuned them or we haven't done an
effective enough job to actually help
the organizations understand
so then the challenge then becomes how
do you help a company
understand that it's not an if it's not
the fact that you've built all this
technology in place and oh they'll be
perfectly safe which is what they think
they're like well why am i spending this
money
we don't explain it effectively we don't
talk about it as a journey or a path or
a way that we're trying to do things we
say oh it's okay it's fine
we as our industry have to take a step
back
and we have to look at what we're doing
what we're doing right and what we're
doing wrong and unfortunately we're
doing more things wrong we are
definitely led by marketing messages
when i first started this industry we're
talking a long long time ago we were led
by innovation
we were led by people who had passion
who had desire who wanted to see
change you just listened to an amazing
talk by eff which was taught by eva
which were talking about change and
wanting the passion back into this
industry to help people
and help society get better but we don't
do that we spend much more money on
marketing messages to try to confuse
everybody
then we charge down the latest buzzwords
so it doesn't matter if it's
ai or machine learning or picky buzz or
you know endpoint detection etc etc
we'll go charging down this in the hope
that we can make some more money on it
we're not focused on protecting we don't
care about protecting
we focus much more on making profits and
for me that's a shame there's so many
in this community and you know that's
why i love talking at these even if it
is a crazy hour of the morning
because we have a community and so many
of us want to see
change but we have to be able to affect
it something we'll talk about
and unfortunately you know we haven't
evolved
for the right reasons we've evolved to
make a lot of people some people a lot
of money
and not necessarily to protect people
effectively so we have created
an exceedingly good breeding ground for
an attacker to succeed
not for us to be able to do things as
well as we want to
so this is about where we are really
when we look at it let's face it we have
actually not just got a bit of a [ __ ]
show we've actually set it on fire
so what do we do how do we actually do
something about this and we have some
options
this isn't just to do this or us we have
a couple of options we can
go all thanos
now what i mean by this is if you look
at where technology is and you look at
the work that's being in doing the
technology especially in healthcare
especially in biotechnology especially
nano and embedded technology
especially technology and critical
infrastructure we
are at a point so even a maybe or a
possibility we are at a point where we
affect actual humans
when we screw up it is no longer just
reboot the computer
it is when we screw up in healthcare
people die
when we screw up by ransomware in these
places people die we've already had
examples we've already had potential
examples
the us and the club in europe is going
through it at the moment with a whole
bunch more healthcare attacks that are
going on
people are suffering so you take that
extrapolate that out even further
we kill more people unfortunately
especially in the united states
people only pay attention when more and
more and more people die
and more bodies pile up so we have that
option it is a bit drastic
especially very very drastic when you
turn three and a half billion people
into nothing more than dust bodies
the other problem with this as well is
phallus was very short-sighted
um i grew up i mean i was born in the
70s
so when i was born the world's
population was only about three and a
half billion
fast forward almost 50 years were seven
and a half billion
so we would literally have to kill off
half the population of the planet every
50 years just to keep people's attention
not sure it's a good thing to do but
it's an option it's out there especially
the way we're turning to technology
especially if we look at healthcare i
mean this is just you know the last four
years with healthcare the amount of
places that are being hit the amount of
systems that are being attacked
the overwhelming amount of machines and
people and everything else that are
being affected on this
and the costs that go with it it's um
it's pretty substantial
and as i said when we get it wrong at
this point in time when we screw up
people die it
there's no even question about this at
this point in time it's no longer
reboot the computer will be fine it's oh
that icu system just went online as
ransomware the person couldn't get
to the hospital on time because of
ransomware there are
too many examples of this where we're
seeing this so this is no longer
us just screwing around with computers
these are people's lives that we're
affecting
and this was that ransomware attack
unfortunately where we were talking
about you know
um this was several weeks ago and i said
16 hours this is several weeks ago where
we were talking about this
where you know it wasn't just the first
one we've had one of pride we've had a
whole bunch of other things how many
people do all through stress so
it's not good now option number two
we've all been charging down the
technology arena and looking at
artificial intelligence so
there is a part of me i will admit that
she wants the machines to take over
because as
humans we suck i mean we're terrible
we're
not good with looking after each other
we're terrible between different
countries about how we help people or
ignore people unfortunately
and we tend to have too many biases we
really tend to have too many biases so
let's let the machines take over as far
as i'm concerned
now there's a bit of a problem with that
we haven't got quite the machines where
we want them this comes off of so i
i'm very fortunate i live in a nice
house um you saw one of the dogs come in
a minute ago
we have the roombas we have we have a
couple of roombas running around the
house
um cleaning up you know all the dog hair
and stuff like that so apparently
according to roomba
it has advanced decision making
capabilities
powered by artificial intelligence it's
capable of scanning a room
remembering things sorting out and
everything well no no it doesn't
this is artificial intelligence in
action
this is exactly where the bloody rumba
gets stuck day after day after day no
matter what i do the stupid thing ends
up getting stuck but it eats the carpet
and it goes to try to hide under the
side
so and if you look on top of this this
is actually a fairly modern example
when we look at how that intelligence
system is
able to categorize imagery is able to
mess around with them we look at us from
the hacking community
at how we can mess with it so on the
left hand side you have basically a
picture of a pig
great wonderful now you manipulate that
image by
you know by literally less than one half
of a percent
and all of a sudden the actual
intelligence system classifies that pick
as an airline
this is where we get into adversarial
machine learning
adversarial intelligence so if you think
about it
artificial intelligence is typically
very very dependent
on the data but it's learning from and
how often that data refreshes how often
that data is used
et cetera et cetera et cetera if you can
poison the well
and actually put your own data into that
data source it's learning from
all of a sudden you now influence the
outcome of some of these decisions so
perfect example
um i don't think clown strike is
supporting us who do we have we are palo
alto tenor will naysay mcafee
all right i can annoy clown strike so
plan strike is a good example of this
one same thing with doctorates those are
two organizations that rely very very
heavily on on artificial intelligence
now if you can get to the source of the
data which is possible and you can
poison it and you can do all sorts of
interesting stuff with it
all of a sudden the machines it's
protecting become the machines it wants
to attack
and defend against so you basically
induce a self-attack on systems it's
kind of fun to do
so for good measures apart from making
pigs fly as it says adversarial machine
learning
uh it really is the new frontier of what
we're doing for those of you that are in
the industry are looking to advance in
the industry take a long
hard look at how companies and
organizations are
using large quantities of data to make
decisions and then look at the attack
vectors
that you can insert across those and
please have some fun with that
so as it says despite what the vendor
say ai is not
going to save us just yet it won't
exactly be the downfall of us but it
isn't there yet
now we could just keep going down the
same route that we've been doing i mean
we obviously have that option and here
it is
head in the sand and we all know how
well that works we are going off the
edge of the cliff we're going off the
air
the cliff at full speed or
we try something new we take a different
approach to this we take a little bit of
a look at this and see what we can do
we can take a step away from the
technology and we can look at how
we interact with each other we can look
at how we communicate with people and
exchange ideas again
what i love about this community is we
have you know 8.8
10 years old this year okay 10 years
of working with the community we have
the b-sides community
which again is amazing all over the
country we have all these areas where we
can exchange ideas with each other
and we can influence um we have
cooperation
the ability to actually share the data
and this is a very very crucial one and
share in a timely fashion that's a huge
one
we can coordinate effectively we can all
actually work together for a common
course
as opposed to all of us behind the
scenes pulling in different directions
we're going through some challenges at
the moment
um and i've got to be honest i'm kind of
pissed off with some of the some of the
people in our industry
because we're having problems with
healthcare and there's a number of
amazing people
evan frankfort ryan fortier and some
other amazing people of other companies
that are actually doing some amazing
work to try and figure out what's going
on
and then you get some people which are
holding on to information and don't want
to share
that's when i start getting pissed off
because we need to collaborate much more
effectively
so uh a shout out to some people in our
industry that are holding on to
427 hospitals worth of information
share your [ __ ] um krebs i hope you're
listening to this
all right when we talk to people
when we have conversations with
companies
when we engage with companies think
about it
think about it not just in your shoes
but think about it from the company
if somebody was to walk up to you and
somebody was to have a conversation with
you go hi
i'm chris i'm gonna penetrate you
what the hell are you gonna do i'm not
only gonna penetrate you i'm gonna
penetrate you
with a piece of software named after the
goddess of death and destruction
doesn't sound very inviting doesn't
sound very nice and not only am i gonna
do that
i'm gonna penetrate you with pineys
pineapples and ponies and you're like
what the hell are you talking about
that is not the way to do it
how about walking up to the people that
you want to engage with
how about walking up to somebody you
just want to help understand security
how about walking into that next client
engagement with
tea or coffee in one hand and donuts or
pastries in the other hand and sitting
down going
can we have a conversation can we
talk can we role play can we engage in
discussion
much more collaborative much more
engaged the barrier comes down you're
not
in an adversarial relationship
and here's what i mean and again i'll
take this as english but for those of
you that follow
xkcd i know he does these books in other
language
so talk in a language that others
understand
in other words you know you're in chile
when you are talking
with your clients don't talk in code
don't talk in acronyms talk in spanish
have a plain and simple conversation
with them
don't talk in geek speak but explain
what we're doing
in a language that others are
comfortable with and others understand
this comes back to training
so for those of you that follow me i do
a lot of work with the wiser team so
wiser
we do a lot of education work and we do
it in plain and simple language and it's
free
you know there is a ton of free training
out there the wiser training site
i've even got a compendium i've got a
dictionary where we break
down how technical terms are going to
english take them
translate them to spanish please in fact
i think we do some of the languages
but we need to be the ones that come to
the table and talk more effectively with
others
the other thing we need to do is ask
more
questions we also need to help the
people around us
ask more questions and i have them help
understand what's going on with security
have them understand what's happening in
this industry
this is a big shout out devsecops
whether you like the name don't like the
name like what's going on et cetera et
cetera
to me this is where we have
collaboration this is where we have
development teams security teams and
operational teams
working together a big shout out for
like mark miller on the devsev ops teams
here
they have a conference in two weeks time
there's a hundred and fifty speakers
over
24 hours it's completely free it's all
day devops go watch it go listen to it
go engage
go understand how we have to collaborate
more effectively and work together more
effectively break down the barriers
just because we know the development
teams are a pain in the ass and just
because we know operators become a
strange
we're also weird in the middle and we
have to be the ones that go out there
and help
everybody else listen to be more
effective
we gotta share again this is a community
you have so many people here listening
you have so many people here engaged
get to know each other get to understand
this and when you are talking and when
you are basically working with each
other
figure out exactly who you can tell
if you get hit or when you get hit with
ransomware or you get hit with an attack
talk to the people around you and help
them protect themselves as well
we shouldn't be waiting for the lawyers
to get engaged and we shouldn't be
waiting before the authorities tell us
we can say something
even if you keep the back channels open
the signal channels and all these other
discussion points open
we should be the ones reaching out and
helping those
around us the only way we get better is
if we work
more effectively as a community it's as
simple as that
oops there's some slides there we go i
think that's the one yep
so there's more on this there's a lot
more on this that we could obviously
have a conversation about
but i want to talk a little bit more
about this one so if we look at our
industry and we look at where we started
it used to be people process and
technology but let's be perfectly honest
um we tended we have forgotten the
people we've looked at technology as
solving these problems and it's not
going to do everything for us it isn't
going to solve the problems unless we
re-engage
with the people you know unfortunately
as an industry we've blamed people we've
said oh
users are stupid or users can't learn or
i can't teach them or anything else
that's on our problem that's awful we
need to take a step back and go look
how do we engage with the users
how do we enable them how do we make
them more effective not just training
them once a year that's useless
but how do we do something on a regular
basis like once a month
just teach them help them understand
help them protect their families their
friends their kids their grandparents
and everybody around them
that way they learn and then they become
our best
asset they become our first line of
defense
and the processes as much as we hate
paperwork and as much as it sucks
those processes the policies or the
controls
they help a lot
start thinking about them more
effectively before you start throwing
more technology of the problem
here's one for us again for those of you
that know me
i have two of these guys hanging around
and i love them and they're probably the
only thing that kept me going through
last year
no two ways about it this is a shout out
to the mental health hackers
we as a community need to unplug
sometimes we have to
um i take my time um
monday through friday with work week i
get up in the morning when i eventually
get up i'm a nighttime person i get up
in the morning and i work until six
o'clock at night
from six o'clock at night till nine ten
i don't touch the computer it's my time
with my family it's the time with the
dogs it's the time to eat it's the time
to relax
nine ten o'clock at night i picked the
computer back up again i worked till two
three o'clock in the morning
saturdays apart from this saturday
because
these crew here the chilean crew got
hold of me and said we really want you
to talk
saturdays normally you will never find
me in front of any of this damn
technology i don't touch it i don't
wanna know there
i leave my phone behind i hate
technology on saturdays
this is the one exception i have made in
probably
months because i believe this is so
important and the guys called me up and
said hey can i come hang out with you
folks on saturday so normally i'd be
nowhere near technology i'll be up in
the mountains hanging out
but please look after yourselves
take time away reach out to people in
this industry and go hey i got a problem
i've done it often enough other people
have done it that's what we're here for
so some final thoughts
this is our future
our future is simple it's going to take
all of us
i don't care about your background i
don't care about your race your color
your creed your language how many limbs
you have
your orientation or anything i don't
give a [ __ ]
what i care about is here i care about
your passion i care about your desire
and i care about your want to help to
protect other people and this should be
when we employ people when we engage
people
and when we work with people that should
be how we define people
and it's going to take change we can't
blame leadership we can't blame the
research i'm sure as hell don't blame
the hackers
we all need to take responsibility for
what's going on in this industry and we
need and have to be the very change that
we want to see
and this is my loved one i love this one
this is a fundamental attribution error
we've got to stop blaming everybody we
really have to stop blaming everybody
else you know
when you get breached when something
happens
when you fail stop trying to blame
everybody else take a step back
go look in the mirror what could i have
done differently if a user clicked on
something and they infected the system
could you have educated that user more
effectively could you have trained them
could you have taught them to do
something
when leadership says no we're not buying
any more tech maybe take a step back and
go
did i explain it effectively what could
i have done
differently to influence that situation
because the attitude of i can't affect
change
is [ __ ] we can all affect change and
we can all choose something on this one
so last couple of slides and i'm going
to shut up and we'll do q a
so this is kind of a cool we've all come
at this from different directions by far
and away i've been in this industry way
too long i've seen way too many changes
and i love the industry
the people that are coming into this
industry now are great there are some
amazing ideas some amazing thoughts
you know i was introduced by an amazing
individual who has done so much in this
industry as well
the people that are putting this on for
the 10th year
are amazing in this industry we've all
come at it from different directions
so we're all in the same boat we're all
trying to affect change we're all trying
to do things differently so we need to
figure out how we can do that
and as i said as individuals if we
do this individually we're going to fail
the only way
that we work effectively is if we do
this together the only way this succeeds
is if we work together
and that's across the globe that's
everywhere and
and this is remember this is a part
english part scottish guy who was born
in cyprus who lives in the u.s talking
about a conference in chile
so if anybody can reach across the globe
and do this that'd be us
so do me a favor let's put the country
barriers down let's actually figure out
how we can all work together please
all right huge thanks to everybody for
everybody for listening on a saturday
morning
um a massive thanks to the team for
putting this on it's freaking awesome
for 10 years on this one
and uh to the organizers and for
pointing us so with that the final slide
um i want to just say thank you to
everybody for listening thanks for
everybody hanging out
i'm not sure if there's questions or if
i've managed to stun everybody into
silence so i'm going to shut up at this
point in time
and i'm going to stop sharing my slides
so hopefully that was fun and
interesting
hi chris this is lisa hey hi email how
are you
good how are you doing hi fine thank you
so much for your talk
so interesting thank you that was fun
it's fun hanging out
and i you know it's i'm going back to
bed in a minute it's
[Laughter]
it is but this is important that you
could be here with us today
really oh it's totally i'm glad i'm a
priest thanks for her thanks for asking
me to come and hang out and it was
awesome listening to ava before
that was i loved eff has done i i owe
them
a lot of thanks for various things in my
past oh that's good to hear
well we have some questions from the
from the attendees so
do you think today that the artificial
intelligence
is generating cyber attacks
or do you know if they're working or
investigating to create that kind of
attacks
oh yeah we've been we've been working on
that for years so
if you go out and do some research uh
four years ago i think i was i was part
of a project so i'll put my hand up on
this one
it was called the darpa grand cyber
challenge or the darpa grand challenge
and it was basically
adversarial and defensive machine
learning against each other so it was
machine against machine
and they were learning each other's
tactics and it was a self-enclosed unit
and we had a whole bunch of competitions
from a whole bunch of people this was
four or five years ago now so yeah i
mean is it being designed that way
absolutely is it in use at this moment
in time good question
we have seen advances we've obviously
seen advances in the defensive system so
security orchestration takes
sets of attacks and tries to do tributes
and stuff like that but
yeah it's definitely coming along no two
ways about it
thank you um
uh can i am i more protected from an
attack if i use linux or ubuntu
um you can protect i mean
you can protect anything well
let me rephrase that let me ask you
really rephrase that you can't
protect anything but you can reduce the
risk so
nothing is secure let's be perfectly
honest i mean linux has its own problems
ubuntu's got his own what linux is
i mean i use macintosh system so at the
end of the day that's a bsd an open bsd
system which is like
mother and father of all of these um
this has issues
windows that all the operating systems
have issues
it's what you do to lower the risk you
know
how active do you use the firewalls how
active are you at putting some kind of
protection
what do you know that should be running
versus what is running what do you have
on the browser
and then also what are you paying
attention to are you watching your logs
are you doing all these things
everything's everything can be attacked
no two ways about it it's just what do
you do to lower your risk
i hope that helps okay i have another
question here
thinking in the theory of tanners who
or yeah who one or more persons could
uh could leader this could take the
leadership of this and
and as to your experience say that one
again
yeah i'm sorry my i'm done that's okay
so thinking in the theory of tenors of
thanos
oh yeah yeah as to your experience
in other words who could lead who could
lead our industry
yes yeah oh there's some good people
there's some
i don't think it's one person i i think
in our industry we yeah and you've i
mean i've been watching
i've watched some of the some of the
videos that you've put out
um and some of the people you've had
talk there have been some amazing people
that have done talks
to me i think the leadership takes a lot
of us it cannot be one voice
it has to be numerous voices i mean
you've got jack daniels you've got chris
nicholson
you've got amazing people there you have
amazing people in the middle at least
you have amazing people in europe
south america i mean you think of some
of the fantastic people
that are in the community in south
america that are leading the community
i think it takes a number of us and i
think it's going to take a number of us
you know ian admit i mean there's so
many good people
that i think it has to take a number of
us to sit down together
and go how can we affect change
um and if i can be at the table and hang
out and help people
i will definitely do it i would love to
help out because i think it takes more
than just a single leader i think it
could down i think somebody has to kick
it off which is kind of what some of us
are trying to do
but i think it's going to take numbers
of us because i think ava said it right
she's like you know i'm an old white guy
let's be honest
um and old white guys can
not be the ones at the table you have
karen elizari
from israel as an amazing female leader
you have so many people
that are in this industry that are not
old white males that
need to be at that table that need to
help out you look at africa i mean
there's some fantastic
people in the hacking community in the
research community
that need to be at that table so i think
it will take a number of us to do this
thank you
which way do you think is the best to
explain cyber security to the users
since a lot of i.t people think that
only they have to know
and they don't have to democrat
democratize their
we have to talk to users so i talked
about a little bit in the talk
um i have partnered up with a training
company and i don't use part time i help
them out
and they pay me and i do it on a
part-time basis for me what i do with
that training
is we turn what i know up here into
english
plain simple english
now that also gets translated i know
gabrielle has those translated into
other languages
but we talk with people we don't talk it
down to them
and we don't say oh you're a user you're
going to know we talk to them in plain
simple english and i think that's what's
going to help
it's going to be those communications
it's going to be the training companies
that help people and it's free
the stuff that we do is free we're not
charging you you can watch
like at least half or two-thirds of the
videos
without having to pay anything so it's
out there we use it and it's available
the dictionary that i've built i've
built an entire dictionary we're
building more of it
that we've put together that translates
geek speak into english it's free
put it out there so the people can use
it so the resource is
there for people to actually learn we
just have to put them in people's hands
and the i.t people
anybody who says that they don't want to
educate or should not educate the users
needs to be tasted everybody it this is
everybody's problems i mean the thing is
you know
we're all walking around with these
things
um we all we're we're all sitting around
with with flipping
with iphones these are dangerous
these are damn dangerous pieces of
technology
but we don't think about it that way we
hand them to our kids
and we're like oh you go use this but we
don't
think about the consequences so
that to me comes to the training it
comes to educating the children
it comes to educating the parents or the
guardians
it comes to doing that and school
education and home education it comes to
educating everybody
so we can do it we just have to do it
and there's plenty of resources there to
do it in a plain simple language
thank you so much i have one last
question
totally educate politicians about cyber
security changing their
character or thinking that it's all
related to technical things
can we shoot the politicians please some
of them
especially in this country
i don't know that's a tough one i so
that is a hard one because i don't
my tolerance for politics is low there's
an amazing so
for those of you that know the industry
um josh
and there's a bunch of really good guys
called i am the cavalry
um do a little bit of research on josh
coleman and there's a bunch of other
guys inside i am the cavalry
they have more patience than most saints
because they will deal with the politics
i mean they are amazing they've gone in
on healthcare they've gone in on
transportation
they are trying to educate the
politicians
um i think more of us could step up i
mean perfect example
the us is going through elections at the
moment i've done
a bunch of talks on election security
and the lack of it
but if you look at defcon defcon had the
voting village for a number of years
they put an
amazing like an amazing report out about
the 29
votes 2019 voting village something like
that report needs to be printed off by
everybody
and handed to their politician to go
are you really telling me this is how we
deal with democracy
and helping to educate people as to what
their report actually means
so i think we can all play a part in it
we can look at the resources again the
voting village stuff is a perfect
example
we can look at ransomware we can look at
healthcare we look at the military i
mean i do a lot of stuff for the
military and the government
and we're educating people but it
is a huge uphill battle
like a huge uphill battle no two ways
about it
and it's there's no easy solution i
think it just takes more and more and
more of us
talking about it in non-technical ways
it's talking about it in english
so i think that's going to help a ton
thank you so much that was
very important what you just said there
thank you so much
chris for joining us today much
appreciated thank you for having me
thanks to everybody hanging out this is
fantastic you guys just
freaking rock i am hugely appreciative
of being here
thank you so much we're very happy to
hear that
well um i'm gonna switch to spanish now
so um thank you so much chris and we
hope to see you
definitely take care bye-bye thank you
so much
[Music]
nosotros