everyone my name is Matt Cagle i am a
policy attorney at the ACLU of Northern
California I work on privacy free speech
and surveillance issues and today we're
going to talk about surveillance and
what you can do to really stop it and
roll it back in your communities and
we're going to use three different
places as example so I'm based out of
the SF bay area Mariko's in here in New
York and then jared is in the Washington
area of people to introduce yourselves
to hi everyone I'm marica here I say I'm
an attorney at the New York Civil
Liberties Union and I like matwork God
privacy surveillance free speech issues
and also work on a range of other issues
on our docket including criminal justice
other discrimination justice issues and
i spent a chunk of my time filing and
pursuing Freedom of Information request
and I'm looking forward to talking about
how we might set up systems where we can
learn about these police surveillance
technologies without going the route of
pursuing flower class I'm Jared friend
i'm a volunteer attorney for the ACLU
washington seattle and I focus on like
both Matt Mariko surveillance and
privacy issues i do a little bit on the
litigation into filing lawsuits against
the government but predominantly my work
is focused on policy legislation and
activist outreach so we're going to talk
about Leo specific surveillance
technologies today we're we're examples
come out things like stingrays license
plate readers biometrics even drones but
we're also here to talk about power and
and what surveillance is ultimately
about at the end of the day is the power
to control people the power to control
information and ultimately the power to
bring the criminal justice system to
bear on communities often communities of
color so you know to TWP I think it's
really important to talk about you know
the communities were coming from here
and surveillance technologies were
seeing and Jared you won't talk about
Seattle has a rich history of
surveillance
yeah so that was an interesting area to
think about privacy issues and it's
predominantly white it's very affluent
communities on a very privacy engage
communities and so there's been a number
of cases where
actavis in seattle have come out in
opposition to acquisition of drones by
the Seattle Police Department deployment
of closed circuit TV cameras deployment
of mesh networks that could be used to
you know monitor people's mac addresses
things like that but one the one King
can all this is that Seattle is an area
like most of America where white
supremacy is a really serious problem
so as soon as surveillance and privacy
issues start reaching into some context
for lower-income people are for
communities of color the engagement
level for everyone across the board
whether it's community leaders you know
activists or just kind of concerned
citizens drops off really steeply and
really quickly I'm i don't think this
should come as any big surprise
um but you know especially when you
think about somewhere like seattle where
you know class lines and and and ethnic
groups are kind of drawn along
geographic boundaries but what happens
is that these arguments against
surveillance and against privacy
invasions that are that are unique or or
more exacerbated for these marginalized
communities these arguments end up
falling by the sideline because they
don't get the same type of support and
they don't get the same type of air time
as lots of the other generic issues so
if you're talking about you know black
lives matters protesters on then in the
police department surveilling them on
social media that that doesn't get a lot
of traction but talking about you know
deploying a ccd camera in the you know
you know in a white affluent
neighborhoods park does and so that's
that's a attention and a problem that
you know we had to deal with a lot in
the in those communities and something
that has been difficult especially in
the last few years so in New York City
we have the NYPD which i'm talking about
a rich history of surveillance and even
more recently a very concrete examples
of the department spying on Muslim
communities and allegations that
included putting cameras right in front
of mosques and using license plate
readers in order to figure out who is
going in and out of mosques we also have
a domain awareness system which is the
system that connects surveillance
cameras automatic license plate readers
now ShotSpotter data other environmental
sensor data and aggregates that into one
system and your questions about what
policies are in place how it's going to
be expanding in the future and how
weather will be notified about the way
that system changes and we're also
seeing you know technologies coming in
from the military I mean we're seeing
this all across our country stingrays
have been in the news
those are devices that spot on your cell
phones can be used to track people we
recently got documents from the NYPD
showing that they've been using
stingrays since 2008 abused it over
1,000 times this had not been reported
though in the media until this year and
they didn't have any written guidelines
for their use and they weren't getting
warrants they were relying on lower
level court orders so stingrays a very
powerful surveillance device that was
initially developed for the military
it's coming into the local police
departments for use in everyday
investigations and questions arise about
you know why I was in the public
notified about this and shouldn't the
public have notice about what policies
are in place and should we all know
about whether the police department is
using warrants or not or what kind of
retention of pretension practices are in
place and and one issue that comes up is
all of this also seems like the tip of
the iceberg and there's probably a lot
that we don't know about the police
acquisition and use of surveillance
technologies in the bay area you know
there's this there's always a desire and
tech savviness because of the the
communities that live there so many
really you know tech-savvy folks live in
the bay area so there's this tension
though because we also encourage our
police departments to be at the
forefront of certain technologies in
places like San Francisco and ok
and and even santa clara county which
have which is in the heart of Silicon
Valley but there's a tension there
because as we encourage that as you know
communities law enforcement is like in
the bay area becomes the first one
always jump at new creepy surveillance
technologies for instance the Alameda
County Sheriff's alameda county includes
berkeley and oakland the Alameda County
Sheriff we just learned a few weeks ago
not only has like one drone which we had
heard about in a surprise sort of public
press conference I think last year they
not only have one drone they have like
an entire arsenal of drones now I think
about half a dozen DJI drones that
they've been registered be registered
with the FAA and that they've been
rolling out at routine law enforcement
sort of exercises you'll see when these
technologies are adopted and if there's
pushback or if there's questions asked
of law enforcement they always say
actually we're only buying this so we
can do search-and-rescue missions or to
like fight terrorism or something but it
i mean the pattern always is that these
tools if there are safeguards in place
that elected officials and the public
can use to 22 really constrain their use
if those aren't in place then the tools
end up being used for routine law
enforcement i think one of the drones
was used to break up like a gambling
ring that was running or being
investigated in the bay area we've also
seen this with this tech savviness and
like jumping to adopt new tools we've
seen in social media surveillance so the
same analytics tools that you know
companies in Silicon Valley startups use
can be repurposed of course to just do
searches for hashtags on places like
Twitter and Instagram and because its
software it often ends up being cheaper
and easier to adopt then something like
a stingray which you know my cost you
know in the six figures in fresno
actually in fresno is the central valley
there in California we learned last fall
working with local activists we sent a
public records request and we learned
that the fresno Police Department had
purchased social media surveillance
software and they actually tried out
like four different tools because of the
trial like kind of testing
periods that these companies were
offering so they didn't even have to pay
to really try for different social media
surveillance tools that scraped publicly
available tweets publicly available
Instagram post facebook and then allowed
for like hashtag and keyword searching
geo you know specialization and just
kind of exhuming on certain places where
then geo tags on the actual post and one
of the what one of the tools that they
were working with actually in its
promotional material suggested to the
police department that they should
search for hashtags like mike brown
black lives matter
hands up don't shoot things that were
clearly being used for peaceful protests
and protected First Amendment you
exercise of First Amendment rights were
being suggested in the promotional
materials that the police chief had
received in their work email as search
terms so it just goes to show like when
there's no oversight and depending on
the community here and these things can
really kind of rush out of control i do
want to encourage folks to we're going
to take questions that comes to raise
your hand
I don't know if you spot them or will
somehow spot them and if not we'll we'll
try to reserve time at the end
gary said there's also challenges with
like the criminal defense bar you were
talking to me about this earlier so I
mean I that I see this is probably one
of the most crucial issues in the
surveillance context is that the current
surveillance climate on create a set of
circumstances where it sits next to
impossible as a criminal defendant to
get adequate representation if you're
being charged with a crime and there's
kind of two fundamental reasons for this
the first is the the obfuscation that
police departments are engaging in to
prevent the public from knowing about
these types of surveillance activities
so not only is this kind of kept out of
the the field of view the general public
that also means that criminal defense
attorneys that are representing you also
don't understand or know the types of
practices that that law enforcement are
engaging it on this is magnified of
course by things like parallel
construction where if a police
department finds a piece of information
using illegal or questionable means
they'll just come up with another story
for how they got that piece of
information write a new narrative for
for how they came across it
I'm so for example in Washington we
found out that the Tacoma Police
Department had a stingray as a result of
of some investigations done by some
activists I'm upon learning that we sent
some public records requests to
specifically for the list of cases that
stimulate had been used in because first
and foremost we wanted to understand
what types of cases they were being used
in but as soon as we got that list we
sit around basically to every venue that
we could come across that criminal
defense attorneys might see and let them
know hey this thing was used this is how
it works
these are some of the legal challenges
you might raise and here's like all the
case numbers let us know if you have any
questions and I got dozens and dozens of
emails back from criminal defense
attorneys that said I got this email my
cases in your list i have no clue what
the fuck you talking about
um can you explain what's going on and
and how this works and why I'm seeing
this on and it was a good example that
like these people were being told
entirely different stories for how the
government had found out where they're
know that didn't get to where the
defendant happened to be at a particular
time on and so the second problem here
right obviously building upon this first
one is that many of these criminal
defense attorneys lack the the expertise
to really understand this stuff even the
stuff that's pretty well explained and
in public knowledge like stingrays even
that type of stuff it's really hard for
some of these criminal defense attorneys
to mount a good defense to this much
less to find you know expert witnesses
are people that can come in and so you
know this is a really really serious
problem because the the forefront of
these types of technologies are these
these these criminal cases where you
know these people are being charged with
drug crimes you know or routine you know
your property crimes and they're not
able to mount a good defense and of
course this is magnified if you're
someone that can afford your own lawyer
right in your provided but one by the
state where the expertise you no
restrictions are still in play but
there's also problems where you know
public defense attorneys typically don't
have a whole lot of time to dedicate the
cases so they're not going to be able to
get up to speed on this stuff anyway
even if the resources are available so
conditioned on one thing and that you're
lucky in the sense in Washington that
you're able to get the list of kids yep
the docket numbers because I've tried to
get that before and a lot of departments
don't keep track of this and so they
you might have a list of users but it's
not actually connected to the criminal
case and resulted in which just
magnifies the problems your secrecy and
no one knows how was used in a criminal
defendants may not find out about it at
all and often you see the sharing of
these tools as well so maybe that in the
community that we believe their
surveillance happening it's actually not
being conducted by the law enforcement
that that is based in that that city so
in Southern California for instance a
lot of communities a lot of cities use
the county sheriff or neighboring Police
Department's for their own law
enforcement so last year we sued the
city of anaheim to get records about
their use of stingray devices because we
had suspicions that and I madison rayne
that what they were using it will
ultimately we got documents back through
our lawsuit that should that not only
did anaheim have a stingray they also
had a dirt box which is a stingray like
on steroids that can be put into
assessing the plane and flown over head
to do the same sort of cell phone
surveillance as stingrays so they were
not only using this this airborne
stingray Calder box but they also had
agreements to where they could make
these tools available to neighboring
communities across Orange County I think
there's a question right there but yeah
so we were seeing that you know the
Democratic safeguards that could've been
passed by residents of Anaheim or
residents of the neighboring community
to control surveillance in their own
communities
those would have been an effective
because anaheim had behind the closed
doors agree to share the tools with the
neighboring Police Department your
question
so I'm just going to use unhappy in my
works exactly sort of record like
another hardhead pre this convention so
does like record like the conversations
record the metadata or like what is it
was a do-gooder so on the quick cliff
notes version stingray pretends to be a
cell site so the sell side is you know
cell towers that your phone connects to
in order to receive service right there
on top of buildings there littered all
over the place a stingray pretends to be
one of those cell-cell side so it
pretends to AT&T or t-mobile or whoever
you're trying to connect two on and once
you connect to it you share certain
information with that that's outside of
that fake sell-side in this instance you
share a unique identifier that's
associated with your phone
I'm usare you share geolocation
information there's other types of
information that sting rays can collect
depending on the model on we we've seen
references to their ability to intercept
communications and calls on most cases
that I've seen at the local level tend
to be just about identifying the phone a
person is using or their location on so
the two common use cases I've seen for
local law enforcement are we know a
person uses this phone we want to find
out where they are so because we have an
arrest warrant for them so we're going
to drive the Stingray through a
neighborhood or you know through an
apartment complex to figure out where
precisely this person is so that we can
you arrest them or questioned them the
second case is where you have a suspect
and you want to know what phone they're
using so that you can use that unique
phone number to go to AT&T and say hey
give us all the records associated with
this person and so what you would do in
that context is would find the person
writes a go to their home turn on the
Stingray make a note of every single you
know unique device in that vicinity and
then follow them to the grocery store
turn it on again you get another lights
of the list of devices in the area you
cross-reference that list and say okay
this person is using this phone so now
we can send a bunch of other requests to
gather information about that fun
there's also been I've seen hints that
stingrays are capable potentially
delivering malware two phones and other
things but in the local law enforcement
context generally this is about location
information or unidentified number
and just to highlight from jared's
response i mean it was clear from your
response but in the way they work
stingrays do is collect and sort through
the information of cell phones in the
vicinity
i'm using the same network so that in
your raises concerns it's not just the
phone that's being targeted or the phone
person for him there's an arrest warrant
out its the phones of people who are
around my son
one question could be difficult balance
on that person following 24-7 sure why
is running the lab why should I put
manpower on twenty-four/seven when I
suspect that you do something wrong when
there's an easier smarter way to get it
done so I think the first reason is the
reason that Rico just said which is that
I'm its indiscriminate right you're
inherently collecting the information
from all sorts of by standards not just
necessarily the person that's the target
in the event people in their homes to
potentially sandra bullock people and
also because they're sending me signals
into cars homes purses you know whatever
collecting information in private spaces
the the second reason is that you know
there's a really good argument for
surveillance being expensive it would be
incredibly expensive to follow some
around 24 7 you need a team of people
who need lots of resources and so your
desire for that really sensitive
information about you every little thing
that a person does in every place that
they go that is offset by the dramatic
cost that you have to undertake in order
to do that with the Stingray those costs
dramatically reduced you you flip a
switch and in all the sudden you're able
to to collect an enormous amount of
information about a lot of people and
then how big is it just a curiosity is a
varying size but they can they can fit
into a backpack
okay thanks some models yeah um so
quickly and will take few more questions
in a few minutes but um so one thing
that is really tied to this is like how
do communities learned about
surveillance we kind of touched on it a
little bit i know in the bay area you
know we rely on what is a really
sophisticated set of activists and
advocates to really do things like as
simples going and downloading and
scouring agendas and put minutes of city
council meetings to look for you know
acronyms like you all see which is like
a DHS program that often funds a lot of
surveillance technology or to search for
cell phone reception or triangulation
device you know there's a there's an
entire set of folks who are really great
about searching through public records
because often at the end of the day
things like stingrays and license plate
readers are attached to like an
attachment on like the 400-page of a
tuesday morning agenda for local city
council meeting and so you know often a
lot of these communities and I think
this is true across New York and
Washington as well as that their lacks
mechanisms for really you know making
these things rise to the surface before
their purchase because once they're
purchased and once the grant money often
from the federal government has been
spent the cats out of the bag it's much
more difficult for advocates and the
ACLU to come in at that point into force
there to be or to pressure them to to
adopt safeguards in place and then often
you know we discovered these things
because the cops just brag about them
recently we learned about I think I knew
well the drones in alameda county for
instance the sheriff was on television
bragging about the use of the drones and
we're like let's that's much easier than
having to violate public records act
request
there's also a lot of there's a arise of
what used to be called like domain
awareness centers and i think is now
being labeled the more innocuous
real-time crime centers that are popping
up and often these are kind of like you
know room somewhere in a police
department or county building where
there's a bunch of TV screens on the
wall and it's just like really there's a
lot of flashing lights and like usually
it's just cable network television on
the the screens but sometimes it's if
there's no passwords on the wall or
something but they'll often bring in the
news and have like a chat about their
new check crime Center and then that
really provides like an inn for local
advocates to just be like wait what are
you doing here and so that's and of
course we find Public Records Act
requests and litigate them
yeah I think that's working with the
working with activists like many of you
is really important actually just met
somebody
who had alerted us to an issue that we
should investigate and we followed up
with a full request so yeah and then and
then looking journalists who are
covering this issue we do look at a
local store procurement notices and see
what we can find but it is really
difficult i mean there are loopholes in
the law that makes it very easy for
local police enforcement to get new
surveillance technologies in ways that
won't show up on the local notices and
even if it shows up it might be kind of
obscure so we might not realize that
it's something that we should be keeping
an eye on so getting to you in that
first step step of knowing that the
police agency has a certain type of
technology has been very difficult one
of the challenges of doing this and I
think Matt alluded to this but um the
value in kind of uncovering this stuff
isn't always just in figure out this
piece of technology is being used by
your police department but also
uncovering collaborations with the
federal government
I'm that's because a lot of this money a
lot of these resources are coming from
the feds and they often come with
strings attached right information
sharing agreements and things like that
and so we had an example where on a
local activists by the name of Lee
colleton in seattle was walking down the
street and he saw a surveillance camera
on 2013 union which is a historically
black neighborhood in seattle and he
thought I'd never seen that before and
so he tweeted the seattle City Light
account like Twitter account said what
houses camera like what what is doing
and it let it over a week-long like a
multi-week long period it sent out this
this firestorm of finger-pointing of
actually that's not our camera that's
this person's camera turns out we
learned that it's actually an ATF camera
and the ATF has this practice of posting
cameras on local city infrastructure and
that this this process was essentially
sanctioned by our local government in
contravention of a local law that we
have I'm and so as much as Lee was
interested in this camera it was
actually a much bigger indictment
this kind of collaboration that was
going on between local government
federal government that was actually
really compelling and led to a lot of
controversy so you know those types of
kind of small questions act and can
snowball into something much larger very
quickly and we'll take another question
sure any hope of countermeasures
associated with stingrays are similar
devices pretty much a dead issue there
are multiple legal prohibitions against
either emitting a signal in those
frequency bands or intercepting one the
Electronic Communications Privacy Act
284 prohibits recovering anything out of
the air that's used for that purpose but
if you had a passive device that only
measured the strength the power level of
the nearest cell station it would not be
violating any of those prohibitions and
the Stingray has an Achilles heel
it must by necessity be provide a
stronger signal level to the mobile
device to capture its receiver and spoof
it into believing that the stingray is
the legitimate base station so I wonder
if this immense boost in base station
signal level couldn't be detected and
Exploited and turned into a warning
device it doesn't tell you oh they're
listening to you may be listening guy
upstairs but it could at least passively
maybe without violating any existing
prohibitions provide a person with the
least
oh don't use your phone go down the
street kind of warning
I mean we're actually seeing the sort of
the unlit on the issue of like the
passive reception in the Anaheim lawsuit
that we did we actually they not only
editor box they had a stingray but they
also had something produced by the key
corporation and its KYW not exactly sure
how to say it but this was i think
between five and ten thousand dollar
device that was designed to passively
interest up cellphone signal strength
and an information identifying
information about cell phones and so
that I think that really just goes to
show that the issue here isn't for us
the privacy issues and whether it's an
active or passive certain device it's
whether or not the police should be
doing this in secret without any
judicial oversight
there was a case the Supreme Court over
a decade ago that involved a
heat-seeking device that allowed it's
called kylo it was a device that allowed
the long law enforcement to look through
walls to look for marijuana grows and
heat and the supreme court in that case
found that there was a Fourth Amendment
search and then that was like there was
there was a serious issue even though
those heat waves were being passively
admitted and received by that
heat-seeking device I mean that device
was not generating anything on its own
it was just reading through and and
capable of seeing everything from
marijuana grows to the lady of the house
taking her steamy shower so I'm i think
the real issue for us is regardless of
the the way in which the single
functions is focusing on the really the
principles and the privacy interested at
stake so you know once we've learned
about something
the next step is always to like explain
and talk with coordinate with out of
advocates and activists and explain and
try to get change made and try to get
restrictions placed on these devices try
to get them rolled back all together and
so the challenge there becomes
especially for issues like privacy and
and technologies like stingrays that are
sometimes sort of like a higher level
and and not so easy to just you explain
in small sound bites the the challenge
becomes like how to make these issues
resonate with people so I'm interested
in how and and how you guys make these
issues resonate other people and what
the challenges there are yeah i think on
one thing is that privacy is in in the
u.s. especially is inherently the
privileged value i think that on
relinquishment of privacy is often a
prerequisite and this is a legacy and
anglo-saxon legacy going back to the
fifteen sixteen hundreds right
relinquishment of privacy is often a
prerequisite for receiving Social
Services on so in most states if you
want food stamps if you want assisted
housing if you want childcare services
that have a thing you have to subject
yourself to an extraordinary amount of
invasion into your personal life by the
state so if we're talking you know to
you know your community advocates about
privacy is some abstract human right
we'll see people glaze over really quick
because that's not that's not where
their battle is fought right it's fought
in the day-to-day struggles with
bureaucracy that are trying to limit
their ability to provide for their
families and so the conversation changes
really really quickly be lots of privacy
activists that they believe really
strongly in the work that they're doing
and and have her incredibly good
intentions but there's a major kind of
cultural barrier and and language
barrier and talking about these issues
I'm and so moving from a space where we
talk about privacy is this absolutely
right and in coloring that with more of
a discussion of kind of the day-to-day
political battles that that many people
face is really really important if you
want to gain traction with those groups
at all i'm in and find opportunities for
collaboration I'm and that is useful as
well when you bring the conversation
from the community leaders and advocates
to legislators or lobbyists right if
you're trying to push for legislation or
reform because those personal stories
those day-to-day stories are often much
more compelling to you know assuming
their progressive you know Democratic
lawmaker whatever and there they care
about these issues at all on you're
gonna have a lot of time bringing down
and drilling down to these personal
narratives as opposed to in the strictly
relying on kind of lofty ideals or
constitutional principles
yeah i agree taught that talking about
specific technologies and specific
issues that communities care about is is
very important and and and these are
very important issues for many
communities especially for low-income
communities of color where there is more
police surveillance so I was just
talking to a local community leader of a
lower income community and she said yes
surveillance issues privacy issues are
really one of the biggest areas of
concern right now because they're seeing
you some more and more surveillance
cameras pop-up they don't know where
that's going to what the policies are in
place for those cameras they have no
control over where those cameras are
popping up their questions about social
media surveillance
you know what that my pee dee is looking
at their Arkin questions that are come
up over these linked NYC kiosks that
have popped up around the city and
they're going to be communities that are
going to be depending on that in order
to access the internet so questions
about what those kiosks are collecting
and how that information is going to be
used there are these issues these
questions are all going to be very
important for for her community
yeah i mean law enforcement often talks
about surveillance technologies is a
force multiplier something that can make
you know surveillance cheaper something
that can make up for what is often like
cutting budgets cut budgets at the local
level like and this is happening in a
lot of California communities where law
enforcement is struggling to retain
folks and and and and sees the need for
these technologies will they say this is
going to be a force multiplier but I
mean it really can be a magnifier of
biases as well and that's what we like
to focus on and what we've tried to make
a lot of effort doing at the ACLU is to
really focus on the human stories and
the fact that if you send tools to
certain communities and if those tools
are collecting information about members
in those communities and if you're
following your old patterns of policing
you're going to result in databases that
are filled with information about
certain communities and not other
communities the eff did a great public
records act request and story a few
years ago about Oakland's ALPR program
they requested during the week of
Ramadan and they looked for information
about the use of they asked for the hits
all of the hits of the lpr machines and
then they map them out and then they
overlaid racial data and socio-economic
data and it was so stark I mean whether
it was deliberate or not and it would
likely was not deliberate all the hits
although the deepest Purple's on the map
were in downtown Oakland not in the
hills of Oakland not in piedmont
similarly for and that that overlapped
with the poorest communities that
overlapped with the
the the black communities and so it just
goes to show that like if these tools
are rolled out there they're going to be
a force multiplier but they are also
going to multiply the biases that
already exists in the way with police
and if they're not safeguards on that
data and how its collected and how it's
retained then it's going to be you know
in orders of magnitude of amplifying
these biases is there is another
question
yeah I was hoping you could talk a
little bit more about parallel
construction and the due process issues
that raises I found in DC talking to a
lot of congressional staffers who are
more or less willing to sacrifice all of
our privacy rights for security against
mosquito bites suddenly pause once you
get to the part about parallel
construction and say wait you have
police officers lying in court under
oath about the origins of evidence that
seems to be perjury on a mass scale on
my question is are you seeing are
parallel construction in courts or
evidence laundering or perjury whatever
you want to call it at a systemic scale
and if so what is the response to
prosecutors and police officers seeming
happy to circumvent due process rights
of potentially tens of thousands of
dependence I'd say absolutely systemic
without a doubt on whether you and
they're so of course different gradients
of parallel construction you have you
have cases where yes you have a police
officer lying in open court about where
he found a piece of information you see
that all the time but then you also have
cases where the police department or the
prosecutor just misleading in math so
the classic example this with stingrays
is on and this took place in Washington
as well as many other places around the
country is that you had these police
departments going to judges and saying
we just need a pen register and so what
a pen register is is a is a device that
is a relative when you know we had
actual phones with wires and and what
the Pinterest would do is basically just
monitor kind of outgoing and incoming
calls like this number dialed this at
this time
the call lasted this long so that type
of metadata about landline phone calls
so they were using existing pen register
laws to work
request the information collected by a
stingray obviously these technologies do
not map to each other but they didn't
bother to clarify this point to anyone
criminal defense attorneys judges even
so we had this fantastic kind of
incident in in Washington where it
became apparent that I'm thanks to some
activists that that coma had a stingray
that they were using it kind of
persistently and a local journalist by
the name of Cape Martin who works for
the tacoma news tribune had the
wonderful idea to basically call it the
judge and say hey do you notice
stingrays and the judge said what and
have no idea and you know the fact that
he had been misled it willfully and
intentionally by the police department's
coupled with the fact that a reporter
called him to ask about it led to
basically a very very upset judge who
got a bunch of other judges very very
upset and change the rules internally
for how they would process these types
of requests but to answer your question
you know
yes i have absolutely systemic
across-the-board yeah and these systemic
problems stem from the confidentiality
agreement that the FBI has been making
these local police department sign
before getting the stingrays right so we
got one of these documents in one of our
public records request litigation and
one of the paragraphs is you will not
essentially not disclose any information
about stingrays in number of
circumstances including in response to
court-ordered disclosure unless you get
private concern of FBI and if it looks
like you're going to have to disclose
that information we may request that you
drop the prosecution and that was in the
confidentiality agreement so there's
already the culture of trying to not get
this stuff in the court and trying to
mislead yeah i think i think this is as
Moore's learned and was revealed about
stingrays we are seeing a shift though
in the willingness for local you know
law enforcement to just dive right into
these NDA's and buying these tools i
know in alameda county which which is
where I
it's not only of drones there but they
also have stingrays advocates discovered
that there were going to do the DA was
seeking out an upgrade to their existing
stingray to something that could track
4G and LTE cell phones and activist
caucus at the right time because they
looked at the minutes and agenda and
they saw it on there and brought it to
the attention of the DA and the board of
supervisors and really past what is
probably i would call the model local
stingray policy requiring a warrant
under and a new California law called
calacatta requiring a warrant for the
use of this tool and requiring none of
these fit doesn't allow for any of these
fishing expeditions when you drive
through community without an MZ number
already that you're looking for
so really reduces the sort of secondary
effects on third parties but I don't
think alameda county has entered into
their NDA because they would have to it
would a he would like violates so many
parts of the NDA the sort of
transparency that's already been forced
on the community and enforced on not the
community forced on elected leaders in
the law enforcement and so I think there
were seeing a shift and I think Harrison
and FBI are scrambling to figure out how
to keep these secret going forward as
places like alameda county and seattle
in New York really push back on them
will take that question
yeah i remember reading an article where
after it was revealed that an aerial
drone had taken pictures and it lets
this a kidnapper being caught that
actually led to a town hall meeting and
one of the responses from one of
somebody who supported the drone was a
of when it's your kid then you would
support it was your kid right so when
these things do come to the forefront
when it does lead to a town hall meeting
and these and they're actually
discussing it do on the whole see it's
civilians the communities supporting it
or standing against it and uh and what's
the best way to approach somebody who
completely understands the issues still
feel safer because of these LPRs and
things like that and talk about the
surveillance independent yeah so I mean
I think Ali it really depends on the
context right and when they were these
conversations come up I think you're
absolutely right that town hall meetings
in the right context ever
one's gonna go yes surveillance please
because I'm worried about you don't
think of the children that kind of thing
and so one way that i found is actually
good to kind of start some of these
conversations and to learn some of the
stories and to kind of illustrate the
need for kind of common-sense controls
to surveillance is actually surveillance
self-defense conversations with people
so one thing that we've done the ACLU of
Washington is actually have some basic
kind of surveillance self-defense and
threat modeling conversations with
domestic violence survivor advocacy
groups for whom you know resisting
surveillance can actually be a a
fundamental kind of important life or
death question and the conversation
turned to geolocation information and
turn to ALPR send this discussion of the
fact that a lot of this fairly sensitive
geolocation information is being
captured by lpars well the state
admission that the purpose of alp ours
is to protect against these terrible
scenarios to find stolen cars to find
amber alert vehicles where a child has
been kidnapped that type of thing but as
we all know the reality is is that this
location data is held in incredibly
large databases on with millions and
millions in some in some cases billions
of Records it is shared with the feds
that is shared with private companies
sometimes private investigators can get
access to these things members of the
public can get access to them so all the
sudden this conversation with these
these domestic violence survivor groups
turn to well surveillance self-defense
only go so far right there are some
cases where because law enforcement or
because other agencies are collecting
you limitless amounts of information and
the fact that other people get access to
it that there's a there's a there's a
threat that you have to confront so all
the sudden we had these groups that
typically didn't think or talk a whole
lot about government surveillance you
volunteering to help us talk to
legislators about why we need
restrictions on an automated license
plate readers which is a wonderful turn
to be able to have you know this type of
collaboration it makes for really
effective storytelling you know to
legislators that typically when the ACLU
gets up what you know to testify in a
hearing for a bill talks about Big
Brother and and you know why privacy is
important in surveillance you know a lot
of legislators glaze over you get a
domestic violence you know advocacy
survivor advocacy group come up all the
sudden people start paying attention
because you have these really compelling
personal stories that did that bring it
down into the real world for them and so
there's a lot of opportunities there
think it's also important to say no
we're not saying like no police
surveillance technologies ever for the
most part you know what we're saying is
well it depends on the technology but a
Warren is appropriate if there's an
intrusion on privacy and there are
emergency exceptions to that there are
some state law swear you still you know
you you can get it warn't really quickly
in case of an emergency or there might
just be a you know you just go and fly
drone if there is an immediate emergency
so you know what we're talking about is
you know what level of process is
appropriate before put the police
engaged in surveillance of communities
yeah i think to piggyback on what Jared
was saying for us in passing reforms in
a place like santa clara county where we
recently worked with local advocates to
pass an ordinance that requires there be
public process noticed the public about
any proposed acquisition so before the
money is even applied for the federal
government oversight for tools that have
been voted on by local legislators there
has to be a strict use policy in place
that addresses all the sort of data
concerns including security and
retention and sharing with others and
then also annual auditing so one of
these recently passed one of these
ordinances recently passed in santa
clara and it would not have passed have
the ACLU simply supported it
what we relied on was it started with
conversations with activists and
community members bringing to bear our
knowledge about the actual surveillance
tools to talk about the ways in which it
impacts their lives so we had
organizations like care the council on
american-islamic relations there who
have a you know history of legitimate
and you know concrete concerns about
government police surveillance we had
the Center for Media justice
we had restored the fourth we had ESF of
course and so many different community
members and a lot of younger community
members to who are more tech savvy and
more interested in these issues and use
cellphones obviously and and understand
these things we have those conversations
in the lead-up to meetings via call via
in person meaning and really got on the
same page about the different interests
that we want to we wanted to bring the
bear and then we had individual meetings
in the groups have individual meetings
with actual local legislators which i
would encourage folks to do you see law
enforcement adopting these tools are
seeking to adopt these tools email tweet
at your local city council member border
supervisor your state legislature set up
a meeting they tend to be like really
responsive and want to do a really good
job they're often elected pretty
frequently so they may also need to be
really responsive and we found that to
be great and in the lead-up to those
meetings where law enforcement is
inevitably going to put up the defense
of these tools and tau out the story
maybe that was like and fed to them by
federal law enforcement out a story
about how it saves X number of people or
how it's great for this sort of
kidnapping case in adjacent county that
is way far away or something so I think
that's been really effective before we
take another question I just wanted to
make sure we have time to talk about
other solutions and ways in which once
this is all out there once we've got
community members interested and once
you know we're starting to move towards
you're going to these meetings and
thinking about reforms what are this bad
we approach solutions i just talked
about one solution which is like a local
legislation that can be passed but
that's obviously not the only type
solution so well and I think a local
legislation is probably the best
opportunity to to combat this thing at
the local level I mean of course you
know passing laws at the state level at
the federal level kind of restricting
surveillance is important but at the
local level if you can limit a local law
enforcement ability to acquire these
things in the first place that it's it's
a huge win but there's a really
fundamental important caveat to that and
that's that if you don't draft that that
legislation very carefully on
or you kind of don't have the political
capital to do so there's opportunities
for expectations there so the first
obvious one is that while Seattle Police
Department they're subject to an
ordinance in Seattle that limits their
ability to acquire a stingray without
approval for the City Council but
nothing stops them from using tacoma
stingray so you have this problem where
it becomes willing to send an operator
and and a you know a machine up you know
to seattle for the day they can use that
and and run it on their own
no problem the problem is even worse for
federal agencies so most states have
laws commonly referred to as silver
platter doctrine laws which say that if
federal law enforcement hands over the
proceeds of an investigation or
operation to local law enforcement local
law enforcement can use that even if it
would have been illegal for local law
enforcement to collect it so you can
write in your constitution you know
using a stingray is illegal but as long
as you have these silver platter
doctrines which are typically judicial
law right it's not something that's
written in the statute is something that
judges have developed over time if you
have that on the books then the problem
is is that doesn't matter what the
Constitution said it doesn't matter what
what laws legislators passed you know
the feds can still handle the program
and the proceeds of those investigations
over local law enforcement so there's
but there are ways you can limit that
I'm and and kind of work against it at
the the easiest one is to say you not
you're not only limited from acquiring
these technologies you're also limited
from providing material support to
federal agencies that are engaging in
this so for example the the example I
gave earlier about putting up a video
cameras on telephone poles you have a
lot like that in place and then all the
sudden right
the feds can't use your telephone poles
right without some type of court order
or some type of action compelling the
local government to do so on so that
there's lots of ways to combat these
kind of caveats but the important
limitation of these laws is that the
feds can still come in often in most
cases and and connect the same type of
surveillance
yeah i also agree that the local law
approach is one of the best ways it
really gets at the
threshold problem which is that we don't
have a clear sense of everything that's
going on in terms of Police acquisition
of surveillance technologies and without
knowing the the full range of what we're
talking about it's really hard to create
a loss that get at the substantive
problems of each technology so we do
that as well and we want to have laws in
place that ensure that warrants are
required for use of certain technologies
but as as a first step would be really
helpful to know what technologies were
talking about i mean i think in addition
to crafting the loss carefully it's a
critical about you have we've built a
community when there's a such a law in
place that cares about these issues and
that will weigh in because you have a
few of a transparency law and and the
agency is being transparent but nobody
cares that is really accomplishing the
purpose and it creates opportunities for
counter-surveillance I mean I think
there's an inevitability here that these
local law enforcement agencies are going
to acquire some of these technologies
are going to utilize some of these
technologies but if we have it on the
books that they have these things that
they're using these things
it enables you know more sophisticated
activist groups to engage in the counter
surveillance and and take measures to
protect themselves against against you
know this this type of activity i think
a big part of it is just changing the
conversation passing this legislation it
creates you know means and and a medium
for exposing these tools and enforcing
and putting in place strict safeguards
but also just changes the conversation
about what is appropriate to do if I'm
law enforcement in this community and it
will create these cause these
conversations we're slowly but surely
they will know there will be a historic
memory in local police department or in
the Sheriff's Department in the DA's
office about what happens when we try to
move forward on the surveillance
technologies without going to the
community first and that's ultimately
the goal here is to make sure that that
conversation happens early and often and
that you know the the ordinance or the
local legislation doesn't even need to
be turned to in a form
most sense because those conversations
are happening i'm sure another question
back at the beginning of this talk you
briefly mentioned technologies that go
to social media scrape them and then run
analysis on that and it sounded like
they use a lot of publicly available
data to do that and it's very easy to
see how those are the technologies can
be abused or exacerbate existing
problems however it is using publicly
available data and there's probably a
lot of people in the same room who could
do the same and then throw in a pretty
graph on reddit um how do you write laws
that stop that will limit that because
it seems like you don't have a lot of
the privacy protections available to
build off of
go ahead yeah so I'm i think it's not
it's not exclusively a privacy argument
it's it's a free speech argument so
Seattle actually has this really really
old law they call the intelligence
ordinance which limits the collection of
information about people's political
beliefs in this law was passed in the
early eighties late seventies right you
know following a period of lots of
activism and and political turmoil and
the law was passed because there was a
sense that we just shouldn't ever trust
police with information about people's
political beliefs that when certain
parties come into power or when their
shifts in in kind of predominant
political you know mentalities that that
information will be inherently misused
that it that it is harmful inherently
for police to have access to that
information
I'm and so I think you see that carried
through in what we've seen you don't
happen to a lot of the black lives
matter protesters and things like that
is that it's just not appropriate for
the police to hold onto this information
absent incredibly concrete reasons to do
so and even then you know I personally
am incredibly skeptical of it but you
know there is precedent for having lost
like this past I think there's two or
three of these in the country and it
would be interesting to try and update
them so that they limited this type of
activity is currently I think that
they're drafted in a way that never
contemplated you know Facebook or
Twitter anything
yeah i think you know we make rules all
the time as a cook as a size society
about what law enforcement may do that
have nothing to do with the
constitutional issues at places like yes
this is we believe a privacy issue we
believe it's a First Amendment issue but
also we don't think police should be on
facebook at work and we mean that in
more than one way like we have the power
as a society to decide that there are
certain lines going to draw about police
conduct in law enforcement conduct and
if that involves them not being able to
go whole cell search for hashtags that
are related to peaceful protesters
without any sort of justification that
they may be written down and justified
to a supervisor or to a judge will then
so be it can't do that we can decide
they can't do that
yeah so I think that about wraps up our
talk
thanks guys for coming out and
if you have questions
yes you have additional questions the
group here will actually be taking
questions in the back