good afternoon everyone
it's very good to see you it's I'm kind
of scared forgive me
it's great to see you wait to see you on
sunday at hope I know we're all kinda
party after all kind of tired from
Saturday night the concerts it means a
lot to me that you're all here and I
want to thank you
so that said I'm going to dive right
into my talk
this is constructing XO cortices with
hookah and halo so just a moment
okay there we go now the slides are
properly sized my obligatory disclaimer
I'm speaking only for myself not my
employers past present or future so a
brief overview of my talk I'm going to
talk about what an extra cortex is when
talk about some possible components of
one we're talking about what they can do
i'm also going to go into a one of the
applications i built into my own exit
cortex that use fairly heavily which is
a personal web archive i'm going to
describe how you can build 1 i'm going
to talk about the software you can use
to build one and i'm going to talk about
how to interact with the framework used
to build next cortex the framework is
called human i'm going to show a simple
agent network in a complex agent network
i'm gonna show what the events that
comprising information inside the
framework look like then i'm going to
talk about the soft stuff which is why I
built next cortex and what I do with it
I'm going to show a few of the agent
networks that i use then i'm going to
talk about what I get out of it and what
you guys can get out of it
so let's move on what is an extra cortex
well the and of course there's a Greek
Greek perfect XO meeting outside or
external to the word extra cortex was
first postulated or the concept of the
neck support ex-excuse me was first
postulated by JCR Licklider in march of
1960 and paper he wrote called main
computer symbiosis and he said that an
extra cortex was a either a hypothetical
or a nascent additional cortex of the
human brain situated outside of the
organism in a day which would function
in addition to the various lobes of the
brain
in like the frontal parietal occipital
the temporal lobe etc etc
he also said that next cortex
constituted and external information
processing system which could provide
additional cognitive capacity or
abilities to the human mind which not
yet which are not yet directly connected
to the human brain but we're starting to
get there we've got TCS TMS brain gate
and these direct interface technologies
are going to be developing in years to
come but that's I'm not going to touch
on this a couple years later
Benjamin Houston wrote that in extra
cortex would be an organ that resides
outside of the brain that aids and
high-level thinking
ideally they would be a symbiotic
relationship between the user and the
information processing infrastructure
where each compliments and compensates
for the shortcomings of the other
ultimately where the book where the bits
meet the hardware and XO cortex is a
hardware and software construct which
works in concert with the brain to
extend its capabilities so some possible
components of an extra cortex they're
actually surprisingly common these days
we've got networked handheld devices
like smart watches and smart glasses
pretty much everyone has a cell phone
these days so we've got cellular data
service Wi-Fi and bluetooth for
interfacing devices it will as well as
accessing information storage services
in there are information processing and
storage capabilities which are
everything from notebook computers
netbook computers laptops all the way up
to virtual machines and bare metal of
course their security infrastructure
like multi-factor authentication
protecting access to these assets
firewalls IDS's IPS is enforced crypto
real-time response
you know the drill and there is
extremely addressable mass storage blogs
link collections wiki's personal
archives file dumps home directories in
short it's worse stuff it's all of the
information that you collect you
accumulate you process you go through
later to draw conclusions to come up
with new ideas and implement those ideas
and of course there is the software that
hooks it all together lots of software
gonna shut down the feedback here
so what can XO cortex do ultimately
whatever you design it to do explore
texts from functional functional modules
can monitor data feeds in real-time and
respond to them they can manage some
aspects of your finances they can
implement a personal search engine they
can manage an archived data on your
behalf they can monitor your
infrastructure and they can find things
that are useful to you that you didn't
know about previously the application
that i mentioned earlier is a personal
web archive and I've got it broken down
in broadly speaking in a functional
modules the user interface front end is
an instant messenger client that's
running on both my smartphone in my
desktop UI back-end is a bot which is
connected to the same xmpp server that
stores requested a message queue
ok I was fun up cut down the feedback
all right and the user interface
back-end is not connected to the same is
xmpp server that stores incoming
requests a message queue there is a
software agent that pulls that message
queue every 60 seconds configurable i'm
looking for urls and when it finds the
URL it sniffs it out of the message and
it downloads it when it downloads HTML
it renders an HTML into text and then
excuse me it's I'm really sorry and then
upload it into the archive application
the archive itself is an application
that source text very efficiently and
presents it in formats easy-to-read
later you there also makes it easy to
edit pages rename pages and delete pages
i use a copy of etherpad light with the
rest api built with the rest api plugin
for it
there's also a search engine which lets
you search the archive for desired
content later because it's kind of
worthless if you can't find all the
stuff you have
and there was no venting system which
which alerts the user when archival is
complete or when a problem arises
so whenever and so whenever the either
the page is archived tour there's an
error i get an email on my phone that
either has the URL to my personal
archive that goes right to that page or
i get an error message that describes
what happened couldn't access the page
43 44 what have you
ok now how can you build an extra cortex
if you have a need to build one
well first you have to figure out what
you want to accomplish do you want to
just experiment with it do you want to
build an archive do you want to
experiment with machine learning
do you want to build automation system
that plugs into different api's now you
want to have some idea of what you want
to accomplish then stand up a server to
virtual machines work well bare metal
works well or you can set up an account
with a service like haiku and then
upload your code to interact with it
that way
install your software build some major
networks build some BOTS if you want
that sit outside of it but interact with
those agents and I'll get into the
distinction a little bit later and then
set up your user interface UI can be
minimal which is set it and forget it
the agents run in the background
occasionally you'll get a message
there's medium there the user interface
can be can have a use can use telephones
for user interface you can send SMS
messages have them picked up for buying
SMS provider parsley for specific
correctness parts the commands out have
it obey the commands you can use you can
send commands to the agent networks via
email or you can use some nifty app like
an xmpp client or something like deeper
kyo and then you can pretty much enjoy
not having to hit refresh all the time
the software used to build Mexico cortex
is based around
all right thinking is based around a
software framework by andrew canty no
called hougan it's a framework for
building networks of autonomous agents
that carry out tasks it's written in
Ruby it uses rails for the front end and
it has an event-based architecture
internally there are dozens of classes
of agents that are optimized for
carrying out specific tasks external
butt plugged into hougan is a lot of my
own code which is called halo which is a
collection of box to carry out more
complex tasks that hooligans event based
architecture isn't well suited for the
thing about the event based architecture
is it's very good for short turnaround
time tasks and event comes in its
processed it gets sent to another agent
that asian processes it gets sent to
another agent it gets processed yet what
happens the turnaround time for that is
usually in order a couple seconds
unfortunately the human frame work isn't
well suited for things like taking a
rather large volume of texts running
through a text to speech synthesizer
then placing a voice over IP call
playing the synthesized speech over the
call and then tearing everything down
but a bought that about that takes cues
from Hogan and is running x external to
the event scheduler is much more suited
for that so some of the bots that
built-in that comprise halo speech
synthesis voice-over-ip clients
integration with other external
applications i wrote interfaces for
etherpad light i wrote and wrote
interfaces for gps receivers and mapping
software i also wrote a fair amount of
software that interfaces with search
engines there are different ways to
interact with who can have all the
agents there there are basically three
classes of agent input processing and
output to interact with you can
there are a fair amount of input agents
there's a web hook agent which basically
you get your of webhook you give it an
API key it pulls events out packages
those events and send them on their way
can read from and right to MQTT message
queues and subscribe to
there's a website agent which lets you
interface which lets you interact with
other websites and AP is and there are
also many different agents for specific
services like Trello Weather Underground
a couple of flight booking services
things like that and there is also an
agent which is disabled by default which
lets you run show commands local to the
box student is running on so it will
Spanish Oh it'll run as it'll run a
script or Commander something capture
standardout standard error package those
as an event in a minute and put them
into the internal event queue the output
agents are pretty straightforward
there's EMQ th and of course there are
couple of agent classes which interact
with other websites and AP is there is
also a post agent which lets you make
arbitrary HTTP requests of arbitrary
sites so get foot delete head stuff like
that and there is a data output agent
which let's see which sets up a custom
RSS feed or a custom rest api which
means Jason this is probably one of the
simplest agent networks that you can
build in an extra cortex here's an RSS
agent which expects RSS feed to change
every five days the clean flag basically
tells the are the xml parser inside of
the agent assume that this is good at
this is well formed and well-formatted
xml you start getting errors he talked
about to true and will do its best to
clean up the xml and then pull events
out of it and then here's the URL of the
RSS feed to poll on some schedule so
2600 Comstock RSS xml for every entry
the in the XML document that has changed
intimate it's packaged made it as an
event and each of those events is sent
to an email agent which as the name
implies a construct smtp messages so the
subject line will consist of the title
of the article from that from that entry
in your RSS feed the headline which is
the first line of the email it consists
of this vline published on it published
the body of the email the script the
description field of the RSS of the post
on the website two line breaks and then
the contents of the content field in the
RSS event and expected receive period
days it will expect to receive an event
at least once every 365 days and if it
doesn't it will shut itself down and
assume it's a narrow state and every
time
femaleagent fires the articles email
automatically it by default it goes to
an email address that's configured in
the Inhumans and file it's the system
configuration file but you can also give
it a arbitrary list of email addresses
to send events to here's a more complex
agent design i can show you the source
code for it but it would span probably
20 slides because it's pretty involved
but at a high level here's where
consists of there's an RSS agent which
pulls the RSS feed for the DNA lounge
archive on archive.org the the DNA
lounge in San Francisco makes available
for certain period of time downloadable
mp3's of all the concerts and club
nights they hold and there's a small
collective in San Francisco that
downloads mp3's and upload them to the
internet archive which has and that
collection has its own RSS feed so i
have an RSS agent that pulls that RSS
feed every 24 hours and then it sends
the events from that RSS feed to a
couple of trigger agents which look for
specific keywords in the title field so
I look for information society concerts
Cruxshadows concerts anamanaguchi
concerts and turbo drive which is a club
mate i think they don't happen often
enough but what about that there are a
couple of RSS agents which also pull the
internet archive's hacker con collection
the infocomm cabinet collection which is
their archive of curiosa and ephemera
from the game company infocomm and in
the internet archive's national security
archive which i highly recommend the
events from those the RSS agents get
sent through a number of trigger agents
of which i've listed just a few here
which look for another specific set of
keywords for example COINTELPRO packing
freak all of these events then get sent
through a deduplication agent which has
a memory of a fixed size of events and
every time an event reaches it it goes
back through its memory to see if it's
ever seen it
for I deduplicate based upon the human
readable message written by the trigger
agents I could just as easily duplicate
by based on the globally unique ID feet
a little unique ID in the ID field of
the RSS event but it's easier to
duplicate on human readable message and
everything that makes it through the
deduplication phase gets emailed so I
get a direct link to download whatever
just hit one of those archives
this is what one of the events looks
like it's a pretty standard Jason
document and this is from an RSS feed
this is from an RSS agent so I've had to
cut it down by about 30 lines but I
think you get the gist of what it looks
like date published last updated those
are two those are timestamps in two
different formats so depending on what
you want to do with them you pick one of
the other the specific URL of the
article the description of the article
which is basically a bit above the fold
on the in the content management system
content is the complete it the entire
article from the content management
system the title of the article the
author's is a Jason array of strings
where each spring is the byline of one
of the authors and categories is a JSON
array of strings for each string is one
of the categories the CMS uses to manage
articles
ok so now you're probably wondering why
I built next to cortex to do all this
crazy stuff
well it didn't start out as a unified
project reading personal tool it was my
it was my I want to learn about food
project my started college where food
was C or parole or Python or how do i
make HTTP requests had white parts HTML
how do i do how do i programmatically
recognize and sort text stuff like that
it was also a manifestation of my hey
I'm not on dial-up syndrome because i
discovered the joys of ethernet in the
comp side or this meant that I had
constant access to the net and all the
information sources on it which also
meant that i don't have enough time to
keep up with everything and became
something of information junkie so i
started writing bots that would pull all
the stuff that I kept reading in between
classes
and it would filter it based upon what I
was interested in and I would get an
email every couple of hours with a
digest of what popped up and keep in
mind that RSS wasn't invented until 1999
and the atom spec didn't make it big
until about two years later so years
went by and I kept rewriting my code I
kept having to modify it because the net
changes and it eventually mutated into
this one maintainable you know shoggoth
of hacks and eventually to stand up one
new bought I was having to do
substantial rewrites to an entire bot so
i started writing my own framework to
re-implement all of these agents and
make them easier to maintain I got a
proof-of-concept going to show that some
of my co-workers and my coworker said
hey there's this thing called who can
written by andrew canty know why don't
you take a look at it so I took a look
at it and realized in about 60 seconds
that it did way more than my weekends of
hacking did so i scrapped my own code
base and poured all my stuff over to get
in afternoon and i started building on
top of hougan and i've been using it
ever since I see no reason to reinvent
the wheel if something is already
written a wheel that is way better than
anything i can do what i can do however
is I can't go on top of it i can extend
it i can try to add new stuff to it I
can try to make it more useful i started
writing bots that were external human
because i also ran into some hooligans
functional limits so what do I do with
my exit cortex I i tend to name my agent
Network sandbox so i can keep them
straight in my head I try to make them
if not automatically relevant then at
least you know somewhat catchy
so for example Antigone whenever is so
for example whenever I send Antigone a
URL it submits that URL to a bunch of
certain a bunch of independent search
engines that rely at least in part on
user interactions it also submit that
URL to my copy of ya see which is a
personal open-source search then search
engine written in Java which uses the
which uses a distributed hash table to
form a global network of independent
search engines
so basically you can make queries of it
and i have a man copy that I submit urls
to so I have a personal search engine
and I submit a copy to the global search
engine network because I'm trying to
help build jackhammer it implements my
personal web archive Argus and Montauk
our interfaces to my personal search
engines because i have a couple of
servers that are full of their full of
files and stuff and I keep trying to
keep them indexed butterfly in China is
an agent network that compiles daily
weather and air quality index reports
cherry bomb monitors police fire ems
radio dispatch networks for
statistically unusual spikes and
listenership Edison follows and analyzes
feeds of several dozen news agencies
World Health Organization bunch of
defense-related news magazines and
online archives firefly monitors
currency and cryptocurrency networks
markets accounts and addresses 464
statistically unusual activity which
monitors manufacturer websites linux
distros exploit archive stuff like that
looking for new vulnerabilities is that
to keep my own stuff updated and i use
it i use glitch a heavily at work to
keep situational awareness for what we
have to do next
ironmonger follow the stock prices of
the 20 largest defense contractors
petroleum markets investment funds and
multinational corporations around the
world at to as a sort of indicator of
geopolitical change pathfinder is
plugged into the public API is of
several public transit services
calculates best routes and alerts on
delays and police activities because
Bart shuts down or get snarled up the
weirdest times and I like to know why
and switchboard carries that secretarial
duties for me she monitors my email
addresses watching watches for new files
on different services like box.com
dropbox stuff on pastebin things like
that switchboard automatically post my
blog and syndicate's my blog posts
switchboard has a couple of aid of agent
networks that and inform certain people
certain new developments like things
going on commits to get up things like
that
I because google took away SMS
messaging for calendar i have my own
calendaring service now and I get SMS
messages as reminders and also
switchboard his agent networks which
monitor the credits that I have
available to me in certain paid
subscription accounts like showed an and
my voice over IP provider so if I start
getting low i get an email and then i
have to throw some money at them and
crank my account balance up
ok demo time pls being with gods be with
me
ok so this is butterfly in China i'm
using hooligans graphical graphical
flowcharting application to show how the
agents played in a nut in a nutshell i'm
going to show the agent network for New
York City this is a website agent that
pulls the Equality Index forecast for
New York City going to show that looks
like real quick
this is the schedule every morning at
four a.m. eastern time
this is the list of agents that will
receive events that are generated by
this agent and this is basically the
source code to the agent this particular
agent expects an update to show up every
seven days
this is the URL I that it pulls data
from aaron out there no api dot org
which basically provides an API off air
quality indexes here's the forecast zip
code that's asks for Jason asks for the
forecast for the area code 101 and a
distance of twenty-five kilometers and
there is a liquid templating tag here
for my api key you email them they'll
give you an API key they just asked you
not to abuse the service surprising
number of places are like that if you
email them and ask very nicely for api
key so let's give it to you they might
ask you to make fewer than 1,000 or
10,000 requests an hour but that's not
difficult
this agents going to expect
Jason to come back and every Jason
document gets its going to expect that
the Jason document will have changed if
it hasn't changed
don't throw it I'll just throw the event
away and go to sleep but it has changed
it will parse the JSON document and it
will use Jason paths to pick out two of
the entries which is a qy at which is a
numerical value and what that numerical
value corresponds to as an english word
and it will pack them into the variables
aqi and summary respectively and it will
admit it will pass that copies that
event on 24 other agents which are
trigger agents and basically they party
event looking for something very
specific and all show one of those looks
like whenever a trigger agent receives
an event it runs you know schedule them
and basically it expects to receive an
event every seven days i will not keep
the event so after its part of state
made a determination will throw it away
that helps save room in the database and
the rules that it matches against our it
looks at the value of the variable aqi
any event and if it is greater than 101
and if it is less than or equal 250 it
will form the message today is air
quality forecast is value variable
summary actual that actually actual aqi
value is the value of a Qi the AQI is
unhealthy today be extremely careful
have your inhaler on you
this goes into an event formatting agent
which basically takes events and makes
another event by putting together bits
and pieces of other events and this one
is really simple take the value of
message for you from whatever messaging
from whatever event receives copy the
value into another value called message
and throw it down the chain and there is
another agent sitting over here which
only gets it
weather forecasts this polls this is
whether agent i havenít i have an API
key for weather underground com
and all it does is it contacts weather
underground com gets weather forecast
for the zip code 101 expect it to change
once every two days and then it admits
that event and that event goes to
another event formatting agent today's
weather forecast for location is
conditions with a high of 80 degrees
Fahrenheit and low-flow degrees
Fahrenheit the average humidity is
average humidity % and it all that goes
into an email digest agent which runs on
a certain schedule today is New York
City weather report headline here is
your new york city new york weather
report for today
here are two email addresses that
receive it and that's pretty much and
this is repeated several times the next
agent network is cherry bomb
cherry cherry bombs the event hmm is the
event is the asian network which
monitors please scanners i'm just going
to show very briefly how that works i'm
not going to go into too much detail if
you if you go into broadcasting 5.com
you will find please scanners plugged
into the plug into the net all over the
world and for each page there's a little
counter that says how many people are
listening to at any one time and that
little counter on the web page is a CSS
entity called dot C so this agent pulls
down the HTML Parsons that buzzes out
the cs entity dot C grabs the text of it
and then emits it in an event and then
that numerical value goes through a peak
detector and what the peak detector does
is the peak detector has a 14-day memory
that value is updated once every 30
minutes and if that value changes by two
standard deviations on five minutes if
on a five-minute time scale it sends a
message and then I get an email on my I
get a link actually sent to my phone it
through paper do I can tap on the link i
go right to radioreference com and I'm
listening in on the police
I do it for the bart police dispatch I
do it for the Oakland police dispatch i
do it for San Francisco Bay Area ems an
element of Alameda California fire
dispatch Edison is my News bot i guess i
should say newsagent network and then
follows The Associated Press twitter
feed and a very large number of new
sources from united states where I live
outside of the United States Voice of
America voice of Europe as a haitian
moon the world health organization a
bunch of defense-related journals like
next governor defense news national
interest
here's the example age and I pulled out
for the DNA lounge the blacklisted 411
collection are archived that works
mapping the internet data set which is a
kind of fun to poke around in sometimes
the archive that works afrikaans
collection they have an extensive
collection of media from pretty much
every hacker con it's ever been held i
highly recommend it
defense one is another defense wait a
magazine and electro space and the last
agent network i would like to show off
is ironmonger ironmonger pulls b-stock
pool stock ticker information for
defense contractors here's the opec
crude oil reference basket price
rds-a hok SI y and for each of these
there is a peak detector which watches
for rapid stock price changes on the
order of two-and-a-half standard
deviations and five minutes as well as
trade volume changes i get asked you
standard deviations in five minutes that
usually means that somebody's I've made
a very large by a very large cell or
somebody's closed a very large contract
which usually means that something is
going to go very wrong somewhere in the
world
ok so what do I get out of this because
I'm self-admitted information junkie but
I admit I spend a lot of time at what I
spend a lot less time at work reading
security briefs and websites and Twitter
feeds to keep on top of me
vulnerabilities and attacks and data
breaches I get more work done by
applying the information that i do
hunting it down while I'm doing research
for stuff I farm the tasks of executing
searches against multiple search engines
at the bots so I can spend more time
digesting the information in writing i
send one of my bots a text message a
text message or an xmpp message to the
effect of Montauk get me the top 40 hits
for top 40 hits for of I don't know
early 20s early 20th century chandeliers
and then five or ten minutes later i'll
get an email back with 40 search results
ranked by relevancy ranked also ranked
with a French word for it
there's a couple of other i also run the
results through a couple of natural
language processing modules so sentiment
detection sentiment detection analysis
so in addition to what the search engine
thinks relevancy is the Senate the
sentiment detection modules also make
also help determine how relevant it is
and then I'm writing
okay that looks interesting click open
up in a new tab in a new window go back
to writing I don't have to spend the
time grinding up to you know searching
down searching for data myself some of
the grinding up is done for me I find
out about new and interesting stuff
without having to spend hours a day
browsing dozens of sites i get email
digests with links that i scan whenever
I have a free moment and I filter out
stuff that's not interesting
whenever I go back and take her with
code because i tinker with code i also
have a framework for experimenting with
stuff in a new way because it's really
easy to get information into and out of
hougan in the form of RSS feeds and
custom rest api is I've been wanting to
experiment with neural networks and
machine learning systems so I've got
kind of a crazy idea but turn the screen
back on gamma there we go
I got the idea from reading an article
written by the guy who wrote a machine
learning system that would analyze posts
on Hacker News to determine what might
might might or might not be interesting
to him and I cause some amount of
controversy on hacker news i think i
like to try out myself
it also means that i even though i'm a
nympho junkie I get to spend more time
with my family got to spend more time
hacking and I get to spend more time
enjoying myself so now what can you get
out of it
this was a bit of this was a trick your
question answer noseriding these slides
so I thought about a lot of course is
news and social network monitoring for
whatever interests you and use cases
that you happen to have like keeping an
eye out for data for data breaches the
next master death or terrorist strike
I'm really sorry had to go there but I
think we're all worried about our
friends and family also everyone's
favorite like 20 days in extra cortex is
good for connecting devices and software
that so they can interact with each
other i have hopefully oh well hopefully
when I get home I'll start playing
around with the Mycroft speech
recognition system is an open-source
speech recognition package plan on
plugging it into my momma Dee jukebox as
well as my code I media box and living
room so I could basically say something
to the effect of jukebox random default
playlist shuffle and I I've got music to
hack by i've also been toying with the
idea of interfacing in rtl based str1 of
the have a couple of the rtl e28 radio
scanners and which use the software
package gqr x which is built on top of
new radio it doesn't have a rest api yet
i'm going to write one but it does have
a very good network API so i also have
the sort of crazy idea of saying Mycroft
scan from 100 megahertz to 550 megahertz
and that the Raspberry Pi that I have
with the RTA 28 on it will just start
scanning on a on a predefined interval
and stop whenever find something
interesting
there's also something i plan on doing
at work which is connecting our radius
server to the to a copy of Medicine
plate using the RPC
p I so basically a new box joins the
network the user logs into the radius
server the radius server runs a script
that the radius server runs a script
that pings my XO cortex to say hey
there's a new box on the wireless
network XO cortex picks it up and hits
metasploit RPC API metasploit throws
auto ponad it and then the results of
auto pone get emailed to tech ops tech
ops intervenes if it's too bad
also i use extra cortex to interact with
cryptocurrency networks it's very easy
for someone to plug a copy of human into
point into pretty much any
bitcoin-litecoin or any other coin
gateway do book and do puts and gets on
the order book i don't know if any of
them support moving money out of the
Gateway to bank i wouldn't be surprised
if thats gets added very soon I if
you're into currency trading it's it is
something you can totally do my lawyers
probably gonna yell at me for after this
i'm also going to say that I accept no
responsibility for what may or may not
happen you you know you flip currency
your own risk i'm so going after that
exit exit for disease are also good for
responding to sudden changes in your
online social activity if you suddenly
stop posting for some reason or if you
post something sporty post certain
things at certain times or just post
certain things at all
you can set up XO cortex to respond in
pretty much whatever way you want it
could be a distress call it could be
texting your lawyer
it could be for all the people on this
list text them a copy of the National
Lawyers Guild phone number stuff like
that
XO cortices are also very good at
interacting with third-party api's and
making them do things are not really
supposed to do
everybody's played with google maps
mashups stuff like the Fukushima map the
it was Thor networks de las map before
that went offline but think about doing
not a map mashup but a mash-up with
halos speech synthesizer the Trello
agent to place phone costs to send text
messages voice over IP bought to send
phone to send phone number to create to
create and place phone calls over via
voice over IP and rtl8187 do scanner
which is constantly scanning police
bands as well as some code to detect
whenever listenership spikes so whenever
listenership spikes
yup the radio scanner tuned into that
frequency records three minutes
throws it over to the the voice over IP
box it just starts calling people and
playing it back because they're in that
general location and they need to know
what's going on and I think of well are
there any comments or questions when you
were talking about how you can get it to
go through search engines for you to LA
you research more easily
it seemed really interesting to me how
do you get it to collate the results
from multiple search engines into one
top 40 list
ok so what I used to do was I an early
version of the search engine bought had
a configuration file which specified
what search engines were in it as well
as these as well as what get it would
then download the HTML and it would pull
out all of the URLs and the HTML and
then sort them and then each of the and
free search engine configuration file
was what links to filter out because it
was late because they will be links to
like go back to the homepage or stuff
like that and then I stopped doing that
because of our way too difficult to
maintain so i stood up a copy of circs
is x SQ it's spelled s VAR x it's an
open source
front-end to search engines and it also
has a really good Jason API so basically
that search request gets routed to the
circs Search API circs in her search
simultaneously searches all all of these
search engines is configured for and
have it configured for 40 different
search engines pulls all the results
down does the first level correlation
based upon what it considers relevance
and then I have some additional glue
code that pulls down the HTML pages
rendered some his text and then runs it
through the NLP package to do the
sentiment analysis and then sort of
refills the scent sort of refills the
accuracy and then send it as an email
and so your system plugs into a lot of
different API is a lot of different
external things how are you handling
errors in those systems so the areas
that so for the agents that are built
into hougan it has its own really good
error handling it's usually stuff like
I'll give you an example for the twitter
agent it will send back
hey you got there for 20 if you've ever
used if you've ever got
if you've ever used Twitter API if you
go over your rate allotment delhi they
will hit you with an error 420 enhance
your calm which basically means you have
to wait for an hour you have an example
of a really good use case like this like
substantially helped you something or my
the two substantial use cases that I've
had for this were the search engine BOTS
because I find that I do more and more
writing preseason analyses at work which
means i have to research also the agent
network switch board because I wrote
switch forward to specifically manage
parts of my life I don't have time to
anymore so even though i've got a bunch
of email addresses for work you know
personal stuff all that I don't have
time to go through it even though I've
pared it down as far as i can so i look
for the really important stuff the
really important people and i get a
message on my phone saying hey this
person contacted you and I know that if
I'm getting notification that
says hey this person contacted you this
is really high priority i have to get to
it because otherwise i will just not
respond i'll forget to and it goes to
the bottom of the stack and then I find
myself apologizing a lot later lifestyle
management
are there any hooks for two dues or a
project management in inside of your
exit cortex my to do's are generally
part of my calendar and the way that I
manage that is i just put events in my
calendar and switchboard hits the ICS
feed and then whenever it starts coming
up sir getting text messages on it
I'll a project management know I've been
considering it I don't do a whole lot of
project management I don't actually know
how to do it so well i don't so i don't
know i don't know what this time what
would go into it i can carefully
speculate and say that if a project
management package had an API of some
kind specifically web-based API rest
will be great but doesn't have to be it
would be fairly easy to write an agent
network that would pull the API to pull
events out of it process it and then
make requests back to the API to update
the events that have pulled out
originally and specifics of it would be
applicable it it would be
application-specific but would
definitely possible
alright thanks for the talk
so do you use semantic web technologies
and now you talk about RSS a log i know
it is integrated with a semantic web in
certain ways but does actually affect
you know your whole infrastructure at
all now I'm i have I keep running across
stuff about the semantic web but the
information sources i use don't seem to
use them at all
it's kind of odd RSS as far as RSS is
concerned in the context of semantic web
it's a user interface that I don't see
it is i don't see it are treated as
really anything else you mentioned your
personal search engine
I've wondered if you could expand a
little more on some of the the tools and
techniques are using for the indexing
and searching your own files
ok so there is an opens there's an
open-source search engine called ya see
why Acy the homepage for is why AC y de
it is an open-source distributed search
engine
basically it's there's a distributed
hash table which every almost feeling
which almost every SE instance is
connected to and basically every SE
instance in the DHT just says hey I've
got this chunk of the index that's a
hash table and what people do is people
make search requests of it to see if
something's been indexed by a sea and
whatever node you that the query first
checks its own index to see if it's been
spidered if it hasn't been spider to
check the DHT to figure out what note
out there may have spider it and then if
it finds a match it relays the search
request to that particular node in the
HT and if that particular node has
indexed it its senses it sends the
search request back to the note that the
user contacted and the user gets the
searches gets the search results that
way you
users also submit domains to the a/c
network proactively to spider it or
proactively for spidering to make the
search engine more useful now you can
also set up a gassy node in what is
called Caruso mode which is it doesn't
interact with the sec network it's
entirely isolated but it's still a fully
functional search engine and it still
presents the XML and JSON API is for
interacting with it not only for making
search requests but for making requests
to submit urls for indexing i do both
have a personal one for stuff that's
just of interest to me because it's also
my way of keeping track of stuff I've
been looking up also to be a good
citizen of the net I also submits or
urls for spidering to the a scene
work to help make it more effective for
everyone else out there it's now the
front end to the other search engines i
use i did I decided to go with circs
just because I got tired of having to
rewrite my search engine parts or every
couple of weeks I'd rather just have a
better just have a cronjob do it get
pole and then update the copy of circs
restarted and just hit the ground
running
hi did you have to do anything to secure
the system and did you have any security
concerns when you were setting it up my
security concerns our paranoia because
the functionally speaking this is a big
part of who I am and what I do if you go
digging around in someone's extra cortex
are going to find out a lot about them
so there are serious privacy
implications to people getting access to
it which who probably should not have
access to it
I've built multiple multiple layers of
security and all of my stuff requires
API Keys everything even the stuff that
listens on the loopback interface only
the code is it's hard coded to listen on
the loopback interface so you would have
to physically compromised machine to get
into it I don't put all my eggs in one
basket have multiple servers around the
world some virtual summer physical there
don't all have copies of the same thing
all the back everything is backed up
every couple of hours all the backups
are encrypted all the backups are
downloaded taken offline two removable
drive
yeah I'm the parent just in case
unfortunately i'd i do log certain
things because occasionally I do because
I always tinkering with stuff and
buttons new crop up so i do have to go
through a debug it and having the option
of logging really helps with that for a
while I tried to go the all I don't log
anything route and but then I started
running into weird interactions and
weird errors i kept having to go back
okay i'm gonna copy and paste the
configuration for the logger module and
and then you know logger.debug blah blah
or i could just leave it in and then
turn it all the way down and we turn up
as I need to
everything is encrypted by default i
also have multiple layers of
authentication different usernames
different passwords separate databases
in the database servers separate service
accounts in the database separate backup
service accounts and databases which is
specific to those databases also
operating system diversity so you have a
very well-defined system of all the
different aspects have you thought about
creating as modules to share out with
other people to help them create there's
I have indeed so i have a get hub
repository that I'm going that i'm going
to post a link to write should actually
say switchboard is going to post a link
to a couple of days which has gotta
which has the source code to a bunch of
agent networks for Hogan so basically
you can import them into hougan and as
long as you have the API key for weather
naoto weather now receive to me
weather underground com they all come up
they'll start running you can look at
them you can play with them you can
tinker with them and you can use them to
learn how to build your own agent
networks also the halo all those bots
are in their own get a repository and
actually there's going to be a link to
that actually there was a link to the
repository in an earlier slide now
here's the link to the repository for
who can buy injured cantinho hi andrew
and down here is a link to the github
repository for halo which is all of my
box and I'm trying to document my bots
as well as i can so other people can
stand them up they can look at the code
they can tinker with them submit patches
make pull requests open bugs and
contribute more BOTS to it because I
really want to see this technology take
off as a personal technology also my
slides will go up on monday or tuesday
so this my slides were an HTML page so
you can just click on it you'll get
right to it
I know personally how do you manage all
the notifications
yeah that's so that took some
fine-tuning so the lowest priority stuff
are digest messages so that digest so
those digests get sent every couple of
hours and I might look at those if I'm
standing in line border something the
next level of priority up our individual
emails so if I get an email then that's
something that I should probably pay
closer attention to and that's usually
stuff coming out of iron monger the next
level of severity up or sensitive area
or severity is stuff that comes from
beeper daioh which is basically it's
sorta kinda like text messaging but not
and it's things like interesting stuff
that crops up on Twitter or things like
that
cryptocurrency network notifications the
next level of severity up from that is
actual SMS or mms text messages and the
next level security or next level is
very up from that are getting phone
calls from the voice over IP bought
because if something made it all the way
up to text is being turned into speech
which is then being placed over x over a
voice over IP network then I really have
to see that I also have some stuff in
also have some stuff going to make the
cortex that calls up other people just
in case those are usually health-related
stuff UI designer here so more the beer
behavior aspect of it the way that I see
you have a circle of advisers that is
like either digest or triggers that
comment you reduce your anxiety because
your new job
got it do you have any case of some part
of information that didn't come true
that you already had an intuition of
like this is missing and when it arrives
it's kinda you know what it means it's
like you're trying to get to a certain
trying to control situation and and some
information that's supposed to come
didn't but you already had the intuition
that he should
if I'm understanding you correctly then
I do things occasionally come across my
XO cortex that seemed fishy or not
complete never complete understanding
that if you can't learn get any Jewish
out of it
yeah it goes way right yeah a lot of
that is information security related
stuff like vulnerabilities data breaches
rivers of rumors of corporations being
compromised stuff like that sometimes it
makes sense sometimes it doesn't
some of the political and geopolitical
analysis stuff I don't take it as I
don't take it as perfect but I do take
it under advisement
for what it's worth the geopolitical the
geopolitical analysis stuff is I'm very
relieved when it winds up not being true
and if nothing else it's let me build up
a much better bullshit detector for
interacting with the world personally
rather thank you for your talk
do you have you developed have you had
any sense of anxiety over losing agency
/ part of this now externalized part of
your personality or part of your
affordances no i haven't developed
anxiety over it because it's actually
helped me manage how much information I
need to feel like I understand the world
and i don't have to do it personally now
I don't have to run around like a
chicken with my head cut off punching f5
every five minutes to see if something
new has come up but I mean you are you
all right are you concerned about losing
that now you've become
it's become part of you is now living
external to your biological being those
are giving certain types of abilities
and if those are stripped from you or if
they break and you no longer have access
to them to separate present you with any
sense of anxiety losing those abilities
it does give me a certain sense of
anxiety and the way that I manage that
is I try to go and media fasts about
three days a week so basically I you
know there's a there's a scheduler agent
which basically you which controls
whether or not
agents run or not and the reason i have
the schedules in place is once five
o'clock on Friday comes around i'm
shutting down that's it
I go offline i spend it with my family
and then it's only the highest priority
stuff that gets vented on and that's
work and that is family related stuff
but otherwise i'm offline i'm spending
time with my family
I'm you know I'm packing for fun i'm
watching TV i'm doing other stuff also
to manage that sort of anxiety because
because it is a very real risk it's
helped me focusing on my health going to
the GM stuff like that and then you know
losing myself in a workout with my
headphones on for two hours so yes but i
just had a real quick question for you
I'm about how large would you say the
infrastructure for that is number maybe
like an estimate of nodes and there's
hardware and virtual machines and are
using any sort of config management on
them
ok so i will carefully say between six
and a dozen machines virtual and
physical each of them has anywhere from
40 gigabytes of storage to 40 terabytes
of storage
no links lower than a hundred than 100
megabits anywhere from 64 to 256
gigabytes of ram and as for
configuration management
I'm sorry to say that they're all more
or less bespoke but i try to keep that
under control with basically I check out
to get a check out the appropriate git
repository and then everything has a
shell script started up and then I have
a custom if it's and bsd style init
script in a if it's BSE style system
then I have bsd style init scripts
otherwise have a cup of custom that
screen RC files that i run screened a
shell everything comes up all at once
and then not like can i monitor if I ssh
in but everything started and everything
is managed thank you
and I am out of time thank you very much
everyone one