Devon so as it says I'm Alex Matthews
national chair of restore the fourth
which is a troublemaking civil liberties
organization that opposes mass
government surveillance and we have some
of our store for folks here in the
audience shout out to you guys so this
talk is on surveillance give me chills
it relates to some research that I and
some other researchers have been doing
to explore and to quantify the chilling
effect that arises from surveillance one
of the biggest questions in the
surveillance world is the fundamental
question that we get asked all the time
which is do people actually care and the
research that i'll be talking about
today is an attempt to get a part of
that question so part of the
preconception is that maybe people don't
care maybe people are ignorant maybe
people are able at a pathetic maybe
people have other shit to deal with
frankly and particularly there is a
stereotype about young people like Becky
with a good hair over here that maybe
they just lay it all out online and
maybe we can interpret that as being
that they are happy to have law
enforcement have access to the data that
they put online and use it against them
so I'm more than a little bit skeptical
of this stereotype but when i started
off this research project which was
immediately after the stone revelations
in 2013
I actually thought it was very possible
that what we will come up with was that
there would not be a a measurable
chilling effect from surveillance and it
was something that researchers had a lot
of problems in identifying and
quantifying before the advantage of the
Snowden revelations is that they
provided what social science researchers
called an exogenous shock that enables
you to measure more precise
see what actually happened the first
element of this and I'm going to talk
about is the DHS list which is a list of
terms from the Department of Homeland
Security social media monitoring unit
which is a thing as to what they are
interested in people posting about
online then we'll go into a look at the
recent research and then into the cases
where social media postings have
triggered actual law enforcement
involvement will be talking about some
of the ways in which governments define
and redefine or choose not to define the
term violent extremists and how they go
about suppressing what they define as
violent extremist content online and
then i'll be offering some very limited
and provisional non-state based
solutions to the problem so one of the
most interesting questions that is a
part of this is how do we know what the
government is looking for when it comes
to social media when it comes to google
searches and the DHS list which days
from 2011 was definitely still in use
still in mid-2013 gives a limited take
from one agency on what they are
actually looking for so we are going to
play a game it's a very very very simple
game compared to most of the games here
at the conference what I'm going to do
is I'm going to protect present you with
six pairs of terms one of them is on the
DHS list and therefore is something that
the government is looking for in terms
of postings online and one of them is
not keep track of what you think the
right answer is
and then I'm going to be asking at the
end of the six terms who got them all
right so let's start off man i hope he
doesn't fade into the next screen here
we have two terms agriculture and we'd
one of these is on the DHS list and one
of them is not
take a moment to think about what it is
and then i'm going to show you the
answer 321
the answer is agriculture we think that
perhaps this is because the DHS is
concerned
among other things with eco-terrorism
and with disruptions to the food supply
this does not mean of course that the
federal government has a hold is
unconcerned about weed because evidently
it's not just means that in the context
of the DHS social media monitoring unit
they choose not to use that term to
search for suspicious activity so next
one more conventional stuff that gets
talked about in terms of what the
surveillance state may be looking for
online and one of these terms is on that
one of them is not take a moment to
think about it
321 and what they're looking for this
perhaps is the least surprising of the
six is jihad but it's interesting in the
context of the shootings in san
bernardino where the government actually
came under fire for not having been
interested in or having flags
sufficiently postings of the San
Bernardino shooters on the topic of you
had and the interesting thing is here
that jihad as a search team is actually
on a government list
it's just that presumably the volume of
postings on the topic of jihad the vast
majority of which will be innocent is so
large that in practice it was not
possible to drill down and identity
these things that ahead of time which is
what we run into as a problem a lot in
mass surveillance systems so next one
white power and illegal immigrants take
a moment to think about it
and it is illegal immigrants is on the
list and white power is not we think
that this is because the DHS has
something of a focus on cartels
smuggling people across the border and
wanting to disrupt them but this points
up an interesting aspect of the list
that the terms included on it
our terms from the analyst perspective
of topics that they might be interested
in then there isn't always what looks
like careful thought going into them as
to what people might actually post about
because if you are a coyote trying to
smuggle people across the border
are you really going to post the term
illegal immigrants on facebook or
twitter well probably not
next one activist and anonymous and
disappointingly one of them is on the
list so 3 2 1 which of them is it then
the answer is activists but fortunately
absolutely nobody in this room would
ever post on social media on the topic
of hacktivism so Ward ok i'm alright
thank you I'm glad to be with certain on
suspicious people it's so comforting
next one another couple of topics that
may be of interest to some people in the
room one of theses on the list one of
them is not bittorrent and freaking
spelled with a pH and yes it looks like
the Department of Homeland Security is
very interested in whether you get your
freak on last one
0day and revolution one of them on the
list one of them is not 321 and they are
interested in 0d this is interesting
principally because it's not as if vine
in violent revolution might not be a
concern of the government but maybe they
felt that revolution will be too
ambiguous attempt section awful we as we
all know now Bernie Sanders preaches a
revolution of a kind and maybe they
wanted to escape that sort of thing
in any case zero-day vulnerabilities
seem to be a concern
so who in the audience got four of the
six right
whoo-hoo got five of the six right
okay and who got six of six right
absolutely goddamn nobody what this
illustrates is that even for an expert
audience like you guys are who are
knowledgeable in this and who are
interested enough in the topic of social
media surveillance to come and listen
even to me about social media
surveillance nobody got six out of six
right and this poses interesting
questions is to the legibility of these
systems to the general public
if we don't know if we cannot tell what
the government is really interested in
then there's going to be a mismatch and
an inability for us to tailor our
behavior or tailored searches to deal
with the phenomenon of mass government
surveillance and that to an extent is
going to be intentional because
government agencies frequently expect
expressed that they do not want people
to be trying to evade massive n systems
by tailoring what they do and to express
online so we're going with that in mind
that there is that mismatch there
we're going to go into three research
papers that are recent papers that are
worth taking a look at in this context
so for our paper we were asking more
detailed version
of do people care which is does
knowledge of mass surveillance lead to
self-censorship online the title of the
paper there i call third with France
Katherine Tucker at MIT is government
surveillance and internet search
behavior and we looked at how social
volume on google trends changed after vs
before the prism revelations and your
don't know the term prism that is the
specific regulation on jun 6 2013 that
where the NSA was depicting that they
had partnerships with major tech
companies Google Yahoo Microsoft skype
dropbox a few others due to have access
to their data and bulk there was there
were arguments and confusion over what
this actually entailed but there have
been reports it's a ninety-three percent
of u.s. government surveillance
collection is classed under the prison
program so it's a major thing we looked
at google trends data for a hundred
thousand-plus observations of specific
search engine search terms we developed
a list of 282 search terms and a lot of
this analysis is going to be contingent
on whether these search terms can be
considered to be meaningful for the
analysis so I'm going to talk a little
bit about how we came up with those less
so we started off with this DHS list of
sensitive search terms i have the file
of the search times on my computer
people can take a look at that i can
give you a link but also need more we
need a control list of search terms that
one ambiguously innocent that would not
get you in trouble with government that
would not be personally embarrassing
either and for that we use the google
zeitgeist listed as published every year
where Google list 100 search terms that
people are using a lot online 44 as a
way of analyzing shift in culture so
this list contains names of celebrities
names of people who died major sporting
events new launches of tech products it
contains
absolutely no references to pawn
whatsoever so there's certainly some
curation going on but it is some
reflection of what is happening in a
given year on the clean internet so it
serves as a good control for our
purposes it except for term number 93 on
the list which was Edward Snowden so we
only use the top 50 so then we also
needed because we wanted to tease out
the differences between stuff that
people thought we'd get them in trouble
with the government and stuff that they
would think was personally embarrassing
we crowd-sourced at a tech incubator a
list of a hundred personally
embarrassing terms and I'll talk a
little bit later about what those may
have included but even so think back to
what we were doing with that exercise
just now there is a mismatch between
what the government thinks you will post
about that will get you in trouble and
what the general public thinks we'll get
them in trouble for posting about so we
still needed to independently rate the
terms on these lists using Amazon
Mechanical Turk workers for how likely
this term is to get me in trouble with
the US government and how likely it is
to get in trouble me in trouble with my
family so these are the findings that we
came up with a small but precisely
measured chilling effect is in the US of
about five percent on search volume for
government sensitive terms this is like
anthrax and pipe bomb and a few other
things and note within this study we're
not making a judgment as to whether
suppressing that search volume is a good
or bad thing we're just reflecting that
it is happening in non-us companies get
countries among the top two and ten us
trading partners there was also a
chilling effect on personally sensitive
terms and there were not only only
talking about the medical things listed
there like eating disorder depression
erectile dysfunction also talking about
other things that may be embarrassing
like my little pony Nickelback and
locking
and tend to be honest when we went out
him validated this and try to find what
people thought would be embarrassing
terms that would get them in trouble
with the government so many people
mention my little pony it was freaky and
also foot fungus of various kinds it was
gross so um this was the first study to
actually put a number on what was
happening after the Snowden revelations
because they've been serviced where
entities like pew research and pen which
has rights organizations who had gone
out and said we're calling you about the
Snowden revelations do you think these
are very serious yes I think they're
very serious have you taken any actions
in response them has it changed your
behavior yes yes of course we were
skeptical of this because of social
desirability bias if you said that the
Snowden revelations a serious thing then
you might say that you are changing your
behavior when you haven't actually done
squat not even changing the password so
we wanted to get at actual user behavior
and this was the first study that did
and as a result made something of a
splash most most downloaded paper in
July 2014 on ssrn lots of government
departments calling us taking a somewhat
creepy interest in our findings so it
also inspired other researches to take a
look at broadening these findings so
this is research by John penny at the
Oxford for in internet institute that
came out in march of this year looking
at Wikipedia how did that change before
and after the after the prison
revelations and looking at 48
terrorism-related wikipedia pages major
wikipedia pages with it with a lot of
traffic but things like the wikipedia
page for Hezbollah and again grating the
topics independently by Amazon
Mechanical Turk traitors to provide some
objectivity in the process the findings
in the penny study were a sharp decrease
in traffic to wikipedia pages related to
terrorism after the prison Robin
revelations people going much less to
find out about terrorism related traffic
again most of the people going to
wikipedia page for Hezbollah are not
looking to join a Hezbollah but they're
looking to find out about the world
around them and that is the traffic that
is being suppressed no such effect was
seen for security-related wikipedia
pages such as the department of homeland
security so that slants a little bit
what people are trying to find out about
and then there was a third study which
came out in April which was completely
not based on our research but still
fried some corroborating evidence which
comes out of the journalism literature
from Professor storage effort at Wayne
State University and she ran a lab
experiment to examine how people was
thinking about surveillance affects
people's willingness to express opinions
online very interesting experiment I
thought it was great
a fake facebook news post about
airstrikes against Isis and participants
reported how willing they be to share
their opinions opinions with others on
facebook on the subject and finally they
lost about how they thought other
Americans felt about the same topic and
for a random subset they were shown us
special notice before they saw the
facebook post remind them that the
government monitors the online
activities activities of individual
assistance so here the findings were
that people were likely is to alter
their behavior after they were reminded
about government surveillance even if
and especially if they thought that
government spends were justified and
they would take avoiding sharing
opinions that they held but that they
believed were outside the main streams
such as in this context maybe airstrikes
on Isis in this story might be a bad
idea and people who said that they had
nothing to I hide in previous interviews
were in fact more likely to censor
themselves which i think is illustrative
cause again this is a phrase we come
across a lot and maybe there's a certain
defensive pneus to that phrase that
there is in fact stuff that people have
to hide this is documentation of a
phrase in the in the literature from
Professor Shauna Zubov at Harvard of
anticipate ree
conformity somebody knows tsubasa name
so for people are constraining
themselves this what these three studies
say they are constraining themselves in
what they search for not only on stuff
that they think will get them in trouble
with the US government but also outside
the US in a documentary to weigh stuff
that will would get them in trouble with
with their mom if she was looking over
their shoulder and that's kind of
psychologically how this surveillance is
operating people are constraining what
they got to look for Wikipedia people
are constraining the opinions that they
voice online on controversial topics to
do with terrorism war so we find this
profoundly interesting and it's
something that should feed into the
debate over what kinds of mass event
should be done and again there are going
to be a lot of people who look at these
findings in the government and
surveillance agency world and say good
we want people to be constraining their
opinions we want people to be
suppressing their production of violent
extremist content online we want people
to be searching less on anthrax and pipe
bomb
even if there are legitimate research
interests in anthrax and in pipe bombs
or if you're trying to find out about
the news rather than trying to produce a
pipe bomb yourself so there there is
room for that different viewpoint here a
perspective would tend to be that
chilling effects are bad and there's
evidence that mass surveillance is bad
but was so with so black-and-white about
this or it's disgraceful so I want to
move on from that to talk about how soon
the social media surveillance systems
couple of cases where they have led to
actual law enforcement involvement and
please don't consider these to be
exhaustive they're simply a couple of
many and once that have happened to
happen physically near me so one thing
to understand
is that social media surveillance being
conducted by d by DHS and also by the
FBI's Joint Terrorism Task Force to some
extent they're competing systems tends
to ramp up intensely around major public
events and so in the Boston area with
the two biggest public events of the
year are the Boston Marathon which was
attacked and the july 4th celebrations
which were plan to be attacked so law
enforcement gets kind of antsy around
those times and fit social media
surveillance at the DHS funding fusion
centers and at JTTF grand ramps up so
this one of the things that happened
following on from the marathon
there is a guy he lives in the town next
to me which is arlington massachusetts
or he lived there
his name is Travis Cochran and he will
own a comic-book store and was very into
his firearms in the way that many u.s.
people are and he also light to post
vaguely unsettling things on Twitter now
he got to hear in late June of 2013 so a
few months after the marathon attacks he
got here about surveillance activists in
the Netherlands who are putting party
hats on surveillance cameras to mark the
birthday of george orwell and it's cool
idea right I got here about it at the
same time and I was like yeah you go
ahead but because i was born in another
country and I don't quite get the
armaments think three
I didn't do what Travis did which was on
the morning of july 4th to put up this
tweet putting a party hat on a security
camera good shooting a security camera
better shooting status who in place
cameras best within the hour thanks to
social media monitoring there was a
12-man SWAT team rounded his house
strongly urging him to allow a search of
the premises
he called up his tourney the attorneys
well you could say no but i'm reloading
you to say yes here and so he let the
men
unfortunately for Travis him for his
girlfriend his girlfriend was cleaning a
couple of her legally owned farms on the
bed and because Massachusetts has
relatively strict laws relating to farms
just like new york state does they were
both charged with felony improper
storage of firearms that is not the
interesting part 1 interesting element
of this is that the charges were dropped
in exchange for Travis and his
girlfriend setting up the comic
bookstore setting up their home and
moving out of state so he now lives in
hat New Hampshire because live free or
die
the other interesting part is that this
case was used by the DHS funded fusion
center as the key case when talking to
legislators about why they are doing
good work to thwart terrorism and we we
found out about this more or less by
accident that they were doing this so
what the what does this tell us this is
the best case that they had to bring
forward of the good they were doing and
this guy wasn't planning a terrorist
attack he may have been a blow of
bloviating guy who likes guns but
ultimately America is full of millions
of people who blow the eighth on Twitter
and who like guns and you cannot arrest
them all but on the other hand
Massachusetts is relatively less full of
such people and maybe it was the
violation of a local social norm in that
respect that led to more law enforcement
attention than he would get otherwise
next instance of the activities of the
local fusion center they implemented
after the marathon attacks for the
boston marathon 2014 a geospatial
intelligence system there would monitor
for threats in real-time and map them
out
we know this because a fusion center
employee then presented a geospatial
intelligence
conference and this was one of the
slides there were exactly to threats
identified at the 2014 boston marathon
and both of them on this slide one is to
Middle Eastern males acting suspiciously
asking questions about crowd sighs we
know nothing further about that because
the description is too vague for us to
have been able to follow up with them on
the other hand i dunno the journalists
at the Bay State examiner and they
that's an online publication that lets
say takes a skeptical attitude towards
the surveillance state and was probing
the security arrangements and asking
questions such as do you have a warrant
to search any of these bags and trying
to find out whether it really was
effective and they found themselves
designated as a security threat even
though this comes on a slide which is
from the fusion center itself the fusion
center instantly completely denies this
ever happened but it is an illustration
that activity on social media in this
case doing some activity on Twitter can
lead to being designated as a security
threat even if what you're doing is
entirely protected by the First
Amendment now there is a growing
consensus in government that these kinds
of activities are appropriate and with
every terrorist attack they're
considered to be more appropriate the
head of GCHQ the British equivalent to
the NSA came to NSA k over the NSA came
to MIT and gave a talk and one of the
things he was trying to convey is that
he really felt that everyone should be
able to agree that what he characterizes
the worst behavior should be driven off
major platforms that there are people
who are abusing the internet is spread
violent extremists ideas and that it
should be a shared goal for customers
industry and government to make that
happen
now granted this is britain they don't
have the first
moment but there are similar efforts
that are afoot here it just tends to be
done in a slightly more piecemeal unless
unitary government away one recent
proposal comes from the eu-funded
counter extremism project which has
former senator joe lieberman on its
board how far it is a scholar at death
Dartmouth University and the this takes
its cue from automated DM dmca takedown
systems and systems for identifying
child pornography on the internet and
tries to apply it to what they
characterized as being violent
extremists content and have that be
proactively and in malta mated way taken
down and according to press reports
google and facebook are both interested
in adopting these this kind of robust
hashing in order to be able to say to
government that we are doing something
here we are taking part in the fight
against Isis we are trying to limit the
spread of dieted those materials on the
internet which brings us to the awkward
question of defining the violent
extremists here in this talk I'm not
going to make the argument that Isis are
anything other than mass mailer
murdering and raping horrific people
were horrific regime but there's a lot
of plasticity to the definition of who
is indeed who is not a violent
extremists that comes into play with
governmental efforts at social media
surveillance the I tried to figure out
what an equation for this would look
like and this is more or less what I
came up with that according to police
and more and law enforcement more
generally violent extremists are people
who are actually planning violent crimes
which seems entirely fair
plus people who are organizing
peacefully against the state and its
interest- violence by the state or
people of whom the state of fruits and
we can see illustratively of this mental
attitude a treat from the sheriff of
milwaukee county who is speculating that
black lives matter with join forces with
Isis which two people who know black
lives matter folks seems horrific and
absurd but it is easy
it appears to define on one side of the
line police and state and the
surveillance agencies and characterize
what they are doing as not violent or
extremist and then on the other side to
take peaceful activists who are sharply
disagreeing with the activities of those
entities and lumping them together with
people who actually are violent and
planning violent attacks so it's
something to be exceedingly cautious of
as a pattern and my personal opinion
here is that we cannot allow governments
to work with social media companies or
tech companies to define ahead of time
who is and who is not a violent
extremists and suppress speech
accordingly and we have some examples
here of how this can start to go wrong
at the top we have DeRay McKesson
internet LZ who are two leaders of the
black lives matter movement they are
already actively under FBI surveillance
and have been defined in FBI documents
that have been leaders being violent
extremist even though they have not done
anything violent Leslie pickering a few
of you may have heard of he runs an
environmental bookstore up in upstate
New York and back in the early nineteen
nineties he acted as a spokesman for the
Earth Liberation Front and supported
publicly the destruction of property in
the course of their activities but he's
never advocated violence against people
and Ross nielsen I can almost guarantee
none of you will have heard of but he
was identified last week as a violent
Anna kissed for having set up a Facebook
page with resources for people who
wanted to protest the republican
national convention in Cleveland none of
which resources advocated violence but
he did have a black and red flag at the
top of the facebook page and maybe that
was enough
so when we have these unacceptably board
definitions of who is and who is not a
violent extremists and when we go about
trying to investigate all of these leads
then we run into deep problems the FBI
actually has a state of policy that they
are going to chase up on every lead in
the Terrorism space when you chase up on
every lead then you run into an awkward
problem with some of you will be
familiar with which is the false
positives problem so the vast majority
of people who are posting on any of
these topics that asked are of interest
to the government are innocent of any
malicious activity and when you conduct
mass surveillance according to search
terms on the internet or according to
where people go on the internet the rate
of false positives to actual people
involved in terrorism is extraordinary
according to various analyses that we've
done sometimes we come up with a figure
of 9,000 force leads for every true one
and if you have a policy because you
don't want to be seen to missing it be
missing out on any terrorism lead of
investigating every terrorism lead then
you run into a situation where you don't
know which of these people who is
posting stuff that is maybe
controversial like Travis cauldron stuff
which of them is going to turn out to be
planning into an attack and who isn't
and the vast vast vast majority of them
are not going to be it's like haven't
have any of you ever stayed in the
hospital overnight
yeah you have and there are beepers
going off all the time every five
minutes every 10 minutes it's hard to
get any sleep and all of these alarms in
themselves are valid
according to the metrics that the
machines are using but the nurses know
that many of them are going to turn out
to be false
it's just that they don't want to miss
out on anything and so the result is
that nobody gets any peace
well in response to the sep tember 11th
attacks in the attacks ensuing from it
we are in a situation where nobody is
getting the piece from government that
they should be able to get so I have
enthusiastically trashed what the
government is doing on social media
surveillance I've enthusiastically
trashed their efforts to infiltrate and
disrupt peaceful activist groups of
various kinds and so it will be entirely
legitimate to ask me well you so smart
what the hell you think should be done
in response to these kind of attacks and
to be honest I'm kind of suspicious for
the reasons stated that what the
government will do could actually be
helpful i tend to be a strong opponent
of a militaristic foreign policy as well
and I tend to think that that doesn't
make things better but there are a few
suggestions that I have for you a knife
or a non-governmental people in excusing
the agents in the audience to we have
things that you and I can do that will
help they weren't necessarily prevent
attacks as such but they may decrease
this sense that we are heading into an
abyss where everyone is being pushed
towards the extremists edges so one
thing to do is to listen to what the
president said in a completely different
context which is in the context of
campus speech and he was saying you
don't have to be fearful of somebody
spouting bad ideas just out argue them
now in the context of suppressing
violent extremists can't
get online it can actually be helpful to
have revolting Isis stuff up online and
then have people challenge it
I have seen people take Isis recruitment
and training videos and repurpose them
with the theme tune of yakety sax and
it's hilarious because they're not
really very good hope that to him and it
does ridicule what they're doing
I've seen people challenge extremist
views expressed on lines in online all
sorts of helpful for ways when they do
it is a way of expressing community
opposition to this that does not involve
the government telling you what you can
and cannot say so in that sense i
encourage more practical day-to-day
solidarity in our everyday interactions
i encourage reaching out across barriers
of race and class and gender to listen
to people on the other side of those
barriers and to try and find ways to
articulate common principles in common
thoughts
it doesn't have to be the government
mentoring that process it doesn't have
to be them doing what they're doing with
countering violent extremists programs
in the US and targeting the Muslim
community and trying to prevent
radicalization by having psychologist's
report back to the FBI on what young
people in those communities are thinking
it can be something much less sinister
and much more bottom up the problem here
is that politicians get asked to do
stuff in response to every attack and
what I hear again and again is that
politicians do not want to feel like
they will be held responsible if there
is a major attack and if they can be
said to have not done everything
possible to thought it but the
counterexample there frankly is
President George W Bush who allowed a
fairly major terrorist attack to have an
honest watch and he was rewarded
electoral efore it the last
recommendation that I have
have is there is a great deal of talk in
this friends world about how you need to
gather as big haystack as you can
because if you don't have a big haystack
how can you possibly find the needles of
violent extremist content of people
planning terrorist attacks our
perspective is a little different i
restore forth we care a lot about the
Fourth Amendment which for refresher we
don't know it by heart yet is here and
the perspective of the Fourth Amendment
is really that you collect less hey you
only investigate and search and seize
the papers and effects and online
material of people who you have evidence
are involved in actual crimes on an
individual basis not a mass basis not
gathering everything in them flagging
what looks suspect suspicious
we believe that this is a law
enforcement approach that actually helps
law enforcement because you don't have
FBI agents having to chase up enormous
numbers of false leads
you may miss stuff if you collect less
but we're missing stuff at the moment
attacks still happen even in France
where they've gone much further towards
martial law then we have attacks is
still happening and it's an unhelpful
ratchet to be on we need a better
approach an approach roost rooted in the
Constitution where you gather less but
you follow up on it thoroughly and that
is the wisdom of the Fourth Amendment
here so restore the fourth is having a
social evening at eight-fifteen p.m.
tonight at the Stokes pub which is just
around the corner on West 33rd we
encourage you to join us if you want to
learn more about what we're doing around
the country are both the national and
local level and at this point I would
welcome questions from the audience
yes
impressively be a gentleman
i have come across the third amendment
argument is an interesting one though I
find it difficult to believe that the
court will accept it but any solution is
worth trying
I feel that the Fourth Amendment is a
little more on point for it but I'm very
happy for people to try whatever
strategy safety war will work Steve
yay
I thought I i think the exact phrase
poorly spelled was fucked the Boston
bombing i'm going to go one better
what I gonna do with all you haters
what
it is agree yes
I think I think that's fair comment and
there certainly have been FBI efforts to
disrupt white supremacist groups the the
difficulty here when you're analyzing
the surveillance state is it you kind of
go with the data that you have out there
and we have more of an understanding of
what this unit in DHS does then what the
JTTF directly searches for so if anyone
has access to that information from
within FBI then we will be deeply
interested not that we're advocating
anyone doing anything illegal yes go
ahead for my money's in that I fired
I i have daughters who are twins to an
eight-and-a-half i'm familiar with the
brand new verse being
inside and corporate side I'm seeing a
lot more surveillance taken place in the
corporate world and being so bad
US government big data like you could
not possibly
no one can see are being made
interracial basis i'm thinking
no this is for the oxygen replication
anything about that i think that can be
a valid strategy the way that we
characterize it at restore the fourth is
that there are individual things that we
can do in terms of confiscation in terms
of encryption and these are useful and
we work on legislative advocacy and we
work on litigation none of it none of
these strategies disparage any of the
others and self-protection with your
data is hugely important when it comes
to this we just have to work on this on
the whatever angles we can find in that
we can develop confidence in Thank You
responders are very time
are you over any
you're working
on
looking at our engagement
research on the long-term psychological
effects of self-censorship how does that
play into the work
I think that will be a fascinating area
to look at I think that personally as a
researcher my orientation is more
towards empirical techniques and so I
wouldn't feel like I was a natural for
doing that kind of longitudinal study
but we do have a 501c3 arm that tries to
encourage research into this valence
state and so that's something that we
can certainly discuss in my cards are up
there if you want to talk about that a
great lengths to someone at the back
and
I more
I think this isn't it and a topic that
comes up again and again taking when it
comes to browsing like if you use tor is
it labeling use a suspicious person if
you are not on social media does it
label you
facebook has shadow profiles of people
who are not on facebook yet but that it
develops in case they ever want to come
onto facebook which are internal to them
so it is hard to say exactly what is
being inferred from it without being
inside these system it is unfortunately
the case that as our public lives become
more digitized more commodified it comes
lesson as possible for us to participate
in the world without being surveilled in
some way and there are people who go
further to try to avoid this and others
richard stallman who's speaking tomorrow
has gone further than almost anyone in
trying to cleanse his profile of
anything that is available i frankly
don't go very far i do have profiles on
social media I do use encrypted
communications for some things but not
for others and my general cross-grained
attitude is that i should be able to use
these services and have them not be used
against me to lock me up but that's an
idealistic perspective which is why I'm
in an idealistic line of work
to be mostly oriented
social media postings searching and
curious if there's been any data on
chilling effects on one
the Penguins the greatest revelation
it was dark someone
I found that personally
I was restricting what
out with my colleagues
minnesota signal such rose where
I could use those
securely
found myself freeing up again so you
know i'm wondering curious from room and
large people wanted
here
where at
our data chillin
ok
is this question and when it comes to
that sort of 1121 analysis of
infiltration the bed best recent study
the number where of is a qualitative
study out of the UK that deals with the
police infiltration and surveillance of
activist groups that is being analyzed
in the pitchford inquiry and it is clear
in the context of those activist groups
their fear of infiltration and fear of
in of individual conversations being
compromised had a significant effect in
inhibiting their activities which were
mostly environmental in that context I
can ferret out that study and send it to
you but so it does happen but that kind
of analysis is inherent is inherently
qualitative and is therefore more
vulnerable to people saying well it's
just those people maybe it doesn't
matter so much
the merit of what the Snowden
revelations enabled was to be able to
and that analyze the online activities
of hundreds of millions of people at a
time and to see that there was an effect
that was very broad across society that
was not limited to people who are
activists and I think that's helpful for
people to know but optimism in the you
remember the people remembering that the
network
her to appear infrastructure originally
and if we can get away from using these
big central like data warehouses like
Facebook and Google and shipped to
slowly to of either mesh based network
where we all know get together and have
some sort of free internet and that goes
on to the public pipe and anonymity is
built-in encryptions built-in from the
start I think technologically do how to
do an end-run around some of these
things if we can just get herself off of
these is being essentially data
warehouses and go back to more
peer-to-peer communication on the net
ipv6 is a big part of that verse
encryption is too it's important that we
have to keep that encryption in our
toolbox but I see a lot of Hope here to
kind of get away from make it very
difficult for authorities to trace out
exactly who's you know saying what
there's a lot of Hope technologically
politically it's not going yeah i agree
that mesh net server are very
interesting and useful potentiality here
and I would encourage people to
investigate and adopt them as with any
of these fairly new ideas
the key is usability and we saw that
with encrypted communications that p-gp
was very hard thing for members of the
public to use and signal is a lot easier
and I've really appreciated the focus on
the user experience to make it simple
for somebody like me who studied
medieval literature college to be able
to access that Jeff think that there are
any more relaxed
of effects of surveillance on people for
non political reasons such as Brendan
surveillance of children wore
surveillance on by thousand users on
victims
testing violence that would be useful
for understanding
acts of political surveillance or is
there something
about government involvement
I think that those studies could be
useful and if you have good ones then
out love you to send them to me one
thing that we see here is that for a lot
of people in these systems they are
thinking of US government surveillance
is being analogous to surveillance by a
parent and they're thinking of it not
necessarily as big brother but maybe as
big mother and so they are chilling the
stuff that is embarrassing that they
would want their mom to see as well as
the political stuff so that is
indicative that that kind of research
might be might be able to offer insights
into the political spin sighs yes
awesome
increasingly it's not just us
what
buy off-the-shelf commercial
there
you like your own watch-list or
they would populate it black lives
matter and dump them
over
things going forward really
it's not just
it's all the other
this
often
yeah i think i was completely right I
had a whole section on fusion centers
that I didn't quite get to but this is
something that state and local law
enforcement is very keen to get on in
into because it is an essentially an
infinite spirit of funding and so foot
we have to be aware of that incentive
for them that making their terrorism
buses an important thing like with
Steve's example from methuen
massachusetts of camera and ambrosio
this stuff that can make a career in
local law enforcement if they rate make
the right bus so this is there are
powerful impulses towards expanding this
kind of space that's all we have for
questions or time for questions but if
you do have further questions I'm sure
Alex would like to entertain them in the
bag that's our yeah all right back