alright okay so welcome to our talk and
captures where hack existence
dr. Dave this is redfish we'd like to
talk today about captures their a
popular thing to see them all over the
place just about everywhere but man they
sure are a nuisance right but they are
doing us a lot of good keeping box and
black cats from abusing valuable online
resources right hold up a little bit so
i don't know if you guys can see this
but this is the Statue of Liberty
burning and it says imagine a world
without captures New York is in flames
right so first we like to start out a
little bit of humor just to get you in
the mood
I you know this is a the old joke you
just wanted to post your comment in the
new section but I can't do it until you
saw the caption and you know we'll get
to talking about reverse Turing test and
Hardy I problems but this is a nice
little bit of irony
so you know will test your humanity
young kids probably won't get that ok so
this is me I'm a bomb academic I think
about captures all day and AI and
machine learning stuff i do both attack
and defense and I enjoy all types of
information security research says me
have a business degree so actually not
an engineer
although i do consider myself a
developer on if you went to DEFCON 17
you might have seen my speech called
Hadoop Apaches open-source
implementation of Google's MapReduce
framework so basically when he was in
version 4.1 seven so very very infant on
give a speech on how it worked in what
map reduces for those of you don't know
it's basically the base of what google
search engine works off of its how they
deal with all of the scrapes that they
do from the internet how they rank pages
related mall on the check us out act
existence column eventually slides will
be up there
on shameless plug check out my youtube
channel youtube.com slash hacked
existence of all kinds of tutorials
everything from Wi-Fi pineapple building
websites and Django Raspberry Pi all
kinds of good stuff up there so check
that out
ok so we're going to be hearing this
word a lot tonight capture what does it
actually stands for it stands for
completely automated public Turing test
to tell computers and humans apart so
there's a little bit of argument about
who invented first group out of yahoo or
dr. luis von ahn from Carnegie Mellon
generally dr. von Ahn gets the credit
he's the inventor of recapture I'm sure
we've all heard of that
so the whole purpose of this is just to
tell hey is this user on my page
human-robot how do we tell you know the
goal is to prevent the abuse by bots and
black cats right so you know if we just
have a form wide-open someone can come
in and write a clever pearl scripter
python script or whatever your favorite
web form interaction scripting language
of sources
the goal is just to protect scarce
resources right you have a finite amount
of bandwidth you have a finite amount of
server space finite amount of the count
space whatever it maybe you need to make
sure that you can police it in a
meaningful way
so that's the challenge you face as a
web service provider right
the cost of your security versus the
cost of the operation of your service so
you know you have to have some level of
tolerance for bought activity in your
service because guaranteed there's going
to be some spammers somewhere looking
for trouble right but you need to make
sure that the cost of your security is
not greater than the cost of operating
your service otherwise why the hell
would you bother with it right sort of a
moot point so we face an existential
crisis fairly quickly and capture when
we can just pay human to solve it right
then we defeated the entire point of
this discerning between human bot
because now we have a legitimate wet
brain sitting from
Peter solving the challenge so we get to
a point where you know you can pay like
five dollars for a thousand solutions
and you know you farmed out to a farm
and what's done is done right you get
extremely high accuracy usually ninety
percent plus and solve rates and
generally it just ruins your day as an
administrator so we have to start
thinking about captures in an economic
sense you know what does this cost to
protect a resource right so you're
forcing the attacker to pay and expend
resources right so we can sort of think
about it in a game theory way so one you
know effective way of doing this is
amazon's mechanical turk right whoo all
here is used mechanical turk anyone
ok so when they say you can see the
audience are not light
yes black 15 okay well if anyone's use
Mechanical Turk you can pay people to do
small tasks for you for a small fee and
get generated this way right so this is
sort of an example of a of a human
solutions farm that will encounter so
there's three major types the text-based
one you've all seen this right
alphanumeric characters with some noise
added in to obfuscate the text
they're very widely deployed there
easily scalable they're very unique they
have a very large sample space and there
they've been the gold standard for quite
some time
we're going to talk about how they'd
fallen out of favor when we get into our
tax section but you still see him just
about everywhere because they're so damn
easy to implement and you can just find
them on every ph people to board
comments section whatever they're going
to be there
the future is image-based ones right so
we're seeing now a move towards
image-based captures these ones ask you
to perform an image or object
recognition task as the hard AI problem
right we want to know that you have the
ability to recognize an object this is a
cat this is a flower this is
telephone cetera right I that's not to
say computers can't perform that task
but up until very recently that was
generally considered a hard computer
vision problem we'll see where we've
evolved in computer vision shortly then
last but not least let's not forget our
blind users right some people have
disabilities you know blind deaf
whatever it may be we need to make sure
we accommodate them so audio-based
captures are there for the blind it
speaks of phrase and the person has to
enter it in there is also some
obfuscation added into the audio to
prevent speech-to-text translators from
just automatically answering the
challenge for them but obviously that
has some impacts on usability it's not a
perfect solution but it does provide
access for our blind users so now we
come to the criteria for evaluating a
design so there's three major criteria
that we care about usability scalability
and robustness so when we think about
these ideas we have to ask ourselves a
couple of questions right so usability
is key if humans can't solve it
your captures garbage right we whatever
it is you come up with
it's no good so we want to make sure
that users understand the challenge
right so when we say challenge what that
is is the question posed to the user to
verify their humanity that's where the
challenges we say enter the letters into
the following text field that's the
challenge right so can the user
understand it in answer it quickly so
the general rule of thumb is a capture
should take no longer than 15 to 30
seconds to solve any longer than that
and you're starting to negatively impact
the user experience and generally the
user will begin to become frustrated
they won't perform the task that will
neglect whatever it is that you put
behind the caption and then of course we
have to consider are impaired users
right so scalability is actually in my
opinion the the second most important
criteria how well does your challenge
scale so that means can you accommodate
a large number of users so you know
think about you know let's say you run a
basket leading for more
k in there you know you have 30 users
you just need to capture that's going to
keep out you know your standard PHP
bulletin board bots nothing fancy
now imagine you're running gmail ok the
number of people and the sophistication
and resources of the attackers were
going to be hitting you
it's going to be much higher and you
want to make sure that the uniqueness of
your challenges is extremely high we
don't want any repeats we don't want
anything that could lead to a dictionary
attacks database attacks any bit of
information we can keep out of the hands
of the attacker is something we want to
do as much as possible and then finally
the automated portion can the challenge
be generated without humans that's
extremely important
that's the completely automated part
I've seen personally an academic
literature a lot of designs that require
some aspect of human interventions such
as a labeled image database for example
something that yes we have a manager
ok we're going to get to that I'm glad
you brought that up we will definitely
address that in detail shortly and then
last but not least robustness is sort of
a descriptor for security is it
resilient to attack so we know there's
things like segmentation attacks
filtration attacks things to get our
tricks out so that the standard computer
vision tools optical character
recognition whatever it is will be
effective again in solving these
challenges and then also real-time
content that's something that is hot in
the field right now we're looking at
that if any of you have seen the latest
recapture you'll see Google Maps data
they're asking you to solve you know
click on the storefronts or identify all
buildings that have a street number on
them or something to that effect right
so they're sourcing this content in the
real world and they're having you answer
the challenge quickly they do an
aggregate you know the last 10 or 12
people the same thing and then see if
you there's a height of threshold to
authorized the challenge right so here's
a now we're going to get into the
section about breaking captures so
here's a little haha philosoraptor right
he has trouble reading it is here robot
well we don't know so now we'll get into
the breaking techniques optical
character recognition i'm sure you've
all heard of this right it was
originally designed so you could scan
documents back from paper into digital
format in your computer but so just
shout out how many people had a scanner
in the nineties flatbed scanner
alright so OCR has been evolving since
then right and so it's pretty good now
so so we're we're almost at a point now
where with deep learning models which
we'll get to later on because of the
regularity and structure of text it
doesn't really vary that much so when
you get you know you and I can't ella t
in a thousand different fonts because we
know what he looks like we have a
conceptual model in our brain of what
atty looks like when we develop a neural
network that can perform the same
function nearly as well as we do you're
going to see where text becomes real
shitty real quick
segmentation is just we want to be able
to separate individual characters are
important pieces of an image out and
identify them filtration is designed to
cut through the noise filter out
additive noise lines garbage things like
that we have computer vision algorithms
who here has played with Intel's opencv
at all just give me a yes you have
okay so we got a couple people there who
do computer vision stuff object
recognition now it's becoming
increasingly more powerful it's no
longer as trivial as it once was seen
tagging and image annotation our hot
who here has seen IBM Watson alchemy ok
that's really fancy stuff that's
bleeding edge it can provide image
annotation where it gives you contextual
information about an image
such as that lets say there's a guy on a
beach drinking a corona will say man on
the beach holding a bottle right that's
creepy that's some next-level stuff
there that I I've been in the machine
learning game for six years and that
blew my mind
deep learning models are hot now they're
third-generation neural networks google
uses them a lot
they were the initial developers of this
for processing their Maps data they're
very powerful very adaptive and
extremely good at image processing tab
tasks speech-to-text i think is fairly
straightforward so we'll keep it there
for now
ok so now we'll get into breakin tools
right so let's say you're a black cat
now and you're faced with a capture
challenge is there an automated breaker
around if the answer is yes great use it
but what do you do when you reach
captures that you can't break
well now the fancy ones will let you
farm the ones you can't break out to
human to solve them
so for example death by captcha is a
service provider that will sell you
human users to break the captions you
can't break so as a black cat this
allows you to optimize your expenses
where you break the automated ones with
your automated breaking tool and the
ones you can't break you pay for right
so they also now have the ability to
share custom algorithms for defeated
challenges so let's say you spend the
time making one some guy wants to target
you they can now share it through their
tool with everyone else so GSA is the
most popular one
it's a german group that does it 247
bucks for the seat updated frequently d
capture is a human solving service that
integrates with GSA it's two dollars per
1,000 images and then capture snipers
the third one just an alternative to gsa
if that doesn't float your boat
ninety-seven bucks
so here's an example of a challenge
being ripped apart one through ten so
number one shows you the basics of what
the challenge looks like then you can
see where we begin the color
modification and number two it gets
stripped down to black-and-white right
then we have some great scaling
functions here averaging maxing things
like that which helps you know filter
out some more of the background noise
until you see with you know number four
where we can do some smoothing and
sharpening on the letters then we end up
applying the grayscale bucket here to
clean up the letters set the cutoff in
six and before you know it you know it
will gloss over the rest chopping you
know the number of passes you want to
make on a particular segmentation and
before you know it you're you've got the
characters in this took less than a
second to perform so tester captain's
was a tool originally released by mcafee
security that lets you play around with
this manually right so normally this is
a fully automated thing this lets you
sort of see the steps and treat them out
if you google around for this I'm sure
you can pick it up
here's a screenshot of GSA so this is
sort of the the one that black hats run
at scale right so they have all the in
the capture type box you can see on the
left-hand side they have a big list of
known challenges in the wild that have
been broken and you can apply them in
accordingly you can set it up as a web
server so you can do farming attacks and
programming all that stuff make sure
you've got your death by capture account
in there it'll just make your life that
much easier right so you know automated
breakers are great but from a defense
perspective if you know how they're
breaking your challenge you can make a
couple of simple tweaks and break the
automated tool and then you send the
attacker back to the drawing board
to come up with something new right so
it's a it's a constant arms race there's
no real you know end-all be-all it's
it's a constant game of one-upmanship so
here's an example of of alchemy and
action they give you this picture of a
cat you can see here in the code where
it gives you a text string that hey this
is a cat and it gives you a confidence
score as a percentage of 100-percent
where it's 98.3 % sure that this is a
picture of a cat right and that's pretty
creepy because now if you have an image
challenge where you ask them to perform
a recognition task we now have an
automated tool that can perform the task
and provide you a text string pretty
creepy right so they asked you know hey
type this in
you're gonna get nailed just to show you
how robust it is this is an example of a
horribly polluted river that's orange
but it's still able to detect that those
people were kayaking in the river and
was able to say hey this is a body of
water even though it was a different
color than water would normally be so
text captures are basically dead
we've seen google's recapture move to an
image-based service and deep learning
models have effectively deleted text
based implementations now that's not to
say you're not going to see text-based
implementations around on the web
because let's face it there scalable
they exist they're already deployed
they're good enough at stopping skids
from running wild on your webpage the
fancy attackers they're going to be able
to bring more heat on your challenge
those are the guys you gotta watch for
and you as a service administrator can
watch and if you noticed an uptick in
bogus account registrations maybe it's
time to reevaluate your capture so to
the gentleman's point earlier we will
talk about current vested breeds right
so now we're seeing migrations away from
those
three traditional ones to something
called a behavior-based model so
behavior based models ask the user
hey you know what are you doing you know
is this guy clicking on things is he
clicking on things faster than a human
would be able to is he populating every
single form space text box on the page
even hidden ones you know those are
behaviors that BOTS typically show can
be targeted and identified and stopped
accordingly by behavior-based captures
is the bot no to click this box is I'm
not a robot
alright that's an example of a
behavior-based model so risk base models
are a little bit fancier so what Google
has been doing with the risk base model
is based on how much they think you're a
bot before you even perform the
challenge the difficulty of the
challenge is directly related to a
number of points that they measure and
when we say number of points that they
measure they mean your browser user
agent your cookie history
are you logged into a google account do
they have a history of data in this
google account right the more points of
data they have on you being a legitimate
human the easier of challenge you're
going to get so there's a great paper
published at blackhat 2016 Asia that
showed some guys doing some testing of
the risk-based model with custom crafted
user agents look into that if you want
to know more about it highly recommended
stuff but the long and short of it is
you can go all the way from solving
these complex challenges that we see
here on the right where they want you to
identify bodies of water all the way
down to google already knows for a fact
you're human because you're logged into
your gmail and you just click the box
and you don't even need to solve the
challenge now they still offer the old
text based model as something called a
legacy capture because there is some
difficulty and solving these image-based
ones are people have difficulty
sometimes the images are too blurry they
crop them
it may be a multi-layer challenges ask
you to perform a task a number of times
and update each time you perform a task
so sometimes for example in this one if
you click on a body of water the image
will fade out based on your response
either right or wrong in a new image
will come up and they ask you to repeat
this multiple times until you've solved
it or they'll give you two different
forms where you solve this one and then
after that they'll hit you with a text
based one so it just really depends on
how much they trust you as a human or
not so now comes the fun part
fire up your phones or laptops whatever
and jump over to our website
rbs capture lab com
alright so if you guys want to try this
go ahead we already pulled up the
results for now but basically this is
the capture that we built on it's pretty
straightforward
here's the image has been modified
here's your set of emoticons you just
kind of have to guess I was wrong
right Scott looks neutral
yeah that was right
so basically we just fed a bunch of
images and we'll get to how this all
works in a minute here but present an
image give it a bunch of emoticons try
it out right so the goal of this is
match the emoticon to the expression on
the face that's the challenge
ok so here's some results the results
true alright so basically we have our
five emotions here arm and we tell you
how many times their guests correct and
how many times are getting correct so
you can go into neutral here for example
will tell you
19 times somebody guest neutral they
were right 16 x 3 x them to guess
neutral for an image that was in neutral
army will tell you what the incorrect
yes is were surprises one happiness was
one on and then i'll show you all the
images the whole filter change that we
applied to each image of all the
emotions that were possible account of
how many times each one was guest on if
you guys want to try that out we'll look
at a the results at the end of the
speech here
ok so our heart a are hard AI problem
try saying that three test is human
emotion recognition so what is that it's
contextual information contained in an
image right so what
when you look at the face right being
able to read the emotion on the face is
contextual right so great you can detect
the face but do you know what the face
is expressing right is it impossible for
a computer to perform this task
absolutely not otherwise we wouldn't be
able to automate this in a meaningful
way and we actually in fact use
computers to do the original analysis of
the facial expression and then apply
filters on top of it so we're in
feedback through the computers to where
they can't recognize it anymore so it
starts with computers telling you what
emotion is in the image and then trying
to break the computer right so it's not
a trivial challenge we have microsoft to
thank for this gem in their surveillance
to xbox and just the sheer scale of web
services they operate success is highly
dependent upon specific criteria right
so we can't just take any old image the
image has to be high quality of a
certain size properties composition
things like that so there are definitely
tolerances to the detection algorithms
for emotion and we plan on exploiting
those in a meaningful way
so we're going to turn and burn through
these really quick for the sake of time
these are facial cues for measurement
just so you have a reference point of
what the algorithm is looking at so this
is a neutral expression right no real
facial relax facial muscles eyes are
open no furrowed brow no fraud nose lips
are straight right anger you can see the
point's these are the types of things
the algorithm is looking for right
eyebrows down together narrowing of the
lips things like that
ok
we'll go through these pretty quick
contempt corner lip surprise you no
eyebrows raised mouth open happiness you
know crow's-feet pushed up cheeks lips
pointing up sadness you know drooping
upper eyelids lost focus frowning
frowning mouth-to-mouth pointing down
fear you know you got your eyebrows up
raised upper eyelids lives parsed
discussed nose wrinkled upper lip pulled
up so what those r is eight Universal
emotions those emotions are conveyed
across cultures no problem any human can
ostensibly recognize those eight
emotions so the way we generate our
challenges the following so we use an
image scraper to gather data off a web
image search
so that was an important challenge to us
we wanted to make sure that we could use
existing tag data and then protect it
from certain types of attacks to handle
that so we use the emotion API from
Microsoft to perform the facial
recognition so that means they identify
face in the image and then be recognized
the emotion on the face then we save it
to our database we run filters on it
until we get no results from the emotion
API engine then we ask the user to
demonstrate their humanity be matching
the emoticon to the face and then we
evaluate the responses a pass/fail
alright so i'll talk a little bit about
what we built on so basically gave him
to me design the whole setup and I built
it implemented it through it up on the
internet so you guys can use it on so
basically we have an open-source python
image scraper on that uses google image
search
so this is interesting we started out
with where we going to get images from
right that's problem one we can see here
in hand curate them all but that's not
really scalable we need to just pull
them off in some automated process so we
tried using Google's Image Search API
that didn't work out well at all on the
results were completely different than
when you go to images.google.com type
something in arm probably could've spent
a bunch of time tweaking it out figuring
out why but
instead I just hit get hub type in
google images and boom python
open-source scraper does it all for you
on we'll look at that in the next slide
here on so then we've got a big bank of
images now that we've ripped off of
google images on we feed them all
through Microsoft Project oxford API on
which at the moment you can get a free
api key they have rate limits on it so
you gotta go real slow handle images on
the comeback identify the face in it
tell you all the different emotions and
what they believe
uh the rating of confidence for each
emotion inside of that face so you can
actually handed images with you know a
different people's faces and it'll draw
a box around each face and tell you what
emotion is in each face pretty cool arm
took those emotions so now we know what
emotion is in an image reply bunch of
GIMP filters so games awesome open
source free runs on a headless server
apply filters at to it one at a time and
shoot it back through the oxford motion
API until it comes back as we can even
detect facing here and then we're good
on then we use django to do all that and
then presented to the users as a
challenge
alright so here's the whole python
scraper arm it's real shorts like 15
lines of code on so the python api is
actually called google really easy to
find on github arm and it's awesome
it actually goes and launches if you do
it on like a desktop in linux it'll
actually launch the Firefox window type
your image search into google images rip
all the results down and then close
firefox so that kind of poses a problem
when you try to do it on like a cent OS
box that you pay somebody to host out on
the internet because there's no GUI on
so we had to use this pie virtual
display here which is really cool you
just tell it hey open up a display
visible equals 0 so we don't even have a
GUI and
resolution is 800 x 600 and then inside
of that you can pop a Firefox window and
then run your google image search here
and the coolest part is that you have
this option stock image type and you can
set it to type face so basically you can
search for anything you want like you
searched for rock or like Mustang or
chair and it will only return images
with faces on them so really doesn't
matter what you searched for you can
throw garbage at it and you're just
gonna get facial images all day long
because Google has already gone through
their massive image collection and
figured out which ones have faces for
you on so that's pretty sweet
and then we just save them all to the
web server so that whole thing happens
right here
alright so Microsoft cognitive services
this is pretty crazy like I had no idea
that it was this deep they have a
ridiculous amount of computers that know
a lot of human things so computer vision
emotion face video like a new video
analysis you can feed a video and we'll
tell you all kinds of things about it i
mean languages so it doesn't matter what
language it's in you can handle all
kinds of stuff academic knowledge you
know being web search all kinds of crazy
stuff so here's the MS emotion API on
and it's a rest api so real simple you
post an image to URL along with your API
key and it will detect up to a different
emotions in human faces and provide the
bounding box the responses are all in
JSON they look like this so I'll tell
you here's the face box that will give
you this point and tell your width and
height
here's your face so for an image that
has multiple phases with dropbox for
each one and then it tells you all the
scores from each emotion how confident
is as a percentage arm pretty easy to
work with you can hand it up to 64
people in a single image so it's a
pretty ridiculous amount of processing
for computer to be able to do just take
a single image
be able to identify so many people in it
are all kinds of image formats all your
standard image formats anything less
than 4 Meg's it can't end it massive
images but most images on the internet i
would imagine or less than 4 Meg's on
detectable face size between 36 and 36
pixels so that's really tiny right all
the way up to 4096 pixels so that's a
little too high definition I want to see
my face in that much detail it's
ridiculous
the faces are ranked by face rectangle
size in descending order so it starts
with the biggest face goes down to the
smallest on and frontal and near faces
give you the best results I'd profiles
are a little rough but they'll still try
and tell you what emotion is in like a
side profile so here's just like a quick
example of the points that they look at
four when they're trying remember those
earlier slides where we saw where people
were looking at you know the stuff
these are the points where they measure
that movement on these and then you can
generate a probability based on where
these points are moved as to which
emotion it's being displayed
alright so arm like I said we start by
we've got an image source now bunch of
collection of images are we shooting off
the microsoft emotion API and let them
tell us where's the face what's it
displaying arm and then once we get back
we create that is called the original
image and we have an answer to it we
already know what emotion is displayed
in that image so our proof of concept
thus far only deals with images showing
a single face on we're going to expand
it out but it's not there yet so then we
start using GIMP and applying these
filter chains one at a time and shipping
it back to the API and saying what do
you see now what do you see now
eventually we'll come back and say
nothing
that's when we save it and say alright
this is ready to show out on so it's no
longer recognized by the emotion API on
and then the user is asked to provide
the emotion as the challenge response so
here's the image that's been modified
can you guess which emoticon man
is pretty straightforward so here's our
game filter on in django two lines of
code very simple write function called
the plug-in filter basically all it does
is it runs gimp console so it runs in a
headless sent OS box out on the internet
applies again filter to an image that's
on the file system you can change the
options so you can decide how intense
you want these filters to be which is
randomized at all so Papa random filter
on their tried again through the API so
one important point is jordan ality is
important in filter application so
because some filters can be destructive
and subtractive things like that they
play a role in defeating challenges that
need extra image data so if a particular
cv algorithm needs something right we're
taking that data way so as we start
destroying the image right it becomes
progressively more difficult because
there's just straight-out less
information and we've added additional
garbage information that makes it nearly
impossible for these things to read
yes yes so here's an example of the
distortion chain you start with the
regular image end up with something like
this you just keep applying filters over
and over until that API can't deal with
it anymore on the cool thing about that
is it becomes completely scalable right
it seems microsoft you know they can
just sit there and flip the switch and
detect a little more deal with a little
more filters on top of it all we have to
do is just apply a few more so it's that
cat and mouse game but in this case all
we have to stack more filters on it as
long as people can still deal with it on
your fine right
alright so stopping the emotion API this
is what happens you get zero face
detected arm so we asked it over and
over after each time we apply filter
eventually we get 20
ok so this this piece here is
interesting so if you look at on the
left this is a google reverse image
search
so when we feed it the unaltered image
it does a couple of things for us it
tells us the image size finds the image
and other sizes beyond
that particular lengthen with and it
also gives us a text string gentle smile
right so clever attacker can use
metadata on this image to figure out hey
this is probably a happiness image
because of the keywords smile so when we
noise the hell out of it here in the
right side now look what happens the
visually similar images are garbage
they're all related to the grid pattern
we added to the image there is no longer
a text string and it can't find any
other images that matches right this is
very important
now we don't have this security
guarantee in place yet because our
filter chain is completely random but
when we finally do apply orden ality to
it it's going to be able to prevent
reverse image search from nailing us to
the wall right because if we're drawing
our images from this pool we need to
make sure that these tools can be used
against us right that's all these are
all phases this over here looks like
carpets and sweatshirts and all the
internal stop afraid
alright so version one point of we
started with eight emotions all eight
that the API can deal with a few of them
are experimental on there's no guarantee
on the reverse image search we'll get to
that later on is designed for usability
not security we're getting to security
but because this is for Dave to get a
PhD
we have to keep put all of our variables
constant and modify one at a time so we
can measure what kind of change a single
variable produces on so gathered
responses from a bunch of people just
threw it up there said try this out
here's the matrix you guys can find
slides online later basically here's
what comes out of it
so when we show people neutral images
the first time when there is a choices
ninety-six percent of the time they got
it right when we showed people disgust
images forty-six percent of forty-seven
percent of the time they got a right so
discuss like more than half the time
they couldn't even guess what image that
was so too interesting points are
contempt and discuss our experimental
emotions in the API there
not fully implemented yet so keep that
in mind arm and then this is all of the
so this is guests based on results so
when people guessed happiness
eighty-three percent of the time they
were right when they guess discussed
forty-five percent of times they were
right so fifty-five percent of the time
that people click that discussed face
they were wrong so discusses obviously a
good candidate for just being chopped
off
so therefore version 2.1 o we drop three
motions arm and tried it again and
that's what you guys see now in this
time way better right
ninety-seven percent 95% 9494 eighty-one
percent sadness is still a little bit
rough but way more accurate right people
can handle this a whole lot better
ok so let's let's take a look at our
design and make sure that actually does
what it says it does so can you
recognize the faces well I'm sure you
can all be the judges of that the
problem becomes as we keep increasing
our security
it could be that humans can no longer
use it right the warping and distortion
is gone too far
it's no good right since this is an
image recognition capture we do not have
an option for blind users so that is
exclusionary and unfortunately we
haven't found a way around it yet
good news is it is scalable so these
KPIs are in place we have image scrapers
we can do that we've thought about
scraping social media or hashtags you
know we can get live faces in their
recent faces that haven't been indexed
anywhere else so let me talk about that
real quick that's kind of where I see
this going and that's one of the things
i think is probably the most awesome
pieces project if we go scrape hashtag
smile or hashtag happy on Instagram all
the sudden we have this live feed of
images that are brand-new there's no
metadata about them that don't work in
reverse image search because they've
never existed on the internet before all
the sudden you can take these live feeds
of images running through an emotion API
that's going to tell you already what
emotions in it a filter channel and then
pop them out there so you can
literally produces in real-time with
images that are vulnerable to a lot of
this stuff so right now we're working on
making sure that they're resistant to
reverse image search and computer vision
attacks
there's a variety and the method of
challenge expression so we do have you
know all these motions we've been
looking at you know the confusion matrix
to see which emotions are easily
confused by people so that when you're
offered challenges you get the best
blend that will give you the highest
possible chance to be accurate
now any of your image processing
specialists you know you work in the
spatial domain the frequency domain can
you filter out my distortions can you
come wrecked my day that's what i want
you guys as hackers to challenge me
don't hack the web server we don't care
about that if you are an image
processing specialist and you can remove
those distortions to the point that you
can now get the emotion API to re-pick
up the face or you can get a hit with
metadata on reverse image search that's
that's what we're interested in and i'll
put up the source on github so if you
want out the other side and actually
build it further
you're welcome to that as well so we've
already pretty much talk about these in
in detail so so one with this so bender
says prove that you're not a robot by
injuring a human through interaction
allowing humans to come to harm
questions you want to step up tonight
yep people who are blind but also people
who cannot maybe process emotion as well
so when you see the face you may not be
able to understand which face is
actually being displayed which might
result in probably i think it was less
than I think probably 30 or 25 percent
of the time that would be even accurate
so do you have any answers for that
already alternatives i would hope that
out we could do an outreach program to
the Autism Awareness community
perhaps maybe use this as a tool to
enhance the motion detection based on
where you fall on the spectrum that
maybe a little bit far-fetched but it
would definitely be something we'd like
to look into but as of now unfortunately
the prime challenge is emotional
recognition so yeah we completely
recognize the shortcomings of it right
we can't solve all the problems are our
goal is to solve the big one and then we
can move on to all the French cases so i
found one small little loophole in your
logic of using Instagram absolutely
twitter for that matter you're using
people's faces without their consent
that's kind of boredom on Instagram and
its public good i mean that's that's the
internet may have but that's the world
we live in and wanted a tiny play but
you're a hacker conference there's
there's a button on your Instagram or
that's what your ideal about right
if you don't want to share it with the
world don't share it with the world it's
really easy and they give you that
button that's not a problem we're trying
to solve sorry but i have a question and
these images being run through some
filters for people with color blindness
because i used an app real quick and
they all check out pretty well for
people who are colorblind
I i'm afraid i must admit that was not
intentional but I am glad to hear that
are you know I i think we would have to
look at filtering specifically for the
different types of colorblindness it's
something we can look into in the future
for sure and further usability studies
just want to say i love the the idea and
I'm just curious have you seen the
twilio programming video I know we
haven't seen that with settlement you
guys are you just look it up
ok you'll love it hello there thank you
okay last but not least we'll just throw
up the resource slide this a couple of
white papers to read that are pivotal in
the capture community highly recommended
stuff
dr. motoyama dr. Lyanne dr. Bernstein
check them out and then last but not
least the links to the new image
annotation stuff packed existence calm
all the stuff will be up there soon
check it out thank you guys all for
coming yeah we got one
listen okay just one more thought if the
way that images are selected is sort of
predictable than you might be able to
try to match that the challenge with a
limited pool of images then given an
original sin enough to an IP I and get
absolutely wrestling Robin that we run
into when we scrape google images is
that all those images already exists and
if we search smile you know it's going
to be obvious we get top 100 you can do
a match to top 100 its cool thing about
this python library is Google's already
figured out that images have faces so
you can search things like rock or sign
or red and it will return images that
have faces so it's a lot harder to
figure that out backwards on but our
goal for solving that is pulling stuff
from the firehose of Instagram and
Twitter and images that haven't been out
there before so
alright thanks everyone
appreciate it
ok