they do so if you'll join me in please
giving a very warm 11 hope welcome to
the social engineering panel well
greetings everybody here we are again
the 11th hope social engineering what
we're going to do is introduce the panel
maybe tell a couple of stories maybe try
a few tricks but mostly talked about the
theory of what social engineering is all
about which to me is about building
trust with people who really shouldn't
be trusting you but there is a lot of
information as long as people have the
information there is always going to be
a weak point menomonie computer systems
and manage encryption you have as long
as you have one dim with that will give
you something that I supposed to give
you you're going to be able to get in
and affect all kinds of chaos and of
course that is the goal tonight
my name is Manuel and i've been social
engineering pretty much all my life
it's a fun way to get around and get
things done arm I'll tell a couple of
stories i guess in a bit but i want to
introduce the other members of the panel
we have car over here
hello hackers i hope everyone something
fun thanks for coming with Alex
everybody and we have Bernie s greetings
from Philadelphia
[Applause]
I probably sound better now than usual
on the radio
yeah that's his tag line you can't use
it so we're gonna start with some
stories party want to start with you all
the way over there with the story of
social engineering maybe that you have
performed in your life at some point
that either benefited you or did not
benefit you
alright here's one that by then when you
asked me recently like like couple hours
ago
beyond the panels like what am I talking
about alright i've been working on this
project since early last year in
Philadelphia ought to with a group of
volunteers to build a nonprofit
community FM radio station and uh uh
there's a really good social engineering
story behind it the we got our FCC
construction permit which there's a lot
of social engineering pirate radio that
led up to that over like 15 years before
that but that's a whole another story of
social engineering but we got a
construction permit we started building
the transmitter equipment and so forth
end up we need a call sign
they don't just assign one to you
randomly you you select from a database
well like internet domain names all the
good ones are taken
there's just the only things laughter
like w xq Z or something that you can't
not useless akron I've got that one
so you got that one got a good ones so
on
you can't get four letters anything not
anymore
so this is going to be a people-powered
media radio station by thought like WP
p.m. would be perfect of course you
check the FCC callsign query database
it's unavailable registered to US Coast
Guard to a cutter vessel called the
Galatea was a Greek goddess who fell in
love with a cyclops you screwed her over
but that's another story
and so both this ship the Galatea like
me research this turns out the Galatea
was built right across the river from
Philadelphia camden new jersey 1933 was
commissioned in 1933 probably build a
computer for that and its first mission
was to do running introductions during
Prohibition like was cool longer read
more up on this so early war on drugs
and so the ship serve that value mission
and then after after alcohol became
legal again think there's a speakeasy
downstairs at one time they uh they
decommissioned they had a grand some
other missions and then he commissioned
at 1946 and I'm not even 40 80
Commission I'm like well this is what I
found out from the research on the ship
since the Coast Guard was sitting on
Sundays call sign for like 68 years like
what are you doing just sitting on a
shelf and nobody asked him for it so i
did some research online and found some
radio people and the Coast Guard called
called around reach the guy named Jerry
who turned out to be a ham radio
operator like myself and I didn't have
to i didn't like i used my name's Bernie
s not like my legal name but I told him
that too you know I'm a ham like you and
turns out he was the last Coast Guard of
official to send a coastguard person to
send Morse code message when they got
rid of marks code 95 so we bonded over
that was code and like wouldn't it be
great Jerry if this former FCC calls for
this former is this Coast Guard callsign
wpm could could again live a up a us a
mission for the for the community in
into in dickinson inconsistency with the
the public service mission of the Coast
Guard and he's like yeah yeah yeah let's
do that so he gave me a name of somebody
in the Navy to call who manages all call
signs are all vessels a contact person
the coast go in the in the Navy and he
said are you gonna talk this other guy
who's in the Coast Guard and that guy
was dead so they had to find someone to
replace him
and then a so i finally somebody if they
replaced them with and they said no you
got to talk to this person the FCC and
then this person a sec said you need to
talk to this person at the department
homeland security because the Coast
Guard is part of that and I've talked to
Homeland Security then back is typical
government bureaucracy and back to the
Coast Guard and have talked about 10
different people for different federal
agent for different agencies or like go
through three months finally reach the
guy are actually woman in the Coast
Guard I explain this whole public
service mission of this this uh this
callsign could be could come alive again
in the form of a nonprofit community
radio station in philadelphia right
across the river from when the Galaxy
was first launched and like let me see
what I can do and she she released it to
the FCC and I i had her time in such a
way that we applied for it at just the
right time windows would never showed up
on the FCC's call site as available they
just went from registered u.s. Coast
Guard to uh to register to Philadelphia
community access media and we grab we
got the call sign
so it's now people-powered media and it
wasn't i didn't have to lie or anything
it was just social engineering this guy
bonding the hams and the other radio
people and getting them to think that
this would be a good mission for their
call sign in the future and they bought
it and we got a great call sign i asked
talk to people are commercially rated
that that's a great call sign how did
you get that it's like well there's a
story behind it so what our launch party
our launch party in a few weeks we're
gonna have a big bowl bowl of rum punch
because of yeah the running mission but
that's an example of social engineering
we don't have to lie we all do this i
think we all start a social engineering
our parents when we were like two years
old so just different ways of doing it
didn't involve any fraud or lying but it
was social engineering and it really it
accomplished something really useful for
the community so that's my story
I looks your own i am ok alright well i
think some of you thanks for that thanks
for the warning appreciate it
he's good at that isn't it we're gonna
see him in action in a few minutes as
well that may be funny if you well let's
hope ya anyhow I I think I recognize
some of you something so my talk
yesterday on the panama papers and if
you haven't
thank you
I'm a lawyer so I was actually very good
segue from what Barry invention
sometimes I'm not allowed really to
social engineer anymore i did have a
long history of this back in the day but
as a lawyer
we are not necessarily allowed to
misrepresent who we are there could be
ethical implications with the bar
committee for that you know you're
basically saying you're somebody else
when you're an attorney and getting the
information that even in social media we
have very strict regulations about
impersonating other people to acquire
evidence or information that can be used
in court and we can get into deep shit
basically if if we do something against
those regulations so I'm very
constrained by their but that doesn't
mean that I have to be fraudulent I can
still social engineer i can still
essentially use the trust of other
people to my advantage and i have done
so in many occasions of course one
particular case comes to mind and it
also another good segue because this was
really in the public interest and it was
a pro-bono case that I had several years
ago and wound up in the New York Post in
the Daily News and we were on 1010 wins
and in New York magazine
I represented a poor woman and her two
kids an Indian woman or two kids that
came out of a homeless shelter and they
lived in housing and queens and I
inherited this case from associated my
prior law firm he left and I thought
well this is this will be good
experience of going to court
I'm not around the landlord's attorney
for a little while and you know this
will be that the house will be you know
i'll get a judicial order compelling the
landlord to fix the property so this
poor woman and her two kids can live in
it and this will be done it wasn't that
easy this actually wound up dragging out
over two years i went to court 32 times
on this matter and i lost my bonus from
my big law firm two years in a row
because i spent too much time on this
case and they wouldn't give me credit
for it so that's yeah it cost me a lot
of money as well but one of the things
that complicated this is that the
landlord hers herself into too many
details about her but was very sketchy
and when she
showed up for court the first time it
was a young fairly attractive blonde
sorority girl from local university on
Long Island owning a property in a
predominantly black area and cleans
which kind of struck me as a little bit
odd
so I started to try to co-opt her
attorney and figure out what the hell is
going on here
this is a very unusual situation so we
start talking about Long Island various
bars nassau county and I got him to sort
of trust me and then I just presumed to
know a few things kind of guessing and
then he assumed that I knew these things
because I guessed right about them and
he gave me a couple bits of information
that I was then able to combine these
tiny little bits of information
lamee actually mostly about addresses so
it wasn't anything really confidential
but he gave me a couple addresses and
with those addresses i was able to
combine real property records from a
Chris an online database in New York
where you can look at real estate
transactions going back basically about
a hundred years it's actually pretty
cool to just play around with blue to
determine that essentially this landlord
had acquired the property that was in
foreclosure and was in disrepair
essentially through what appeared to be
mortgage fraud and not only was at this
property but when you traced out the
transactions of the corporate entities
of these particular parties in the
transactions it led to more controlled
less you by the way
yeah and then when you trace out those
transactions it led to more mortgage
fraud and mortgage fraud and mortgage
fraud and I basically stumbled on a
mortgage fraud scandal worth tens of
millions of dollars running all
throughout queens and brooklyn and I
didn't know what the hell to do about
this because my job was essentially to
get the property in in good repair so
that my client and her kids didn't have
to go back into a homeless shelter so in
my job is not to enforce the law of my
job as an officer of the court I have an
obligation to the court to be truthful
make accurate
presentations but at that point I
decided with the Council of our own
essex lawyers inside that we weren't
going to let this information out to the
court and that we were going to keep it
under our hats and try to get them
basically trying to force them to comply
with the judge's orders and this lasted
a long time
the heat was shut off i'm starting to
get he was shut off in the winter
she lost electricity she almost lost her
kids because acs got involved it's the
administration for Children Services if
you're not from New York so that's why
they're all these emergency situations
required me to go to court jump into
action the house flooded with sewage and
at that point mysteriously well back up
one second i followed another lawsuit to
help her back into court she started
complaining that the landlord that is
she didn't have an attorney at that
point and couldn't afford one yet my
process servers when I was hitting her
with a subpoena were writing down the
license-plate numbers of all the cars in
the driveway one of which was a
brand-new Mercedes so I don't know what
that was about but then mysteriously the
house burned down and yeah i think they
thought that if the house had burned
down that it would make the case go away
but I had already made the case about
contempt and I was asking the court to
throw the landlord in jail at that
particular moment for what she did to
these these two kids and her mother and
it became a of again pretty contentious
situation but we had got in touch with
the daily news in New York Post and let
them know that an open court we were
gonna break this mortgage fraud scandal
and so they were sitting there in the
courtroom when we broke this and they
had the reporters out side and waiting
for it to come out of the courtroom and
then all these stories came out and we
want up settling the case and getting a
decent amount of money so that this
woman wouldn't have to essentially live
her life back in a homeless shelter but
it was all because I co-opted this guy i
gotta trust he gave me a little bit of
information and i was able to use that
entirely to my advantage and I still do
a lot of things like they're gonna say
I'm gonna unscrupulous lawyer but
you know I think having a hacker
background definitely makes a what makes
a world of a difference in negotiating
tactics you know in my life today
it definitely helps and unscrupulous and
lawyer are contradiction in terms right
that's right yeah oxymoron right yeah
you it is a good administrator honest
mechanic right yeah absolutely
this is the skills you can use in any
profession just being alert noticing
things being able to connect with people
that will get you very far
Kyle's going to talk to in a moment but
i think first you want to do one little
exercise here
so what we have there we have a tiny
picture shouldn't be the home screen and
also use okay can you guys see what that
is so truck go get it
that's not even a truck yeah that's
truck now you might see a truck like
that all the time and I think anything
of it but if you're a hacker you might
see something and and and think wow ok
there's something more here there's a
system at work we hear this so many
times that this conference I've heard it
in so many different areas airplanes
trains electronics programming we're
always noticing things that nobody else
cares about and kind of my walking
around a few weeks ago we noticed one of
these trucks tiny again yeah and we want
to okay with these trucks are everywhere
what are they doing because they're
always they're going around the middle
of the night and they're outside of
starbucks so we figured out that this
Bartlett company is actually the
distributor for starbucks in Northeast
and so we figured you know how is that
work exactly how that relationship work
it doesn't say starbucks on it they
don't want people to know that they
delivering the starbucks but it's not
hard to figure out because it's an
18-wheel truck parked outside of
starbucks for about half-an-hour arm and
then we started wondering okay so how
how these guys get into the starbucks
you-know-whats how's that work they have
a special kind of code is is the key
left under the mat is there an employee
waiting for them someplace we were
curious and that's really all it is it's
curiosity we have no ill intent we just
we see a system at work here and we're
curious how does that system work
well most people just kind of give up at
that point and say well I guess what is
not meant to find out but fortunately we
know of this thing called the internet
and i decided to the hell did this all
within the last hour because we had
nothing prepared as always
but that's it that's appropriate because
social engineering is not something you
practice however research and pretexting
is is good to build on whatever kind of
goal you're working on the end but it's
better if it's fresh so we have done
this right away it's all sort of our own
digging so keep in mind we know not that
we knew nothing we still don't know very
much about this we're learning right now
about this whole relationship so we
looked on the Internet to see if anybody
was talking about the relationship
between starbucks and bartlett and we
came upon this wonderful site known as
read it which we can make that big that
the great you see this there's there are
starbucks employees here literally
comparing stories about how there's
tortoise work what time they open when
they check in how they lock their doors
430am to open at 5am and and then they
start talking about about Bartlett down
there somewhere talking about how they
screwed up and left the door open and
how do you know barley was other did you
do control and i use google and search
for starbucks and and and bartlett and
you didn't have to search the page it
was just there I knew it was on the page
someplace and it's it's down here
someplace I go through all the taxes a
whole lot of conversation here but that
what this did was just told me that yes
indeed at least in some cases they have
access to the place on their own because
they can leave the door open when they
leave
well so obviously it's not an employee
there right but we still have any real
like they didn't reveal necessarily like
how to get in or the the operational
structure of how that works but
definitely the folly of having these
guys there and the mistakes that are
possible with that system so now with
social engineering you you pick up key
phrases you kick up a pic of words and
and people trust you because you know
those words so when I call a starbucks
arm and I say something that involves
the word Bartlett they're going to know
that I know what I'm talking about
because they know what Bartlett is far
as to call them and say are you do you
leave your door unlocked at night that
the probably not going to believe that I
Madden and deserving of any more
information from that point but if I if
I inject Bartlett into it maybe they'll
give me more information
I don't know we have not tried this is
all untested and this is an exercise in
social engineering which oftentimes I
think more times and not fails and you
have to be able to cover your ass when
you do fail and in fact i'm hoping we
fail because that's an important part of
it all is you know you don't say oh my
god you got me and then hang up now you
know yet back out of it gracefully so
that they don't suspect any anything
beyond that one phone call but you're
listening has to be tuned because in
that failing you could you could learn
five different things you wouldn't have
you would have been able to glean from
any other source but it was revealed in
the context of them correcting you
people like to be right so they want to
correct you they want to say no no
actually no this goes at this time or
whatever it is so you must be keen with
your hearing as well so the third part
of all this was a wonderful a store
locator site that the starbucks runs
which gives you every phone them for
every store so we can just go down the
list of Delta it was not last the
audience too much
dial the number now I don't care for
number gets out
oh and please try not to make too much
noise when i'm talkings awfully hard to
explain yeah but when I'm talking to me
forget all services were thinking of you
as well from but I pulling back about
the problem we have with access the
other day what's that we have some
trouble with access the other day i'm
falling behind with okay has anybody
talked to you about that
noclip okay because we don't have the
problem again we couldn't get in because
this girl is very difficult to open and
you don't come to this you just come to
the stores will be closed when we don't
want our time so am a drugstore i'm
talking about again please I said I
we're always open when finally come so
maybe I'm calling to one which which
stores bitch from hell
oh I think yeah I think you're right i
think we might have the wrong store
because the crowd here before because
okay my mistake that five haha ok well
that's that kind of is exactly what i
was talking about
did she give you the delicious panel I
can fail and still get applause yeah but
did she give you the name of a store
that does close
why did I did she go ahead and share it
and we hear that I think she knows your
energy we got you must have the wrong
store
okay widget which tells me a couple of
things there are stores where it is
closed right I'm when a comment but
they're always open so now i know that i
know when Marlon comes they're open
so yeah I think I'll try another store
then maybe I'll get lucky maybe I'll
find someone
another store that that they're always
open for it so I don't have any specific
stores because i have so many III kind
of maintain in in contrast without
saying that were already were always
miss representing ourselves I mean I
want to get to Shakespearean but i think
i think that there that charisma that
empathy I've talked about on the panel
in the past those are part of all of our
personalities and I daresay part of
survival in a lot of ways that whether
it's you know getting your phone bill
corrected or we're getting out of a
situation i mean i think us us telling
NSA security we're looking for a
restaurant by the museum there i think
that counts
well yeah when you pulled over by a
bunch NSA cops you have to tell them
something
yeah and why and when you have when you
have a hundred millimeter you have a
camera between you and your you're
definitely doing some some capturing of
imagery and so that that was the
situation where yeah I was like all the
camera was on the floor and I'm like
trying not to be a journalist and I add
that's actually a proposed I think
there's a lot going on with that now and
as someone who is a journalist I'd kind
of represent often when we travel MIT
represent myself or misrepresent myself
as someone who is not in journalism
because of well how things have been
going and and how they may go here in
this country sweet-talking cops is
definitely absolutely i could use social
engineering quad officer I wasn't I
wasn't anything really
yep and
look at normal it doesn't work in to go
on the roof dog so don't write try it
back
yeah that the security although they'll
give the story of the cops that right
from the video but Alex would you were
talking about also process service i was
a process server at one point and that's
right for it doesn't surprise me but it
was interesting work but yeah I mean
there's so many hats you can wear so
many different types of jobs
yeah to gain entry 22 to get a sense of
what's on the other side if it's the
other side of the door
it's a system whatever that may be
you have a plethora of things you can be
to someone else to to get what you get
at information or whatever goal is the
important thing is to be seen as a
trusted person for instance
ok I'll give an example are you walk
into a bank and I've done this so i
walked into many banks and with the the
bank that I use most often they know me
so they don't ask me for ID when I when
I were thrown money however other
branches don't are so they would ask me
for ID but i try to attract one time I
try to get around that system what i did
was i walked in i know where the bank
manager's office is on the left so the
bank manager waved now you have to be a
complete dick not to wave back with
somebody waves at you so they way back
at me tell her season he knows the bank
manager so they must be cool didn't ask
for ID something as simple as that and I
didn't rob the bank i took it out of my
own account but still that's how you
gain trust a simple hand gesture
sometimes can do it
um another thing comes to mind is
credentials there's a lot of different
types of things you can apply for I got
several different forms of
identification i'm not going to get into
it but just by passing background checks
you can become someone who can go into
all kinds of places and not necessarily
be in any kind of industry specifically
like with a lot of the logistics just to
get supplies here and create the event
getting a CDL license not i mean that's
that's kind of sensitive right now but
driving trucks
all kinds of different levels of access
become available when maybe just a
five-dollar application fee or something
simple and and passing right through
whatever screening you then become
something else that might there you
might have some verification some some
things to show that would support who
your uh who whatever character you are
creating to to gain that trust and go
down that sort of that logical path and
help them with their decision making it
as to like if they're gonna assist you
if you're in distress or something wrong
that kind of thing to get them on your
side and and help you whether it's
remote on the phone or in person like at
the security gate talking to somebody I
don't know
yeah and unless we're ready to make a
phone call while i'm always going to
make a phone call that you want go ahead
ok I've got all right side always I
don't wanna interrupt that that's that's
why I'm here too and I i think what I'll
take a poll do you guys want to hear why
I think lawyers are susceptible to
social engineering
I mean in particular and I think it's
extremely dangerous and I need to
preface it why
while Kelly tell you that's actually
want to get in trouble here but I think
lawyers and it is very dangerous and I
put this out there so that other lawyers
will become aware that this is I think a
great tactic you know for social
engineering lawyers you establishing
that trust establishing like the
Bartlett name essentially is is really
all you need to do you were so inclined
to try to social engineer lawyer you
would really be able to capitalize and I
mean social engineer with the intention
of let's say gaining access to a lawfirm
Network this is why i think it's
extremely dangerous and lawyers
practices are inherently insecure
because we love to freakin write letters
we love to write letters to each other
and not just letters that you know in
the form of an email but always attached
as an attachment as a PDF or something
akin to that where we write emails to
each other and we say please see the
attached correspondence in the
above-referenced
her with the judge and say you know you
see you see something come in and you
say oh shit somebody sent a letter to
the judge or to the court
I need to open this immediately so boom
you know you can pop them that way but
if you really wanted to establish trust
it's extremely easy to find all the
cases that a lawyer has been working on
her is actively working on by using a
pacer system the public access to court
records and you can find lawyers active
cases and you would look at who which
firm is his adversary and that point
once you have this knowledge of the
lawyers adversary you could call a
lawyer and impersonate that lawyers PA
is personal assistant or paralegal from
that law firm and say where we really
need we're trying desperately to send
you an email that contains
correspondence with the judge in the
matter of Smith be Wesen something like
that and for some reason is getting
bounced by your email server so without
even registering let's say confusingly
similar domain name that would
impersonate the adversaries law firm you
could then say I'm gonna send this to
you from our gmail i really hope this
gets through it's extremely important
letter you send it over
obviously you know what to put in the
attachment the lawyer would open it up
and he would open up as a lot of it
would pop this law firm immediately you
make your lateral moves inside and there
you go i mean it's extremely extremely
easy to establish that level of trust
but then you would have to back up you
would have to call up again and say and
probably apologize and say I'm so sorry
I know you're a senior partner at this
particular firm i got our matters
completely screwed up I really screwed
up
could we just keep this to ourselves
please because my job is on the line
here and of course the lawyer Wilson
don't worry about its fine he'll be
relieved that there was no letter to the
court in this particular matter and have
no idea
quite possibly that he just popped his
entire farm I think it's incredibly easy
to establish trust
another thing is extremely dangerous
with the way lawyers have operated for a
very long period of time as that in
federal court when and every federal
court has its own bar so you need to be
admitted to
it here in New York let's say the
southern district of new york and that
which is in manhattan and then the
eastern district of new york which is
Brooklyn and and Long Island everyone
has around registration their own
registration number but the number
system is actually fairly consistent and
hasn't changed until relatively recently
so you can go into previous filings and
look at attorneys registration
information which is their first initial
their last initial and then none other
than the last four of their social
security number that makes things a
little bit easier as well what's really
bad i mean this is an incredibly bad
practice and now the federal courts have
woken up to this but these historical
filings that contain that information
are all their and their public records
that's a big problem you can use that to
establish trust very easily we really
make funcle' well ready to at least
think of something okay show on the
screen we have here I really got a
present
yeah i want to fuck with this guy really
do this
I mean look we've got a 10-game network
we've got the 3000 hackers at the
world's gone insane saw you know what we
have a moral responsibility to something
alright so so a couple of things first
there's a phone number on this on this
website I don't know what's going to
happen if i call and try to call it and
want to save the answer
[Music]
thank you for calling Trump campaign
headquarters
our goal is to make America great again
relating to mr. Trump campaign press
releases or our event schedules please
visit our website at www.kttape.com haha
ok for all other inquiries please listen
to the following often if you would like
to volunteer please email volunteers at
Donald Trump dot-com it's a good way
social and one and leave us a message if
you would like to offer advice or
insight to the campaign already growing
on Trump dot-com or press to and leave
at the message if you are calling with a
press inquiry please press three for all
other questions or to speak with a
member of our team please press four and
we will connect you
ok for it is then please hold while I
try to connect you realize that no idea
what this
these people high 34 traffic president
campaign and I find no one available
it is decidedly know your name and
information that I more attention to the
story please enter your PIN and then
around this is the Trump campaign so I'm
going to try 1234 you've entered an
incorrect pin we enter your PIN and then
66 from the trucks from that's a good
one
I'm sorry you enter to see my times are
you feeling this bribery and your pan
2016 okay i'm sorry you have entered an
incorrect pin goodbye
ok you get you get three tries but that
wasn't really what I want to try to
expect anybody to answer this
let's try cellphone that because that
actually was publicized at one point I
don't think it's still it's still works
your call has been forwarded to an
automatic hit them nine 1775 thick 80 is
not available the mailbox is full and
cannot accept
oh well we don't have to disguise that
number it was it ended in 8000 which is
unbelievable but ok again this wasn't
what I was really thinking we could do i
I figured you know they just had their
little a shindig out there in Cleveland
they must be planning some other
activities tomorrow sunday right and
sunday is meet the press day and sure
enough on meet the press tomorrow
look who's appearing none other than
Donald Trump and senator Bernie Sanders
so well not together not together but
done
I thought it might be fun
we need to screen please on the
self-help on voicemail pricing pound get
you the Prophet ok the screen there i
don't see it right where is it
yeah i'm moving to get this yeah we
don't need us we need the screen
ok so as you can see they have a
schedule ready for tomorrow show Donald
Trump and senator Sanders and I have no
doubt that's the order they're going to
go in
well I thought it might be interesting
if someone from the Trump campaign said
you know we want to go we don't get the
last word so we want to flip that
alright so but we have to call them so
how do we do that well I i did some
searching online i'm not going to show
you what I search for because i will
show you the results but i was able to
find some numbers some numbers in New
York some numbers in DC and again it's
possible that nobody is there but even
if nobody's there we can leave a message
and maybe get the wheels in motion
because sometimes in social engineering
you don't see the results but you know
you started the results we back in
college I i worked with some very
mischievous people we we started a feud
between two professors
one cent we have because our thing was
was cut and paste letterhead before
desktop publishing so we took someone
from the department of mathematics we
took that letterhead and type the nasty
letter to someone in the department of
physics
I think of the exact issue was maybe
it's a parking space maybe it was
something in a building I don't know but
very nasty words were spoken and it went
through the the intercampus mail so
there it wasn't traceable in anyway just
went from one box to another and no data
was received by the physics professor
who then sent a response equally nasty
to the mathematics professor things
neither one of them sent either of those
letters but they both received them and
we know that something awkward happened
after that I don't know why we picked
them as they did something that pissed
us off i don't know what was so anyway
that's the idea here is to to get wheels
in motion to have somebody at NBC saying
what the fuck just don't want to do now
and even if we get voicemail we're going
to i need a name
I don't have a name what name should I
is why
true true is good i like Drew I can't
get when you shout out John Miller I
don't like 30 John Miller's ok yeah that
was the student soon a little crazy i
kinda want to ask for john miller like
that's a different thing but somebody's
gotta ask for the CP actually you know
you'll have you'll have eight years to
play these games
Oh God careful what you ask for yet
suggestions
I was just saying that was Trump social
engineering by I don't think of a name
given name for it i'll be looking for a
name associated with Tyrone forgotten
people about use a Jonathan guile Roy
Jonathan guy i don't know we talked with
that 1i have no idea
guile guile last date girl it's a little
bit little bit of a pun not remember
it's okay all right
John you a lot of livin you're probably
unlikely to find a Mexican name on the
me jon kyl about that John against just
young yeah about that
all right drew got drew I'll dry like
your first I don't like it anymore
yeah true true sounds like somebody who
should be on a yacht
yeah here's the thing okay I i search
for I search for NBC internal numbers
online and I found them
ok that someone had their list of NBC
internal numbers and there it is online
so i was able to get a number for meet
the press so let's um let's try this
I can be my own writing 25
your call is being answered by audix be
surprised he's not available
wait for the town when finished
recording print button otherwise for
assistance press 0 now record at the
tone tried it we were in touch for a
living
the weirdest thing ever i don't i don't
know i don't know what happened there
with my own okay i don't know what
happened in the middle of my message
she said you have 45 seconds to finish
talking and then give me another beeps
oh I was all confused so that didn't go
well at all but I you know if it did go
well we had the right the right tools at
our disposal to be able to do that we
have the right phone number we could
have left a message and maybe maybe
something will come of this
there's another half to all this but all
that other people talk for a moment I
like gather myself to get your mouth
full benefit of your own invention we
still recharging Trumper looking for
Trump ideas I've got plenty of ideas but
you go ahead tell a story or something
or i'll just just to go with the when
you when you run into situations like
that you've got your name you you've
come up with this persona like speaking
to a couch Ramon of of the character
you're creating i I've spoken about mood
of voices in the past but mood is a
really critical thing I mean you can
have a character and maybe a draw or
whatever their name is and so on but
what's going on with them you know
what's their state are they in a hurry
that that kind of stuff is really
critical to the believability and and
and so on
you met you might have been able to save
that if you have been if you're
anticipating some disruption by saying
you have bad connection or or your
you're driving or something
stuff like that helps because it builds
out what it is part of you sound like
you're going through you know the
Woodstock PA system it's a little hard
to explain that I that's what threw me
off so maybe the next call makeup on
I don't know it's really difficult to
get the balance right but if I could be
heard but also not sound like I'm going
through speakers but we'll do our best
maybe hold the phone
I don't know this is that you have to
keep the rest
it's an unusual way to do that usually
get your you're sitting on a phone by
yourself and and your you have all the
time in the world doesn't take a few
minutes
ok so now Carl you actually found this
one
yeah we were looking for Trump people on
and you found a list i believe of of
important people
yeah so I'd i was i was thinking about
okay so you need to this part of free
texting part of doing your research
being prepared for eventualities you
want to know a little bit more than you
have to know so that if something does
come up you can pivot or react and and
keep that up so I was coming up with so
what would what would you want to know
about the organization you know the
structure so because it's this behemoth
or whatever it is it's got characters
actors within it and media media
relations departments and communications
directors and check it out check it out
on the communications you see that
person their whole pics whole pic come
on
is that not an invitation
so I searched for Trump media staff and
we found uh we found a pretty good
it's called ballotpedia or something but
hope it's come up
yeah I like that the mystifying triumph
of Hope Hicks there's a lot of press
about her
Donald Trump's right-hand woman
right-hand woman so there's also
information we have this person that we
have a name obviously we're not going to
call Donald Trump cell phone i'm not
gonna be able to reach him at the
campaign headquarters but we can look at
her pics a little bit and maybe learn
some things and there's this article all
about her about how this is a big change
for her
Donald Trump introducing her saying this
is hope this is hope this is hoping that
way it is but he's saying this is help
which i think is really funny and we
basically scroll down through this whole
article which is really a very long
particle that is one person and if you
look down here the demands of her
schedule let your breakup with her
boyfriend of six years and while she
technically still lives in Greenwich
with her sister Mary Gray's when she's
not traveling on Trump Force One she
stays in a in New York and a trump
apartment provided by the campaign well
okay what we learned here we've learned
she has a sister named Mary Grace who
lives in Greenwich which is in
Connecticut and it doesn't take much to
go to whitepages.com and look up Mary
hits and look there's her address right
there in greenwich connecticut now you
can't get the phone number because if
you click on phone number you have to
sign up for something you get all this
malware and and various other things but
but you can look up the address on
yellow pages and bingo
no pics shows up with a phone number so
if I were so inclined and I really don't
want to get into this but I could call
hope Hicks at home at ten o'clock at
night on saturday and say hey let's meet
the press we have to reschedule and you
know cause all kinds of mayhem
alright alright i'll give it a shot but
but let's keep the speaker down i'm
going to outsource 67 this time which i
forgot to do the other two times you
know when when
oh yeah this is really weird when you
call out on this phone you know what the
caller ID says hope now only shit if I
call her house and it says hope on it so
we're gonna think it's her and then i
can know why doesn't say your last name
but that's gonna that's gonna be weird
ok let's give it a shot i mean why not
i'll be jon kyl again why not let them
confuse themselves whereas John gal your
guy or our guy yeah at some point it
just doesn't matter anymore
ok so not getting it out home
you know where women being dicks you're
calling me at this hour of the night and
hope doesn't even live here
I'm so this is the only number that we
have across from solid the address
number today
well what what did we learn from that
this happens we learned that that Mary
Grace and hope aren't on the best of
terms right now
because she didn't even offer to take a
message
and for God's sake she works for Trump
and always could be important
okay well I I know I've caused a little
bit of mayhem and I'm good with that if
you are all the Donald is just beginning
is just beginning we have all kinds of
things planned any questions do we have
a microphone there's anybody wants to
come up with and tell their story or ask
a question of us can you guess
Trump using microphones right there's a
start can you guess
Trump's pin you have his cell phone
number it goes to voicemail
can you guess this Ben well not in front
of an audience in five minutes no but it
only give us three tries don't use three
tries and you you know put me in a hotel
room for a weekend maybe I could yes
microphone right I'm not listening to
people just shut up in the audience
anyone else shy bunch so no questions
yeah okay yeah you started your get your
shot up
ok alright we're a little bit beyond
that alright but i think that this meet
the press scenario if it wasn't so
impromptu and you literally have a
couple of hours of predatory ten o'clock
at night and Saturday it could be really
highly effective although to just
prepare it with one email to this meet
the press person I see that you have
some numbers and names here on these are
the numbers that we got just from an
hour ago looking it up on google and i'm
looking at people's names and things
like that bc you know how easy it was to
reach somebody who is one step away from
someone of influence not hard at all we
didn't wind up doing anything we might
have just basically got a whole lot of
suspicion but we did get to those people
if you leave anything on the internet
you can be gotten to as well it's it's
really really easy this there are very
few people that can cover their tracks
on
but it's not hard to cover your tracks
you don't have to give your phone number
out in your facebook account you don't
have to use real information you can
confuse the system as much as possible
and give a good fake info and fake
details and that way when people try and
start mischief with you it might be a
little bit more difficult
eventually they could get something but
if you have fake information out there
maybe maybe you'll be safe for a little
longer or maybe you'll know somebody's
trying something you'll get hints your
question go ahead
what are your feelings on responsible
disclosure in social engineering such as
do we have responsible disclosure you
know do we have a responsibility to
disclose if we find significant
vulnerabilities see how do you draw that
line
it depends what you are doing it for i
mean if if you're doing it for nefarious
purposes obviously that's not going to
be high on your list someone in the
hacker community what we do is we we
printed in a magazine when we find out
things so I consider that to be
disclosure we're telling people things
are keeping it to yourself I don't think
that's really very responsible to get
selfish but but sharing sharing security
vulnerabilities including social
engineering ones i think it's something
that we need to learn from and that
other people benefit from from others
failings maybe I was imagining it
because no one else come to join but
when you're on the might go meet the
press call it said didn't say all press
0 2 if you need assistance
ok I would have got to meet the press
operator probably we've got another
voicemail at this hour if it's so yeah
probably won't happen again I wasn't
really trying to screw it up so much
more demonstrate how easy it is to get
to the right people
I I feel if it had succeeded it probably
would have been worse if it failed i
mean i don't know i'm not sure how they
would have reacted to that
go ahead someone's avoiding the call so
I made up and then the sound like it
descended of a former president like
Ulysses something grand something or
other and start again through with
things like that
okay i don't understand that but I think
you're saying historically speaking as
has been presidents and the president's
with presidents I don't know how do we
have incoming call you know what is very
Mary Grace calling back I'm sorry Mary I
really feel bad about this
no I'm not no no all right fine i'm
going to meet the press return your call
that's revenge that go back to the very
first social ceiling panel very first
hope in 1994 and I pulled the same trick
on smh you realize it was funny then
it's not funny now that was funny and
it's itself history repeats itself
alright folks posing commentary anybody
could use to be another panel you'll get
another drink
I gotta run right up I got alex's panel
across thank you guys thank you
please continue I having fun and hope
and we have lots of panels left to go
and we have hackers got talent at
midnight in the other room
yes thank you check it out