everyone hear me okay all right i want
to introduce these folks who work very
hard to get here we have a Jesse Redakai
Jesse by video via Skype glad you can be
here virtually we have a carry Shankman
and we have a néomi coleman and they're
gonna be talking about hypocrisy with
our government who is no persecuting and
prosecuting people for telling the truth
being charging them with with capital
crimes like treason for telling the
truth yet our own government just
continuously leaks information for its
own interests
we've seen this from the White House all
the way down and various intelligence
and law enforcement agencies to very
common problem and there needs to be
some more equity so these people are
going to talk about leaking Apocrypha
and what we can do about it
thank you thank you so much everyone in
it it's really an honor for all of us to
see such an interestin see such a packed
room right now I'm Carrie Shankman a
First Amendment and human rights
attorney representing journalists and
doing freedom of expression freedom of
religion and also state power cases work
with the Center for Constitutional
Rights representing WikiLeaks and Julian
Assange perhaps one of our most
well-known cases and these issues are
very important to our office and here
with Naomi called in
if you wanted to introduce yourself
briefly i'm sure yes I'm a campaigner
for the courage foundation and we have a
session tomorrow as well and we run
defense funds for a number of
whistleblowers and activists and i'm
going to give it a quick view from
Europe on some of these issues so i
think it would be most appropriate for
for Justin to start out I think she
needs to know
introduction but she's the legal
director at exposed faxes is famous for
representing many whistleblowers was a
whistleblower herself at the Justice
Department currently represents Edward
Snowden and it is one of the most
prominent voices up defending
whistleblowers and freedom of
information so so jessalyn it's also an
honor of a big honor to be on this panel
with you
thank you for having me it's an honor to
be here and I'm really glad you're doing
this
basically I you know in my experience we
really do have a two-tiered system of
justice and high-level officials who
leaked for political game get cover and
those blowing the whistle on crimes and
abuse end up facing decades in prison
and this problem is urgent
it's costing the daily liberty of people
like Edward Snowden and chelsea manning
and many whistleblowers who are really
really having their lives ruined as well
as the liberty of joy and Assange a
publisher and it's very important that
that we address this and the pack that
there really needs to be some sort of
Public Interest defense for people who
are telling the truth as opposed to
people who are leaking purely to score
political points or for their own
personal reasons and it in weeks that
have no public interest value whatsoever
suggest Elenna i'm curious what your
experience has been you mentioned public
interest defense but maybe not everyone
in the audience knows what that means
how does how does the US sheet
whistleblowers publishing and public is
that should I answer that or shipping
should do I probably should
I'm on with you
um basically add baby yo courts don't
recognize a public-interest defense and
yo that was abundantly clear in the
court-martial of chelsea manning clearly
there would have been a public interest
defense that you're leaking not for
political gain and not for personal
reasons or to score political points but
because the public has a right to know
and would benefit from this information
and there really needs to be that kind
of defense especially if you're going to
be prosecuting people for something as
serious as espionage so I'm interested
especially because you represent Edward
Snowden who's currently in exile in
Russia and and John John Kerry now
presidential candidate Hillary Clinton
have made statements saying that he
should come back and face trial that if
he's committed an act of conscience part
of that is facing facing justice and
facing a judge and I think Kerry also
said that he should quote man up
what what's your response to that why
why doesn't why doesn't he just come
back and and and sort this out in the US
Court has said that he'd be happy to do
that if he would be allowed to raise a
public-interest defense that what he did
was in the interest of the people but
the US government has specifically said
I'm including the political people you
mentioned that he would not be allowed
to raise that and I know that actually
an interview a few just a few weeks ago
former attorney General Eric Holder said
that said I had performed a public
service through his disclosures and yet
should still face trial what do you what
do you make of that having the highest
prosecutor former highest prosecutor in
the land saying your client is performed
the public service but still shouldn't
get a public-interest defense
well I'm glad bit Eric Holder agrees
with us that had performed an amazing
public service and what he did but I
find that completely hypocritical and
contradictory to say that he should
therefore still not be entitled to some
kind of public interest defense if what
he did was a public benefit it's sending
a really mixed message to people about
about how you should behave as a citizen
I i want to push a little bit more on
that why would it be hypocritical you
know what I think it's hypocritical to
say that someone performed a tremendous
public service but we are going to
continue to try to punish them and go to
the ends of the earth to get them to
hunt them and to make them pay for
performing a public service that's not
normally how you think people sometimes
people get statues sometimes people get
walk and people you know people have
things that you know wonderful public
things done in their names but normally
you're not told to come back and be
thanked by facing jail i recall i live
in new york and for others to live here
i think maybe a year ago there is a
there's our project to put up a bus that
were snowed in brooklyn and I think it
was quickly taken down so so i think
that's that's the closest attempt to
just actually I know that there have
been monuments internationally certainly
there's there's one that has 33
truth-tellers on Assange Snowden Manning
on chairs and a fourth a fourth chair
that's a it's called anything to say but
it's quite a remarkable exhibit where
basically a member of the public can go
and just stand up on the fourth chair
with these other truth tellers and the
idea is that it's in a way that we often
think that whistleblowers are
our exceptional on these heroes that do
something that's unattainable but I i
think one of the points that that you
jessalyn it made so so strongly in your
careers that it's it's really up to
everyone whether working within
government or outside government to
speak up because there are so many
people with clearances are so many
people who are facing misconduct sorry
viewing and seeing misconduct abuses and
and cover-ups that have an obligation
under the old city take for office not
just under oats and the Constitution
which is a lot of the land to respect
the First Amendment the Fourth Amendment
the Fifth Amendment but also human
rights treaties which are also the law
of the land under the Constitution and
numerous conventions which which make
torture for instance a severe human
rights violation that when witnessing
torture or cover-ups of torture
individuals have a duty under
international law to report that so it
can be prosecuted
so they think the the big lesson from
that is that is a public we all we all
have a duty to stand up and it's very
possible it's not it's not it's not
unattainable for anyone i was curious
jessalyn it in terms of the next just to
emphasize that point I wanted to say
most people don't set out and say wake
up one morning and say I'm going to be a
whistleblower today you know most people
are doing their jobs and trying to
follow the rules laws rules and
regulations that they're working under
and then they find themselves crosswise
with the government for doing that but
most people are not out to make waves
most people are trying to serve the
public right and many many much of the
narrative is that a low level officials
will get prosecuted for exposing
misconduct
where is so-called like protected or
important officials are are are given
protection for the most part that tends
to be true but it's not always the case
that it's a high-level low-level
distinction and in fact some of the most
prominent whistleblowers
have been very very high-level officials
like Thomas Drake for instance was a
senior official at the NSA bill binney
also a very senior official who devoted
their whole lives and careers to public
service out of a sense of duty and
patriotism and they saw that the very
system that they had swore to protect
we're betraying the the people the the
people that they had a duty towards
because ultimately the question is where
does that duty
where does a duty to protect why what
are.what are secrets designed to protect
or they designed to protect
embarrassment misconduct or abuse or the
designed to protect people are they
designed to protect constitutional
rights and where those secrets are
covering up violations of constitutional
rights that raises not just legal
problems but severe ethical and
constitutional problems as well now i
agree completely and and people blow the
whistle because they do see violations
of law rules and regulations but i think
they also have strong moral compunctions
and i know i would hate to think that
employees feel like they should have to
check those morals at the door and you
know basically have their belief system
be subservient to a government manager
or someone in a position of power name
you want to jump in and one of the
things because the courage Foundation
which Naomi's a campaigner for Ramsey
official defense fund for edward snowed
in and has
you can bring bring them on as well
above friends the official defense fund
for Edward Snowden and several tree
tellers I'm is committed to the legal
defense of those who often are neglected
and are faced with big legal battles and
problems alone and i'm curious to get
your perspective in terms of encourages
and a vision going forward and where I
have what kind of the maybe european and
international perspective to towards the
u.s. is on some of these issues so i
guess a lot of these cases which seemed
to be incredibly painful controversial
in the US the view from Europe is not
you know much more straightforward and
injustice is much more obvious than
sometimes seems to be evident from the
debate you see in the United States its
I think implicit in what courage does
that by making it clear that there's a
support and the support net for
individuals that suspect that's
available and ready to step into action
you make it I mean you know i'm not i'm
realistic about this
the barriers towards people you know
against people making these clothes and
massive psychological barrier the
barrier toward you know being be able to
work you know what it but it does what
it does psychological to you what is
socially but we hope that by making
clear as an organization there which
will fight your corner and finally
quivered individuals which not many
other not many other people do that it
and changes the calculus of can I actual
cannot act at least slightly
and just like I know that you've
actually led delegations to Europe like
he went with former Pentagon Papers
whistleblower 10 in ellensburg thomas
drake and and and and several
whistleblowers and you visited a mosque
on Julian and the Ecuadorian Embassy in
London and so I feel like you've got a
chance to experience like the european
parliament and there's actually been a
lot of progression like the european
parliament voted by majority that to
that Edward Snowden whistleblower should
be granted protection and and record and
solemn should be respected
I'm curious what your perceptions are if
you've seen Europe to be more
progressive on whistleblower issues or
if you feel that right now we're kind of
shifting into a darker time I think
overall we're shifting into a darker
time but Europe is certainly more
progressive and I mean they had may have
different works for it like in France
whistleblower is a lunch there to alert
someone who sounds the alarm but it's
the same idea and so there's definitely
an appreciation of it there though you
know in the grand scheme of things I
feel like it still has negative
connotations that have to be overcome so
many my note by chelsea manning filed
appeal in in her court martial in May
challenging the draconian nature of her
unprecedented sentence which was 35
years in
in prison for disclosing nothing that
was to lose wrestling and just can you
hear me
so maybe maybe i'll continue and then we
can alter my video off
no come back
yeah maybe we can get one of the sound
folks up I don't know why it keeps
turning it off if this doesn't this
isn't like shows she's offline so maybe
she got disconnected
we'll just try that one more time
that's my recording or is this what did
I just hit this am I doing this
that's a video right that looks like a
video call thing that's a video message
that sound okay great i'm i'm in chat
right now what am i doing that that's a
call that's this is what years of
education does for you i'll try that and
kind of multitasking bit but i'll
continue in the meantime and maybe if
somebody wants to come up and help
otherwise i'll just like paddle my feet
and struggle up here but so on that
point of actually comparative defenses
so chelsea manning filed her appellate
brief in May which challenged the the
length of her detention 35 years
unprecedented sentence and numerous
organizations actually felt supporting
briefs in that case which is very
interesting so there's a coalition of
different human rights groups so the eff
for instance filed a challenge that the
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act which is
one statute that Manning was convicted
under for the use of w get a batch
downloading program to access cables
that she actually had access to the
individual cables and actually
interesting academic question is whether
that same theory that was used to
prosecute Manning could have been used
against Hillary Clinton for batch
downloading materials that she had
access to individually but so the FL the
excellent brief challenging the CFAA the
ACLU took on the Espionage Act arguing
for Public Interest defense and the
another group the open society Justice
Initiative filed a brief basically
comparing the international law in many
jurisdictions and looking at essentially
how the u.s. is way more draconian than
just about other any other civilized
country in the treatment of
whistleblowers so for instance they
looked at how whistle blowing or leaks
to the press are punishable by less than
five years imprisonment at least 12
countries and punished by at most 10 in
most countries and also a number of
jurisdictions as well as a European
Court of Human Rights which is the
highest human rights court in Europe and
a binding court over Europe
in countries allows for Public Interest
defense which is again we're
whistleblower will have an opportunity
to present the their motive and the fact
that they're making disclosures in the
public interest again there's there's no
chance
yeah it looks like she's offline actual
so I don't know maybe try to run away
from you guys
I i can have that effect
yeah showed on I'm worried because the
little dot was no she's not on let me
get Nate maybe you can okay great
maybe if you could give her a call to
but so in the meantime you know I it's
really a problem and Jesslyn is
completely on point and I think the only
will speak more to this in a second but
the view isn't Rosie anywhere it is in
Europe especially the financial
whistleblower cases but certainly in the
u.s. it's a lot worse and I i think one
point I kind of wanted to end on was
that when we talk about these
whistleblower prosecution's and a
teacher justice system when we compare
cases like Hillary Clinton and General
Petraeus you know who essentially got a
slap on the wrist for disclosing top
secret code word materials as pillow
talk and when you compare that to what
happens to whistleblowers to act in
public conscience on BGC a two-tiered
justice system but it's it's not only
about prosecution's of whistleblowers
and in fact that that's kind of a tip of
a much larger iceberg in fact most of
the most of the censorship and
repression is in secret because that's
that's the most Sarah piss and that's
the most effective type of repression
so if we look at Freedom of Information
kind of like a valve of information
flowing you know from the government's
perspective that that that flow can be
cut off at any point so it could be cut
off at a drawn-out public trial of a
whistleblower that could send a message
but it can also be cut off by draconian
administrative policies and threatening
and FBI visits
that are much more difficult to report
it can be cut off at the publisher level
so the whistleblower can disclose all
the materials you can have all the
technical protections and anonymity of
whistleblowers but the publisher can
simply be afraid to publish because
they're afraid of losing access or
they're afraid of a criminal prosecution
so we saw that actually with the New
York Times and waiting a year with the
AT&T store years ago and we also see
that today when you look at how the
mainstream media behaves a lot of the
reporting is actually dictated by fear
of losing access to the kings or now
maybe Queens Court so I think it's an
important thing and what I'll leave
honor some quotes from from President
Nixon so in 1971 there's a often
forgotten story but there but they're
essentially Nixon almost started world
war three secretly because India and
Pakistan broke out into a conflict and
the official policy was neutrality but
Nixon and Kissinger decided to have a
secret till in favor of pakistan and
send a giant worship to the region to
try to provoke Russia and it actually
almost started like literally was a
flashpoint at the level of the Cuban
Missile Crisis a moderated breaking
reporter by the name of Jack Anderson
broke the story actually just days after
many he leaked memo an internal memo
just days after it was written and Nixon
and Kissinger was so absolutely furious
that they wanted to go after the source
of the story the story actually ended up
later winning the Pulitzer Prize but but
the quotes of mixing about this affair
publicly available and I'm and
collections of his quotes buddy but this
kind of gives a window into what going
after whistleblowers is all about
so the first one is mixing saying about
about the the source
the point is mrs. Nixon is there any way
that we can keep radford the source
scared to death so that he doesn't get
out and think oh I'm now going to write
the book or I'm going to do this or that
or the other thing can be told that a
criminal
I think he's got to be told that a
criminal offence hangs over him that
it's going to hang over him and that
we're going to be you see what I mean I
like to scare the son-of-a-bitch to
death
another one that's perhaps even worse
he's speaking to John Ehrlichman his
counsel so this is Nixon we better do
something with him the source but i
don't know what the hell have you got
any ideas
Ehrlichman replies yeah but they're all
illegal mixin all of them illegal haha
that's good
Ehrlichman put them in a sack and drop
him out of an airplane that would do it
yeah replied the president so on that
note i'll pass it over to and Naomi to
talk more about the financial
whistleblowers shields
oh sure just lucky
yeah I can hear you and night okay oh
yeah
please don't leave this is very
difficult to follow so i'll try not to
make too much money do it myself but I
think it's worth pointing out the
situation in Europe although definitely
in some respects is more positive than
here
certainly the case that the EU has had
you know quite serious investigation
into Edward Snowden's revelations and it
was known was allowed to it was able to
present a statement that the council of
europe have done the same and Germany
has a very long running an investigation
in into NSA surveillance and German
complicity with that now and I think
that's been going on for almost a year
if not if not longer but at the same
time actually if you look at
whistleblower laws within edu and
Germany is is really bad for domestic
whistleblowers in you it doesn't
actually have a proper whistleblower law
at all so the pic the picture is very
mixed and I just wanted to draw
attention to one particular issue in
Europe which does impact some of the
most important big important
international disclosures that we've
seen in the past few years
to clean the area of financial and
whistle blowing whistle blowing on
corporate tax avoidance and tax and tax
havens public understanding of these
issues increased massively over the past
five years
social activism in this area increased
matter of the overpass values would not
have happened without reporting and
whistleblowing you can cut would not
exist without the contribution of
whistleblowers actually no mistaking
that at all within Europe within
particular countries in Europe
luxembourg and switzerland in particular
banking secrecy laws really serve to
chill disclosures and punish
whistleblowers and some people industry
may be familiar with the case of Rudolph
Elmer who publicly gave information
about bank julius the private banking is
better
WikiLeaks and your family has been
persecuted and there's no other word for
it persecuted relentlessly over the past
five years and you know i recommend you
go and look up the details this
absolutely absolutely incredible
what's been going on at night but you
know he's still under threat and it's
still happening now I'm obviously the
your it doesn't quite have the same
problems with exemplary punishment that
happens in the United States but in some
ways the direction of travel
it's very worrying and in my job of the
card foundations is something you know
we are concerned about and we're
tracking quite actively and one of the
most interesting examples over leaked
Apocrypha I've seen recently and
actually reported in public in private
I so interesting british magazine just
last week is pricewaterhousecoopers the
accountancy firm saying that the luxe
leaks disclosures that the International
that the ITA Jay gave worldwide
attention to in 2004 this is the
systemic exposure of tax avoidance that
was happening via Luxembourg saying that
those disclosures were justified and
this is interesting not because any real
debate about whether these disclosures
were justified or not they resulted in
multiple investigations they all
most cause the resignation of the
President of the European Commission who
as finance minister and then prime
minister of Luxembourg was directly
responsible for a lot of this stuff and
it's interesting because
pricewaterhousecoopers and were direct
work in turn directly responsible for
the prosecution of to whistleblowers
concerned and and one daughter who came
forward publicly and another guy called
Rafael hele and these and they were
seeking so these two guys were peppered
prosecuted under banking secrecy laws
and for theft in the Luxembourg court
they also try to prosecute one of the
journalists concerned you might be
interested to hear and the journalist
was acquitted but both and but both
Delta and how we were given suspended
sentences and fines and that decision is
being appealed now but I bring this to
your attention because the European the
European Union is also just passed trade
secrets directive which in theory
obliges every member state of the
European Union to passed similar laws
which would be applicable in a wider
selection of cases this is such a clear
and present danger to press freedom in
Europe that even the New York Times
Editorial Board you know great editorial
saying so things in your not i'm not
totally crazy and their issues that we
should be keeping an eye on i'm
wondering if we should continue the
three of us are jessalyn center alphabet
did you say it didn't want to cut you
off i just wanted to underline mimis
point and if you look at whistleblower
protections for bank whistleblowers in
the u.s. like dodd-frank and star beings
oxley bank whistleblowers have far more
protection and national security
whistleblowers and i would say that it's
just as important to know if your
airplane has not been properly inspected
and might fall out of the sky as it is
to know if you're you know if your
account is being totally mishandled and
we really need to have parity and these
kinds of laws
what do you think is the best way
forward
do you think that's in the courts do you
think that's in Congress do you think
that's not a grassroots level or a
high-up level because you spent your
career looking at these issues and I
know that had you know so many different
experiences you know I think it takes a
multi-pronged approach
I mean Congress unfortunately what you
end up with in the end is not what
people are often seeking in the
beginning which can be really get really
positive reforms to get so watered down
by the time they're past as to be
meaningless courts have you know had
limited success for the problem is that
banks can take years and years and years
to unfold and let's just wait up wait
again you can have a really good law
like Whistleblower Protection
Enhancement Act but then there's a big
gaping loophole for national security
and intelligence whistleblowers who get
cut out with the protection so you know
there's not what I feel solution but i
think you know you have to take a
multi-pronged approach and keep pushing
on all these different fronts and I i
know there's there's another element
that I think tents to be kind of more
psychological a way at this idea of
shooting the messenger which is I idea
that goes back is as far as civilization
where I you know oftentimes the there's
kind of a human tendency to want to
punish or ostracize someone who speaks
out because of institutional dynamics or
for secrecy internal secrecy codes i
know this is something that always berg
has written a lot about that that
organizations promote cultures of
secrecy and I keeping secrets ends up
being becoming a mark of worth to we're
losing a security clearance can-can
almost become like losing one's identity
and end and value and I wonder because
you've had a lot of experience fighting
stigma personally with your
whistleblower experiences but also in in
defending your clients not just in
in the courts but also in the press
because the press has a tendency to
mount attacks on whistleblowers and
we've seen this very recently on and
tragically with the case of chelsea
manning who who are lawyers reported
made an attempt on her own life and that
that wasn't treated with any respect by
the army which actually leaked
confidential medical information and a
violation of HIPAA it appears so
and I mean and this isn't the you know
this isn't any exception this is
treatment like she was subject to
solitary confinement and numerous
whistleblower cases like in thomas drake
there is this man and their
mismanagement of evidence and and so
many of these cases involve break-ins
violations of the law so I i wonder if
maybe you can speak to this esteem of
stick mine if there's any any way to
promote and and push back on this idea
of a whistleblower as as a trader which
is toss around i know it came up
actually even in the introduction of
this talk this I idea that of the
traitor how do we push back on that you
know I think it's you know you
historically Queen out that whistle
floors throughout history have been seen
as traders turncoats and more recently
or painted as terrorist sympathizers and
this is done to marginalize them but
also to try and minimize the importance
of what they're revealing and I think
one of the best six to do is look back
at historical examples and say look at
someone like Dan Ellsberg who revealed
the Pentagon Papers which now 40 years
later we're comfortable saying you know
this is something that is credited
widely with helping and the Vietnam War
and we shouldn't have to wait for the
years before were able to do indicate
whistleblowers on Tom Drake is got a
quicker vindication but still is eaten
up you know this is eaten up more than a
decade of his life dealing with us and
us speedy resolution would be preferable
than having agencies drag the stuff out
forever certainly I mean we know this
through the wikileaks case and and and
and Julian who's been subject to with
the UN the UN highest authority on
detention actually came out with the
ruling months ago saying that his
situation the embassy is is arbitrary
detention that it's illegal and that
sweet in the UK are violating
international law and neither state has
agreed to abide by that opinion in a
process that they chose to participate
in and involving human rights machinery
that they both countries help create and
this is mean and this is in the context
of a ongoing over five years now
investigation into WikiLeaks in the US
that's been unprecedented pervasive and
included dragnets of associates and
supporters of WikiLeaks visitors to
WikiLeaks so we see this at every level
not just from the whistleblower but also
to the publisher facing censorship that
was the case going back to the Pentagon
Papers trial when the FBI would visit
independent publishers who are thinking
about publishing the pentagon papers and
there's a famous case involving the New
York Times and The Washington Post but
in fact they're 17 newspapers that
published experts from the pentagon
papers and actually Nixon administration
tried to get gag orders against four of
them to prevent them from publishing
except the information was spreading so
fast that they just couldn't sensory it
anymore so this in and now today I mean
you have Obama saying things like you
know
whistle blowing today it's not like
Daniel Ellsberg be seen as a hero he's
you know he's the good whistleblower and
now you have these absurd i mean absurd
hoops that that officials jump through
and commentators drunk through to try to
try to distinguish dan ahlberg from like
Chelsea and
and and it's completely absurd because
he publicly supports them he actually
says that he should have blown the
whistle earlier and he you know he's
been at the demanding court-martial and
been very vocally supportive so I think
that really goes to light that there's
so many inconsistencies with with these
cases and I'm really glad you brought up
that point that last point especially
should i do you think we should go to
questions for sure what you were
thinking okay yeah should we
I guess there's a microphone if you have
questions and then we can try to answer
them or you can direct them to one of us
i think yeah we make more sense to come
up directly to Mike could someone
comment a little further on this whole
idea of the Public Interest defense and
why it's not allowed under either
federal law of the very state laws that
might apply it's just not recognize gets
part of the I mean if you look at the
whistleblower protection laws of the
simpler Protection Act Whistleblower
Protection Enhancement Act there is just
there it's not written into the law it
just says that a person may reveal
information that he or she reasonably
believes evidence 'as fraud waste abuse
illegality but it doesn't say anything
about what to do or what happens or what
your protection you're entitled to when
the government does retaliate against
you
so it's just not in there at all and
that would be a great affirmative
defense debt to have available for
support and also a knob so the main law
that's used to prosecute whistleblowers
you might be familiar with is Espionage
Act of 1917 it's a hundred years old and
was passed by the wilson administration
not to not to prosecute spies but the
first few thousand prosecution's were
actually of socialist party and then
labor movements
and that law is extremely vaguely
written and also provides no defense and
it's been interpreted most often by the
eastern district of virginia where many
of these well whistleblower cases are
Arbroath where individuals don't have an
opportunity to introduce evidence of of
positive motive of their acts so in
previous cases like John Kerry obvious
case Thomas Drake's case they actually
tried in the Manning court-martial tried
to say look at the party you know look
at these like look at these things that
bad things that were exposed but the
judge will actually say you can text you
can introduce that what makes it even
worse is that despite that the
government is allowed to introduce
evidence of harm
so in a way effectively taining the jury
and this happened in the man in case
allowing spectacle speculative and
attenuated ideas of harm caused by
disclosures without allowing the
individual to defend against that so I
think the public interest defense is
probably the the most needed most needed
revision to the active you know I think
most lawyers in the space
sure just one would agree for you know
the need to repeal the espionage act as
both outdated and draconian law violates
the First Amendment but I think
realistically speaking the public
interest defenses is probably the most
important is probably the most important
thing that we need my agreed absolutely
should make a difference whether you're
leaking the score political points or
retaliate or get revenge vs because
there's information that the public
needs to know and the public has a right
now that's a huge distinction and it
shouldn't matter and the fact that
courts have been saying it doesn't it's
very drunk I'd like to return to the
topic of whistleblowers and stigma I can
understand that
a large corporation or a large
government would be would take offense
to someone who made them look bad and
they would retaliate by trying to make
the person who made them look bad look
bad or look worse so I think that sort
of the nexus an expected response but
one of the things that I'm wondering i'd
like to get your thoughts on is during
with some of the leaks that have
happened during the last few years i do
you think that whistle blowing at least
among you know there's it seen it seen
with some element of virtue or heroic
pneus think it's always been a
double-edged sword people vilified dan
ellsberg including Nixon is a very
publicly when when people to the whistle
but now you know many years later use
you have you seen anything as a hero
that he is so I think there's always
been this love-hate relationship with
whistleblowers that our country has we
celebrate erin brockovich but then you
know we always you know every article
that was suppliers is normally you know
has these under tools of oh they're off
they're weird they don't go with the
flow they didn't fit in they have an axe
to grind you know and all these other yo
get it it's in all these other mixed
motives that they might have I add to
that I agree totally with all of that i
think it's also worth recognizing that
was sometimes a bit of a fake public
debate about you know hero or traitor is
used deliberately in the media to crowd
out discussion of the revelations
themselves and the University of Cardiff
have done a survey of all of the British
coverage of Edward Snowden's revelations
and what they found is particularly the
right-wing press endless stories faculty
hero is he a traitor
you know we use and that if you like
spread out and allocate you know and
occupies all of them
speaking of space in those particular
newspapers that might actually be used
to discussing the revelation of himself
was cleaning the British government did
not want to do at any level so i think
that's also worth bearing in mind what
do you think of the goose refer to of
leaks and the DNC lakes and the
insinuation that this is an attempt by
the Russian government to influence us
politics
do you think this is yet another case of
people in the US trying to maintain
power and stigmatized the whistleblowers
who are acting the public interest or
that it is in fact Putin trying to
influence the US or something in between
someone else want to take haha i haven't
had a chance to fully digest all the
stories so I know that with respect to
WikiLeaks it's WikiLeaks is position to
not comment on any sources on an
anonymous around you think torn
anonymous browsing is going to make it
easy for people with the world without
actually giving cop sorry can you repeat
that the tour and anonymous browsers
will make it easy for people whistle
blows without being caught by the
government so they can verify the source
is real but they can't find get it do
you want it or making it easier
I'm love life and I think it already has
in some extent obviously the risks the
risks are very great and what we've seen
particularly i mean if you look at
chelsea manning is case it's not the
initial submission mechanism which
causes issues its
it's a problem of you know who you have
someone to talk to eat the issue of not
getting caught is bigger than can you
submit something from A to B anonymously
is a bigger it is a bigger more
complicated problem in that but
anonymity is certainly an important
factor and being able to blow the
whistle successfully and I tried to
limit the whistle anonymously and then
basically ended up getting outed by a
government and so am i if you think
anonymity as an important factor and
being able to blow the whistle it's
certainly a valid way to blow the
whistle and and according to certain
amount of protection and safety that
person taking the rest i wanted to
return to this very important issue with
bokra see which is what this talk was
titled on in particular around
prosecutorial discretion because we've
had in the United States a series of
intelligence officials that have
actively lied to congress under public
oath and they have not been prosecuted
and I'm wondering if there's a
structural mechanism within the
Department of Justice Justin where you
work that we could use or advocate for
that would hold seer officials
accountable for lying to the public if
we're going to hold people who disclosed
information the public interest like
Edward Snowden to this basically exile
thank you i mean the proper mechanism
would be to appoint a special prosecutor
or independent independent counsel to
look into these cases and investigate
them but the departmentation itself to
be very very poorly capable of
investigating itself unwilling and
unable to do that so I just don't see
that happening
I i found the discussion of different
whistleblowing laws in different
countries really fascinating and I'm
wondering
if there any other places we could look
for inspiration maybe outside of your
outside united states just does Canada
anywhere in Latin America Japanese
anybody else you know especially on the
other financial side or an intelligent
side is there any other place we could
look to inspiration to maybe get the
stuff for peridot better
yeah well they're there some other
jurisdictions that have that have public
interest defenses of different forms so
you can imagine that sometimes they'll
be national security exceptions carved
out which is less helpful but I know
it's actually been some time since I've
done done research on this but by canada
and Denmark I believe have explicit
public interest defenses written into
their laws like I said the European
Court of Human Rights has allowed public
entrances look to support what's called
a proportionality test under article 10
of the European Convention which is free
speech article looking at a so basically
allowing the public interest to be
considered that would apply that to
europe i know i want to say i want to
say saw something in Australia but was
less helpful because i think it had a
national security exception carved out
but a number of other jurisdictions if
they don't have those defenses they
certainly are not issuing as extra Conan
sentences and I think that's a very
important point I think there's a lot of
guidance and international law there's
numerous organizations have produced
principles you know articulating
national security cases and human rights
laws actually been progressive there's
been a lot of work by civil society
works on this interview last
I mean there's a glutton blueprint for
free speech we've been doing comparative
work on whistleblower laws within the
g20 which is really which is really
interesting but yeah it's taking bits
from different jurisdictions I don't
think anyone has a complete again
there's no one country that you'd
recommenders having it you know
great set of laws of whistleblowers
generally i don't think just we running
out of time but if you just want to say
yeah I don't think there is one to like
oh this person this country has the
ideal model law that if we should a
pattern off of but I think you can take
that some pieces from what other
countries are doing and say look okay
it's this should be a good principle
follow or they're doing the right thing
injury so recognizing this s2 was like
where we're out of time but thank you so
much
jessalyn Naomi for
[Applause]
Thank You Jersey