I'll tell about this experience I did
last year name my presidential to but I
in the mid-nineties i was working for
affirming bonus is doing computer
programming i was in charge of content
management system for womans news
website not a good one of the articles
were like finding your prince charming
and the summer diet winter diets I don't
know six move stuff like that and we all
work in the same place the journalist
and the people in the computer
Department and I think this tree or some
kind of reaction on me
not a good one because i started to work
in this side project of becoming a
partner and so I started to work in this
website they do I was a front-page with
different woman's to choose which one
with different features
let's put it that way so you choose a
woman then you pay with a credit card
and then you start to have a
conversation if you say the right things
the woman will take her clothing off so
and you know how it goes
that was the use case and business plan
to one but I had trouble
I didn't know where to find us this
woman and worse than that was a little
short of money what I did have was
programming skills so i decided to make
a child but if you don't know what
charities child is an application
decided to conduct the conversation
maybe the most famous one was down at
1966 MIT lies at the computer therapist
that was the basic idea and a friend of
mine working for the same company
provided pictures from webcam stream
with striptease progression so the chat
but the pictures should make the trick
I thought our the website was a complete
disaster
I didn't last a year and i talked with
some of the users and they gave me
feedback and it turns out that they
always recognize the bought
behind the woman so whatever whatever I
put all the files in a back up the
database the code that in place and the
pictures and completely forgot about it
and feel last year our last year
National will change of your monarchy
style government first of all this guy
over here mr. Kishore won the presidency
was in fact he didn't want heating when
he came out second but we have in place
something called dash which is just
another terrible French idea like rotten
cheese with bala Tosh if you lose an
election you make everyone both again
and then maybe the second time you win
because your opponent will not be
present because of the poles that are
not so convenient I think hear you call
it to run system so this guy was
president when twenty-two percent of the
boats and after that his wife right here
waiting for another show won the
presidency for to private so for years 8
years 12 years the same family in the
government are the men in the middle in
this case is not a communications attack
that is just for Chavez the former
dictatorship of Venezuela that's a nice
3some and I don't know who that woman is
within funny happy so innocent you know
we have 41 million people as you can
imagine having the best 24 office in the
same house
we also really low and maybe you know
that because you have like father and
son and now maybe you had the marriage
as well but that was not even the
problem in Argentina the problem that
was that you know those years we had
like a huge corruption it is pretty
common in South American countries if
you want to work with the government
let's say you want to make a highway you
have to put a 10-percent under the table
like a sweetener
you know those years that ten percent
went to fifty percent and of course if
you don't want to make the highway
that's ok as well we also had a nepotism
friends and family working for the
government
we had statistics manipulation the
government made up all the numbers of
economics and if you have a company you
work in that area and you want to
publish your own numbers they will put
your fines and well anything then
exchanged fraud the use privileged
information to exchange basis for
dollars and they won't like 23 million
dollars and if you want to change your
own places for dollars as a common see
to send you were allowed to do that
what else are a little drug money
financing campaigns everything smuggling
everything he said drug use it to make
another drugs and imports of everything
were really low during those years went
to the roof and everything is used to
make drugs
let's remember that and least but at
this one
yeah last but not least our prosecutor
investigating the connection between the
government and people from Iran involved
in bombings attacks and when a scientist
was found dead just the night before
going to make an accusation against the
President as we see in Argentina we know
it was a suicide which isn't know who
did it and two months ago and this guy
over here was a former public works
Secretary was found trying to hide nine
million dollars in cash in a comment
nine million dollars bags and bags and
bags of money he was also occurring huge
military weapon that's understandable
nine million dollars and of course he
never heard about bitcoins on blockchain
and well god forgives but it doesn't
always help
he's now impression so that's good news
during those years the last eight years
Christina frontier for the president
doing give press conferences after all
press conferences are annoying events
where you have like journalists making
awkward questions
instead of that she uses twitter account
to provide exquisite pieces of
information also to harass the position
to excel fanatics and even to make
racist Chinese jokes like this one this
is an actual do it from the President of
Argentina so after reading i was one of
the followers of the president's account
after reading that I thought well my
point board is able to tweet like that
so i went to i found that backup folder
i extracted the cold and try to look
what was in there so I found our PHP
code that's active server pages it was a
programming language way Microsoft no
longer use I was pretty common back then
connected to an access database so i
migrated the code from PSP to PHP a
great programming language with all the
features I needed and I migrate the code
from the database from axis to my sequel
then i wrote an important piece of code
to connect the chat but with twitter
let's remember that the child was
originally obtained all the inputs using
a web form and all the outputs using
HTML so i wrote this code and now all
the inputs were provided using
terminations and all the outputs where
answered using twitter status update
then I had the database are in the
database i have words and expressions
from the porn industry you can say that
point in politics have lots in common
you could be right but you won't find an
important and not even sadistic porn
somebody sewing reseller former
president so I went to the database and
started to load the database with words
and expression from Canada national and
international were long really long to
our three-hour-long presidential
speeches and that by law all TV stations
from radio networks should supposed to
broadcast of course the law also says
that you need an emergency to make a
national but you know for them like
emergency was a broad concept and they
use cutting-edge you're not even to
announce when the person got a new dog
that's true you can look it up
so let's take a look at how these check
works
first of all there's a piece of code
monitoring that twitter account i
registered this one cfk responded the
original what cfk argentina that's the
initials and I thought well maybe the
people will think that the person use an
institutional twitter account but
maintained by sem and then with this
account she want now to answer the
citizens so piece of code monitors the
account when you mention is found that
mention he's saving into the database
into a log for three reasons first of
all I wanted to have to check what's
going on in there to have a lot to tweak
the application then I don't want to
answer twice the summations and then I
was going to use that Louis wall to
provide answers to use that and i will
talk about later the next step was to
parse to remove the account from the
tweet and to parse worse and phrases and
make the database cooperation and
finally one answer is found it sent to
Twitter using twitter status update
so now let's talk about the answers are
i have three levels little one is when I
want the child finds a complete phrase
if I i have a complete phrase chances
are that the answer will be pretty good
if I'm not able to find the complete
phrase i try to find just the word if I
have a word
the answer is good but not as good as
the last level 1 and then I have all
purpose answers in the cases I i'm not
able to find phrase or word and i'm
using just generic strings like tell me
more about that I don't agree let's
agree to disagree whatever and a nice
trick that the chat bot else
that is a mix of online and offline
content in this case are the child is
able to go to the main opposition
newspaper get headlines from the
politics section and mix those headlines
with offline content
an example would be well look what the
the newspaper saying about me i don't
agree what do you think so it's a nice
trick and usually people get some
pressure on that and other things is
able to use information from Twitter for
example the child is able to say well
you could be right but you only have
five follower so who cares and then the
child is also able to use regulations
that are now in the database in the log
so it's able to get something that
anybody says and put that asset twitter
update so I put everything in place and
I thought well maybe a few people start
to use these and they they will say well
I know you from the stupid party chat
but in the mid-nineties but to my
surprise things started to work really
well here we can see an example from of
an actual tweet a guy named joe says uh
I'm going to make a real-time
translation you're a criminal
assessing you're going to be in jail for
the death of alberto nisman that was the
prosecutor you are going to have a fair
trial USS senior going to be in jail for
life that's pretty intense and the Board
says anyone who does sometimes makes
mistake
you never did anything and the guy
answers are i did some things in the
past and it paid for them but I never
stole like you are going to be in jail
so the conversation is taking place in
this case a girl named Lucas says seen
that 30 years ago on building democracy
day-by-day from my works in the
opposition party all the ones makes
build makes wealth using the boat and in
this case it seems that they bought
detected our this world years and it
says your notions of timing are a little
bit confused so middle-class
and the conversation goes around and the
girl says is it wrong that everyone has
the same opportunities you are the
confused one and hear the answer is you
shouldn't be so extreme so it is working
pretty well in this case our devices by
the way how do you reach here while a
question and a guy named leonel says I'm
casually that means that is a follower
of the official party and I'm writing
because of workers at sea are without
jobs nobody listens Christina please
so this guy over here things that the
second is actually actually the
president and the chat but is not
allowed to give jobs so he says
until what point the job is just an
income source just taking one word
answers
I'm sorry that guy want I hope he has a
job by now
well here are the boxes you have to know
that we are leaders in human rights for
everything we had to leave this it seems
to be actually phrase obtained from
Canada nationality certain propaganda
made by the government all days and I
hear all in uppercase is really pissed
off says I doubt that is you in person
the one is answering and if it's like
that you give yourself a moment and fix
what can you do better so he considers
that maybe this is not the president but
he thinks that there's someone there
answering and here you have a guy named
or a clever one
this is like LOL is laughing and he says
this is not the official cfk that is
just and damn the CM who's giving
scripts to talk to the people so it's
clear enough to understand that this is
not official account but he never
imagined that this is just a computer
application so it's important to know
that this this is not real time this PHP
script is executed using a current job
in linux box once per hour so the usual
is far from perfect because if you
I the true in the morning the president
will answer at you in the morning of
course i can change that but that was
not necessary and the account anyway
started to have real engagement so i was
able to identify three main groups of
people interacting with this bot first
of all have people that things that the
second is actually the president the
former president now some people that
think that this account was maintained
by an employee like the official
institutional account
lots of people here and some people
think that this is just a fake somebody
there answering the question but there
is no group be there is not enough
people in fact for months and months
nobody not even one person says well
you're about this is a computer this is
stupid but then i wrote an article in in
in the magazine and some people try to
treat the board and that is ok and of
course you can do that it's not perfect
let's remember that this is the same
shot from the mid-nineties so my
reactions with this project or like a
rollercoaster that supposed to be me
there i don't have my team are not so
white at first I was a little bit skirt
because it all started like a small
experiment it started to grow and
sometimes you can imagine all the things
your government is able to do in my case
in Argentina I was very aware of the
things that this government have done so
like maintaining violent groups and put
in fines and sending the IRS investigate
you if you have an opposition voice or
something like that but then last year
there was the situation an extrication
was dead
cristina kirchner was person for two
prides so she wasn't able to run again
for president and they haven't any good
candidate and they will were a little
bit worried about how to get out of the
power without being prosecuted and so I
thought well maybe I was safe now and I
said to have some fun with this brushing
so i made this little box the box over
there right now are inside it has a
Raspberry Pi has some USB Wi-Fi dongle
is the screen and
to borrow know and it monitors the
account in real time so I'm able to see
what the people is is telling to to the
bottom and I have that on my desk every
day I go there now and I read it's it's
really fun but then I started to think
how is to cheat people in the main
communication platforms with today like
we're and what's up both use of course
you can use links and videos and stuff
like that but mainly both use a small
phrases small bursts of text and that is
very easy to cheat and then I started to
think another thing why is that we
cannot tell the difference between a
person and about today and like 20 years
ago the same application didn't come
compare the average upon user wasn't
convinced about the solution and today
is really easy and I thought that maybe
we cannot tell the difference anymore
because we have today sports we write
like a sports we use small phrases we
don't pay attention to the other part
are so we cannot tell the difference
anymore because about right just like
ourselves then I start to think about
the connection between politicians and
social networks I i don't think that
they both share the same agenda but they
both have have something important in
common they both need your contributions
really badly and they both want to put
your contributions in a sandbox so
there's nothing you can do that will be
able to hand them in Argentina we have a
very popular social network that is only
popular there and once i wrote an
article 13 well with comments and stuff
and then they delete the whole thing and
I ask what's going on here and they
asked me they reply well you're not
respecting the protocol and the program
was a fancy way to talk about terms and
conditions i went there i read terms and
conditions and they say they're you
cannot make criticism against the the
social network of course you can if
you're happy you can say that but you
can
not talk about how we are running those
things and I think this could be hidden
this could be explicit but it's the same
in in all social networks and in
Argentina building this monitor you have
to vote if you're both they you can
you're not allowed to renew your
passport they will put you fine so you
have to devote and you have to about
three often you have like it primaries
and you have the bowling for this and
that and you have the ballot issue have
to go again in both and so they need
your contributions in and in social
network then your post or anything and
here they need your boat but there's
nothing you can do that will be able to
change the system and that's the sad
reality so see this common this type of
projects you end up with more questions
than answers in my case I started to
think about how many times do we
interact with with with boats without
even knowing so sometimes we are
chatting with someone or asking
something about them a pre-sales
question using a chat system and that
could be about and we don't know about
that then I started to think why do we
use twitter for to discuss politics it's
a place that I don't know make maybe for
politics units like to elaborate more
and then we use twitter i don't know why
and maybe because the people is there
and then I i also started to think why
the politicians feel so comfortable in
Twitter maybe the answer is that you put
a monkey there with slogans all the time
and that's works just well you don't
need to elaborate
nothing so maybe we'll have a little
question and answers i have the language
barrier so if you're going to make an
and a question this please make a chart
slow and clear but first I wanted to ask
this guy over here ever see the street
or well-being here at hope he says his
name is for when carranza he asked
that's helped conquer about Argentina
who does impact on politics running on
the panel over simplify scriptures
record and I respect all opinions i
think our event has a point I'm
sure of our simplifies kitchen
Strikeforce women's about this
who does impact we have in the seventies
and military government and military
government is bad this one also kill
people and torture well it was really
bad and the cashiers wanted to present
themselves are some kind of Human Rights
superheroes but in fact if you take a
look at the records and you and you read
the fact you understand that the only
thing that was common in all the history
of this family was greed and money and
not human right so that's my answer to
the street you're interested in the code
r.i.p polish some pieces of this code in
in this medicine you can find it on the
page 15 right outside
so again thank you for being here I
really appreciate this opportunity and
promotion penis really far away so being
here in New York is this great
experience there you have my to track
down facebook and again thank you very
much
here's the phrase from a writer from
Argentina thank you well you is there's
no questions
ok
ok how many followers are you sorry for
photos
no no second in fact as I think 8004
worse it just started like last year but
and lots of the people that interacts
with about it's not following account
just conversations that they don't
follow the account so it's not a huge
success in terms of followers but it is
a success in terms of conversations and
began taking place there so anyone else
yeah you thinking on this council
politician
yes you find interesting doing this
without politicians yeah sure that could
be a good experiment right now we have
another president Mauricio Macri and it
could be interesting of replicating this
experience and maybe doing this in
English as well maybe we can do it here
to know it's interesting if you're
interested in this they have the code
available
yes ok that will be fun but I think we
should know it's pretty fun so I don't
know what can I had their so yes just
when you start in the morning just think
of and you start closing
how how the conversations start that
that's an interesting question what I
have a piece of code that i did not
explain here i have a script running
that identify one word the word is Karen
anymore
that's some one-on-one your opposition
you use that word to talk it's like to
talk bad about the government so I tried
to find that word and I start with a
tweet from the second so that usually
start the conversation of course if you
go there and you start yourself it will
answer as well but usually that that
script starts many conversations yes an
hour to our if the question is does the
current job executing these if that
control only answer to one
no in fact it answers to all they're all
the mentions without answers until that
point it was like a time are not all the
tweets at the same time like seconds
later but usually if the contract is
executed right now at 17 minutes every
hour you will get between 17 and 18
minutes all the answers there
yes
by Microsoft people put on and within
about a day or two it going people were
able to manipulate the bottom really
hateful racist is there any chance of
someone getting your bought your body
saying things that you would not want
the sales
of course what I mean difference is that
that was developed by Microsoft so
there's an interest there so if you do
the same here and no it's it's nothing
terrible will happen of course you can
treat this boat
well if you have that intention but
mainly the people last that is
interacting with about our doesn't think
that this is about so they don't have
that intention but of course you can do
that as well
anyone else yes
coming up
ok so this shot is exactly as the
original I i did in the mid-nineties the
main difference that maybe right now I
have a huge database the database when
you have a huge database chances are
that you're detecting traces complete
phrases and worse and those answers are
pretty good so are the procedure was
like that i try i parse the notional
takes i try to find worse if I'm not
getting word a crisis sorry if I'm not
getting phrases i go with words if I'm
not getting worse i use that makes of
online and offline content and sometimes
i use i put random things so you're not
always getting the same responses for
worsen and phrases and that works pretty
well basically because the databases is
a big database
in
you are you just picking out a single
word
already
kind of good
no natural language gear just a huge a
huge database and um script and defect
is bringing with them and your question
okay that's all up
sorry get like 15 information
in your language
cries out
that
if you have the same answer if you write
the same thing that's the question our
chances are that you're not getting the
same answer because they're random
factors there so if you're putting twice
the same thing the body will detect it
is exactly the same thing and it will
give you an answer because you're
repeating things it's not going to find
the same phrase so you need those small
things to avoid like cheating
no no because I i think because of the
timing I i started with this thing just
a few months before change of government
of course if I did this like a one year
before i'm sure that I I will maybe I
had trouble so I don't know but the time
it was really important here and your
question yeah as parents
and other articles and
are just started this I think in
September November like a few months ago
and it has some appearances in articles
and stuff but I'm usually not monitoring
I'm not even monitoring the account as
well maybe once in a monthly check there
and I put a little called or phrase but
i'm not really it's just working myself
and is working world
well thank you very much if you're
interested to talk about this will be
outside thinking