but without further ado it's my great
pleasure to present now and then here
and there please give a warm 11 hope
welcome to jason scott there there's a
tension in the room related to the hdmi
cable coming out of this it's sort of a
random quantum cable so if it clicks out
in some sort of way
I'll improvise but I apologize ahead of
time for that possibility anyway thank
you all very much for coming to a talk
with very little to say about it in the
program and I appreciate that and fi to
all the people who thought 10pm was the
time to get their dinner and so on and
also hello to all the people who are on
the stream and the people in the future
of the centuries to come of seeing
what's going on here and what people
talked about in 2016
thank you so very much for being here in
whatever way you are brain cases and so
on so there's two different kinds of
people out in the world who deal with
the stuff that I'm doing and so you
either kind of know what I've been up to
or you don't have any idea let's go I'm
just gonna go with the never heard of me
crowd put your hand up never heard of me
what the hell is this guy smattering a
small smattering of brave individuals
possibly dragged in by other individuals
and I apologize to you in advance
that's fine with me my name is jason
scott and i go around the world doing
lots of things to talk about history and
computers and a bunch of other stuff and
besides being a public speaker i'm also
a documentary filmmaker I am also a poor
sort of a pundit and all-around general
agitator in life so that's just what I
do I'm sometimes known for the fact that
I have a cat that has 1 million
followers on Twitter arm
so you know that the circle ality of
that cat always comes to me for instance
here is cinnamon toast writing to the
cat asking if the cat wants to do any
kind of a deal is the brand would like
to know how much you charge per tweet is
something that our forefathers would
murder us for saying so that happens oh
no Katrina roberts phone numbers on this
anyway so I work at a place called
archive.org I can i yeah okay fine
wonderful place it just on the internet
it's a wonderful place it was the
wayback machine and a whole bunch of
other awesome stuff that i'll quickly
talk about are in real life of course it
looks like this which my boss brewster
kahle bought because quote it looks like
the logo which is a level of real estate
speculation few of us really have the
wherewithal to go after inside of the
building it's even more impressive this
is our great room on inside of the great
room our little statues if you work at
the place for three years they build a
little statue of you because my boss
says we don't have stock options so in
the background of course there are
computers that are constantly worrying
in the back of this renovated church and
each one of those holds about now
now it's currently holding two petabytes
per hour so there's a lot of there's a
lot of petabytes sitting around on the
archive and there's me so I can't
believe the two people & 0
he's got black wings because he's the
Angel of Death and he's clutching
software to his heart
I actually do a whole bunch of things
involved with the archive so besides the
things that I'm doing involving uh like
I said being the angel of death and
wandering around talking and making
noise
um I've got all these other projects i'm
involved in it and the archive itself
has a whole bunch of projects involved
in the primary 11 can think of is the
fact that has millions of books up books
that have been scanned by the archive or
scan by others
it also has movies music and web and and
so we have stuff going from modern-day
all the way back for in terms of texts
that you can read immediately in the
browser click on it full screen and boom
you're reading that same thing with the
music we put up music and you click on
it and you're playing music and isn't
that amazing and same thing with movies
you go to the movies and you can click
on them start them up and we don't have
content ID so it's much easier to get
stuff up there and I'm you're able to
play a whole bunch of different cool
movies and i'm always trying to put up
things like hacker convention talks and
all bunch of other things are but arm
the series two trumpets something
yeah is um the fact that I have
something called the molarity how many
people here know what the molarity is
good lineman ok so here's what the
angularity is haha other people there
who is aware of what emulators are
alright alright so the emulators are
basically the ability to play older
computing experiences in other computing
experiences we can you know get really
tooty-fruity with the description but
basically comes down to make old things
run now through whatever means necessary
Malcolm X of programming so the molarity
at the archive is this framework where
we have taken emulation and put it into
the browser and we have ported it so
that emulations run within the browser
because when Brewster first hired me he
said we do movies we have music we have
books and you can browse the web we have
only software lying around and it's all
dead anyway to make it play and he came
up with a couple ideas and I said let's
do it the hardest possible way
um so if you go to the archive right now
and click on software and you click on
that button that Apple to will boot up
in your browser and play castle
wolfenstein and there are 10,000 Apple
programs there are like 19,000 spectrum
programs uh the their consoles it was
atari 2600 5200 this there's a you know
weird machines like the adventure vision
things you've never heard of it and it's
it's the fact that this is why i worked
with people on this was that we wanted
to turn you know like like with you say
your friend um do listen to this one
recording of this band
listen to this one Rolling Stones take I
mean it's obvious the base basis trunk
and if you tell him giving the link to
the mp3 any plays at his first reactions
and holy crap music is coming across my
computer
how did you do that it's in stereo holy
crap because we're just used to the fact
that now music and movies are an
instantaneous experience and that's what
we have now with the molarity it's i'm
able to go to like the phone store cuz i
was bored and booted doom up on phones
at the sprint store
why not and I'm able to put a Jaguar at
best buy which is gonna ruin the sales
of this machine or a museum in new
zealand connects to the internet archive
through the molarity and put up an
arcade machine that lets them play
arcade games locally arm or you can play
Doom in a browser inside of a link New
York City kiosk
there's doom everywhere now so um I
wanted to make it that now computing is
everywhere
it's everything it's easy to get to and
it's everlasting the molarity is very
network aware so it doesn't matter it's
not going away now you can't get rid of
emulation now it's it's in the web now
and one of our software packages had 1.5
million plays 1.5 million which one is
it of course the oregon trail and here's
the important thing about the Oregon
Trail is that because it's up there and
it's played by the way once every eight
seconds on the internet archive 24-7 arm
and I was trying to figure out like some
of the places where it was it turns out
in schools so what you're seeing if you
look there this is a school that made it
part of their curriculum to come to the
internet archive and make all the kids
play oregon trail because they all want
to play it so they use that they told me
they used to have one copy and one kid
would play it and all the other kids
would have to surround them and yell at
them what to do next
now each kid gets to play the organ
trail on their own and died of dysentery
instantly that's the molarity very proud
of it the angularity is actually a
JavaScript port of both name and dosbox
so that it's gonna be able to do other
JavaScript emulators too but let's talk
about Maine for a second which is just
amazing
one of the things that I find is that
people go to the either go to the
angularity and play a game and they're
done or when you start to describe it to
them with what's really behind it they
don't quite get it and this is a call
out the people who are watching who may
not have known this existed on its at
main like name in the last couple years
has really changed the multi arcade
machine emulator which is now got a
different background and let's call it
that emulates um you know thousands of
computing platforms and tens of
thousands of arcade games and it just
ports to JavaScript now because the work
of many many many people and they open
sourced it to a GPL license in this last
year it took them eight months of work
to track down everybody some of whom
were dead to figure out the ownership so
it's a hundred percent GPL so it's blown
up on to get hub now and so you can fix
stuff in there today and were able to
have the internet archive reflect your
improvements within 20
four hours so if you see something in
there you see something say something
and so if you want to change let's go
ahead and I want to be clear you know I
this is just my idea and I worked with a
lot of amazing billion people i'm not in
the code I'm not people sometimes go and
jason scott porter Jason Scott did
nothing
Jason Scott make stuff happen like this
like Ronald McDonald cooks burgers okay
let's just be clear about that
I'm the clown but i'm just not the cook
alright so for instance they have this
thing for a very obscure Swift card for
the Apple too and you can see all of the
people who worked on it and they go so
far as to include an ascii graph in the
in the comments to talk about which
chips did what I mean these people are
working hard to get that history and
then lots of to do's and please people
and then here are some of the programs
that are out there right
it's all these amazing weird old
programs that before you wouldn't go and
look now you're like what the hell is
that and you click on it and 10 seconds
later you're looking at it right that's
what we want to do i want to turn all of
computing history into an instantaneous
browsing embeddable experience and so
then you're like well okay so all the
problems like you're like wow you played
all those games took screenshots fuck no
fuck no because once it's in the browser
when I just have a machine do it so i
have this machine called the screens got
shotgun into set of scripts that go in
boots up a headless firefox takes lots
of shots gets rid of the duplicates
chooses the most complicated one as the
interesting one and makes it the
screenshot so there's piles of these
things and I've never played them and so
there's a machine you can be well
assured there's a machine out there
playing right now playing video games
all day sadly by the tens of thousands
unsure what's going on and hitting
random keys to see what's going on
poor thing plus they're animated gifs in
the screenshots of like here's a boot up
program and it just happens to boot up
and mr. crack man we love you
he's a name you can trust when it boots
up it actually literally goes through
and like looks for what's going on in
the program boot it up so it's kind of
neat it's actually almost got Luca kind
of feel to it and there's all sorts of
crazy stuff in there for instance here's
a benchmark program that uses 3d
programming so i mean like i love this
one and i love this one to this one
actually looks at the chips of the
emulated machine and tells you how it's
working
and I've always said that it's very very
very much like the matrix with the
architect where the program's boots up
and the architect is there and says your
first question while the most pertinent
well the most well the most obvious is
the least pertinent its counterparts the
floppy drive doing and it's like you
have no idea where you really are you
now you're inside you're inside of a
machine that's inside of another machine
that is running forever in a in a
network of billions of machines and it's
been 30 years anyway so yeah tons and
tons and tons and tons and tons and tons
and tons our baby for you
pregnancy shareware what more must I say
I'm you know this one right here here's
an example of a weird program and you
notice how he's coated in shadows arm at
a time before this would have been done
this is a boot that boots up to tell you
what can't be booted anyway so we know
we we initially did it with like um you
know pc machines and everything else and
I knew one day you're gonna have to put
in arcade machines so we put an arcade
machines are we put in 1,000 arcade
machines from 1976 to about nineteen
nineties out and put them up and then
waited i think i tweeted one thing about
it like this happened and then I waited
so that leads to the verge reporting
about it that leads to TechCrunch
reporting about it that leads to
lifehacker that leads to forbes that
leads to it being a question on
@midnight with chris and it leads to Fox
talking about how to play it and land
and megan on the right there you can see
what the internet archive servers did
that shit hurts and so like what would
cause that will cause that was the
answer was um yeah it turned out like
when i did it and i was testing a 256
meg footprint and if you run pink want
it makes it look the same but it reduces
because you see all those those cute
little images of all the Marquis I
didn't compress them well
so anyway once we fix that it was great
we actually did really well we had three
million new users in one week so it
turns out people like video games and
then it's so now there's 600 video games
so just to be clear about that but for
what for what for like you know like
1,000,000,000 month danke danke Gott was
free for everybody and I have to define
a little have to find a certain lawyers
attitude when he came as like what did
you think what did you anyway so that
was pretty good
so yeah like a shout-out to the
emulators because I want to make it
clear on this is regulation work and
what I wanted to do was that we have the
script in which ports c++ to JavaScript
and so the emulation team of Maine they
are the real heroes here on the same
thing with the volunteers who came and
helped with the porting of the code all
right and and and also to the OCR OCD
nerds who work on all of this to make
sure it's just right and it looks just
good and everything else and of course
the original creators of the game only
some of whom have been angry and many
many more have been really happy because
there's nothing like finding out of
thing you wrote you know 30 years ago
was suddenly up again and you can play
it and show people what you did
instantly and of course to my boss
brewster kahle and when I always try to
explain like why I really like working
for Brewster is this how many people
here know about practicing
ok so in jurassic world is apart when
Christopher Pratt playing the really
cool and dashing zookeeper arm holds off
three dangerous velociraptors arm in
this amazing scene where he's like doing
this and zookeepers thought this was the
shit so they started to do it with all
of their animals too
and so you just started to have all the
zookeepers doing this everywhere and it
was just whatever made it happy now I
came running down when this hit the
Boosters office I said Bruce trying to
do something i really can't explain any
of it and he was like okay I said go do
this go to this go through this is like
okay this is big with the kids i'm like
yeah he was like okay so and the reason
that this is really makes me excited
right the reason that this just
wonderfully makes me excited effective
Brewster trusted me he's like okay
alright you think this is important
you go ahead and I was like I want to
make browsers be the source so we can
have infinite simultaneous uses of the
emulator human ok ok do it all right
we'll see what happens and what happens
is the molarity arm so one of the things
he's like what you want to do now and
I'm like I want to close the air-gap
this is kind of irrelevant to the stuff
you're doing like you guys are
generating a lot of both physical and
digital data and the digital day there's
a little bit easier to deal with you put
the digital data somewhere hopefully not
somewhere stupid like Dropbox and hope
that it's gonna last forever or put it
on tumblr and not make it back up please
make backups of your own stuff just a
little bit of a USB stick throw your
shit on it put the USB stick away will
find it when you're 50 and but that's
the thing you know you gotta quit so but
the problem is that there's all this
other technology that even though its
digital in formats that are hard to get
to and they represent real and actual
culture and I think that's what you know
something very important to get across
to people is you know it's the culture
that we really care about
that's locked away on these floppies so
I have been really focused on that this
is a box of floppy disks and capable
we're capable of pulling the data off
those floppies into disk images which
can then be loaded into the molarity and
boot it up and this particular one came
from the corpus christi Apple users
group so you know we are all up on the
archive that's fine
and when I grabbed them they get
synchronized and turned into that
directory in the back and I'm doing it
with cd-rom is currently the archive has
over 7,000 iso's of cd-roms all
everything from commercial to share
where to everything else
lots and lots and lots of cd-roms and I
have thousands more that I'm going
through and I've got people sending me
floppy disks
and of all sorts of shapes and sizes and
we're closing down and trying to get all
these things in digital form without
assessing them because robots the same
thing that the screen shot guns going to
have other friends who are going to work
with it to analyze these
machine-generated programs so I'm not
too worried and so people see this
they're like oh what a cute milk crate
I'm like this is where i started my
software and I'm like it's not a milk
raid I got seven of these and these are
everything from shareware cd-roms that
have been sent to me to educational
software just so you know a little
software nerd ism games are easy to find
educational not-so-easy productivity
harder still
and then system is the hardest of all
and then custom is not is so out I don't
even count anymore because it's almost
impossible to find custom that's like a
once in a year yet a thing of like a
full customized setup but like the
software that drives are our elevators
the software that drives our hvac
systems the software that's used to like
drive a certain kind of hat knitting
machine that's updated by one company
that's really hard stuff to get so I'm
trying to get all of it but people
always like wow so all you're doing is
you're saving Mary oh my fuck marry Oh
Mary was fine when the earth is like
nothing but a smoldering heap of ashes
going to be one of city and Mariano head
floating for the further for the evolved
aliens to come down and find it will be
like wow that was there god this is my
inbox
and this is what happens when the inbox
gets turned into and I'm just pulling
them and I'm not even looking at them
like okay what to say on a boom-boom
side one side one this is going on this
is all going on very very very nicely
um I put up a bunch of cd-roms and this
is me really sick and really poorly
dressed at work putting in cd-roms if
there's anyone here remember walnut
creek
yeah so here's what happened
um I put out an article called yes I
want your goddamn AOL cds and i said i
want all lcds these are all lcds they
all have variations and i love that
people like why I'm like because they
were fifty percent of all cds produced
many years they were and there were
variations upon variations upon
variations there were ones that had
wrappings packings customized brand
label ones they have cases where they've
modified that you know one of them will
say uh for you know 40 hours included
and then they'll be a second one that
says 30 hours included 10 hours bonus
like there's all sorts of weird a/b
testing and things and they all have
unique serial numbers for the different
variations so I was doing that and what
you are seeing here was the head of
walnut creek emailed me and said also
you're doing that d1 all our ship was
like yes
so this is the walnut creek back
catalogue which is now on archive.org
and it was just a case of you had in
this garage and when i'm loading it out
i drove down to his house
loading it obviously i told my wife
there be a place that wanted
so I guess that you know like this is
absolutely one of those cases i really
like it because it really illustrates
that even though we look at this is the
truest the unpleasant aspect nes people
may look I destroyed my Michael thanks
for the info arm
the fact is that this represents a whole
mass of information and culture that we
will then be able to read from and find
those unique versions and unique
historical things browser versions
there's special rapids I've had people
who like historians need to find a
specific version of quicktime cd-rom
will provide it
you know things like that as we move
forward with this again I think software
is going to be as important as books and
movies are to a previous generation then
there's this thing I've been working on
some people know about this is a coffee
shop in Maryland we used to be anyway
that I'm renting & inside of it is boxes
and boxes and boxes and they are all of
manuals
so here's what happened I got a call
from place because now like I said I'm
the Angel of Death and I come calling it
was explained to me that a company
called manuals plus was going out of
business they had one of the largest
collections of manuals for sale in the
world and I said okay well how big is
that turns out it's like unbelievably
big it's super big it is this big when i
came to it so arm those doubles of
course but they said to me I i drove
down because I knew he'd only take me
seriously if I drove down and I said
awesome you know it was a Friday and I'm
like so when you throw these out he's
like wednesday like oh so i put the call
out and people donated money a lot of
money and came and to you know we could
argue about what the value is but to me
this is one-of-a-kind data going back 50
years about the operation of testing
equipment that's what these all are
testing equipment manuals and there's
tons and tons and tons of them unique
and interesting that I think should be
scanned so volunteers came and we tried
to pull one unique of each one because
they had multiple copies because they
were for sale
people came around they did their best
they weren't perfect
they did their best and they started to
assemble them into boxes and put them
aside and there were people assembling
boxes we bought four thousand dollars
worth of boxes this turns out to be
wrong
don't do that there's a packing box
called Gaylord and it's like the size of
a children's play pen but imagine you're
crushing the child with with manuals and
so that should have been what we did we
didn't know that we did with boot good
so as a result we ended up with 1600
bankers boxes of unique manuals a lot of
them these are all sitting in a coffee
house in Maryland right now and that's
what it looks like by that wednesday so
they are not I wasn't allowed to take a
picture of the dumpster so anyway arm
the fact is we weren't there i think
these things have value and it was
debate about like amateurs doing it but
I'm like better amateurs that nobody
better that than this so that's what we
did that
alright so um you know here's the thing
how we doing on time what time is it
wonderful i have time to this poor
surprise perfectly
excellent alright so let me complete
what I'm saying here by saying that arm
so the work that I when I joined the
archive and this year is my fifth year
anniversary with the archive and a big
thanks to mr. kale for hiring me and a
special thank you to the person who
immediately wrote him upon the
announcement to say you should not hire
this guy which I found out to my to
their credit for months later I was like
yeah I'm really surprised people didn't
complain because of my reputation and
they want people complained they said
hiring you was the worst mistake and
stepdad was gonna drive you down the
drain arm but myself and my group of
friends and associates and volunteers
are now uploading something on the order
of four or five
let's go about actually it's more along
the lines of like between one half and
two terabytes of data a day into the
archive that means websites pdfs drag
software music pieces i put up seven
thousand hip hop mixtapes arm i put up
arm i worked with a guy who had been
recalled who had been quietly taking
away the kmart repeatable cassette tapes
that they play during the speaker
announcements and they're all up on the
archive
are you know we've got everything from
Russian soldier of fortune manual
manuals and books to model-making to
magic to music and everything else right
and and we're just building up this
massive pile of culture and the thing is
is I haven't can become completely
agnostic if it's well-formed I no longer
and never really did but don't play the
form of gatekeeper and what I'm saying
out to you in this first of two requests
is pleased you generate unique things
and you're in a place so i have three
words for you that are critical in those
three words are steal from work take
from work things that work considers
uninteresting or is no longer relevant
because the project is over take things
that work had got rid of take things
that were headed for the dumpster but
now they're gonna head into a box that
you see land throw into your attic maybe
with a note
we'd appreciate a note like that it
doesn't say I am hoarding but something
that says something along the lines of
like finished project you know for 2014
4 2016 because history has shown that's
where the stuff gets saved all of the
stuff we have about Atari is because
Atari sold at auction a to filing
cabinets full of all of the prototype
artwork for all of their video games and
it was sold to the guy as to file
cabinets and when he picked them up they
said we have a dumpster over there if
you want to empty the file cabinets and
he said fine with not doing that
and Mark Teixeira who created marble
madness which is a video game gave a
talk at on the game developers
conference where he showed the stuff and
by the way I didn't have any of this
it was this guy with these file cabinets
he had all of my original art all of my
original notes i had to give it back to
the places work product steal from work
now I i love the whole conference I love
coming here this is a very real
conference to me this is a conference
that feels like it talks about things
that are not just the newest info SEC
knowledge that is not just about how are
we going to turn this lovely community
into a juice machine that can squeeze
out Bitcoin right it's got this cold
sense of it
I mean you've got people who are on
their own track but this narrative that
I've never liked that the natural
progression is curiosity hacker infosec
engineer drives me insane
there are other patterns there are other
pieces so um but one of the things
that's reflective that in the hope
conference is that not all the talks are
meant to sell you on something and our
other talks are meant to like fully
change your mind but to give you a
glimpse into perhaps another damage mind
you know I i always want to say because
that's a very very special thing and
it's held once every two years like some
sort of bizarre ritual
I mean these rituals that is yearly
ritual then there's those two year
rituals those are pretty weird right
like once in a while we get a storm that
just wrecks the lighthouse and so um so
in that way i just want to say um I have
a different talk which was not announced
and I'm going to do it very quickly and
i'll put a thing and it's very important
to me because this is where real
information comes to real people and
it's about not now and then here in
there it's about suicide and the
creative mind
alright so are we living right now world
of startup culture and startup culture
it's what matters is we all get together
and things look great and we put things
together we all drink coffee and at the
end we all become rich or we end up
somewhere else and all the way along we
bitch about it already
and in this world everything is going
fine everything is going absolutely fine
we are in a wonderful world and things
are cool and only get cooler and one of
these days we're gonna hit a big rich go
down so you're gonna take an oj s going
to attach it to a stack you're gonna
lamp your apache you're going to apache
your uber and then your uber is going to
tumblr into your yahoo and so you are
gonna be rich
ok and in a world where are the Dollar
Shave Club is sold for a billion dollars
on it's a real world right and so that
narrative really really really really
hits the people and in that narrative
you as a young person and this is mostly
young people is one of come here and
your talents which you have held inside
if we use them will bring you a
happiness and power you will not believe
and so come to our little farm and work
in our little place this is a dating
site i love that this is the other side
of a dating site
what do you do helping people fuck
coffee coffee coffee cup now they're
fucking that one won't get fucked
but then what happens is that the story
always ends because startups are parties
and parties come to a close right and so
that was one thing that is displayed is
that communities get shut down place
gets shut down and and this is actually
why I found something called archive
team archive t dot org and that is an
activist preservationist group we go out
and we save your shit that's what we do
we just got to go in all the time we're
constantly grabbing things constantly
grabbing news tweets everything that
represents stuff that is supposedly
transient and doomed because people are
told is gonna last forever but then it's
going to shut down so many of these
things get shut down like i love this
one right here on the left that says
it's gonna be great and then on the
right it says after more than three
years of great conversations
our team has decided to shut down branch
com we want to let you download the full
texts so you gotta sign in with twitter
thanks thanks
and there's a line that's always used
that's called are incredible journey
which is thank you for being a part of
our incredible journey and yeah and then
they find your body under the porch and
so all of these oyster launched two
years ago with a simple idea to build a
better way and then the rest of this we
put on the thing I i'll translate a
quick fuck you
body so arm so this Kickstarter's right
and so um kickstarters are kind of like
that writ large and in fact in some ways
are you know they took the world by
storm
I have an idea people give me money for
the idea my idea is amazing and then I
go down and become famous for the thing
i finished everybody help me all the pot
hey thanks for finding the pots out
thank you
well dot-coms be and I had a kickstarter
in the first month or two of kickstarter
and it was the jason scott sabbatical
here's the pitch give me a lot of money
and i will spend all of that money to go
back and look that's exactly what it
basically says and the theory behind it
was I just got laid off from a job as a
unix admin you imagine the terror i was
in the office and I don't want to go
become one
I love doing this history stuff on the
side if you guys give me enough money to
survive for a few months on it i promise
i will redirect my life 100-percent
towards history and they gave me 25
thousand dollars and i did i redirected
my entire life towards history it's all
I do my waking hours is work on saving
things so all those people they were
pretty happy Kickstarter does not allow
this anymore
give me a lot of money and i will spend
a lot of money is not around that's what
GoFundMe is for anyway so I done the
Kickstarter thing i've done it still got
a Kickstarter out there floating and so
anyway so i was involved in that and of
course as you know i was involved in
lots of hacker cons and everything else
and people don't like this weird little
narrative like give me a lot of money
because they're like what are you doing
in them and you just deal with it right
and that's fine little world will always
have its lair of people who are just you
know it's a little too sad and don't
want to do a thing I had a buddy named
skyler town
Skyler town and I kind of knew each
other soda defcon look at me I look
awesome but I'm with him and I just
announced him because he was amazing i
called him six-second Skylar because
this guy could pick a lock in six
seconds amazing and he was a little
darling and so he loved locks loves
Lovelock's Lovelock's I mean just love
these fuckin thanks
and so he really got into like studying
them he's going to block history is
going to get involved in everything and
this is a beautiful smiling face of a
guy who knows what he's up to
loves it he wants to gain his whole life
around the study and understanding of
what brought locks together and he has
given he gives heart-rending descent
right what a smiling beautiful face so
he decided I'm gonna build my own lock
picks because i use them in competition
so let's put together this lockpick then
and it was unbelievably popular it
actually was the second-most funded
Kickstarter at the time behind this es
para like it got $80,000 he had wanted
for anyway so here's the smiling face of
a person who has been told that the
world is his oyster and he's going to
work on it and it's wonderful arm and
then he didn't make them any kind of
fell out of awareness and he wasn't
there and he had been like updating and
integrate everything else going on and
this is where he says that i was
committed basically against my will
because I was really really really in
that bad shape trying to figure out what
to do now the thing is that Kickstarter
hadn't worked for him because it turned
out that four thousand dollars was
losing money and so he just was losing
more money the more people at
to the Kickstarter but there was no way
to shut it off and he can see all the
smiles of startup culture so he just let
it grow until it became impossible and
so then he sent pictures of his room and
this was the room that he wasn't leaving
for months at a time behind that smiling
face right and somehow i heard about
this now I hadn't back to care about
lockpicks you grab knock yourself out
knock yourself out it's locked it's not
locked boom ya go
confetti but the thing is that what I
did see and I'd seen this pattern before
was I was like this guy is gonna die
he's gonna die he's going to look at all
this and he's going to say oh my god I
can't do this i'm never gonna make these
people happy and they were brutal to him
brutal he take a picture of progress and
they tell him the price of the camera
that we used to take it that's how
bitter and angry was so this beautiful
smiling thing was destroying somebody
and I said okay I'd like to come in and
help and I said we're gonna do our best
to try to deal with this in whatever way
we can we came in
it turned out he had bought the rewards
but he hadn't finished lock picks but he
had piles of rewards he had bought for
thousands of dollars they were sitting
in his basement because you don't want
to make it all perfect and he didn't
know what he was doing he was drowning
and everything else and that's when I
saw this you know what I saw was this
what these are this is the saddest slide
i have ever done in 15 years of doing it
these are the last week's of people for
they killed themselves each one of these
is a person who tweeted that and then
died because the world got to them and
they were committed now some people you
can't save some people are on a path you
can't see it but a lot of these people
were people who were just trapped in a
story a narrative that is purchased by
our world that says if you're not happy
if you look like you're sad nobody wants
you get away from us and it's poisonous
and it's toxic that's killing us and
there's young people in here who are
living that right now okay and I want
you to know it's not like that for you
this is what I felt from these people I
just wanted to hurt him to stop and the
reason i knew that was because that was
me too
right that was me at 12 miserable sad
hated when I was hated the people i was
was was with a parent I didn't want to
be with not getting the food i wanted
and not getting the life I wanted I was
visible so I said okay you know this is
me this is the same me three years later
right fucking awesome
look at that stolen payphone I tried to
get into the yearbook that test that i'm
holding up like it's a fucking trophy
right the highway blinking again not
purchased i was looking at this is
literally in evidence photo that i want
to submit as a yearbook photo and I love
cows and listen to howard stern and I
had I had all this shit going on and
look at this this is actually a local
calling area this is when I first
actually met a manual was about this
time was like this is a local calling
listing because of course costs more to
call here to there and you want to have
that right by your phone that you're
freaking fun to know what you're gonna
call in the stuff
this is a kid who has his whole world
and became me that's amazing
and then there's a part of that
particular love because it was taken by
my fiancé who I met in high school and
we went off 20 years separate and we're
together now so it's a very special
photo to be
so here's another bad idea
do not make a calcium internet service
provider turns out doesn't work not
wanted our there's a promo photo from it
dial-up I swear to God 18 16 17
countdown that was a number calcium
count on net we will provide an access
to you trust us come on
doesn't this a stability fuck quantum
link fucking well these guys
oh shit they're gonna own delphi exactly
and here's the thing
uh so within a year I was fifteen
thousand dollars in debt because middle
doesn't work use my blood is your as
your salve and and don't open a calcium
service provider you want the scary part
is there were three there was a calcium
service provider in fucking Connecticut
dude fucking bit me anyway arm so I was
fifteen thousand dollars in debt because
I couldn't afford the the you know i was
paying so much money for a 56k modem and
I could you know I met with this
connection you know the whole thing it
was it was eating me alive and I was
borrowing from friends and I wasn't
eating and I was a-going to friends
houses to eat and I was again drowning
and I could tell every single day became
pain for me because I woke up going i've
woken up and I am behind i don't have
the money
I don't know how to shut this down
people can be so disappointed in my case
you think this provider arm you know and
so I was drowning again at 25 and then I
got a job with the boss James Patrick
O'Malley I wanted to just tell you how
long ago this was i went to any dot jobs
and look for unix and dollar sign and
look for any unix job that had you know
a salary and um it was one that said you
know $50,000 something i said i'll try
that
so so paddle malli hired me not because
i was the best unix guy because he gave
me a homework assignment to read
something up on raid and all the other
guys just went well fuck this homework
assignment often got a job but I came
back and reported what I learned
and he said okay I'm gonna hire you but
here's the thing i hate it when we hire
somebody and they drown out after like a
month sucks and we gotta get this whole
like are we really firing you're letting
him fuck that what i'm going to do is
you're gonna be a consultant from me for
one month and we're gonna pay you
seventy-five dollars an hour and you're
gonna make bank to make bank and after
30 days
you suck you got some money go find
another job if you don't suck gonna make
less money per hour but now you got a
job so as a result they made about you
know seven or ten thousand dollars in
the first month and i went and paid back
everybody who I want money too so i went
from fifteen thousand dollars in debt to
within a couple months
zero dollars in debt I can't imagine
what my life would be like if I was like
33 and had this debt over my head for
years so I knew that was happening with
with kyla to don't you look again one
more time
don't do this for the love of god don't
do this so i took over with a coup other
people
Brian Martin Jason our intrigue agony
and we want we took it over and said ok
we are the board we are the Skyler
repair board and we're gonna do the best
we can so we went in we found his locks
and things he had taken the rewards he
was gonna send the people we found the
t-shirts crumpled up that were in his
basement we flatten them out we got the
practice locks that he had he had so
much stuff ready to go but because you
don't have the pics he was paralyzed
we took it over and at the hasty pastry
we assembled the packages we had to
borrow money
thousands and thousands of dollars of
postage and we had to make all the
things he had promised and put them in
there and a scholar wasn't required to
come we were like we're gonna get this
done we're going to do this and we had
to go through all the locks and sort
them out by number and everything else
and i actually went to flickr into the
search for sweatshop and left that on a
slide show above us so that's what's
going on there that's just running over
us the whole time is the sweatshop
photos but Skyler came by which was very
very nice of him i thought that was
pretty amazing
um he was sitting over watching us do
this and and i'm doing work and i'm
getting stuff and I'm like wait a minute
is it
this to this and I go over to Skyler and
his head's on this desk
I'm like hey dude what company he looks
up to me he's crying I'm like oh no
what's wrong and he goes what how do I
have friends still what he said to me
because he was just devastated at that
point the fact that people were reaching
out to help him just blew him away and
this is what hundreds and hundreds of
boxes sent out the people of course
people need to email back where the
fucking lock picks and that was my job
to take the brunt and go like well there
aren't any yet arm
we have many many many many boxes and
the post office fucking hated me i think
i'm on the wanted posters i think they
put me there
no we're closed anyway but you know
actually within a few months Skylar was
actually making lockpicks arm and he was
doing them by hand don't do this but he
was doing them and cutting them out and
he was assembling by hand this is
completely inefficient don't do this but
he was producing lockpicks of some sort
arm and then we packaged up the ones
that were there and sent them to the
height we know said ok if you gave a
thousand dollars towards this you get
this amount stuff and we're gonna send
you all the stuff we can and we're gonna
send the lockpick shiny also actual
lockpicks one out on the project was
absolutely impossible
I mean we're in the numbers it's
impossible the number it couldn't work
how couldn't work I mean this was like
one of the bonuses was a lock set and he
you only have to give like three two
hundred and fifty dollars to get this
locks it's worth six hundred dollars so
he made here to make five of them so he
did
they're really nice stupidest thing in
the world is losing money every time he
was one of these to the think we did we
got them to a whole group and he made
this little this is super inefficient he
made a little arc welder for himself
that would do the whirling and
everything else you know we did all this
crazy shit built on sand it the projects
now mostly just really incredibly hard
now he still owes like 20,000 lockpicks
arm
I don't know if he's ever going to
produce them I honestly don't people
look and what happened is that i ended
up at one point we've gotten to a point
where
it was like look we've given you all the
tools we've produced a business plan
it's not a great one we've produced a
business plan here's one here's what it
costs you here's all the numbers you
need to sort of make it work and we
can't do anything we can't oversee any
more like you have to do it here's the
numbers here's the metal and he may or
may not do it but we said okay we're
misleading people now being a report
pair bored because repair board is done
it put things back on a track a really
hard unpleasant track and scholar and I
haven't talked much in the last year and
a half since this happened but all I
know is is that Skylar is alive and so
this is the last picture when I last saw
him right so you know you could be sad
inside but he stuck around and people
like also why you again i have to say i
didn't know skander that well i didn't
know i don't care about lockpicks but I
just didn't want someone to die and so
let you know when you see somebody out
there and your like care about them and
you like something's wrong there smiling
too much understand please reach out to
them talk to them a little bit even if
they're putting it on be there be that
one little line that one little bit get
in there you know lockpicks were
produced things were done it became an
annoyance and an embarrassment but it
wasn't a crushing unattainable mountain
starting his every single waking day he
now works as a barista don't look like
if you want
um so
so yeah so I'm just saying I'm just
saying that's what that's a real thing
ok so I mean I i gave a smaller group
this this discussion and this is Chloe
will who passed on our own hand arm and
seems happy in the world and this is
ilya who was one of the architects of
diaspora the most funded kickstarter and
he killed himself a 22 and so you
probably got friends like this maybe on
that edge
all I want is for you to make that one
little step yeah it's great i'm saving a
lot of god damn computer history and
it's great that you can play castle
wolfenstein in a browser but if the real
payload of this little limp i was given
is to drop the idea of saving a life
that's what I really care about
I care about you out there I know you're
out there by the way this is for the
person who's watching this right now is
crying out on the string and we love you
we want to see what you do next
we care about you so I stick around a
little longer
thanks
I don't really want to answer any
questions but it's like you're literally
they're like oh Jesus right now go ahead
it's right there burning right now is
there one yep know what
yes male me cds I'm glad that's your
takeaway jason scott care of the
internet archive 300 funston avenue san
francisco california 9411 a please don't
send anything that bubbles burns are tix
arm a shoutout to the guy who did send
me a blank CD with the words written on
it
fuck you you useless idiot
yes of course I archived it stored in
the
have you learned nothing
anyway um ok so i'll be back at midnight
for the hackers got talent I'm the MC a
little bit of levity and I'm just happy
for everyone who stuck around for this
and thanks a lot again and enjoy hope