alright everyone thanks for the welcome
so let's get started
so this presentation is going to be
about Chinese mechanical locks obviously
so why do I call it an insight into a
hidden world of locks it's because the
lock market in China hasn't really been
on has always been kind of sequestered
in its little bubble so we really
haven't got an idea of what what unusual
kinds of locks they have so this is
presentations going to be talking about
a little of this stuff
ok so how general introduction
here's my disclaimer yes I'm not gonna
waste your time with uh an exceptionally
long as the scammers just that i didn't
get paid by any this company's cause i'm
going to be like bashing some companies
while promoting others so i didn't get
paid by any of them i'm not affiliated
with any of them this is strictly
personal research also armed
yeah I did my best to try to make
everything as factual as possible but
i'm i'm not a hundred percent sure with
something so this is my best guess
alright next Who am I
I am a small-time lock collector i call
myself small time because i only collect
one type of lock and that is Chinese
locks so yeah that's me
padlocks and euro cylinders which are
that's the main types of locks I calm
collect I'm a Chinese lock specialist
and researchers that's what i call
myself when I talk to other people you
know I'm Chinese lock specialist in
research that's who I am but uh yeah it
makes me sound more special than i
actually am photo okay yeah it makes it
real ok
nope i'm a member of tool on i actually
got in the membership application
yesterday so i could say that
yeah I thanks
yeah i'm certified now you know oh I am
a lock picker not a good one at that but
still locked figure i can pick a master
lock and that's about it so i can say
that too and I'm 16 years old so I've
been interested in Lock since I was 10
that's six years thank you so yes been
awhile and if you have any questions
just feel free to ask them while I'm
going through this so you don't leave
them to the end
alright some terminology this is for the
people that aren't really into locks so
I'm going to be referring to these quite
a lot some people call other stuff but
this is what I call them so a keyway is
where the key goes in
they usually have a shape to it that
only that kind of he'll fit in the law
and the plug is the round thing where
you put in the key it turns that's the
plug
I hope I got that clear all right parts
of a key on this is a Chinese key by the
way so i'm trying to use as many Chinese
loss as possible in my pictures
the bidding is the cuts on the key
sometimes it's engraved on the side is
like a squiggle and let me get this
laser pointer awarding is this track
that's milled in the key to get it to
fit in the keyway alright so that's that
and pins are two sets of pins that one
race the correct height allows like
start like that
sliders are elements that slide when
interacting the key instead of going up
and down and the sidebar is a rod or bar
that locks the plug until the element
has been aligned correctly which is yeah
that so finally answer gets too far into
the Chinese locks so let's have a small
Chinese lesson so I know
well it's fitting though so the first
word means lock so all the reason I'm
saying this is because if you wanted to
go and look up blocks on google if you
look up lock and changes you're not
going to get anything from China because
they use a completely different wording
system so if you go on google translate
will give you a bunch of options so this
is the ones that you should select the
first one swap is that
that one of the very top renounce war
oh gosh sorry that one is means it just
means lock so if you look at that you'll
get all types of locks the second is
cross which translated literally means
hanging block which is a padlock the
third one is sauce in which is a lock
cylinder literally means a Lockhart
which if you think about it is a lock
cylinder is literally the heart of the
lock and lastly we have Y sure which is
key
it means well yeah it doesn't mean
anything it just means key
alright next something many types of
keys some of the many types of you there
are many many different types of keys
these are the ones i'm going to be
talking about a lot so here we go there
are pictures of the keys some they're
not the best pictures but I think okay
so here's the terms that I used to call
them and some other people used to call
them this is the first one is called a
standard key i called the standard key i
don't know other people call it a
mycologist us something else is a
standard key because it if you look in
your key ring or whatever chances are
you have one of these on it's the most
standard be the cuts are on the side
like any other thing next one is
slightly more unusual the dimple key
this one has cuts down the front of it
like like that i'm sorry this laser
pointer I'm really shaking why so that
it's cut on the side instead of on the
like the top of the key
the third time is called the cruciform
key so this key is basically what
happens when you are take for standard
keys and put it across and that's where
you get the cruciform key the fifth type
of the fourth type of key is a distant
chatter key this one has angles come on
the side instead of cuts like that and
the last type is called a laser track he
which shop it's cut by a laser which is
called the laser track he and it's like
it looks really weird and funky which is
the why it's like cut kinda cut like
that i don't know how to better explain
yourself
all right next oh now if underneath is
what you'll see sometimes if you go on
aliexpress which is a website if you
want to buy lots from china but they're
not too great so this is the English
translation so when you literally
translated so the first one is they call
it a yell key in China the reason they
call it a yield he is if anyone can
guess
does anyone know are the inventor of the
law
a lot of people yes incl senior so
that's why they call Danielle key second
one is called a computer key they called
a computer key in Chinese is also called
computer key ganache which means
literally means computer key i have no
idea why they call it that
so I'm just gonna go pass on the third
one is called across key for obvious
reasons the fourth one is called a
finland key now distant a nurs were
invented in finland by abloy there's
some security stopped selling avoid
products downstairs so are you a few i
asked about the history of a boy
probably know but uh if anything the
distant interlock was invented in
Finland so that's why they call in China
finland key and last one they call it a
blade leaf tea I still I don't know why
they call it that photo
Oh a blade or a leaf key us feel free to
interject if I late
yeah well yeah well if you come as well
and when you go to China stuff
yeah I'll pin tumbler kiai that too ok
thanks
next the word about Chinese lock company
name so they're usually unusual sounding
so they'll be kind of funny sounding
when you are
read it out there the word out version
of their Chinese names so i will try to
say the english and chinese name in the
proper translation of the chinese name
so you get a sense of what the law
company is and the word about packaging
packaging is very important china since
there are hundreds of hundreds of
different lock manufacturers in China
packaging is how they present the lock
to the buyer so it's pretty important to
see how they market their lock to the
buyer and we'll see a lot of weird
things that they do to try to market the
lock and we'll talk about that in a
couple other slides and I think it's
capitalism at its finest it shows
exactly how capitalism is supposed to
work except just in the last market and
a word about he controls is a big thing
in America but not so in China key
control is preventing someone from to
play d duplicating a key without
permission so usually institutions use
this to prevent you from copying their
dorm here whatever this is not a problem
in China because there are hundreds of
variations of the same type of key way
so if you take the Yale keyway there are
hundreds of variations of that key way
so a locksmith will not have basically a
locksmith will have one or two types of
planks the rest of them
you're not gonna be able to copy this is
why when you buy locks in China you're
going to get six or seven keys with the
lock because they know that you can try
to duplicate it but you're not going to
be able to so that's Chinese control it
works alright characteristics of
security in China
Matt along with the control master King
and institutions is also very very very
very very very rare arm because i'll
talk about that how does an institution
keep track of keys then I'll take a look
with one of those things it's not fun
so you can see from the girls pain smile
that she's probably have to open someone
door with that
so basically what it is is that all the
locks have their own individual key and
they're not master key master King is 11
lot when he will open a bunch of blocks
but know in China they just have one key
opens one lock and that's it so they'll
hang a bunch of different keys along the
side of that and they'll go and
sometimes they're not labeled I've had
to use one of them before and it took
about 15 minutes to try all the keys in
the law so it's not well the reason is
because most locks in China are like
sealed shot there either ping together
or like welded together there's no way
to get them apart and there are just so
many different variations of lots in
China they're like thousands of
different models of lock that it's
impossible for a locksmith to stock any
kind of pins or wafers to master key
lock so a locksmith is not basically all
the locksmiths dozen china is not master
keying or key lock is basically to get
you in your house when you know or or
install a new lock one there were two
need arises that's basically what a lot
with us
alright next so now let's talk about the
a/b the ABC or the 1+1 King system so
all nearly all of the entrance door
locks that you buy in China are come
with two sets of keys or three sets of
keys defends so the a key is always
given to the contractor the lock
installer and the B key is usually
always sealed its always seal basically
usually see what I say because there
might be one or two that's not seal and
that package is given to the owner of
the house so although contractors
building the house the owner can also
still get into the house the C key is
used to lock out the achy after they're
done building the house if you
understand what I'm
it is construction King it is
construction key where you lock out the
so basically what happens is that when
you come in with your new key the a key
stops working so the key that control
the contractor the locking star has will
know the guy will no longer be able to
get into your house and that's pretty
good
and we'll see a lot of that with the
locks that we talked about ok the
uniform national lok grading scale a
uniform is in quotes because it's not
uniform but they like to make it seem
that way
oh ok let's talk about it so there are
three official grades that are
sanctioned by the Public Security Bureau
which is kinda like the FBI which is
kind of a weird thing because you know
you never feel the FBI and the US
talking about how terrible kwikset is
photon well in China you got people like
like the public bureau literally comes
out and says that this lock is terrible
this lock is terrible don't use this
lock this lock is also terrible this
one's not that terrible you still you
shouldn't use this lot kind of thing so
the official grades are a B and C as you
go down its better so when you have so a
is the worst it has one minute of
manipulation resistance and our regular
pin tumbler locks were the simple dimple
blocks which rhymes and like that B is a
slightly better you get five minutes of
tape resistance or bump resistance or
whatever it is and it's all 10 you get
pin tumbler locks in a slider or simple
sidebar based lock for that and child be
or B plus is the best official standard
you can get so this is the one that if
you're searching for locks on the
internet you're going to want to put
this standard and if you want the good
locks its kind of weird because
manipulation resistance requirement
basically jumps to 270 minutes which is
then basically saying that all the locks
that are like basically impossible to
pick in this time should go on that they
send you get complex slider systems
proprietary systems all the weird stuff
goes in that category and then the
non-official stuff so if you ever see
this
don't buy the lock because it means it
hasn't certified a lot of people a lot
of different companies use that
so we got a C+ which has no standard
that d which also has no standards and
the d+ which has no standards as well
but we'll see on some of the packaging
that we talk about later we'll see those
designations on some of them
okay what kind of reputation do chinese
locks have over here
yes
decided
well it's because that were originally
they only had two grades A and B and
then they added a b-plus and they might
assy so they basically they don't want
to start from backwards
otherwise they'll like have to do
something like negative 8 negative
fearless differentiate the different
types of this craft so what kind of
reputation new Chinese box have over
here i forgot to bring that padlock so
awful if you want to know what it was it
was a cheap Chinese lock with a plastic
or and you could bang it open well if
you stare at it hard enough it'll open
to so yeah so that's a summation of the
reputation so does anyone want to say
what they think of Chinese locks before
presentation
oh ya lousy that's true everyone thinks
their allows them again
yeah they have someone's are going to
talk about that later so what can we say
so far most of the locks that come out
of China are not good i agree with this
statement most of the locks that you're
going to find in a dollar store or in
the home depot or wherever that come out
of China are not good
it's the locks that state in China that
were actually going to talk about which
this is the good stuff interesting stuff
and I just spent 15 minutes by talking
about all the stuff so let's go on
insecure Chinese locks why are they
insecure because we have low-cost
production basically what they do is
they try to make the lock as cheaply as
humanly possible like it cannot be more
cheap than whatever the Chinese have man
you manage to think up of our casting vs
million they'll cast the cylinder if
possible they'll mail out parts of the
cylinder to try to save on some brass
not hardened parts like a lot of the
locks that happened here actually i
don't know if i can get the document
camera working
it doesn't matter it says hardened on
the shackle this silver thing over here
but it isn't because it's easier to
stamp pardon on the shackled and it is
to actually heart in it
alright and then we got inferior
materials make brass which is basically
pop metal and they spray paint yellow
paint on it so it looks like grass
I mean if you go to dog so you'll find
some of them and it's just I don't know
who they're trying to fool because you
can only if you have two brain cells
maybe you think that it's real grass but
it's not pot metal which is zinc it's
really cheap and you can melt the lock
if you have a butane torch or something
like that and plastic which is needless
to say should not belong in any kind of
lock and then we have simple machinery
low-cost going so high quality like
medico in the US they'll use CNC Mills
to try to mail out the lock cylinder so
it fits perfectly in China they usually
have maybe a grinder in the factory and
they'll grind out something that looks
generally like a padlock but isn't so
that also we've got clones of clones
which is basically someone factory comes
up with a new design or maybe they stole
it from somewhere over around the world
and another factor will see that lock
and try to make an exact copy of it but
as you know like copying files if you
copy the same file over and over again
to get corrupted so it's the same thing
with this so each time they take that
design they're gonna try and make a
cheaper and some other company is also
going to try to take the previous design
and make that one cheaper and so in the
end we get the locks that we'd that end
up in our dollar store and stuff like
that and tolerance problems which is
basically are all needless to say all
these equal the tolerance problems which
it makes the locks really loose or not
work at all which happens a lot
ok now we're going to discuss the types
of high security Chinese locks so we've
got i like to say through there are
three types we got the security through
obscurity which is i'm pretty sure the
hacking world they use this term so
basically you can't pick what you can't
see can't pick what you can't don't
understand so basically these locks are
gonna look really weird and stuff and
you're not going to know how to attack
it because
well it looks weird we got security
through complexity which is safety in
numbers design you know have more of
this and more of that and more of
everything it's better than having less
and then the last one which i really
like this is the one that I prefer to
the kind of lock that most of the locks
I want to talk about our security
through design where they are designed
to be secure they they take advantage of
their weaknesses which is tolerance
problems and they make it secure so most
secure designs are eclectic which means
they utilize two or more of these
categories that one
ok that's ok now is the good part after
all this we would get to talk about
actual lock design so yeah no no that
boring stuff anymore
our security through obscurity some
obscure lock designs so first we have
the smiley face keyway design this ends
up in the u.s. sometimes that will see
maybe in some chinatown dollar shop or
ill you'll get it from aliexpress or
something like that a smiley face keyway
an evil q it but the reason I say it's
obscure is because these two are both
smiley face key ways however one is
better than the other can you guess
which one is better than the other
yes the left one but two the average Joe
would you be able to tell at a second
glance which one is better
oh come on ok no yes that is true no
that's that's the answer
alright yeah but the one on the right is
fancier you have to admit I mean I find
if I was just an average person I would
go for the fancy lock right the one on
the right does say top-security our top
comes in on the very top where it below
a you know
ok yeah so yeah so basically this design
is cloning of that design basically what
i call security through obscurity is
they're trying to hide it so we have the
really good design which is basically
it's really hard to pick on the Gold
atom design if you don't know about you
should look it up it's really hard to
pick our that one is really easy to pick
but basically what they tried to do is
make it look as close to that as
possible so we could hide in like kind
of hide behind the shadow of that one
ok so the next one ok that's a blank
slide oops
you saw it oh gosh the con power grid
padlock is a very simple-looking padlock
this one all right where's my laser
pointer so we see it's a brass padlock
these are used on that by the Chinese
power grids to secure their boxes and it
comes with this very simple-looking key
it's just a barrel with a little bit on
it and when i first got this lock
I was like and here's the key holders a
little shudder in there that opens when
you put the key and when i first got
this lock
I thought well this would be super easy
to pick you know I could just take
anything like a stick or something and
stick it in there and work but I tried
for hours and hours of doing this and in
the end I was so frustrated and I threw
the key and it stuck to a little metal
noticeboard in my arm in my bedroom and
I had to bang my head on the ground if
you like I should have known it couldn't
have just been like a little bit so in
fact arm if we can get the document
camera where
how do we use the document cameras
that's possible are never mind i guess
i'm okay how do I get this to show up on
the screen
that's what's important it's beats me
but it's probably the switchbox alright
i think it's going to explode if i play
with this is all right i'll just talk
about it from here
is there anyone from AV in this room
right now maybe I should have gotten
that to work early but anyway there's
series of magnets in the key that are
unlock the lock and I didn't know that
and you probably wouldn't know that just
by looking at the lock so yeah there's
that
ok so next is the next category because
there isn't really that many designs in
China that utilize security through
obscurity because as you know once it's
once it's out there once how the lock
works out there it's pretty easy to all
be able to pick it
oh there we go how do we switch back
though I'm just switching the guys on
one
okay just just ask someone switches
magically you don't focus focus
ok security through complexity some
complex lock design so basically i'll
just remind you is basically where they
try to fit as many moving parts into the
lock as possible to make it is hard to
pick or as hard to manipulate as
possible so let's take a look at them
ok some simple complex designs which is
simply basically what the lock
manufacturers trying to do is trying to
get it into the next grade without using
too much of an effort which is um a lot
of companies do that simply adding
another element to make it look more
secure this innocent-looking pin tumbler
cylinder which just looks like your
standard lock that you might have on
your house
however if we look at the key it says
otherwise
are you can see there's a little track
grew engraved on the side which also
actuates ten little sliders on the side
of the lock
it's not particularly secure but it adds
another layer this is
try they're trying to go for the
complexity angle over here and so what's
better than one row of pins two rows of
pins so what this company has gone ahead
and done and is made another rule pins
next to the row of pins so there's that
this is also an a/b lock i should say
that first this is an AP lock so the
pinky is the construction key and one
and there's also set a couple like six
black keys that i didn't I don't have
pictures of that when you put in the
lock it locks out the pinky I 100 i do
know i think what happens is this is
they're not really trying to copy the by
lock design i think is dust them trying
to add another opens because also is
similar in design is a two-row dimple
lock that also does the same thing and
one that has like kinda looks like this
Lake Primus but it really isn't on the
side so they're not really trying to
copy any of the designs besides so by
lock isn't that well known but I I can't
vouch for the manufacture maybe they got
ahold of the by lock and try to make it
look at somewhere as possible
yeah that is but this is way low quality
because it doesn't have the angle like
the kind of curve to it so this is
really cheap anyone would be able to
pick this with anything basically so if
you go downstairs to tool you probably
able to pick this comparing it to a
biopsy
yeah i was going to say that it's
ok maybe I just contradicted myself
whatever it's very very similar to the
by lock and I must admit maybe they were
trying to do something but the by
Lockheed is cut then folded into two and
this one the Chinese lock i think is as
is milled down the center which is quite
strange really
oh it's two different cuts it's like
kind of staggered so they can fit the
pins in if you want to see these locks
you can just come downstairs so i'll be
there and I can show these off the pan
wrong Locker design so this is a weird
name chinese name pan wrong i think it
means like a guard dog or something like
that
ok why didn't I I don't know why they
just don't use google translate button
ok so the pan wrong lock is a classic
example of security to complexity
we've got over here a set of sliders on
the back of the key we've got 10 pins on
the front of the key we've also got this
keyway blocker on the front of the key
to block the keyway until the key is
currently cut awfully and started which
should go through the key so yeah so
looks pretty unpickable but you'll
notice that this lock is used and why is
it used
well because my uncle's house got broken
into and this is the lock on their door
how did they get in if they can't access
the keyway because of the blocker well
they use some tin foil and put it on the
key and they put it in and open so this
just shows how this might look good and
they advertise how many elements it has
it isn't the best now in extreme example
of a complex like this is an extreme
example you're not going to get a lot of
this is super EXTREME it only has one
type of element but i'll talk about that
the soul aki slider lock this has known
its the chinese name is solution which
translates into lock god
but I think they're going a little too
far they're this lock key lock so it
looks pretty standard it's got a tracks
on it's got tracks on this side and it's
got different tracks on the other side
fits in this keyhole right here so can I
have the document camera please
yay ok so that's what the key looks like
like that so we've got tracks on this
side and when we turn it over
we've got tracks on the other side as
well so that it might look normal and
here's the cylinder and it works
perfectly i shouldn't i'm gonna put this
down for a second all right to put this
over here and just talk into this is not
gonna work i move this over here so it
works fine it's everything that a lot
should be it works which is a miracle
compare considering Chinese locked
manufacturing technology
ok so back to the slide please thanks
always lock he looks so what makes this
complex well how many sliders are in
this lock ? 12
how do you want to guess
alright these all seem to be pretty
conservative they're getting close there
are 48 sliders in this lock 48 of them
they've managed to cram 48 different
moving parts into this lock which is
amazing and it has 6 locking points they
have to see it has two sidebars and for
little points that lockout and keep the
plug in place so this is what it looks
like when you blow it apart we've got
sliders here there everywhere we've got
to sidebar as you can see in the red
over there we've got six locking points
right there like that and yeah that
we've got so many sliders and basically
what this says is at six locking points
over here it says it has to set aside
bars over here it says it's got
something anti-drilling over here it
says something about 48 sliders
well its bum proof it's fairly pick
resistant here's what is package that
comes in i'll talk about the pic
resistance later
this is the pattern so I was talking
about packaging this is what it comes in
it cuz it's called a blade lock cylinder
quite a bit but not too much I care
yes it's quite a bit by Chinese lock
centers but to us it's a pure bargains
to a cheaper you can buy like three of
these for the price of medico so anyway
so they call it a blade lock cylinder
you'll notice that they use the
designation child see here which is c
plus which as I mentioned earlier does
not exist so there's a little trickery
for the consumer right there how are you
doing on time all right okay halfway
through alright so it's all stainless
steel blade lock cylinder this is the
inside of the cover let's take a look at
the English which is always fun to read
the chinglish all stainless steel super
c class which as I may remind you does
not exist flat tumbler lock series the
latest patent products all stainless
steel to sidewalks 46 locking points
dual 12 x 2 flat tumblr man
so which is two x minus 2 which is 48
well I don't know why they just didn't
go ahead and say 48 moving parts that
would be much easier on and the rest of
it is it's actually cnc precision
machine supposedly which I kind of would
hope it is but I haven't taken apart
because if I to take it apart everything
is going to fly everywhere and it will
never have 40 pieces after i take it
apart
ok on to the next thing so this is the
little how it comes in it also comes
with a key duplication card but it does
nothing
as I've told you already because if you
have the key duplication card you can
say i have authorization to duplicate
this key but you're never going to get
this key duplicated because no locksmith
in all of China is going to hold this
plank the manufacture this is it's
really hard to most manufacturers in
trying to just make the lock and then
they get out of the business days
well and it's for obvious reasons
because yeah so you're never gonna get
blanks for this
yeah the machinery is the same you know
this is so they have the same machinery
so if you think about the machinery to
make wagons it's not very precise is it
so when you are use it to make clocks
it's not a very precise
yeah basically that's how we got the
crappy blocks but they're also some good
manufacturers like this is probably the
manufacturer I don't know if it's still
in existence i hope it is but it makes a
pretty good luck
ok so what do these all these sliders
make this lock its bum proof there no
pins the bump
well you can try pumping downstairs if
you want to know what that is it's very
difficult to pick so has anyone tried to
pick around 48 different way for
separately
no okay if anyone wants to try to pick
this lock it will be downstairs and if
you can pick the lock
I guess you can have it so so anyone
would like to pick this lock
alright alright whatever drill
resistance it's got 40 different sliders
and you need to drill out six points in
the cylinder and the cylinder stainless
steel so you're not gonna get very far
with that all right now onto the better
section security through design now I
like seeing this part on its
well-designed locked and or improvements
on current loc design so very good
improvement
all right the UM Allah company which i
like to call the a ploy of China because
they've been constantly updating their
product to be more and more unpickable
trying to make it as an i think with the
most recent update it's been basically
like the a ploy protec to which i'll
explain in just a minute so I call this
the the color you i'm sure that you've
heard of the UM Allah company at some
point some of you like that are really
into it so yeah it's the a ploy of China
the evolution of the uml a company we
first what happened was the smiley
keyway lock if we can have the document
camera please
I can get this lock
all right here we are on it's got this
little key way that looks like a smiley
face which is like all the smiley keyway
yes got years to it looks like the
little face you know
alright there's that and the key looks
like that so let me find the key is the
key looks like this that looks like that
so I back to the slide please
so yeah I'm gonna give the guy behind
the curtain a big workout now hitting
the switching the thing so the second
kind of the 750 they came out with his
slider system with one side bar yeah now
the sidebar for these locks are really
special their reverse side bars which
means offer those of you that don't
really understand locks just tune out
here because it's just more for the
people who understand locks a reverse
side bar pushes into actively pushes
into the pins and something pushed out
like a medico sidebars push being pushed
out the Umi sidebars being pushed in
which makes it much much harder to pick
the 750 is a slider system so on can we
have the document camera please thanks
it's looks like this looks like that
it's the same it's basically the same
deal with reverse I bar except it's got
this
it doesn't look like a face anymore
unfortunately and this is what the key
looks like it's a typical engraved key
all right now back to the Kingsley's
thanks and we have the 750 k which is a
big step forward
basically what they did is they made
this lock
free spinning because it when you have a
reverse side bar it's very easy to make
the lock free-spinning which i'm not
going to goto into detail but if you
want to ask me about this i'll explain
to you downstairs
so basically what it is is just give me
a second I need to get out of the depths
of Tartarus down here it can we have the
document camera I'm sorry
basically what it is is that this
cylinder right here it looks like yeah
it looks angry doesn't it's got a
different base now it's like I'm gonna
eat you you know so i basically what's
so special about this cylinder is that
if the any key is inserted it can turn
the cylinder will still turn around so
if you've been down to the Loch sport
village downstairs you'll know that you
need to put tension on the lock in order
to pick it and what this does is take
that option away by making a free
spinning which is pretty evil for the
lock Pickers but good for homeowners and
stuff and only the right key will
actually cause the lock to unlock like
that
theoretically yes because you could
technically slide it back and forth and
feel for where it drops in but it's very
hard it's basically impossible to pick
but there is that little possibility
right there
I can we have vs lies again slides
well thank you are and then we got the
730 k which is the same thing you see
that smiley face
actually I'm afraid I'm gonna have to
ask for the document camera yeah I'm
okay okay pull the chair over so i don't
so basically this is the 730 as you can
see it's an actual smiley face this time
see it smiling at you guys you know the
Chinese seem to like to make lots of
faces on them so yeah that's good
and basically it also freely turns
whenever L any little torque is put on
it but only the correct he will actually
turn the tailpiece which you'll see in a
second like like that like that
okay so yeah basically these locks I
think are pretty tough to pick but can
we have the slides be sorry
thanks so these locks are very hard to
pick now the 760 so let's here's the
grandma classic with the smiley face in
the ears that's upside down
I've demonstrated that already so the
UMR 760 the a ploy protec to of China
it premiered just this year in march
februari or april or january i'm not
sure but it premiered this year in 2016
they presented it at the Canton Fair
which is this big fair where all of the
lock manufacturers in China go to show
off their new products and jim i was
there and they own that show you know
they were like well our new lock design
with us Umi 760 we're going to hold a
public picking and folklore bypass
contest with a 1 million un reward which
is not a lot so I 149,000 852 dollars
but still a decent amount and so they
held this contest and they and for those
who bought their law they gave you a 10
x money-back guarantee if your stuff got
stolen so basically if you could prove
that it was the lock that got picked
they would pay you ten times your money
are worth of the stuff your stuff
obviously not the lock
ok yeah I'm very sorry I maybe a little
condescending points5 ok ok so anyway
let's go on this is what it is so you
can see this pretty ladies some going
like oh these people are world Chinese
champion lock they said international
but i don't think anyone internationally
went there to go try to pick the locks
did anyone here try to go
oh yeah so did anyone here try to go and
pick now why not if you're here
listening to this than your pride can go
armed so basically none of these people
could get it open and it was there was a
1 million rmb bonus so there was that
so they're pretty confident that this
lock cannot be pic so basically what
they did is that they said that this
free spinning design which is basically
impossible to fake it's not good enough
for them it's not good enough for us we
want to be better now this is completely
different than the American like la
companies where they just make the
smallest improvements to try to keep the
pattern going but in China pet as you
may know patents don't really exist for
the term so basically in order to stay
ahead of the group they have to keep
innovating and so
this is what the lock looks like you'll
notice that i have no homemade pictures
because i have not managed to obtain one
of these locks yet because they haven't
been released the one that they have
released is is in a safe which is very
heavy and if you can imagine lugging
that thing up to the 18th floor to do a
presentation on it so basically what the
why it makes it so curious is so secure
as they taken a step back and they've
gotten rid of the reverse side bar
they've done a regular sidebar but
instead they put in a dislike slider
blocking system so whenever you try to
put tension on it it's going to lock all
the sliders in place so you can't
manipulate them when you're putting
tension on it so the only way to unlock
it is that all the sliders at the exact
correct position before rotating which
is basically the concept of the a ploy
protec to so this is the a ploy of China
that's why talking about that
alright another weird name oh hello the
Oh mellow rotation 3d design a reboot of
the Corbin em heart lock now Corbin my
heart is has been one of my favorite
locks except I don't have one of them so
how can it be my favorite but still it's
one of my favorite designs and locks are
this is basically I don't know if they
designed it themselves or they went and
bought a corporate and part lock but
this is of a very interesting take on
the design so the first thing you'll
notice when you buy this lock is that it
comes in a can
I'm like wait a moment this law comes in
a can
I mean if you had this nexus soft drinks
i'm pretty sure someone would like try
to drink it or something but uh yeah but
the revised is what so you may ask why
is it a softer and can well this one
doesn't what I'm sorry it's okay you can
say it out loud
um so basically what it is is that to
keep the key safe so you know that if
you order off along online or from locks
with you know that they haven't been
inside and copying the keys with wax or
whatever to try and get into your house
so this make sure that you can't um well
steal the keys or something when you
open the can you got how to install a
lock on the top and you get the lock
cylinder and nestled in there with some
foam it looks very snug and cute and
stuff but it's the the problem with the
can having a candidate that the edges
are razor sharp so whenever you try to
go and get the lock out of it you get
like stabbed by the edges of the can
yeah is another level of security except
it's kinda in the wrong direction
yeah yeah so it becomes a beverage can
if it does that so ok only if you're a
vampire put okay next
so this is what the lock looks like and
i'll talk about this lock under the
document camera because that's a little
interesting if could I have the document
camera please
alright so this lock is special so how
does a Corbin em heart lock work it has
interlocking is actually i have asked
for the slide please sorry
I know I I gotta think the guy after i'm
done with it cause I really gave him a
workout they're also a Corbin em heart i
got these from these websites uses a set
of interlocking pins in order to allow
the pins to be both rotated and lifted
so it requires these to be lined up and
you can see the corporate em hartke as
angled cuts on it a bit like a medico if
you've heard that lock company before
except instead of using a sidebar uses
interlocking pins
now let's take a look at the oml oro
mellow lock
well it uses the exact same mechanism
except with a different key so make sure
there's nothing after that ok so
document camera I promise I won't change
my mind this time
oh ok i think Oh
alright yeah he's giving it to me all
right
okay I'm just gonna wait a little bit
it's okay I don't mind all right now I
do mind foot still oh there you go
thanks oh I promise I won't change my
mind again
ok so basically this is the key all
you'll notice that it looks like a
slider base key on this side it has like
a left and right it's very gentle but
something else that special about this
lock this key actually is that not only
do this does this little track go left
and right but it also has depth to it so
it goes down and up as well as left to
right which is why they call this the 3d
lock so the key is three-dimensional so
the left and the right of the the
curvature of the tracks on the side
right here the curvature of this track
rotates the pins and the depth of the
track list up to the correct type so
there's that and uh ok if you want to
see the lock-in demonstration this is
all Chinese locks use this basically
designed it's a gyro cylinder because
most locks in Europe are shaped this way
so it's all yours owner and it works on
this side it were all just about quality
even this lock is not without its
quality issues is whenever I insert the
key into this side it doesn't come out
so yeah it's very hard to get out there
you go
but yeah so that's some quality quality
issue but that's fine
it's the lock mechanism that were
interested in ok the next one the
geometry a rotating disk design which I
think can we have the sorry can we have
the five things that Yahweh rotating
disk design which i think is an
improvement on the abloy classic design
at the abloy protest for the alloy
classic design so so let's take a look
at the box
the main thing that we notice is the
fact that it uses the designation d+
which as i write said does not exist
the second thing I notice is that this
company is at
remember of a saveloy which I looked it
up and it is so they're not just putting
it on there just to like CEO or part of
a saveloy you know just yeah so they're
actually a member of a sample and the
box is really good it's like a blue
velvet is very heavy the boxes prime
more expensive than the lock but still
yes the box is very it's harder to get
it out of the box
ok so this is what it comes in you have
this when you open the bosses on the lid
it's singing the praises of the lock and
all mechanism so you'll notice that
locks in China they tend to are they
tend to i try to show off their
mechanism so like if we can see the
omalo lock this was on their website
showing off how they lock works and so
this one they're also showing off their
locks and how they work
so here are the two a keys as you can
see the other for the people installing
the lock and you'll notice something
that is a little weird is that they have
this heat
oh five minutes key duplication card
over here which is a problem because
well-armed you can go and duplicate and
make the owner keys with that cars so
that's not supposed to be there as you
can see the owner keys are in this
little plastic box over here that you
have to break the box to open it looks
pretty substantial but you have to like
destroy the box to get the keys here to
cylinder captain here's the cylinder on
hurry it up a little bit cause i only
have five minutes left are ok ok if you
want more of this all be downstairs and
we can talk about poop so come on by
doing what the alright here's what the
lock looks like in the front it looks a
bit similar like the a ploy class sick
of the profile if you want to be like
really exact about it but there is that
and there's the app low profile
what's the difference well you'll notice
on the GI wakey we've got on a track
instead of angles like on the profile so
basically what this means is that
instead of needing to turn it 90 degrees
to to move the discs are so there's the
insides of those locks the disks on the
inside the tracks move
dis to the correct angle while you're
inserting the key so this saves you on
the need to turn it 90 degrees to get it
out and also it can be turned in both
directions so how do we get into the
lock is like picking any other lab
warlocks and also as fall skates so
free-floating and spending lakhs the
future might do I call us now it's not
the future of mechanical locks I don't
know I thought that their here's the
minimalistic both side in lock which is
a company it's pretty minimalistic comes
as 10 and you'll notice there's a box
there with the keys you have to break
that box as well to get into the key
switch you really hurt me because that
was like really high quality box for the
keys and it was like a critic and it
looked more expensive than the lock and
the keys inside the box so yeah so why
is it free spinning you'll see notice
that's pretty minimalistic there are no
wars in the key white nothing and
whenever you put any torque on the lock
it turns a little bit and that's the key
over there and you'll see it has two
tracks running down the side of it
ok now we're done with this we're very
close the other category some other
interesting locks the Catman GT series
locks you'll notice that this looks
exactly like another company's lock
mul-t-lock interactive yes that is
correct
it looks like the multi lock there's a
multi lucky and there's a cabin GT key
but the main difference is if you'll
notice and if time allowed me is that it
has this extra little thing here on
which the multi lucky and on it is
absent and what this is is a magnet
which pulls down this little magnetic
element here which actually surprised me
because most of the time are he might
have a magnet on it but it doesn't do
anything
and here is the package we've got the
advertising over here and you'll notice
over here I know it's a little blurry
all but it says dating triangle which
basically means exclusive to Beijing so
basically what they're doing is they're
geographically restricting the
distribution of these locks since
there's only a certain amount of
combinations before we have to reuse
them and so basically they're doing is
there are trying to restrict the
geographical location but the ironic
thing is I the guy who sent me this lock
didn't was not in Beijing so ever it
didn't work and now
tsa keys okay there's going to be a talk
about this tomorrow at eleven o'clock
you should go listen to it a night owl
is going to be there and darksome 905 a
bunch of interesting people
tsa keys so this is the last thing i
want to talk about so well they have
completed the Chinese have a disregard
to all the security procedures in other
countries so they've gone ahead and
mass-produced the keys to the tsa locks
that are on your luggage and so here it
is those keys and I have some with me
right here if they'll turn on the
document camera please please all things
here's what they look like and they work
perfectly on this lock just hangs there
here's a tsa lock i'll just put the key
in there and it's open
ok so that's not supposed to be like
that and so you know I'm not supposed to
have this key in the first place because
well it's restricted well not that
restricted anymore but still and now
questions I don't know if we thought I'm
questions two minutes
ok questions
oh I'm not too familiar with that I'm
very sorry
all right any other questions or do you
have to go
ah well our way for tomorrow night that
is
yes my slides if you want them i'll put
them somewhere and are also nite owl can
get the distribution and all right okay
anything else or I think we should get
going
alright thank you thank you this is my
first presentation ever front of people
thank you