thanks everyone for coming out so quick
yeah Scott urban associate director
activity head up healthcare and medical
device security for the firm also a
security researcher so i spent just over
the last four years researching
vulnerabilities in connected medical
devices and prior to coming over to the
consulting world and helping on that
side i actually managed information
security team for a few health care
providers so I also come from industry
only been consulting for a few years is
my twitter handle at the bottom if you
want to follow me i tend to tweet on
healthcare and more specifically a
medical device security vulnerabilities
and research so feel free to follow me
and turn over to Adam quick to get us
kicked off
i think scott and my name is Adam brand
also with activity director privacy and
security
I work with him on healthcare security
among other things medical device
security i have a history of custom EEG
manufacturing of some pictures of those
later which you might find interesting
and I also volunteer with i am the
cavalry which we'll talk about a little
bit later and there's my twitter handle
ok so in terms of the agenda for today
and the number of topic areas will cover
related to medical device security give
you a sense of the landscape some
specific research will start off with
you know why we're interested in medical
devices at all go into some phase one
research on device vulnerabilities just
you know what in general DC will talk
about the secondly the internet exposure
of these devices so are these things
actually on the internet and admin
access how difficult is it to achieve
admin access you need to create 0 days
to achieve that and honey pot research
so are these attacks reality so if you
put some medical devices out there what
happens and and we'll get into a little
bit in terms of the diagnosis so what do
we think are some of the root causes for
some of this activity or some of these
vulnerabilities and then some of the
treatment plants so what do we think
should be done about that
so before we get into this at
too much just by way of definition when
we talk about medical devices that can
mean different things to different
people could be a surgical instrument
for example we're talking about software
driven and continually or periodically
connected devices so these are the these
are devices that will at some point
connect to a network and also have
software in them and when we talk about
the medical device sometimes you'll
think of just the actual physical
hardware thing that's maybe running
embedded linux or something like that
a real-time operating system were
talking about the entire solution so if
there's a device that's controlled by a
computer and that's important for the
function of the medical device we
include that in this definition so in
terms of why we would research medical
devices at all and I guess firstly
there's certainly a personal impact and
so it's just time it can kind of see
through these lights in terms of the
folks in the room how many of you rely
on a medical device daily or know
somebody that relies on a medical device
daily yeah Wow a lotta guys
yep and you know I think similarly if
you think about maybe you don't
personally or somebody you know doesn't
on a daily basis certainly within the
past year I'm sure each of us can think
of examples where someone the other
selves or someone we cared about was in
this situation in a hospital where they
they were connected to one of these
devices so even it even if we're not
personally affected at a given point
someone we we care may be affected and
that's certainly a high personal
motivation for looking at device
vulnerabilities an example that comes to
mind for myself so few years ago my
sister-in-law and she was pregnant with
twins she was had to go to NICU because
it seems like the twins might be
arriving a few weeks early and so my
wife and I went and SAT with her and
we're talking with her in that the
nurses would come in periodically to
check on the the heartbeat of these
babies to see if they were okay and
whether or not they needed to do an
emergency see or something like that and
the nurse had come in and we notice that
she kept messing with the the device
itself with the sensor and she
seemed a little frustrated and and you
know that of course made us all a little
bit nervous in terms of what's going on
i do these you know is it time I mean to
the do we need to have action here and
she said well you know hang on hang on
it may just be that I need to reboot the
computer exactly what you want to hear
in that situation and the second thing
that you exactly want to see in that
situation is when she reboot the
computer a certain logo appear on the
screen
can anyone guess what that logo is
windows XP
yes so you know I'd really thought about
it that point is that what this is that
fetal heart rate monitor this is
actually windows XP machine and it
certainly got me thinking a lot more
about the security implications that
we're going to talk about today one of
the other things that we like to discuss
when it comes to medical device security
vulnerabilities is sometimes we get a
question well who would actually do this
who would actually try and attack
medical device and and exploited or
something like that and and getting
beyond the fact of you know people do
crazy things and we should rely on the
you know trusting the internet right and
one key point is that malicious intent
is not a prerequisite to a patient
safety issue so it was an example of
that is a few years ago about five years
ago at a hospital in Austria to gunshot
patients were admitted and they were
connected to morphine drip sand most
morphing pumps and you know as they were
receiving this morphine they're like it
was pretty good you know would be better
than the morphine more morphine right so
they set out they looked at these
devices and they started to engage in
some very apt style hacking using this
technology called google know if you
guys have you heard of that I'm so they
went on a Google and they found the
password for this device on google and
proceeded to up the maximum dose allowed
and get addicted to morphine very
quickly and they were both admit you
know that the nurses recognize something
was wrong they switched them to patches
after a time but these guys were highly
addicted to morphine had a respiratory
events and definitely did not have a
good day as a result and so again
malicious intent not a prerequisite so
it doesn't take a malicious person to go
out and do this patients could
potentially take advantage of security
vulnerabilities and do harm to
themselves so what are we doing related
to this when I say we I mean security
researchers involved and I'm the
Calabrian in Scott nine others so few
different things so first is looking at
the actual medical devices to discover
patient safety issues so with the device
itself
what's going on what's the vulnerability
landscape there and what types of the
floor what are the types of laws we can
see and how can we equip you know the
people that are doing these to prevent
these vulnerabilities from being
introduced new devices and secondly
coordination and notification so as we
uncover these vulnerabilities and
coordinating the disclosure of those
vulnerabilities working with the
affected parties working with the
manufacturers working with the provider
organizations to try and get these
problems addressed and then thirdly
public awareness so talking about these
issues and forms like this and for you
know other broader groups talking about
just the idea of the fact that these are
you know these are computers at the end
of the day and there's an issue here
that we just start focusing on so I'm
going to turn it over to Scott now is
going to talk specifically about the
phase one research and overall device
vulnerabilities and then go into a few
other areas of research
alright so you see that morphine stores
pretty awesome on the I think the one
thing that that it comes to mind before
we start talking about all these super
elite advanced vulnerabilities is that
it paints a good picture that's it
who has been on morphine yes so if you
can hack into a medical device on
morphine
it can't be that difficult
so so here we go so instead started on
this kind of path like four and a half
years ago and for me it was kind of this
like personal passion thing of working
at a healthcare organization and really
you know healthcare organizations as a
whole have been you know focused on
patient privacy and protecting patient
information which is important but when
i seen these devices become connected
you know to the network to the as you'll
see here to the internet potentially and
i was able to identify vulnerabilities
work with the manufacturer to resolve
that that kind of went to you know every
healthcare organizations mission and
values of new patient safety and quality
care and so I really felt you know
passionate about that from the safety
perspective of really having an impact
on healthcare organizations mission and
so what we found over all I've done
handful of talk to the last you know
two-and-a-half years on this research in
detail so you look like DEFCON talks for
example if you want you know hard level
hour-long technical detail talks on each
of these phases but the first thing was
when we started to look at device
vulnerabilities it was are these
advanced attacks or are these really
security hygiene issues that we've had
you know no one fixes for four years and
that's kind of what we found out like
this is the top three that i would call
like big mistakes or security hygiene
issues that we still see in devices that
are implemented in you know in hospitals
and healthcare provider environment and
so that first one is you know we default
are hard-coded credentials which I'm
gonna touch on later today and show you
some of the awesome passwords that these
systems use the second is no known
software vulnerabilities and that's you
know two atoms point we still do have a
lot of XP even older you know 2025 see
regularly still in operation legacy
devices and with known vulnerabilities
that are you know open to exploit and
lastly is a lack of encryption and and
at first when you look at this
like we said we we tend to focus on the
patient safety impact privacy kinda gets
wrapped up into that sometimes in our
first glance this may seem like this is
a privacy issue solely right it's
encrypted data
but as you start doing things like
medical device integration a pump
real-time data from for example
anesthesia card or a ventilator into the
medical record and then you're treating
on that some of these systems that don't
use encryption and transit so you can
man in the middle that you can alter
that data and ultimately cause data
integrity issues and push incorrect data
into the medical record system so that
comes up with you know stuff that
research has been done on like bad data
leading to you know misdiagnosis
mistreatment those types of things so
it's definitely also safety as you not
just a privacy issue after we finished
that research we said okay these devices
are definitely vulnerable but what's the
real risk to an attacker being able to
get to them are they gonna have to have
physical access are they going to happen
you know selfish email in or you know
what are they directly connected to the
internet or are there hospitals that
have misconfigurations it's exposing
vulnerabilities and other systems that
give direct access into the internal
network into the internal connected
medical devices so i worked with another
researcher Sean murderer and ended up
looking at the show Dan and so at first
we were you know going into show Dan and
we were doing you know super elite
hacker searches that you'd never think
of for medical terms and the the one
that I came up that was super awesome
was anesthesia that no one would think
of and when we did that I gotta return
and I'm like look at the system like at
first I'm like okay you know this i know
enough i've been doing this awhile like
this clearly isn't a medical device like
what's going on
I mean the only indication that a kid
for medical devices it was an XP system
but but outside of that I knew like this
is no medical device will realize there
is a SMB was actually open on this XP
system and it was an anonymous read to
active directory and so it was leaking
intelligence out on all of their
internal systems hostname is identifying
information going to show you some of
the examples of that
so the first organization that popped up
on the status t-shirt or anesthesia
search was very large so it was in the
US over 12,000 employees it leaked
intelligence
and provide a direct attack vector that
will talk about for 60,000 internal
systems and third parties so there was
hospitals often time will make
connections one for supporting medical
devices with 24 third parties doing
radiology reading for example or third
parties doing lab testing those types of
things and so they were very well-known
organization names that do those
services inside this data set which
indicated they were also you know
connected and had open access between
those those networks in those systems so
did we just find and just happened to
come across like one big massive problem
no we didn't so we took that searches
showed and we basically looked at the
organization names and we did these
quick searches as you can see for like
health clinic or hospital or medical
that would indicate it's a healthcare
facility and also had a misconfigured
system with SMB that was leaking
information of other medical devices and
so those are the returns very quickly
found hundreds once we change those two
like subspecialties so they looked like
radiology or podiatry for example we
ended up with thousands of healthcare
organizations that had this problem so
what was it what was the issue a
treasure trove of information was the
first issue as you can see here on the
left you would get stuff in here so
you're getting specific locations right
so r1 echo vascular or2 you're getting
screen lock 0 exemption so you know
active directory with zero is enforcing
like a timeout which one would be a
violation probably but two from attacker
perspective if you walked up to that
system which will talk about there
wouldn't really be a screen lock on the
right that's electronic medical record
system now this healthcare organization
happened to use epic which is a very
large provider this is an epic issue
right
it just happened that they used epic and
they misconfigured their edge network
with this you know vulnerability but
these are all of the epic servers that
hold all of that patient patient data
treasure trove of information sitting
out there and so if you're familiar with
epic like down on the bottom and stuff
there's like my chart my health that's
the actual patient portal back-end
server that used as a patient to connect
into the the environment this one here
we go
you know cardiology systems cath lab
you'll see first floor pediatric nuclear
medicine
in and on the far left those are the
actual host names of the system are
scrubbed out what they were full host
news you'll see anesthesia or it would
tell you it was anesthesia or seven for
example so very detailed information for
an attacker to have this overall was
just that one organization the types of
data are the types of systems they're
inside that organization that we had
intelligence about a new the system and
host names on so you can see a lot of
cardiology systems MRI systems infusion
pumps pack systems packs for those of
you that don't know what that is that is
basically an archiving system of all
radiology images so a lot of you know
protected health information inside of
that a lot of ph I and that is the
backend storage when you take it from
any of those radiology images it stores
it impacts systems I which traditionally
have very poor security around back and
storage so outside of that you kind of
before I let Adam go on the attack
perspective one thing that was important
as i said in the beginning was this was
XP right it was an XP system with SMB
open and ms 0806 7 which the
vulnerability that configure exploited
happened to exploit these vulnerable
systems right XP 4003 but it also used
SMB by default so you also not only had
this intelligence you had a direct
attack point into that Network so
definitely treasure trove of information
to turn it back over to Adam you're
quick to kind of talk about you know
with that information
what types of attacks and then we'll get
into you know some of the further
research that we've done beyond this
thanks got so yeah when you when you
look at some of this stuff they get face
value might think oh well this is an
information disclosure vulnerability
right i mean this is what can you really
do with this information and I think
certainly if you think about it a little
bit further you'll start to realize you
can do something interesting with this
information so terms of these two types
of attacks that you could leverage this
I think about physical attacks so you
have the desire to go in physically
access a particular station in a
hospital and you know before you
before you let's say you want to plug in
the USB or something like that before
you go into that facility if you have
this information available to you you
can see you know you already know the
specific location for this healthcare
organization you know the floor and
office number so this equipment was
tagged in these systems were tagged with
exactly where they were and you also
know which ones have lockout exemptions
right so if you're going to plug
something in and run it be pretty nice
if you didn't have to you know worry
about a lockout coming on and having to
have a password be entered so it
certainly makes a physical attack easier
to conduct by having this type of
information
next would be a phishing attack so the
key with fishing really is you want to
make it as realistic as possible so that
the target feels like it's a legitimate
email with this type of information you
certainly have a lot of data to make a
very effective phishing email you know
the employee names you know the host
names of these devices you know maybe
there are the label on that device
oh hey you know Jennifer can you go over
to host XYZ and please go to this
website we need to do an update to it
right and and furthermore because you
know the entire inventory of that
organization you know where there may be
certain other vulnerable systems for
example medical device that you know as
a no default password or something like
that or an open share and you can create
a custom payload so that it jumps in and
then goes right to the system that it
needs to go to you don't need to worry
about you know that the clock starting
to tick on getting detected and then of
course there's the pivot which got
alluded to so you have the system out
their windows XP vulnerable to msoe 067
and you know it's touching those back on
networks because you can see them
enumerated so if this thing can see that
enumeration of devices it you know
there's a way to get to them so you
could create a custom payload when you
explain that to very quickly get in and
then pivot off to another system that
you find is interesting and that you
want to have is the next point of attack
so certainly a few different varieties
of types of attacks that you can do with
just this fairly straightforward
vulnerability and then I'll turn over to
Scott a little bit more talk a little
bit about how exceedingly difficult it
is to obtain admin access
it's about as difficult as the the two
individuals in the beginning of going on
to google so we said okay we have
vulnerable devices and you know what
they are directly accessible to the
internet either either directly which I
didn't touch on you gonna watch the Deaf
contact we did find infusion pumps
patient monitoring all the way up to
high dosage radiation systems like
linear accelerators directly connected
to internet facing IPS so we did find
that also i focus on this kind of this
hospital scenario but we did find
directly connected devices and so then
we said okay we have vulnerable devices
directly connected or there's a lot of
hospitals that have misconfigurations in
their system that allowed direct access
to these medical devices well how hard
is it to get remote admin access if
that's the case and so this is a
disclosure timeline for those of you who
are interested in that this happened to
be with GE Healthcare i'm looking at the
radiology equipment as you'll see as we
go i only through a few examples in here
but previous talks have all of the
examples so that we release them
publicly but if you if you go through
that it's all of these all this
information was as simple as you know
what those folks did in the hospital of
going online going to their website is
all publicly available documentation
with the intended use of providing you
know shared passwords to support
personnel so that they can keep those
systems operational and securities kind
of that unintentional you know use case
and I think it's also doing a very
important to point out when we talk
about this that although this is
specific to GE what I'm going to show
you this you know problem right is not
specific to GE you see it across the
industry it's a systemic issue in
healthcare and in medical devices
historically they were not designed or
did not have security embedded during
design or engineering so here we go
so overall I'm just going to a subset
but overall there's just over total like
30 C B's 450 sets of administrative
remote credentials on system so this
year and it will be followed the CVE
will start this and then the cdss score
so every CD that we we put out was given
a CSS score of 10 because they were
remote admin access to the system you'll
also see the identifier of the year and
you're like hey Scott have you been
hoarding this thing since 2006 know as i
mentioned since they were publicly
available we go back to the last
instance of when that documentation was
found on the internet and then we
reactively request the CD back to that
year so that's why it was 2006 but it
gets interesting to look at these years
to see some of them you'll see are like
2013 a couple years before we release
the research reported the research so
it's not just the issue of years ago it
was up until like two or three months
before there was new products being
released when we did this that still had
the systemic issues so this happens to
be a nuke imaging system and so you can
see default user accounts emergency
accounts those types of things admin
windows accounts
here's another on the discovery on the
new imaging you get into remote
management so you gonna tell that into
root super-awesome passwords like to get
in
yes and that and then you get down to
you know Nick imaging systems down below
on like FTP and interfaces with like
printers things like that
this is also a different versions this
one's from 2011 of nuclear imaging and
CT scanners and you have no problem big
gap on big one
those are also really awesome and the
thing that you see across this is it's
interesting when you look across all of
them to see like a certain password
where you're like hey this development
team must acquit this product and now
started on this product because big guy
is like coming from like $2,000 2 2016
across like seven product lines right so
here you go really you know down at the
bottom this one's awesome you see this a
lot like these windy and see logins or
pcanywhere logins again in 10 intended
uses is to be able to support that
system but real poor you know practice
and
really weak passwords on those systems
so this is a word cloud I mean what
better when you have a bunch of
passwords in to create a word cloud and
so this is a hundred and fifty sets of
usernames and passwords in a word cloud
and in big guys definitely you know
leading that charge anyone to notice
anything interesting about the big guy
though
No so if you looked when i had when i
showed you the actual password it was
pound pound big guy pound big one guy
one
well I quickly found out that word cloud
app sec is much better and actually
sanitizes your data input so i couldn't
get it to do a leading pound sign
so when we went through disclosure some
of the things were
hey a lot of these are default and in
some cases they are default and in some
cases they do actually provide you know
instructions in the manuals that are
given to the installers or to the
hospital systems that
hey you should change this and this is
how you should do it but saying they're
all default i think is contradictory
because i will show you some examples
inside of that specific documentation
that would indicate otherwise and these
are the installation guidance that
either the manufacturer support staff or
the hospital or third-party are using to
install so there are still indeed issues
so for if you wanted a customer to make
this a default password you want to
ensure they would change that password
would you tell them to check user can
never change password would you tell
them to check password never expires
that's not something that's indicative
of a default credential and so these
credentials whether they're truly
hard-coded on the back end in some cases
they definitely are or if they just are
in in the instructions told like this
like important do not change the
password or we will not support you
what hospital organization is not going
to listen to that especially putting big
and bold and say don't do it we're not
gonna be able to support that system so
there's still issues that were see that
are you know common here here's another
one again in big bold do not change this
password another one hit tech support
will log into your system with our
backdoor account
and use this username and password and
hey dr. I know you love remembering
passwords so just click yes and you
won't have to ever enter it again or or
ask the remotes the station operator to
reset it to the super secure password
password the bottom one here this is a
good example on this is kind of getting
the mindset of you know a hacker how we
look at intentional use versus how could
you modify a system and you know bypass
the intended use so this is if you read
this really quick it's basically you
must generate extra radiation follow
safety precaution so we know radiation
is going to get admitted right and with
those types of things it's like dosing
limits and also like exposure time
limits those types of things that could
cause harm and so we know if we run this
its calibration so it's probably not a
high-level radiation right it's just
login here simple user name and password
do this in your run radiation well if
you capture that traffic between the
application that actually post to a web
server on the actual x-ray system it's
not encrypted it's an xml file it gets
passed in many cases you can modify
those parameters what happens if you
modify those parameters to be higher the
exposure link to be different and then
post it doesn't accept it so that's the
type of thing that we look at this
specific system i haven't tested i have
done stuff exactly similar to this on
other manufacturers system but that
gives you an idea of you know how we try
to find intentional use and then make it
do something else so we have honorable
devices are connected the internet not
that difficult to get remote access
server to another researcher mark allow
and we he's a massive like honey pie and
so with him to you know set up some
honey pots see what's happening so we're
basically looking at you know setting
them up realistic so if they had poor
you know default login credentials like
I showed you we we mimic that completely
we wanted to see are there you know
specific campaigns against specific
vendors are they attacking medical
devices if they're attacking medical
devices is it targeted are they trying
to steal intellectual property stuff
source code things like that try to get
an understanding of the motivations
so this is kind of a setup what we did
again service connection strings we did
everything to where you could you know
Google dork it would be exactly the same
we replicate a real-world environment so
those systems that were XP that we did
so we did external defibrillators we did
some pack systems we did some radiology
equipment we did some infusion pumps we
would mimic that XP with that
vulnerability because that's really how
it is in the environment remote web
management services those types of
things and then file structure
attributes all the way down to make sure
that those were accurate some of them if
if the company actually other source
code sitting in a file like three levels
deep we you know we mimic that and then
we get the word out so throw out a
showdown right you know John matter has
been awesome to work with and a lot of
the research that we've done you know
make those google friendly searches
actually a pickup also drop you no
indicators of you know releasing cds or
disclosing vulnerabilities with
usernames and passwords and using
systems that had been publicly disclosed
to see if people were doing that we also
you know get facebook and twitter dumps
with honey cards that will talk about
here's the data after six months we set
up ten honey pots we don't over 55,000
logins now those weren't late
those were not blank logins now they
could have been weak right equipment
adamant that system was where they could
have been very weak like the guy one or
you know to get in or something like
that if that was the type of system but
they were actually credential logins we
had 24 times that they actually went
around the exploit on it most of that
was 08 067 on XP almost 300 unique now
our samples dropped most of that that
we've seen was actually just you know
meant to your script a test script
credit card data those types of things
top three source countries was
interesting you know and we're not doing
attribution years telling you the source
country that the attack came from as is
netherlands you know China and Korea and
netherlands we worked with the the cert
team over in another lens and ultimately
it ended up being a data center that was
compromised over there and then was
pivoting and and coming into our systems
most importantly overall i think eight
times so we put those honey Craig's we
took a subsample of that and we through
unique username and password out on the
pavement and onto Twitter and kind of
publicize it like a use these medical
devices sitting out here here's the
credits go ahead and hack away and eight
times are actually used against the
system so
yeah yeah yeah that was definitely south
I think I don't know if North Korea any
internet-connected systems they have to
they don't have too many it's all like
that centered in the in the city but
real world of taxing a conclusion right
what did we see
did we see any indication that it was
like targeted to the actual device know
what we saw was hey it was just random
you know for the most part of those like
honey credit logins were a little bit
unique right but someone just scrape
them off a placement probably put in a
word list and then I don't know if they
just hit him but we just anything that
was like targeted we didn't see any
indication once they got in that they
actually knew what they were doing they
were definitely calling back they were
sitting there but we don't see any you
know malicious intent from a patient
harm perspective or trying to offload
her steal you know any type of data so
in turn over to Adam quick to kinda wrap
up on your diagnosis treatment plans and
then we'll shoot in the Q&A after that
thanks guys so yeah it when i was
looking at honey any net stuff honey pot
results i was thinking myself you know
yeah that's the kind of that's good way
right we didn't see any direct attack
vector like people going after a
specific medical device and I was
thinking you know but how good does that
really make me feel right if I'm a
patient I'm connect to a medical device
somebody didn't intend to compromise it
but it still is compromised and I think
there's certainly an element of yeah
it's still an uncomfortable place to be
so why is this stuff happening so in
terms of the the nature of the problem
we can talk about your first the fact is
i mentioned earlier we're talking about
software driven system so software has
flaws anyone designed a soft piece off
without a flaw out there
ok few of you great hit exactly exit
return
ok so yall software has flaws right and
when you connect something that's
previously not been connected you're
increasing the interaction point so if
you have this like great idea to have a
you know software-driven you know
connected medical device it could be a
vulnerable exposed one
right so it's just the nature its
inherent to the the thing that you're
building and then also we see is the
lack of alignment from a patient safety
perspective in terms of these medical
device cybersecurity practices so we
talked about this earlier that HIPAA
certainly is a driver but in terms of
what is the potential impact from this
patient safety perspective that didn't
seem to be as much they're so in terms
of problem awareness so we talked about
a lot of this i'm not gonna go through
in detail but essentially we have all
these medical devices connected to the
internet this is going to be growing in
terms of connected medical devices in
general this is not you know tomorrow
people are gonna be like oh you know
what we should really just unplug
everything from the network that's not
gonna happen and we still have hippo
which focuses on patient safety and we
have the FDA which does not validate
cyber safety controls so i think a lot
of people especially you know new to
this might think well the FDA should be
or has been validating cyber safety
controls on all these devices that is
not the case and as we talked about
malicious intent is not a prerequisite
so it doesn't really matter whether or
not you believe that people are out
there trying to do this to have a
negative potential negative outcome in
terms of looking at the problem in a
different way if you look at the
ecosystem of people that would need to
be involved to address this problem so
what we observed was that there seemed
to be silos so you have the healthcare
providers out there doing what they're
doing the Met device manufacturers doing
what they're doing
security researchers doing what they're
doing but not enough communication and
this is certainly improved over the past
few years is scott will talk about in a
little bit but one of the key
fundamentals to this problem is getting
people to talk so here's some attack
scenarios that i like to call TV show
scripts or risks to plan for right so
this is scripter this real and the
reason I say that is because you can
certainly go down the path of fire on a
lot of these things i'm not a huge 52
fan I guess but I do find it interesting
just to think about these risks and make
that risk determination if you can't
explore it then you can make a decision
so here's an example of one fetal heart
rate monitors in a NICU reboot
periodically
due to incorrectly operating malware
increasing stress among staff and
patients so is this real or TV show and
I want to guess real right yeah
ransomware encryption key application
configuration files on an MRI controller
causing critical care patients to be
relocated to another hospital okay
yeah I don't know that exact but you can
certainly support see that and we have
attacker compromises hospital network
and periodically reboots medical device
computers until ransom is paid TV right
yeah it starts getting those these one
started getting the TV I i don't know of
any examples of this happening and you
can certainly go down to these scenarios
where you start talking about you know
terrorism where you have a coordinated
attack between kinetic attack and then
messing with the hospital's medical
devices at the same time causing
confusion these are all kind of the
wargaming type things right and that
make potentially for good TV shows but i
think it's something to consider when
you when you're going through this list
of you know maybe today we have a
certain perspective on what that risk is
and maybe yesterday we had a certain
perspective on the impact of ransomware
on hospitals and how was that changed
over the past year so many of these
scenarios that we think about look like
TV shows today maybe their number never
happened there too complicated there's
easier ways to get things done as it
were
it's certainly something to think about
when you're doing your risk management
and I think the important point here too
is that you know as we're increasing the
use of technology and connectivity when
providing patient care right it's going
like this we're ramping up all these new
connected
cool devices that are improving patient
care enabling people to respond more
quickly at the same time are our
security resilience posture should not
be like this right for increasing our
use increasing our dependency we should
be also increasing the security
assurances so to be fair we talked a lot
about these default passwords so medical
device security is hard and as i
mentioned i had done custom EEG
manufacturing so I had first-hand
experience with that will get into this
in a second
and so you have to worry about secure
design and development so here's a child
labor that I employed to build a custom
EEG machine actually this is me age of
12 I think putting together a science
project in EEG and so certainly
understand how difficult it is to secure
design and development
don't worry the voltage only goes one
way that poor kid
yeah look at rockin turtleneck to what
happened at those are the nineties and
secure implementation right
does it get any more secure than das
three-point Oh running on a headstart
explorer and I don't think so
so in all seriousness in terms of
treatment plans so what can we do about
this going forward so few different
things so first I think this is part of
the cavalry message as well as you know
it falls to all of us and patient safety
is not a spectator sport
so we talked about earlier all of us are
going to be impacted by this this is
something that we all need to get
involved with so even if today you may
have a certain expectation when you walk
into hospital for a procedure that this
has been taken care of and ask about it
talk to your doctor you know have you
and you know what do you know about the
cyber safety of this device I'm
connected to it maybe next time they
talk to the vendor reptile asked the
same question and if you're a researcher
what are some of these devices that you
can look at in research how can you get
involved and help solving this problem
so importantly you know we have to have
the stakeholders understanding the
prerequisites you know as i mentioned
before our increase in implementation is
is fairly rapid do the stakeholders
understand you can't just plug something
into a network that you can do that but
before that you probably should do some
other different things and how can get
people to talk together certainly
important part of the treatment engaging
with willing allies where we overlap
with think so not everyone is an expert
in everything but certainly this is a
big enough problem we can work with each
other to try and find a common solution
and also incorporating safety into
existing processes so how can we work to
make sure that when we have a process
like procurement a hospital how can we
incorporate cyber safe
he is part of that so Scott's going to
talk a little bit about highlights for
the last 18 months and then we'll have
some time for questions after that
yeah yeah so really quickly
you know you might think well this is a
lost cause like nobody's doing anything
about it
it's all doing gloom in and while I
think we'd be ignorant to say there
isn't a serious problem that needs to be
addressed
there has been a lot of you know that
stakeholder engagement and collaboration
with the willing allies right and so
over the last 18 months so we've seen
the u.s. to the FDA actually take a
stance now they did historically a very
good job of evaluating clinical efficacy
and safety under intentional use and the
security stuff is it's definitely
different right it's unintentional use
or abuse cases of these devices and so
that's new to them so they released
premarket in post-market draft guidance
the draft guidance from a security
researcher perspective is is awesome
it's awesome for a healthcare provider
to that includes language that they have
to have you know a coordinated
vulnerability disclosure program and set
some time limits around that so that's a
huge win and that's a government agency
working in collaboration with security
researchers so you know I go and speak
with them many other members of you know
their associated with the calorie or
device researchers like Billy rios you
know we spend time to educate staff and
let them know our perspective of that
that stakeholder perspectives from the
researcher and and they've been open
they've opened the doors and a lot of
what we've said in the message has been
communicated and has push that forward
there's my Tripoli workshop that was
funded that was on a secure building
code design that was involved in how
we've been embraced in the healthcare
community conferences so you know I
speak at hymns which is the largest you
know healthcare IT conference in the
world i mean it's over 40,000 people now
so I've spoken the last few years
Varner ability disclosure policies two
years ago we didn't have a single device
manufacturer that had a coordinated
vulnerability disclosure program and now
two years ago at DEFCON Philips
Healthcare I was the first one to
announce that they were going to do it
and they finished it at the end of that
year
and so they were the first healthcare
organization to implement vulnerability
coordinated disclosure and now there's
there's more so now there's a dragger
has done it and announced that besides
last year and in phillips and Medtronic
has a dedicated website
GE has you know a dedicated reporting
method so it's getting better and now
it's in the FDA guidance the FDA
actually issued a safety communication
and this was with hospira ponds result
of Billy Rios's research on the infusion
pumps but they actually issued a safety
communication that said hospitals look
at these systems they're vulnerable
we recommend you pull them out of
service that happened that was
precedent-setting that happened before
evidence of harm befall the FDA recalls
things like that typically don't happen
until there's recorded lots of life or
adverse events reported to the fda so
that was precedent-setting they stood up
and they said hey we're seeing the
safety communication so that was great
and I'm the cavalry Boldwood's were
those you have no who know him he's
actually here at the conference a highly
encourage you to speak to him I worked
with him but he was definitely heavy
lifter on kind of creating a Hippocratic
oath for kinect medical devices which
outline cyber you know safety
capabilities that can be incorporated in
these devices so go and check that out
as well as definitely value for both the
manufacturers and providers and other
research or other resources right you
can follow awesome researches on twitter
like my handle or Adam and you can go
industry working groups if you're in
healthcare like the I sex you can argue
effectiveness but if you're not there
talking to folks you're really not doing
much
I'm just kind of being that antagonists
so get involved with that and this is
another group you know conferences
everywhere from technical research
conferences all the way to you know
going to those other stakeholder groups
and speaking to healthcare folks that
typically aren't aware of that this is
even an issue that have the power to
make you know and influence change and
finally I am the cavalry and check it
out it's a group of you know a grassroot
grassroots group of researchers that
focus on the intersection of
you know security and public safety
right and before I am the calorie even
existed i mean me telling my story why I
was passionate is i was able to solve
problems with these devices come you
know all the way through remediating
those vulnerabilities and having an
impact on patient safety or public
safety and that was rewarding for me so
i can tell you as a security researcher
you know everyone in this room is very
smart and awesome things I could tell
you it's much more rewarding personally
if you focus you know your research two
things that actually impact Public
Safety because with this emergence of
IOT with auto you know even you know I
CSK this stuff just general IOT medical
devices it's very important and so the
people in the skills that are in this
room you know i highly encourage you to
start looking at this stuff because you
really can make a difference in the
cavalry you know she's a great group of
folks to you know share ideas with and
kind of move that message forward so
thanks for coming out will open up for a
few questions and if we don't get to you
will be all back in the hallway looks
like you got a giant corpus of showed
and related exposed systems did you
report that to the director of HS for
hip enforcement under the security role
so certain things yes so they're sent to
typically in like disclosure like it
will go to cert in the early days there
wasn't really anyone that would even
respond to us right when we would start
to send in the disclosure so we just
kind of started mass like sending
everyone to like HSN its FDA sending it
ics-cert ics-cert is the one that
rightly or wrongly I don't know if
that's the right place ultimately but
they started to respond to us and
actually work through it and some of the
similarities you know with the ICS
infrastructure we're close enough to
where
so these manufacturers even so like the
ger the Phillips for the siemens they
have in ICS type of equipment and so
they had like a contact with them and so
they kind of started that route and then
now it does get get get shared through i
would say more so than HS so far taking
a stance has been you know the FDA
involvement it still has not been
completely started out from like an OCR
HIPAA patient privacy perspective okay
quit and I was a little surprised that
you didn't talk at all about installed
customer and medical devices like
insulin pumps and cardiac pacemakers and
that kind of thing
yeah because of course there could be
millions of those when there are only a
few hospital-based fixed devices is that
an area of interest to you also
absolutely we definitely taking a look
at those types of systems all the way
from implantable you know defibrillators
to pacemakers I think some good research
has been done before all the way back in
2008 dr. Kevin foods now at university
of michigan and these are communities
did some really good research you know
back when we weren't using any type of
encryption maybe call it proprietary you
know but it was really just radio
frequency / like you know the 400 band
and lack of encryption and you could do
in your field can your social update
yeah absolutely and you know insulin
pump something you know Jay Radcliffe is
is done that Barnaby Jack kinda show
that as well so that's there i think
with insulin pumps interesting is this
our idea of artificial pancreas and kind
of continuous loop and now you have
these systems in development that's
going to do a lot clinically for people
right i mean bottom line it's going to
help a lot more people than harms but
the risks of that are you have the pump
talking to the glucose monitor talking
to your smartphone and it's a full relay
and it's taking that data integrity
becomes an issue if you can compromise
that because the system's automatically
treating based on you don't know I'm
didn't find any attempts at attacks on
individuals who are hospital hospital
which I would expect i'll see you at
some point way I mean you can think
about targeted attacks but I think it's
important to look at like that can
happen but I'm more concerned honestly
with unintentional consequences so how
do we have low assurance because these
devices lack of forensic logging
capabilities in many cases or you know
forensically sound evidence capture that
how do we know that malware that we sent
see that was meant to steal credit card
data didn't cause a configuration change
and we actually reported the clinical
engineering team actually reported a
medical device malfunction but it's
never adjudicated out of it just goes to
a general medical device malfunction
related death bucket
several hundred thousand reports that
you're going to the FDA of medical
device related malfunction adverse
events and it's that generic so how do
we know what these connected devices
that it's not we have low shirts and I
think really unintentional is is more
realistic on a mass scale i I'm great
Baker I'm with the National Board of
Medical Examiner's awesome for those of
you who are unaware the national board
is a hundred and one-year-old nonprofit
focused on protecting the health of the
public through assessing the competence
of the healthcare team and as you amply
demonstrated IT is an integral part of
the modern healthcare delivery system so
i have two questions if if I may
it's not first question can I put you on
the spot go ahead second question up
times up
no go ahead i'm just thinking
off-the-cuff how would you recommend my
organization think about assessing the
competence of the individuals who set up
these healthcare delivery systems using
the individuals that are actually
installing into the system
yes I think that's a good point of
talking about how do you implement those
security so you have secure design right
and the focus right now even from the
FDA has been putting pressure on the
manufacturers and oftentimes the
providers the healthcare system say
what's the manufacturers is their
problem we're going to sit on our butts
and we don't need to do anything until
they secure these devices but as we've
shown like with that showed and stuff
that was actually the hospital swap for
implementing it in an insecure fashion
so there's certain things that you need
to do things about so that concept like
that i truly think that I said was a
concept of this was a software
perspective but it was a building code
right and so I see something like that
of almost you have inspector regimes
that going and specifically in a
hospital now if you put electrical into
know are there specific specifications
you have to do and there's an aspect
regime to do that I see something like
that on the provider side of securely
their secure design and then they're
secured employment that needs to be
addressed
I got two minutes left I guess hugely
informative and an important i'm
wondering if you've been following along
with that with the sensor pills so like
you said with you yet i swallow and then
imagine swallowing or just the roof was
a an anti-psychotic abilify which would
be being used for force treatment so on
the flip side of this like when the
devices are
used against the interests of the
patients have you been doing any
research to help protect the patients
from the devices not necessarily so like
some of those newer like prototype
devices like they're like ingestible so
like you would digest them and then it
would monitor something and then I would
typically we'll talk over like Bluetooth
actually to an app that then we'll treat
you right or just transmitted like
real-time data and so we haven't done a
whole lot on those kids a lot of them
are actually like prototype devices that
would be super expensive to get ahold of
the episode we haven't had any like
research universities to hey come check
this device we're willing to let you
have it so no we have not but it's
definitely an area of concern going
forward in it
I'm sorry to cut you off but we're
getting shoved out here so if you have
questions or want to talk will try to
jump your back on the hallway so thanks
for coming out