hi everyone thanks to be you hear my
name is a metro and presenting with that
it today we're going to present you
about it cluster that is a tool that we
gonna release at the end of the talk in
fact it's already on get them and we
release the database also it's the tool
that is able to the anime eyes
some actors or some entity in the
Bitcoin network so first of all who are
who are we
I am not aware i work as a pen tester
for a large canadian institute a
financial institution
i'm also a close friend of the north
state organization a security conference
montreal and am presenting also with the
that is the key to yeah I one so I'm an
assistant professor in Montreal who's
been looking at the cybercrime and im-
markets for a number years now
alright so we're gonna go that the talk
is pretty long so we're gonna go as
straight to the point
so first of all going to start a little
bit cliche and what this talk is not
about definitely the stock is not about
creating another bitcoin currency is
broke in a clickbank title
I'm sorry we're not going to devote are
not going to tell the names are owners
of Bitcoin wallets into the network at
least not all of them and we're also not
going to show you a of magically
retrieving the private key for Bitcoin
wallet and then spend all the money as
you want
sorry guys what this talk is about is a
lot of detail about how there's a bit
when works at you when you're going to
understand those concepts going to
understand the limited to an empty of
Bitcoin so you understand how traction
works why we are able to get some
details about the note how we are able
to correlate all the data that is public
and to find interesting stuff into this
network and that's bring us to the limit
of pseudo anonymity
i well yes bitcoin is an animus into
quote but there are some limits so we're
going to present the limit and for we're
going to present also if you don't use
well the tools if you don't use well
Bitcoin how you don't understand how it
works
you may get cut by our tools and finally
Howard to cluster and we're going to do
the to release we're going to present
the tool with the small demo explain how
does it works
what does it do and also what you can do
it is so the case study will be present
by that it so the Bitcoin auto in parts
I'm sorry for those were cryptographic
expert but i need to give some basic
details about how does it work so
everybody will be able to understand the
rest of the talk some details that we
going to show our it's it's supposed to
give you some information about how we
achieve the an immunization of the
network so if you want to participate in
to the Bitcoin network you need an ID
and an ID is an address
it's an address where we care when you
can receive money and you can send money
to get an address is pretty simple you
need to generate a pair of key I private
and the public key the public key will
be encoded and will be will be encoded
as
and addresses so in summary a public key
is in addresses is just represented as a
simpler representation of of it we've
seen about pregnancy 146 million
different wallet and as I said press
previously those wallets are addresses
are generated by the user itself so on
your machine with openssl with your own
between client it's not a central
authority that delivered the addresses
it's the user that generate them
directly on this machine and for the
rest of the talk and we're going to talk
about wallet and addresses both mean the
same thing now that you have an
addresses and you generate and your
pretty pretty proud of it
now you want to use it how we're going
to be able to use it well we have to
make a transaction and the transaction
will be included of what we call a
blockchain so the black chain is in the
simple representation like 40 stock it
can be seen only as the public lectures
of all transactions that have been made
up to there up to there since the
beginning of Bitcoin it store
transaction into blocks and the new
blogs created every 10 minutes
that's mean that new transactions are
included into the blockchain every 10
minutes the interesting part now the
transaction so now that you have an
address now that you know how
transaction get validated what is the
transaction actually well i'm a
transaction is is composed by input and
output input our money that you own that
you want to spend and output is where
you want to send money so we're just
going to take my
alright an input is a reference to a
passenger section where did where you
receive money so for the example that it
sent me to Bitcoin two months ago when I
want to spend those Bitcoin what I do is
I tell the network remember when that
give me that coins right now I want to
spend it and i want to send it to
someone else so what I do is I refer to
the transaction where I did receive the
money as in the input and to prove that
i own this addresses that did receive
money I sign this input with the private
key associated addresses so you may
remember that when you generate and
addresses have the public in the private
key key priority for yourself and for
obvious reason and you encode the public
key to get addresses so you take the
private key associated addresses you
sign the input and the transaction will
be considered as valid so how can we
achieve the destination with those
information
well as you may guess actually already
it's related to private key and
transaction but we're going to be a deep
deeper into that the title is misleading
is not the Bitcoin didn't user is the
Bitcoin this enemy the enemy maser for
people who don't know how to use Bitcoin
like four it's like a little example if
you are asking to get to for help on
stackoverflow to create a new crypto
markets name velcroed usually you're not
good to use Bitcoin I'm so in this
example I forgot to tell you that in the
transaction you can have multiple input
and multiple-output so you can send in
one transaction money two different
piece person and if you want to send
money a big amount of money at to
someone and you don't have this money in
and addresses you can use multiple
addresses that you own and merge it
together and then be able to pay
your debt so in this example I take a
transaction that where I did receive
tribute point and another one where i
did receive six Bitcoin and i'm paying
some 19 between well in this case there
are some information that leaks
what I mean is you did use two different
addresses at the same time and we're
able to sign both of this addresses with
their each private key so you were able
to find the private key from where from
the addresses that have to Bitcoin
anywhere able to use the private key for
the addresses that you have six between
so what you're telling here is that you
own boat of those private key and as you
may recall a private key is private so
that's mean that if the transaction was
validated by the network that's mean
that the person that did the transaction
had two of the private don't have the to
the boat at private key so in this case
we are linking those two addresses to
and then in an entity or an actor of the
network and what happened if you use the
weekend if you reuse addresses over and
over
well actually this happen so here are
three transaction with two input two
input entry input and what I can do with
this and I i'm able to know that all of
these are texts are related to the same
person because they are reducing
addresses so here there's a reason
addresses between two transaction so I'm
able to merge those bow transaction and
I'm also able to do the same thing with
the other addresses so it's still using
another addresses on to other
transaction so have the full link here
i'm able to merge all those three node
to a big note i'm going to give an ID
and this case will be the ID 2 3 4 5
so that's how we can achieve to create
all the to create cluster all the
addresses into notes that we are
presenting identity or our actor into in
the network and then after you can
recall it back and see the money
movement between those actor so instead
of seeing transaction we see money
movement in blood of addresses that are
representing identity or person into the
network so in summary the assumption
made to do the tools is and transaction
are signed with private keep private key
are private and one and only one entity
can or should know the private key largo
all the addresses that you see on the
previous slide are necessarily and owned
by a single entity actors or person as
you as you may call it so what why is
this possible is because people are
using addresses over and over instead of
generating new addresses I'm as you
should do and in this case the first way
of blowing your cover is pretty simple
so we take the same example again the
tree Bitcoin and the six Bitcoin
transaction but instead of sending money
and set instead of sending nine Bitcoin
two addresses i will use i was sent a
Bitcoin two addresses and send back the
change to addresses and out i already
own
so in this example the tribute point
addresses is the same as the one that
did receive the change they want this
could change and when I will use the one
this could change in another transaction
in the future i will also take other
addresses and painted to the node that
already contains addresses the number
two did the social number to blow your
cover is to give the same addresses to
multiple people so for example i want to
receive here a transaction from Joey
generation from a friend and a
transaction from david i'll give them
boat
I'll give them the same address of to
those three person so I give the same
addresses to that it to Fred and to joke
and they all gonna send me the money and
when sorry when I will reuse the money I
just receive i will also take it with
multiple addresses and be able to
correct to incorrect correlate all this
addresses into a single node what you
should have done is this is not this is
how not to blow your cover
so for each person you want to receive
money actually what you do is to
generate a new addresses because you can
generate as many addresses as you want
and you should generate at each time a
new addresses each time you make a
transaction and when you can spend their
money you receive will not paint each
other and we will you will not think all
the addresses you just a part of the
addresses and i will not be able to
merge all those node into one big note
containing a lot of addresses here and
what we're talking about Alwine that was
never open that mean that we're not the
first one to think about this concept
has been discussed in the white papers
and academic trip research a sense 2011
a good one a good paper about it is the
one from MIT about the clustering that
is a title is on the screen and also
there's a website that i didn't know
until that it tell me I think it's a
three months ago and called water Cloris
that did approximately the same things
but not in the same way so there are
clustering all the addresses together
but they're not giving the same
information
the problem with those tools are those
two achievement is for example for the
white paper the research I've been done
on the only a small part of the network
so they take a really really small part
of the Bitcoin transaction and they do
the research on it so it's not part of
all the bits all the Bitcoin
transactions have been done up-to-date
also proof-of-concept code is not
available
right at the of the the results are the
input is not available either and any
information about the concrete mythology
is not available either for water
explorer and it's a close source website
you can only query to the web so you
don't have any access to the raw data
here is not able to download it it's
only representing the note the tractor
protection nose was not grouping them
the transaction the movement / notes so
you won't see like for example so
lending money to enter God's and back
and forth
you're just see so throwed transaction
but the tagging is quite accurate on
this website so they did a really good
job on tagging but it's not able you
cannot have access to the database you
cannot have access to raw data you can
have anything it and it's closer so you
cannot like do whatever you want with
this
that's the reason why clusters there and
it's open its open source
it's free and the database will be
released it's already available
intolerant so it's a 2200 gigabyte of
that are representing all the addresses
that been seen in the network and all
the transaction regroup by notes into a
database you can query it and take
information as you want and we encourage
you to customize it to make millions of
query directly to the database and to
expand into something really really cool
so it's up to you now so a bit about
designing adjuster I it started with a
good intention a good coat designing and
everything and wasn't able to scale so i
have to scrap everything out and do
something quick and quick and like
really really efficient but not really
really really nice to see so the code is
pretty difficult to to follow what I've
been profiled and optimize over and over
and over so concept is pretty pretty
simple it's basic map that is public
it's only known addresses it's so if
you're presented in a graph it's easy
totally fit in memory
well why did somebody didn't do it
ready this is where the fun parts began
it then hitting a wall around a at this
point i was already accepted in the
conference which will release so i
started like a sunday afternoon at all
well I should begin my tools it will be
easy at the end of the day I'll have
something that will be working so i
started the blog take a traditional
black teach input calculate the Bitcoin
addresses put it in a graph and actually
this happened
yeah that pretty accurate so have been
accepted to talk presenting a tool that
doesn't work so have to do something
about it
so that's what we do surround be ok now
have to optimize the code and see
another method of calculating addresses
i did something that things to works but
all the addresses that generated that
exist in real life so have a problem
somewhere and finally I was able to do
something that the final recipe here was
out and need to computer 1 for the
crawler invited one for the hosting the
manga database and i'll create partial
graph r5000 blocks in vitamins emerged
me2 did all the big graph that is there
in the DB and while it's merging the
data in the DB enter in the full graph i
start again building the new graph
invite on while it's still inserting in
the DB and I repeat step 224 for a week
at least
but you don't have to do it again
because the database is now available
publicly that can just download it like
with the within the department so it's
approximately 20 gig of compressed text
in a target that you can download and
install so don't have to wait a week now
so the minimum system requirements or
big cluster is the fastest processor you
can afford 500 gig SSD and SSD really
really important you you're not gonna do
anything if stored in HD at 32 gig of
ram and 64 is way better by 10 64-bit
it's really important because you have
you will reach for and the four gig
limits in the 32-bit process a week of
free time as I said previously you don't
need that anymore since the database is
available on the internet and you can
download it but if you want to recreate
it from scratch you need a week of free
time and multiple type table flips the
tools that is we seem up-to-date 146
million different addresses or while
we see a proximate which exact more than
6 58 million different note are
presenting personal actor in the network
that make an average i refer to the tree
addresses per-user the largest the
largest node with the note with the most
wallet is with no surprise and guts so
at 12 million addresses is associated
with the MTX node and the total amount
of production so in our transaction DB
the number of Rho is 387 million rows in
the transaction database so that it
seems quite simple have the table
addresses
its symbol is the wallet addresses and
the node ID associated with this address
and in transaction you have the source
and destination no ID so where did the
money come from where did it go
you have the amount in BTC in Bitcoin
and converted in USD using the the
conversion rate at the time that
transaction have been made and you have
also date and the block where this
present this transaction happen so it's
now time for a small demo of the tools
so I sorry guys I did record video
because like the mall always fail so
it's going to be a video so i think i
just have to press next start ok so
first of all you need to search first an
advert so this time I'm going to search
for such as she dies addresses that you
don't see on the screen because I've
been crap it's there but not there and
you find an address associated to setup
sheet ice you punch it into been a bit
the cluster and you find it it takes
approximately approximately five minutes
to compute and you get a result so we
already have the results for you
so to prove it we're going to start for
the address that you get to google and
you see that is there and you'll see
also a lot of addresses that started one
dice that is a perfect for saturday she
dies so that it's indicating that the
clustering algorithm is quite efficient
for each node you have the total income
you have the total outcome in Bitcoin
and USD what we see here is there a
difference of 5,000 bitcoins so even if
there's two possibility won saturday's
only made five thousand Bitcoin money
out of it
are they already transferred the money
into other notes and you see the income
section so we can see where the money
came from so you see the node ID you see
how much money it is this note sent it
to the current notice the dice and us
ended coin and you see in harmony
transaction does it make
and you can also grab it by date so you
can see by date how many that such as
she dies did receive money so how many
transaction and the amount also in USD
so that's back in 2012
so you see that one day we receive a lot
of money and some transaction and you
can see also a goodbye amount you see
the distribution of the amount so you
see there's a lot of small transaction
are being made at to send money to this
note and you can see also the read data
of all the transaction associated with
that you also have the same stuff for a
spending a transaction so you see where
the money goes from several she dies two
other note you see also how many that
standardized send money per day and what
is the amount of money what we see here
it's around less than one cent per
transaction most of the transactions
that are been sent from socialize or
less than one send us because of the
concept of the game is that it's makes
sense and you can you can see also all
the addresses associated then after you
can just see random node and click on it
and to get information so we can browse
to node and note like just by clicking
on different link and it gave you this
information for the note that that you
select and give you also the income
group the spending details and the North
addresses
so this tool is now available and it is
not available available and get them so
you can run a clone it and you'll have
the full web interface if you don't know
the dbl so so for the second part of
this presentation what I want to do is
move two case studies and kind of give
you an idea of how you can use big
cluster to just learn more stuff about
the actors in a Bitcoin network and
because i'm a criminologist by trade
i'll be talking about fraudsters hackers
carding and other stuff like that so we
should be having a lot of fun x about 20
minutes and i'll show you that sometimes
yes it's true crime does pay and i'll
give you some examples of when that
happens so the first case study I want
to talk about is ransomware so we've all
heard of ransomware it's a type of virus
that encrypts the thousand your computer
and then ask you for money to get it
back and actually don't get your files
back you only get decryption keys to
decrypt the files that have been
encrypted on your computer and you know
these guys are really serious because
you know they're using military-grade
encryption to encrypt your files and so
the ransomware business is actually a
pretty good business to be in for those
interested and it does make a lot of
money in some cases and why doesn't make
a lot of money well first of all it's
because the ransomware guys only asking
for a small amount of money for each
victim sort of being kind of reasonable
and they're telling you all are your
files word $500 in many cases people are
going to say yes and they're going to
pay up the money everything is also that
they always have a time when these
ransomware and they tell you well you
have 48 or 72 hours to pay the ransom
otherwise the price of the ransom is
going to double or going to destroy the
descriptive the decryption keys and so
this means that the victims have to
learn what the hell bitcoins are how do
you buy bitcoins how do you pay someone
with bitcoins how do you decrypt your
files and we have a few hours to do so
and so this is why kind of ransomware
works and so why would be plus would be
useful to learn more about ransomware
well we can ask if we give it for
example a wallet that was where ransom
was paid we cannot be closer if it knows
about more wallets that are associated
to that one and see what other wallets
are into the same note as the ransom
wallet
and so we can ask bit closer to give us
for example time series analysis to see
how long the ransom or campaign lasted
how many victims they were how many and
how much revenues were generated through
this and so for this talk what we did is
we asked a few of our friends and
enforcement community for one of the
dresses that were related to to read
somewhere and I think the mall for sex
for sharing some and we got a sample of
about sixty addresses that we divided
into the kind of three very broad types
of ransomware and so I call the first
type 1 ransomware is here you have the
community of revenues of this ransomware
and what it shows is actually a pretty
successful ransomware which made about
611 thousand dollars in revenues and I
don't get the sense but it's still I
guess every penny counts when you're
when you're earning money and so what we
see here is actually kind of interesting
which this ransomware made about 1,100
victims over its lifespan and that's
about 20 victims per day and that's
about ten thousand dollars that were
earned every single day and I don't have
to tell you once again that this is with
very low cost in your infrastructure and
of course very little taxes to pay at
the end of the year and so and so here
we see that about eighty percent of the
revenues were generated between november
second in November 24th so most of the
money was done in within three weeks
which means that if you want to react to
these ransomware campaigns you have to
be very quick and very efficiently from
to stop it from propagating and
ransomware can be very personal and the
one that i just presented is actually is
is actually for me a research center
that i was working at was actually hit
by this room somewhere and so we weren't
sure if we're going to pay for to get
the files back or not of course there
were no backups at the research center
the security people weren't sure we
should pay because it would encourage
more crime and finally we decided you
know we're just gonna do it and so I
went to the local bitcoins com find
someone who is going to sell me bitcoins
really rapidly because there's this time
we're going down and I go and meet this
guy who looks you know kind of like the
guy having a slight over here and he's
just in sweatpants and he's just waiting
at our local a Bitcoin nbc4 people have
been hit with ransomware and just
selling them bitcoins at a very high
price
and so apparently you can also profit
from a very profitable business if
you're into the bitcoins and if you're
wondering and the blue the blue the blue
box over there that's me paying a ransom
at about two years ago and so there's
other types of ransom of course the type
to ransomware is also very very good at
making money the second case is a case
that made about the hundred and seventy
thousand dollars us but this one was
kind of different from the first one
first of all because it lasted a lot
longer if it was active for a couple of
months and the other interesting thing
is also that it never stops making money
it just keeps on making more and more
money and I guess is that this room are
actually continued well after at the end
of this graph but they kind of changed
our wallets we kind of lost track of
them
so this is perhaps kind of more
sophisticated cameras from you that you
could perhaps be traced with bitcoins
maybe the force that because there was
coming a few years later and so they
switched up the tactics and how they
were using their bitcoins and finally we
have the type 3 ransomware and these are
the guys that are really sophisticated
that really frustrated me because we
only had one payment one day with one
victim and so that meant that they were
smart enough not to bring all of their
money together in one transaction only
use as much as saying one input per
transaction and this means that we could
still use but bit closer to follow the
money around but we can't just I can
just you know amazing by telling you how
much money they've made in a couple of
weeks the second case they want to talk
about today is online enlisted markets
now i'm sure everyone here has heard of
these online illicit markets their own
farms their own chat rooms
they've been around for decades and you
can buy pretty much any listed products
or services online on them over the past
five years has been a new generation of
online real estate markets and they're
called capital markets i'm sure some of
you may have heard of silk road
yeah at least one person that's good so
well these these new generation the
script markets are really interesting
because they're a lot more secure than
the old- and markets for a number of
reasons and one of these reasons that
they're using technology to help them
secure themselves and so they're going
to be using pgp keys for communications
there can be using the Tor network
whether that secure network
and always talk about it but at least it
gives you more security and of course
they're gonna use bitcoins for their
payments and at first script Americans
were really into drugs so he was kind of
a place we could go online buy drugs and
get it you know shit by the mail to your
own house but over the past few years
that they've actually diversified a lot
and right now we have about fifty fifty
percent for listings that are for drug
related items and the other half is for
something else completely different
we're talking about carding hacking
financial fraud lots of services if you
want to buy a proxy for by your netflix
account for cheap they have them for
like five dollars so what's a very good
offers on the script markets and one of
their main feature is that the customers
here you have an animus customer don't
actually pay the vendors directly what
they do is they take their money and
they pay the marketplace and they put
into escrow and when they put into
escrow the market is going to hold onto
this money until you receive the good or
service you've purchased and once you do
receive it then the money is transferred
all the way to the vendor and what this
means is that if the crypto markets are
very smart about how they manage these
bitcoins they're going to have one
wallet for each of their customer and
they're going to separate everyone's
money and not put it all in one big pot
and you can guess from what I'm going
why I'm talking to you today is that is
not the case and so using the classical
we can all actually do is going to bring
all these wallets together and follow
the script markets and try to understand
a bit more about how to behave and so
I'm gonna give you a few numbers and
show you kind of what you can do with
this
and the first thing that's kind of
interesting to me is using the flusher
to learn how many transactions are
encrypted markets and so here you have
the case of so-called won the first trip
to market that was active between
2011-2013 and what we see over here is
that number of transaction sharply rose
/ times we went from about 500
transactions per day all the way through
three thousand transactions per day so
once again it's not this big thing that
was selling millions of transactions per
day but so interesting to see how many
people were involved how many people
were putting money into this this silk
road to buy drugs and other stuff as
well perhaps in learn more interesting
is when you look at the revenues
how many bitcoins fluid through these
escrow payments and here you see once
again that the the numbers about
quadrupled over the years so they went
from under two hundred thousand dollars
all the way up to a hundred thousand
dollars at the end of life of silk
road's lifespan and at the end the graph
ends because that's when law enforcement
just shut down Silk Road and its really
interesting if you look at the Silk Road
page on big cluster you're gonna see
that it's generating a lot of money and
then just one day just stops and goes
down to almost zero from one day to the
other and here when you look at this we
see that we generated over all about a
hundred 96 million dollars
the FBI was saying when they began 1.2
billion dollars and then they realize
that this was totally false and they
brought down the estimate to about 240
million dollars so we're pretty close to
what the FBI has estimated from the sea
servers and I guess we're missing a few
wallets from this because well nothing's
perfect but we still get a very reliable
idea of how much money and how many
people were involved into this into this
community and what I've presented so far
has been very macro level but it's also
possible to go more the micro level and
to look more detail about the customers
of so-called who are these people and
what we're buying and the one thing that
was of interest to me was looking at
well how much are these people paying
with their making a purchase and you see
here that about ninety-one percent of
all the transactions all the money that
was put into bitcoins was under five
hundred dollars so probably these people
were many cases buying small amount of
drugs maybe social supply but still from
what we see from the number of
transactions it was fairly small
transactions they were still actually
transactions that were raised over a
thousand dollars and these are for like
kilos of cocaine or kilos of weed
because you could buy such big amounts
on the script markets and these are very
small we have to remember that even
though it's a very small proportion
itself thousands and thousands of
transactions if not more and when you
look at the revenues while you realize
that when you just added the revenues
and you see where the revenues were
coming from about half of the revenues
were coming from these small
transactions so under five hundred
dollars but the pie chart really chart
changes and you see that these big
transactions were buying massive amount
either of drugs or whatever else are
very important about a third of the
revenues are generated and so when
you're trying to understand how these
markets work what are people buying it's
actually not only just small quantities
of drugs and small amounts of whatever
hacking software they're going to be
buying something some things that are
very expensive and that's something that
I found in my own research in the past
in my own research in the past what we
did before we had the cluster is look at
feedbacks so most people when they
bought something left feedbacks kinda
like you do an amazon and ebay and here
you have some guy talking about the
purchase of coke at that he made and
apparently his coach had a strong bubble
gum taste and apparently that's very
good because he gave it a five star out
of five and and so you have a price you
have a date you know the product and so
that kind of lets you kind of add it all
up together and kind of multiply the
number of feedbacks but the amount that
you pay for and I guess you kinda size
and scope of Krypton markets and that's
kind of what i did in the past and
that's what many colleagues of mine have
done also in the past and if you look at
silk road and here i wanted to show you
kind of the differences between big
question what we had before
perhaps one of the most exhaustive study
looking at feedbacks was made by two
guys Susskind Christian that was
published back in 2015 and did an
amazing job of bringing all of this data
from many many crypto markets together
to kind of find what is the overall size
and scope of crypto markets and here you
see at the bars are the kristin kristin
data and the line is the big question
data and you see that we see a lot more
bitcoins going through the script
American this is only for silk road one
that we saw in the feedbacks and now you
could either hypothesize that actually
feedbacks don't tell the whole story
that there's actually a lot more drugs
being sold on Silk Road then you could
see with the feedbacks but my own guess
is that actually people that so-called
be around forever
it was this magic community where
everyone was fun and everyone like
everyone like the every each other and
so people actually when they were buying
for example hundred dollars worth of
drugs that would put in two hundred
dollars selling themselves well just
keep a hundred in there and when I need
more drugs i'll just go back and we'll
be there for me and so my guess is
actually the difference can be explained
and because there's this gap where
people were leaving money on Silk Road
at the end of this graph but you don't
see that the police shut down Silk Road
the dream ended and so they were a lot
more capital markets are launched later
in 2014 and here you have a a
combination of the revenues from all of
these crypto markets brought together i
think there's about six of them and what
you see is that people i think we're a
lot more scared to leave money on
Krypton markets because they thought
they can be shut down at any point in
time and this is why you see that the
correlation between our data and systems
and Christians data it's much closer and
that graph and very interestingly you
see and some time intervals especially
on the Left there's actually more money
according to the feedback then we could
find in bed cluster and one of the
things that I've suspected was that they
were fake feedbacks I know this is very
shocking but that the crypto markets
were actually generating fade feedbacks
to make it look as though there were a
lot of activities on their credit
markets and so this would suggest at
least on the left you see there's more
feedback and revenues is that these
markets were generating these feedbacks
to make it look as though there were a
lot of money though it did increase over
time and we ended up about where we were
about eight hundred thousand dollars a
day in total revenues and so because we
want to save some time for questions i'm
going to go very quickly over the main
takeaways for this talk and I think that
the one thing to remember is that the
Bitcoin network never sleeps
it's always collecting money the
blockchain is always there and when
you're looking at what success can
Kristin did they did an amazing job but
it took a lot of time of energy and a
lot of money to collect all of those
feedbacks matter and i were just two
guys playing with the blockchain and we
managed to replicate some of the results
not perfectly but still some of the
results with very very little resources
and in a much limited timeframe and so I
think it's very important to notice how
important how useful the blockchain can
be and one of the most interesting
feature i think is that you can go back
to the future if you will which means
that even though you never knew that
so-called existed when it was online
even though you didn't care about silk
robe when he was on line five years
later 20 years later you can go back in
time if you have at least one wallet
from silk road you can go in
investigate what was happening there
where people spending where people
receiving and you can you don't need
your not limited by time the feedbacks
once the pages taking down there is no
way to get back it's gone we're not
going to get back with the bitcoins
however it's very interesting that you
can just go back in time and just play
with the data as much as you want and
finally I think it's very important to
stress that you always have to validate
no matter what finding you find with big
first you have to find alternative
sources of data to validate your results
if you look at my so-called one data for
example the headline could say well you
know
silkroad was twice as big as we thought
before I don't think that was the case
but you could still use you need to
validate whatever results you get and
assembled around somewhere if it says a
campaign and a single date maybe they
just change your wallets and you have to
go and find answers elsewhere and so
what's next for a bit cluster basically
having real-time automated database of
dating so right now you have to do it
manually so it's maybe more of a pain
and we're hoping to have that down so
it's pretty much live so when you're
running it on your own computer kind of
have it up-to-date adult time the
labeling of notes right now all the
nodes are only known for their numbers
and so it may be difficult to remember
that 2146 562 is silk road it's easier
to have names and also have some visual
graph so basically just you know
point-and-click and just click on a node
and see where the money is coming from
where it's going kinda more visual
aspect to the tool and finally perhaps a
hosted version of the tool i'm saying
here if we get a quantum computer at
some point it's just it's very very
memory intensive and cpu intensive and
we could host any query that you guys
would have but we only have like eight
queries at the same time so it's a very
limited tool so we'll see what happens
with that in the future and so the URL
everyone has been dying to to see so the
tool is online databases online as well
you can download all it's free and open
source and bit dash cluster calm and
that's it for us if you have any
questions would love to hear them and
share what we've learned
thank you
maybe if we can open the lights so we
can see if someone has their hands
raised
Mike thank you so well he started giving
ya tonight and I start to see you guys
mentioned that because of the difference
in the FBI estimate the size of silk
road and your big cluster estimate there
was like maybe actually like 50 million
dollars in escrow is it possible that
later markets were just stupider and had
fewer wallets going on in that you know
people still kept the same amount of
money in escrow
it's possible i would say that there's
been so many crypto markets that were on
and off for the past few years that I
would never leave any deposit in any
quarter market because it could be taken
out anytime I didn't talk about exit
scams where the market is still
everyone's money from the deposits so i
really doubt that there's a lot of money
being hauled in these deposits what
people usually do is if you're buying
four hundred dollars you put in a
hundred dollars pay with it and you're
out so i guess that's why you see that
the the smaller difference between the
two out
thank you and welcome hey so I know that
doing computation with large graphs is a
really hard problem that so I think it's
great that you guys could get this to
run at all on such a gigantic graph and
have you been thinking about any
interesting ways of optimizing it so
that'll do the computations you want
faster and can we move into my key
well I'm yeah there's a way that you can
remove some notes that are not really
interesting usually to make a query on
really really really big note is
approximately like treat like treatment
for silk robe so it's not that long to
do that the definition what is long as
when we hosted the same queries made
over and over and over so what we're
going to do if we want to host the tools
it so we're going to put some caching so
for example like it never changes in
like at least a block for at least 10
minute so we may be able to reuse that
I've been already computed to show the
same result of multiple user so we're
going to do something related to cashing
to possibly be able to host somewhere
for the graph and now this is the main
problem is the number of notes that's
still there
so even though the jigsaw goes them will
not be able to scale it on f 58 million
of the nodes as so by now don't have any
situation I think we're going to be
limited like to to browse until three or
four level so i may not be enough to
bypass the laundering scheme but it may
be able to depending on the skin but and
optimize on the research into the graph
i don't think that going to be possible
but to host the tools we gonna put some
caching so because the same color is
made it over and over and over again so
we don't have to compute and just give
you back to weasel that it in real time
I'm thanks for the talk
so it wasn't really the focus of your
talk but I moving from just nodes with
numbers to actual people I seems like
it'd be the actual value in this so have
you guys actually talked to anyone or
started doing that
whoo yeah I think that's the whole point
the tools at have the opportunity that
you have to the organized one addresses
out of 1,000 or 100 or 1000 hundred
thousand so main advantage of the
clustering is do you have to
finally one addresses to map it to a
real identity and then you map app whole
bunch of justice to an identity but yeah
i will show you the main concern here is
to put identity on notes and that's
what's the next step is going to do and
you may want to go with wallet explore
and see because they're tagging an
argument sprite quite good and then you
can use the address that you find
associated to note and punch it punch it
into the cluster have a more information
about those at person is it it is a fine
is it is answering the question
yeah okay I think you also can you talk
a little bit more about the two issues
you mentioned mid talk about the change
or about having multiple people get into
one because it seems like that didn't
quite understand how that helps you
didn't I understand like multiple into
one you can tell the private keys fungus
in person like why is there a problem if
multiple people give to the same same
address
yeah the problem is for example
introduction a you associate address ANB
to the same person and then check it
send back to change to address eight and
then if you reuse addresses that you
receive the change with for example d
and e i will be able to tell that you
own a be de okay if I person-centered to
the same all that is for example hit all
of five person-centered to address aight
i may use the output difference the
first output of the first production
that I've been sent to address a within
contractor of address and ABC the second
one with a de the third one with a FG
and then I take away more addresses that
it it should be and that will be able to
regroup all of them together is clear is
okay perfect i just wanna make sure
answer the question sometime because as
you may know it's not my first language
and english thanks for the talk I just
wonder have you take a look at like
tumblr services like Bitcoin fog and
like I've always kinda wanted to know
where that money ends up you know
is it going more in or is it coming out
and going into cash from there are no I
usually I'll explain it on there more
and more and technical way and then
after if they're like habits are trend
maybe they will be able to to answer and
the main difficulty is when you put it
on tumblr there's a lot of transaction
are being made so but it's really
complicated to crawl into this graph and
to find apply like to find a note is
there there's the laundromat the
Landry's king and you have to find a way
of seeing like for example one would get
quite a bit put into this game and
crawling to all the transaction at
different levels of crawling the graph
and find a place where all this money
came back into OneNote less the
commission of the tumblers so it's quite
difficult because you need to know that
the Commissioner tumblers and you need
to crawl doing in with like a training
algorithm to all the graphics really
really exhausted their cpu and resources
exhausted so by now it's a bit difficult
to to to find it
the only way that we may find it is for
example if they're laundering schemes
only like two or three transaction
before sending back to the note that i
don't think they do it there didn't they
do it like a lot of lot a lot
introduction before they send you back
the money
yeah it's it's it's a good system
actually but well depend good
define good but yes it's working you
might have already answered the question
right now sorry we're out of time for
questions but if you'd like to follow up
I'm sure David Matthew would like to
take it offline