really use that I'm looking at your
glory
what's your name camera camera and hi
how are you like me are you on New
Yorker yes
oh excellent every city in the world
my first question is as an award-winning
author columnist and journalists you
certainly know something about
copyrights how do you feel about the
protection of intellectual property such
as music are all copyrights created I
think that's a really good question i
think it can unpack and more than one
way so the first is like are all our
copyrights in all domains of the same
and i think that there's certainly like
different characteristics they have like
I I've always thought that on the
insistence that books should be subject
to the same rules as like movies or
video games is kind of a self-limiting
move like if we have this weird
relationship with books that's really
romantic like we like we've had them for
longer than we've had copyright we and
have them for longer than we've had
money we've had them for longer than we
have printing or even paper right and so
you know getting rid of books it's like
it's a tough thing like people have this
like if you want to show a civilization
and decline in your student movie to
show like a pile of books on fire and so
people dislike romantic attachment
that's really good for the publishing
industry I think people buy books just
as like status objects or aspirational
objects they fill their bookcases to
show who they are you know there's a
reason like you know writers are always
photographed against a wall of someone
else's books you know this is who I am
and so once we say oh well it's just an
article of Commerce the most important
thing of it is like its regulatory
regime then I think we especially like
with ebooks we say all we know you all
those traditional contours you had with
books like the right to sell it or give
it away or or or whatever all those are
like no longer around because it's an
e-book and you click through an
agreement in that agreement as you know
regular by copyright
I like the most dangerous thing i can
imagine as people believe in you
right because then it's oh you know we
it turns out that books are just like
candy bars like who cares if we throw
away we don't need to buy them
aspirationally and that would be like a
kind
click disaster for the publishing
industry so that part of it and then and
then so I don't think they're all
equivalent like I think crossword
puzzles and t-shirt designs and books
are different and like obviously
different and also been officially
different teacher those industries and
then the other pieces like who does
copyright apply to and what's it for
and I think that copyright if you look
at its history has always been conceived
of and executed as an industrial
regulation we said to like the industry
what do you do with books how do you
decide what's fair and what's not fair
and we've taken that and made it into a
law and I'm industrial relations cool i
think that's great i like I wish the
finance industry was regulated with that
be awesome but the the test that we use
to figure out whether you're in the
industry varies from regulations
regulations you can't just apply a dust
regulation and everyone right like so
you know with copyright it was like if
you're making her handling a copy
you're in the entertainment industry
because like a book has a printing press
in its history and a movie as a film lab
and you know you can't just like make a
copy of a book in your kitchen you know
it's it's a it's it's an industrial
activities and I'm sorry this is a party
it's a question that has a big answer
and and the and and so the what's
happened is that like copying has become
subject to a kind of hyperinflation it's
no longer a good mark of whether or not
you're in the entertainment industry
it's now a thing that we do a million
times before breakfast is like the
internet works by making copies and you
know you can imagine like we had
hyperinflation and something like us two
million dollars to buy a friend lunch
right like buying a sandwich wouldn't
make you a bank and like using the
internet doesn't make you a publisher
any if the idea is that like in order to
use copyright are or to use the internet
you have to understand copyright then we
fail because like most people don't
understand copyright most people never
will
the problem with like kids using the
internet is not the kids have failed to
get a four-year law degree in a
three-year specialization in the end
in copyright it's that copyright like
we've decided the kids have to be
experts in that stuff to use that they
never will there's no rule that is on
the one hand like complex and technical
enough that you can use it to tick you
know for water and universal to license
the harry potter copyrights to make
harry potter theme park and simple
enough that like a killer mom's basement
in yonkers can use it to make a very
potter fan site without breaking the law
ok so anonymity is an increasingly
controversial topic since the rising of
the Tor network do you think anonymity
on the web should always be protected if
so why
well i think that in the u.s.
constitutional tradition there's like
good reasons to support my unconscious
we're running out of time here and
that's another just gnarly question i
think that it in the contents top text
of the US Constitution there
the idea of anonymity has been protected
not because it's good but because it's
better than the alternative that there
are things that you can only say when
you're anonymous and if we think about
the history of social change in our
world in our like living memory there
are people alive today remember what is
illegal for a black person in a white
person to marry or when it was illegal
to be gay
you're alive today and you remember when
it's illegal to smoke weed
it will probably not be illegal to smoke
weed by the time you're old enough to
write and the way that we got there is
that people were able to decide the time
and manner of the disclosure about their
activity two other people in such a way
that we were able to create a normative
conversation between us about what was
right and what was wrong whether rules
are fair unfair and unless you think
that like now in 2016 we got it right
like there's no more rules that need to
change then and you know like when in 50
years your grandchildren will say
grandpa how was it that in 2016 you
solve the social contract and we haven't
to make any changes in our social rules
you have to believe that there's like
people that you love and know and care
about who are today living in shame and
who are not able to do something that's
important to them and the only way they
can recover from that and improve their
lives as they can choose the moment at
which they disclose their alliance their
activity there their condition and if we
don't have the opportunity to be
anonymous then they can choose that and
then all of those people that you love
and care about will will lose that
opportunity for one more
it's okay you're so sure so you
certainly play a huge role in the free
software movement and technology
community as a whole
what interests you about technology and
what motivates you to be a part of it
well I think that um you know there's
like the seductive promise that you can
have deterministic machines or you can
like say to them you must do X & Y Z and
this order and they'll do it perfectly
of course anyone has written software
knows that it never works that way but
it feels like it must and there's a
something very exciting better that's
always a really interesting intellectual
challenge and then you know the amazing
thing like i said the top before about
new facts on the ground right the fact
that we can encrypt things that's a new
fact on the ground so I thought I might
let my phone up there and then but we
have another new facts on the ground
which is that out we can make a
universal machine right this was the
thing we never could do before before
like touring and von Norman if you want
to tabulate an election you built an
election tabulating calculator and if
you want to calculate ballistic tables
you built a ballistic tabulating
calculator you wouldn't like just sort
of retrofit went on to the other anymore
than you would like oh I we need to go
underwater why don't we see love this
car turn it into a submarine but we have
these new universal architectures right
where we can build a computer that can
explain that can run every program we
can express express and symbolic logic
and this is amazing and like even
problematic because now we have like
printers that can run malware but what's
amazing about this is if you improve a
computer to make your heart monitor
better you approve a computer that will
make cars better and refrigerators and
angry birds and so now we have this
thing where everything that anyone does
to improve
any part of human endeavor makes all
parts of human endeavor better and so
like lot more exciting thing could we be
interested
alright thank you so on the screen over
there we have our other is major
interview to collide fantasticar use
looks I can hear you just fine community
to excellent you really are going to use
my time in a way that's a bit unorthodox
today please bear with me I'd like to
begin by congratulating Cameron flack
the other contest winner i really liked
your article Cameron noted your mind to
his actions inspire me to your brother
working hard
ok he's nice and he's giving me one of
those
okay now I'm gonna give it that I want
to use my five minutes because the world
because you don't have to get the chance
ok now i will call the matrix and I
think about half hours keyboard and I
can't help imagine Trinity typing wake
up america the illusion has you listen
to me for a little bit the gravity of
our ongoing situation is tremendous and
must think about it I have a degree in
my environmental science from state
university but I shouldn't be the first
to tell you that have leaked from the
precipice humanity is creating careening
towards real self destruction by now we
have a manufacturer to mask their arms
all over the world below the earth into
slavery and in the same world you're
suffering morally physically at the
hands of human evolution and discovery
this is a world in which we are just 80
as exceptional as you comfortably that
idea American exceptionalism is a
suffering miserable an absurd idea
you need only look around last week with
lies opulence and broken people next
week
nothing but seeing the tension that we
are living through that are breaking the
economic system is failing and our
rights and our dignity and human beings
beings
our government our governments around
the world matter what happens is your
head throb proverbial ball in this case
that's the only experiment called but we
must not succumb to the Malays humans on
planet or my message today that we can
make these more than just an ocean we
can reject radical nationalism we can
reject privateering we can reject the
capitalist vanity I important to love
one another if you have her
blacklivesmatter excellent matters
mechanism matters LGBT community matters
and all poor and working people of the
world matter now today our nations flag
stands a policy where it stands for
Socrates reality so I'm gonna burn one
as a protest against or standing instead
of course load the ok alright i was
going to say I saw a smoke detector
behind you
alright let's he's burning a flag what
ya think
oh that's intense
it's taking longer than he thought it
was from anyone who's ever tried to burn
off like this class don't want to go
here goes
there's two minutes left in the but it's
going out kind of thing you want to
practice their art actually do buddy and
flammable and inflammable what kind of
difficult for you look well I as not an
American flag has never really met much
to me and I'm not much about flight
person so I think as a protected speech
that feels completely legitimate
ok alright alright thank you do you have
any questions you have any questions or
anything I mean no I I pretty much agree
with everything i'm not an American so
the flag doesn't mean much to me and I i
support your right to get that feels to
be like a form of totally legitimate
expressive speech the First Amendment
protected right now I not great but I i
also think I priori the idea that that
burning the flag feels like the most
obviously symbolic form expresses beach
you can imagine
yeah like the fact i can't imagine is
sure did was gonna ask original okay
shoot
no I was that real leaders conference
earlier this year and no drops obviously
had made a statement about voting in the
election he said that he suggests swing
states like miami florida voting for
anybody other than Hillary Clinton
essentially the Democratic candidate
vote for the Republicans how do you feel
about this is that so I don't get about
30 corner but I I give money to burn and
i will probably give money to Hillary
and the reason because I because
foreigners can give money to your
candidates they just can't vote for them
and the reason I'm going to do it is
because my understanding having looked
on and off in the US for a couple of
decades now is that the administrative
branch is where the rubber meets the
road for the daily lives of people in
extremely profound ways and it's that
it's that like the elephant in the room
right and so like it may be that you can
hardly get a credit card between Al Gore
GW use policy prescriptions but when Al
Gore didn't take office and GW did he
pointed 40,000 civil servants top-level
civil servants who are all party
hardliners right like the people who get
elected are in the middle the people who
get patrons appointments are on the
extreme right and if you want to think
about what the 40,000 people were going
to be running the military the cops the
welfare regime the Environmental
Protection Agency I we're going to be
doing labor abuse investigations going
to be running the CDC in an era of Zika
and mass pandemic and climate change
we're going to be running FEMA like we
saw what happens when you take a stable
master and put him in charge of FEMA
right like these are like these are
legitimate real no fooling immediate
utilitarian instrumental differences
between the candidates and the next four
years could be like a Hieronymus Bosch
painting because as establishment as the
establishment wing of the dems are and
holy shit are the establishment day at
least will appoint people who are
moderately competence to do those jobs
and who are you know purely like
creatures of political patronage and
corruption they will actually show up
for work and do their goddamn jobs &
hire people who know what they're
doing and some of the things they do
will be bad but it'll be bad because
they choose to do something bad
not because they are off like you know
getting up
reiki massage while the floods were you
know well that the floods were
overtopping the levees in New Orleans
that makes a huge difference and i think
that like if we're going to live to
fight another day yeah i agree like the
reason I fight to free the internet
isn't because information was before you
give a shit about information its
instruction i forgot about the internet
because every single fight we're gonna
have about gender equality and the
environment and nuclear proliferation
every one of those issues is going to be
won or lost on the internet that's why
the internet matters and we're gonna
have a playing field on which we can
fight these battles in four years then
we're going to need to have people who
are borderline competent running the
administration administering the country
because it's a big complicated machine
so i had a vote
it does matter because I live in
California so we're going to let
Democrats divided vote I would vote for
a Democrat in this election because
Trump is a different kind of dumpster
fire to all the dumpster but I think I
wonderful thank you thank you guys so
much
thanks see the smoke alarm behind you
and you said you're going to like a flag
I thought there was gonna be a problem
immediately
alright good nice to talk to you leo
take care of yourself well