one away awesome alright so hello this
is talking about open source of our labs
and this is going to be not necessarily
reverse engineering but basically
malware analysis and then automation
thereof
so who am i I'm the director of research
innovation at threat connect i'm on the
research team and the basic you know
premise of my talk is is malware
analysis labs but i need to answer the
question why do I need a malware
analysis lab so their number of reasons
why you would need a malware analysis
lab so if you're doing our analysis as
from a research perspective you need to
have an automated Mauer and also system
to work on your samples because there's
a problem scaling in the world that we
live in there's more people producing
malware than there are people you know
analyzing malware so you need to have
something that automates the many of the
grunt work components of automated
malware analysis or malware analysis so
what you see on the the right side this
is from Lenny Seltzer's stages of our
analysis and so at the bottom you can
see there is fully automated analysis
and then you have static properties
analysis and then interactive behavior
analysis so this is actually either
instrumenting a binary or using a
debugger and stepping through the code
and then at the top in difficulty level
so we're actually rising a difficulty
level here you have a manual code
reversing so this is using either pro or
hopper something like that and looking
at the assembly code and understanding
what the capabilities of our are so what
we're going to talk about today is
actually not the two top harder by
stages we're going to talk about the top
but the the bottom two and these are
ones that you can completely automate so
one of the things by the way is that the
you know automated our analysis systems
traditionally you know people think of
them as
behavioral and not static but actually
you can do static analysis as well you
get that kind of for free will see that
moment so what can you do with automated
our analysis system so you can use it to
enhance a threat intelligence program if
you have you know if your organization
has like threatened tell people like
they're going to be consumers of the day
that comes out of an automated malware
analysis system there's also the concept
it's a very new concept of a hunt team
where you have things that go bad or
things that alert in your organization
and then you're you know incident
response ER incident responders will go
and look at what happened so hunt team
is actually proactive
so what they do is not kind of the same
thing that in and I our team will do but
they're not responding to an incident
they're actually digging into different
things in your organization and looking
for malware and looking for adversaries
so you any team like that if they find a
piece of malware that hasn't been
alerted they need to have some system
they can do the you know the easy stuff
for them also network defense so if you
have a network defense system and you
know there's many different flavors
thereof but when you have something that
does network intrusion detection many
need systems will have a way to carve
files out of the network traffic and so
you need to have something that will
look automatically at those different
files so that's one position that an ama
will have also if you have a email
server you have a lot of attachments and
so the attachments that come into your
organization need to be analyzed using
an AMA and then finally host-based
intrusion detection systems and so you
know other this is the kind of medical
term but endpoint protection so many
endpoint protection systems will report
a binary back to their mothership and so
that binary needs to be analyzed if it's
not detected by that his system
and then finally this is the thing that
I use that everything for because i love
our analysis and it's a lot of fun so my
talk today is about our analysis as a
process but entry points so you have a
number of different things that you can
analyze and so I've picked the top four
I think of entry points into the system
and I file is the obvious one so these
are executables it also encompasses a
java jar files anything that is
executable in a system it also
encompasses documents so you have rich
text files you know word docs excel you
also have PDF and then the next entry
point i'm talking about is URL so you
have drive-by URLs you also have
download urls for malware payloads and
so these need to be analyzed in a
different way than a file you also have
pcap and so we'll talk about what pcap
is but basically this is network traffic
so you may have a small amount of
network traffic that you want to analyze
and analyzed for malware analysis and
then Matt a memory image so when you run
malware a really good way to find out
what it's doing and what it's thinking
is basically looking at the memory image
while it's running so each one of these
particular entry points in our analysis
process has an open source tool you can
use their and and by the way I don't
want to start any fights as far as like
which tools better than another
I just chose the ones that I use and so
when you're analyzing a file i use cout
sandbox and there are no paid solutions
but the thing is for this talk I'm only
going to talk about things that are
either a open source or be something
that you can login to for free and so
you know there's some systems that i'm
going to talk about you may need to
actually register for but they are free
and then thug this is probably the least
famous of all these tools but thug is
a low interaction honey client that dot
looks at urls and analyzes the URL bro
is a network security monitoring tool
and there's a nuanced and what I'm
talking about today because bro can be
used as a traditional network security
monitoring tool to look at in a broad
network capture i'm going to talk about
it as a malware analysis tool will get
into the details of that in a moment and
then volatility volatility is a memory
analysis tool so first let's look at KU
sandbox and actually earlier today I
included a lot of very new information
in my talk so we're going to look at
some malware that is very fresh within
the past two weeks so the coup sandbox
part of this talk is has some of the
older stuff and so I'm going to kind of
you know move quickly over this to get
into the really the new stuff in my talk
so I a sandbox if you don't know what it
is is a controlled environment where the
you can execute execute malware and
controlled environment and then observe
its behavior and I you at the same time
you're able to run that particular file
thru static analysis tools so one of the
things that dynamic analysis you know
has is that it's very sexy
you get a lot of uh you know network
indicators out of it so I kind of think
that you know because it's sexy it's
something that you probably already know
so I'm going to talk more right now and
i'm going to highlight some of the
things that you can get from the static
analysis components of cuckoo
so this is actually from a mac OS piece
of malware that this was and you may
have heard of this event but there is a
there's a torrent downloader called
transmission and the 2.90 version of
transmission was actually Mac malware
the adversary head in you know basically
pound the trend you know transmissions
systems and so transmission was serving
this particular piece of our so when I
want to reverse engineer this malware
one of the things that you need to do
before you get to that stage is
understand what Packer is being used by
the adversary and so I have tools that i
can look at this piece of our and find
out what packers being used but i always
like to find a shortcut and cheat so I
ran this through strings and you can see
here that it's been packed with upx and
in addition it's been packed with a
particular upx version so I of course
this data can be forged by the hour
author but you know i'm just going to
say like maybe they're not so I'm going
to try and I've shortcut my analysis
process so i know the packer that I need
to use to look at this piece of malware
and find the unpacked source code and so
if you don't know what a packer is so a
packer is a weight of two packaged
software and it's either encoded or
encrypted and so the when you run that
when when you run a pact binary through
a disassembler you're only going to get
the assembly code for the packer you're
not going to get the actual executed
code because that's actually contained
in a encoded or encrypted area of the PE
file so you need to know what packer it
is and then run it through a non packer
and then analyzed the unpacked binary so
again this is the same binary and i
consider AV detection zaz a type of
static analysis because you're not
looking at the behavior of the Mallory
looking at the signatures and so one of
the things that is very good about AV
detection some AV engines do actually
have very highly you know targeted
signatures and so I you run your binary
through that and you may get a head
start as to what this thing is that
you're looking at and you can basically
Google this so this is key Ranger a and
so
you can get from the Navy detection a
head start on what it is that you want
to analyze so I'm gonna kind of change
lanes here and this is actually data
about a PE file we were just looking at
a mock Oh binary for mac OS and now
we're going to look at windows binary
and so windows binary has certain
features of it
student static features that you can
analyze and so one of the things is a pc
sections and so this is the rsr
c-section and because it's malware if it
were a you know a benign binary the
sections may actually correspond to
things that are correct or usable but
sometimes like malware authors will just
make things up and so the rsrc may not
actually be a resource section it may be
something else in our author wants to do
but you can take an md5 of that section
using a sandbox and then you can take
this section you can pivot around in
data sets in
I you know other malware that you've
collected you can see what this section
refers to that is the same as other
pieces of malware that you've previously
previously collected and so I found
their 52 files that are similar to this
one and so now i can then take those 52
files and compare and find other things
that are the similar and see if there's
any like you know thread that connects
these with a previous piece of malware
and then therefore find figure out like
what I'm our family it is etc etc and so
also resources or resources or another
one so this is the RT underscore version
and I you know taking the the shock to
be six of this particular resource I
find 99 files that are the same as the
PE that i'm looking at as my target so
resources and sections are very similar
and this is this is actually really cool
technique by the way so what you're
looking at here is the compilation or
linking timestamp of the PE file so
p file will have a timestamp this can be
stomped on by the adversary so it could
say like zero I've seen that a lot so it
will be you know january first nineteen
seventy but if they don't you have the
time stamp that they compiled and Link
the binary and so what you can do is you
can compare that timestamp to the time
that something was submitted to like
malware or virus total or any of these
things that you can submit files to and
adversaries submit files to these
systems to see if the system is able to
flag it as bad and so as you can see you
know this was a 941 and 34 seconds and
then it was submitted 942 and 47 seconds
on it is i would say impossible for this
to go and infect someone and come back
so I what you get here is I know the
submitter to virustotal of this
particular file and so from now on I can
watch the submitter hash at virustotal
and find every single file that this
malware authors submits and I know that
it's bad so cool sandbox comes in a
number of flavors it has plain-vanilla
this is the current stable version
there's a next generation right now
release candidate one of two point i was
out there is also cool modified which
has a bunch of features that will go
into in just a moment
soku modified does normalization of
files and registry paths this is
actually really important and i'm going
to talk about this in just a moment
it also does 64-bit analysis service
monitoring has an extended API you can
do tour for outbound network connections
and it has a male here integration but
why is normalization important so if
you're doing data analysis across a lot
of data sets and so some of the people
that you work with like you know in the
malware analysis community i get data
from other people that do our analysis
and so they may actually be using a
different flavor of windows for their vm
than i am and so the top and the bottom
and I apologize don't remember which one
is windows 7 and
XP but one of these strings is windows 7
and the other is XP and so obviously
these you can't do analysis across a lot
of sand boxes with this but if you
normalize the data and replace that with
a environment variable appdata you can
now do and you can now do analysis
across a number of different sandbox
flavors depending you know but not
depending on the type of windows that
was used so this is really important if
you're getting data from a lot of
different sources so I cuckoo
next-generation those two point O has a
lot of new features on Mac os10 linux
android or both
all of these are sandbox Abel has
suricata snort Moloch integration SSL
decryption VPN support so if you need to
go from a different specific country or
hide your traffic you can go from a VPN
64-bit analysis and the new version of
cuckoo is awesome so what if you're what
if you're malware is a vm aware so
there's two things that you can do to
prevent or to protect yourself or help
yourself a analyzed vmware malware so
one is paranoid fish so paranoid fish
takes the perspective of figuring out
what malware in the wild uses to detect
whether it's being debugged whether it's
in a vm whether it's being it you know
whether it's in a sandbox and so what it
will do is it has all these
operationalize in an executable that you
run through your sandbox and then it
will tell you i found x y&z and then
these are the things that you need to
correct to improve your sandbox vm cloak
is another piece of software that's
actually authored by one of the authors
of cuckoo sandbox and what it does is it
takes a different perspective what it
does is it actually uh you know
automatically builds your vm and it also
obvious gates all the things that
something like paranoid fish or malware
will look for to find out if it's in a
vm and so it creates these automated vm
that you can use with coup that are
pretty
acted from many of the anti analysis
techniques so cuckoo has a number of
different outputs HTML json baba so it
has drop files and you want to you know
if there's a drop file often you want to
resend box that drop file it will
produce pcap which you can analyze with
the software that i'm going to talk
about in just a moment and then memory
images but there's a nuance to coos
memory image that it produces so it uses
techniques that basically dirty the
memory image so the memory image that
coo produces is good for coos own
analysis of it but I suggest that you
need to create a clean memory image to
use volatility on it separately from ku
and it also produces visited URLs that
you would want to look at with thug
so let's look at Thug thug is a low
interaction honey client and what is
that it pretends to be a browser is
triggered by a drive-by download or on
you know it you would feed a URL that
has just a malware payload uh download
and the goal is to capture the payload
so that you can analyze it gives me
analyze it further so thug is a wolf in
sheep's clothing because it is entirely
written in python and it basically
pretends to be any type of browser you'd
like
via user-agent strings and it also feeds
are you know it has a v8 as the
JavaScript engine so it will actually
feed the the drive-by download the
correct version and you know that you've
that you've told it of java PDF flash
etc and so it pretends to be the version
of Java or whatever that that drive-by
wants to infect you with so there are a
number of available user agents and
ranges from windows it includes you know
android devices iOS iPads and so you
know it has a a wide range of things
that you can pretend to be
so that the output of thug it has
payload files and that's like the you
know that that's the the gold that
you're getting out of this and you would
use cout to then look at those payload
files and execute them
it has other content files that shows
the visit URLs has a number of different
output formats and it has its own native
output format so now this is like my
honestly is my favorite part of this
talk because i love bro i know that many
of you love bro because you do use it as
a network security monitoring tool but
if I may I would love to to convert you
ended loving it as a malware analysis
tool so that the difference here is that
the bro that you would use in in network
security monitoring you're looking at a
large amount of traffic for you're
looking for bad things in a large amount
of traffic i'm actually executing a
piece of malware and only looking at the
traffic that piece of network produces
so bro can do two types of packet
capture it could do life live packet
capture it can also look at recorded
packet capture which is a pcap so a pcap
is a recording of network traffic from
two points in time bro is made up of a
number of scripts it allows you to write
your own scripts if you want but by the
way the talk that I'm giving here i'm
only using the the scripts that are
built into bro
so I want to take a little exercise here
and look at what can I learn from a pcap
only and so I kind of conceptualize this
as having the malware in a different
room and I can't look at the malware
file itself but I can kind of listen to
what it's doing and so what can I learn
from pcap only and this is the sha-1 of
what we're going to look at and that's
where i got it
hybrid analysis good friends of ours and
so you can download this piece of mail
your malware yourself and you can you
know
a look at what I've done and and
validated so first thing you want to
look at is the conlogue so this is a log
of all the connections that are made
that bro has observed in that pcap so
there's a variety of things going on
here so i kind of want to split this out
into different categories and so the
first category is the garbage so the
garbage is stuff that you don't want to
care about this is stuff that is uh you
know benign traffic your operating
system is producing so we throw away
this stuff then we have DNS traffic so
this is this is very good rich data so
we want to look at dns resolution
because the malware asking for the IP
address of the domain name that it's
reaching out to these are HTTP requests
and so this is something going on via
HTTP will look into what that is and
then these where the service is a dash i
like to call this the WTF traffic this
is the stuff that is definitely see to
command control traffic because it bro
is very smart and if bro doesn't know
what the service is probably bad and so
by the way this is a word document so if
your word document is reaching out to
the internet and making queries on HTTP
then your macaroni is infected so let's
look at the dns log first and so like i
said earlier bros output is made up of a
number of text-based logs and so this is
one and the the incantation that I have
the top arm is and I but these are all
going to be published in my github which
you all show you the link for a moment
but these incantations will not boil
down the brow logs to just what you want
and so here we have a number of
different dns queries and so this again
this is like the the good traffic
obviously reaching out to google google
is probably not a c2
microsoft also known as c2 but here we
have traffic that we want to analyze so
these are some indicators that we want
to kind of put in our back pocket and
think about and also you know thinking
about this from the automation
perspective these are the things that
you want to kind of set aside when
you're automating things so I and i will
not name names but there are certain
nonprofit organizations that changed
their tune and now sell what they were
giving away in the past so I'm going to
give you a way to do poor man's dns the
PDS so passive DNS is what domain names
have been resolved to a particular IP
address and so this is a you know the m1
sorry make this a little easier to see
so this is IP on 56 you blah blah and I
you know there's the the word Google
dork but this is actually a big dork so
Bing you can use to find everything that
being has seen that is on this
particular IP address so this is poor
man's p dns so i can see that many many
domain names have resolved during things
you know crawling history to this
particular IP address so this leads me
to believe that this is a compromised IP
address so let's look at the Whois data
and so we go to domaintools on another
to you know site that i really love and
this hooked outdoors dot-com we can see
the creation date is 2007 so chances are
malware see to that are owned by the
adversary are not created in 2007 this
is probably compromised so I look at the
hut the site content and you know this
is someone's I you know fishing lure
site whatever but it's something that's
interesting is I see that it's got that
little a fav icon for drupal so I have a
pretty good idea how the adversary got
into this particular website
so let's move on and look at the rest of
the dns log so we've got the you know
hooked outdoors and then we have this
dent to bogota dot-com and then s web
comms dot-com and if any of you are you
know hardcore our analysis or threatened
tell people you know exactly what we're
looking at here but we will get there so
we're going to look at the next IP
address and by the way this is the
didn't know go dot com IP address 77 not
246 I has no poor man's pns so this is
not shared web server this is a single
IP address so you know this is something
that you know leads me to think that
there's something more nefarious going
on here so i look at the Whois data and
lo and behold this was created on the 12
of this month and then we've got a a
registered email address where we can
actually dig into what this email
address is and and what's going on here
but this registers biz CN china and you
know that we've got polish uh you know I
I don't mean to be you know the singling
out anyone but East Europe is you know a
font of malware so we're looking at
something that is probably a little bit
more suspicious so I look at poor man's
reverse who is and so I googled the
email address and so lo and behold like
you know the top three here are from
threat crowd threat minor and scam scam
Warner's dot-com so I think there's
definitely something going on here so i
look at the site content and there's
nothing there
imagine that you know your c2 why why
put content on your c2 so let's go back
to the dns log and let's move to the
next part and look at s web comms
dot-com this is where it gets very
interesting and you'll see there were
two requests for resolution of s web com
and both of them and I know this looks a
little bit like you know number salad
for you but these are the same three IP
addresses and they're just rotated so
you know this looks like this looks like
something fairly nefarious or this looks
like a legitimate website you know there
are legitimate websites that want to
have no backup IP addresses and then do
round robin DNS among them so i'm gonna
go with it not being legitimate so we
look at the the who is data and the
creation date is on the sixteenth of
this month so by the way things that are
created within the past month are things
that are suspicious to me
also the Santa @s webcams dot-com the
registered address I will you know kind
of put that in my back pocket but now
I'm thinking because this is looking
like something that is not legitimate
I want to look at the nameserver so I
want to keep those nameservers in my
back pocket and you know there are and
by the way like I'm saying there you
know everything i'm talking about is
free access but there are services out
there that can find domains that were
respond that are from this particular
dns service so i won't go into those but
you know if you want to look at reverse
nameserver probably there's some nasty
stuff comes out of this triumph verde
dot-com so we've got uh you know we've
got a number of things that I want to do
but one thing is P dns and like I said
free services you can go to our website
this is all freeze in our common
community so I loaded this IP address in
you know our PDAs service and I find
down here all of these are you know July
thirteenth 2016 July sixteenth 2016 and
all these are kind of you know a red
flag ish domain names like EJ
d qz KD sounds like a domain generation
algorithm to me also ln x y blah blah
and then they were registered July
thirteenth july 1613 13th 1917 1914 1913
all this is bad you know just died I i
would flag all of this so let's move on
to the next like stage of bro so you're
looking at also the httpd log and so bro
will not only show you the connections
it will show you deeper into the network
stack in show you are you know HTTP
connections and so we've got this set of
HTTP connections and so we're looking
here at 77 blah blah at didn't know go
dot com boy gate dot PHP so I being a
rishta file and you know fluent in
Russian I know the words a boy so the
point is a term used in Russia and other
post-soviet States to describe alcohol
abuse behavior resulting in two or more
days of continuous drunkenness so I
would imagine that most of us are on a
support at the moment but this is
something actually put in your back
pocket and think about because now we
know that the adversary is probably
rissa phone and oh sorry and and by the
way so I'm on some secret squirrel you
know lists fight club sort of things and
I had to reach out to some friends and
get some more information and so from
people that I can't cite the poi Kate
that PHP is an indicator of pony so pony
is a loader module and a password
stealer and at of our family again let's
look at the next piece of httpd logs and
I know where we're skipping over that
install.exe and but that's really cool
stuff will come back to that but so this
is sort of a random string / index dot
PHP and lo and behold those same secret
squirrel friends of mine say this is my
name
alright so nine Man plus pony we're
going to see this in a moment we're
going to see where we're actually going
to go from understanding what this is to
finding out kind of not necessarily who
the adversary is but knowing who the
adversary group is so we're going to
look at these now these are really fun
so i nst 1.exe are both hooked outdoors
and so remember this is a compromise
website and so this is how they're
serving their executables the payloads
and so let's look at the first one so
this is the log from bro called the PE
log p log gives you some really inform a
good information so by the way you'll
see here there's the f8 k that first one
this is the awesome thing about bros it
will allow you to connect log from log
using you IE u IDs or IDs and so that f8
kaid is findable in other logs and I can
grab for that particular uh uid and I
can see in the PE log the the line in
that p log refers to that particular
file so we can see here it's a windows
GUI we get a few section names we also
get the compiles the timestamp so all
very good information so now let's look
at the files log and so anything that is
a file will be put into the files log
and so i can if you look at the
incantation those two particular you
ideas are in there and so I'm looking at
the you ideas for this one and I get out
of the files law get all the file hashes
and the total bytes for the these files
so this is the point where we kind of
back away from using the tool and we do
some open source intelligence and I've
got you know my name pony and you know
now when the past month so I go look
around and see if other people you know
other people that the do what I do our
talking about what I'm looking at and lo
and behold so the man 1
krypter gang these are variously known
as fought track of all track gang never
quest you might be familiar with all
them but they they use all of these
things together and so I you know threat
geek.com which is fidelis cybersecurity
is blog wrote a really good review of
all of this stuff so now I have not only
the stuff that I'm looking at and now i
have some open source intelligence i
compare compare my results to and by the
way we haven't left a pcap yet so what
can you learn from pcap only so we know
that the adversaries likely rissa phone
you have an office document generating
network traffic by the way your macaroni
is infected we have multistage malware
because it has different things that
it's installing one of the payloads we
know now is pony one of the note one of
the payloads is nine aim-9 name we also
know from looking at the infrastructure
we know that has dedicated
infrastructure and it contains a rogue
DNS server the dropper uses compromised
or Drupal websites and you know by doing
a little bit of due diligence we found
that the adversary is man 1 so we've
collected a lot of indicators and all
zoom in on these for you are i think i
think i can so we've got a lot of
indicators we got a bunch of URLs we and
we have a bunch of a group that didn't
work sorry
so we have a bunch of indicators that
we've collected from just the pcap and
this is a very good you know but image
of what the malware is doing without
actually looking at the malware itself
so of course I I want to help you do
what I do and so local dot bro is the
configuration file for bro
and so these are and i spent a lot of
time going over
how to do the best configuration file
possible form our analysis so this is
here and I know you know that's a lot of
word salad but there it is
so I i am working on publishing the
entire system but some of the components
including my local bro which people
requested because they want to work on
it now that's available right there so
of course i am curious about what
actually happened so we're going to
cheat and not necessarily cheap in the
context of an open-source our lab what
I'm talking about is sending that
particular file over to KU to see what's
happening there and so this is the
dropper and so the droppers cuddlesome
dot exe and it's a ruck drug rug of
dropper alright which also reinforces
the fact that it's man 1 so bro output
you have conlogue DSD NS log HTTP blah
blah you get extracted files also you
can change the output to have json so
that you can consume it with
elasticsearch very easily now we're
going to move to volatility and
volatility another favorite tool of mine
very awesome so what is volatility so
volatility extracts artifacts from
samples of volatile memory
hence volatility so it gives you an
amazing view into what the malware is
doing and like I said where you know
you're holding the cup against the wall
and listening to what the malware is
saying when you're looking at a pcap
volatility allows you to look at what
the malware is thinking because it's
using memory pages and you're looking at
what it is safe to memory so as you know
all the major operating systems support
Windows Mac OS Linux blah blah and then
what I want to do is kind of lead you
down the same
I mean a process that i did with bro and
look at volatility in action by the way
if you receive a file that is a single
letter or number two exe it's malware so
this is the strong one you can follow
along again with my analysis and by the
way you know one of the things I like to
do is I when when I look at stuff like
this i beat my head against a brick wall
trying to figure out when things don't
work so I don't want you to beat your
head against the same brick wall
so if you use virtualbox these are the
incantations that you need to use to
dump a memory image from virtual locks
and have it usable with volatility these
slides will be published so you know no
need to to memorize it now so peel PS
list and PS scan or tools that you can
use to look the processes that are
running in a memory image and so what I
did was I took a memory image of the
clean vm then I compared it to a memory
image of the vm after the malware had
run and so there's a there there's a
point here where the top 10 search
protocol search filter service host
these are things that are naturally
occurring in an operating system but i
double-clicked on a piece of malware and
it wasn't internet explorer but now
explored exe is running so something is
going on
so what I what next thing you want to do
is use mal find which is a plug-in for
for volatility and all the things that
I'm talking about right now all of these
come with the default standard version
of the software so i'm looking at mal
fine and I can find two processes that
mal find is telling me have been
injected with uh you know the executable
that isn't that thing so we didn't what
you can do is dump those processes into
a file and then what I did was I
actually ran those dump files through
coo and i found via
AV scanner results both of these
processes are flagged as malware for
variety of reasons
so the next thing i want to do is look
at the Nets cancer Nets can can look at
the memory image and find out what
network connections have been made out
outbound so we see here explored exe and
by the way I didn't run explorer but it
reached out to these to these two times
the same IP address and port 80 so
that's bad
uh so what can we learn what have we
learned from this
I we've learned that the sample uses
process injection we know what it
targets targets explorer.exe and we've
also pulled out a command-and-control IP
address so volatilities output you know
you get files from extracted services
from injection deal all extracted IP
addresses this one so I by E history is
interesting so i can actually see on the
history of all of the URLs that a user
or malware has visited if they are using
IE so eight URLs extracted from our
configuration so in our config if it's
loaded into memory i can pull URLs out
of that and then also suspicious mutexes
and by the way i'm in volatility it's
like turtles all the way down into
infinity there's so much stuff that you
can get out of it like I could have 820
our talk about volatility alone there's
so much more stuff that you can get
these are some of the major things so
tying it all together the end and by the
way so i've i've made a few swimlanes
here and I wanted originally to have all
four tools in one set of swim lanes but
when you throw all of these together the
the spaghetti starts to to confuse the
swim lanes so what I've done here is
done
koo sandbox and so you upload a file
to sandbox you do the analysis you send
all of your indicators to threat
intelligence platform and you have a
thug instance which will process any of
the URLs that come out of cuckoo you
have bro that will process pcap that
comes out of cuckoo and if you have seen
the file before I you want to say no and
then send your data to threat to your
tip and then if you haven't seen the
file before you want to kind of go back
to the top and throw it into the top of
the hopper and then this is the same
thing with volatility and kind of
conceptually marry these two together
with the same concept and I know like
you know upload URL has a little piece
of spaghetti that i was unable to kind
of you know do right but basically
you're you're you're taking the inputs
and outputs are that one particular tool
uses and if you've seen that particular
thing before you want to just consume
the data that comes out and if you
haven't seen it before you want to
process it with another tool and by the
way one nuance here if you see a file
that drops a file the drops a file that
drops a file you want to actually have a
stop at like I choose six generations of
drop because you can cause an infinite
loop and kind of you know my gum up your
cuckoo instance so for orchestra
orchestration and automation you know
it's up to you what flavor of message
queue you like redness rabbitmq i use
zeromq because it's awesome and then
also like you know the concept of
hitting your head against a brick wall
in one of my other projects plague
scanner i ran into the brick wall of
using zeromq transmit files don't do
that what you should do is use engine ex
dumped the files to engine X and then
serve them out using that web server and
then just use the message queue to send
the location to the next tool so that it
downloads the file itself using engine X
because engine X is built better for
serving files
zeromq built better for serving you know
small text strings i prefer to keep all
of my output in elasticsearch cuckoo
right now needs to be koo modified to
have an output plugin for elasticsearch
i'm personally working on developing a
elasticsearch plugin for the main you
know a KU lug thug uses elasticsearch
natively bro has an option to export
logs in JSON format which can be easily
consumed by elasticsearch as does
volatility i prefer to glue everything
together with python 3 because i hate
python to it needs to die and go away
mainly because of text processing and
the idiocy of and it was just it was
historical mistake they didn't know how
to do it right yet but it needs to die
and go away so by the way we're we're
we're getting towards the question
component but i wanted to say like
there's more more fun we can have with
me our analysis and the week after next
i'm giving this talk as a four hour
workshop at DEFCON and so each of these
tools will have basically you can you
know sleep through the teaching part
because you've seen it but the fifth the
45 minutes of hands-on training for each
one of these tools i'll be giving in Def
Con and then please
that evening so I'm giving it thursday
the first day of DEFCON please come to
our party and get drunk with me that day
at 6pm to 9pm I know if you go visit
this URL it says black hat party and you
have to come to our black at booth not
completely true
come find me i'll give you an invite i
also i'm going to be in Serbia talking
about another completely different
concept that i have called predictive
CDE hunting and i'll be presenting that
balkon and then
I will be wrapping up everything about
the open source of our lab virus
bulletin in Denver so questions three
minutes for questions
I can't even see you because that there
we go it s so how did you like really
get into malware analysis in the
beginning like how did you get good at
all of this stuff it's really
complicated so I mean there's many long
stories i encourage you to come to
blarney rock with me and and continue to
vibe tonight i'll give you the full
story but it involves being a landscaper
and then after being at that I i'm
actually not joking but it so it
involves being a landscaper and then
having someone on my landscaping team
talk to me and say you know what the
fuck you doing as a landscaper you
should come
send your resume to the place where he
was moonlighting as a landscaper I was
not but yet so yeah and then I worked in
a sock and did malware analysis and
fishing analysis and now I'm here so if
you could elaborate a little bit more
something as the privacy conscious
person who kinda likes to roll my own
stuff but doesn't always have the time
passive DNS stuff you were talking about
that's something that I just see like
highly useful to figure out what apps in
services are doing behind your back
so is there recommend every time I think
of configuring bind i don't know go and
do something else is there like a sort
of like one-stop shop for configuring a
reasonable dns server that will give you
nice logs of
everything that's hitting it yes so I
the answer to your question is much
longer but i can say go to meet go to
ISC website and look up p dns ok on
there are ways that you can configure it
to do that do what you want
ok thanks and actually if i can plug
some you know good friends of mine uh
circle which is one of the certs in
Luxembourg provides as long as you are
one of the good people and you can prove
prove to them that you are like an hour
analysis person or a security person
they'll give you access to their PDAs
system obviously this malware as part of
your analysis you liked it punch out i'm
curious do you completely sandbox
isolate that that network like literally
no well I guess it is completely
isolated it's actually living on a so by
the way I'm when you do malware analysis
it's very rare to find a hosting company
that does not use the word malware or
virus in their terms of service so I
will not tell you where i am hosting my
stuff but I'm not violating their terms
of service but I am isolating it from my
network you know completely and just on
that note like are we talking like your
v landing it or we're talking when we
literally hardware isolated on it is
sitting on a dedicated server in X
location and it has all of this software
that we just talked about running on it
and I there is interfaces vapi and UI
and that's it like it then goes out i do
i am a good citizen so I block port 25
and all the other submission you know so
it's not just you know a spamming stuff
from what I'm doing so and then do you
do and if you do how do you maybe set it
up arm where you're going to have like a
like a networked environment because a
lot of times malware will reach out to
your nearest neighbor and so how do you
model lat
I in your setup on so there is no land
situation involved so it's basically raw
internet and so you know there's no
difference between it reaching out to
his neighbor in my sandbox and reaching
out to his neighbor just you know out
there in the raw internet so you know
it's not no it's not in the local area
network and you know obviously we're
doing our analysis so it's up to the
other entities on the internet to
protect themselves from the things that
emit from my box and sorry i need to do
the malware analysis work but so there
are actually have a configuration for a
coup that allows me to use what's called
I netsim and I you know fake dns and so
i can run things and these are actually
really important when you're doing our
analysis because sometimes a lot of time
i will look at a piece of malware and
the c2 has been taken down by the isp
but I still want to know what's
happening so I want to have that see to
pretend to respond to them our so i'll
have it reach out the different network
you know it's completely closed and have
I netsim and fake dns running all right
I'm done by the way I don't want to
interrupt the next speaker but i have a
butt ton of t-shirts and I'll just hang
out back there and throw them in the
given to whoever wants some