really a panel but to talk together so
we are at the 50th anniversary the
freedom of information act hard to
believe that it's a 1966 that was a good
president was that was that Nick that
was before Nixon wasn't in it was LBJ
believe it or not sign the Freedom of
Information Act into law and Supreme
Court has stated that can you hear me
yes the freedom Information Act quote
defines a structural necessity in a real
democracy in quote I couldn't agree more
so uh uh I just want to say who these
folks are an honor harder on our panel
today
Jameel Jaffer is from the ACLU David
poses with a columbia law school and
they're gonna talk about the history of
the Freedom of Information Act where it
is now and where it's going and how it
all impacts us thank you thank you i'm
david posen I'm am honored to be here
just a quick note LBJ didn't sign it
into law was it was enacted over his
veto but we've been asked to inform you
that there's a hack FOIA workshop
tomorrow
17 and 18 in the Paris room and six
floor I'm tonight tonight a saturday
thanks
we are not going to talk about how to
use FOIA as I gather those sessions will
we're going to talk about bigger picture
issues with the law and we're going to
structure it as a kind of rolling pretty
informal conversation so to get things
started
I'll just a quick word about what the
FOIA is and how it works some of you may
know this all too well but in case some
of you don't quickly was enacted in 1966
took effect in 1967 the engine of FOIA
is the request for a government record
that's the term record in the statute
the federal oil law applies only to
executive branch agencies unlike some of
the state level foi laws it does not
apply to the legislature to the Congress
or to private parties or to the
president's inner circle after agencies
receive a written request for a record
they then turns over to them to the
right in the request i might say has to
reasonably describe the records it seeks
turns over to them to have 20 days
absent unusual circumstances to respond
to your request in practice agencies
routinely miss that deadline and
complain that it's wildly unrealistic
they have to turn over the presumption
is in favor of disclosure of responsive
records unless they fall into one of
nine enumerated exemptions the first and
most famous of which is the national
security exemption but they also cover
trade secrets privacy and other matters
if you are denied in your request you
have a right to administrative appeal
and then tradition review in the DC
federal courts and you have no
obligation in submitting requests to
explain why you want the information
what you do with it
why you have some special relationship
to it that actually was the model under
the Administrative Procedure Act in 1946
boy did away with that so it's any
person gets to submit a request for any
reason or no reason at all to any agency
and therefore kind of frames government
transparency as an individual right that
we all have and it's held by the
requester okay so um so enough on how
will come back to more about how it
works i'm sure that's just a nutshell
summary in jameel we have one of the
leading national security litigators in
the FOIA area and that is one of the
most controversial areas of for practice
so i want to turn over to jameel to
start talking about how do you see for
working in the national security context
it's routinely claimed that that's an
area where for it breaks down
do you agree
I'm so so first and great to be here i
would say it's great to see all of you
but we can actually see any of you
because of the lights the transparency
here is unidirectional you guys can see
ask we can see you
I'm so no I don't have a very high
opinion of FOIA international security
context and you know it's true the
government sometimes releases
information in response to a FOIA
request international security context
but it does so selectively and
strategically and usually it it regards
those disclosures as a matter of
discretion rather than legal obligation
and it's very rare almost unheard of
that a court will require the government
to release national security information
that it doesn't want to release and it
does very very occasionally happen but I
had those victories in the national
security context tend to be not just
rare but procedural rather than
substitute they have to do with their
technical victory they're not they're
not meaningful transparency victories
and I thought I just give you one
example and for the last I guess six
years I've been involved in litigation
FOIA litigation relating to the drone
campaign the CIA's drone campaign the
use of remotely piloted aircraft to
carry out at so-called targeted killings
abroad and we understood from the outset
that it would be very difficult to get
information from the CIA on this
particular topic but we nonetheless went
ahead we thought that the public had a
right to know what legal authority the
CIA was relying on
and and how that authority was actually
being used so how many drone strikes had
there been where were those drone
strikes how many casualties other been
basically we thought the public had a
right to know who the CIA was killing
and why it was killing them and the CIA
probably needless to say didn't share
our view and and i responded to the
request by by invoking something called
the Glomar doctrine which is essentially
it is a doctrine that allows an agency
to say that even to confirm or deny that
it possesses records relating to the
request would jeopardize national
security so the CIA essentially said
that everything about the drone campaign
even the purported existence of the
agency's drone campaign was a secret and
it took the position that our for your
request shouldn't be processed in the
ordinary course that it couldn't process
our FOIA requests in the ordinary course
because to do so would jeopardize
national security and even as CIA
officials leaked information to the
media on an almost daily basis about the
CIA's targeted killing practice practice
authority killing the agency maintained
in court that nothing at all
could be could be released so that was
the sort of the landscape in 2010-2011
when we first started when we first
follower request for started litigating
request we won two significant victories
in this case in in this set of cases the
first was in 2012 the DC Circuit the
appeals court in DC in a dissident in a
decision written by Judge Merrick
garland who as you know President Obama
has since nominated 22 filled and the
late Justice Scalia slot on the Supreme
Court and the DC Circuit ruled that the
CIA could no longer pretend that its
interest in the joint in the drone
campaign was a secret and it ordered the
agency to process our request in the
ordinary course meaning tell tell tell
us what documents it had their response
to the request and explain why those
documents are being withheld starts 2012
and then in 2014 the the second circuit
here in New York
another federal appeals court order the
Justice Department to release a legal
memo in which the in which Justice
Department lawyers had concluded that
the CIA could carry out the targeted
killing of an American overseas so those
two rulings were nearby i think by most
people's measure victories they were
extraordinary rulings it's like I said
it's very rare that courtside with
requesters in the national security
context and in fact if you look at
justice garland Judge Garland's
congressional disclosure form you know
filed after he'd been been nominated to
the Supreme Court and he lists the cases
that he has decided that he thinks of as
the most significant on one and one of
the ten cases he list is this case from
2012 in which he held that the CIA had
to acknowledge its interest in the drone
campaign and I think if you talk to
litigators about the most significant
national security victories for
victories or in the post 9-11 era and
everybody would put these cases on their
list and maybe near the top of their
list but but the amazing thing I think
is that in both of those cases the
courts ordered the release of
information only after having concluded
that the government had officially
acknowledged the information we were
asking for
so in other words the courts didn't
conclude and that the government secrets
should be disclosed in both cases they
concluded that the purported secrets
word secrets at all and that's a very
different thing right so so to put it i
guess a little more sharply both course
both appeals courts in these ostensibly
very significant for victories were
willing to rule for us only after
concluding that we already had the
information we were asking for and I
think that that kind of victory that
kind of those kinds of transparency
victories are reflective of the kinds of
victories that are possible to achieve
in this in this context and and you know
that sort of those are the height of
of that that's the extent of the
possibility in this particular context
and and which is why i say i have a
relatively low opinion of voices
effectiveness here so I guess I you know
at this point turn it back to David just
ask you share that you share that
assessment and you know as you said at
the beginning i'm a national security
litigators that assessment even if you
do share it with respective national
security what about everything else so I
basically share that view i just add a
few points the I remember looking as of
2005 at the case law has there been any
cases in which the government asserted
the national security exemption and lost
got a definitive judicial resolution
that the exemption was improperly
invoked and I can only find one case at
that time arguably the numbers up a bit
since then but clearly the US government
tends to win when it starts the national
security exemption from toya i should
say the US government tends to win when
its search for exemptions period the
statutory standard is what's called to
novo review the court supposed to give
no deference to the agency that withhold
information that's very rare in u.s.
administrative law that you get such an
undifferentiated standard but
nonetheless the government wins by most
estimates ninety percent of the time
when its search index any exemption
under 4 is probably higher the national
security area so kourt's just seemed not
to want to get into the business of
interfering with government assertions
of a need for secrecy under FOIA period
and the best case for international
security area would probably have to be
a little more subtle not about what you
would have to concede that the
government tends to win in these cases
but nonetheless in the shadow of FOIA
the government settles more often than
it would our releases some documents so
as to get out ahead of a lawsuit it
doesn't want to suffer in court I think
that happens and pinched your your
perspective melted to some extent but
that even even even so for has to be
seen as basically a superficial response
to the rise of the classification system
after World War Two and during the Cold
War and beyond
oya that the great landmarks statute
affirming the people's right to know I'm
develops basically in parallel with the
rise of the classification system within
the executive branch for national
security information and the ladder
comes to swamp the former i would say
the classification system is where all
the secrecy resides or the bulk of
secrecy resides in government now and
it's not much touched by FOIA due to the
national security exception also
exemption 3 which says of another
statute says you don't need to be
bothered by for that you don't need to
be bothered by FOIA and NSA relies
heavily on exemption 3 for all of its
operations to avoid FOIA interestingly
in the Congressional debates which took
many years leading up to force an
enactment in 1966 initially the National
Security Agency agencies seemed quite
threatened by the law and we're very
worried about it
by the time for is actually enacted
however in 1966 they had dropped a lot
of their opposition and no longer seem
to be as threatened by it
I'm i think making a realistic
assessment of how they would fare
hundred and ironically you might say
Congress had never arguably never
officially recognized the legitimacy of
the executive classification system at
all prior to FOIA in writing an
exemption one we have Congress actually
in some sense validating the
classification system even as it a you
know stands up this right to know in
other areas so that would be my take on
the national security field for is doing
some work in the shadows that we
shouldn't discount entirely but but it
has to be seen as a mismatch and
overmatched as comparative
classification system i wanted i have
thought about how its feeling elsewhere
to which I'll get to I want to see if
you want to rip on any land well you
know I I'm thinking about four headed in
the shadows of for me I think you're
right that there are circumstances in
which
the threat of FOIA and leads the
government even that even the small
possibility of the government might lose
in court results in the government
releasing information that might not
otherwise release there are also
situations in which Fauria forces the
government to confront a decision to
make a decision that it would otherwise
defer and and you know the government
maybe of of two minds about whether to
release a certain piece of information
if or your request is filed a lawsuit is
presented and that lawsuit is sharply
presented to an appeals court then maybe
the government may be in it you know I
an administration that is ambivalent
about the release of information might
be forced to make a decision and so I
think that there are you know i think
you're right you can't you know you
can't say that FOIA is never at all
effective in in compelling the release
of information or persuading the
administration at the government's
release information but I think you're
also writing a right to say that those
are sort of that that's at the margins
and and the overall have you know the
promise of FOIA as stated in 1966 and
say that many many times since by the
federal courts and certainly not been
fulfilled in this particular sphere at
least so so maybe um now's the time to
pivot to wear wherefore it is doing more
work for better or worse as against the
federal government and I think it's
telling to frame that discussion but by
noting which agency was most worried
about for you by the time it was
actually enacted 1966 as i said the
national security agency's more let's
make their peace with it the holdout
agency that was most worried about 40
about time it was clear is going to pass
was HW health education and Welfare now
I'm split up into different agencies and
HW is concerned in a nutshell was that
for would constrain its ability to
regulate economic power that for would
hinder its efforts against big business
to try to promote public health safety
welfare and so forth and there i'd say
that
hws concerns were were somewhat
prescient about how things have played
out and I might I might put it like this
i have a historian colleague at Columbia
Myra Katznelson wrote this great book
called fear itself about the legacy of
the new deal for American governance
today and he says what the New Deal left
us with was it is schizophrenic or
Janice faced state inwardly when the
state is regulating domestically it
looks often weak obsessed with procedure
over substance and a very differential
to and protective of business interests
externally however when facing outwards
the rest of the world the state the
American state looks purpose-driven
powerful interventionist eager to take
the fight to enemies so we have this
this schizophrenia here we have the so
called procedural state in which public
institutions are largely too weak to
check private economic power and we have
what he calls the crusading state where
public institutions of this country dole
out overwhelming violence with little
Democratic oversight so i would say for
you up largely leaves intact
maybe even reinforces the crusading
state the reasons we just discussed but
actually it may be more surprisingly it
it feeds into the procedural state to
and is a problem for some things
agencies try to do that we might like
so a place to start in thinking about
those issues is corporate use of FOIA um
there's been a lot of studies now
empirical studies of who actually makes
requests under FOIA they all confirm
that commercial requesters dominate the
foil landscape in some agencies like the
food and drug administration or the
environmental protection agency they are
not just a majority but huge
supermajority ninety percent plus of the
requesters they have the deepest pockets
and
they tend to have lawyers and the most
likely litigate so there's some evidence
to that agencies prioritize commercial
requests over other requests like from
the media or the general public
maybe for fear of what will happen if
they if they don't so commercial
requesters are crowding out other
requesters in a lot of context they pay
somewhat more in fees then members of
nonprofit organizations or reporters or
academics however they don't pay nearly
at cost the government recoups less than
1% the latest figures from from last
fiscal year say of the cost of
administering foil from fees so we have
this music cottage industry that's
developed i might add of companies whole
business model is requesting information
under FOIA and then reselling it often
to institutional investors like hedge
funds in some agencies data brokers
information resources are actually are
the main themselves the main requesters
in aggregate so you have this kind of
hidden corporate subsidy i think in FOIA
which we don't tend to talk about as
such but it amounts to a wealth transfer
from ordinary taxpayers to certain types
of corporations at the same time in
agencies like HW successors there are
there's some evidence that it diminishes
regulatory capacity makes it hard to get
things done and distracts agencies
Congress has never funded for it
remotely the level it would take to
comply with its deadlines so agencies
end up roping in non for personnel often
to work on for matters and they complain
at least that this industry ability to
do their regulatory mission last point
I'll make in this regard and then
alternate email to respond but also to
start thinking about what we might do if
we if we see any of this as a concern is
a the type of journalism that for
produces i think is is very interesting
in some ways distinctive foil was a
asked in part to help journalists there
are a lot of statements by members of
Congress about how it was it was meant
to facilitate investigative reporting
and it does that to some extent although
with the economic decline of the news
media is doing a lot less these days and
it used to and the delays are so long
that it never really did it for a lot of
reporting really only works for
investigative reporters are willing to
stay with the story for a long time
maybe even litigated they don't get all
the records they seek i'm in any event
that there now been some empirical work
about the journals and that comes out of
foil what do news stories that say they
got records from FOIA tend to talk about
the main thing they tend to talk about
is waste fraud and abuse within
government agencies arguably the second
biggest story that type of four story
now is a story just about how far is
broken so there's like a you know this
kind of meta journalism on on for years
I'm dysfunctionality I'm stories on
waste fraud and abuse are obviously
important and a important part
democratic accountability and I would
just suggest that for over represents
the extent to which that is a problem
with the problem in government today
because of other legal mandates agencies
generally have to produce reports on
that kind of behavior when they find it
there are therefore already written
records out there if you want to go hunt
for them on those subjects are not
exempt like a lot of other things are
there not exempt under any of the nine
exemptions so that the structure of FOIA
makes kind of the sitting ducks records
that tend to talk about waste fraud and
abuse and therefore an end and journals
aren't getting a lot of other things
they might want through FOIA I think
it's it seems likely to be there for
that you get the systematic
over-representation of that as the
problem we should all be concerned about
as against other issues and government
again not to not to say that stuff
doesn't matter greatly and that
therefore therefore kind of produces a
reporting a based on that kind of
distrust in hostility to what the
government is doing beyond what might be
warranted and moreover in the fact that
everyone uses for ya find the delays are
wildly not complied with for you also
reproduces that distrust in this
functionality in its very experienced I
two levels FOIA is harming the agency's
again like HW who more than maybe the
designers of that would have intended so
that Jimmy I what do this this kind of
FOIA harms the procedural state or feeds
a procedural state in ways at least a
certain type of liberal or progressive
might not like while what whereas it
helps the crusading that is this too
bleak assessment and no I'm going to be
guy actually as you're talking i was i
was thinking about this i try to
remember that joke at his punch line is
that you know that the the food is so
bad and the portions are so small
because it's something that's something
that clear to you but that on you want
one thing you have you may have
mentioned this in passing but I think
it's important to to highlight it and
you even if oil were working exactly as
it was supposed to work and it had it
had a very relatively modest ambition in
some ways you know it reaches only
executive branch records and only
records and which is a phrase is a word
that's you narrowly defined and and just
to give you an idea of the significance
of those limitations so for you doesn't
reach judicial documents judicial
decisions and we have a court and as
many of you probably know that oversees
foreign intelligence surveillance or
certain aspects of foreign intelligence
surveillance and 4 430 years has issued
decisions relating to the the lawfulness
of the National Security Agency's
practices and post 9-11 started issuing
these very significant decisions about
the constitutionality of the NSA's
activities and none of those decisions
were ever made public and you can
imagine that if we had a broader statute
a broader statutory right of access to
that encompass judicial decisions some
of that stuff might have come out before
bed Snowden released it in in 2013 and I
think we would all be better off if that
you know that happened but that's a
result of the narrowness of the FOIA for
it doesn't reach congressional records
either the Senate Intelligence Committee
has put together this 66,000 page study
of the cia's detention and interrogation
and rendition program post 911 and the
Intelligence Committee is a matter of
discretion released an executive summary
of that that document but and for you
doesn't reach the report itself insofar
as that report is a congressional
document now there's a there's a dispute
which the ACLU is involved in about
whether that document should be seen as
a congressional record or an agency
record but there's no dispute that if it
is a congressional record the boy
doesn't reach it so you know it's
important to remember that even if you
fix the foyer you know in the sense of
making the FOIA more effective in the
sphere in which it was supposed to
operate it's not actually going to solve
every problem and then even this is
actually point that David is made to me
before much more effectively than I just
made a bit i think it's an important
point I'm so you know what that's also a
preamble to how do you fix the FOIA even
you know even sort of taking the FOIA as
it you know as it is in some sense
I'm they're on my list of things that I
would do and starting with with the
least ambitious and moving to the most
ambitious i would start by strengthening
the affirmative disclosure requirements
so just to give one example and had that
there's a part of part of FOIA is really
it is a bifurcated statute part part of
it requires agencies to release
information on their own their own and
the other part is reacted when people
file request the agency has respond so
but the first part is very weak and has
been interpreted almost interpreted away
by the courts and
and those first affirmative provisions
were meant to require the agencies to
disclose among other things their own
law so when age when an agency issues a
decision or promulgates a policy that
has an effect on individual rights
they're supposed to affirmative Lee
release that that that that document
that policy and that that that doesn't
always happen it rarely happens and some
of the most significant documents
relating to national security and like
the opinions of the opposite legal
counsel for example in my view should
have been released
affirmative Lee you know redacted for
intelligence sources and methods but
nonetheless you are presumptively
released but weren't and in and the
result is that we ended up in in a fight
about the release of those documents in
response to you after somebody filed
employer requests and i think that one
fix you know 111 fixed I would make if I
were in charge and obviously I'm not but
that that one fixed I would make is
strengthening the front of disclosure
provisions a second fix would be to to
prevent or prohibit the agencies from
withholding legal analysis under the
national security exemption so it in my
mind it's one thing to say well the
agency can't release the names of the
people who provided it with information
with intelligence sources or can't
release the specifications for the
predator drone that seems legitimate to
me that kind of withholding but it's
something else to say well we can't
release where we're going to use the
natural security exemption to withhold
the legal analysis that we rely on in
order to carry out targeted killings to
me it seems like that the public has a
right to know or should have a right to
know the agency's interpretation of the
law and insofar as the interpretation of
laws entangled with classified facts
what you can read act the classified
facts that's a second that's the second
fix and finally and this is probably the
most ambitious one and
i would add a public-interest balancing
test of some kind so that you're right
right now once the agency establishes
that a particular piece of information
falls within one of the National
Security exemptions and that's the end
of the game you know the the the
information is then then ordered you
know ordered properly withheld but
security is one you know one value it's
not the only value and in some contexts
you would want to
it seems to me way the security concern
against other no other interests or
other other factors and you know it may
be true that and you know let's assume
it's true that the disclosure of Justice
Department memos relating to
interrogation or surveillance of the
drone program would disclose some
intelligence sources and methods i don't
think it's actually true but let's
assume is true for now and that there's
no way to disclose those memos without
disclosing intelligence sources and
methods i think we should then consider
well should we nonetheless disclose
those things because they are so
important to the public debate or
because these policies are so
consequential or because I you can
imagine a million different reasons to
disclose those things in spite of a real
national security interests in
withholding we don't have that kind of
Public Interest balancing now and it's
it's really just a new a single factor
decision that's made in the first
instance by the agency and then in
theory reviewed by the court but in
practice the courts defer to the
agency's initial determination and
there's no no one who asked the question
well you know in spite of the
notwithstanding the security concern
should be released anyway and that that
doesn't make any sense to me so those
are my three fixes you do you have your
own III large i like them and largest
loss them i'll note that the public
interest balancing is increasingly used
abroad for is one of the country's
leading legal exports in recent times
now over a hundred countries have
some version of a foil law as you all 50
of the US states but some countries have
departed from the US mom gone beyond it
in some ways one of them is this
incorporation of Public Interest
balancing so even if an exemption
applies not just a kill switch for
disclosure there's still judicial
inquiry into whether it nonetheless it
might be appropriate to release some of
the information i would just single out
the first of Jamil's prescriptions as as
I think the biggest one in the broadest
potentially which is the move to
affirmative disclosure as it's sometimes
called sometimes called proactive
disclosure and that is just Congress
instead of waiting for a request to come
and they were over 700,000 request filed
with federal agencies last year Congress
just tells agencies on this timeline
this sort of information has to be
publicized in this sort of way
justjust do it make it available you
know now presumably posted on the
internet and you don't need to wait for
a request i see that as as the big road
not taken in 1966 I think the reason
that Congress didn't go with the firm of
disclosure instead went with this
request and respond model was twofold
largely 1 i'm just-just technically
practically it was unclear how you would
do a front of disclosure just going to
put everything in like a physical
reading room you know in some a in DC
and some agency office that would be
very helpful the most people so just
just physically and technically how to
get how to disseminate printed materials
at that kind of scale was unclear 1966
I'm and then second i don't think there
was faith that the executive branch
would enforce an affirmative disclosure
requirement reliably you tell agencies
every month you gotta put out this kind
of data
who's to say that they're actually going
to do that better to empower a small
army of citizen enforcers through
through force method since nineteen said
that concern will never totally go away
this is it is i think a valid one but
since nineteen sixty-six executive
branch internal structure has changed so
i think we can have more faith that at
least in large part in a furniture store
disclosure mandate
would be complied with their there have
been the development of offices like
inspectors general on boards people
auditors within the executive in and
whistleblower protection statutes all of
which trying to hold the executive you
know to the firearm laws it's supposed
to be enforcing so uh I i think a firm
disclosure and of course the
technological barriers to from
disclosure have have fallen as well so i
think it's much more realistic than it
was in 1966 and it wouldn't necessarily
have the same distributional
consequences and I was highlighting that
FOIA has voice sounds very attractively
democratic and participatory anyone any
of us can submit a request on equal
terms with the most powerful other
person in society and agency equally has
to respond Congress kind of washed its
hands of deciding who should be
prioritized just anyone can request in
practice that has yielded to corporate a
domination I was suggesting of FOIA and
therefore is it's proven kind of
progressive it sounds I said Congress
made no allocated decision but but you
know in practice that's you let a
certain arrangement that I don't think
people would have would have wanted a
beforehand so again so for that reason
to i think I further disclosure post
everything uh within certain limits
would be a way not to improve for it to
get this kind of beyond for ya in the
next 50 years
David what do you think of the the
argument that some people have made that
and relying on so right now
reporter sometimes father's request and
they filed a request in part because
they want they want to scoop right they
they have the information before anyone
else they rely on the other hand they
used to get this information in hardcopy
they would rely on that information
writing their stories in short we go on
the front page New York Times and they
would get promoted right and and and
part of the part of the incentive for
individual reporters is and is to get
exclusive access to this information
what do you think of the argument that
that it would be a mistake to go to a
system in which everything was serves
released everybody at once an
affirmative Lee because it would you
know it would it would get rid of that
kind of incentive
um I think its advocates a concern that
could be alleviated with some design
choices so that's i think is a real
concern journalist seem to feel in some
cases like they have a quasi property
right in the information that get out
before it's there scoop day and they
went through the effort and they had the
kind of wherewithal to come up with the
request and maybe wait a long time maybe
you know file a bunch of papers in
furtherance of their request and then
when they get the records they should
they should be entitled to get a scoop
and get story which by the way serves
the goal of public debate and writing
about what the government is doing so so
if you move totally to affirmative going
to kill that journalistic incentive to
kind of ferret out information in a way
that we might not want um I think the
Obama administration has an interesting
pilot program that suggests one partial
solution so it's it's called release 21
is released to all handful of agencies
have tried it out now since last year
and this debate about whether to make it
the norm going forward
historically under FOIA if you request
records and you get them they're yours
and the government doesn't necessarily
make them available to anyone else and
this was a boon to some journalists and
academics who you know felt like they
had almost an exclusive released for one
is released all the way it's working is
once any requests or get anything from
foyer it goes up on the agency website
and journalists least a number of them
have been quite opposed to release
someone is to release tall as a
undercutting this incentive structure
that we were just discussing i think
that there i think there's an easy
solution which is just at a time lag do
release it to the public but you know
maybe like it
whatever seems appropriate a week a
month so the journalists had something
thank you
um so I i think i think there you could
satisfy both sides with released one is
released all just with a with a time lag
time and then I just on affirmative
disclosure just putting stuff up on
websites and seeing what happened
um I i guess i'm not so pessimistic that
an industry wouldn't develop I'm just as
other industries have developed around
for ya that could you know regularly
monitor agency websites figure out how
to make sense of the data they put up
there I I just imagine a new breed of
journalism what is already starting to
develop it would develop even more fully
that would make use of affirmative
disclosure because you know date is
going to go up in the FDA website in
huge amounts and we general public won't
know what to make of it and we'll need
mediators who can make sense of that
whether it's an old-school journalists
and bloggers are experts in the field so
i imagine just just a firm if we really
moved in a big way to from disclosure we
would generate a new kind of journalism
in maybe even industries around making
that intelligible to to all of us so so
I so I i'm less pessimistic and i think
the the sum of the journalistic attacks
are on getting away from the request
trip and model i should also add if it
can case the reason that we should stick
with boy as it is is because helping
journalism so much
justjust I think it bears keeping in
mind that journalists are now less than
five percent of the requester pool at
most agencies and routinely say that the
delays under FOIA just make it possible
a lot of the stories they want to write
still some of the important stories get
written under FOIA but we should paint
too rosy picture of the status quo you
know they're there i think that that
there's this is sort of a broader and
broader point and there's the rhetoric
of transparency than this transparency
in practice right and transparency and
practices is often messy or uglier and
then the rhetoric would you have you
have you believe this is one respect
we've just been talking about you know
journalist actually want exclusive
access at least for a time to this kind
of information and Geo's do too you know
it's certainly the ACLU sometimes files
for your request because it wants
information before for anyone else has
it and
but i also have also noted notice that
different phenomenon thats related and
so when we would get exclusive access to
information we would sometimes turn it
over to a media organizations say that
your Times or The Washington Post or the
Interceptor whatever was and I and so
you know we have this information we go
through for ya
here's what we think it means but you
know you guys do your own investigation
and they would take time because they
had an exclusive through us they would
take time to to do a deep story about
that particular topic if if you if
everybody gets the information at once
nobody has the same incentive in taking
the time they all the incentive is to
write something really quick to be the
first to write about it but the
incentives change in a way that you know
on balance and it's hard to know you
know how that's going to affect the
quality of the information that we
ultimately get and so that that's not to
say that you know you're you're wrong i
just think that it's it's hard to hard
to predict how it plays out
yeah i mean i think that's useful that
too maybe push against some of what I've
been saying some you may have heard the
distinction between transparency and and
knowledge that some theorists have
introduced and i think that the argument
for FOIA least in part as it operates
that would be it's not so great on
transparency just production of
information in the public sphere as we
might think or want but maybe it's not
so bad for knowledge in that those
people get stuck under FOIA at least the
journalists in the in the civil society
requesters are are highly motivated to
let you know what they found in to you
know kinda maybe even get credit for
finding it and that conduces to public
knowledge at that is like actual
comprehension ability to act on
information not just the raw data itself
although again i think that the the
pathway from transparency knowledge can
because even without some of the way for
you
operates now
great I'm so let me just another point
sometimes made about for which I don't
think really helps its case although
quickly which is there's been another
kind of use of oil that's really
blossomed in recent years which is its
use in removal proceedings for people
facing deportation immigrants facing
deportation they don't have a right of
civil discovery when they're trying to
fight deportation and lawyers in that
area figured out you can request through
foil what does the government know about
you with your situation and so there's
now I'm a very large volume of such
requests being filed with the Department
of Homeland Security and so i'm at least
you know certain people with certain
views on immigration say that this is
something to celebrate about about 14
and I do think for serving important
purpose there i would just say I don't
like its argument for it
that's argument for discovery rights in
those proceedings if if we think we
should we make that decision as a
society so I boy is is like patching up
little other parts of a society where
the laws aren't necessarily they are and
I don't think that's necessarily speaks
to for his virtues as much as to other
areas we might think about and maybe
i'll end with this before we go to Q&A
agilent I've talked a bunch about for it
what we might call for triumphalism
there are a lot of judicial opinions
that lyin eyes FOIA as as Bernie said
the supreme court once said a structural
necessity in a real democracy and you
and you can find a lot of other quotes
like that from Congress and from
journalists and from the courts and um i
would just suggest that for is not a
structural necessity in real democracy
some kind of transparency forcing
mechanisms are but there are many there
are leaks their whistleblower protection
statutes there's old-fashioned
congressional oversight there's
affirmative disclosure there are a lot
of other options out there as well
boy is just one of many mechanisms that
can get at this goal that is is it's so
widely shared I'm so I worry a little
bit about the kind of naturalization of
the FOIA approach like this is the way
to do transports transparency is through
the foil requests are based model that's
what we've exported to the rest of the
world and i think it has some some
predictable pathologies that the other
models might not have so i would suggest
that we should celebrate some of what
for is done at your 50 about the
triumphal this rhetoric about being a
necessity indispensable to the our
democracy obscure it's a lot of things
that aren't working so well with it
yeah let's go to Q&A and i am an
attorney i was 10 my question
I was a little enjoy opening Caitlin
Henry I'm afuera attorney and I'm
wondering how you think the for
improvement act of 2016 will impact
practices for requesters and for
litigators and so it is early versions
that I think this this act was was great
but it was going he was going to make a
real difference and there there was a
provision that would have strengthened
affirmative disclosure requirements
would have made clearer that Office of
Legal Counsel memos that our final memos
are documents that were documents that
that had to be released something
informative disclosure provisions all of
that got stripped away and so my
impression now is that it's still a net
positive but it's not going to make the
kind of dramatic difference that we
would that we hope to it would make I
don't know the details but my vague
recollection is that the change that
makes with respect to older documents
are much more significant and I you know
I'd never litigated a case involving
documents or 25 years old but you know
that those are important request to and
if it does make a difference there
that's that's great i would get me to
get cut away the deliberative process
kind of privilege after 25 years think
that's useful it it codifies the rule
that if three requests are on the same
subject the agency to make available to
everyone that kinda already was the laws
i read the the e4 amendment of 96 I
think it's useful to say it more clearly
and again but not a huge change it
powers modestly this organization the
office of government
cremation services ojas which is like a
new mediator since 2007 for disputes and
excitement that's useful to but i'm but
also a modest before maybe the most
significant piece of legislation was at
the very end it says in no new resource
no no no funding will will follow and
that being a huge proper for
implementation I think it won't make a
huge difference although maybe some not
do so much good either
thank you both for the work you do man
for coming and talking to us it's really
fabulous this question i have might be
out of scope and so we can let go but it
so Edward Snowden found delivered to the
world a lot of documents and they were
delivered in such a way that I guess
even if he were dispatched that they
would still be released on some time
line there would be encrypted and
distributed and certain people have
privileged to see them
my question is how much of that document
stash have we seen and how much is left
to be revealed and insofar as you're
able to talk about it for yourselves to
what degree have you been able to touch
those documents yourselves directly if
you know if this note i don't know an
m-80 yeah I don't know the answer to
that eat either i mean i know that
there's more to be mind i know that some
of the media organizations have records
that they haven't published or you know
published about but i don't i don't have
a sense of this scale of it we might we
go to learn more about that scope and
maybe maybe this is a question for
Arizona
okay great thanks
hi um I'm somebody who's setting like
archival sciences and I feel like a lot
of conversations always amongst
ourselves and we're not really tapping
into the network's we're demanding
transparency and really getting that
work done to you guys like work with
archivist a lot to demand transparency
because we are like the records managers
we are the people who you know have a
lot of say and records collections
I don't know what kind of working guys
do with that i don't i don't personally
really i I just I do think it's a
critical piece of not just for me about
the declassification system the National
Archives and Records Administration
administers declassification a large
part in there was this recent study that
it's the unhappiest place to work in the
federal government funding levels are
really pitiful compared to the scope of
the job they have to do I don't think
it's given nearly enough attention or
resources so in the foyer bureaucracy
the people who are the professionals
implementing it traditionally didn't
even have a recognized job category by
the opposite personnel management only
2012 to get that so I think it's a bad
reflection of our commitment to
transparency we don't treat well the
front line people who are administering
these laws and we and we we haven't in
particular declassification yeah I've
never never had the chance to work with
archivist but that wasn't a decision
that was just I feel like it's like an
untapped a library hours
it sounds right okay will be our last
question I think I'm sorry question
about balancing test so the I'm I'm very
much interested in how lenient or not
withholding the balancing test would be
in practice and I think it and I think
down Jimmy l2 and I'm brought this up
also implied that the courts tend to be
very differential and i would think even
the most independent part of the
executive branch would still be very
differential on the other hand
I so and I I I don't think we wanted
it's applied in that kind of very
withholding way on the other hand even
though i love Jamil's work come but I i
think that i think perhaps you would be
inclined to be to be a lot more generous
in giving out information then a lot of
maybe a lot of the general public will
be pulling too although of course your
work but very good very much benefit
from a standard that was more in the
middle as compared to the current
reality so I'm wondering um since the
since I don't see any branch of
government being inclined to be too
generous
I'm wondering about the possibility of
setting a precedent by having the people
outside government unofficially model I
more in the middle balancing test so
like I'm and one place where that could
be done is like in whistleblower
disclosures at sample public opinion or
deliberative public opinion to see was
this was this worth disclosing was it
not classic example chelsea manning and
i'm in the chimney
ok ok so the question is would you be
willing arm at how somebody would be
benefit from this would you be willing
to see some of the moral authority on
what should be disclosed to people who
might do something closer to public
opinion that might be more towards the
withholding and then you would be but
less so than current reality
ok I was not there i'll say quickly i do
think that there's a story in the way
boys involved about judicial incentives
that no matter how what you say in the
law about what they should do
no difference balancing we can't have a
ton of confidence that they will want to
discuss things executive doesn't and
that councils moving to some other
models i do think would help at least at
the margins have the balancing but i
think you're right i would just say that
on the one about the public interest as
proxy by what the people think poles or
what Congress thinks i would just point
you in closing here this great paper by
Yohai bank
her where he argued recently that if
people are prosecuted like SAS noted for
violations of the Espionage Act other
statutes for leaking they could have as
an affirmative defense a public-interest
kind of standard and they could make he
proposed specific indicators of serving
the public interest in a congressional
hearing result how much journals
resulted in other factor get his exact
list but he tried to operationalize this
idea of getting the public interest into
court in that case through a defense by
think it's a promising idea
okay thank you very much thank you