thank you thank you
hi and welcome to our panel on net
neutrality
my name is Jeremy peasant and I'm so
pleased to be working with these
accomplished panelists just last month
the decision for the FBI
there was a legal decision for the FCC
to enforce strict neutrality and it was
upheld in the DC Circuit what this means
is that we can move away for the
question of whether that neutrality
should exist and start asking about what
it means to turn this from a concept to
actual implementation i'm going to let
these panelists introduce themselves
briefly and then ask a question or two
to get things going but this is
ultimately their panel i wanted to ask
each other questions and take this
discussion wherever it may go within
reason i want to invite you the audience
to participate as well invite you to ask
questions periodically when or if
there's a lot of the conversation so
let's get started please take a minute
introduce yourselves each above
frankston been hacking for 60 some-odd
years and blue yahoo build my own things
and I resent having a provider who for
whom I have to ask permission mouth
federal lopez from May first people link
where a membership organization a
politically progressive membership
organization and alternative service
provider and obviously we deal with
technology primarily Internet
communications technology and do all
kinds of stuff within we were part of
the large coalition that one the net
neutrality thing from the FCC so we have
a besides the obvious interest we have
in it we have an interesting that we did
stuff around it
hey everyone my name is sam gustin I'm a
journalist I work at vice motherboard
and I cover tech policy thank you very
much hope you guys already motherboard
and I i cover tech policy and the FCC
and I've been writing about net
neutrality for almost a decade now
thanks for having us
I'm capable of assisting on ya okay I'm
ready for sea with public knowledge
um we were fighting the net neutrality
fight since basically its inception we
view it as a preservation of the
critical values that underlie you know
the ability of the communications
networks for centuries now to reserve a
gala Therrien values democratic values
and permission with innovation I'm just
as hell i made a I'm the local up local
academic i just finished up dissertation
work on the MIT on the political economy
of internet operations so who are the
folks that ensure the at least for the
time being non-discriminatory internet
continue that private set of networks
continues to go here into that
non-discriminatory common platform i'll
be starting a fellowship at Stanford
cybersecurity fellowship at the center
for international security cooperation
my view on network neutrality as I come
for I come at it from some of the from
from from the anti anti anti from the
competition policy element of network
neutrality that some of the original
stuff that Tim when a Christopher you
wrote about and i'm really interested in
distinguishing the non-discriminatory
character of the infrastructure from the
very diverse public private social goods
their provision to top that as a way to
evaluate some of these issues will be
talking about
great thank you so those last two panel
is actually touched on this question a
bit but i'd like to invite the other
three to answer what does net neutrality
be to you as a concept
um I seeing that neutrality as legacy of
the early days of telecommunications
which were acting like railroads your
provider carry messages for you
I see the future it's not enough to
really give us the internet connectivity
but it doesn't address the issue of who
owns the facilities they pay for once
you have a carrier
dependent upon your in the permeability
situation asking permission
the alternative is to start by only the
facilities and only seeing packets if
you separate the content from the
packets you are inherently neutral so by
having a policy that removes so if
somebody you know only the pipe you get
to travel but you get a lot more great
arm
I mean that trolley has a lot means a
lot of different things for me because
I'm a lot of different things but and I
anyone involved in the in the particular
net neutrality struggle it meant doing
things like going to lobby in Congress
and really really things that I had
thought after 50 years of Acts activism
I would never ever have to do in my life
and I had to end up doing them but the
main thing about that struggle that
brought home the question of net
neutrality to me was the community
involvement which I believe personally
others can disagree but I believe
personally was the tipping point that
want us that have to ccd decision
massive community involvement including
communities of color of which I'm part
you may have noticed as a Puerto Rican
map we don't get to tell our story
without an internet and unless we get to
tell our story
you don't get to hear our story in what
is in the essentially racially divided
society and in order to combat those
decisions divisions so that we can all
try take a crack at survival as a human
race
we need to tell each other stories and
the internet is the way that we do that
I remember as a journalist a commercial
journalist in the whatever it was seven
is late seventies early eighties arm how
fragmented and distorted was the
coverage that even people like myself
would do of communities of color when
you don't have that anymore you don't
have to because now communities of color
can speak with their own voices net
neutrality helps that happen it doesn't
guarantee it
but it helps that happen and i think
that was in some way the tipping point
that brought these communities into that
struggle because they realize that with
a different level of access and add two
to speed and service they would be
buried now I'm think you're afraid oh
that's a very good night Bob him
um so as a journalist what I would say
is that net neutrality is the
free-speech issue of our time it is you
know the principle that allows us to
communicate with the public and it
allows a groups like Alfredo's to
organize and obviously there's a
commercial aspect to it as well but it
really you know it's easy to take that
neutrality for granted but it is this it
is essential to the origins of the
internet you know the the fathers of the
Internet when they were creating the
internet they very much had this idea of
a of a neutral network and so in many
ways to fight over net neutrality is
really a fight to to codify the
intentions of you know the geniuses who
invented the internet so i guess it you
know to put in a soundbite it's it's the
free-speech issue of our time
great so to follow follow up on this
question now that we've got no we're all
coming from i'll ask what do we see in
trying to our current system social
political and technical that either
promote neutrality or work against it
but i think they need to step back
because you keep you the word the
internet without a really agreeing on
what it means the night thing about
words like the internet board band
they're really good because they allow
you to talk without communicating
without having shared meaning so I see
the technology of the internet or the
technique entirely separate from what we
do with it
so having a means of unfettered can
to the committee communications allows
the social goods allows these activities
and this is wonderful but we have to
step back to understand why so I go back
to when the internet sort of was just
skip button so much invented as
discovered because we discovered how do
you soft with a problem around lack for
provided with packet nets with internets
and the internet as a technique is
really the internet working technique to
expand these so if you have two of your
own networks we just plug in your jack
and connected you can interconnect them
and they become one where it gets
confused is actually took the time
traditional you dial up the bulletin
board systems a well and confuse that
with the internet record which is even
though that was a temporary hack so for
me the intensive technology work there's
nobody to pay
I just communicate like these roads and
sidewalks and it's not like railroads
will have to buy a ticket and can only
go its profitable to railroad and that's
why I'm talking about an approach which
removes the need for enforcing
neutrality by removing the need to sort
of have a provider or railroad in the
path non-text a lot of explain what that
means but the key things if we pay for
it away they paid for other
infrastructure we get neutrality lot
more and I think we need to discuss that
level of the unfettered technology apart
from the social policies good can you
repeat the question I was asking what do
you see enshrined in our social
technical political systems that either
promote neutrality or work against it
business and profit work against it
arm and the fundamental need and drive
to communicate to improve society and to
survive as a human race work for yeah
that's what I think
yeah i mean i would i would sort of pose
a rhetorical question to the audience
which is how do you guys view the
internet is the internet a luxury for
you guys
or is it an essential tool for commerce
for communicating for education for
political organizing etc etc so you know
the question is you know how should we
view the internet should is the internet
is broadband access a public utility
should it be a public utility like
electricity or water once you start
saying it should be a public utility
then we say okay are we going to have
rate regulation so you know the way we
conceptualize the internet is changing
and it's evolving and I think a lot of
the big cable and phone companies would
like you to think that it's a luxury
right you gotta pay honor 50 bucks a
month you know you don't need the
internet i remember a year ago I wrote a
story when the FCC Commissioner Mike
O'Reilly he said well you guys don't
people don't need the internet you don't
need the internet you know it's not a
necessity and then you have people like
tim berners-lee says no actually the
internet should be a human right i mean
deep you know
do people think the Internet should be a
fundamental human right so the way we
conceptualize the internet on is
changing and there's this tension
between commercial interests which would
like people to think that it's a luxury
and people like tim berners-lee who say
no it's it it should be a human right
and you know so it's more of a
rhetorical question about you know how
do you guys think of the internet and
you know are you willing to to fight to
to advance you know how you how you
think about the internet i agree with
Sam one hundred percent i would also go
a step further to say that it's pretty
much acknowledged by anyone who's not
the people that you mentioned that it is
a necessity I mean you need the Internet
to apply to jobs to apply for health
care you know to communicate with people
to basically do your jobs to do homework
there's a big you know discussion right
now about the homework gap for consumers
from a legal perspective you know we
viewed the FCC's decision as a huge win
for consumers because although it's
great to talk about
about you know having the sort of this
free sidewalks instead of railroads
unfortunately the legal and practical
reality we live in right now is that we
deregulated for many many years the way
that these private companies work the
access component of the internet so you
know you're differentiating between
access and content access is the only
part the title to applies to vs content
and so it became necessary when you
don't have competition you have these
big incumbents like the comcast in the
time warner cable's of the world which
is now charter because of course we
consolidated you need some kind of cop
on the beat to ensure that the
incumbents are not starting to creep in
and play favorites with the type of
content that you access so prioritizing
the ones that they have a an interest in
or financial you know investment in over
the ones that they don't and that's how
you know preserve the values that have
underlined all of the types of common
carrier communication systems since ya
last 200 years so I'm going out I'm as
may have become evident might my
description of what I do I'm an
infrastructure guy and I look for
interesting innovative ways to provision
infrastructure so when I think of
neutrality I think of things like the
internet exchanges in particular I think
of a great example which is the linen
internet exchange these guys on how
enshrined in their institutional fabric
the notion of neutrality they started
out with carrier neutrality where they
didn't want to place their inner
connection fabric in the facilities of
one particular carrier another they
wanted to ensure that anyone who wanted
to interconnect in the London area and
later in Britain writ large that they
could own that they could do so that
they can exchange traffic amongst
themselves as a community of networks
that are all have a profit motive but
they are working against the large
incumbents at the time the large transit
carries you don't have to send your
packet all the way across the pond back
just to go up the street in london that
when we when we talk about the ethos of
where the internet came from and where
this non-discriminatory character came
from i believe that there's a lot of
potential for innovation amongst these
actors amongst these amongst these
private actors that are often vilified
as going after just their profit but in
many cases when you when you go to the
network operator conferences when you go
to things like the rer conference of the
internet exchange providers they are
also speaking directly to how can we
improve the infrastructure in our region
viet your local metropolitan region your
sub region of Western Europe or parts of
Africa or kabah say in Argentina's a
fantastic example of an exchange that
goes out and gathers villages up and
says hey let's help you
provision infrastructure so that we can
both make money doing it but also expand
the expand the reach of this
infrastructure and provide better
quality services so I'm a I guess when I
think of the future of a future of new
network neutrality i would like to avoid
foreclosing on the potential for private
industries innovation that can start to
bridge the gap between pure private
interest and start serving not only
their common good but also garner some
of these collateral public benefits that
I've seen these communities create the
digital world coming to jesse has a good
starting point that there's nothing
wrong wrong with make your profit it's
really question of creddie align the
incentives and when you have the current
model now which is when we repurposed
and infrastructure that was used to
deliver television content and phone
calls but left the content providers in
control we have a conflict of interest
inherent conflict of interest and I
think the way you sort of incremental
path indicate says is if you remove that
conflict of interest market forces will
actually start to work in the right
direction because once the companies in
and we're going it's called over-the-top
you know you can now pretty much get
anything get a cable TV over IP and
sling got TVs even getting traditional
content once you've got companies whose
only business
is his kind packets it's going to
collapse into a Heracles neutral
infrastructure and won't be quite like
acid electricity's utility but those
costs money to maintain mean electricals
Micah generate water clothes money
that's what your generator to purify
whereas the internet is about bit so we
can have a business model the reasoning
of sidewalks as a matter of four is when
we create ourselves we do our own walks
we create our own content so you really
discussing how do we pay for copper
radios fiber and that is something that
we're gonna happen that's where the
model of passive infrastructure is a
better model than utility because
nothing to meet her question my arm
what if not neutrality isn't all that
arm
what if for example the major gaps in
net neutrality not in theory let me I
are their major gaps that what if are
their major gaps in net neutrality that
defeat the Democratic purpose of net
neutrality example we did see this with
cellphones initially that's been
tightened up a little in the reason to
clarify on that sounds cell phone that
cell phone usage was not heavily covered
in the network original Mandrell efcc
your friend to mobile access and mobile
access right the cell phones which is
what we use what people call use kids
cover yeah you know and i think almost
everybody in the whole wide world is
using them more and more
which brings me the whole wide world net
neutrality was a decision made by a by a
government governing body in the united
states of america
the internet is not contrary to what
some people may think is not does not
belong to the united states of america
and in and in a very very dramatic way
increasingly other countries regions and
continents are taking more and more
aggressive role without necessarily
protecting that net neutrality so is is
that a problem for us and if not then
how could it not be problem that so I
think that I'm just from a legal
perspective we need to keep in mind sort
of what the scope of the network
ality decision was um it specifically
applied and by the way
yes i agree that it was great that they
did apply it to mobile we pushed really
really hard for that because there were
a number of carve-outs in the 2010 order
that were not satisfactory from consumer
perspective and you know relating to a
lot of the things that Alfredo said but
we need to keep in mind that we're
covering access content the scope of the
FCC's authority under title to as
regulating these as common carriers
really don't have the ability to apply
that beyond the United States so even
though the internet is not is not the
property of the United States they're
doing sort of what they can to preserve
those values within the scope of their
authority
yeah i would just make two points the
first is that the comments about the
internet not being the property the
united states are absolutely correct and
literally as we speak right now the
European telecom regulator is trying to
figure out how to implement their
candidly problematic net neutrality
policy that they approved last spring
and I would encourage everyone to the
extent that you're interested you if
you're interested in this issue online
and kind of get hip to what's going on
in Europe because there are some
problems with the European policy that
was my first point
first the second the second point that
would make just with respect to
capitalism and businesses is that you
know I don't think you know I think of
all of us agree that capitalism you know
was like Winston Churchill said about
democracy is like it's the least bad
form of economic organization and it's
got a lot of problems but we have a
problem in this country which is a
problem of cup of competition or lack
thereof and it's not just in the
telecommunication space it's on Wall
Street in the pharmaceutical industry
it's in the airline industry it's in
that I mean and on on and so competition
is kind of the subtext of of all of this
discussion and that's one of the reasons
why net neutrality is so important
because without it
um you know baby basically you know
these a few companies could eat you know
basically just turn the it turn the
engine you know basically turned the
internet into the into the equivalent of
cable TV right where you know you pay
for tears and you pay for different
packages and stuff so you know one of
the most important things to do mind
about this discussion is that we have a
broader problem of lack of competition
across industries in this country that
needs to be addressed and I think next
week if you guys watch the Democratic
National Convention you might see some
discussion about this because antitrust
and competition policy is in the
proposed platform for the first time
believe it or not since 1988 just keep
competition in mine
thank you Sam I was I'd like to I'd like
to build on that a little bit night I'd
like to kind of throw out the idea of
like when I when I look at the network
operator communities that I that I that
I've studied I've had a lot of them
mentioned a lot of the favorite word
that they used as competition and I'd
like to throw out an example of that
again using the one of the newer
internet exchanges as an example but
also that out to see what the panel
thinks about this notion of cooperation
in the vein of not-quite chasing down
the the evil the evil image of
capitalism so arm back about two
thousand eight if i'm remembering my
dates correctly forgive me if I'm wrong
because dates are not my thing
arm Paris the interconnections seen in
Paris was atrocious they were like 10 or
11 internet exchanges many of which were
just propped up shells by the by the
local carrier so orange and free the
number of others have the exchanges that
were very dysfunctional they were purely
just trying to get people locked into
their facility so that they could garner
all the nice rent-seeking aspects of of
the inner connection business and what
happened was a number of the leadership
in the operator community in our
community came together and said they
actually sent out a survey to the
community they said hey would you guys
are like to see a a rational association
membership essentially a co-op a
cooperative
I'll internet exchange setup in Paris
would you like it if it were that were
run professionally and which you
actually pay membership fees for it and
the community rezound li said yes and so
this is an example and indicate the
three companies that uh that were that
were really that were that were driving
this forward google akamai and Jaguar
and one other company who always jumps
out of my head but you had to
international firms to local French
firms coming together to fix a
particular market for inter connection
and now what happened what what became
France IX is now one of the leading
internet exchanges in Europe and it's a
neutral exchange it is it is managed
again by that can be by its membership
but that's a bit to me that's a
fantastic example of and of private
actors creating innovative commonly
managed firm that helped that
essentially fixed the interconnections
work in that region so that is an
example of the kind of cooperation that
I see the potential for IC amazing
innovation that is somewhere between a a
a cooperative and a commercial firm
you've taken the elements of the best
elements of both of those to make
something sufficiently dynamic to keep
pace with the evolution of applications
and provide the infrastructure necessary
to support those but also have these
norms of neutrality that means not any
no singular large incumbent that may be
a participant in that firm can take
control of it and I can elaborate on how
they did that their governance documents
but arm that that that's an element of
competition that I think should be
encouraged rather than kind of these
have been chasing down the arm chasing
down these kind of and I'm not accusing
you of saying the evil empire capitalism
but i'd love to hear what the panel has
to say about that notion of competition
and the potential for that women are
within either the US or other regions
well i mean i would I was just say that
you know op i mean i'm not i'm not like
capitalism hater
you know like I'm not a communist not
that there's anything wrong with that
but far we've come what what what I
would say what would i would say is that
in order for capitalism to function
markets need to work and in order for
markets to work there needs to be some
sort of effective regulatory authority
and regulatory oversight
ok I think this is pretty sort of basic
tenets of how markets function from the
problem with the United States telecom
regulator the federal communications
commission historically has been
something that we refer to as regulatory
capture and a revolving door between the
agency and private business you
many of you will recall when Meredith
Atwell Baxter left the FCC and baker cjd
baker and proceeded to go straight and
become a lot straight to comcast become
a lobbyist for comcast
so this is that this is a problem talk
about regulatory capture i would even
suggest the term legislative capture
because you have members literally been
you know you can call me cynical we have
members of Congress you know and I'm
just gonna come out and say it who
basically are effectively on the payroll
of cable and phone companies and this
gets to problems with our campaign
finance system etc so the only point I'm
trying to make it i'm not trying to hit
on capitalism but in order for
capitalism to work markets need to work
in order for markets to work you need an
effective effective and independent
regulator ok let me respond to that
because i think the current regulatory
system is a product of basically sort of
a legacy view of you know what a
telecommunication the internet are that
you need regulations when you don't have
a good market-based solution and the
reason i believe a solution we can start
out in the US will go to the world like
when we first got the investiture in the
u.s. it started here and be basically
pt's broke up
I want effective couple wanted effective
marketplace that removes much of the
need for regulation i'm not saying
deregulate I'm saying address the
marketplace dysfunction that leads to
regulation and then marketplace
this function is that bit is what he
said before companies in the business of
providing content on the facilities at
the competition must use and that's sort
of vertical antitrust the silo if we
said you've either got in the business
of using connectivity or business of i
won't use we're providing when he been
careful of supporting connectivity those
two was separate we would then have a
marketplace we get a lot of
complications or who best serves a
community separate for competition who
provides the best content and there will
be a strong right now we have assisted
we make money by scarcity less
connectivity the more value there is
turns out it's we're going to get
gigabit you could have gotten current
fiber infrastructure capacity over
copper there's no need to go 25 we did
that for regulatory reasons not for
technical reasons so once you have a
functioning market place we're going to
see a lot of sort of implicit neutrality
so just one example cable companies
right now they can be a hundred percent
network neutral and keep ninety percent
of the capacity for their own content
just push accidentally doesn't go over
IP up so so it shouldn't be so if we
have a market basically that functions
will be a little regulation not much and
I think we'll get an incentive
capitalistic incentive to adopt the
approach throughout the world
yeah i agree that that's a great utopian
vision but unfortunately the reality
that we're living with right now is that
comcast and charter not to put anyone on
blast or anything
they basically collude with one another
to avoid competing in various
marketplaces so there's a great quote
from you know when we were working on
the Charter time warner cable larger one
of the heads of the company's was asked
what would you do if the
department of justice weren't looking
and the first answer what you should say
is well I'd follow the regulations
anyway what he said was i would call
comcast I mean that's the kind of
anti-competitive situation we're dealing
with and maybe it's because i'm a native
Washingtonian and so I'm born cynical
but i think that you know until we get
to a situation where you're not dealing
with that in every reg been sort of
every system the way that Sam described
it then you need someone like the FCC to
step in and say okay you guys are common
carriers and we're going to be the cop
on the beat until you start figuring out
how to actually compete with one another
so it was like okay this is a hackers
conference that you know user utopian as
you see if we're helpless and as hackers
you can do this you can bankrupt these
companies comcast knows it's coming
which is why i bought NBC universal and
keeps the legacy cable business as long
as we accept that now one thing I did
rise at Microsoft in nineteen nineties
you're gonna have to pay for each pc you
had just like your patrons for online if
you want an IP printer you have to pay
for that so that was why the market work
as a hacker i put the network as a
maximum i put that what we call The Home
Rule now I put the nap between the phone
company of providers and the house and
suddenly they could no longer charger
for each service and as a direct result
18t you have the clay is not a tea that
the AT&T of those days went bankrupt and
today's 18t is spc and this is in the
spirit that gave us the internet
interconnected a locally owned
facilities
yes we gotta make by decision to buy
tunnel through these carriers but we
instead of others if you've got a pipe a
consumer service using with hundred
people will say you have your 50
megabits service
well you and your friends are showing
the same pipe but if you and your
friends got together and you pulled your
resources to buy that pipe then they
would not be the ninety percent profit
anymore and if you start the edge you
started inexorable market process the
same one that bankrupted apt despite the
protection the FCC you will get changed
this is not utopian it's very pragmatic
thank you buy out our asking the same
question to ask you the same question I
asked you outside i mean i-i I have a
very very strong belief in in the
ability for people to invest their
intellectual capacity and doing all
kinds of fabulous things you see that
you see the makers communities you see
all these amazing things that are emerge
when people have the information and
knowledge to do something but
maintaining a and infrastructure of the
caliber of the internet and at the
growth at the speed of innovation of the
internet I just I just have to ask how
our leave the hoop how these communities
going to do that most these communities
or don't have the knowledge base of the
capacity to build that kind of stuff in
to manage it and um hello what what what
would you help how do you how do you
plan on paying for that I mean how do
you mean on maintaining it last let's
say that um one option only gonna say
how many I can see hands here
how many of you can maintain the shore
systems in your community you can see
I'm just gonna bother something i'm a
pauper sewers that is utopia a lot of
trust me to know I i can imagine the
result is your glowing device right
right yeah right
raise your portable flash lights up
answering not many know I don't said
expect any of you a friend of mine was
sure Commission trumansburg New York
doesn't know anything about source big
and hard people do it
he also runs my zone file and that he
knows how to do so they're basically you
can hire people to do but I ran to the
same thing in 1995 when he said people
going to run the home home networks
they're told it's impossible it's too
complicated
I just remove what's complicated and if
you hire people to combination of first
make it simpler but also hiring people
there how many people here would love a
job maintaining community network to
hire those people that I would actually
like to see some glowing device
responses 40 you know it's a jobs for
you people
ok in any case i'm saying is yeah you're
high people decide what your comp case
was all these systems that's not a
problem
the what's missing is an understanding
that the Bears first physically no
attempt the technique is easy that once
you understand how to do it
your powered you don't have to go to
recycle a phone company and remember the
danger in getting a recycled phone
company providing the internet today is
day no not know how to operate it
I know how many of you know that buffer
bloat that's because you like phone
engineers design an internetwork and
they basically make some fundamental
errors so definitely you can hire people
locally start your community and you
don't have to run fiber across the
country you buy it from existing
provider and because you have bargaining
power you will basically drive them
further further way and eventually an
infrastructure model takeover simply
because in a capitalistic sense it's far
more cost-effective you just have to
make sure that you're lying the Prophet
22 supporting maintaining infrastructure
right-handed profit coming from
rent-seeking rent basically many people
to really communicate and profit coming
from having advantage and only the wires
for selling content so I have a question
for Bob which is let's say municipality
or community town city wanted to build
its own municipal network but
unfortunately there's a state law that
prohibits the town from doing from doing
so what happened what do you do then
ok there there couple of answers what
one thing is you take the long view and
as a guerrilla you go where you can get
the job done and Google did this google
chose Kansas City because least
regulatory problems had run into that
was a primary reason for choosing Kansas
City for Google Fiber okay I'm not
talking about not talking about what the
hell let me company like Google talking
about mean you don't let me okay that
was an example so you need to find so
one thing is you need to find exam
in other words it and this is also why
I'm starting the private sector
department also things like that we're
gonna have the most influence so
sometimes patients is the answer now
there's a legal question which is if a
city put in fiber but did not provide
services they're not doing
telecommunications so that through so
right now we have a legal problem one
that that Sam just alluded to that is
actually ongoing which is you want
municipal broadband two cities
Chattanooga and the other one is eluding
me wasn't yeah
Wilson North Carolina yes tried to build
municipal broadband they were preempted
and there's now an ongoing lawsuit
preventing these cities from trying to
build their own broadband networks
specifically because of the fact that
AT&T went lobby the state legislators to
put in a whole bunch of secret laws so
that they couldn't build these out
yeah it's actually it's actually more
than how many of you guys are familiar
with something called Alec the american
legislative exchange council right right
which is better which is it's basically
in the incubator for essentially coke
backed state laws of dropping out across
the country
oftentimes the best of industries in
this particular case the
telecommunications industry is what
state by state by state by state and
rammed through these laws and I think
what it's about 25 states now it
that's a pretty huh let's keep it
network focus I'm not well but anyway
the point is so for for those
municipalities that want to do with bob
is talking about
unfortunately there are non-trivial
legal barriers to doing this and just
you know but that's what is struggling
call your Congressman but just once
that's what a struggle is if you look at
the gay marriage issue look at
bilingualism my ability to speak Spanish
in school we had to fight for that you
fight for it because it's an oppressive
society but nevertheless that's what the
situation is gonna be for one thing
let me just let me just background this
so the people you don't see you talking
too much that the and then you get
anything about how can I talk a lot so
no talking about yet and then you can
you can come in when I just say
something you know you can't talk about
net neutrality as a cure to anything
that's what I mean because it's not
worldwide
internet is worldwide neutrality is not
what it is fundamentally is a possible
model for how to arrange communication
and that model can be enacted a bunch of
different ways including and some people
are insisting that capitalism a system
that i think basically became outmoded
about 20 years ago is still a vibrant
system that you could talk about the
cetera
I'm not going to get into any of that
what i'm going to say is that there are
many models including what you're
talking about that stem from net
neutrality but you've got to act on them
and you've got to continue struggling
you can't just sit down and then log on
and say oh well we want this is a one
nothing we want FCC decision in one
country of an entire world and that FCC
decision is not applicable as you're
saying to the localities so of course
ATT that's what they hire other people
for to go behind your back and to mess
up what you the gains that you made so
you gotta fight and you know that's what
we mean we continue to say you know you
have to build a movement that defense
this stuff otherwise hacking is not
going to mean anything it's gonna be a
hobby
you gotta build a movement go ahead ok I
i agree with a lot except that you can
also use hacking is a tool sure that no
one example of the negative example
yours is utah you try to think of
utopia' which want anymore of
infrastructure and basically that they
were resisted by legislation but they're
too prominent one is kind of laws but
the other problem is you had people put
it you know who who forced it into the
mold of bro quote broadband broadband is
a business model for only a pipe and
selling services on it that was a
resident gateway so you've got two
battles you've got one of legislation
which says you can't compete in Brooklyn
but the other thing is the framing your
infrastructure in terms of all broadband
so one of the is so young so the up gay
marriage things example if you work
nationally
you can you know their end runs around
local community but it takes time you
got it's a long game but the other thing
question is if you don't mind you
infrastructure of broadband but you say
stockholm you just pretty I'm putting
past the fiber in the streets i'm not
doing anything not saying how it's lit
up and then you can let other people to
light it up or the creative other ways
to work around it because trying to
educate legislators on these issues is
expensive which is why the people teach
some of the people the most money so you
need more gorilla workarounds to
redefine the problem to set examples and
i think most important to remove the
econom Macbeth fit only the facilities
which is why i mentioned the example of
the simple thing and map the network
address translator essentially argue is
what bankrupt and AT&T was their
businesses monitoring services once all
the salt packets that went away and if
you have multiple pipes in the cities
and you separate the content from the
date from the bits the profit goes away
great i'm gonna cut in here i'm gonna
ask the parents one last question but I
also encourage the audience members to
start lining up at the mic for your own
questions just don't trip over and so we
give them like certainly can we turn off
the lights a little bit so that the
panelist can see him up
great so one last question and then
we're going to get to the audience which
is I'm have been hearing a lot of clear
themes from all of you here namely it
namely it sounds like that wewe there's
an inherent sort of conflict of interest
that's what I'm hearing a lot in terms
of whose interests are at stake in which
ones are sort of driving the bus here
arm before we go forward I'm going to
take a minute to go backwards which is
sort of the question how did we get here
you know when the network when the
internet was first created or whatever
you want this network or device was
first created it was in the hands of
governments and academics and you know
was the definitely an inclusive model
what sort of translate what happened to
get us to this point where and then sort
of where do you think what were the key
moments of that and that's going to sort
of help us suggest where we need to go
in the future
oh that have been this very lonely so
let me the short version
is that we use words like
telecommunications and all these things
we fit things that old models that's
normal
so we accept we took we basically fit
the we use words like accessing
everything to make it look like a
time-sharing system it's another version
of a well as another television channel
and you know we we look at the content
we look at the web we get it so we have
a lot of confusion and you know back
when I was a kid who first doing this
are you know it was just totally apart
from get the academic things and
basically things got lost in translation
I mean that eight if you want long as
you have a pet but then again i would
say um you know again since I combat
from a legal perspective there was a
vast sort of de Regla Tory pro company
not movement but if evolution over the
course of i would conservatively I would
say 20 years since 96 act but really it
was more since the computer one computer
to decisions where you had a sort of
increasing consolidation into the hands
of a few private companies that was just
sort of enabled by a an administration
that was very Pro company and didn't
really take into account the
implications of the fact that the
network was supposed to really belong to
all of us
yeah i mean i would just say that and I
we should get two questions but really
the origins of corporate consolidation
actually go back to the seventies and
Robert work and the so-called chicago
school of antitrust policy when
basically this philosophy of an address
policy said you know we should only
enforce antitrust laws in a kind of
econometric with in econometrics
rationale and that laid the foundation
for the deregulation started in the
nineteen eighties and that is what sort
of brought us to where we are to the
unfortunate place that we are right now
alright sounds like it's time for
audience questions so in the interest of
time
yeah we'll look deeper into sharp
we can began wrestling with some element
of virtue or ok it's on down
okay so I want to ask about the practice
of zero rating zero rating is is the
practice work prize piece that are
essentially charging by the bed zero
rating is the is is uh cutting
agreements with certain of service
providers and excluding them from the
permit charges and so I guess my
question it is is getting back to zero
rating itself whether whether that
should be split off from the rest of the
net neutrality debate or whether it
should be part of it i mean we've had
situations where in the past in the past
and isp that was providing VoIP services
thank you lakme we get the concept again
you know i'll take it cracked generating
generating is a lot of people think it's
the kind of crucial battle that we're
fighting right now in the FCC's open
Internet order is everyone familiar with
10 rating is the most part generating is
when that is when a wheel yeah you're
better wireless company exempt certain
service from data caps right so the FCC
is taking a case-by-case approach zero
rating but the problem is your rating is
that it creates an economics incentive
for consumers to choose a particular
service over another service and that
has the result of creating the kind of
discriminatory environment the open
Internet rules were designed to prevent
so um you know I it's an ongoing
investigation right now at the FCC we'll
see how it plays out but there are a lot
of people who believe that the FCC
should take a more proactive and
aggressive stance to to crack down on
this practice because again it could
create the kind of discriminatory
environment that the rules were designed
to prevent i would say just to jump on
Sam's point you also have certain cases
certain business practices that
basically analyze your writing that are
more problematic than others so for
example we we filed a complaint public
knowledge it
on comcast stream TV which is not zero
rating per se but they were basically
creating false scarcity in the network
and then exempting their own services
there by incentivizing the consumers to
use those so those are the types of
really problematic practices that you're
starting to see that kind of circumvent
net neutrality without necessarily
running specifically afoul of the rule
five minutes organically just went very
briefly in generating but there's no
difference between zero reading my mind
and cable content just because it goes
over IP so why fight that battle
bracelet really is important that these
people as these yeah I by the way well
you ain't gonna last
yes next hi um I'm an activist in
cambridge massachusetts trying to bring
municipal broadband to the city and
we're sort of best case and that we
don't Massachusetts law as liberal and
explicitly let cities do this we have a
ridiculous amount of money we have a
receptive city government and a
population that wants to do it i'm with
you know Bob on the dark fiber and
compete on the level but the most
powerful argument we're getting against
this is 5g I'm talking afterwards okay
um you know we don't have to do any of
this because 5g is coming which ok
comment do you have a question yes
what's the counter-argument and also you
have better
what should I be watching for to keep
this network neutral begins looking 5g
basically the telco just trying to keep
the business model live past the point
of death
yeah i mean i don't know who's making
that argument but 5g is not even gonna
be here until you know it's not gonna be
like for four years so the
you-know-where as we often say wireless
is not a substitute for for wired access
that that's what i would say thank you
um you were too when you're talking
about capitalist solutions there are two
things that I really didn't understand
about what you're saying
first it seemed like you had this idea
that people could pull together
and by pipes and it seems like we is for
Bob or for the entire panel i'll go to
my second part which is more to the
inner panel one of the prerequisites for
capitalism is that you have a free
market one of the prerequisites of a
free market is that competitors can
easily enter and exit the market with
infrastructure this is physically
impossible for a lot of reasons ranging
from we don't want 3000 fiber buyers
going through our cities with constant
road work tearing them up for putting
that on poles ought to the fact that
they aren't expensive to put in so when
you advocate a free market solution and
the market you're talking about
literally cannot be free
how does that work well we will we don't
need we don't need a lot of fiber you
know multiple fiber lines first of all
everyone should support dig once
policies when you dig the street up once
you lay the fiber and then maybe we'll
think about a wholesale model where the
fiber is you know essentially sold off
at least on a wholesale basis to to you
know market entrance not owned by that
cable company the quick thing is we
don't have competing sidewalks we have a
way with getting competition for
providing cycle
ok you got two minutes left so great
i'll make this really quick in 10
seconds or less per person please tell
me what you think are the most hopeful
and the most scary outcome of the way
things are going on their current
trajectory most people and most scary
under trajectory of what net neutrality
in the house workers will get over the
power house will discover the power
yeah the one thing to themselves up
robust but uh most helpful is that we
have a had a chairman and a commission
over the last several years that has
actually finally increased competition
and preserve the net neutrality most
hopeful is the involvement of people of
color in the net neutrality struggle the
first time they've been involved in fcc
struggle and the scariest is we got net
neutrality internationally and they
Pete coming at us and all different
kinds away so i guess if i were to say
the most hopeful I've got kind of
already said it is that is that private
actors can recognize that the public
good is in their benefit and is in there
is in their economic interest the the
scariest thing is a is titled to
becoming one of the instances where the
FCC decides to stop for bearing and
start to really exercising the broad
arsenal of mechanisms that has at his
disposal is chosen to forbear on all
right we got two questions left mr.
Franks Frank's behind you is just
ringing I might have to do it after ok
that's fine I'm could I guess we could
discuss around the comcast nbcuniversal
statement you said in regards to the
content why its power or con but I'm
just saying the fact that the separate
the tube is out and the perpetrators
thank you
we like this last person go doing for
all of you do you think that preventing
vertical integration more aggressively
could help solve some of these problems
with onto on multiple levels of the
content creation the content
distribution and the hardware whereas
likes a google owns both YouTube and
YouTube CDN so they can control both the
theatrical yeah the short answer is yes
and I think you're going to see in the
next administration um depending on
which political parties in the house
you're gonna see you're gonna see more
enforcement on them
vertical antitrust issues for sure Great
God willing let's have around for our
panelists
[Applause]
stick around maybe for the next five
minutes or so in the back speakers the
Budapest room is available as well six
floor for a continued discussion post
talk
[Music]