so thank you are very much
my name is Benjamin Dean I'm a fellow
for cybersecurity Columbia University
I'm also the president of my own company
iconoclastic advise companies on
impending ways of technological change
and the consequences
welcome to our panel this evening on
smart cities and blockchains new techno
utopian dreams or nightmares to start
with Alaska bird you and James to
introduce themselves and then i'll give
you some background on the subject
hi I'm Brigitte icard I'm a doctoral
student in communications at Columbia
University and my research is on Smart
City experiments in the United States is
this movie right right now in the in the
meantime
hi my name is James I am an adjunct
professor at nyu's ITP and I have worked
in the early stage startup space for my
entire adult life and I very
occasionally get to write about
interesting trends going on in that
general ecosystem and yeah I guess
that's about it lets me
ok so to start with this panel is not a
light panel we are not just dismissing
new technology out of hand
it's just that with each part of hype
around new technology we tend to forget
the misuses and missteps the past when
we've tried to recreate societies using
new technology
my hope is through this discussion we
can be a bit more deliberate and who we
develop technology for and cognizant of
the ways in which technology will almost
certainly be misused the word utopia
comes from Thomas More's book of 1516
with come to define utopia's in one of
two ways an ideally perfect place
especially in social political and moral
aspects are impractical idealistic
scheme for social and political reform
his jewel definitions july the issues
with utopian visions and once they seem
close them within hand at the same time
wildly idealistic throughout history
technologies are played a key and
recurring role inspiring in this
enabling utopian attempts
my hope is next 10 minutes by examining
some of the history around techno
utopianism we might find some lessons
about the probability of success of
future technologies like smart cities
and blockchains we might avoid some of
the missteps the past so to start with
I'm gonna take you back in time to the
nineteen-thirties Henry Ford the famous
industrialist the Ford Company had a
problem with automobiles it was that he
needed more rubber so his solution to
the problem
were laying the jungles of brazil Henry
Ford decided that he would go to Brazil
and build what he called for land
fordland er a factory to produce Robert
the largest in the world that would be
based on you would use the tailor's
assembly line technology of the that
time and he would export what he called
the healthy lifestyle which was
essentially American culture hamburgers
and working from nine to five
the problem was that for didn't actually
sit down and look at where he was
building his Factory and exporting his
technology and his healthy lifestyle he
didn't hire any agronomists or botanists
for the rubber plants that he planted
and so they all ended up lighted and
dying the workers revolted because they
weren't used to working nine-to-five in
the Amazonian son and eventually
literally the city revolted not want to
be deterred for decided to try again
just down the river with predictable
outcomes the lesson there is that when
you abstract people away from the
environment in which you introduce
technology your misspelling certain to
spell disaster a few decades after that
this fellow comes along hit this is walt
disney and towards the end of his life
he had one big final dream he wanted to
build a futuristic city implan community
which would roll around the testing
input testing of new technology
originally called a progress city but
you might know it as the experimental
prototype community of tomorrow or epcot
for bought some land in Florida and
there he decided to build an
ever-evolving showcase of modern
technology it was to be a city without a
good where the government was corporate
government people were left the the
winds of the disney company didn't died
before the vision could be realized and
so it was never actually established as
a city that nobody wanted to really move
there anywhere anyway given the
restrictions on their lives there was no
land ownership and no voting again the
disney company decided what you would do
it later evolved into disneyland in
Florida you might call it a utopia in
one sense and here's the lesson maybe
for one day it's lovely to run around
the controlled environment and
commercial environment of Disneyland but
to think that you would want to live
there for your entire life
the winds of the disney company does not
sound like a successful plan for techno
utopianism at about the same time the
modernist architects had discovered
prefabricated buildings reinforced
concrete and decided to rebuild entire
cities for the automobile low-carb uca
had a one project according to leaked on
top again it was never realized but the
ideas were borrowed you see this picture
here 60 story buildings each separated
with their own contained officers and
shopping below in the end it was picked
up and used as a model for brasilia the
capital of Brazil for some reason Brazil
ends up being the playground of techno
utopian dreams
the poor Brazilians and predictably well
perhaps not so predictably it start
given that the wild dreams that
corbusier and the modernists had
brasilia has been criticized for decades
about ignoring residents habits and
desires and for his lack of public
spaces for open encounters corbusier did
not like any chance encounters he wanted
everything ordered on a Cartesian grid
so what's the lesson here top-down
implementation of Richard optimization
is not necessarily what makes for a
utopian society is almost certainly
going to be a recipe for disaster
more recently peter thiel of paypal Fame
sponsored for a number of years finance
what was called seasteading the idea was
that you could find autonomous
self-governing cities built on platforms
in the ocean outside the reach of
national state governments these were
meant to be places to experiment with
new technology no regulations no laws
the only laws created by the people who
live in the seasteading platforms they
be no welfare no minimum wage a few
restrictions on weapons the seasteading
institute says it'll give people the
freedom to choose the government they
want instead of being stuck with the
government they get that sounds an awful
lot like the united states already and
with no welfare I guess there is a
minimum wage but it doesn't move a few
restrictions on weapons i'm not exactly
sure what Peter was angling out here but
his vision was never realized i guess
he's been sidelined with trying I guess
the monumental task of putting the end
to your car and I guess once he finishes
his his endorsements the republican
national convention to make America
great again he might get back to the sea
setting makes seasteading great again
the final example our give is one closer
to home here and it's John Perry Barlow
in the mid-nineties and I like John
Perry Barlow and his declaration the
independence of cyberspace was really
part of this internet utopian movement
of the nineties of quote some words
government's the industrial world you
worry giant flesh and steel i come from
cyberspace the new home of mind behalf
of the future I ask of you the past
leave us alone you are not welcome among
us you have no sovereignty where we
gather of course for a little while that
was true but for anybody that was
sitting in the panel just before on the
crypto Wars you know that very quickly
government's did reestablish their
sovereignty in cyberspace and continue
to do so
continue to do so until today that
lesson here is detective that existing
power relations while technologies might
have the promise to change them in many
cases the technologies end up being
co-opted by those powerful institutions
that previously existed the technologies
make them more powerful they don't
undermine the power in the long run and
so we turned to the smart cities just at
the moment that Edward Snowden points
out to us how the internet instead of
being a you at all for freedom and
liberation can be used for surveillance
and control the Smart City utopians come
along and start laying down blueprints
for cities of the future at this point
I'm going to turn to bird true because
this is your area of expertise and I
wonder what exactly is a smart city
well thank you I'm so the question is
really interesting because i always ask
that question when I do research you
know in the field working with people
who either have a vision for the smart
city or try to build tools for this my
city and I never get a straight forward
answer it's certainly a fuzzy concept
with like neither a single definition or
like a one size fits all type of framing
but in general terms it what we might
see that the continuation of all the
example
that you've just given how can we
leverage technology to solve urban
problems and create this sort of utopian
land where the quality of life which is
again a very kind of a concept is better
and we govern ourselves freely and it in
some cases way more democratic than
whatever we have now but when you go to
the field and look at the Smart City
experiments that are being conducted now
it's either on the extreme of creating
these controlled environments that is
really mostly centralized high on the
surveillance side of things mostly built
from the ground up such as the city
called Songdo in Korea or mother city in
abu dhabi there's like one company
behind it and the local government and
they pretty much decide on how the city
should operate so not that far from the
examples that you've just given like one
vision on the other side it's it's not
that utopian actually so my research is
based in Kansas City and for those of
you who are familiar with Google Fiber
Google's broadband project Kansas City
was the first experimental city that was
selected by google and it wasn't
imagined as a smart city in the first
place but once the fiber-optic cables
were laid and the city sort of kind of
realized that this was becoming a thing
like cities were becoming the center of
tech innovation or kind of the next
frontier in for the Silicon Valley folks
they loop cisco in and they've
there now instituting it hasn't been
fully implemented yet but the most
expansive smart city project in the
United States what that means is still
very you fake but it seems like the idea
is to kind of have this model of
data-driven urbanaz them which is again
like one might read it as either this
like corporate vision or the look or
busy is like urban planning vision where
everything is like you track of area to
track down every movement streetlights
you put you put sensors everywhere smart
traffic and then the city becomes much
more efficient hence a better place to
live
my interest is to see a have those
imaginaries are kind of raised by the
collective of the city not just the
second largest companies or even the
local government officials but the city
residents and I have a lot to say about
that in a minute but also how they are
implemented and how that is actually
affecting cities that are already places
where we see the most inequality where r
wherever not necessarily actually on the
same page with the government's in terms
of privacy like not even without
thinking about these new technologies
like the existing within the existing
frame so these are my interest one thing
that I wanna say though and I'm actually
really curious to hear your reaction to
this so when i do this research and talk
to entrepreneurs are hackers who are
working in this field of smart cities or
urban tech or sometimes Civic tech but i
think the terms that i'm working with
are mostly smart cities and urban
technologies it I I don't see the same
techno utopianism that Ben has just
described not even actually Barlow's
vision necessarily i see more mundane
more practical processes where
you know we're just going to put sensors
around and see how it goes rather than
this is the city we want to live in both
at the conversation level but also at
the implementation level and also i
think to me most importantly at the idea
generation level so they expect that you
know most entrepreneurs are hackers I
interview or sort of moonlight in my
like in a dated on a day-to-day basis
don't even think about the problems you
know like they don't like when i asked
them so what kind of problems do you
want to solve i get like a you know a
big list of potential problems that they
could solve one day but like I'm like
what what is the immediate concern that
you have about this particular city
which actually has a very concrete
problems instead over and over again I
see the real constant I mean not the
concern that the real goal being
unlocking new of flows of information so
if we put sensors around and if we
generate more and more data like which
is the immediate goal we're going to
find out about new problems that we
didn't even know existed which is which
is something that I'm still trying to
figure out like what that means instead
of looking at the immediate problems
like all looking at the city as a data
generator of some sorts but i think the
most immediate concern i have other than
understanding what that means is like
app then if all the kiosks and sensors
and like all these tools that we use for
data tracking become the new normal
we just stopped paying attention to it
and the way you know I don't have to
tell this crowd about this but the way
like software works for these folks is
like it's all like constant fixing
constant feedback constant reaction to
it up but without actually having the
big conversations that needed to be
there in the first place so one example
i really like is
NYC so then you might talk a little bit
more about it but if you don't know
already like this is part of a
consortium that Sidewalk labs and this
company called intersection has new york
city is not necessarily a bona fide we
want to be a smart city type city but
they're very interested in this field of
urban text so David's like put in place
these kiosks and kiosks are for some
reason are very big in the urban text my
citi field to like turning these like
pay phones into portals of data which is
a very expensive definition of what they
do but one thing they constantly do is
to collect information about us without
actually telling us what is going on
behind so do you want to say a few words
about it
well that's something i'll pick up more
detail sunday at 11am have a dedicated
session to link NYC what I will say
though is that I haven't yet heard the
g-word so in Kansas City and and you
mentioned in the second side will
intersect
yeah intersection your intersection
sidewalk labs the question asked is who
decides what a smart she looks like and
and that's going to bring up the g-word
yeah so um so the G word is a google i
guess in the specific context so the the
example of google is really interesting
especially in terms of what Ben said
about for landia like not looking at
where you build your tech so Google
Fiber emerged as the like
next-generation broadband super fast
internet that's like hundred times
faster than whatever you know the
average American has now and kansas city
was this perfect place for it because
the public utilities are kind of
centralized it was easier for Google to
both arrange things with the local
government but also implemented
the ground but they created this model
of not if you build it they will come
but if they wanted we will Beall so the
the plan was to say hey neighborhoods if
you're interested in getting google
fiber just chipping ten dollars and show
us that you're interested which will you
know signal as to us that it is worth
coming to your neighborhood and we will
come and lay out lay down the fiber
optic cables what obviously happened was
a the middle-income upper-middle income
neighborhoods who are already paying a
ton of money to get internet access or
like oh yeah sure like same prize faster
internet just ten dollars like there you
go
a lower-income neighborhoods which are
kind of the urban core of the city found
that amount quite outrageous and they
didn't have internet in the first place
so during the build-up phase the google
had this website where like if your
neighborhood has enough interest it was
turning into if i'm not mistaking green
and the other parts were yellow or red
and you know one like sort of already
rich or the better of part of the city's
was green as the interest phase was
going on and the poorer not to mention
mostly people of color living
communities were staying yellow to the
extent that like the map pretty much
looked like a once-upon-a-time redlined
map of Kansas City and google was
rightly accused of at the time i read
digital redlining that doesn't
necessarily mean and i'm going to kind
of leave it at this point that like
Google was trying to deliberately
discriminate against a certain part of
the city I I i don't think that was
necessarily the case but they
had no idea how to kind of adapt their
business model or whatever
implementation model that they had in
mind to the realities of the city which
is you know again and again we what we
see when we try to solve problems off of
living and breathing city with
technology so I'm gonna leave it there
and maybe we can discuss more about like
how we can prevent those familiar
mistakes
no I have an idea but I open up James if
you have a question or comment
yeah sure I i find the smart cities
movement of perplexing for sure
at the very least it seems like it would
be nice if whatever I think of the
trade-offs and whether they're worth it
if there were a lot of openness to the
data so there is a google who is
involved with smarts initiatives in
place like Kansas City or New York and
then there are a variety as you
mentioned other companies that are
involved in this of both in the United
States and internationally
what kind of track record are we seeing
so far in terms of how open the data is
to the taxpayers who are paying for it
well and not in the case of like NYC not
at all and I mean the corporate model
almost precludes them doing that which
is yes oh yes and now um so definitely
not in the case of Lincoln YC although
that's being discussed negated
negotiated whatever so you access to the
data for the public access to the data
the city definitely has access to the
data is definitely can demand the data
that's being collected from Lincoln YC
like when you plug your phone in there
to get connected to the internet or make
a phone call that data collector IP
address
mac-address clickstream yeah so the day
to work alone
yeah so the data that i am talking about
like you know what happens when there
are cameras sensors on your own
streetlights that track movement or
I don't know other types of sensors in
like parking lots because they know they
want to have efficient traffic
management in cities that kind of data
at least well first of all there's no
framework to regulate that right now
that's an open question and I don't
think there's enough interest from the
at least for now like from the privacy
community that we're having these
discussions at that large-scale in
kansas city specifically the
algorithmically manage data is owned by
cisco as it happens internationally too
and then the city has raw data which
they will share with the public so
that's for Kansas City and there are not
many other cities where we can actually
look for examples but that's the current
situation quickly what is
algorithmically manage data min here um
if I mean I I don't I mean whatever
dashboard cisco created which is their
corporate you know it's a tree city
yeah okay yeah to analyze and like
Purdue like you know develop new
products to probably sell to other
cities in the future and that's pretty
much their business model like that part
is obviously not open
yeah yes mostly and our citizens
fantastic
yeah so I mean to come back to your
previous question about so you know
where you go from here what solutions
struck me in your description of it
helped projects managed that are people
who are working with developers working
on it you were saying well let's see
what problems come out of the date and
if we don't find any let's collect more
data and then we'll find the problems it
strikes me that if they wanted to find
the problems that people have in cities
why don't they just ask people what
their problems are that I i have the
same question
I mean I like honestly if anyone has any
ideas I'm more
I'm all ears up yeah well I mean it
solves everything
yeah I well I maybe i don't know but i
think that that's definitely like this
big
I y combinator this CC company funding
to recently actually had this call for
research first but I think they're gonna
move on to developing products are
invested in products like asking how to
optimize the city like that's clearly a
concern for entrepreneurs or hackers or
programmers these days but I should send
it to Brazil do they gonna live there
and see what about our Zilla is actually
a big smart city center and it's pretty
much a failed experiment there too yeah
he solved the problems that were built
in 180 brasilia by adding more internet
and stirring yeah I'm conscious of time
and you know the other half of the talk
today is on block chains which very
interesting this I i love this project
and this picture because the big nation
i'm picking on them a little bit because
they're not the worst offenders
the idea is that you can add blockchains
disintermediate decision-making and in
that way solve governance problems like
land title in Guatemala and have
incorrect birth certificate notices and
so you'll take everything that is good
about Bitcoin and then apply it to
problems are nothing like Bitcoin and
hope that it you know it fixes the
problems like the internet didn't it's
james i'm gonna hand it to you now you
know give us a quick issue most people
in the audience familiar with
blockchains a Bitcoin but if you just
give it on that and then maybe why do
people see so much hope in in at all
that is like a hammer doesn't mean
everything's a nail right yeah so
blockchain it's I think it's pretty
pretty pretty easy to the groc there's a
lot of a complexity that goes on in the
way that these
user or explain but it's a database it's
a database that's a more generalized
version of bitcoins of bitcoin is a
currency blockchain is will the new the
the so-called blockchain to point out
implementations will allow for say a
currency and some kind of program or
instruction built around exchanging that
value they are fully distributed which
makes them very interesting and they are
transparent meaning that there is
everyone can see what everyone else is
has has done so when bitcoin is referred
to for example is anonymous
it means that there's not an easy or
direct method of correlating a Bitcoin
wallet ID with an individual but we can
look at the sum of those transactions
over time so and yes and so blockchain
yeah generalized version of this and
then it nation
I have things to say so the distributed
nature blockchains and the fact that
they're anonymous are two key features
that people think and it's immutable
alright so people really like that that
they are depending on how you're looking
at it really really hard or impossible
to to modify retro actively you know
without there being a record of that
modification so I neglected to explain
here with the big nation it's the
attempt that they say the world's first
blockchain powered virtual nation is
going to put marriage land titles birth
certificates world citizens ship ID on a
blockchain the leader bit nation
Suzanne tempelhof sees the future this
way all laws should compete on a free
market and be subject to the same
reputations people are I guess a bit
like on yelp we should all of our
marriage certificate should be judged
based on whether or not people think
it's legit marriage i wonda I want to
dig a bit deeper into this idea that so
Bitcoin has done a relatively good job
of having a borderless currency that's
kind of a means of exchange not very
good store of value but it doesn't a
decent job of that
yes it's a cheap way to exchange
currency across borders compared to
wiring in such so we're going to move it
but we need blood changes other problems
like land registry and and birth
certificates
I wonder what is it about a distributed
anonymous immutable ledger that is
needed here and what problems are we
solving well the fact that it is
immutable is awesome
uh but i think that i think that people
there's some disconnect where we think
about what we we should be I decoupling
decoupling on what we are trying to do
with how we are doing it so we see a
blockchain and we assume that it's going
to solve the problems that existed
before say without difficulties in ghana
with land usage or maybe we for some
reason see a problem with the way that
marriage licenses are granted by states
states meeting like a federal
government's ours will state governments
the United States and I guess that
people perhaps they feel that they throw
their hands in the air and say whatever
we're doing now isn't working
this is new let's try it and I do think
that there is there are things about
blockchains they're awesome but i do
think that there's a lot of treating
every problem like a nail going on when
taken booted you have any comments or
thoughts I had when you guys were
talking like describing it
is there anything necessarily Democratic
about it or is there a democratic
promise because that's something I keep
seeing in my own smart city experiment
so this is more like even the idea that
you're going to put kiosks around that
are in beta mode and people will
constantly give feedback not necessarily
being aware or not but you know by using
it it's more participatory and more
democratic so that's kind of the thin
definition of democracy that I usually
see in my research I wonder if there's
kind of a similar version going on and
get nations or block chains or whatever
right I wouldn't necessarily say that it
can make things more democratic but it
does level it does level the playing
field a bit in that it limits the power
of the state to be able to do corrupt
things to be able to say this thing that
you own
well now you don't own it because the
records are very difficult to modify so
I'm going to disagree on that into areas
one so it might be immutable ledger but
who determines what's put on the ledger
know if you've got corrupt land titles
and the person is putting the entries in
the existing system is corrupt
what's the thing that this person is not
going to put false information on a
mutable blockchain that will forever be
so I don't know why I let you make your
second point as well
the other one is around the consensus
mechanism and for anybody that pays very
close attention to Bitcoin you'll know
that much of the mining power that now
pro powers the consensus mechanism of
bitcoin is based in China now the
decision of you know which block chain
is the true blockchain is kind of Don
assist it's a bit like a it's not like a
referendum you have a 51-percent
threshold you have to cross of agreement
a referendum there was one person one
vote but in Bitcoin it's the amount of
the hash rate you contribute to the
network so you can find concentrations
of power as we're finding now in China
that is highly on deck
attic at least according to that typical
definitions if you look at the the dow
hack the other week in the hardfocus
followed it with the theorem the theorem
it's one node one vote but because it's
pseudonymous is we don't know who
controls what nodes and how many they
control again it's kind of open to
gaming in a way that's very undemocratic
so the public nature of the ledger helps
prevent corruption however to be clear I
don't think the blockchain is able to
eliminate corruption
uh I don't think that changes anything
about human nature and I I yeah I I am
bearish on it from that utopian
perspective
cool it 730 is my understanding is we
have roughly 15 minutes for Q&A
unless either of you have any other
further comments I'd welcome people to
come up and ask questions if I have them
and and change that you mentioned before
we'd like the questions phrase to it in
the form of a question
yeah imagine imagine a question mark at
the end if it makes sense
good question so i hope this fate I my
name is pretty Dale I'm a journalist
who's covered cities in and I technology
with a big focus on smart cities and
block chains and I think a lot of you
got to say about smart cities is dead on
this last conversation about blockchains
I'm I I do sort of i wonder if i run
this body so here's the question i run
this by is this a compelling when I
heard about the idea of putting land
titles and blockchains I thought wow
this is a pretty this is a pretty great
idea right as a person who was bought
and sold the house and and realizes
you're doing that there's all these
different people who do this every day
and you do it maybe twice in your life
and they have a lot of different
mechanisms just to screw you a thousand
different ways over the course of like
buying a sign of home and one of those
people to very minor player player and
it is that is the land title people you
pay like 23 or two or three dollars
I'm just to show that there's no debts
on your property right well if you know
in in a place if all properties went on
to an immutable record which doesn't
have to be the blockchain by the way
just a boy
help change right I'm is on some kind of
you know record that you know all those
things are are put in there and are
logged over time and we sort of trust
that our system of government does that
you know kind of ok the price for that
particular chunk of the transaction
dropped to somewhere close to zero like
maybe like ten dollars and that's
billions of dollars across normal people
saved across the entire country right so
and sort of insert that same logic into
the world of personal debt where lots of
personal debts were also logic lot of
blood on the blockchain people screwed
left right and center there too because
of the fuzziness of those records right
so i guess like when I guess when you
put it that way you sort of think in
terms of brass tacks how normal people
could like possibly save some money like
that doesn't seem kind of that's that's
how it seemed sort of compelling attempt
to me just for that those small levels
mr. ? the question is that argument
compiling like you know like I mean you
buy it you know I'm because I because I
i see how you sort of this there's hard
high-level theoretical objections but
that's one where I'm you know there's
there's just a simple way in which a
bunch of money could be saving some
there's some logical efficiency so um
yeah
on one hand were discussing how experts
are you like say a property expert a
costs money but provide some useful
expertise and perhaps the blockchain
they don't need to but then there's the
issue of maybe only once or twice and I
in in a normal person's life to doing a
transaction I do worry that a blockchain
does not eliminate the need for some
kind of intelligent intermediary land
uses an example but I i am very
skeptical that if we see smart contracts
being adopted more that this would
somehow eliminate the need to pay lawyer
personally i would i would very much
like to have a lawyer involved in
documenting the details of my particular
smart contract whether that contract is
on a blockchain or not you have anything
bad version i would just point out that
thinking again about Henry Ford rubber
trees that your parish in the Amazonian
jungles the land titles in a country
like i'll use an example Venezuela you
throw a blockchain
you know and you say alright this will
fix the problem of corruption
record-keeping and contractors whether
the problems around record-keeping and
not because you can't keep the records
accurate is because the corrupt people
that put information on those records
and control them so it's lit blockchains
might help and they might reduce the
costs of grade but there are all these
other elements hard elements that we
have to think about a bit more at least
I've seen from the community around
throwing blockchains of problems
hey yeah so short
sorry this is mostly free storage you
but I guess obviously really answer so
that comment on that question about that
comment i work with some projects that
are used the term Pacific tech I know
that's like the least use but in a
satellite city of New York that's also a
sanctuary city so there's a lot of latin
american communities mostly from central
something obviously central and south
america over here and don't know what
they're doing here or especially in this
weird kind of satellite have techie half
very rural city and we deal with a lot
of like we realized very early on the
problem that a lot of people were
dealing with want to build these big
grand technical solutions to non
problems and we're approaching it from
more of a like start with the people
that are strolling first and then build
solutions to those problems and it's not
always technical solutions but obviously
there's a lot of overlap and is the have
you actually in your research like
seeing that few people actually trying
to do that first like problem solving
first
are there any examples that stand out to
you this is more like picking like for
resources
yeah um definitely not i want to say yes
in Kansas City maybe not a ton since I
feel like I feel like those models work
better when there is actually already
grassroots groups who are maybe more
socially or politically oriented and i
have yet to see those communities in
Kansas City embrace technology but I so
after i started my research I've got
really interested in this
ideal Civic tech and kind of like you
know like why do these like really smart
tech folks who are in a well-intentioned
in the first place wanted to carve their
space out and we don't want to call it
Civic tech instead of just tech you know
when the tech become not civic if you
look at the history like it it does
surprise me as a researcher so i do have
lots of examples i'm happy to share with
you like maybe after the panel mostly
from New York and some other cities in
Europe
yeah okay so maybe given the time
constraints we should have three
questions and then we can kind of take
whichever ones we think other once we
can address i got very quick one
dimension to be nice to have some
openness to the city data i posed the
question all three of you if it was up
to you it's your call would you apply a
rule that says all public spending all
public sector wages all sensor data and
all surveillance-camera feeds be public
to the citizens and we're gonna take
three rapid-fire yeah yeah
hi I'm going to talk about smart cities
something that struck me that actually
having been said they want to put
sensors everywhere but they don't talk
to people and I don't think there's
anything new I mean you want to look
busy but also like robert moses and
reading like about just other urban
planning and twenty century like they
always want to bulldoze the local
community they never wanted to engage
I mean they just never want to talk to
them so as researchers have to have a
mindset into how like why this is just
keeps happening I mean it's gonna be
like 80-something years where they just
like over to the plan from the top down
like never ask a local person what they
want to think like I would love to know
any insight you have into that I was
wondering if you sort of like get things
that make sense these are differentiate
the top-down philosophy enthusiasm for
the and get stuff with the idea that
we're going to sort of improve things by
building infrastructure providing people
with more tools i mean like to continue
to 30 years ago you probably couldn't
predicted all the things the internet
would do and I'm just wondering
something like or smartphones and stuff
like that something like Google Fiber
seems like i'm kind of surprised you put
in the same category
areas like the top smart cities because
it seems like it's kind of a case in
point of building a better technology
and kind of letting people use it how
they will and I know that like maybe
they didn't appoint most equitable
manner but some people say well Lacey
was more of a proof-of-concept to show
what it could do and the people in the
poor areas of Kansas City they only have
the same crappy internet that you ninety
percent of the people in the US have
kept him quickly pick up your I'm the
last question um just to make it very
clear I i'm not sure if the smart cities
idea like it's necessarily top-down I
think it's more of an open question
right now and the only reason and I and
I think this you know it like proof of
concept that Google Fiber did is very
very much
the kind of mo in the smart city
community like let's just do experiments
and see how it works
the only reason why put them all
together is because i think in my own
narrative since the alphabet city
sidewalk labs is because it has become a
thing and I know historically google has
always been interested in cities maybe
if not openly I think I IC fiber as an
example of investing improving i mean i
don't know how
however you want to define it you know
tech data file technology izing whatever
city is so that's one reason
Julie we're going from first to last
year
um if you want a transformation oh yeah
that's good the initial question right
Griffin yeah um so I i do I don't want
every every piece of every every atom
from any possible sensor to be
completely public no I am obviously
concerned about the cost the authority
of the dangers of identity being able to
identify individuals but I mean there's
a
you can really like you can do a lot
here where I think that you're you're as
far as i know the risks alone of course
as if some vulnerability if you were
like I sort of data or statistical
vulnerability becomes exposed then that
can be patched but I mean I think like
for example of the in a Southeast Asian
particular apparently a lot of sensors
around water usage if i recall correctly
so perhaps it could be a privacy
violation or at least a scary scary if
every time that my toilet flushed then
that data is that those data are
available because that indicates that I
or someone our home but perhaps if this
were generalized to my apartment
building and it's an apartment building
of a certain size they're already
differentiations that the city makes
their regarding rules of say i think
over four units are under I would be
comfortable that one of those toilet
flushes is mine
sorry I like to all those questions the
first one I'm going to very quickly
certain times of inflation yes sometimes
no budgets for instance there are many
countries where city budgets are
completely open in fact elected
officials emails to completely open
Finland for instance sky hasn't fallen
there and if you look at what WikiLeaks
down today you'll know that having
emails of elected officials open might
be a good idea
second question I very much liked as
well I maybe because we don't have
enough talks like this about the
horrible failures of the past so we can
learn from them and the google fiber is
yet there is potential day if we do it
in a way that's participatory and it's
not just the data is just not owned by
Google and sealed up forever out of
reach the people who generated it so we
have five minutes left
could we do three quick questions and
then three quick answers please answer
quickly so try to generalize what's your
opinion on how
the current issues surrounding money in
politics may be influencing who has
access as either providers of smart city
tech or consumers of the data in if to
sort of color that question could there
be conflicts of interests with granting
some of these companies basically
virtual monopoly status when they become
a de facto utility and we we've seen how
well some of these monopolies have gone
when verizon gets tax breaks to deploy
bios and then drag their heels on it in
things like that too
good comment and a question the toilet
flush is probably worse problem than you
think because the MIT senseable cities
lab is putting sensors and sewers so you
know how far upstream they put it
becomes a privacy issue but my question
is this i live in a city cambridge
massachusetts that's looking at
municipal fibers so you don't forget
google fiber but of course one of the
reasons we're doing it is because of the
Internet of Things and smart cities that
nobody can define but how how would you
suggest a city frame a discussion about
those things because the whole notion of
putting out sensors for data is a
common-sense one but then what
how would you start asking the policy
questions to try and drive this in a
sensible way
if I understand the tenor of this panel
correctly part of what you are asking is
why certain technologies are being
applied to areas where they don't appear
to be a problem or whether they're being
applied correctly so again questioned
similar to the previous ones which is
when the internet was invented we all
know that when the internet was invented
it had vision was very wild from what it
is today and many of the problems and
advantages broad we're not even
questions of solutions people were
clamoring for so ultimately my question
is how can we determine whether these
technologies will or won't solve
problems or improve our lives unless we
actually try it can I jump in
um so I'm gonna start with the second
question I i think the city's should
definitely have those policy
conversations do I have a direct answer
how no but i think one you know I think
one problem is obviously and this kind
of goes back to the question of like why
does this keep happening like these are
like some of these questions are framed
as expertise questions like tech folks
should be around the table and like
ordinary citizens may or may not
understand i think that's one way to
start you know by kind of finding a
common ground in framing those
conversations are not making them a part
of specific expertise but other other
than that I don't have like a golden
solution um and I do agree that those
experiments should take place to know an
answer to the third question and that
and that's something i always hear about
like oh like we didn't have these you
know 15 years ago and like now look at
all these amazing things that we're
doing and people actually think those
kiosks will be the city is iphones like
I've met so many folks who believe that
they they might be right but again I
think it's even while we were building
these smartphones we should have had
some conversations around privacy
inequality and data sharing and whatnot
that we're kind of like trying to catch
up later on so that's the only reason
why I
we should question these vision to have
a quick comment with 10
yeah um I mean it's the the data
collection I view as an input when it
comes to this smart cities and I think
it's a question of inputs and outputs if
i can just look at this in a very
general way so the outputs are what
matter those are the variables that you
can tweak whatever you can change and
there doesn't seem to be as much
attention paid to them and they seem far
limited and uncorrelated to the inputs
to the data which are being collected
okay thank you there's a common thread
through all three of those questions and
it's a great note to end on and I think
so often what we found with the pop-up
failed you Toby's of the past is a
top-down control process of application
of technologies to problems that they're
not designed to solve so if we're going
to go forward we're going to start using
these technologies in a constructive way
there's no problems delivering
technologies to people new ones
it's just when you kind of rigidly apply
them almost missing akley to problems
you don't understand and to people whose
interests that you don't recognize or
ask for that seems to be the the root of
the problem here and so going forward it
would be very nice with the smart cities
if there was more community engagement
and openness around decision making with
the block chains there are plenty of
ways in which we can implement
blockchains but again it has to be done
in a way in which has except that
there's a wider context in which these
technologies are used and that there are
unintended consequences that we should
be cognizant off before we go Natalie
chasing after a unattainable goal and on
that note for overtime
thank you very much for joining us this
evening for the discussion and I have an
excellent conference