welcome in
yes this is my talk on malicious
behavior detection with WR mine we start
the little caviar I have a function on
the timings this could be a 20 minute
job could be applied with it young but
it's look next so like the way I'll get
you all out room and I'll be happy and
get to lunch early alright
so Who am I mouki science or math
graduate graduated in July from the
University of Manchester I've been an
intern nzc groups in just over two years
now and on Monday I'm gonna start a
proper job you know become an advil into
big wide world and this photo is me for
a week ago when I was jumping off tower
in Australia I'm hoping that the Rose
didn't snap all I heard was bungee
jumping and I'll say I was less nervous
about doing that that answer right now
alright so what this top going to be
about this is going to be part of the
research of my final year project at
university so why give them up on your
project if I created a rudimentary
detection system built around WRI and
try to get a better idea about how to
view my works but also one problem
probably tackle some issues with where
comes to detecting a fishy focus on
living offline binaries or bobbins so if
you don't know these are binaries
executables which you'll find on Windows
operating system every day to come with
home with the build and you normal use
of them they're pretty standard so I'm
going to do anything what people find
ways for using them or using them in a
way trying to malicious activity so what
is WR mine this curry that toughest part
makes its it's not exactly a nice simple
concept to work with so the easiest one
that got was is an interface for
applications act
data provided by the operating system
and hardware components so what does
that mean well this basically sudhish
into the paper
it's basically you've got everything
every aspect of the operating system the
affinity book processes services to
start commands what you can think of it
there's probably an object which is
record WI represents where and if this
objects have properties associated with
them and we basically have all these all
this data all jumbled together and then
got ways of working with it to be a
protocol to transmit the data around and
we have this service that runs and this
service that manages that stuff and how
is its execution around them all right
so what's the most useful thing I found
and so when frame this text and system
was how do we query the data now to do
this w life has its own query language
it's called WQ are very similar tasks
you up it's got a few keywords they're
different and it's somehow more useful
features like joins and Union that kind
of thing but for all intensive purposes
are pretty useful and we have these two
objects here these are the eventful or
object and the event consumer object now
what we can hear winny's in the event
filter we give a we're given a query or
what the service will do is the service
will run it will query for it will look
for this brilliant and return the data
now what will we actually querying for
well we'll have you have look in a foe
on the right gives you a query so that
is looking for the instance creation of
wind and the process objects that is
named Mike Harsha
so it's pretty simple we look for
instances creative modified or deleted
and then we can pick one of these
objects which represent some part of the
operating system and it will return or
any data so in this case it will return
any process which is what starts with
the word what does the event consumer
objecting well leave a consumer get to
be linked with the event filter
this will run on the query data on the
return data from the query so what we
can do is we can run scripts we can
combine lines we can log events send
emails through it this whole thing
together with the filter to consumer
binding object which is just links or
two sort of service will run it looks
for the event filters it queries to the
data any days this return passwords the
event consumer the event consumer months
so what the example on the right what
we're doing here so we're querying for
any powerful object I mean how would
process object of the name PowerShell
and then we're going to run this VB
script on the return data so looking at
all this so this is where I got the idea
of trends in context we've got a lot of
data we've got a way of querying the
data or a goal way of acting upon the
query data so we can query for events
and that we can act upon them and that
gives us the basis of some bomb
detection so how is this going to run
out of it so the B on the right is what
we call more files that manage object
wanna now this is how we create objects
or one of the ways cream objects tax to
W my repository well neighbors stop and
this is just a stand informant what we
do is you would write it this is a text
file with right it would never use a
utility that comes with Windows called
Malcolm run that through and it will
compile the the tax kill hook and put
the objects into the WI repository that
they themselves will be queried this
will be my service back and look at them
we can read them and this is the main
way if we can use two things so did it
section system file is there so we get a
big well we're going to create some more
files so the each rule if you like we're
gonna cram more file we're going to have
event
shelter we should have pulled some
suspicious event this might be like
purchase tration service equation it
might be DLL loading and it might be
could be of various fun things anything
that returns
that's just look at it from our VB
script with it the VB script might
perform some additional checks if needed
it might be that yeah we want to think
it's a little bit suspicious we want to
try a little bit more we've got a bit
more functionality by reading the script
and then what we're going to do so we're
going to compile this mod file it's
going to go into our pod the tree the
service is then going to pull through
it's going to go through it finds your
men it runs it runs our script we lock
the event
biff-bash-bosh sort see ya so this is a
crudely put together diagram found out
with word up in ms word kind of
described wise but it's es we're gonna
have our detection systems and create
the more file it's going to work within
the building of my architecture the
service is going to run it's gonna
execute our script it's going to write
12 so what sort of things are we going
to be sending so I kind of split into
some more simples and then some more
kind of complex rules so what we're
talking about simple rules we're just
looking at things that happening the
behavior of stuff happening at one one
time so this might be looking at command
line arguments like I said so these the
11th one wineries that normal use from
is fine which is when a pack is trying
to abuser that's what we're looking for
Tricia's events all of the ways of
looking at that is understanding how is
being run and a good way understood how
is being run is what come on line
arguments beans so a great example of
this it might be PowerShell via road and
some of using the back exec bypass like
yeah that might be a normal or might be
an indicator to only indicators that
might be sufficient or might be growing
and code
again pretty normal but it could this
end here specialist and the floors don't
offer examples first I'm probably gonna
use PowerShell demotes just because it
works well with a lot of the examples
but Shaw a little bit of thinking think
some other other things that could be
happening yeah next one they look at was
looking at parent processes so we're
looking at not what's being run but what
is running it so again I'll get using
example a PowerShell is PowerShell runs
normally this run is parent practice is
going to be exploring on XE you know
storms justice click the power icon
opened up but it's get suspicious when
maybe you get Word or Excel sporting
PowerShell you know you're not probably
gonna have some kind of malicious macro
in there and then you can look over
other examples of the kind of check the
hierarchy processes so what all you want
so I don't be the way around this would
be you just call its florida exceed and
powerful I see that would get on the
first rule but then you're looking to
explore to exceed masking run from say
from CMD so you know that's special so
you've got a saw about looking at the
the behavior of how the processes linked
together how what parent process does
well from finding simple would be D are
learning so we're going to look at what
dll's
are being loaded into the process so
this uses the slow this is the query
right at the bottom and uses a slightly
different type of query will see from
the top to they're both looking for any
instance creation event the bottom one
doesn't use it just like these are
looking for the creation of something
this guy's own event is the modulo trace
which is event that comes up every time
a DLL is loaded into a process so what
this will return this will return the
name of the deal are being loaded and
the name of the process is going into so
the system that management automation
deal is
but powerful deal it's basically if
you're if you're running some kind of
power shotguns or you're looking into
that functionality you're going to need
this dll so obviously if powder loading
in that's fine that's normal behavior
but you may look at other processes
loading in anything
yeah that's not right something's going
on there I'll give an example of a
little later on and then that we have so
there are a lot of simple rules and then
I don't have to have any examples to
these we have some ideas and more
complex rules
so these are what you're looking at
maybe a bit of a wider picture you're
not just looking at what's happening a
very shortly and the first one is
looking at frequency based schools so
this is where you're looking at an event
might if you just happen once it might
not be suspicious if it's happening a
lot of times in a very short period of
time then that might be something that
you're looking at and you can run all
that with these WMI queries so if
there's a special clause but having
which is where you do like a select your
a been within the women clause in
keywords all about the period of time of
looking at removing one means within the
last minute
and if you then I'm having it maybe
having 100 and I'm saying this events
happened over hundred times in the last
minute maybe that's that big enough
something suspicious
and finally linking rules together so
again one process doing one thing might
not be suspicious multiple processes
doing slightly different things so you
might have the creation of file say my
Psalms written to deal fast death and
then they've run from dealer well maybe
that might be a suspicious event you
know they're not exactly
you're not exactly looking at that
happening a lot it might just almost
drop their malicious payload and then
using one of these logins to run it so
you can create those like that by
linking them adding you some line
logical operators into your commands
enter your queries you can get pretty
intense with it they can be as long as
you want
they match will you just lay by the few
keywords that you have all right and
yeah I said pretty sure yeah yeah if you
want more there is this market Humber
there's a the whole project so there's a
nice long read over fall which goes into
a lot more detail than Apple in today
and yet this mobile cook does one
example that will give actually house
can have a demo video for laps about
passwords it'll be alright
yeah the example the demo video is gonna
show is going to give example the deal a
lot everyone and this is a little most
fun part my project was working out how
it's because it's not something that you
see them all kind of thing so why that
was a bit is I've created a malicious
macro trying to malicious think that
Trinidad malicious dotnet 0 which had to
make but which was an unmanaged year
also could be loaded in by the word
process and I created malicious micro
and the macro load with live she had was
a one-liner Peng it loaded in this DLL
and random function this function excuse
and PowerShell and what that meant is
the macro had full capabilities of your
PowerShell commands yeah you could run
you militias payloads about this kind of
thing but never actually use PowerShell
if you looked up your practicing support
ourselves never called you know they
shoot is all coming from it with all
excelled IX e so this is like so there's
not a lot of indicators for something
that I've got you there upon a macro to
be alone so what we have there is an
example of the deal are being loaded in
and what will happen is that module load
rings event would be called Oh
systems automation dot management have
been loaded loaded into Excel by XE
that's suspicious
and we would have a good happen it's a
lot more interesting in the video but I
thought the memories were good but
watch it anacondas up but hey thanks for
coming I hope you've enjoyed it I hope
you got one job any questions soon
you're like handsome to fight those
pitchbook postures yeah testing it was
lengthy process especially the some
lights on the dl uploading rules that
was basically a runner rule
look at my logs how maybe like at one
point I ran it I just had it running for
about a minute and my log file had about
thousand entries that I had to go
through like work hard what is this
process doing it was one of the big
things this is a kind of a background
process that pre-compile a lot on that
do deals so I can notice existed so when
you're looking at DLL loading this wall
with load in so we'll do a little bit
pre-population before the process needs
them so I can have to light this that
one and then look back through log this
is a lot less thing is but yeah but
intense process so possi old things that
was around detection wanted to say bill
to prevent yeah so like not going to
detection I was just writing for logs
yeah kind of restricted by just having
BB scripts like that was pretty much all
be excused my heart it's not I finally
saw right in this moment it's it's old
for reason no one uses it for reason
there is a discount
I never implemented it but a good way of
getting around that would have been if
you implement in a college jet sure a BB
script can then will not call again but
come object could be written like C++ or
the seashell that gives you a bit more
functionality
you don't look there's more prevention
stuff so like this process is running we
think it's dodgy
alright let's fill operands are looking
at a more
yet more product if you're trying to
walk not using the comics is the
philosophy a good way of looking to the
notch like Windows notifications so like
what suspicious have had occurred you
could pop up a notification guess want
to check it money leave
yeah I'm call of I never really got
round time restraints a unique on had
enough time tapes monopoly but it's got
to be something that without how old
cabbage I just feel a lot more fit
thanks Jesus person saying okay yes yeah
Sevilla the the big downside of this
disease relied on the process name as if
someone's changing the person's name you
gonna get around them I didn't realize
this yet bit to lay out but they're all
they're all moving indicators you would
have a look for like you could then you
go to the thing is create an event for
the file modification event so someone's
saying alright I want to run PowerShell
maliciously I'll get change it its name
that make you look for a pop
modification os1 changing the name back
seat or DLL awesome blog and the new
credit is that would be an overhaul and
another suspicious event that you pick
up so people changing it into system
file is also not at all be tempted using
the same double your libraries I so the
best way to learning
yeah is to copy PowerShell today I
legitimate yeah I see and yeah I mean
yeah be good dipping into you then have
a look at so I'm crazy legitimate yeah
we told by something else yeah I don't
recognize that but that we get into by
adding some pot like so
by to the farm motor casing and just
change things it's like songs copying
stuff but I said or deleting stuff
actually it says in Texas as strong as
the amount of effort that you want to
put in to create rules like I think so
you have to like happy citizen part of
that days of my life to to stop people
doing so by that you had overalls which
detected people doing but if you just
have the basic will that them Fred stay
then yeah you're right so now if you
think internet that easy job okay I
think about like a minute lesser by one
by sure maybe is everywhere I'm gonna
like a lunch great stuff
[Applause]