well hello and welcome to knock knock
who's there uh identifying assets in the
cloud
uh my name is ben sadigapoor and i also
have tanner barnes here with me we'll do
a quick introduction in a little bit
uh for this talk today um on an agenda
again we're gonna do an intro really
quickly talk about why we were so
focused on the cloud i talked about our
solution and what we designed how we did
some mass exploitation and then talk
about some real life but on the examples
uh so yeah i'm ben sadigapoor i'm a
hacker husband and a gamer i'm the head
of hacker education here at hackerone
and i'm a content creator and streamer
so if you find these kinds of topics
with hacking and bug bounding uh bug
bounties interesting
uh feel free to drop in on youtube and
on twitch and
watch me do more of this stuff live and
i'll let tanner quickly introduce
himself
awesome thanks ben so yeah as he said my
name is tanner barnes i'm on twitter and
all the things that static flow so i am
a developer a pen tester
and occasionally i do some bug hunting
as well
my job currently is i'm at aeon cyber
solutions as a
pin testing consultant
full time some of the code i build for
the hacker community which is mainly my
focus is on github at that link and then
i do occasionally
do some live coding at coding with
static flow on twitch
[Music]
cool so part of this talk where it kind
of centers around our research in the
cloud so a natural question is why scan
the cloud
well um it's still cheaper there's still
cheaper to do it yourself than options
like census or showdown some of those
licenses can be incredibly expensive
and additionally who isn't in the cloud
right especially if you're looking at
your large organization's verizon a t
yahoo is a part of verizon
just kind of all across bug bounty and
the scene at large
pretty much any large organization is
going to be in the cloud so it's a very
target rich environment if you're
looking at
aws azure gcp alibaba digitalocean if
you're looking at just their compute
space so an equivalent would be like ec2
on aws you're looking at about 88
million different ip addresses right so
a large
large attack service that possibly has
bad bug bounty targets in it
so
it also allows us to see areas where
currently
some new resources are being deployed by
large organizations so we're seeing from
looking at our data where we're seeing a
lot of
quickly spun up and then spun back down
into instances at these large
organizations so they're using the cloud
for testing
some maybe new features and that that in
and of itself can be some very target
rich areas
next slide
right so kind of looking at an idea of
what's out there right so we took a kind
of a step a stock of
common subdomains or subdomain pieces to
kind of get an idea of what might be out
there right so
a thousand corp
you know subdomains uh 13 000 internal
subdomains which we found very
fascinating that something with the name
internal would be out there on the
public cloud
dev that's to be expected especially we
said earlier
looking at a lot of
you know testing environments that are
being put out in the cloud apis those
are super common nowadays to have those
spun up in the cloud
oauth is an example of oath as an
example of something specific to verizon
right you're looking at almost 5 000 of
those subdomains out there and then
yahoo the large and ever popular bug
bounty domain sitting at 108 000 it's a
huge
huge area
surface attack surface wise
right so now we'll get into a bit of our
solution how we were able to get at
those 88 million ip addresses right
so it's built and go
go routines are a huge
win and a good way to really make
something like this happen
that's kind of one of the hallmarks of
go is that it is incredibly concurrent
and can really help you knock out a lot
of concurrent type of workloads really
simply
at how it works kind of as a simple
thing it's really just a scraper for
cname and dns name records from tls
certificates right so
not a lot of magic really in the code um
but the issue becomes
it's really simple to write a scanner
that can pull those from a certificate
but the issue becomes now how do we
scale that to tackle 88 million ip
addresses
so this is my favorite slide i had a lot
of fun writing it when i sent it to ben
and some people they were really taken
aback and it was just a lot of fun to
build so
we ended up getting to a point where we
were able to do 1.4 billion unique
targets in 15 minutes
which ends up at a rate of about 1.6
million a second so the way we're
getting to that 1.4 billion
is we take those 88 million ip addresses
combined with some other
large ciders from bug bounty targets and
some asn's combine those all up into
about 535 000
slash 24 ciders which is slash 24 has
256 ip addresses
and then we across those
slash 24 stars we looked at 11 unique
ports so that's what you end up with
your 1.4 billion unique targets
across those ip addresses across 11
ports
once that scan is done we found about 28
million identified targets on those 11
ports and what's really amazing is that
all of that costs about 25 in aws
charges so
just
pennies in the bucket drops in the
bucket for what we're able to hit that
fast
uh for every great side of a coin there
is kind of a flip side that's not so fun
uh we learned a lot of lessons that
ended up with some maybe not so fun aws
bills along the way to that amazing 25
scan charge
we tried some really silly things with
the lambda you can do a lot of really
concurrent really fast things with
lambda they will not let you spin up 535
000 of them though and
that was found out immediately by a very
large aws bill
because sadly once you kick off lambdas
there is no stopping them so once you
tell lambda to run 535 000 it will do it
and there's really no stopping them
from a code standpoint
every bit of memory and cpu cycle really
matters especially when you're going
through that much data
so at first to get like a a baseline it
was really just kind of rough and dirty
but then to get that type of 1.6 million
you really had to spend a lot of time
with some profiling tools really cutting
out the fat from the software to make
sure it's doing the bare minimum as fast
as it possibly could
and kind of as a last lesson learned
you really got to be careful with what
who you're scanning once we had this raw
down to the 28 million targets
we wanted to try to get some sense of
what was out there on those targets and
we inadvertently ran into some people
who weren't so happy with that and we
got some really hilarious linkedin
messages from some csos
and some people really not happy that we
were poking around so definitely things
to keep in mind when building
large-scale tools like this
so more uh
past what do we do
you know with
all that data is so we have all these
targets right we want to know something
more about them than just that they
exist right
so we turn to looking at ways we can
enrich the data to really do something
with from a bug bounty standpoint
so the first thing we needed to do right
was take those 28 million targets that
came back and figure out which one of
them are bounty targets right so we used
a handful of resources there's a really
great
github repo that we'll get to a little
bit later that had a large list of kind
of pre-compiled bug body targets that we
were able to use to sift and then just
kind of our own knowledge of what common
bug bounty targets were so that was kind
of our first step right is getting just
a bug bounty table
of data that we can start looking at
once we have that data
a really interesting type of next step
to do that we got a lot of success with
was diffing the scans scan to scan to
see what was newly created right so
if you have a scan on monday and you're
scanning again on say thursday what's
really fascinating or what's new is
changed from monday to thursday because
those are going to be your most recent
and maybe most vulnerable targets right
so the diffs that we would check every
day uh really got us a lot of
interesting results there
another thing was checking for v host
discrepancies
so some of these targets
responded differently based on the host
header you gave them right so we we
built a tool that will demo or a demo
we'll release later at the end of the
talk where
you can take a host and it will check
that host based on access by the domain
by the ip address and by a host header
of localhost and it will check the
response links and status codes
to see what might be different there so
we were able to find some really really
interesting targets that we were only
able to identify
by checking those vo's discrepancies
um some of the last things we were able
to do things like pulling titles
responsible response links and status
codes in general just to kind of get a
lay of the land of what was running on
these targets
and that kind of
lent itself easily to doing
fingerprinting so we built another tool
that we'll be releasing as well that you
can
you can supply it a customized
fingerprinting list
and it will check whatever targets you
give it to see if they match those
fingerprints
next time
right so
looking at extracting bug bank targets
right so again 1.4 billion targets a lot
of noise
uh this was repo we were mentioning
earlier uh it's bounty dash targets dash
data
so
that was a huge help in kind of getting
a first start and first crack at what is
an interesting target to look at right
so we filter them at scan time so as
that scan is happening
we're kind of bifurcating the data and
writing them to two different locations
so we don't have to go through the data
afterwards we're just kind of doing it
at the same time it's happening
and this kind of gives us our first set
of targets to provide into further
tooling right
next slide please
sure so again like we said the dipping
obviously multiple scans
whether they're a week or a month across
are obviously going to have a lot of
overlap right when you scan on monday if
you come back and scan a month later
tesla.com is going to be in there twice
that's just a given tesla is not turning
their site off anytime soon hopefully so
you kind of need a way to filter through
that noise of what is an interesting new
target right
and again like i said it's most useful
for finding those newest hosts from the
most recent scan
another fun thing that we were able to
do with the diffing is it allows us to
learn really well
how targets are naming their hosts i
think it was a a really fun message from
ben about a week about a month into this
where he he noticed that he had
basically clocked that the way a certain
bug bounty target had named all of their
hosts so we were actually able to tell
ahead of time
what hosts might be in existence just by
looking at all these diff scan data over
multiple days and weeks we learned a lot
about their organization
and then we're able to do a lot of fun
things with just historically keeping
data so all the data from scans we've
kept archived in cold storage so if ever
we wanted to go back and look at a kind
of large sentiment analysis or just
a large understanding of how an
organization works over the months and
days and maybe a year we have all that
data and we can go back and learn some
really fun things from that
next slide please
right so the next part being virtual
host discrepancies right so after every
scan we take our targets that we're
interested in normally we would run this
against the diff results
is we're looking for the status code and
the response link for three specific
cases right when we hit it by the ip
with a host header of the ip address
when we hit it with the ip with a host
of the domain that it comes back with
and then the ip address with the
hostname of localhost and as an example
here you can see an a aem instance that
we found on a bug bounty target
that happened to be vulnerable to a
couple different things
that you can see very clearly here by
accessing it by an ip only we get a
response
but if we hit it by a
host header of the domain we get nothing
right so that tells us that there's
something there right they don't want
you hitting this or there's something
blocking you from hitting it by a domain
but if you come out and buy a p it's
happy to let you in
and so i'll let ben take it away with
some of the um
some of the kind of mass exploitation
and just exploitation as a whole that we
did with some of these targets
yeah thanks tanner again so we
we're trying to do things at scale and
uh one of the things that we forgot to
mention was we were originally going to
test this thing out for a whole year
uh but unfortunately we cut down our
timeline from a year to two months so we
really have to move quickly because we
want to get this in
you know we wanted to start doing these
talks uh this year instead of waiting
for next year so we cut our timeline we
had to get creative
and mass exploitation was a very very
big part of it
so how does it look like well you have
two options one you can either go after
a single target you must exploit the
same mistakes over and over that you
know they have made
or you go after
multiple targets based on things that
you have seen as a pattern across
multiple organizations if this doesn't
make sense right now i promise it will
make sense by the end of this talk
but let's talk about the single target
so for a single target you have to be
pretty much based on what you already
know so if you know where the deployment
process is like
how do they name the apis where they
store it
where are the docs stored and what are
the internal corporate sites so if you
not have that information you do your
you know basic recon you gather this
information
it makes it easier to deal with
so as an example
if you are familiar with the verizon
media bug bounty and you've watched my
streams online you can tell that they're
notoriously
very well known for leaving api
documentation behind
and to have this port 4443
that is very very interesting and a lot
of times it has some really really juicy
apis so we knew all this data and we
already knew all these things existed
but we just had to figure out a way to
access them across every
single yahoo.com or verizon media domain
and we'll talk about how we did that in
a little bit
but then there's a second thing where
you want to mass exploit multiple
targets you know what i call the
display and prey so you realize that
there are mistakes that are made
regularly by developers or
folks that are behind these assets and
you pretty much shift your focus to
things like non-vulnerabilities
how you focus on things like spring boot
jolokia you look for api docs because
you know you know everyone's going to
use swag or application model uh you
know again you look for sensitive and
internal tools that were supposed to be
internally hosted and accessible where
they're not accessible by the domain
directly but if you hit it with the ip
address it may give you access to that
github git lab jenkins or jira instance
so we keep all that in mind but still
we have to figure out how to identify
them and proper identification is a huge
huge part of this entire thing if you're
not doing this properly then you're
going to be always a step behind because
at this point you're dealing with a lot
of false positives
so how does that work well let's uh
let's figure out what we want to work on
first what are you going after
understand what that thing you're going
after looks like what makes it unique if
you're going after graphql what makes
graphql unique how do you identify it
how do you fingerprint for it if you're
looking for swagger documentation same
thing grafana springboot all that stuff
make yourself familiar with all those
uh different things that
make these applications so response
headers response body a specific
endpoint this could be a fave icon it
could be
a particular endpoint an api endpoint a
login page and so on
so let's talk about some examples if you
are looking for swagger swagger has a
swagger resources endpoint that if you
hit it it will tell you where they are
holding the documentation and it also
has a keyword in there if you look it
says swagger version and it says the
version for it so
in other words if i hit swagger and if i
saw if i hit swagger's
resources
and it has the word swagger version in
it that tells me i have api docs for
that particular website
another example of it is if you just hit
swagger api docs where the actual api
documentation are you want to look for
the keyword base path because they have
to by default specify where
the base path of the api is and that's
something that you can also go after and
look for where you're
searching for these things in mass
and of course last but not least graphql
if you ever hit graphql slash graph ul
and i want to say in almost every
instance i couldn't be wrong but almost
every instance that i have seen so far
it will return a 400 bad request and it
will also tell you that the get query is
missing
so again if you wanted to look for
graphql you would have to look for the
get query missing in return and make
sure that the response code
is a 400 to avoid any false positives
and if you're looking for things like
arfana gitlab they're all that's the
same way if for grafana's instance if
you hit slash
it's going to send you to login
and it's going to have the keyword
grafana in there and also there is a
grafana logo as an svg file that you can
always hit and see if it's there
to make sure this is an actual grafana
instance but all that is cool you know
we know how to fingerprint for these
things you know we did our we studied a
little bit of what makes these things
unique and what makes them
identifiable and we just wrote scripts
that did it for us
so now that we have all this stuff
what's next we have to use some tools to
be able to exploit these
so we use tools like meg meg is an
absolutely powerful tool written in go
by tom nom nom if you're not familiar
with tom go on github.com tom nom nom
sponsor is github repo and make sure you
use meg if you are doing things at scale
and you don't have the
ability to write your own tools like we
did and this is prior to what we were
building we decided to while we built
our own tooling and we have our
fingerprints let's work with tools that
are already out there and figure out how
we can do this as we go so the way mag
works it allows you to spray a number of
endpoints against a number of hosts and
what it does it saves a response code in
a file called index within a folder
called out so if you go cat out index
this is what the output looks like it
tells you where it's stored
and what the response came back it came
out 302 200 whatever
but also what it does is
it also saves the entire full http
response
in the in another folder within out so
it's out subdomain or the ip address and
it has the entire response so you can
actually read that afterwards to make
sure it's not a false positive so if you
can look when i went after netflix with
all those ip addresses
every single request that i've made
against those ips are saved within its
own file in that folder and out
so what do we do well we get creative i
love bash
and i'm pretty sure this is not the best
solution to
look for it but
we made a bash one liner that would
look for things and tell us if it's
there and i'll explain what it does but
again there's probably a better way to
do this but let's break it down and talk
about what this
one liner does
so the first thing that it does is it
grabs for the response code so i tell it
hey i want you to look for this
particular response code make sure it
came out as 200 400 whatever i'm looking
for
and then i want you to tell me
if sorry i want you to tell me if
the output of the last command
and can i restart that again
your one sec
okay got it
so what it does is it looks for it grabs
for the response code so if i wanted to
look for something that's returned as
200 it's going to tell me that and then
it's the next one is going to cut it out
and just print out the location of the
file so if it came back as 200 tell me
the location where you saved the output
of this thing
and we're going to make sure it's unique
and then we're going to feed it back to
an xrx and tell it to hey i want you to
get through all those files and look for
this particular fingerprint tell me if
the keyword that i'm looking for came
back in the response that makes saved
within the out folder and then i want
you to cut it up again and just send me
the ip address where this was found
and i made this whole thing the one
liner that i showed i put that into a
bin search so every time i type in
search i give it the two arguments and
it spits out every ip address that
matched that fingerprint with that
specific status code and i will give
some examples of that here in a sec so
now we're going to talk about how we use
that to eliminate false positives
so first i say meg i want you to
concurrently run it in 70 times and look
for swagger resources within all the
hosts that i have in host.txt
and we already know from previous slides
that we're looking for the keyword
swagger version
and we want to make sure it comes back
as 200.
and if you can see i know it's blocked
off but all the things that are under
that white box are ip addresses that
came back with the keyword swagger
version and slash swacker resources
same thing if you did with graphql i
said search for a 400 status code and
the keyword missing cut it up and just
gave me the ip addresses and every
single one of those had graphql on them
and did some really fun stuff with it
that uh gave us leads or potential
vulnerabilities
but all that is fun
but it doesn't scale with the automation
that me and tanner were working on
especially going after billions of
targets and you know hundreds of
thousands of ipads is through the bug
bounty cycles so i'll let tanner quickly
explain how we did this with go
fingerprint and why we did it
awesome thanks ben so right so you're
saying we needed something that did much
the same thing but that was kind of
hands off for us that we could just feed
in
our scan data to so that's kind of where
go fingerprint came from
very similar to a lot of other
fingerprinting tools it's there's really
only so many ways to make a tool like
that
basically what it does you give it a
json list of a specific fingerprint or
fingerprints multiple if you'd like and
the type of just a name for it that you
can identify when it comes back in
results
so basically what it does is
as our scan is complete we have a setup
where as the scanned data comes in it's
fed into go fingerprint which then uses
a really great go library called kali
c-o-l-l-y which is a
go
native
built
html crawler so it will take a url
crawl the data and then you can build
all these
iterators on those results to pick out
different things you want out of the
html data so that's basically what it
does is it takes our list of targets
walks down the html looking for the
fingerprints that we have and then sends
that back to us
in a couple different ways it writes it
to a file and we also have some kind of
custom discord hooks for letting us know
a little bit easier that way
now time for the fun stuff uh real life
examples and i have a few of them and um
some of them are very very
easy easy to catch because of the data
we had and some of them were strictly
based on the fingerprints that we did
so the first one is asset monitoring
like tanner said we figured out this
company was
naming things a particular way and they
were deploying things a particular way
which by default would give us a
vulnerability if we caught it in time so
what does it look like well
about a year ago uh it's a big shout out
to
space raccoon if you're watching this
eugene this one's for you
me and this uh we found this xss
it was on this site.com dev site.com
demo app demo app html and some
parameter had xss
reported a year ago
never thought of it again but naturally
as a habit i took that endpoint of demo
app demo app html and threw it in my
word list just in case it comes up ever
again
well it did come up
at some point it came up when i was just
hacking on random stuff on the site
and i realized that it's coming up more
often than i expected it so with tanner
who decided to feed this thing into our
tool and say hey
look for this demo app see if the
fingerprint and the fingerprint we had
was a particular javascript file then
the way the javascript file was named it
would come up every time in the html we
looked for it and every time we saw a
new asset go up on this company we would
run it against this endpoint to get an
xss report it and i think we caught
about six times at least the last time
that we looked into it we found it six
times and those were easy bugs to report
just by having the data that's
already in front of us
hunting for cves is another really cool
thing to do with uh
being in the cloud because a lot of
times that's where they deploy them they
think it's not accessible because the
domain doesn't work but you can hit it
with ip again
um i'm not going to talk about the
technical
information on how the cve with grafana
works uh this is an unauthenticated ssrf
ingram fauna if you want to watch this
talk you're more than welcome to look it
up uh ryan raider justin garner did a
talk for
how he found this exploit at activity
con with hacker one i highly recommend
watching it if you want to know how it
works i'm not going to cover it at all
on these slides
but again the way we did it um we knew
the fingerprint it's a 302 to login and
it's going to have the keyword grafana
in that instance and the funny thing was
um we also caught on halfway through
that people love to just
deploy grafana on port 3000
that was a default port for it if it's
not on 80 it's on 3 000 in a lot of
cases so we ran that fingerprint across
all these ports
and found a lot of targets that were
on port 3000 throughout our bounty table
and had the keyword grafana in them or
we had login with meg or through what
tano had ran and we made sure these were
fauna instances so once we had this
the exploitation this is where it get
this is where it gets fun so we pulled
everything in three thousand that was in
our bounty table this is what a bounty
targets that we were monitoring and we
pulled out everything that could have
been grafana we ran it through meg we
said hey look for everything that comes
out as 200. make sure it has a keyword
grafana give us all the possible
instances
and we even got a little bit more
creative we skipped the login
portion of it and we straight up gave it
a poc and said hey this is on aws hit
the ipl just for the aws metadata hit
latest and tell me if if you hit this
particular poc
and if you actually have an ssrf and the
keyword metadata comes up let me know
because if that does come up that's a
vulnerable instance because when you
we're abusing an ssrf to hit an internal
ip address that's deployed on aws by
default and if you hit latest metadata
is a part of that it's a folder within
latest so if it came back with all these
different ip addresses it would tell us
hey you have found a vulnerability
already we don't have to verify anything
else
and
that led on to getting some really cool
bounties
again i kind of like went over this
already a little bit fast but uh with
when we designed the go fingerprint tool
we no longer really had to run it
through meg we just monitored for
assets that were tagged as grafana
because
um the tool that tanner had ran already
was already looking for these
fingerprints
so this one was one of the funnest ones
this is a huge huge
mega uber corporation it's not uber i'm
just saying it's a mega big corporation
and they were very surprised that we
found so many instances of it and this
is because again we caught on to the
poor 3000 we went after every single
asset of theirs that was running
something on port 3000
and i want to say roughly about 12 or 11
different instances of this were
vulnerable for a single company
and that just kept on giving and giving
so that gave us a ton of good bounties
just by going after this particular cve
these are all again the same cvs on ssrf
with grafana instances that are publicly
accessible
but there are some uh take uh there are
some takeaways that you have to also
understand when you're hunting for cves
you don't want to report them too early
make sure you give the company
enough time to patch these things
because they're going to say it's a
duplicate because they already knew
about it you know you haven't given them
enough time it's an old day
just be nice play nice if you don't get
paid walk away you probably did it too
early
and then the biggest thing is just
because a company has multiple instances
of a vulnerable app
doesn't mean they're going to give you
multiple bounties but i want to say 9
out of 10 cases we ended up getting a
higher reward or bonus because we went
the extra step of
identifying additional vulnerable
instances
we also went after
more stuff than just that we at some
point sprayed
admin across all of our targets just to
see if anything comes back that says
there is a login on this page you know
it's redirecting to login it's showing
the word login it's asking for a
username and password none of them
really looked interesting
except this one instance where it was
redirecting us to this
mgmt
some path log in jsp
and the mgmt to me sounded like
management maybe who knows but when we
hit it it turned out that there is a
admin site and the credentials were
actually admin admin and that got us
logged in but again that is not a lot of
fun because
it's not really it's not that cool you
found an admin login they messed up and
they had um
the admin admin as their password
but
we want to get a step further we knew
there's impact here already but we want
to also see if this mistake was made
multiple times across this entire
organization
and see if we can find more of them so
let's talk about this
the url for the site looks like
wxyz which is the app name that we
redacted the permutation could be a
different platform if they were playing
on ios android whatever else
and then i wish i could disclose this
target is the website that we were going
after that always stayed the same and
the slash thing is after you would
log in
it would send you to that end it was
send you to that slash whatever app and
this was the core app wasn't just name
core app it had a very unique name
so it would show us so that was the that
was what we use for a fingerprint
so what we ended up doing is we went
back to our target
uh so i went back to our database and we
looked for that app name the xyz
whatever it was and we said give us
everything under this domain that we're
going after that has a xyz app name
within it
and we fit it to meg
and we were able to identify 15 hosts
that had the same exact login page as
this one and at approximately i want to
say 12 of them if as formula remember
allowed us to use the admin admin
credentials to login and they each had
access to user data piis and from what
they security team told us at this
company
it was that there was about a million
users data on there
and um based on the screenshot that i
showed earlier there were some server
updating things we could have done so
probably had rce by design we didn't
push it just because we already felt
that we've pushed our luck a little bit
too much by already logging into an
admin panel in a production environment
with a million users
data being on the line so we reported
immediately and that got us a bounty as
well
now this is probably one of the most
fun phones that i've worked on this one
allowed us to
get some really really cool data
in this mega corp that unfortunately
came disclosed but gave us access to
some really really cool internal
assets
so based on the spring boots
documentation we know that there are
different endpoints uh do different
things
two of them in particular are very very
important one is the http trace and the
second one is the heap dump the first
one gives you
the exchanged response exchange so if
you make a request if there is something
on there your cookies your headers all
of that is being stored in http trace
and the heap dump is obviously a heap
dump of the applications jvm
but on top of that if you look at the
documentation if you ever hit any of
these endpoints the content type will
always have
boot actuator inside of the header so
for the content type we knew it's going
to say springboard actuator and that's
how we could identify it
if there was a http trace or heapdom
available
well
working with
tanner
zlz and really really really wanted to
own this mega corporation so we went and
dumped every single asset we could uh we
realized that they used this thing
multiple times so we just dumped every
single asset and we spayed http trace
against all their domains
and we came across this http trace
endpoint on a
app we call it like an xyz but the
permutations were xyz internal prod
site.com with an actuator http trace
interesting it's internal and proud cool
um that gave us some cookies and
naturally you take those cookies
and you
[Music]
swap them out and you try to log on to
the application that's on there but
unfortunately i think that session was
expired something happened we couldn't
log in but that's interesting because it
tells us there's internal prod right so
we're looking at internal prod
of this app this version of this app so
that means there's probably a dev
and not internal just proud who knows
like there's obviously other
permutations of this
so what do you do at this case well you
try to play with these other
permutations we bring back to our
database we plugged in the keyword for
the app so xyz and we said hey give us
every single site that has the xyz app
name within the site.com and it gave us
four different permutations one just
being the
appname.site.com the next one being the
app dash internal and then third one
being the app dash prod and last but not
least the original one that we found
that had xyz internal prod within its
name
but
none of these were giving us any good
data but we knew that actuator http
trace was available on all of them and
once we started digging through all of
them
we dumped all the data that we had from
it and we realized people were making
requests to other folders outside of the
actuator where we were in so they were
hitting things like core dash corp
uh application
viewer and again xyz services so the app
name services was a folder that we're
hitting that also had some stuff in it
and it turns out that all of those had
their own instance of the http trace
that leaked more cookies and more
endpoints and more information that we
could have used
so naturally again you dump every single
heap dump in every single
http trace that you can you we we hit
every single one of them and we gripped
for cookies
and we tried every single cookie we
could get our hands on until one of them
hit
and gave us a login to that application
so to take a step further we realized
since this is an internal app
they're probably using some single
sign-on to make sure this cookie carries
over and it needs to log into other
applications that are owned by this
company
so we made a match and replaced
through
burp suite and we told that every time
we hit any of these megacorp sites
replace our cookie value with this
cookie that we just found
and let's see if it works and it did
work so we had some really cool internal
sites that this one had access to about
4 000 people all internal employees
probably email addresses and we could
you can see on the right side we could
have edited deleted uh whatever we
wanted to do
this one was some sales thing that i
don't understand what it was but it was
definitely internal and
it was related to sales
this one allowed us to manipulate i
think some user data stuff we didn't
want to mess with all this stuff because
again these are production sites
internal and it's a huge corporation
but again just finding that one cookie
that works because you leaked http trace
gave us access to a lot of good stuff
but there's a lot of lesson learned with
this um it wasn't easy again this wasn't
uh this was an entire sunday spend for
us between the four or five of us to
figure this out
so what we learned was
dig very deep find as many as these as
you can find look for cookies don't stop
for just cookies look for credentials
look for
keys look for
authorization headers it's not always
cookies they could have an api keynote
request and a parameter they could have
a header that has an api key they could
have
better tokens all that stuff matters
stop brute forcing is a huge one
because the more brute force you do the
more requests you do the more you're
flooding the http traces
logs and you're not going to be able to
monitor for actual valid cookies
and the best part of it all is again
this megacorp as we refer to them wasn't
the only vulnerable company
we ended up actually selecting a
number of i would say nine or ten
targets that we identified that were
using the same exact thing
and we ended up spraying it with the
same exact thing and we ended up just
getting more and more bounties as we
were
identifying them
i'll let tanner wrap this up by some of
the tools that we wrote to make this
easier and i think this might also help
a lot of hackers or internal security
engineers identify assets that shouldn't
be out there in the wild and in the open
awesome yeah thanks ben that was uh that
was a really fun week we
we had a lot of good fun there
can you go to the next slide
awesome so these are the tools that we
talked about previously that are out
there
for people to use so the first is again
go fingerprint so it takes a list of
urls and a
fingerprints.json file which has
those you know different fingerprints
that you built to look for different
things right and so you can see the top
right there is kind of the output you'll
get you'll get the domain that it
matched on the url that it matched on
and then after the colon you'll get
which
sorry let me start that sentence over
you'll get the url
and then after the colon you'll get
whatever fingerprint that it matched
okay i'm going to start over again
because my dog
my dog just stepped on a squeaky to it
yeah i'm going to go to it let's just
start the whole slide over all right
ready
yeah
so these are the tools we talked about
earlier our first one is go fingerprint
so it takes a list of urls and the
fingerprints.json which we talked about
was where you'll put the custom written
fingerprints that you have in the repo
we have kind of a basic one that we were
using for some testing
but you're welcome to write your own in
the top right you can see there the
output you'll get the url that matched
and then after the colon you'll get
which fingerprint that it matched for
that url
the second one is v host scan like we
said it takes a csv file or really any
file of the form
hostname ip import
and it returns a json file containing
objects that have the input target and
then the result for all three of the
checks might be a little bit hard to see
on the slide hopefully it's easy to see
but then that jason document you have
the target you're after and then it has
the
host name or sorry it has the status
code and then the response link for both
the three checks of ip with the host
center of ip
the ip with the host name of the domain
and then a hostname of localhost
right so this is a fun slide as well for
something we decided to do is actually a
little bit outdated uh the
current
sorry let me just stop how do we wanna
because we'll go back to this how do we
want to actually do this slide since it
is kind of cool just said there's an api
out there that you can hit and it will
let you get some of the data for free
and if you want to get more data we have
uh you know pay as you go right now you
can get access to our data as you pay
sure okay everything is there the api is
so they just have to register on on
recon that api.recon.dev well i guess it
is there yeah but it's not going to yeah
i'll just say that if you go there now
it's going to take you to it's going to
redirect you to our site and you can use
a site to you know get this data
all right
so along with the tools that we released
we released also an api
to give you access to this data we've
been compiling so you can go there at
api.recon.dev
uh currently you'll notice that when you
get there it's going to tell you that
you're missing an api key that's because
we've most recently moved this to
recon.dev
and you'll have to sign up for an
account to get access to the data so
it's very simple we have three different
kind of pricing tiers there's a free one
so you don't have to worry about we're
not trying to price anybody out of this
data so there is a free way to access
the data
you can hit it one domain at a time
and there's no need to do any type of
like periods or any sub domains you can
just simply put in the root domain
you're after and it's going to return a
json document with all the results
for that domain with both the dom the c
names and dns names that match that
domain the port that it was found on the
root the like i p address it would match
to and the
root domain that it matched to
so i'll let ben kind of wrap it up for
us
so conclusion um some of the things that
we did learn is understand your target
understand where to deploy new apps
understand how they deploy them
get familiar with all these different
tools and uh things that companies use
to deploy their apps
get good at fingerprinting understand
what makes these apps what they are how
does this be how do they behave with
certain things what do they return what
are the headers like just get to
understand them
it also created really good database of
your own uh you don't have to do this
like we did you can obviously use our
data but if you have a good way of
keeping data on your own and having a
database it really really helps um to
hack on these companies and get an
overview of what their assets look like
what is new what's old and what's
internal and whatnot
and just a quick reminder that a lot of
the things that i showed as examples for
vulnerabilities
just another just an example of all the
examples that i've shown are
vulnerabilities that were old tricks
there was nothing new but it just shows
that there are still a lot of
low-hanging fruit out there you just
have to understand how to approach him
and how to look for him and some of the
stuff that i showed like example with
the
heap dump
that is a really good way for a person
with bad intent or black hat hacker or
whatever you want to call them to get
into a internal
environment for a company and start
pivoting through and getting access to
more stuff or starting their own
campaign
don't just also don't just spray and
go after assets with generic word list
really go wide
understand how the entire organization
looks like
and then look for common things that
gets missed because you need to have a
login we need to have a cookie attached
to your request and really dig deep you
have to go a step further than just
again brute forcing with generic
wordless login and then do boot forcing
create word lists that are particularly
made for your targets based on previous
information and experiences you have had
with this if you don't have that that's
okay you can build that as you go but
always get take some good notes of juicy
and juicy information and points you
come across while you're doing your
recon
and hate on this last sentence all you
want but
a lot of people say that bug bounties
aren't worth it to make money
there was roughly about 50k in bugs in
this presentation
we just spent the extra time to learn
about our targets to know how to exploit
them and we went after impactful bugs
again the things that we showed you can
access a lot of this data through
sensors to show them to certain.sh you
just have to know how to use them
properly
you just have to learn how to manage
your data better and spend your time
seriously spend your time understanding
these targets before you decide to
attack him and go after them
i have this last line in there for no
reason
i just love this meme that was given to
us and uh
look into some of these talks uh orange
side did a talk on
path normalization at def con i would
definitely give that a look uh you can
see a lot of cves that came in the past
year are all caused by it
and this was a really big part of us
understanding a lot of our targets i
wanted to give an example of this but
unfortunately because our time was
really really limited
we don't have an example but look into
it i promise it's worth it it's a tip
for people that want to go beyond just
spraying with their word list
again thank you all for watching and a
big big thank you to
zayat zlz donut tom nom nom irb sam and
ryan raider and we appreciate you all
being here
cheers