hello everyone good morning good evening
good afternoon uh depending on where
where and when you're watching this and
thanks for um choosing this presentation
i'm far both for money and i have many
years of
research experience at security compass
and at
in academia and also in industry
and i'm taking a perk pro
product manager of security research at
security campus and previously i was
researcher and senior researcher and
lead researcher and my research
interests include privacy engineering
and includes security engineering and
considering my background the use of ai
and machine learning methods to automate
them
so i have divided this presentation into
four different sections
and in the first section i'm going to
talk about the opportunity and challenge
here here and why we're talking about
this so we're going to talk about
privacy modeling for cloud services
based on the compliance regulations so
there are three important components
here cloud services
privacy modeling
and
finally compliance regulations
so this is a very typical situation i'm
sure you have been
in this situation that you've had a
number of standards compliance
regulations laws that you have to abide
by and you have to comply with and you
were creating a process or a
product or a solution and you didn't
know how you can relate how you can
bridge between the
compliance mandates and between them the
actual tasks that you had to create for
the technology and
and the features that you had to create
with the technology this is the problem
that uh has fascinated me for a while
and i've focused on this problem and
threat modeling is
one of the very important and useful
tools for privacy engineering that tries
to solve this problem
so what is threat modeling so i
i looked at different definitions of
threats and one of the most
reliable ones and most coated ones are
from mistaken
160 that says that threat
is an event or condition that has the
potential for causing asset loss and
under desirable consequences
so what does it mean for privacy
so i'm going to talk about the challenge
that we have in privacy so
this code from benjamin franklin i think
actually summarizes our situation with
privacy it says it takes many good deeds
to build
good reputation and only one bad one to
lose it so in my opinion it's very much
um
very much related to privacy and in
privacy that the consequences include
uh find and replace reputational damages
and many things and many other
consequences that you can you may care
as a result
so the challenge is that privacy threat
modeling as a tool is not well known
not a lot of people know about the
privacy
threat modeling techniques that exist
in the literature and that's actually an
opportunity so by learning about these
ideas that i'm explaining today and i
will pro i provide a lot of references
and links
you will be ahead of the curve and
you'll you will be able to have impact
in your organization and you can go back
and apply those
ideas to your
problem
and then have it have a positive impact
and influence and contribution in your
organization and for the problem that
you are solving
the other
the other important challenge that we
have here is cloud cloud has a shared
responsibility model between the
provider
and the consumer and you have indirect
control over data and over the processes
so that also complicates
the privacy
engineering of cloud services and cloud
solutions
but what's the opportunity here so this
is my goal opportunity statements what
i'm saying is that with
having regulation-based privacy threat
modeling for cloud services we can avoid
all the privacy risks and we can we can
achieve compliance and privacy by design
with minimal overheads
so again throughout the presentation pay
attention to three different concepts
and components cloud privacy thread
modeling and compliance compliance
driven or compliance of their
privacy threat modeling
so in the talk i'll talk about different
privacy threat modeling methods and i
will compre compare and contrast them i
will share my own experience
with you and also the experience of
other people that have used them and i
hope that i will give you some tools
that you can use for your own
uh problem
so the next section will be about
privacy threat modeling so i have chosen
these four
um four different
uh threat modeling techniques privacy
threat modeling techniques uh from a
bells of different
methods from many from a myriad of
different methods that exist in the
literature so these slides don't render
correctly because of the
difference between the systems um
so the i have chosen linden qttm cptm
and privacy tagging and we have chosen
them selectively for a reason so linden
gets its threat from a threat a number
of predefined threat categories
cptm is first of all is mostly it's it's
mainly and chiefly
designed for cloud and it gets its
requirement from some privacy
requirements and from compliance qut tm
works on some privacy goals and i also
introduced the work that we had done
previously on privacy tagging
during this research i have looked at
all of the other methods and
only i only chose these four methods
to be able to tell a story but there are
also other methods that you can go and
check
um
including propane square press and all
of these links uh
take you to the research and initiatives
that have worked on different methods
but for the sake of this presentation
and for the for the sake of
conciseness and brevity i have chosen
only these methods but all those other
methods also have similar elements and
common elements with this one i start
from clinton
linden was
is the result of research at k.u leon
university and uh you can you can read
more about this in
thesis uh phd thesis at in 2010 and 2015
uh linden was inspired by strike so
you're probably familiar with the strike
that is
used for security threat modeling
so lyndon these are the steps in london
so you draw a data flow diagram
and then
you map linden categories to the end
elements of data flow diagram
and you find the threads and then you
prioritize analyze them and
design require mitigation methods
so if you look at this
the third the first three steps are
probably in the problem space you you
try to find the problem
and uh this
this is where we are focused today so
we're just paying attention to the
problem space finding the threats
so
i talked about
data flow diagram and linkedin so what
is linden you ask and what is data flow
diagram
so the
linden team define a number of
root threats
or a number of category of threats
and uh there
and this lindens actually and the
mnemonic is acronym for these
different type of threats
so
the first one is linkability so the
ability to
link two items of interest for example
you can say that you may not be be able
to identify the sender and receiver of
message but you say that
this person has has sent a message to
this person so these two people are
linked
the other
concepts that is
coded there is identifiability which is
clear that you can identify the subject
from some evidence
uh we have non-repudiation there which
is exactly the opposite of what we have
in
security
uh which
he though here it is a threat but in the
in security is it's a goal
uh we have detectability which means
that
whether something exists or not
an example of that
that linden
team gives is for example whether a
celebrity has a
court case or a
record in the hospital or something like
that
you've whether
you want to know if there is a record
but you may not be able to link it to
something or you may not
be able to identify it so it's not
disclosure of information but just the
fact that you know whether it exists or
not is detectability and then you have
obviously disclosure information that
has some overlap with cia insecurity
and an awareness which is being unaware
of the consequences of doing something
in the past now
or in the future
and finally non-compliance and you can
see how they have coded the entire
legislatory domain and compliance in one
threat
so these are different threats in linden
methods
so what's data flow diagram
so data flow diagram actually shows the
flow of data through a process or a
system so there are four main
elements in a data flow diagram
one of the elements is data store where
you store the data you have an external
entity that is normally a user or
administrator or other systems you have
the flow of data and you have a process
and also you have a trust boundary
and cross-boundary of system shows where
the sub elements of the subsystem
trust one another
so i've shown a diagram here and it
shows on on the top it shows the
architecture diagram for a typical
application and you see that there's a
mobile
device that connects to a web
application that is hosted in
an app engine and then it the app engine
collects connects to a database and
cloud sql
and uh you see on the bottom
on the bottom half of the page that it
shows the that in dft which it shows
only one of the processors in dft so
it's the user registers themselves and
then it's the data is stored in the
database so this you can see that you
can have for for an architecture you may
have many dfds which each of which
focuses on one process
so how do you do london
back so you look at different elements
of dfd for each element you try to apply
l-i-n-d-d-u-n
so you you look at user database and you
see
how linkability identifiability and
reputation and all are applicable there
so this these two diagrams i've taken
from
some from kim voice
2014 and 2019
papers and documents
the first one on the left shows
the
one of the threads and the sub dress the
subcategory of thirds which
they call concrete threads and the top
is like root thread so you break down
the root thread into some concrete
thread and do the study uh it's very
much like
if you are familiar with tank trees this
is directory with threads which is very
similar to attack tree and on the bottom
you see that you have to repeat this
process of applying linden concepts to
various elements of
dft
so for example if you have
five data flows you have to look at all
those five data flows and and think
about linden
uh and then see how they apply to this
situation and what what kind of concrete
threats they create so you have to to
start from the internet from the one of
the elements and then go back and create
the
thread tree
uh there's a more there's a lot more to
be said about linden and there's um and
in the references there are a lot of
links that you can use to learn more
about linden i have summarized my own
experience and
also other people's opinion about linden
here
linden in my opinion is the most
developed and advanced method for
privacy threat modeling there's a pulse
of information about
linden
some of the threat categories are not my
favorite
and also i've seen that other people
have reported this
um some of these
categories
may not be applicable or may not even be
a goal to avoid like for example
detectability in a particular situation
especially when you look at some of the
dft elements
also these uh this work that they have
done on different levels of threats and
attack three
threats trees
are not reusable and not may not be
generic for all of the problems so you
have to
do this again
and uh the last and maybe the most
important
part is that uh is it's introduced as
by elements by element threat modeling
and uh for each of the dft elements you
have to
analyze landon so if you look at their
table there are 21 threat categories for
a simple dft of only four elements for
each element
each
example for each for for elements so for
example this uh simple example that i
showed with only four elements you have
to analyze 21 threads and i don't know
how scalable it is
so we talked about linden and now we
want to transition to cloud privacy
threat modeling and the reason that i
chose to talk about cptm
is that it's it gets its category
categories from somewhere else
and that is the
privacy requirement
so cpkm is based on privacy requirement
what does this mean
so
cptm is the result of uh aldi hola me
research and uh they have published
their work in 2014 2016 there is another
advanced cptm uh with minor changes to
the original cptm and
the
uh i have summarized the algorithm for
ctp cptm here is that you you go and
analyze the cloud environment
you identify architecture actors assets
then
you look at you you get a source of
privacy requirements and that is the
interesting part and that's why i chose
cptn so you for example you say that i
wanted so because the work was all there
they didn't use gdpr for example they
used data privacy directive directive 95
and they got their requirements from
there so they the requirements were
lawfulness informed consent purpose
finding data
minimization and all
so you get those requirements and then
you correlate cloud actors and actors
that are specified in law for example if
you have cloud provider it translates to
a data
controller
and then
um
it's very cloud
different situation it might
translate to processor or it might
translate to controllers so you
correlate those uh requirements and then
you for each of the pr privacy
requirements you extract a number of
threads
so they the way that they have quoted is
that they say that threat inj
comes from the privacy requirement i and
the threat number j the actual threat
chain so i give an example from the
biobank research so we know that privacy
requirement two is informed consent
then
what they do is that they think about
cloud and then they come up with
excessive
terp of service as the actual threats
under this informed consent so this is
the first one in the category of
informed consent and that will be t21
and then they go and prioritize this
um i'll try to
give the pros and cons of cptm
so it's driven by compliance
requirements this is positive
so you can use any set of requirements
it could be any law any
any standards
the
difficulty or the challenge that i found
with cptm is that was that
it doesn't specify how you get from
architecture actors and assets
to those actual threats see it tells you
that you go and um draw a architecture
diagram identify actors identify assets
it also says i look at the pi here i but
there's not an established process from
these two elements to the threads
okay so we learned about linden and the
x-ray categories we learned about cptn
and the fact that you can get privacy
requirements from different sources and
the fact that they have introduced
that for cloud
the third
system that i'm going to introduce is
qttm
so qt mm sorry ptm is similar to linden
in problem space
but it gets instead of those
uh acronyms and those categories those
predefined categories it uses a
different set of privacy and security
goals that solves one of the problems
that we mentioned
so there's steps of qut tm in the
problem of space is exactly like linden
so you draw a data flow diagram but
instead now you get some privacy goals
that i will explain later in the next
slide and then
you apply them to the elements of dft
and then you come up with threads the
rest of the method is outside our scope
because it's like about the
quantification of the attack trees and
quantification of the risk which is
outside the scope but in the problem
space is exactly the same influence
linda
so where are the privacy goals that
they use
so in the security space the privacy
goals that they use was cia
and in the privacy space space they used
they um borrowed the privacy goes from
another paper privacy protection goals
uh of 2011
and a nitrogen paper and they have
published their work in
and
and uh
this is i
i've taken this from
the paper the this is the
data flow diagram again the same same
same
flow as linton
you get each of the elements of data
flow diagram and then create attack
series they call it ataxies as twit as
opposed to threat trees and the circles
shows the tags and the rectangles sorry
the circles uh show threads
and um the rectangles shows attacks
so
what is new and qttm and what are the
pros and cons so
obviously the method is very similar to
linden in the problem space only church
categories are different
but i wanted to give you a quote from
their study and it's very interesting
and it was very interesting for me
because it
actually validated what my own
experience and i it it resonated with me
so they said that performing a
comprehensive security and privacy
analysis with bismuth methodology
required a big set of parameters they
were talking about linda
so they said that if we wanted to use
lyndon instead of our privacy goals
we had to do we had to take six first
security and by six they m they meant
dementia strikes
and seven for privacy lyndon
and
they had this ambiguity around like
non-repudiation and unlinkability
and also they mentioned that there was a
missing concept which was
intervenability
um so i really liked their the concept
of intervenability so let's go back back
to this slide
so the security cia is clear but in
privacy domain they mentioned
unlinkability which has a similar
concept in london they mentioned
transparency
which is somehow new if you don't relate
it to the compliance non-compliance in
london and also intervenability which i
think i've in my own experience i found
it useful and necessary to consider when
you're doing threat modeling because a
lot of regulation especially ask for
intervenability as for a allowing user
ask for user control control of user
over their own data
so what they say is that first of all
linden was too complicated not all of
the concepts would apply in their own
experience and
also they they wanted the concepts of in
concept of intervenability
i found the 2012 paper
and then i also found it useful to quote
from adam jostak book
he also says that adam schuster is the
author of uh designing for security at
set mother and design for security book
and he also says that linden leaves your
author deeply conflicted
the privacy terminology it relies on
will be challenging for many readers
however however however it is one of the
most serious and thought-provoking
approaches to privacy threat modeling
which i agree with
uh the other
challenge that i wanted to mention and
actually related to the last code was
that again for if you want to do linden
for a very simple diagram with four
elements you have you'll have 21 threads
which
when you're doing thread modeling by
elements most of or some of these
threats are not meaningful
so there's another another idea of
threat modeling per interaction
uh that you focus on interactions
instead of
each elements of dft you focus on on the
entire interaction and i quote from a
2017 paper that is protection strategies
are normally enough to protect systems
so um i i don't have enough time to
explain the whole idea of privacy threat
modeling parent traction but i want to
draw your attention to the fact that
there is a pair interaction way of
threat modeling that i'll try to use in
my
own method that i'm going to propose so
the last idea that i'm going to
share with you is based on our own
research we presented this with
mina miri and
constantin k at different
venues
in
iu pregnancies in symposium and also a
nice soccer journal and an absolute
conference the idea behind tagging
and you can go and read about that it's
there's a huge room to develop this for
privacy engineering but
the challenge that we had and want to
address and the problem that we wanted
to solve was that
how could we identify the features the
software features that are needed to
comply with gdpr and how how could we
ensure that gdpr requirements were met
so we came with we came up with the idea
of a tagging system which was a
was an abstract layer between
regulations
and the tasks and user stories
uh so i
i really i want to be
brief about this so you look at one i
will only give a number of examples so
you look at article four seven of gdpr
and then you read about write to
withdraw and then you code it
in a tag and this is the idea comes from
and it's inspired by uh grounded theory
and different type of open coding excel
coding and selective coding that
you do there and then you come up with a
number of codes and tags
i will go to the examples
this is one example just let's focus on
one example again the slide is not
rendered correctly
uh so the example starts from article 12
recited 58 or article 12
article 12 recite recycle and recycle 59
of gdpr and we looked at that and we
tagged it into transparency a whole
program and then we wrote a user story
which specifies the goal
from a user's perspective so it says
that as a user i want to be able
able to freely
access information about processing
activities that involves my personal
data so that i can exercise my right to
view my process data
so this is a user story then the slide
shows how we got from the
mandate
to the tag and to that from that to user
story there's another example here
again tag user story mandate
and
you look at the
compliance regulations mondays
you
find a tag and then you turn it into
users
so you we had tens of user search based
based on gdpr and i want you to in this
slide i want you to focus on the user
story so we had this user studies i only
read the first one like as a user i want
to be able to edit update my information
in the system so that i can ensure
accuracy of
any
and have control
i can ensure the accuracy of and have
control over my data
so the third part is where is the center
says
this which i'll try to put everything
together and give you some tools
and tips about this
so this is probably my favorite slide of
all time about combining and merging
different standards
i give you 2-3 seconds to take a look at
this if you haven't seen it
so whenever you try to
merge everything and create a new thing
that unifies everything else it's
probably uh it's an illusion it's it's
hard to do that because different
standards try to solve different
problems but yet i tried to do this and
i tried to put everything together and
create a taxonomy and relationship
between
all the elements of cloud privacy threat
modeling so and this is actually a
summary of everything that i said so far
and summary of
my study and research on various
different
types of privacy threat modeling so i
see this pattern that you can get your
threads from goals
and the example of goals was obviously
qttm method that they use some privacy
protection goals or you can get from
threat category
uh what's the example of that
correct linda
and you can get that from compliance
requirements for example in case of cptm
they got they got that from the
directive 95 if bu directive 95
and then you arrive at the threat
so now
what are the threats are
you apply those threats to the cloud
service
and then i try to code that with the
diam on in the diameter of circles i
would like to
suggest that you should put this much
much emphasis on different
uh elements of dft so entity usually
less but data store data flow more and i
would like to ask you to focus more on
interaction and processes and then by
applying those you write requirements
and features that are needed the other
idea that's shared here is that
the compliance report requirements can
be can
give parameters to the threads i'll give
you examples
and then the compliance requirements
also can define
the requirements and with that you know
with within
in a quantitative way and with some kind
of parameters
i will explain more
so this is the whole um scheme and
framework that i'm suggesting
so i'm suggesting that you can use any
set of goals and threats that you're
comfortable with it could be lyndon
it could be
i'm actually suggesting some other ways
that you can do that privacy protection
goals that the cptm that the qttm
team has used
you can use gaap
or you can use gps the the the global
privacy standard that
uh and kovacian has
has created and also you can for example
get the iep for information practice
principles
i did that based on our own um user
stories and i went through all of our
user stories and tried trying to find
out what the threat was that this user
sort of became
necessary based on the compliance
regulation so that is actually
indirectly coding the companionship
regulation and translating it into
threats category and also i mapped it to
linden and goes
so based on my own study so this is the
result of my
own work i'm not saying that this is the
only way that you can come up with those
threats but this is one of the ways that
you can do this
and i came up with four categories lack
of control lack of protection
lack of minimality and lack of
transparency
and under which under under each of them
there are a number of subcategories of
threats
or
concrete threats and with the definition
of them
so again this is not the only way that
you can do
and if you ask if i had doubts about
where i should put these threats and
concrete threats yes obviously i did
have doubts
and uh there are many ways to do this
many ways to create a hierarchy and tax
science
uh so the next step is that focus under
on the interaction
so this is an example that has all the
elements of cloud
and i chose an example and then and i i
did the thread modeling on this but the
reason that i chose this example was
that it had all the other typical
elements that
we needed so it's a mood diary that
people take selfies of themselves they
uploaded to the application the
application saves service saves the
store saves
saves the pictures and closes the search
and some and it
connects to the cloud region a vision
api understand how happy or sad the
person is and then stores data
on a regular basis on cloud skill and
also logs
use the cloud login
so we don't have time to go to the
details of this application but i
i can show you that you can you can go
through all these concepts
different kind of threats and threat
categories and then
see
whether they apply to this particular or
typical service
and then
if yes then you can
go one step further
so you look you look at the thread
categories and you look at a typical
service and then you look at various
interactions that it has and you will be
able to be even beforehand we will be
able to collectively
have typical services and have typical
processes and interactions under each of
the services
and then we can code them
and so we'll have a pre-populated list
of threads for generic services
then we'll identify some kind of
relevance or applicability criteria i've
shown two of these examples
just for the sake of simplicity so the
first one we know that we have lack of
control is a threat and lack of control
over agreement is addressed so the
question is that are user agreement
requirements
at rest under this component or it's
addressed somewhere else
because you need to address this
probably once for the whole system you
don't have to address this or mention it
as a threat for each of the components
the other real applicability criteria
that i've given this example is that
what another threat is lack of data
protection
for the data transfer to the third party
or third country
so the question is is the data
transferred to a third country or region
or is locally
store
so based on the answer to this problem
this particular threats becomes active
or not
so you will
using your tool you will have a subset
of threads so you start with
pre-populated
of threats for generic services there
are a number of questions that you
answer and there will be a subset of
threats that you will get
and the last point that i want to share
with you the last step of this framework
and this process is parameterizing
threats or parameterizing the
requirements based on a regulation
and i only give some examples
so we know that different different
regulations have different requirements
right how do we code them how do we make
how do we make different threats based
on the requirements of
their regulations
so you can do that in two ways one way
is that you can parametrize the threats
so the trust that i mentioned i will
give only a few examples like let's
let's consider lgpd
which is um enforcing brazil and gdpr
which is the eu eu of data privacy
so we know that for example we have lack
of control on data access right so gdpr
allows 30 day to answer access requires
an lg pd 15 15 days so you have two ways
you you can either
code these as part of the threat
analysis or you can
code them as part of the requirement
generation the other example is lack of
transparency or breach notification for
example gdpr
asks for 70 maximum of 72 hours after a
breach to notify the users and lgpd says
reasonable time
or lack of transparency over the legal
ground
gdpr applies to obviously all the all eu
citizens but uh lg if lg lgpd doesn't
apply if the
processing is not done in the country
but gdpr applies even if the processing
is outside the country on the data from
the
from the from eu
residents
or for example
lgpd provides additional grounds for
process processing of data on the basis
of for research purposes for
for legal in legal circumstances and for
health and credit data protection
so again you can parametrize the data
parameterized based on the requirements
of the regulation
in for the threats or for the for the
requirements that are are associated
with the threats
so my last slides are conclusion
and some suggestion for the future but i
have summarized everything again and
reiterated the same thing again here so
start with any set of priority threats
it you can you can compile that
list based on the compliance you can
compile that list based on requirements
uh and uh
it could be compliance where you could
it could be requirement based it could
be a goal driven it could be category
driven i gave four examples of with
examples of each that you can you can
use any of the sources to compile a list
of threads then you need to apply the
threat analysis to the interaction of
the cloud services again i want to
emphasize that
focus on processes and focus on the
interactions
and you can all you need to also define
those relevance or
applicability rules for the threats
and this makes it repeatable and
scalable because you can do that on the
generic services for example for logging
and identity management for storage and
then there will be a question number of
questions that you answer and a subset
of threads will be given to you instead
of analyzing the dft for each of the
components again and the last part is
that you can parametrize the threats or
associated
requirements based on the regulations
um i gave examples all of this um my
last points are that um privacy
treadmill and is chiefly compliance
driven so i really suggest that we
should start from compliance try to code
the compliance it doesn't mean that we
cannot go to threat categories like
linked
the categories that linden has uh
has introduced or the or other privacy
protection goals but uh mainly starting
from compliance is very helpful
this was my
opportunity goal statement again i want
to each reiterate this that by
regulation-based privacy threat modeling
we can actually both compliance and
privacy by by design with minimal
overhead this will be the process will
be repeatable and we have to do it once
for a number of
services cloud services typical services
i think future research and work should
should focus on modeling typical
interaction processor for cloud services
i showed some examples of that
modeling relevance and applicability
criteria for
threats and processes
which again i showed that for lgbt and
gdpr
and also coding compliance specifics as
parameters and then
last one and maybe the most important
one is creating a data exchange format
between customers and providers that if
when we create this kind of
privacy information and privacy
pre-populated lists we can communicate
and we can reuse the data
that was all i had to say and i really
hope that what i said and what i shared
with you has been useful for you and you
have tools to
take it back to your organization and to
your own problem and try to solve
problem
with this
tools and techniques thank you very much