acunetix helps thousands of
organizations secure their websites and
web applications across the globe
whether you're a one-person team
ensuring the security of a few websites
or a large organization interested in
automating your web vulnerability
assessment and management acunetix is
here to help
hello everyone thanks for joining uh
welcome to the roblox global upset 2020
the virtual edition
my name is ismail gonzalez and this
presentation is called start me up safe
let's go over that mandatory slide who i
am
i've been working in the
information security industry
specifically application security for
about 13 years
along with my career i've done
lots of i've played lots of different
roles
such as
developer
building security solutions to companies
pain tester performed lots of code
review
consulting and also in different
industries such as government and the
private sector especially the finance
sector
currently i'm a senior security
consultant in f5
and i'm also a cyber security advisor
and i start up
related with
social network
i'm also a former owasp chapter leader
dao in brazil i am brazilian and i don't
know how to dance samba
uh i'm also i've made contributions to
the
some of the wasps projects such as the
oas testing guide the yoga cheek shift
and also the oas zap proxy communities
i'm also a bug hunter
and one of
known
bug bouncy initiatives
and
i put things and share things with the
community
on the
on my github flash hiring colleges and
also
i blog when there is some specific time
at the sharingfact.net
so
start me up safe
um when i came up with this presentation
topic i was i was thinking about
about these small start lines especially
they come up with like great ideas and
those small companies
and
uh it's time to build their solutions
and i was thinking
you know they they might be struggling a
lot to
add security on top of the products and
i was thinking how they could do better
you know how we could consider all the
challenges that we'd be seeing those
kind of companies that they they suffer
how they could do how they could do
better and starting in certain security
in their process
since day one
and there are a couple of numbers here
uh quite interesting
there is this research from vodafone
that says that 80 of the high growth
companies see superior as a business
enabler
and what does that mean see security as
a business enabler
that means that
those leaders from those companies
they
see a security as a school to
increase the business partnership to
retain customer loyalty
and to
to be ready to expand
the markets
right and also being in compliance with
regulations and law those who allow them
to
to expand their business and
expand their partnerships in general
however
60 of the smaller business
companies they are feeling poorly
informed about security and this of
course is security in general imagine
now application security which is a
quite complex topic as you can see we
have a whole conference dedicated to app
sex
another number that caught my attention
is the verizon data breach investigation
report so in 2019 out of all the
incidents that they investigated 28
of the incidence
of the data breach they were from small
business what does that mean from those
small companies
that means that they are getting
targeted
either they are getting attacked
directly on a target attacked or if
there is something in the wild just
happen to hit their servers their
applications and
and
breach their systems
and that is not a surprise right if you
think that okay i have this small
company i'm just discarding that i have
this only application still not in
production if you put the server in the
cloud
it's just a matter of minutes for the
first http request
to
start
hitting your web server probably for
knowns on their abilities and of course
if you have a component that that is
vulnerable there's those
automated attacks will basically breach
into a system easily
and there are some more
numbers that is impressive uh as a
bleeping computer
over
300 millions of record leakages from the
fertilizer and on the top of everything
like this
there are laws and regulations that
you'd be looking to comply right
especially as their business grows and i
could name a few of them like the gpdr
and the lgpd in brazil
the gpdr in europe so related to privacy
concerns and also the pci css
and finally there is the culture
the cultural aspect of deserving
security early then
you
is a chance for you to
to base security into the culture of the
company
let's have a look
how do you build your solution right
traditionally as you had a great idea so
you come up with this and and uh this is
how
security uh like a software development
traditional that software development
looks like and there was a really
funny
uh situation today when i showed this
slide to my wife
and she read where's the security sit
here she pointed right away to test it
even if she's not an i.t and i said no
that's not the
that's not the right place but
lots of people are putting security only
at the time they'll be releasing that
product
it's especially those small companies
when they are about to make big
integrations or do business with some
partnerships
they call the external company say hey
i'm about to integrate this product that
i built here with this big credit card
supplier and they come with this big
list of
security tests that i need to run and i
don't know anything like this can you
help me then you're paying them and
they'll likely find lots of security
holes in your system
uh that is not the correct way if you
look at the
if you look at this
software development lifespanical there
are lots of security that could be done
across all the all those specific phases
uh security requirements you'll be
talking about the requirement phase
you'll be taking into consideration
regulatory requirements so just thinking
about the pci dss for instance if you
are
willing to deal with credit cards in the
future you might be subjected to that
then you come to the design and uh you
need to perform some specific threat
modelling to understand the risks that
your application and your business have
and design a secure review on the top of
that
so time of coding there are a couple of
activities secure activity that exists
at the coding phase let's call it like
this
you'd have
an approved list of tools and libraries
you'd be performing a static analysis so
looking for the code for the
vulnerabilities
you'd be following thicker coding
practices
how you do
input validation how you
prevent seeker injections
don't store
[Music]
credentials in the source code etc and
also some peer review those are all
secure activities
uh across the the software development
life cycle then you do in the testing
phase right on the top of the regolith
has a unit test
you'd have some security tests like
dynamic analysis
static analysis and dynamic analysis
uh very well known as the vulnerability
scanners you'll be running on the that
specific phase of the security test then
the time of release you want to do the
paint testing for sure you want to make
sure that everything looks good however
you still need to plan on an incident
response plan and you need to make sure
that the interface structure that is
supporting your application is is
hardened so it follows hardening guides
as well and finally when you release the
product
that is still the incident response
activities you need to do continuous
security testing because new vectors
might arise and you might have left
components in production that you're no
longer
using or
they are an outdated component
and vulnerability monitoring there are
new vulnerabilities when you call the
software there was no vulnerability for
that specific
let's say 35 component you're using but
now there's a new vulnerability out
there and people are
starting to exploit that in the wild so
how do you get information about that so
as you can see
there are lots of things here to do
and and of course
when you're thinking about those
small companies there are even more
challenges
uh with the application security
you know even in the big ones we have
those challenges imagine on a very small
company with a handful of developers a
very small team sometimes you don't have
a person or uh
infosec team
and imagine an abstract team or an
abstract person right
some of the challenges like the
perception of
security as a bottleneck this is
one of the things that
you know the business says okay so i'm
putting
all of those activities
if you look at the pre the previous
slide
so many work to do this will slow down
my process this is slow down
the process and slow down the releases
to go to the market right
you'd be
you might have lack of funding with
sponsorship or lack of awareness
you know it's a small company you have a
great idea
but
you are not let's say especially these
companies that are
started by some ic folks so they might
not have the proper education in terms
of security they might not be aware of
those
all of those issues
then the lack of
specialized
security immunology and
resources
right if you're thinking about freezing
threat mode is a very specialized thing
and lack of resources you don't have
people to carry all of those activities
and also lack overall strategy if you're
thinking about those very small
companies and thinking about the
startups we usually are in the
some sort of
risky business they might change
overnight their business direction with
the kovid we saw lots of examples like
that
and last but not least uh the business
pressure to go to the market right a
small company needs res needs funds
right it's money so they want the
products to go to market
this way they basically can
start gain some revenue
and
gain our customers and maybe looking for
more investors and
other partnerships with
more bigger companies and so on so
lots of challenges here to to address
then i thought
considering all of this situation
how one could start
in where especially if you look into
this
previous graphic here and all those
activities that involve
delivering a secure solution uh how
could you how could you one
start these and where they should start
which one is more important than the
other
i don't think there is a
one size
uh one-size-fits-all solution in my
opinion this might vary
and i thought about three items that
some of the companies they could start
and
they would be using
open source and free resources and you
could
start getting into the security right
away since day one and improve the
overall security culture of your
organization
let's get into them
then a great start is secure
requirements
uh secure requirements
is the foundation of any secure software
it's the backbone of any secure software
it's a quality attribute to increase
trust on a solution on a specific system
the security requirements they should be
considered in all phases of the software
development what do i mean
for that by that
it can be described as a non-functional
requirement um imagine for instance a
secure requirement is the system should
prevent
sql injection that is a clear secure
requirement or
your
the api should have a mechanism that
throttles
uh
ip addresses at the 10 requests per
second those are also some secure
requirements
they could be developed
either let's say for doing a more
traditional waterfall model which
usually people
i i think they're not no longer using
that nowadays they're more into agile
ones and
it could be part of your
your spring
basically it could be baked into the
acceptance criteria or into your
definition of done
and also it can be used to derive
security tasks and verification because
you have the security requirements
clearly stated as i said the api needs
to
support a maximum you know the api needs
to try to any client that does more than
10 requests per second so that's a clear
secure requirement and you could
bring this to the security tests and
secure verification
how do you do that you should use uh
industry best practices uh combine that
with some regulatory that you need to
meet
and submit some specific business
requirement at the end
also event early to collect benefits in
the near future
nist says that fixing a bug
our weakness after the software is in
production
costs
up to 30
000 i'm sorry up to 30 10
uh 30 times
than fixing the specific bug when you're
doing uh in the beginning right
and i really like one example of a
software that i've
audit in the past and i call like the
md5 case to illustrate a little bit of
that
and basically that specific system i've
performed a penetration testing and a
code review for that system and i found
out the users
were having their
passwords start using the md5 mesh which
is widely known
as not secure and
not good for that use case
and the thing here is
when i brought this to this issue to
to the to the customer they they
acknowledge the issue
and basically we discussed a little bit
of
how would be complex to fix that in
terms of time and in terms of money they
outsourced the
outsourcing the development so they need
to brought the company the external
company to fix the thing for them
and as you can see if you're thinking
about they planned database to have a
specifically uh
size to store an md5 hash so that is the
first thing so they need to change the
database
then the system was in production
a little bit sensitive so they need do
the governors to scatter a change window
to change the database then they'll need
to change the code
verify every time they use the type a
username and password 3575
okay if it matches then i
record the new
recommended hash algorithm to start the
password then they do that for all of
the users until and of course when you
change the system like that you need to
you need to do all the tests all the
regression tests make sure everything is
working fine sometimes you need a
maintenance window as you can see this
costs a lot and
those are the kind of things that could
have been avoided
if they're practicing security
requirements
since
the beginning of the
of the software development
but
you mentioned some industry best
practices where do i find those lists of
things that could be rough uh a little
bit complex right
here comes the o1
open security verification standard or
asvs
this is an application security standard
which one could
uh
verify your application against those
specific requirements that is reading
that it's put together by experts
is
compliant
with some nice recommendations
with the common weakness enumeration
as well which is well known in the
industry
and provides basically three levels
of verification let's call like this
verification
and the level two is recommended for
applications that contain sensitive data
and what is the cool thing about the sds
is they have
14 sections
and they
they assist you answering most of the
questions that you might have for
instance
how should i do
how should i start a user's password how
should i implement
this authentication where should i use
tls what kind of tls should i use
so
this is this standard answers that
question for you how should i handle the
api how should i handle for instance xml
and you can see that it goes
a little bit deep into some of those
topics and also link that with some
other amazing your watch resources
it also address modern issues such as
satisfied request surgery
or two-factor
authentication
and even a little bit of iot so that
would be
a great place for you to
start bringing this document and
bringing this as part of your when
you're
writing your requirements to look into
that because this is based on common
thread modeling that applies to
say the majority of the applications out
there
just for you to give an example here's
the section for the password
uh and you can see
uh three items right verify the user set
password that at least 12 characters
how many times you asked it what is a
good password right how many characters
what's the minimum characters that i
should have that verified passwords
64 characters no longer are permitted
and then there is a risk that's the
reason for that it's a good
a good start point because your
developers and your team will start
basically getting interested
understanding why those uh
why that state like this and then you
can make the secure requirement as clear
as that and
very consistent and testable right
and you can bake that into your user
stories
so i put an example here that uses story
and writes the user should see a link to
use assignment
so if you're using a giant methodology
so this story it goes a little bit like
this
um
as an unregister use it i would like to
register myself then i could start using
the application so it's a very very
simple definition of the user story
and then there will be a bunch of user
criteria
i'm sorry of the substance criteria and
you could bring those secure
requirements you could bring those items
from the asvs and
adapt them to their
users target so as acceptance criteria
for instance for this specific
functionality
you should verify that you use a set
password at least 12 characters verify
their passwords 64k repairs alone and
verify the password transmitter is
provided to
to help users
uh to set a stronger password as you can
see you should make them as clear as
possible as consistent and testable
so when you're building a task on the
top of the the security requirement will
drive your test not only the business
requirements but also the security
requirements
as well
and some of the items
are
not exactly
um
not uh not exactly non-functional
security requirements they are they're
provide functions like how we do a
two-step authentication right it's a
function that you'd be using that so and
i think this is a great uh really great
start and
as i said if you have for instance this
provide guidance for you how the story
uses password
if the company that i mentioned earlier
had used that would be
avoided you know they should be avoided
as md5 specific situation
so there's the first thing
second thing that i consider that will
help you and start security early
and i put a stamp here as a quick link
because i love that is the dependency
scanning process
so
likelihood that you'll be using open
source components in our solution
is great right
and the os top 10 a9 is using components
with known vulnerabilities that means
you're
shipping your product with open source
components and open source components
that has
open source components that have
vulnerabilities so even if your code is
completely secure the open source
component might not be completely secure
and there is one report from synopsis
last year 99 of the code-based code
bases outed in 2019 contain open source
components and
75 of those open source components they
had vulnerabilities and 49 high risk
vulnerabilities
so and some open source components like
jquery node.js react prime phases etc
lots of them that you might be using
day to day so the dependency checking
process
assists on identifying vulnerabilities
on open source components
and the way it does that is by
the
class of software that is called
software composition analysis that can
assist you in that task and this could
be integrated into our cicd pipeline
could be run on a schedule basis or
integrated with the developer's id which
you
find even early problems with that
the great project once dependence chat
is one of the software composition
composition analysis too
and the way it works basically it
attempts to detect public disclosure
vulnerabilities contained within a
project's dependency
in doing that it leverages the national
national vulnerability database from
nist and compare the database on what
you have in your dependency
on the screen on the right i'm sorry on
the left there is a
snip of
pom.xml fire from maven and where we
specify the dependence
check maintenance and then on the right
in the bottom you see the output as an
example
so
uh it found vulnerabilities of the
bootstrap on the bootstrap minimum and
also
on the bus bouncy castle library
this is specifically oasis depends check
it scans
with its own analyzer java applications
and dotnet and also leverage third-party
services and data source such as
npm audit and retire.js for some
specific
technologies
and this is it's it's a great wing as i
said
another example
uh especially nowadays with javascript
being really popular in react and
node.js and node express is the npm
package manager quality function and the
yarn
audit function
so this is very simple to run you just
run them from the command line
on our source code folder npm audit or
yarn audit it will check the components
that you are using
and the dependency of those components
as well
and it will bring to you the
vulnerabilities and suggest you how you
fix those components this is a great one
integrates really easily with pipelines
so i put an example on the right i
create a pipeline with four stages
check software composition analysis test
build and apply
and then
on the stage check sca i run the yarn
audits and i pipe the results to a text
file so i could examine it later and the
cool thing with this yarn audit and the
npm audit if they find a vulnerability
they exit the process
uh with a status code other than zero
and this breaks the build for you
automatically
which is great and i think this is my
recommendation for this is start
breaking the build with this if you find
that you're using a software
vulnerability you break the build early
so this will give you
they give a time to check this and it's
so let's call it like your first
security gateway right you could also
run locally if you're a developer you
could just run this and fix the things
even to before commit to
the code baseline
and if you are in doubt because
you know
dealing with this
uh terminologies might not be especially
with lack of training uh you might be in
doubt if there's a series or not i'll
just go to the latest versions of the
open source component
and the last of the three that i
recommend
is deploying our static application
security testing
tool
and this is fantastic because it speaks
the language of the developers
so it could catch errors uh really early
in the software development life cycle
when our
when our coding
such as hardcoded password sqlite best
transversal
with cryptography and hash algorithms
and basically this will assist you with
uh the verification of the
implementation of your security
requirements if you just said okay i
need to
not have
[Music]
secret injection vulnerability so the
application should provide the mechanism
to defense you've coded everything so
you can use the sas to find
if those problems are happening or not
it can also be integrated with the cicd
it could also be run on a schedule basis
and also being part of the id
plugin
i put one example here i put the list
i'll not name one specifically here um
there is a list with the oas with a list
of them
so the cool thing is it highlights the
precise source file
and and the lines that have the issues
and provides detailed explanation on the
security issues and in general provide
some guidance on how to fix them
and one of the cool things that some of
the code repositories that are out there
now very popular in the cloud and they
have the free versions of them they are
making the sas the open source stuff of
course available for private projects as
well so definitely you should check this
out
i would recommend you to break the build
initially
you know especially the first time you
run this might run might see lots of
small things so i would digest
everything how the two works because
this is a more complex too
than the software composition analysis
too right and then you look if there is
any false positive or that something is
okay and also recommended to run
more than one fast if possible so you
could compare because sometimes
especially the open source
you might have different rules on
different projects so you could compare
one might catch one problem the other
one
might not catch
that specific problem right
and also for all the issues you
identified like all the other security
issues i strongly recommend you
especially if you're using a labeling
system on your bug tracker or on your
issues tracker you create a label called
security and then you mark that a
specific issue with that security label
and why why do i think that is cool
because you could have a visibility
right away first of all you're still
feeling the culture of security right
and
you have that label you could basically
select all that label right away
security and maybe do a sprint to fix
all those security you could pull all of
them
pretty easy
so
those are the three things that i
consider you could start right away and
this would make your software more
secure since day one for sure and there
are a few other small recommendations uh
to close this out
and one is get the developers in contact
with the application security world
and the way you could do this you could
use the owasp black channel lots of
people are discussing that daily
the same problems we've been discussing
here how you do authorization how you do
authentication how you do security
testing
you attend the chapters
uh you know local chapters meeting and
look for meetups and especially now you
have lots of meetups online there's no
excuse to not learn about things invest
in training for your developers i really
like trains that combine
some showcase showing hey this is a real
scenario that specific vulnerability
somebody does this and this and that's
thinking about a
malicious cross-site script and show
show the impact and then show the
vulnerable code
and show how you fix that in the code
and of course if you could do that
if you could attend those classes you
know at a certain point
and you do something specific to your
uh your stack that's even better and i
would strongly recommend you to start
with some free training from the various
uh academics that they are out there you
could start your data
if using public cloud in probably the
small companies they are
moving toward the cloud right they are
not keeping like a data center which
does not make sense
leverage the security features from the
public cloud such as container image
scanner
secret storage
and even generate ssl certificates for
you without paying that because you're
at a customer
their repetitive tasks
or integrate them with the cict i think
that is the best approach is the
integration i show the next very simple
exam example that you could do that
and establish the practice among the
developers to integrate the code often
that means you're committing the code
that you are
developing to
to your code baseline so
when you put the security checks on the
ci cd this will be running more and you
take the benefit that those secure
checks will happen early and
you'll be catching errors early
keep an inventory of your application
api
and subscribe for vulnerability alerts
just an example if you're
using node.js then you have this
application that sits on that specific
url and then you have node.js then
node.js reason has a google groups that
you could subscribe yourself
and every time a vulnerability
results in a new js will be out they
will alert you right away so that's a
very very rudimentary process but could
give you a quick win getting those
alerts
and when hiring an external company for
a pin testing if you're doing
periosteal release or because you're
complying uh you're com you're making a
compliance with some regulations
prefer a hybrid methodology where you
disclose with the fantastic company
details of the software
uh you make your developers accessible
to the consultants because
they will be do a better job for sure
you know than just a simple black box
and even share the source code with them
they'll be able to see things that they
might not see during the
on the black box
and finally
uh
you know after all of these lots of
things that they could start doing to
improve security as your business grows
it's time to plan the next steps and the
next steps basically are related with
the
software
maturity
uh in the osm the software issues
material model
is a great place to to do
a self-assessment
and see what other activities that you
could
introduce uh to your development
lifecycle
so
thank you so much for having me for
watching this presentation if you have
questions or comments please send me an
email at seasmyorg gmail.com