hi everyone thanks for joining uh
you know thank you very much to uh the
osp foundation and apsec usa for for
having me along uh pleasure to be
speaking to you all today and uh looking
forward to a quick and exciting session
um my name is casey ellis the talk today
is on time for a change why it's more
important than ever to revisit the cfaa
before we get into that just a little
bit of housekeeping i am not a lawyer
the lawyers that have given input to the
projects that i'll discuss here are not
your lawyers this is not legal advice
and no lawyers were harmed during the
creation of this presentation so you
know what we're going to be talking
about is a fair bit of
kind of content material around the
legal frameworks that exist around good
faith security research
you know what we've tried to do is
create tools to make uh you know
improvement in that area as easy as
possible for everyone but you should
always seek your own legal advice so
getting that part out of the way all
right who is this guy my name's casey
ellis i'm the founder chairman and cto
of buck crowd i've been in information
security for about 20 years i've been
you know monkeying around with computers
and hacking things my entire life but uh
started the the career in infosec
straight out of high school my career
arc is kind of um interesting in the it
started off
you know just intrigued and messing
about with stuff i turned that into a
career in pen testing uh and then moved
across into the dark side getting into
solutions architecture and sales
at some point that kind of back of house
experience and the front of house
experience got together and conspired i
got it in my head that i wanted to be an
entrepreneur um and you know did that
basically um
you know went off and did the did the
startup thing so
you know as a result of that um you know
very very proud to have pioneered the
crowdsource security as a service model
uh starting bug crowd out um in 2012. uh
we're an american company i'm actually
usually based in san francisco i'm
actually in sydney australia as we
record this hiding out from from covert
uh but normally based in san francisco
um but started the company from here uh
moved across to sf in 2012 launched our
first programs in 2012 so you know
having broken ground in the space you
know at that time it was an incredibly
novel concept but you know today eight
years later as we talk about it it's
something that's far more broadly
accepted um you know i'm an aussie i'm a
husband and father too and as i
mentioned i'm based in san francisco
normally when it's not unprecedented at
times as it were
um so just quickly what is bug crowd um
really you know the the the genesis of
the idea was out of running a pen
testing company a combination of running
a pen testing company and
and seeing the need for human creativity
to be applied to cyber security problems
like when you think about what
we're trying to do it's it's a creative
problem set you know software
development software creation the
deployment of systems that all involves
human creativity um it's not a
technology problem at its root uh the
technology just makes it go faster and
makes it more impactful um
when you think about the the adversary
you know they're creative as well so
really the idea behind bug crowd was
this idea of
so the concept behind bug crowd was
really how do we take the latent
creativity and the latent potential that
exists in the white hat hacker community
from all around the world
and actually plug it into where the
problems exist and where questions need
to be answered in in the cyber security
market right across the board
you know the whole idea that kind of got
it going was was seeing
you know bug bounty programs the likes
of uh you know netscape and google and
facebook you know kind of making that
concept popular at the time or at least
making it kind of a thought about idea
and something that people starting to
consider um really what we've
worked on ever since is this idea of not
just facilitating vulnerability
disclosure and bug benny programs but
really like plugging every available
person who wants to do this type of work
into the problems that are available for
them to actually connect to you know
solve and and then obviously earn money
and earn a living from so that's what we
do as an organization uh bug bounty
programs
as you would know them um in terms of
public programs
you know crowdsource penetration testing
attack surface management and
vulnerability disclosure programs and
that fourth piece is a lot of what we're
going to talk about today so let's get
into that
now that my spiel is done
so agenda past how do we get here when
we're talking about um the legalities
and
and really the legal kind of backdrop to
good faith security research and and
making the internet a safer place like
what's the back story uh the president
where are we up to i'll talk about some
data that we've gathered out of the
disclosure project and a few other
things and just talk about kind of the
current state of conversation around
legal frameworks and so on
and in the future how do we improve um
you know what i'm what i'm going to do
at that section of the talk is actually
talk you all through the disclosure
project itself um which is you know
something that i'll i will not preempt
right now but that's basically something
that you know i know owasp has an
incredible and a rich history
of
you know basically turning security into
a team sport disclosure is an open
source project uh and and hopefully this
will encourage a bunch of you to either
adopt what's going on there or actually
contribute and help out so let's do that
all right how did we get here what is
the cfa um
yeah it's it's an interesting one i've
got the uh i had the hackers backdrop
before i changed it to usual suspects
because it didn't quite fit into the
frame but
as we're recording this it's the 25th
anniversary of the hackers movie
this is another you know hacker classic
war games
the interesting thing about this movie
is that ronald reagan actually saw it at
camp david basically kind of freaked out
and and went back and spoke to the doj
and a whole bunch of anti-hacking law
was the product of that so so the cfa
that we deal with today was really the
product of hollywood thanks guys um and
honestly at the time it was actually i
think a fairly appropriate
measure because the internet back then
doesn't look anything like what it looks
today um so really that's that's kind of
you know
the back story of how that law came to
pass and you know the challenge with it
is that there's been some evolution of
of the law itself over the past
were where are we up to now 35 years um
but not a whole lot and and what we've
seen
you know alongside that is this
incredible acceleration of of the
engagement of good faith security
research as a part of the internet's
immune system and the way that it keeps
itself safe and understands where its
issues are so so they can be fixed all
of that good stuff
the law is basically trailing behind
that so what do we do about that which
is kind of what we're going to go
through today
so in terms of backstory
i'm just having some trouble advancing
the slides here
so in terms of backstory around you know
bug bounties and vulnerability
disclosure in 1995 netscape launched the
bugs bounty program uh they dropped the
s later because it's cleaner and yes
that was a social network joke for those
who missed it um
yeah
there's been
like the idea of basically putting
rewards out for people to to you know
test security systems it's been around
for centuries uh people used to do locks
prior to the internet and the technology
industry showing up but you know
netscape's broadly accepted as the the
first technology bug bounty as we know
them today right
uh in 2008 google and facebook started
off their programs and really that was
when
there started to be a bunch of noise
generated around this idea that kind of
broke out of the
you know almost the echo chamber of you
know vulnerability research uh prior to
that point in time at that point the
rest of the security industry started to
sit up and take notice and some people
in technology outside of security
started to understand what was going on
as well
really you know that's where
kind of i got involved in this stuff
from a a commercial and a career
standpoint you know having been involved
with the hacker community for a long
time prior to that seeing
the intrigue frankly that organizations
were kind of showing
around this idea of just being able to
access the talent
you know the entire talent the internet
has available to be able to help make
them more secure and this idea of like
if we're trying to outsmart an army of
adversaries then having access to an
army of allies makes sense so bada bing
bada boom you've got you've got bug
crowd um and about a year into that we
we noticed a couple of things that were
pretty interesting um you know is where
as we're basically trying to make
vulnerability disclosure and bug bounty
programs easy and and you know connects
these two very different groups of
people to have a productive conversation
there's a centerpiece of that that whole
kind of
interaction um that is the program brief
and the legal language that exists
within the program brief and we noticed
a couple of things it was you know the
first i think was the fact that like the
legal teams that the companies that we
worked with at that point in time this
is still true today
aren't used to the idea of inviting
hackers to come in and poke around their
stuff like we've got
you know 30 years of technology law
that's basically focused around the idea
of saying no go away and now we're
trying to find ways to say hey if you're
helpful um yeah that's okay like how do
we do that so the the legal teams in
general just weren't quite sure how to
approach
um this whole thing uh and lawyers
have a tendency when they're uncertain
to basically trend towards verbosity
they'll write war and peace and that's
their job they're actually doing the
right thing from from a legal standpoint
but the problem that that creates is
that the hackers
on the other side that are trying to
read and interpret these briefs you know
half of them are english as a second
language not very many of them have a
legal background there's basically
almost like the euler problem that you
have with you know itunes or installing
an application on your computer like you
you should read it ideally you know
everyone would read every euler before
they accept it but the reality is that
people tend not to they'll either gloss
over it or completely ignore it right
and we saw a similar thing happening
with what we were doing
this is a problem because
um you know the whole idea around the
cfaa is that if you're
you know we'll get into this in a second
if you're touching a computer or if
you're interacting with a computer in a
way that you haven't been authorized
to
to do
it's potentially a felony crime in the
united states and the thing about that
this is not just about the cfa it's
actually about equivalent any hacking
laws that exist all around the world
so okay that's not great
um what is the cfa it basically
prohibits behaviors that exceed
authorized access to a protected
computer or the accessing of a protected
computer without authorized access so
you're either exceeding or you're
touching something that you just haven't
been told you can touch in the first
place
the challenge with the way that this law
has been written
and and the way that it's phrased is
that protected computer
is incredibly broad it was actually
intended at the time to
cover government systems
but the way it was written it was
anything that's communicating across
state lines or internationally which is
pretty much every computer that's on the
internet right now so it brings
everything into scope that someone
else's computer or that you know has the
ability to to connect to the internet
and why i call that as it is different
from
you know laws like the digital
millennium copyright act where it's more
about software that you can actually
hold in your hands that's more relevant
to things like iot and and so on so okay
there's that and then this whole idea of
authorized access well if i'm doing
security testing
exceeding authorized access is probably
one of my goals so
how do you
how do you make that safer for the
people that are actually trying to
trying to do that in good faith and
actually try to help make things more
secure not to act as a adversary in in
in doing all of that
and i think the challenge with the cfa
you know since it was instantiated
is that it really is being used um you
know what what we've seen and and what
we've heard from
you know people like the eff and and the
department of justice and so on is that
when it comes to actual prosecutions
that make it in front of a a judge and
jury
the cfaa tends to be used correctly
there are examples even recently of of
1030s that have been prosecuted
they do tend to be folks that you know
in context of the conversation we're
having right now it's not a security
researcher that's
you know kind of stumbled into something
that they've then been pursued for it's
usually actual
you know criminal behavior or things
that you know are alleged to be criminal
behavior um the challenge is that it it
really does create this chilling effect
around security research i'll give some
examples of how that how that plays out
shortly
it's less about whether you actually get
you know vanned and and the books thrown
at you from a legal standpoint it's more
around the fact that that's possible um
that's the thing that is
chilling and has been chilling to
security researchers for a very long
time and there has been plenty of
examples where the cfa has been used
i'll give a few of those
in a moment so
yeah we're thinking about all of this
stuff as bug crowd trying to you know
trying to grow as an organization trying
to basically change the perception of
hackers from
just being you know burglars to also you
know potentially being locksmiths in the
eyes of of the industry and that part i
think has actually been quite successful
um at this point in time
you know hackers there's still
a stigma and and you know work to be
done there but we've gone from being the
default bad guy to being potentially
helpful which i think is actually pretty
pretty cool um
but really we were looking at all of
that and we started asking ourselves how
do we make it easy to do this well like
if we're trying to create briefs that
are legally complete that you know
address both sides that are easy to
understand how can we make this easy to
do well
um so in 2014 we released the open
source vulnerability disclosure
framework uh in collaboration with
cipher law out of dc um
you know at the same time the iso
standards were being released so there
was a few a few people kind of
triangulating all on the same problem
which was awesome uh between 2014 and
2017 what we saw was the osvdf being
basically copy pasted and translated
into different languages and that
original language is kind of everywhere
now at this point which is really how
this works you know what we observed was
the idea of like prior art and copy
pasta you know legal templating and
boiler plating was was fairly common it
was something that legal teams and
people trying to stand up these programs
were actually doing to to make those
things work so that was an interesting
data point uh in 2018 mean elders there
are el eller excuse me
in 2018 emit el azari started hitting
the the talk circuit talking about safe
harbor
a drop box launched there safe harbor
clauses in their program and then really
what we started to do
in context of bug crowd and the osvdf
was collaborate with all those folk and
try to figure out how we can like how do
we blow this up how do we make it easy
to do this well how do we do that
together right
in 2018 we decided yep okay it's time
that we actually spun this out into its
own its own project its own brand its
own you know potential organization
we're actually pursuing 501c3 for
disclosure right now um
and we basically
you know took our project legal bug
bounty and a few other things and
brought them all together into the
into the disclosure project itself
uh and in 2019 bug crowd started adding
this language to programs by default
we've seen it adopted elsewhere as well
so you know going back to this chilling
effect like 60
of good faith hackers don't submit
vulnerabilities for fear of legal
retribution so these are people that
haven't necessarily
been prosecuted or even necessarily
arrested they've just had
um you know negative interactions with
organizations uh or you know they've
they've heard of others that have that
have had those sorts of interactions and
they're not submitting vulnerabilities
they're not actually participating in
their capacity to make the internet a
safer place because this law
is so ambiguous if you're a good person
doing things to just kind of wander a
little bit off into territory that could
be considered a bad thing and you end up
working with a company that's having a
bad day
that's not a good thing so this is a
this is a problem that we need to solve
an example of where this actually
happens practically
kevin feinstein's phenomenal guy
knows all sorts of incredible things
about
the security of drones and he did a fair
bit of work on the dji bug bounty
program
and when i say a fair bit of work some
of the vulnerabilities that kevin
started to identify and pass across to
dji started to make them a little bit
concerned so they they were
unhappy and and basically trying to
chill and control the security research
that kevin was doing
um i'll you know make these slides
available so you can actually read this
letter it's it's quite a read it's it's
actually very threatening it's you know
talking about all sorts of legal action
coming from all sorts of different
places including
you know the use of the cfa in a federal
context you know basically accusing
kevin of a felony crime um
none of that stuff should have happened
in the first place like the the fact
that that they'd gone out and actually
put together a bounty brief and got it
out there and invited this input
would have suggested that this is
probably not something that's going to
happen it happened anyway so again the
question becomes how do we make it easy
to do this well and avoid situations
like this avoid chilling the input of
people like kevin into making the
internet a safer place
so that's backstory um the present you
know in terms of where we're up to i
think the thing that that really drives
a lot of
you know acceptance and acceptance in a
way that rolls up into the reformation
of of laws
um
it goes to adoption it's like how you
know i mentioned just before how you
know hackers have gone from being the
kind of the boogeyman to to being you
know potentially helpful to being even
invited and celebrated by by you know
all sorts of different parts of the
internet which is which is a fantastic
thing we've seen a bunch of other stuff
in terms of the adoption of
you know this whole kind of core concept
of vulnerability disclosure and actually
inviting input from the outside world
which is what i'm going to go into in
this section
um as a part of disclose io we have a a
tool set uh called the uh
we call it dios we haven't figured out
if we should acronym it or just use it
as a word but dials we'll we'll do for
now what that's doing is actually going
out you you basically feed it it's a go
script
um that you feed input and it goes out
and checks for the presence of a
security.text file
uh passes that file you know dumps out
the format into json that's compatible
with some other components of disclosure
that i'll get to shortly and it's pretty
interesting what we've seen it spitting
out like within the top 100 000 websites
on uh according to alexa
there's 933 of them
in total so that's like less than one
percent that have a security text uh
file in place in the first place
and of those uh 933 programs only about
50 of them have a policy um that's
important because without a policy all
you're really doing is establishing a
communication channel like from from bug
crowd's perspective and i think this is
a broadly accepted um
you know kind of definition of a
vulnerability disclosure program at this
point you can have an intake channel but
without a policy no one knows what's
okay and what's not okay so you have to
have those two things together and you
can kind of see
you know
one percent in in the top
100 000 is actually indicative i think
at the fact that you know
companies that are popular on the
internet tend to be more progressive and
more understanding of these types of
things and that's frankly you know our
theory for why that's
higher than it is for the 1 million
which is where it's less than the tenth
of a percent
um and in the 10 million it's it's half
half tenth of a percent so
you know it's it's one of these areas
where we're seeing
you know people use these tools and and
and get these things out there uh in a
way that makes you know vulnerability
disclosure programs and the ability to
actually you know submit issues to them
identifiable to uh to the internet and
not just the security community but the
internet at large
but there's still a pretty long way to
go
yeah another data point that we've got
is is through uh
the disclose io list this is actually a
tweet that goes out fairly regularly
from the disclosure twitter uh and what
we're doing there is essentially
enumerating the safe harbor status which
i'll get to shortly uh on on all the
different programs that we've actually
got logged within our database at this
point in time so you know 973 programs
141 of them 14.5 with what we consider
to be full authorization um you know
21.5 percent with partial and and so on
so
you know again there's progress what
we've seen with this number is it's gone
up you know fairly steadily over time um
yeah and it continues to do that you
know really what we'd like to see is for
it to do that faster
with respect to the cfa itself um
there's some pretty interesting stuff
going on
the the van buren case which is which is
actually currently up in front of the
supreme court
is
an interesting read uh you know there's
there's some
some stuff that happened that you know
essentially i won't go into that side of
it but really what it's done is actually
brought the cfa into question in terms
of how it's interpreted um
and that has the ability or the the
potential to set precedent for how it's
used in the future so that got a lot of
attention from
from us from from you know the
electronic frontiers foundation from the
center for democracy and technology and
and so on we put together what's called
an amicus uh brief um which is
essentially a friends of the court brief
um where we go in and say okay
you know here's what you're trying to
figure out with with how you're
interpreting the cfaa like this is a
component of that decision that you
probably should consider uh and and that
particular brief really does go through
you know the role of security
researchers on the internet um you know
the fact that cfaa has been chilling to
to a lot of good work uh and that it
continues to be so and the fact that it
should be narrowed in its definition to
you know make it more focused on actual
bad faith actors and and not catch good
faith actors in
in its kind of definition and covering
so
that was a that was a pretty exciting
thing um
unfortunately we had a
uh a vendor
by the name of votes who who uh are
trying to put elections on the
blockchain um
basically write a brief saying no
you can't
tell the difference between someone
who's who's conducting security research
in good faith versus someone who's doing
that in bad faith
you know the cfa
should be broadened
to basically have it hinge on
authorization so only people that have
been authorized to do security testing
in any circumstance should be allowed to
do that otherwise it's illegal
which clearly um i don't agree with nor
did
uh about 70 other security researchers
organizations some congress people and
and others that responded on this
on this letter here so
yeah i think just as a as a practical
piece like this is the kind of thing
that's ongoing right now like as this
goes to air
this conversation around van buren is
actually going to be
progressed
um
so you know reading up on understanding
you know what your um
own viewpoint is like forming that
viewpoint and understanding what that is
uh but then you're doing whatever you
need to with it it's an election year
there's also different ways that i i
think the input of experts that
understand this type of thing can can be
brought to bear in order to get a good
outcome for you know security research
and for the safety of the internet
itself um as well as that we had you
know signatories um
again by the time this goes to air we're
going to have the ability for
others to actually sign on and uh and
and basically agree with the letter um
you know from a petitioning standpoint
so that's that's another thing that you
can do as a call to action
all right so
cool
this is sort of where it's up to um
you know going back to uh the the the
back story piece of the presentation
really where we got to thinking as we
started disclosio and as that that's
progressed is you know how do we make
the adoption of vulnerability disclosure
with best practice so not just have
organizations
accept the input of security research
and actually invite that
but to have them do that well like have
them extend things like you know
authorization against cfaa and so on how
do we make that go viral
and that brings me to the next section
of this talk i'm keeping an eye on time
here so how do we improve
and this is where i'm going to introduce
disguise io itself as a as a project
so really the vision of disclose io is
is a healthy and a ubiquitous internet
immune system um you know our our view
and i think the view of of most folk
that that work in
this kind of aspect of vulnerability
management that involves the security
research community is that security
researchers are kind of like the
internet's immune system like we we run
around we find things that need to be
fixed or need to be addressed uh we work
on those things and
kind of the problem that the internet
has right now is is almost equivalent to
an autoimmune deficiency or disease like
there's a rejection of that help that
consistently goes on
and ultimately that means that
everything is less resilient less safe
less healthy and we want to solve that
um credit to
uh karen elizari for for the internet
immune system um analogy she did a
fantastic ted talk probably about six or
seven years ago now um that actually
established that that analogy and i
think it it's perfect
um so really the way or the the mission
of disclose io is to drive vulnerability
disclosure adoption through safety
simplicity and standardization and i
will say again like this this started
out of bug crowd um at this point in
time there's all sorts of different
folks that are contributing to it it's
an open source project that we've
actually worked pretty hard to make
agnostic to to bug out as an
organization like
bug crowd benefits from this type of
thing because if you know the the
internet's more accepting of of security
research everything we do becomes that
little bit easier but really the design
goal of disclosure is for it to
actually function independent and and
you know above uh what we're doing as an
organization of bug crab so just to call
that out
all right so what are the what are the
components of of disclosure there's the
terms that we've put together
um
and really what they are they're boiler
plates it's it's really this idea of you
know being able to going back to the
explanation i gave at the start around
the us vdf you know how can we
have like good copy pasta on on you know
bug bounty boilerplate briefs
um that are actually going to be useful
so it's it's not something that is like
a check box and you're done it's it's
it's useful from a legal standpoint it's
useful from a readability standpoint um
and it's easy to access for all sorts of
different organizations we've seen
people just copy paste it we've seen
people use it as a foundation for their
own framework we've seen people use it
as a starting point for their own
versions um all of which is uh is stuff
that we want to you know see continue
that was like literally the the stated
goal um
and
you know on the on the right here um
just to be clear to call out these
aren't
endorsements of the project from the
organizations themselves uh the reason
that these logos are up here it's the
kind of organizations that people that
are contributing this to this project
are coming from so it's not just you
know casey the bush lawyer and
and and a bunch of other folk from the
hacker community doing this we're
actually bringing in and actually you
know frankly fielding interest
from from the kinds of people that can
really do this well um from all sorts of
different parts of of of the internet
all sorts of different organizations
government and so on so
that part's pretty exciting um
when we're putting together the terms uh
you know i touched on this before it's
it's kind of hard um
to be honest because you know what we
have to do is balance this idea of legal
completeness uh against some of these
kind of overarching laws that are very
vague and require a fair bit of
clarification you know how do you make
that clarity as complete as possible
whilst keeping it readable and brief
and also whilst you know maintaining the
safety of
the organization as well as the hacker
so as a company that's trying to launch
a vdp and and that wants to do that well
what you don't want to do is put legal
terminology out there that says hey
everyone can come and do whatever they
want
and i forfeit my right to any recourse
for an actual bad faith actor like that
would be a bad outcome so how can you
you know balance that out to make sure
that you're protecting people that are
operating in good faith
while still maintaining your recourse
towards those that might be attacking
you for real um
it's pretty interesting like we've we've
you know put a lot of work into this the
the the
biggest challenge and i think a a call
for
you know participation and and help from
the os community from an open source
standpoint is actually around
translation and and making sure that
you know the legal terms communicate
across language barriers um you know
half of like more than half i would say
of of the hackers that participate in in
in these types of things that would
actually need to read and understand
this type of thing they're not
necessarily thinking or speaking in
english as their first language so
there's an element of translation that's
already in play and we've tried to be
mindful of things like that and how we
put this uh these these terms together
um yeah so
it's a good thing
uh and really what we're doing is we're
extending it out into uh you know
different
regions different geographies we
actually wrote a a version that's been
adopted
um or used as a as a foundation
foundational template by the state of
ohio
and uh esns and some of the other voting
machine manufacturers as well around
election security i can tell you that
writing a
vulnerability disclosure program brief
for
uh an election system
set
within a state that's that's a pretty
interesting thing to do because it's
quite a diverse attack surface and
there's a lot of players involved so
yeah it's it's those sorts of problems
that we're trying to solve with with
these boilerplates that we're putting
together and again from an open source
contribution standpoint you know
submitting prs if there's
local language translation that you feel
you can do if there's local
knowledge of laws you know outside of
the u.s outside of
at the moment there's
canada the us and the netherlands
covered um and we'd love to see more
countries in there so if you've got you
know local legal or local language
knowledge of of a jurisdiction and would
like to actually translate the terms
please submit a pr or get in touch that
would be fantastic
yeah
all right next up in terms of what we're
doing uh there's the list so the list is
really it's it's a community powered
vendor agnostic directory of all known
vdps and bugbendy programs
it's essentially a big json blob that
sits on sits on github
and really the idea of it is for it to
be as as you know broadly contributed to
and broadly consumable as possible we
don't want to make it proprietary uh or
you know kind of focused or tilted it in
any particular direction we just want
this active you know kind of true
directory of
you know all of the different places
that you could potentially go off and do
proactive security research if that's
what you're looking for or if you're
looking for someone to actually you know
submit an issue once you've found one
this can serve that purpose as well
uh it's up there in json csv uh you know
the probably the big call out with with
the terms and with the list is that
they're both licensed under cca 4.0 so
it's
it's open source it's you know free for
reuse for repurposing with attribution
so
that's that's kind of the spirit of how
we put all of that together
i think the piece that i get excited
about is is is this one um
this is the seal
and and really where we'd love to you
know the people that are working on this
project and myself would love to see
this get to was the idea of the seal
almost becoming like the green padlock
uh of of you know vulnerability
disclosure and
you know the the right kind of like
legalities and channels and frameworks
being put in place
behind that and and i use the green
padlock deliberately knowing full world
that that's in the process of being
phased out like i would love to see that
happen
for this to be a thing where you know
vulnerability disclosure programs and
the acceptance and understanding of good
faith security research is so ubiquitous
across the internet you just don't even
need to say it anymore like that would
be
a fantastic goal i think a fantastic win
for everyone we're not there yet so this
is this is what we're doing next um so
how we've broken out
the seal at this point in time is is
basically
uh a good faith statement which is uh
sometimes referred to as partial safe
harbor and then a explicit authorization
which is sometimes referred to as full
safe harbor
those two things are really important in
terms of the difference you know partial
safe harbor or a good faith statement is
essentially when you read a
vulnerability disclosure policy and it
says words to the effect of if you're
not a jerk we won't layer up um
it's better than nothing and you know if
you go back to the tweet that i posted
just before um
not you know the it's actually in the
minority the the the number of
vulnerability disclosure program
policies that have even
you know a basic good faith statement is
actually not the majority of the ones
that are out there so
you're doing better than
a program that doesn't have one if
you've got something like this
the challenge
to it is that it it isn't providing
authorization like
the
um
you know under
the the con
the problem with this is that it's not
actually providing explicit
authorization which is kind of the
linchpin term
of cfaa so
theoretically uh and if you go back to
the dji case with with kevin this is
pretty much what happened there
um
you know if there's
vulnerability submitted or if there's
security research that's that's done
that
you know as a organization you don't
necessarily like
you can turn back around and say hey
that was unauthorized and all of a
sudden you're kind of back to square one
so you know i think the risk of that
happening uh with a good faith statement
is lower than you know if one doesn't
exist at all but it's still incomplete
so that's where full uh safe harbor or
explicit authorization kicks in
and really what that what the deal is
there is that
you know you've got legal language which
obviously is in the templates uh that i
just mentioned um
you know you've got legal language that
that explicitly authorizes good faith
security research in context of any
hacking laws like the cfaa
but it also provides exemption for any
circumvention laws
which
uh you know things like the dmca for
example um you know making sure that if
you're doing security research and and
bypassing circumvention controls in a
way that could trigger something like
dmca there's an exemption from that
there's also an exemption under
the acceptable use policy or terms of
service
which is kind of in the spirit of what
aaron's law was trying to to basically
achieve you know the whole idea there is
that if you
if you violate the terms of service uh
in in the way that you're interacting
with the computer system or a service
does that then constitute or
unauthorized access that that kind of
brings you into scope for prosecution
under cfaa um so there's an exemption
for that and then just a general
acknowledgement of good faith it's it's
you know really kind of almost this idea
of hey like we believe that you're
trying to do a good thing so let's make
sure that that's stated and clear
if you've got those things then
yep that's full safe harbour um
well that's that's you know explicit
authorization in terms of the disclosure
seal
and at that point organizations that
have have met
kind of the burden of
of of proof or the burden of you know
compliance to either of these two things
they can then display that seal which is
when it starts to get interesting which
is what i'm going to get to in the next
slide
so
this is where it starts to go viral
and this harks back to the whole the the
picky and the brain slide
earlier on
how do we get it to the point where
it's not
conversations like this one where people
like myself and others in the space are
trying to convince uh program owners
that doing this well is a good thing
like how do we just make that
you know something that that is a is a
draw it's a pull rather than a push
and and really this is this is how we're
looking at it and this is how we're
actually trying to get this done with
disclosure you know an organization
launches a vulnerability disclosure
program they're added to the list either
because they do it themselves or because
you know a hacker or a security
researcher or you know someone who works
on disclosio adds them to that list
if they don't have
a good faith statement or explicit
authorization at that point
they'll notice that
because they'll come up with a yep no
you don't have that um
at which point you know the
organization's going to go back to the
repo and see this opportunity for them
to add terms that are going to make
their vulnerability disclosure briefs
safer
at that point
safe harbor is is granted or the seal
rather is actually granted to them
they display it and a couple of
interesting things happened at that
point their customers see it uh you know
the beauty of vulnerability disclosure
programs i think compared with a lot of
other security controls that we have is
that your you know your grandma or your
grandpa can understand it it's something
that's accessible as an idea to a
non-technical uh person because it's
basically neighborhood watch for the
internet so as an organization if you've
got the neighborhood watch sign
on the front of your website all of a
sudden your customers are feeling more
confident and comfortable in your
product as they're rocking up and making
a decision whether to buy or not so
business improves that's good right
then hackers see it and realize that
this is an organization that's been
proactive about making me feel welcome
as i'm trying to help them out
so security improves which is good um
the part that i get really excited about
and we've seen this in in all sorts of
different industries through throughout
the life of bug crowd is that peer
pressure starts to kick in so the idea
of you know there being like three banks
um
two of them are running bond disclosure
programs with safe harbor the third one
isn't all of a sudden that third one is
starting to look a little behind the
times and they'll correct and actually
work to catch up to to be in parity from
a best practice standpoint with their
peers and honestly i think that's the
thing that we need to trigger um
getting it to the point where
you know it like vault disclosure and
interaction with security researchers
isn't the thing that uh
the crazy crazy bay area companies do uh
anymore or people that are you know
technically aggressive and progressive
and how they're approaching security
it's just something that is a normal
part of being on the internet and
frankly you're kind of weird if you
don't do um that's you know what we can
kind of trigger with this network effect
and you know given again the uh the
unprecedented times it it feels
a little too soon to be talking about in
terms of you know viral marketing and
network effect but really that's kind of
what this is about how do we
increase the the r naught of of doing it
right so that's the goal of this project
um
you know in terms of how the folks that
are
that are watching this and and
participating uh can
you be a part of it you know start a
vulnerability disclosure program if
you're in a position to do that within
your organization don't go off half
cocked and just do it it's something
that you need to actually think about
and plan out but like get on that get on
that train um i think you know
interaction with security researchers is
something that everyone who is in the
security industry is going to need to
figure out how to do at some point in
their career
so the choice right now is to be
proactive about that or to wait until
you need to be reactive with that and i
think proactive is you know probably a
better choice um
if you'll if you're already running a
volume disclosure program or if you're
launching one
you know add those causes like make sure
that there is either good faith or
ideally explicit authorization causes in
your brief enjoy and disclose io like
display the seal proudly um
you know get to the point where you're
not only making hackers feel comfortable
but you're driving best practice in your
industry and you're actually signaling
back up to legislators and people that
are you know considering whether or not
it's time to reform the cfa
you're giving them something to look at
in terms of you know the groundswell
support for that idea uh that's
something that we can all be a part of
as a team sport um contributing to the
project uh you know we're at github.com
disclose um
you know hello at disclosure uh
all of those contributions you know
there's there's a bunch of stuff that
we've got
already kind of
working that really relies on constant
community input and contribution so so
being a part of that would be much
appreciated there's a bunch of tooling
that we're wanting to work on as well
you know you saw the security.tech
scanner there's other variations of that
that we're working on putting together
to actually map out the internet so
folks that you know particularly can
program in golang and and
you know can
work with
others in an open source tooling
capacity we'd we'd love to hear from you
and to be able to work together on that
as well and then spread the word i you
know i think again
the idea of this movement is to
basically make vol disclosure normal i
think of the you know i mentioned
earlier on that bug crowd was the first
platform to market there's
at last count 40 or 42
i believe um
you know similar to bug crowd platforms
that exist all around the world at this
point that's fantastic like honestly
this is bigger than that i think it's
it's actually making sure that the
immune system that the internet can
function properly um
and you know i think that's something
that we can all get behind
so to sum up
the cfa and other anti-hacking laws
do continue to chill good faith security
research we're seeing
evidence of that we're seeing things
that go wrong even as recently as this
week
as as we record this talk
but you know there's been enormous
progress over the over the last eight
years
in spite of that there's still a long
way to go
but things are trending in the right
direction so like let's all do our part
and uh yeah
thank you very much for attending my
talk i uh you know again
many thanks to uh to the os crew um
vanderage and and all of those folks um
you know really appreciate the
opportunity to connect
uh i am on twitter at casey john ellis
would love to
connect with anyone with questions or
follow up from this and enjoy the rest
of the conference thank you