acunetix helps thousands of
organizations secure their websites and
web applications across the globe
whether you're a one-person team
ensuring the security of a few websites
or a large organization interested in
automating your web vulnerability
assessment and management acunetix is
here to help
hi and thank you for watching the waffs
wasps we don't need no stinking wasps
presentation here at the owass
conference
before we begin let me give you a brief
background of what i do and where i work
i'm a senior application security
architect working at point click care
which is a world-class software
organization that primarily focuses on
the long-term post-acute care the senior
care and home care markets
essentially what we do is we make sure
that your grandparents
or your parents depending on how old you
are are very well taken care of i'd also
like to say that it's an honor working
up quickly care because for every hour
and every day's work that i put in it
really affects millions of lives of
seniors in many countries and it's a
very fulfilling career
so let's begin
first i want to talk about
web application firewalls giving you a
brief history
now labs or web application firewalls
were originally created in the early 90s
as firewall
network uh as network firewall
extensions by gene
spafford bill cheswick and mark ranum
but they can only handle a very few
applications like ftp or rsh
here you'll see in the picture
a request comes into the firewall the
fireball detects a threat it returns a
403 forbidden
or if everything is fine with the
request packet coming in it validates it
to the application
and the application's been secure
now dedicated web application firewalls
they entered the market later in the
decade aaron reshef and gilly ranan were
the inventors of the first dedicated
wife the app shield
here again we see the firewall taking a
request and projecting or forbidding
if it doesn't pass its rules
but now you see a separate entity it's
called a web application firewall so the
request get proxies to that it then
inspects all the data coming in
if there is an error occur it returns a
403 or forbidden if not it sends the
request to the application
that's now secured
so the top 10 web application hacking
techniques laid the foundation for the
waft market these will look very
familiar hidden field manipulation
cookie poisoning parameter tapping
buffer overflow cross-site scripting and
many more
now in late 2002 that's when the open
source project mod security was
introduced which is heavily used in the
market today
so what is the purpose of a web well in
short
it is to block malicious bi-directional
web-based traffic
it's not an ultimate security solution
meant to work
it is it is not an ultimate security
solution meant to work with other
network perimeter security solutions
when used alongside network firewalls
and intrusion prevention systems wavs
provide a holistic defense strategy as
you can see in the picture below
so what are some of the problems that we
have with waffs well graph rules and
policies can be overly broad this leads
to many false positives
which leads to white listing uris or
headers or cookies or parameters you
either disable rules to allow the
applications to work as they were
designed or you add custom rules to
limit the exposure
and why does this happen well because of
wasps they can't be sure how your
application works on its own
some interesting information an article
i've read approximately a month ago
it said that forty percent of security
professionals say that half of cyber
attacks bypass their wasps
wow that's a big number
traditionally from the web here is a
listing from azure's website
it talks about web exclusion lists
you can exclude
uris headers parameters cookies and the
like and even the wording below states
that you know certain active directory
applications they they insert tokens
with special characters that could be
blocked by the laugh itself so you can
exclude them
additionally
you can even remove certain rule sets
from running themselves why would you do
this because if you need to have your
application actually be running
and the loft that you just implemented
is blocking that particular page you
might be desperate and you might
actually disable whole rule sets
completely this is a horrible thing to
do
so why do these problems arrive
well what's uh they don't actually know
how your application works here in the
picture below you see how the wife takes
in a request
it valid anything any validated request
it processes the application deem safe
but
if you have any whitelist or disabled
rules or custom worlds you really are
bypassing the waff itself
and everyone knows once a wife once a
bypass is established that hole is very
hard to close in the future
have you ever tried to google bypass
waff
you'll see lots of websites and cheat
sheets and get repos owasp itself even
has a sqlite bypassing guide
that'll help you bypass
their your wasps
have you considered these we're all
familiar with the javascript colon
syntax to run javascript in line and a
webpage
but take a look at the very next slide
java percent foo
right you see that
that's exactly the same thing you're
actually allowed to embed characters
into the javascript keyword or how about
the next one that's expression tag
that you can embed comments within every
letter of the word
how about the very last one
uh this product is well it rhymes with
js duck
let's call it that there is no textual
characters it's all spaces and
non-alphanumeric characters does your
wife block these
generic rules are extremely difficult to
create and maintain so you always need
to validate and sanitize untrusted data
now we're going to introduce you a new
concept of san waf it's an application
level security control what it is it's a
sanitation web application filter and
it's implemented as a filter or
intercepted and it's added to increase
your application security
it's application specific
it executes prior to any application
code being executed
the pre-validates parameters before
passing them to the application that
works in line with your application
it addresses white listed waf rules uris
cookies headers and parameters
and it really validates untrusted data
entering into your application which is
one of the biggest security issues
is trusting untrusted data how many
times have we seen
where data that's entered in by a user
gets echoed out hence you have a
cross-site scripting vulnerability
introduced
so what is the purpose of sandwath well
it's to provide a generic
application-centric mechanism to
sanitize all untrusted data entering
applications during the picture
anything that comes prior to the san
juan is deemed insecure the sound of
itself it will forbid data from entering
the application
or it will proxy into the application
itself
after the data has been sanitized making
your application secure
now let's take a look at the bypass
example
let's say you have a cookie that's being
blocked by the waff
and it's causing you an issue so you
decide to whitelist it
does this decision create a
vulnerability
so here a request comes into a firewall
passes the firewall rules
it'll get protected to the wife
the laugh itself well if the request is
valid and passes its rules
it's still green everything looks good
however since we actually whitelisted a
cookie what are we doing we've
introduced
unvalidated data into our application
which turns your application
red
with the introduction of san juan which
would then inspect you can configure it
to inspect that cookie and make sure it
is valid
it will turn your application back to
green again making it secure
now it's got to be understood that
sandlots do not replace waves like waves
never replaced firewalls
they are an additional layer of
protection
they can be implemented as a filter or
interceptor
in the session themselves they don't
have to be validated prior to the sanofi
interrogation
it really stops all invalid requests to
the applications
so this reduces your compute time
especially if you're not inspecting
those sessions
it's extremely fast in operation very
low overhead
it's simple to implement and configure
and really it focuses on data sanitation
now who hasn't seen this code well java
developers anyway
we've probably written this code
thousands if not tens of thousands of
times
where you read a request parameter into
a string called s and then you inspect
that you say if it's not null and the
length within a range of zero to ten
and then you have some more code in
there
this well this is writing sanitation
code and it's very tedious and time
consuming which leads to it being error
prone
thus
your data is not really fully sanitized
wouldn't it be better to pre-validate or
sanitize your parameters before using
them in your system
let's take a look at how san juan works
it's at a 50 000 foot level
so it's a logical view from the browser
to tomcat to the application
so the browser submits some payload
let's assume there's an evil payload
into the application
the application
will then call the san joaque is threat
detected passing in the request object
san juan will process the parameters
it will look for errors and any errors
that it sees it will compile them and it
would set the error attributes onto the
request object and then return a pass or
fail to whoever called it
then it's up to the application to get
these error attributes right if it's a
fail that is
uh sorry if it's a pass if it's a fail
then it gets the error attributes and
it's up to you what you want to do you
could throw you can throw an exception a
security exception and allow an
unhandled
exception handler to handle it and to
you know nicely present the data to the
end user but it's really up to you how
you want to progress from there
here's the structure of sandwich it
really has
it has global settings and it has these
things called shields
we'll talk about them in just a bit
the shields themselves have shield
settings
regex settings and metadata settings
now
let's first talk about the global
settings there's a master enable
disabled flag well this is kind of easy
to figure out what that means what it
does it turns it on or off
it also includes app version information
now this is this is useful because every
time you have an error and it gets
logged you might want to include this
app version so for austerity or for
inspecting what's what's occurring
in your application you know exactly
what application version this error
occurred in
it also defines error handling
how you want to handle it do you
actually want a tracking id to be
correlated with this log entry
do you want it to return the list of
elements remember in that flowchart
before when it said it sets these
request error attributes it's up to you
you might not want them you just want to
say it's a pass fail that's fine you
don't have to have it that's what you
configure here
next is generic error messages
these are default error messages for san
joaq data types which will be explained
shortly
now shield settings well
what are shields shields are really
logical units to group your rules
you don't have to have
many shields but you could have to have
at least one shield it's up to you you
can have one shield and put all your
rules into it or you can logically group
your rules into multiple shields
now these shield settings include the
name of the shield right so that you can
understand
which one uh which shield actually
caught the error if you have more than
one configured a maximum min data length
before processing this is useful because
let's assume you have a shield
configured for examining cross-site
scripting and you can't do a cross-site
scripting uh exploit under four
characters so if you specify the minimum
to be four characters in data length
this shield won't even fire saving you
processing
time it has specific error messages for
sound data types these actually override
the custom error message the global
error messages that is
and you can specify them
[Music]
for each individual shield that you have
configured next you have regex and
metadata settings which we'll get into
right now
so for the regex settings it has a
minimum length for the regex to fire
again
everything we do in cenua it's got to be
performant because if you're going to
expect every single parameter inspect
every single parameter you've got to
make sure it fires very very very
quickly
so the minimum links there in the set so
why even bother run the rig x unless
it meets a certain condition
you have a force regex settings which
includes exclusions we'll talk about
that more in detail in a little bit
we have auto run patterns and this is
defines what all your string type
elements have to go through
you have custom you have custom regex
patterns to secure specific parameters
headers and cookies
some of the metadata settings well
you have enabling sections
that is
perhaps you might want to have a shield
that only looks at request parameters so
you'd only enable the parameter sections
not the headers or the cookies
next you have
section key sensitivity
well with this one
you can specify whether you want to when
you're requesting parameters to look at
them in a case insensitive or case
sensitive way
in a previous job not where i am now in
a previous job we had i remember one
page was written we had a variable let's
just call it fubar
and in the page it was read three
different times and they all went to the
same variable
one was the foo bar with the capital f
next was fubar capital f and capital b
and next was all lowercase
they knew one of them was there but
different developers are passing in
different cases this is terrible i know
but that's what this is for is to
address that issue
next it has three lists security lists
and these are for parameters headers and
cookies and this is where you define
which parameters headers and cookies are
actually going to be protected by sand
well
so now let's talk about
the sandwich data types there are nine
of them in total and they're very
powerful and they're a lot of them are
written to be
very
fast
first is the character i think that
one's self-explanatory it's a single
digit single character anything you want
notice it doesn't have a max min setting
that next is the number which could be
any positive or negative number
right there's no limit to the length of
the size of the number itself
now notice here we can specify the max
and the min
this determines the length
right of the string that's coming in
so if you know that your number assuming
it's a positive only number with no
decimal has to be two characters long
from zero from zero to ten you can say
minimum is one character maximum is two
characters and that'll limit it
so if somebody or a hacker tries to
actually send you a lot more data it
won't even be looked at it will be
rejected just by the length setting
next is a delimited list of numbers what
this means is you could take a look at
the example 123 comma 456 is that you're
expecting this parameter header cookie
to actually be a list but it's delimited
by some character in this case a comma
next is alphanumeric that's all the
alphabetic and numeric characters that
are allowed
next is alphanumeric and whitelisted
characters this is a very powerful
very very powerful data type
in our example you see o'brien very
common it's also numeric well not
numeric but it's oh it's alpha anyway
but it has a special character the
single quote apostrophe so this allows
you to increase the the
increase the scope of what alpha numeric
and the whitelist characters represent
next is the string the s for string and
this uses the shields auto run reg x's
that are generated
next is constant
which is a list of constants to match
this is very useful for instance let's
say you have a form
and you're going to ask for what is the
user sex either male or female
or other
you can have three different values
specified so if it's not one of those
three constant values coming in
it will not it will be rejected at that
point
next we have custom reg x's and these
are ones that you define specifically
for parameter so they're not like the
string one which uses the auto run reg
x's to find the this shield
this one is for specific parameters and
it can be used by many parameters you
could use date as an example
all right and apply them to all your
date fields coming in
and finally we have a java class method
and here is where you're actually able
to run a java method for a particular
parameter very powerful you could do
whatever you want you connect with
databases you could do anything that you
want
now
so how does san web actually work here
so what a request is processed by san
wash
remember it has multiple shields if you
only have one for elimination blue
it leaves you for each shield
and in specs is the
header
cookie or parameter let's call that a
key is it within the shield's minimum
and maximum range if it is keep going
otherwise
fail out
is it key protected by the shield itself
that is is it part of the secured
parameters either parameter listing
cookies or headers
next for each value
that is well if the key is a value for
each array value of that key
right
does the keys value max the max and the
min range setting pass of the shield
yes
well look up the key data type
and then let's call the is threat
detected for the key value
and here notice the string is not listed
on here we're going to talk about that
in the very next slide because it's a
more complex behavior
then that's assuming a threat was
detected
it says is error handling enabled well
if it is it adds the attribute to the
request object
the tracking id and the error json
and then it returns true
now let's take a look at strings
we'll check out we'll start off
where the is threat detected occurred
and again this is just for strings
we look at the data type
can it be a string if no data type is
found interesting so this isn't a
non-secure parameter cookie or header
it says is a regex always enabled for
this shield
if it is it checks are you not part of
the excluded list
so if you're not excluded
run all the auto run regex rugex's
configured in the shield
and return pass fail
however if it is the string data type
well it knows just run
all the autorun rug x's
and return your password
so it's really quite simple
so what's the performance of all the
stan lot data types well
it was written to be very very highly
performant
now obviously the the quit the quickest
ones are going to be character
number
number delimited alphanumeric
alphanumeric and more characters and the
constants they are by far the quickest
of all the data types out there
we inspect we fell very very very fast
so let's say you have a number coming in
and the very first character is an a it
fails on that it doesn't look at any
other character so it doesn't have to
it's written to fail fast
now string performance well it really
depends on the auto run regex is created
and specified so if you have one that's
very quick it's going to be quick
now remember that zenoff will actually
cache compile and cache all the reg x's
upon startup
this also impacts the regex
data type
they are also
the performance will be dependent on the
regex itself but they are also compiled
and they are cached at startup so it's
only done once to compile
so they are quite quick
and finally it's listed as the java java
method the
the performance depends on the
complexity of the code if you're hitting
up a database that's going to be a lot
slower than if you just use standard
code
so the way java
methods work is that it uses reflection
but we instantiate and we cache the
class method on startup so this is done
once so the performance of really
running a java
data type channel data type is that of
you running a static method
so it's still very quick but again will
not be as fast
as the above ones listed
so let's take an example here of how do
we actually use this in san juan
so in this example we're talking about a
delimited set of numbers
so we're going to have a parameter array
which is called parm array and just a
regular parameter called dlim
and it's going to contain
a comma delimited set of numbers that
must be all five digits in length
so here in the shields metadata
secured
parameter section we have two items
the first item being the parm array
specified with the n curly braces
comma and curly braces
bracket five comma five in bracket
so that's a numeric
comma delimited numeric that has to be
five characters long and we also have
the item dilem equals
n comma the exact same thing
you can also specify this is the exact
same configuration as we saw before you
can specify it in one line so for
instance you you say that i want to have
all my five digit comma delimited
numbers in one parameter item entry
these three colons to sep to separate
them so here in this example you have
two
parameters defined
within one item entry
you can have as many as you want
and it's a nice way to keep for instance
all your dates together in one simple
line so you don't have to keep looking
for them as people add it it item
let's take a
well before we take another example
let's take a look here that
all headers cookies and parameters they
can be array notated
we use the star character
right as a placeholder
and as an example we have p star so
parameters of p 1 2 3 4 and on they're
accepted
but all these have to be numeric
here are some more examples you can use
it in square brackets you can have dots
before
or you can have the complexity increases
there really is no bounds you can be
square brackets
regular parenthesis and so on it's up to
you so you can experiment as you like
it's very very easy to use
let's take another example here of a
delimited set of numbers but this time
let's use a reg x
this time let's also use a cookie called
cookie numbers and it contains a common
delimited set of numbers that must all
be five digits in length
so here you see the shield and a new
entry that we haven't seen before regex
with its custom parameters
and in there there's an item
which is
got a key that says delimited set of
numbers
and a value so that would be the regex
associated with that delimited set of
numbers
next we have metadata secured but this
time instead of parameters we see
cookies because we're addressing a
cookie now
and the item name of the cookie the
cookie name would be cookie numbers
and its data type is r curly bracket
limited set of numbers
five comma five now why is it important
to add five comma five well let's assume
you don't and your reg x defined above
it doesn't deal with the length either
this is a great way to have a regex dos
denial of service
because somebody could pass in a cookie
number that's a thousand characters long
and if your rug x is quite complex that
takes a lot of processing a lot of
compute time
on this case if you say it has to be
five or zero to five however you want to
specify it you're actually
pre-validating the length of the data
before it actually hits regex
right but it also should be noted that
this example is an unrealistic example
because using the n
right the number the the n curly bracket
comma is much quicker than using a regex
let's take another example an
alphanumeric and a white listed
character so here we're going to use a
header
right and the header name is going to be
alpha comma colon that supports all
alphanumeric characters including the
comma and the colon characters
so same what we see before shield
metadata secured but this time it's in
the headers it has an item
with an a curly bracket comma colon and
curly bracket that's how you specify
a header with the name
as an alphanumeric and more
finally let's take a look at using a
java class
well first thing you have to do is you
have to create
a class that has a public static boolean
method that takes in one parameter right
now the java class only takes the value
of the parameter that's that you've
defined it for or that you set that
particular data type to
in this this is an unrealistic scenario
i know but here is a package called
package.com.foo
and the class is called bar
and the method again is public static
boolean greater than 10 with a string
one string called v
and we check if the integer the percent
is greater than 10 return true as false
and the way you configure this in this
shield is the shields metadata secured
parameters and this time
you say that the item so this this
particular parameter name unit test java
it's going to be protected by this
particular
fully path
class dot method name
very simple to do
next we're going to look at string and
rig x's
so here you see an empty listing on the
page that has a shield and a regex
section as well as a metadata section
i mentioned this before but i want to
reiterate again because it's quite
important we have this concept of
inregex of auto run patterns
these are the patterns that you want
every string
every parameter cookie or header that
has the data type a string to run
here you see
i've set up a string called string
parameter equals s so that string
parameter equals s notice it doesn't
need to specify the key name because
here you're it's going to be using its
data type of string so it's going to run
all the autorun parameters listed
on the other scenario if you just want
to set up
a reg x
for one specific parameter so here's a
delimited set of numbers that we've seen
before again
that's where you use the r the data type
the reg x data type so that's where the
difference is between a string and a
regex one is assumed to always be
writing it and one is assumed to not
always be running it
right
and the reason why this is done is
because remember that force regex you
might want to set up a shield that's
always looking for sqli and you don't
care what the parameter is inspect it
for sqlite
so how do we implement the soundwell
unfortunately only java projects are
currently supported if you want to
create another open source project in
your own language please contact me
i'd love it
this current currently satellite is zero
dependencies well i'm not sure i should
call it zero dependencies but it really
has no runtime dependencies other than
the jre and the tomcat servlet
the reason
we don't even have any loggers defined
in san juan
the way we do that is we implemented you
have to implement an interface and pass
in that class to us and whatever logger
you want to use an slf for j log for j
and so on it can be used without
incorporating any dependencies now we
feel this is important because it makes
it very simple for you to consume san
joaf in your application
it can then be implemented as an
application filter or an interceptor
you can use sanof methods independently
or in the application code
here is an example of implementing a san
juan filter
so you create a sample filter to
validate all incoming requests
right so you see public class sanja
filter implements filter
then you add it to the filter chain well
it's done
right but make sure you call the filter
chain.do filter at the very end and
notice the white
the white text below
static san joaquin's new sandwich
right
then in the method it says
in the do filter method if that is
threat detected passing in the request
if it is well it's really up to you what
you want to do as mentioned before
if you want to get the data you call
said and wow
you call request you call sound left i
get error messages
passing in the request object and it'll
give it to you in the json format which
we'll see an example very shortly but
it's really up to you how you want to
process when a threat's detected
quick mention about logging here
if you don't provide
a logger
the system.out.printline will be used
for logging this is terrible
so the way you do this is you create a
class that implements a
com.soundlab.log.logger
interface and there's only two error and
info that are provided
and there you could set up your own
loggers that you want that's the left
for j log for j as i mentioned before
it's up to you now we do this in order
to not
add any more dependencies than we have
to
which is essentially it's next to none
then when you instantiate san juan
you pass in the logger
right so here's another equals new sound
with the new sound off logger
very simple
so please do not ever instantiate sound
wealth unless you're doing it for tests
without passing the logger because we
all know system out the front line is
not
fast it will not be as performant as you
probably need
let's take a look at some of the an
example
of an error message and how it's
presented
uh by sandloff
in this example we have a parameter
defined as alphanumeric and more
parameter right which allows spaces and
um
question marks
and here's some payload some bad data
blah blah blah
when you call the cell when you call the
get tracking id if you've enabled
tracking id that is in in the globus in
the shield settings
it will pass in the
tracking id
this is very useful because if a
customer sees an error repeatedly they
can give you a tracking id and you can
see exactly what's occurring and help
them get get past that block
next you have an example of what get
errors would return
this is an exploded json view of what
would happen but typically it's on a
single line
so you can actually configure your sim
to monitor your log files looking for
this and if they repeatedly see the same
thing occurring
you can raise further alerts and have
your security team investigate further
what i want to point out here are the
sample points
because notice how we tell you what
parameter the data that's occurring
that's going to be
escaped obviously what error we give you
the error message these are this error
message these are what's either
configured in the global settings or in
the shield settings
it tells you what data type that caused
it in english text in english terms the
shield's name that occurred as well as
the app version where this error
occurred
and the reason why you do this is notice
how the sample points over here they
mark up with the data look at below
right i only put the numbers so you
understand the positions that the
exclamation
the semicolon and the four dashes are in
error
now you can actually take that data that
json and then even in javascript
you can you can specify it to the end
user come up with a nicer screen not
that this is a nice screen by any means
but you could come up with a nicer
screen
and prevent a nice message to the end
user saying in this case invalid data
submitted please contact and reset
please correct and resubmit
well the alpha numeric characters and
spaces in the question mark are
permitted show the bad data you can even
highlight it in this case give them a
back button to help them out so they
don't have to re-key and all the
information and again there's that
tracking id with the 1.2.3 which would
be the application version it's up to
you how you want to render this data to
the end user or if you want to at all
now sanof if you download the
application you'll notice you also get a
sample
uh well i can't really call it an
application but let's it's a servlet
right
and this cenroth servlet it gives you a
simple page it's a very rudimentary
servlet
all the html is hard code and so on but
it allows you to play and test with it
so you can put in valid data and as you
can see this mmf results with the air id
and the error json listed below
so it's very useful for you to play with
and then you can even add your own and
maybe
try to make these error messages look
better
before you present them to the end user
so where do you get sandwell well you
guessed it and get in github so you go
to https
github.com slash bernardo1024 sandwell
and here on the right you'll see this is
what the code looks like it's very tight
code it's very small
zero dependencies well
not really zero but mostly zero
dependencies
and then here you notice that there's no
bugs or vulnerabilities this is a jacoko
scan represented in sonar in a sonar
report the two code smells are really
related to that logger dot system out
right that one that if you don't
instantiate send one off with your own
logger it will use the system out one
that's what those are for so i can't get
rid of those unfortunately
so thank you for watching my
presentation and i hope that you'll
incorporate san juan off into your one
of your projects
if you want to contact me please email
me at bernardo.torontowass.org
but before i sign off i'd like to give
special thanks to my wife and family for
putting up with my late nights of coding
san juan i'd also like to thank
pointlesscare especially my boss andrew
jeters for encouraging me to open
sources ny software and finally i want
to thank tabitha lama for calling and a
good friend of mine for helping me with
this presentation
so now i'm leaving you with my
collection of deflated balloon animals i
hope you enjoy them and have a great day
thank you bye