well welcome back again uh
we're our next speakers created the
fashion at tech studio amped antelio as
a way to explore modern fabrication
techniques and interactivity and
clothing through medium of wearable art
which is of particular interest to me if
anybody if any of you know me i hope you
all enjoy their talk as much as i will i
welcome
sarai cohen and how rodriguez as they
share details about conductive melody a
texture instrument
well welcome we're really excited to be
able to talk about our piece conductive
melody i'm sorry and this is hal um
together we have a little wearable tech
couture design studio called and a
player
um
so we started this piece in 2019
as part of make fashion which is a group
out of calgary
and this is for a presentation at beaker
head which is the science and art and
music festival in calgary
one of the things that we like to create
are
wearable garments that have
interactivity so
um both of these examples i have up here
on the screen are
um one is a piece that has a color
sensor so the model can
change the color of the lights in the
garment they're 3d printed lights and
she can change that with the color
sensor using um different objects and
then on the right hand side is
a piece that we made for a dancer that
has an accelerometer and
she's controlling the speed and the
color and the
action of the lights on this garment
through her dance moves so
um
it's kind of really important to us that
the garments we make are not just pretty
flashy lights although that's fun too
but they can be controlled by the person
that's wearing them or they can be
controlled by you know
sensors that interact with the
environment or even the audience so some
of the pieces we make have bluetooth and
they can be controlled by the audience
as well
so when we were thinking about this
design and thinking about how to make a
essentially wearable instrument so i
like to
play around with electronics and
make garments and do costuming and how
really like synthesizers
and kind of electronic music
and we were thinking about what are some
examples of
um
essentially musical instruments and and
how we could fit those onto a garment um
so one of the things i was thinking of
were hearts you know large strength
instruments and
this is an example of a historical
garment um kind of medieval
poupons and other kinds of garments that
have really large sleeves and that would
give us plenty of room to do kind of a
conductive fabric interface for this
and then other examples that we can look
at are pianos which also have kind of a
keyboard that you can touch and then
kind of strings extending from that with
hammers that are making the the musical
notes and um kimonos that have also very
large sleeves that provide a lot of
space to make this interface um there's
been some wearable instruments that are
kind of drum kits um there's a drum
hoodie that people have made
and other kinds of ones but i wanted to
make sure that there was enough room
um for
the
the wearer to really demonstrate that
they were playing that instrument
and also to be able to kind of make it a
performance so they're performing the
music and they're performing the garment
so i start all of my pieces by
essentially doing a design sketch
um some of these are rougher than others
you can see on the right that there's
one that's basically just like a
humanoid shape that has kind of ideas of
what this garment might look like and
usually if it's a piece that we're going
to make i develop it into
more of a
a complete design sketch so on the on
the left hand side i have an example
that would kind of use a kimono inspired
sleeve with these metallic
kind of scrolly baroque or floral
interface that i wanted to use
for the where to do the interactive
music
and then as i produce a piece i
typically do a mock-up um for those who
make wearables or garments this is
typically called a muslin it uses a very
thin cotton fabric
um and it's intended to you know just
see how the garment might fit i do this
through a combination of drafting using
measurements from the body and then also
draping
so here i've made a piece that has you
know a sleeve
a bodice and a skirt and then because i
wanted to make it a little bit different
than some of the dress type garments
that we've made before i added some
leggings um to kind of give it a
different look
and then as that comes together i
usually choose fabrics
one of the things that i really like to
do for my garments for like tech couture
is to use couture techniques and
materials so for example this garment is
made out of silk
um i just think that it helps you know
when you're gonna do a one-off creation
it really helps to pay attention to
those details and another design
style that i like is to kind of hide my
electronic components
so in the center here there's a
semi-shear net peas with sequins and
beating
and and some of my electronic components
for my lights are going to go behind
that
here's an example of the couture
techniques that i use inside the garment
i find that this helps them wear better
and just makes a more beautiful and
complete project i've
found the seam allowances and bias
i have a netting piece that contains
the light strands that i'm going to use
and that's sewn onto
the other the main garment so they can
be removable um definitely something i
think about a lot in making wearables is
how will this be worn how will it be
washed
how can somebody care for it
one of the materials that we really like
to use are
conductive fabrics tapes and thread um
so i made conductive pom-poms
um all sorts of sewn garments that have
conductive thread for this i wanted the
conductive interface to be very large
and i used a conductive fabric this was
you know fairly easily acquired it has i
believe steel woven through it and it's
colored copper
and
it is a mostly a polyester fabric so
what i did was i bound the fabric with
heat n bond and that has an adhesive on
both sides so it binds the conductive
fabric to the silk
and then using design software
illustrator we drew these kind of
organic almost art nouveau
interfaces that
kind of replicate the strings of a harp
and then cut them out on the laser
cutter
and then bonded them onto the silk and
so this is what formed kind of the
interface the conductive fabric
interface for our instrument
yeah
so this is what's going on in the dress
we have
as sorry i mentioned that the
essentially the the main
uh interface the main control area is
the sleeve
and the sleeve is uh
the
copper looking fabric is is
basically sensed by a
capacitive time solution we're using i
think a
breakout board made by i think adafruit
uh and it all communicates the touch is
all communicated to a small arduino the
small arduino controls the lights on the
dress
so as as notes are played
you'll start to see
you'll see the lights all light up in
sync with the pen because they're
they're responding basically to the
touch as well
uh there's lights on both the front and
the back of the dress and that's all
controlled by arduino which actually
lives in the sleeve
now the the um
the machine so we're also we're also
turning the 8
the 8th century little strips
into a wider range by extending against
the music by using a raspberry pi
running
a machine learning model put out by
tensorflow project magenta called
pianogene the pianogne essentially takes
eight inputs and expands that out
musically into what you encode would be
an 88 piano keyboard
the output from that from the raspberry
pi is essentially uh originally we were
using audio but this time we decided to
actually pump out to midi
the idea is that we'll have um rather
than relying on wireless mics we'll rely
on bluetooth midi or another kind of
midi over the air to basically have a
standalone dress that can be performed
the raspberry pi is actually hidden in
the ruffles
of the dress in the back
uh everything's powered by just a good
old um
uh phone battery and it seems to work
fine so uh to get if people are a little
bit interesting to see what goes on
underneath essentially the raspberry pi
is running magenta uh using a javascript
library so we're running it within a
node app and all that basically happened
there is it's reading in serial from the
arduino uh just essentially byte data
because we have eight eight control
eight little individual controls so it's
coming in as a byte we tran we we parse
that out we run it through pianogenie to
take a input from one of the buttons to
actually get a midi note
and then that gets output as midi so the
the fun thing about that is that the um
if we hit a particular note
you'll you'll hear that it's essentially
not the same note every time
it'll change
uh and that's essentially the model
which has been trained on uh
on classical music pieces to actually
expand that melody expand those eight
buttons into something that is actually
a little sounds a little bit more
melodic
uh and i think we would like to do a
little demo
so we're gonna we're gonna
we're gonna stop screen sharing
okay
[Music]
that's
so one of the things that you'll notice
as we play this and i'm going to let it
um
not play for a while is we wanted both a
musical output and kind of a light
output
so that um
people could
experience this garment both ways both
visually and
through music so if you'll notice i'm
not playing the garment right now and
we're getting kind of more of these
white and yellow tones and the lights
aren't turning on very quickly
and then as soon as i start playing
we get more of these pink and blue tones
and there's a lot more activity that
happens on the garment
[Music]
yeah
yeah and because it's all middies we
basically uh allowed we basically are
able to switch the instruments on the
fly really easily for example we can
switch to a
another instrument let's try this one
[Music]
a cello sound
but that that's all the the magic of
mini
oh and
yeah
[Music]
we could also introduce a
little backing soundtrack as well
[Music]
yeah all right so some lessons learned
about the construction of this garment
um
uh we've done several things with
conductive fabric
and it does need to be stored carefully
because you can run into issues where
if you make
parts of the connection too thin
or if you use a silver fabric it might
tarnish and you'll lose some of the
connectivity
so
it won't be as conductive you might not
be able to play all parts of your
garment
you want to talk about software issues
um the software the software running a
raspberry pi were you know the biggest
problem we had initially was getting
good quality sound out of the pie just
relying on the
the the bill italian audio system the
raspberry pi gave us sound that was a
little clicky
uh and also uh
we have um
we also decided to move off over to midi
just because we can rely on external
sound modules that can be plugged in
directly into a sound board at a either
like at a show or a fast short or a
music venue
kind of separated just the the music
generation out of the piece just to make
what runs on the dress uh a little bit
more um manageable
uh stable and uh just to leave the dress
as essentially a controller
um
but yeah i think that's you know it's
been fun um
uh
yeah i think yeah i think that is our
talk
unless there's anything else um
so thank you very much for listening if
you have any questions about
conductive fabrics or any of the
electronics or music that we used or the
components that we used for this project
um how we'll be hanging out on the
discord i'm going to answer some
questions for you
i guess we'll we'll play it out yes
well thank you very much uh we really
appreciate you speaking with
our remote economy again