hello
no namecon 2020 my name is question tim
corson
i'll be talking about the country of
unlearned lessons today and
i hope you guess what country i'm in
it's a bit dangerous now in ukraine to
say
where do you work so i'm just
regular everyday normal cyber security
expert
i cannot see you and cannot hear you now
but i feel you
so you know cyber wars
became more than actual in modern world
ukraine was on an epicenter
of cyber attacks in 2014
2015 2016
and 2017.
let's remind what happened on ukrainian
cyber battlefields
in may 2014 pro-russian hackers
intruded into central election committee
network
and tried to mispresent far-right
candidate dwitro yarosh
as a winner of presidential action
in december 2015 pro-russian hackers
intruded into ricarpatia obal energo
power station network which
led to blackout for more than
230 000 people
in more than for more than six hours
in western ukraine
in june 2017
attack against popular bookkeeping
company
caused huge damage for ukrainian economy
many companies had to stop the
activities
for weeks and even months
in 2016 2018
many types of malware affected
energy and transport companies media
banks many other critical infrastructure
objects
whole world carefully watched the
biggest
cyber attacks
after similar attacks on the ground
in 2014 2019
ukrainian army became one of the
most efficient in europe
as the same happened with ukrainian
national
cyber defense and cyber security
let's take a look and make our own
conclusions
uh so let's begin with the volunteers
initiatives
uh ukrainian cyber alliance
set up in 2016 as
informal community of patriotic
pro-ukrainian cyber activists
from ukraine and worldwide
you see
united falcon flames trinity
roof 8 and kiberkunda
cyborg hackers groups
main goal of uc is protection
from russian cyber aggression
uca took responsibility for many
cyber attacks and cyber operations
against russian and pro-russian
politicians
persons and organizations
hacks of terrorists pavlov moscow
ministry of defense of russian
federation
russian first channel and a news channel
and other hacks
in october 2016 uce
leaked gigabytes of emails and other
documents belonging to russian political
senior kremlin official
vladislav sorkov and head of department
in the institute of the cis
countries curiel from very close to
kremlin
next initiative inform nepal
this is an in information and
analytical web media to keep ukrainian
and international audience posted
about the donbass war the annexation of
crimea
and the activities over the russian
special services
as as well as pro-russian militants
ngo informed nepal was set up in
2014 their main focus
is open source intelligence
uh they also revealed tons of evidence
on
russian relation to mh17 crash
balling cats researchers are based on
original informed napalm's materials
next initiative responsible disclosure
frd it was set up
by ukrainian cyber alliance as well
i told on frd in details
at some cyber conferences including
international ones
at a glance this was something like
patriotic activists flash mob
when activists make public incredible
facts
of low protection of critical
infrastructure including governmental
resources
it should be said previous government
didn't like frd but
supported it unofficially because
eventually
it was useful for the country's security
current government fabricated false
criminal investigation
against activists and the project died
in february 2020
so what has ukrainian government
been doing since 2014
let's consider facts and figure it out
more cyber centers had been set up
for millions of dollars however
they still don't work correctly
law of ukraine of main principle of
providing cybersecurity of
ukraine this law was
adopted in 2017.
below is very weak
and doesn't work now it was
born only because of western partners
requirements
to and in law on cyber
any according to
current valid law six
central authorities and one coordination
center
should provide national cyber security
all of them are governmental
agencies no private sector
no community no ngo no academia
only total government
and of course such a system
cannot work
totalitarian draft law number
it was about digital civil surveillance
and against freedom of speech freedom of
the internet
freedom of access to information
ukrainian parliament tried to vote it in
and 2018 twice
but civil society and cyber community
united and stopped it
and incredibly motivated blocking
of about 100 websites
by ukrainian courts
a quotation from court's decision
to arrest intellectual property
right which a website visitor
gets by viewing this
website one more time
to arrest intellectual property right
which a website visitor gets
by viewing the website
more than 100 websites including big
platform
with million of users like enigma.ua
have been blocked
they are still blocked now
in november 2019 vice prime minister
minister of digital transformation mr
mikhailov fedorov stated literally
following
i think that the role of cyber security
is a bit overstated
vice prime minister
this is how my emotions look like on the
previous statement
and of course this is picture of
loyalty
digitalization gear and governmental
digital services
now about four million users have
downloaded
governmental application dia
this name could be translated as action
its security still haven't been proven
no documentation no security reports
no open community research nothing
just trust us guys it's secure
in 2018 and 2019
frd cyber activists
led odessa airport and authorities new
on critical problems with via cyber
security
odessa airport cyber security in a year
in november 2019 a known person
defaced odessa airport and placed a
picture
with greta turmeric on the airport video
panel
cyber police ukrainian cyber police and
security service of ukraine cyber
department
initiated a criminal investigation
and conducted searches in frd
activists houses
with no results of course
ford activists arrange a press
conferences
conference on this lawlessness
the criminal investigation is still open
uh in 2015 this gentleman
had had been arrested for a bribe
sorry now
he is a chairman of state service of
information protection of ukraine key
authority
responsible for national cyber security
i don't wanna know his name and don't
remember
don't forget man
what else and zero experience
officer from the most corrupted
department
of security service of ukraine had been
as
has been assigned as head of
security service of ukraine cyber
department
and now what this cyber department
does they hunt
covet agitators they
fabricate criminal investigations
against
activists they
purchased electronic surveillance
complexes
in two times more expensive that it
should be
they they catch horse and
play football
what else no improvement of cyber
legislation since 2017
no one nothing
million dollars and million euros from
united states
european union international
organizations
have been wasted
so what all mentioned above
mean in my humble opinion
to be honest the lessons have
not been learned at least by
ukrainian government
critical infrastructure is still very
weak against potential cyber aggressions
like in 2014 2017
private public partnership still
does not work in cyber security field
of ukraine
cyber tour ukrainian cyber authorities
are still
impotent because of lack of
qualified staff mainly
and those authorities ignore
community driven initiatives
oh this is just a funny picture i like
it
do you like it
local experts are very disappointed
with the government's ridiculous effort
to strengthen national cyber security
in cyber protection
everyone protects itself only like
many years ago sorry
personally i created at least three
conceptions on how to build an
efficient effective cyber security
system
in the country i
presented them three times at cyber
conferences
i met politicians and officials
and tried to explain them
what is wrong and how to improve it
no reaction no positive changes
i met foreign diplomats from donald
countries
and they noted they noted yes you're
right
but continued financing of
useless programs so
i have no idea ideas anymore
this is how optimism in ukrainian
national cyber security looks like
ladies and gentlemen we live in such a
sad reality sorry i cannot inspire you
and give you false hope
our country is still not protected
like in 2014
to make your mood better after this sad
presentation
just look at that funny pictures from my
personal collections and have some fun
this first one is about cat
second one about proper english
next one about pronunciation
and this is something like very
hard to understand joke but i like it
oh there is a positive news although
the us government is going to
support ukrainian cyber security for
38 million u.s dollars
and this is the biggest amount of
investment in such a specific
technical area however
the main beneficiary of this large-scale
scale project was determined
surprise surprise ministry
of digital transformation i mentioned
it in a in my previous slides
just a reminder head of the
ministry still believes that
the rule of cyber security is
a bit overstated
by the prime minister
and this is last funny picture for those
who is going to celebrate
this first conference date tonight
is it really today's uh first or second
conference
i i don't i still don't know okay
so thank you very much and
we have enough time for questions
and answers or probably some
other conversation right
yeah thank you thank you
bye bye so thank you question for this
awesome
and clear speech and i'm going to read
you some
questions from our q a session are you
ready to answer
yeah i do okay so the first question is
um what are the worst
current threats to ukrainian government
cyber security now
attackers insiders or bad security
culture what is it
actually in our world there are a lot of
attackers protectors and and many other
threats
however the level of cyber defense and
cyber security depends on
about on mainly depend on depends on
cyber culture cyber security culture
level of
knowledge maybe skills experience
people it's it's a very serious factor
uh so uh from my point of view
cyber culture uh compared to other
threats
is a most important thing
to to build something
better protection
thank you for the answer we have another
one uh
what's the best strategy of improving
ukrainian
government cyber security you share a
lot of your thoughts and
recommendation in your facebook feed is
there a better way
so uh i wouldn't uh
all i thought on that uh on facebook
pages
on uh articles and i created
uh very big long reads on how to improve
it and now
i still don't know i i have no better
idea
how to improve it and it's a it could be
a very long speech for me from my end
so at a glance very
sure the government could could
not be a leading organization uh uniting
all cyber security people in ukraine to
protect our country better
uh it should be something like mix of
government
community uh probably academia and
science people
uh and many young people skilled
people not very skilled people it should
be trusted computing communities
trust trusted unity probably where
people uh at least trust each other
nowadays community
doesn't trust to government government
doesn't trust to
anyone uh all people who
do not trust to government and to uh
commercial companies etc something like
chaos
uh this is where no one can trust to
each other
so uh the target number one or from my
my opinion uh it should be to set some
some organization or maybe unity or
maybe
i don't know which form it could be
uh something where people
can not trust but can trust
each other this is i think it should be
first time
thank you and the next question is
pretty interesting let me translate it
to you
uh if you were head of ministry of
digital transformation
what be your first steps
if i be it's absolutely fantastic
situation
i won't be a government employee
never again never again so
uh uh i believe that
minister digital transformation
shouldn't
i i will i will do my best to ensure
that
okay oh yeah yeah you will uh
thank you vlad for your support
and yeah i believe that uh this ministry
is not useful for ukraine now this is my
my private opinion
um because of because of many things
so it's it would be long speech again
uh however uh it
i believe that someone it should be
some something like uh
government community and international
donors organizations
organization responsible for cyber
security in uh
in this in this country and to set up
such kind of organization would be very
very difficult
because of untrust because of uh
lack of cooperation lack of conversation
between people
and by the way thank you thank you for
no name conference
which unites cyber security expert and
professional professionals and
many people related to cyber security so
uh
this the first uh step would be
set up something like trusted
organization or maybe
trusted unity of people trusted
community maybe including government
including community
including commercial sector of cyber
security
including somebody else science academia
and etc so if
it probably if
it happens some somewhere
and i'll be involved in it in such kind
of uh
activities uh
i will do my best to
make people trust each other it it
should be first step from my end
okay thank you and the next question is
from alexandre derkaj
uh will electronic petition on
change.org change something
uh no that's a short answer
nothing absolutely nothing
uh no reaction no response
no changes no negative changes no
positive changes
uh only deputy minister of digital
transformation mr alexey wisco
said that
my article on facebook is a
stupid lie yeah uh
and this this was only uh one response
on
it uh um i'm disappointed
and because of that however i expected
some
some kind of of this scenario
so uh this was my long answer but short
answer is still no no
thank you alexander for your question
and one more question is there
any countries which steps in cyber
security ukraine should follow
oh probably
probably finland i like finland uh
approach uh because probably uh i know a
couple of people from there
from uh finland sword and how it works
there
uh how they improve how they cooperate
to with community with business
uh with people uh within the country
uh also i've been in uh
south korea uh
it they they have very very positive
experience however
i'm not sure that it could be applied
applied
for ukraine because of lack of mentality
because of
differences big differences in culture
and approaches into
some relationships between government
and people
etc however it works very good there uh
many countries uh i i i like
how they they cooperate and how they
work
mainly those countries are
germany great britain or
france uh mainly in the european union
uh it uh the
united states experience is very good as
well however
the strong rule of government in this
country i
i'm not big fan of that so
uh canada australia new zealand
many there are many countries we could
fall to
uh however ukraine has
unique way so we have to
we have to stay stay at at zero point
till now sorry okay
thank you uh the next question is really
a
nice question for debates from alexander
kache but
i will ask you it now is it possible
to support market price for government
cyber security specialist
uh one more time please is it possible
to support market price for government
cyber security specialist uh
genius salaries yep uh
i don't think so uh actually it's a big
problem worldwide not only in ukraine
uh government pays less than commercial
sector
everywhere in great britain in
united states in new zealand everywhere
however a good practice would be to
uh involve commercial services
uh as an ad hoc or maybe a
uh how to external external company
providing services some services not all
services
are maybe related to cyber security not
completely whole
cyber security at the government agency
but
uh as uh freelancers or probably
external services
partially supporting uh
government's needs how it works
worldwide
in in many different countries
uh at the same time i do not like idea
when
foreign governments finance
uh ukrainian government uh employees
make a paying them additional additional
seller or additional money
and it looks like uh probably a
foreign influence into our internal
policy
so uh i do not support this idea very
true
probably is it some best way right now
to to uh to fill the gap
great gap between uh salaries in private
sector and salaries in government etc
probably it's a just a temporary
solution
uh but i don't think it's a good idea
generally and to support
uh government
cannot pay private sector sellers
it's impossible everywhere every time
however it shouldn't be so great gap
between those salaries
it should be probably 10 or 20 25
differences difference between private
sector and government center
and government sector could uh hire
probably high level expert and those
high level experts
could hire external companies for
external
for uh some separated uh external
services
to to to supply some some part of cyber
security
or probably technical assistance
probably this could be a
good way from my point of view but at a
glance
thank you for this nice answer and we
have
one more question in our q a
session and in q a section maybe
if someone wants to ask one more you
could type it right now
and the question is what's the
difference between cyber war
and cyber terrorism if russia attacks
civil infrastructure i do not like term
cyber terrorism terrorism is a when when
someone somehow is died
somehow is killed uh because of
uh criminals yeah terrorists i i do not
there is no cyber terrorism cyber cannot
kill
uh nobody it's it's impossible
it could help with something with
communication
or probably if uh cyber terrorism
switched off uh electricity in a
hospital
where people is lying on on the on the
maybe some devices uh making the blood
pressure
so uh it's uh
they do not kill them directly
they switched off something which killed
killed the uh some people
or a person uh so i do not like this
term
there is no cyber terrorism there is a
regular
terrorism uh which uses which which
use uses uh cyber technologies
and i.t technologies uh so it's
again this is my only private opinion
i do not like this term i i think
terrorist terrorists just use
uh cyber technologies i.t technologies
at some other advantages
so yep thank you for your answers very
good answer thank you for your speech
constantine we are happy to have you
thank you