alrighty welcome back from
Dundee nanog program committee chair
will be getting started here in just a
minute I do want to throw out a reminder
to fill out the surveys we'll be
announcing our survey winner between the
next two talks and so hopefully you
filled out the survey yesterday you may
have a prize coming to you one other
note we do still have nominations open
for the program committee and
communications committee for 2015 we had
some discussion get some good discussion
in the community meeting yesterday about
ways we can improve diversity within
this within the leadership of Dan aughh
and this is one of the ways to do it
please please nominate anyone you'd like
to see on these committees we very much
would like to get fresh blood in here
and with that I will hand this over to
Ryan Craven Ryan is here to present
thank you very much Ryan thank you bear
with me one second here
Ryan's got some live demos for us so
brace yourselves
alright so thanks to introduction so my
name is ren craven a little bit about me
real quick I'm a recent graduate of the
ph.d program at Naval Postgraduate
School in Monterey California and now
I'm back on the East Coast working for
the Space and Naval Warfare Center which
is in Charleston South Carolina as part
of the US Navy and some of my work that
did while it's at mps was about
measuring in-flight packet header
modification on the internet and so why
do we want to do this well we'll see it
all boils down to how middleboxes
interact with tcp so prior to starting
up a new connection you know what is TC
TC p doesn't really know anything about
the end end path conditions between
itself and receiver a priori but during
the connection there are questions it
needs to answer in order to make the
most efficient use of that path such as
how fast can send how much did i send it
once you know do the other end get my
data was an intact piece missing etc and
so in order answers questions TCP has
tools to make inferences during the
connection you know and some of these
have been around since TCP was first
created like sequence numbers and others
over time have been added on as a
network evolved and requirements changed
such as congestion control in the 80s
and so we believe that modern TCP needs
to know the answer to another question
and that is am I being misinterpreted in
other words is some new feature that I
want to use going to be properly
communicated along a path and one way we
can check this is by looking at and
flight pachyderm modifications and so
the main reason we have to ask this
question is because of issues with
little boxes on the network so for
example take the scenario where to TCP
endpoints Alice and Bob communicate
across the internet you know we've
actually oversimplified this particular
scenario a bit what it really looks like
is a bit more no boxes like firewalls
proxies etc basically the reality is
that path is complicated by middle boxes
of all types doing things like enforcing
policies expanding address base playing
tricks to Nia's performance etc
and there's a survey in a sitcom paper a
couple years ago that surveyed some
nanog admins and they found that across
all networks sizes this is enterprise
networks the number of middleboxes is
actually on par with the number of
routers in a network and you know what
they found is a lot of these devices or
standalone systems that hard to manage
their expensive to buy maintain keep up
to date and they usually require a
well-trained staff to maintain and
configure them so it's not all that
uncommon when stuff breaks and in fact
that same survey found that most admins
spend one to five hours a week dealing
with middle box related failures and
nine percent said they spend six to ten
hours a week and in that same survey
miss configuration was cited as the most
common cause of failure when it occurred
now that failure could be something
obvious like a bad fire older blocks
traffic or what we've targeted which is
the more subtle issues that can hurt
performance and protocol innovation and
which can be really hard to debug it's a
good example of that that I want to get
into here is with ECM so with ecn you
have the sort of 1980s version of how
the headers looked and then you have the
post ecn version of the headers and the
difference being that the second bite of
the IP header is now split into dscp and
the TVC n bits and they've also
reassigned some reserved bids from the
TCP header but the problem is is that
even as recently as a few years ago so
this is you know ecn was from first
started being created around two
thousand or so so it's been about 15
years and even as recently the few years
ago research was still finding devices
that misinterpreted these fields that
messed that difference up between the
1980s version in the 2000 version and in
one paper the authors discovered a
switch on a major ISP that was actually
messing up ecn by mistreating that
second bite of the IP header and it
turned out it was an issue that the
provider didn't know about another
example that illustrates this problem
pretty well as with TCP window scaling
so imagine for example that two
endpoints are going to talk to each
other and they want to use a window
scaling value of seven unfortunately
there's been real instances where a
device was found during out the scale
value and the result is that these two
endpoints Alice and Bob give differing
ideas of what
all says receive window really should be
and in this case what happens is Alice
thinks our window size is 128 k whereas
Bob thinks her window size is 1k and so
you know what does this look like to the
user so I'm going to jump back over here
to the demo you see I started this file
transfer before I came up here and it's
running really slow so I know what's
wrong with this there's transfer why
it's going slow and that's because I've
put a middle box in between these two
these two hosts that is zeroing out that
windows get value and so knowing that
what i can do actually is kill this
transfer and then turn tell linux to
turn off windows going and then try that
file transfer one more time you can see
that actually runs so much faster now
and it's a bit counterintuitive because
if you look up window scaling in rfcs
it's in an RFC titled high-performance
extensions for tcp and we actually got
better performance by turning it off and
so why was that what was because of that
the no box that's in the way and so you
know what are the chances that an
average user would know that that's the
problem that's the reason their file
transfer is going slow that's sort of
what this this talk is all about so
there's some other examples ecn and
window scaling are just two in a sea of
IP and TCP functionality they can get
disrupted by middleboxes at one time or
another there are actually other issues
we've seen such as TCP selective
acknowledgments artificial flow control
using the receive window and then a
whole bunch of stuff in the IP and TCP
option space the high-level takeaway
from all this though is that you know
these are real problems they're going to
continue to occur the network's not
getting any less intelligent and
something important to stress here is
that even when these issues occur on
just a small percentage of connections
that can still have a wide reaching
impact for instance just a small
percentage of connections affected is
enough to dissuade for instance a large
content provider from turning on some
new feature so in that sense it can
really hurt protocol innovation
but we do recognize that mailboxes can
and actually do do a lot of useful
things for operators providers and
they're not sometimes customers and so
we want to really want to be able to
detect and fix these without disrupting
the more well behaved mailboxes and so
when it'd be great if we can easy way to
detect these it could benefit
researchers with the measurement tools
TCP performance extensive in terms of
performance and extensibility and then
of course operators for better end and
debugging and leading to happier
customers and this end to end piece is
pretty important because you know if the
problem is somewhere that's outside of
our administrative control it can be
much harder to debug and often requires
cooperation from another endpoint to do
some testing to really determine it and
figure out where the problem is in
what's causing those issues so there are
some tools out there already to help us
with this if you do have a cooperating
endpoint you can actually of course you
can just run TCP dump and manually
compare the output and see if a mailbox
is changing something in your headers or
you can use one of the more automated
tools nmap has a tool called n ping
that's got an echo server and client
that you can use eff has been working on
some of these and for purposes of
network neutrality and they have a tool
they they worked on a while ago called p
captive which sort of led into other
tools called switzerland and TP cat but
one of the more useful ones is a tool
that doesn't need that cooperating
endpoint like all those other ones do
call trace box and it actually doesn't
require that bed endpoint and it has a
similar methodology to trace route but
it goes to the extra step of parsing and
differencing the ICMP TTL exceeded
quotes that come back from for matters
and checking to see if any middleboxes
made changes between those hops the pro
is that you get the location of the
modification but there are some cons in
terms of you know reliance on ICMP and
then also the same problems with reverse
path measurement that you get with
traceroute so it all kind of feeds into
the main challenge which is an available
and reliable communications channel so
say you're trying to communicate an
integrity check between two tcp
endpoints you know you could do
something like an out-of-band ICMP maybe
make a new IP or TCP option
try to redefine a field out of the
header but the problem with all of those
is that the very same set of paths that
will most likely disrupt those methods
are precisely the paths that were most
interested in testing so for instance if
you go to trouble and creating a new
option to carry your integrity chuck it
could get stripped out by middle box and
so you need something that will be most
capable of transiting all types of paths
and when you really restrict yourself to
that you also run into issues of
capacity you know getting enough bits to
send the information you want and then
also being incremented playable making
sure that you don't break anything with
whatever you're trying to do and then a
more subtle issue of being middle box
cooperative so this goes back to our
point earlier that sometimes little
boxes can actually do useful things for
us and so we don't want to disrupt or
otherwise circumvent well-behaved middle
boxes and then also being able to inform
both endpoints and so our solution to
meet each of these challenges is hiccups
which is a lightweight TCP extension
that exposes in-flight packet header
modification to end points essentially
what we're trying to do is automate the
question did my packets arrive at the
destination with the same headers as
sent the idea here is we're trying to
protect mailboxes making changes so that
we can help TCP determine whether it's
being misinterpreted without interfering
with the good metal boxes and at a high
level a little bit about how the hiccups
works so we actually overload 3 header
fields out of the three-way handshake
the initial sequence number of the
initial ipid in the initial receive
window and we overload each of those
with a function of the packet headers
and so now each of those three fields
serve dual purposes in addition to the
original job they also contain hiccups
and probation and we spread over three
fields in case one has changed so in
some of our early work we found that you
can't just rely on for instance a
initial sequence number because there
are quite a few boxes out there that bit
translate that and change it and so we
also use a lightweight hash function
because we really have a little bit of
space in our case we only use three sets
of 12 bits so we use the light weight
function and we also make the assumption
there's no shared secret available and
that's so that we can work with general
in the general case with anonymous hosts
on the internet
and the result of all this is that we
create an end-to-end tamper-evident seal
over the packet headers and we want to
stress that this is different than a
checksum for instance if the
modification occurs to the packet header
we still accept that packet it's just
now that now TCP get some extra
information about what happened and can
try to take a step maybe to recover from
it or work around the issue or bring it
to you attention to the user and so in
order to use hiccups a house tcp stack
has to be enabled with it but once that
happens hiccups can be used without
endpoint coordination our long-term
vision is to try to get this into TCP
and so if all stacks included it you
know kind of work in a parallel in terms
of how in the way congestion control
helps TCP and fur and and congestion
congestion state hiccups could help TCP
and for end-to-end packet header
modification state and so for our
implementation we wrote a patch for the
Linux kernel version 394 that alters the
TCP stack in Linux to enable hiccups and
this particular edition requires no
action by applications but if they want
we provide some additional optional
features they can take advantage of for
instance getting the the status from the
check mandame of specifying certain
fields the application maybe won't check
and then also engaging what we call apps
alt mode which is an additional way to
add additional protection to the hashes
and make them harder to fake and we also
have a set of cross-platform userspace
tools so that we can do some one-off
testing in cases where we can't or don't
want to alter the colonel so we use our
tools and some measurements that we ran
on the general internet using planetlab
and also Kate Ozark and the goal being
here is that we wanted to you know
through we call vidding with our
measurements is if there was some sort
of interesting behavior happening we
wanted to find it so we tested a range
of different ports and parameters and
for instance like we checked different
ports because prior work has shown that
some paths actually exhibit port
specific behaviors where middle box may
be operating on one port but not the
other and so we wanted to be able to
detect that and find that and summarize
our measurements at a high level almost
half the nodes we tested
saw at least one in path header
modification to one of the ports that we
tested and this was more than expected
to find especially given the nature of
our measurement network you know we use
planetlab which is mostly hosted on
university networks and it should be
more open and research networks and so I
guess I was a bit more than we expected
we also saw cases of a symmetric
modifications where the header
modification only occurred two out of
the forward or reverse path but not both
and so this table here shows a condensed
version of all the different
modifications that we tested for and
found and each number on the table you
see represents one of the port path
pairs and there's a few one here that I
want to point out in particular the
first one being I signed translation
that occurred on about eight point eight
percent and the potential is there for
TCP selective acknowledgement disruption
the idea being that you know some older
devices will translate the sequence
number but then fail to also update the
to seek with a copy of the secret number
that's placed in the sac blocks and the
result is you get to sort of out of out
of sync sequence numbers and also
another thing I want to point out is
with ecn IP code points being changed
the potentials therefore that that sort
of disrupt between like the 1980s
version in the 2000s version of the ecn
so this is so this particular this for
instance be bad for ECM and we also saw
some cases of TCP options being stripped
out which you think about it's kind of
disheartening because options are the
primary way to extend TCP in most
instances and so and also this was on
planetlab a narc which are you know open
networks meant for research and we still
saw about seven percent of cases where
the options were stripped
oh sorry and I want to add that not
necessarily all options but more like
than the newer option so multipath
capable for multipath TCP and also the
last one on the list is an experimental
option that we added for the purposes of
test so create a new one and try to
transfer that and we also saw instances
of a new behavior to us that happen with
windows scaling being added so a little
more about that we actually saw it on
one of the planet lab nodes there was
whenever we tried to send out a syn
packet without requesting window scaling
there was a box along the path it was
like oh I'll help you out you missed
window scaling i'll add that back for
you and on the syn ack it also removed
the responding windows scaling from the
other end and so we never knew what was
we we didn't know what's going on and
that's only happened what we discovered
is only happened we're going out that
ports 80 or 443 and window hiccups
helped us detectives so what we want to
do is we ran bulk transfer between our
planet lab node and one of our Hank our
server anchor nodes and we observed that
that transfer was obviously flow
controlled and when we told each unknown
or windows scaling the throughput
doubled so in this case we emailed the
owners of the node and it turns out they
didn't know about the behavior the issue
was on one of their providers systems
and they contacted their provider to get
it fixed unfortunately we don't know any
more details about what it was but the
cool part is that hiccups detected
something that even they didn't know was
happening I was a subtle issue that
affected the whole campus and they were
able to get it fixed and I'll just like
to point you to our website TCP hiccups
org where we have posted our code it's
available for download you can grab one
of the Colonel's we and deploy it we
have some rpms available for red hat
fedora and you can also use the users
based tools and go and test your own
networks and see what you can find if
you were to do that I show you real
quick what that would look like back on
our little demo here so in this case
remember what's going on here is there's
a middle box in the way that is zeroing
out that window scaling value
so this is our user space client here
that you're looking at and when we ran
it we find that it does detect the
window scaling modification happening in
both directions and that's when we probe
for windows scaling if we take off this
tack in here it will not check windows
scaling or yeah it will not set a window
scaling option and when that's done we
see that there's no modifications that
happen and so we can infer from this is
there's a middle box in the way that is
sooo is changing that window scaling
value when we set it
and so last we also have an email
address set up where you can send us any
feedback if you download and run the
tool any issues you have with the tool
crazy middle box stories that you have
an experience you get from using the
tool we'd love to hear it so any of that
is very welcome and that's hiccups at
SEMA org and with that I'm finished and
I'll take any questions
Ralph meulen internet archive I would
love to use the tool and easily can put
a new kernel on one end but on the
remote and I might have more
restrictions on what I can do is there
any way to run this in user space with
like raw sockets or so just for testing
purposes to see what happened yeah
that's actually how the user base
towards using the raw sockets in the
client is cross-platform I've got
working on windows and you know it's 10
and everything but there's a server a
raw socket server that actually have
working in linux and it's part of that
same packet you download it there's an
HS tool in there that you can run on the
linux server if you don't use the kernel
for instance we've also set up some some
measurement servers so on a website if
you actually i think you actually run
the client without giving it a
destination it will download a list of
anchor nodes that we've set up and then
allow you to propos thank you
you more questions all right thank you
very much Ryan
you