while they're coming up and getting
settled some quick announcements we have
our break coming up
after they after these
do their thing and that's going to be
sponsored by allied fiber and NRL please
note that we are having the social
tonight that is the joint Erin nanog
social that is going to be sponsored by
erin and our good friends at comcast we
will then transition after this
discussion is over after we have the
election results in the final wrap-up
we're going to transition to two tracks
that's the Bering track and also the
research track and the research track is
going to have some really good research
content in it obviously you guys all
know what's in the peering track but
please note when the researchers come
here they actually want to hear some
operator opinions so that's always nice
to do and I'm going to turn it over now
I think Betty's going to start off with
the election results and meeting wrap up
thank you Michael so it's been a great
Baltimore meeting me and I'm 62 great
attendance and I'm here to provide you
some wrap-up information from our
meeting and some special thank yous and
then we'll move into Mike Smith who is
our term limited board member who will
provide you the actual election results
so before we go I do want to say thank
you again to all of our host our
connectivity and premium sponsors it's
absolutely important and we're so
thankful that we have such a dedicated
sense of ownership of nana special thank
you from me to our board of directors
they're all volunteers just like you and
so I really appreciate their time and
helping me provide this opportunity to
all of you to all the committee's we
have a small number of paid staff and we
have a huge number of volunteers that
serve on our committees the membership
for coming out being a part of nanog and
being engaged in the election process
the attendees all of you it makes nanog
work sponsors are again and I wanted to
just call out some names instead of
doing a simple label for the staff
Valerie wit cup has been doing an XO
job in running our programs and
assisting me in general oversight of
Nana if you haven't thanked Valerie
please stop by give her a huge thank you
she does an amazing job alyssa is taking
care of all of our sponsors eric who
helps us keep the network working and
provide leadership for our contract
contracted staff floor Annabel and Celia
I mean what an amazing job so and with
Vera LAN and the support staff from
network utility force so can you join me
in giving them a thank you
I can't do it alone and I think the next
slide mic is yours nope sorry not yet I
didn't know what it was my part of my
general wrap up is to give you some
statistic about the 729 attendees that
whoa that's care that's scary 729
attendees that were I won't do that
again we'll just move on okay that's
only supposed to happen during Randy
bushes presentations I don't know what's
happening nope so we'll move on it's
just a breakdown of the attendees all of
this information will be posted on the
website as well what I do want to call
out is our our scholars or fellowship
award winners in the room if you
wouldn't mind just standing up so we can
acknowledge you here great thank you on
behalf of banana our board of directors
and some of our donations it's it's I
thank you for allowing me the
opportunity to fund those students to
get here to our meeting or future
operators that's really important the
rest of the data speaks for itself I
thought we had 29 countries we had 28
countries represented at this meeting
which is really amazing still a great
number tap organizations kind of
trending the same if you look at our
historical website in terms of
statistics we see the host bringing in
you know a fair amount whomever they are
of attendees because they are the host
and you'll see ISPs and hardware vendors
and content providers being right there
at the top of the list of sending
attendees to nan on organizational
description that's just the demographic
information of where we're coming from
this is self selecting so
subjective but it does give us a sense
of the kinds of community members that
we have or attendees and some
save-the-dates it's important for all of
you we have an events calendar we
generally just talk about the nantong
meetings but we are adding into our
series and calling out the fact that we
will be doing education classes the day
before Nana for the next few meetings
and want to point that out in addition
not on the slide is that we have five
nanog on the road meetings planned for
next year and we'll be publishing those
dates soon and target cities and
locations so that is my last slide is
there any questions from the audience on
the meeting the statistics how it went
all right I'll turn it over to Mike
and also I'll take this for Betty to
thank you for the upcoming hosts we have
Cyrus one in San Antonio Netflix in San
Francisco Toric's in Montreal and I ax
in San Diego ok so now for the elections
thanks very much for everyone who stood
to serve its I think a great indication
of people's willingness to come up and
help make these offenses success and so
out of 644 eligible voting members 177
cast their vote which i think is a great
turnout of course we'd love to have a
hundred percent but historically
speaking this is a great number and it's
an upward trend and I hope that
continues so the first was the bylaws
change which extends the term limits for
Board of Directors members from two
years to three years that passed and
that means that out of the three
candidates that we have that have been
elected to the board to will serve
three-year terms and one will serve a
two-year term and the election committee
that I was part of actually did a from
the Hat poll to determine who the single
two-year candidate would be and with
that said they were actually right here
I didn't even realize that so the
two-year board member is Greg Dendy and
the three-year board members are Dan
Goulding and we'll charnock and if we
could give a hand to them
and again I want to thank everybody else
who ran and I hope we have continued
participation like that and it's been a
great time serving you guys and I'm out
so I did want to echo a special thank
you to Mike Smith as he is term-limited
and leaving us and to Steve Feldman for
his two years of service on the board so
my last slide because I know we're
anxious to get to break into the
afternoon sessions is to make sure to
welcome you to our next nanog meeting
Nanak 63 in San Antonio in February it's
a great location we have a little bit
more space and warm location for
februari so we will be issuing the call
for presentation probably in two or
three weeks as well as the new the hotel
link and the call for presentations and
registration in about two or three weeks
in the meantime should there be any
questions about where we're going or
questions that you have nanog support
you'll get to me and you'll get to the
staff and get you back an answer right
away thank you again everyone
David's gonna say something more about
the multicast thing but then um so if if
we are all set for a break down again
the break is sponsored by allied fiber
and in a rail yes that's right and then
remember to the social tonight that's
going to be out at the american
visionary art museum which is sort of
around the harbor a little bit so that's
going to be sponsored by erin and
comcast we're now going to switch to the
peering track the pairing track will be
in this room the research track is going
to be in the Maryland sweets so please
select your track and go to the
appropriate room thank you very much
you