you know everybody
to talk about the special security
project which is started in in the Czech
Republic before I start a little bit
about my company sees ethnic which is
the company name is domain name registry
indices it via middle-sized registry
with about 1.2 million domains and the
special feature of the registry is a bit
about thirty eight percent of them is
signed by alien sex so the security
issue we really address very often but
more than registry we have more people
involved in our MD in research and
development group called Sydney claps
and and we do have various projects very
open source projects I think bird was
presented at this forum couple months a
couple years ago and not DNS
high-performance dns server also very
interesting thing maybe for this
community but to the project to race we
we started about a year ago and and the
idea was called very very nice name
project off of shared cyber defense and
we wanted to address three main issue
first of all we wanted to do a some
security research we wanted to improve
the area of energy security and also to
improve the situation of the home
routers those small devices that
everyone have home and you know doesn't
touch it but it works for him so the
security research currently we do a lot
of stuff in security field we we run
honeynet we we collect a lot of TNS
related data we do many anomaly
detection techniques on on top of the
data but we have a very little
information about the you know the end
uses the network the ends of the those
networks so we wanted to have some more
data from this field so that we came
with a idea to put some probes closer to
the end users and and see what happens
there we wanted to distribute those
probes to as many networks as possible
within the country and we wanted to run
the same algorithm views for dns d I
piano melody
detection mechanism to help the end
users we wanted to create a firewall
data elliptic 50 which will be based on
those data we will collect or we will
collect from the other parties and one
of them might be the the national cert
team so it's easy which is also run run
by us actually and and that team has
cooperation did many other agencies
collecting very a lot of information
about some security or some compromise
devices and the third issue the harm
router so her out us you probably know
all of you know that this situation you
know they are they are they usually
don't have good if any support of ipv6
they have many problems with DNS DNS SEC
they never I haven't heard about any
performing DNS SEC validation if you if
you buy it the only thing you can just
switch it on configure its but you
cannot do anything else you can't
usually legally access it so there is no
support for any other application those
devices have just a limited set of
security features again if any and one
big issue there is not an easy way I
hope to upgrade them those producers
manufacturers mainly in Southeast Asia
they just ship it to to Europe us and
three months later its salt cell to the
end users and the firmware is one year
old with mini box there is usually none
newer updated firmware and if exists you
know those those people who who got
those boxes are not able to to upgrade
it to sometimes is very frustrating
there is a lot of bugs in those devices
and and currently some of the botnets
uses use those devices so and and people
are not aware of it so they just forget
it's it's a normal computer running in
your home 24 hours and and it may it may
do a lot of itself so
yeah so back to the data collection so
we set a goal to have about 1000 of of
those boxes we wanted to give it for
free to the people from for tax purposes
it's official at least for three years
and the price is five us give a sense of
really just a symbolic price and we try
to find a some hardware that would be
you know without mechanical parts nice
enough that you could use it as your
home router but on the other hand
powerful enough to to to forward about 1
gigabit of traffic and in meantime doing
some security analyzes so we couldn't
find any hardware on the market so we
decided to develop our own and that's
how the hardware development and part of
the research study also when we are
doing such a hardware quite powerful we
wanted to this harder to have some
additional features to increase the
volume for end users so it should have a
lot of ports and possibility to run as a
print server NASA and stuff like that so
that's how the road to Taurus was
developed we start development from
scratch and and this is the the final of
it so it looks like this it's a aluminum
blue box which is which is given to
people look like a normal hammer out
right but inside the heart is is
freescale by point two gigahertz
processor about two gigabyte of memory
connected by ddr3 slot a quarter
gigabyte of flash memory which is used
for the operating system and a 60
megabyte of another flash which is used
as a backup backup system in case
anything fails it has five LAN port
Gigabit LAN port which has connected
through a two gigabit Alliance to the
CPU and 11 port which is directly
connected to CPU so basically six
gigabit ports it is two mini PCI Express
interfaces inside one each one is
occupied by the Wi-Fi card
and we use three times three my mail
cart but of course it can be changed
it's just a cart inside it has two USB
two slots and internally a lot of you
know pin hundreds many internal
interfaces so it's quite flexible if you
want to play with that so some Europe
port SPI I to see I i do see a GPIO pins
for for whatever purposes so quite
flexible if you want to play with that
we also included one micro sdhc slot so
you can you can put another flash memory
if you wish we thought it might be
helpful but but at the end of the Navy
we couldn't find any usage for it but
some people use it as a as a storage so
it's free if you want to use it although
it's quite powerful and its really
capable forwarding more than gigabit of
traffic it doesn't have high power
consumption so you don't have to be
afraid if you switch it on in your home
it varies on the load and how much Wi-Fi
is using stuff like that from nine to 14
watts and of course but you can use sir
you can use also the USB to power up the
other devices so then in that case the
consumption increases but it's of course
your option and it's the whole thing is
is licensed under open source so so all
the plans how to manufacture is out on
the website so if you're going to make
your own devices feel free to do it so
this is it as I said and you can see
inside nothing surprises but nothing
mechanical no no fan nothing like that
it has one killer feature something that
really people lost love you know it's
maybe you saw that problem if you have
some device with very with some lets
that it's not very convenient if it's
switch on in a room where you also sleep
which some people have the problems so
that's why there is a button at the back
which which can dim all those lights and
that's a feature beloved by many
students running this device in
they're in the you know sleeping room
those those lights are really software
manageable so many people use it for
various purposes I don't know if you if
you if you remember the David hassle of
movies us with Knight Rider smart card
so many people use the same feature you
know flashing from left to right and
back with the with the with the tories
lights as well so people will like to
play with that so a little bit about
software it's ATS linux-based
distribution open wrt we that's not
developed from scratch we use a lot of
good stuff that was done there however
we added some other features we waited
our own configuration bizarre because
open wrt is perfect for geeks but if you
distribute those those routers to normal
people that are not a verb of network
you have to make something very simple
for them so we develop our own
configuration bizarre and also edit a
net con flyer to trace so these bizarre
uses that layer but also this layer can
be done by some other other applications
of course so that's the way how many
teresa's can be configured automatically
using that conf interface something
that's very important for us it's it's
able to be outta matically updated so
you know if there is some security
problems all the tourists are updated
but in case there is that the update
requires reboot you can for example set
up the trees for example if there is a
need for reboot please informing by
email and if I do not react in seven
days rebooted in n3 a.m. for example
this is the way how do people set it up
to so the reboots doesn't you know break
any operations that you need in your
home it communicates with the central
server there's a crypto chip with with
some key material so that's the way how
it's up means the the data to s there is
one process called that collects the
data there's the only mandatory process
if you join this project otherwise you
know device is open you can you can
access it and modify however you want
and you have also an Andrew application
that can that can manage this device so
if you don't have to login into your
computer to look what's what's going on
in this device this is just how the
results look like this is an example of
Wi-Fi setup as you can see you can use
your QR codes to configure your your
phone or tablet of Olivia a little bit
about the data collection the in the
center part is it's a demon called micro
coiffed or you collect if you wish it's
a pluggable system for for data analysis
it's something like you know pick up
module or something like that it's a
heart of the active security monitoring
system we also collect all the fiber
locks so if any unsuccessful attempts to
connect to the router we we look at the
router log so upgrade status some
software problems we also collect some
other data like temperature load memory
and flash utilization you know this is
our first hardware at them so we wanted
to be sure that those devices are okay
they are not too hot and so on so we
collect all those data and they are sent
to the central server using the
decrypted ribosome s
mentioned so the micro call it has about
currently about six medals frizzes
called count it's not for us it's mainly
for the end user it counts how many
packets and which protocol family in
which which kind you know when were
forwarded through the device and this is
displayed on the end user portal another
the important one is buckets that's the
module that that does the IP anomaly
detection so basically the device looks
at the normal data traffic flow and if
there is something suspicious it's make
just an imprint of these traffic's and
it send it to to us its interests a hash
imprint of it and if you collect more
such hashes we know there is something
suspicious and we ask the devices to
identify a little bit more what the
traffic was about so that's the way how
we how we do the anomaly detection
analyzes there is also something again
as a service for the end-users perfect
passive network speed monitor bandwidth
so so you can see how much you pay OSP
and how much actually you did get there
is also a net flow like data collector
which is you specifically for for some
suspicious IP addresses we know that our
center of some botnets or something like
that so these networks use a specific
specifically for data we know that our
that are probably suspicious another
module is called I don't know why but
it's called sniff it's it's a module
that monitors or that Pink's to some
high-profile sites so we know how the
rich ability of network is is performing
and also it does dns resolution and also
looks at the ssl certificates of those
sites so we know there is no man in the
middle attack and stuff like that it's
just to be sure that there is nothing
wrong between us and the trees and also
it may do some sort of net neutrality
measuring
last last deployed module is called
spoof we use it to to test eyes piece
whether they come from two bc p38 we
have a we have some club in the Czech
Republic of ISPs that that have some
higher security standards this is called
Phoenix its associated by by the local
internet exchange point Nick sees it and
and this is the way how we test that
those eyes peas that join this project I
actually doing what they declare for
example the botnet monitoring the you
know the key part of it we are trying to
find some botnets and smaller or
something wrong in the network we are
getting from various sources some laser
5p addresses of CAC botnet centers so we
capture as I said flow data from the
from the traffic that goes to to do side
p addresses and if we see something
suspicious we report it to the end
reduce because that's obviously probably
some virus or something in their network
and if users once they might want to
trigger capturing the whole
communication because we never go into
the packet load we just we just stay in
the head a part of packets because we
don't really want we don't want to tap
wire the UN Jesus communication but if
if the user triggers we we can go deeper
and look at the at the communication and
use it for some research purposes we
detected about 20 infected computers
roughly two percent of of the current
end users which I expected a little bit
more so there's probably high percentage
of geeks in the in the project as this
is not you know project for the normal
in juices
the fiber lux we analyzed about 6
million locks today log entry today we
try to find the most event occurs which
is like the number of clients that were
attacked or number of ports and stuff
like that we also include some data from
the honey net and from those data we
collect the we make it the grey list
which is again used for the net flow
analysis later on so if you see some
strong attacker we create a gray least
informed in de turistas to descend as
the flow data and we can explore a
little bit more what's this attack about
which helped us to find some some
misconfigured devices like some people
as tourists is open they can play with
it so either tories or some device
behind them was open to gina's
refraction attacks we found some samba
that's suspicious samba communication
from the entities network to some
Chinese side so it's probably somatic so
again trying to help the DN Jesus to fix
the problems in their local networks and
and one more thing we are working on is
we are trying to find a patterns of
similar attack behaviors so if some if
some IP address is you know it takes
many many devices as a mother does the
same is the same pattern that's probably
either the same virus or the same group
of device is trying to attack something
so we we use some techniques used for
text mining to find some similar things
in those in those behaviors and again we
collect some list of IP addresses that
probably are affected by the same virus
are we for example fine and network
which which does the same kind of attack
so it's probably not a virus but
probably somebody using some farm of
servers to attacking the internet and
again we we cooperate with the national
cybersecurity team suits you set which
is again part of our company so
we are getting data from them and those
data comes from other security teams or
some simply companies that are like that
are providing those data and we also use
those data for for some firewall use
under on the Teresa so so the tourists
can block some certain iframe so certain
certain web pages that are infected and
stuff like that many many of sites were
blocked already and we also provide some
data in case of some some interesting
attack I don't know if you are familiar
with the synology problem but when this
this problem appeared we provided some
data to synology to help to understand
what was going on something we it's in
progress we are working on a module that
will help the people understand what
other devices in his local area doing
you know accounting data and providing
list of what devices they communicate
ways and stuff like that that's not
something that would be collected by us
that's just a service for the end users
there were several tvs that you know
smart TVs that are communicating with
the manufacturers and and sending
strange data so we would like to run the
engine sees that this is happening and
also we analyze the unsuccessful TCP
connections from land to the internet if
there is too many answers for TCP
connection from from your home network
to the outside it means that you are
either infected and your computer is
trying to attack the the internet or
some sites on the internet or or your
orders virus is trying to contact some
some shortly with IP addresses for for
common and concur centers so again some
sign that something is wrong in your
network and must be fixed and we started
some cooperation with antivirus
manufacturers
and user season much more than if he's
using the normal harm router because we
have the whole website portal which
shows a lot of data that we collect from
the router so so we can easily you know
all look what data we collect well how
many packets are sent in certain time
period which protocol stuff like that we
also provide a lot of tutorials that's
that's the part that we would like to
give some another advantage to the end
users so there are there's a lot of
tutorials how to how to change the
written to turn a server to to use this
as a DN DLNA server to how to have VPN
to VPN server or client if if the user
wish if has more connection to the
internet 3gb cap and stuff like that
many people start to provide teachers as
well you know there are some crazy
people that used to race for example as
a sound server for his bathroom and you
know stuff like that people play with it
and and that's why we have the NTC forum
people communicate and tell us the story
this is just a screenshot of of it a
little bit about the legal basis of the
project as I said it's it's technically
it's leasing for three years and after
three years you can buy the device again
for five us cents so for nothing mainly
we have several conditions in the
agreement one is that is to be your main
router to the internet because otherwise
we wouldn't call it the most interesting
data and the people shouldn't switch it
off at least not very often now on the
other hand and of course the data
collection process cannot be cannot be
killed but on the other hand we provide
open access so you can you can ssh to
the device completely change it the
configuration play the day you can do
whatever you wish if you don't stop the
data collection stuff of course
probably you might think of the privacy
because you collect a lot of data from
the end users so we started really very
carefully we firstly consulted this this
project is the local president Data
Protection Authority then you know we we
when we prepare the agreement we send it
to the community and ask for feedback so
we get a lot of fee by we modify the
contract everything we do is open source
so everybody can verify that what would
we declare we do you really do so that's
that was probably the reasons why we got
a positive Big Brother vote in 2013 and
Weaver named as an example how date
private data collection can be done
correctly so some interesting facts it's
roughly a thousand devices online
transferable 64 bytes of data every day
small percentage is ipv6 we register
about 8,000 IP addresses that tries to
connect more than 20 devices you
probably some attackers and now we we
did some six major releases of the
operating system without breaking any
device which is great and and several
minor releases for example when the
heartbeat attack appeared we we were
able to fix it in a few days the same
for all the shock shell shock and stuff
like that so we are real trying to be
quick in those releases we have some
early stage cooperation with various
parties Fraser vellum is comcast
provided some financial support for this
program thank you very much comcast for
that we are working with cooperation
with ripe at last ripe ncc who would
like to make a software module ripe
Atlas or you know running on entrees so
Theresa would act like a ripe Atlas
probe and we we have some cooperation
with them antivirus companies and also
the the national check telecommunication
office to the check FCC is very
interesting too
you have to be able to use some data
about the traffic so so they can measure
so they can measure that you know
declared data in the agreement are
really sell salted sell today to be
introduced so something being we are
currently discussing some the future we
decided to have a new version 1.1 new
hardware version of the touareg stories
router it's basically the same thing we
did some minor other improvements like
USB 30 slot interface and also sim card
slot so it can be easily used for some
LTE router we would like to manufacture
again 1000 pcs and use the same modem so
it's just the extension of the current
topic nothing nothing new and because
vdsl adsl dsl connection is quite
popular in your country we are working
on a very small factor in a tiny tiny
interface vdsl Interfax basically vdsl2
to ethernet bridge that could be USB
powered so you can just plug it to your
to your to race and you don't need any
other third-party more than to be able
to connect to to the dsl network so I'm
sorry last slide because you know we got
many requests for many people who have
to be presented to race hi can i buy
this device is cool and we say no guys
we we are not for profit company we we
are not a manufacturer of hardware so we
never thought that it could be
interesting for anybody except the
research project but on the other hand
we have some harder team some very good
experience how to make those devices and
also the software i think is unique so
we decided to make a new project for
next year so it's it's it's a future
project not ready yet but we would like
to make another version of to race which
is going to be called tory slide and it
should be some educational board
something like raspberry pi but but in
networking verte in
with a lot of ethernet interfaces and
other interfaces and lacking for example
hdmi interface but something that can be
used by network people for playing
working whatever it should be a little
bit a little bit less powerful and then
the original Tories but still able to
provide one gigabit of traffic and we
would like to to use some kickstart
model of crowd sourcing to finance this
project so the old target is to make
BOTS in price roughly 100 doors and we
don't expect you to you know to get
money for the development we just need
to cover the variable to cost so which
means mainly really the manufacturer of
the board is a not-for-profit project
isn't something for sale we don't expect
any profits from that but that's to
address people that came to us and said
please make a hundreds of boxes to me
I'm happy to pay and we say well we
cannot get it to you because we need to
dis for this project and and honestly
the price of this this box is quite high
I know it's 1,000 pieces manufactured in
European Union so it doesn't make sense
to for commercial market but this trace
life would be enlarged evil women and
maybe it would find somebody some people
to play with we'll see so I think I made
my presentation in time thank you very
much if you wanna if you are interested
in in light tourist light there is a web
page light doctor is that Cece please go
there and / register if we will not spam
you and be afraid you are just any
information once there the project is
ready thank you very much
do we do have time for a question or two
dan is that you yes it is how's it going
man dama Gorean Hopkins Applied Physics
lab so did you think about using
raspberry pi type standard off-the-shelf
devices to begin with or with a too low
power or didn't have gigabit wired or
those kind of things I mean I guess I
was trying to figure out why you you
went the customer out i'm just i'm
sewing out what why you built custom
hardware as opposed to basing and on
something like raspberry probably oh
yeah have you seen Raspberry Pi it's
very good device I like it but the
problem is the networking part is really
poor you know it's it's USB connected
ethernet port so it's nothing you can
use seriously if you want to make a
network device so that's why we decided
to make something different raspberry
pis is excellent if you want to do your
home d via a DVD player mp3 player or
something like that it's very strong in
multimedia but it has very poor feature
so I ability in internet working world
so it's better ones out these days they
have gigabit connectivity and all that
but they are pretty reason this is
christian i'm so
start
any other questions
okay thanks hungry thank you
you