hello my name's Heidi Dempsey and i'm
here with tim Upthegrove we're from BBN
technologies and we're here to talk
about how to engineer Sdn in genie
network Genie is a virtual laboratory
for people to do networking and
distributed operations research and
education we started about five years
ago and we have been building a network
of resources which are autonomously
owned by different contributors to
Jeanne the the project as a whole goes
forward in yearly cycles so people will
bring new technologies new ideas new
software into the come into the project
for a year people will integrate deploy
evaluate and then we'll take a look at
the end of the year and decide whether
to continue or not and whether to
transition things from prototype to
further use and into production
deployment experimenters use the test
bed while we're building it out so like
a lot of the networks that you build
it's being stressed while it's being
used and the people who are using it
have a vote in in what will stay and
what will go on the network the two
things that we do in Jeanne as kind of
the fundamentals of how we build the
network are slicing the data plane
horizontally so everybody who brings a
resource also brings a way to connect to
the to the data plane which is a base
which is mostly a layer to data plane
for the things we're going to talk about
today and then there's a vertical
control plane API which you use to
access those resources this is a picture
of how Jeanne looked when we started a
few years ago the resources that were
contributed were open flow switches
servers that could run virtual nodes
virtual machines
regional networks basically the states
that you see colored in were providing
access for over pieces of their
infrastructure and there were two core
networks that were providing nationwide
spanning connectivity that was internet
too and national lambda rail as you know
national lambda rail or as you may know
national lambda L is no longer operating
so the core of the network is now just
provided by internet too so what we do
is take that infrastructure and slice it
up by experimenters so that people can
share the same infrastructure but do
completely different things run
completely different protocols and
different services on it and those
slices are as much as possible isolated
from each other with the technology that
we've got to build them on and then
experimenters can actually download
their own software into the network to
program down to the lower levels of the
switches and down to the lower levels of
either the virtual machines or the
hardware based servers that they've
gotten the network to try new
applications and protocols and services
so in order to access the genie
resources first of all it's open to
anyone who has an interest in research
or engineering integration so you don't
have to be from University it's fine to
be using genie anybody from the nanog
community or people who are interested
in developing new services that's all
supported by the project and by our
members and the the National Science
Foundation which is our sponsor you do
need to get credentials in order to use
the services and our credential
management is based on in common and we
do shibboleth single sign-on to manage
the usage of the credentials as of last
month we have over 2500 users who are
doing experiments on and off or or
continuously on the network and we span
about fifty two campuses a couple of
enterprise networks but enterprises are
still fairly minor in terms of what
they're contributing
11 regionals and 10 wireless sites the
type of wireless that we do in Jeannie
is wimax or LTE and then depending on
the site that might have University
participants community participants or a
combination of both so we run these
experiments continuously 24 7 365 and we
support operations with six different
groups around the u.s. each of which has
a kind of a different specialty for what
they do well when people find operations
issues or technical issues or other
issues with using the network so a
little bit about software in order to
use your credentials and access the
resources we operate a piece of software
which we group together as the portal
and clearing house so there's a web
interface to this and there's also a
programmable interface to this clearing
house and basically the clearinghouse
software which is open source and
publicly available for anyone who's
interested in it it keeps track of the
users and the projects and the slices
that are on the genie network so if
you're sitting at your house or in your
office you can use the genie interface
either the programmatic interface or the
web interface to create and register a
slice and that's where you're going to
run your experiment the clearinghouse
will return to you your credentials to
use for that slice and then you interact
with the places that have resources
using an aggregate manager API to both
provision and control and use those
resources during the course of your
experiment or your integration or your
trial whatever it is you're running on
genie so there's some links in here to
the software in case you want to take a
look at it and to the API definition in
case you want to see how the common API
works the places where you can get
credentials to use engineer right now
are of course the clearing house itself
out planetlab account if you have a
planetlab count that is federated with
genie or an mu lab or as it's sometimes
known a proto genie account now
engineering for a layer 2 Sdn genies
objective is to let experimenters run
their own Sdn controllers so this is
different than a lot of networks that
they probably folks in this room would
be involved in because we specifically
want to give access to people at the
lowest layers in addition people who
operate networks can run their own
controllers so Sdn switch will support
multiple controllers operating at the
same time at least most of the vendors
will support that and so operators may
choose to run a controller and then
experimenters run secondary controllers
on top of that what we do in advance is
go into the SDN switches and the end
points on the network and configure
VLANs that are available to be used for
open flow and vlans that are available
to dynamically make connections between
endpoints the three types of
configurations that we found useful are
dedicated vlans where you have one VLAN
that connects to all the resources
resources in the genie network that are
part of an experiment and those are all
controlled by one open flow controller
or a shared VLAN where you use that VLAN
to connect multiple resources and then
you can have multiple people running
controllers to share control an example
of this might be one person might want
to use stn for the application another
person might want to use Sdn to bring
nodes into and out of the experiment
over time based on demand and so you'd
be running multiples another thing
that's useful for us as operators is you
can run a controller that you can use to
look at what's going on in a slice so
even though the infrastructure for genie
is pretty well defined and not as
dynamic as Sdn can be with a controller
you still need a view into
each one of those slices if there are
problems with those slices so shared
VLANs are good for being able to look at
what's going on in a slice without being
destructive and then finally for some of
the wimax and LTE applications we use
multi-point VLANs that connect all over
the wireless sites so they can do
handoff and interesting experiments with
multi-point experimenters in genie can
choose to work with Hardware switches or
they can choose to work with software
switches swath software switches are a
lot faster to come up to speed on we're
only going to talk about Hardware
switches here but if you're interested
in software switches come up and talk to
us afterwards the genie aggregate
manager software negotiates and
coordinates the resource access so these
are the links to go to if you want to
see how the VLAN stitching works and
again this is all open source interfaces
and open source software and then
there's a special aggregate just to
manage open flow which we call foam and
this is the link to foam the primary
purchase purpose of foam is actually not
to control the vlans it's to allow
people who are opening up their
resources to open flow to have the
opportunity to approve or not approve
connections into their resources so you
can use the foam aggregate manager
software to define patterns that you're
okay with approving or to look at every
single request and individually approve
those are not approved based on what's
happening with the SDN so this helps
with some of the fear and uncertainty of
people who are just getting into sdn so
this is an example of the one of the
networks that we engineered for a
particular experiment this is showing
the core network with different Sdn
switches in the middle of the picture
and some Genie racks I'm sorry it
doesn't look so great on the projection
but if you look at it in the slides you
can see the details about the interfaces
and what we were doing with this
particular network we support lots of
vendors in Jeannie we explicitly want to
be interoperable we support interfaces
from one gigabit to 100 gigabits there's
no Sdn interface that operates at 100
gigabits right now the high she can go
is 40 but we share links with other
research programs so that's why the
hundred gig is is on the list and one
thing that's interesting about our
network is we're still running on open
flow one point oh and those of you I
guess everyone in the room who's been
assaulted by the openflow hype you would
think that everyone would be running
open flow 1.3 by now but it turns out
that when you're trying to do a
multi-vendor network and you're trying
to work with a lot of network aggregates
1.3 is still early on in development
even though it has a lot of great
functionality so we're still running at
one point oh and hoping to move ahead
with 1.3 later in the year we use
standard internet for our control plane
so all the benefits and disadvantages
that go along with that apply to our
control plane but so far it's been it's
been working well and then we use two
services from internet 24 cross connects
one is called ion which allows you to
create and destroy VLANs to connect you
to that core network and another is
called the advanced layer 2 service
which is another way of making
connections on internet to kind of at a
higher speed and dynamically
so this is a list of the vendors that we
support some of these vendors have
multiple kinds of switches on geni if
you're interested in any particular ones
again come talk to us after the bright
open V switch is a popular software one
that we see but there are other popular
softwares which is as well these are the
three popular controllers that we see on
geni flood light box and open daylight I
think floodlight and pucks are probably
quite a bit more popular and then
operators on geni are contributing
software so operations in sdn is still a
very active thing that we're trying to
figure out and do collaboratively with
other system engineers and network
engineers and administrators so a lot of
those are listed on geni yet but we'd
love to get more things you have to
watch out for when you're running an SDN
network you don't want protocols that
aren't Sdn affecting what you do for
routing and forwarding so you have to
disable spanning tree protocol and
disable Mac learning and this is very
simple to write and very hard to do Tim
spends a lot of his time talking to
people trying to explain to them why
that we need to do that and figuring out
how to do it on every type of switch
there is out there because you need to
do it on the whole path and not just the
SDN switches places that are doing
commercial Sdn might not have to be
quite as Extreme about that but because
we're doing experimentation we have to
be very pure about it you have to
coordinate your IP addresses once you've
connected everybody up on a VLAN make
sure people aren't conflicting in their
choices of addresses especially when
you're using shared vlans that really
hasn't been an issue yet but obviously
with scaling it could get to be a
problem we have some operations tools to
look for loops and to look for heavy
loads on switches and also on the
processing nodes in genie and ways of
limiting traffic externally if needed
most of the support for limiting things
in stn switch is is still very early on
and not really something you can rely on
if you have to cut something off
quickly another thing to watch out for
is you need to compare the firewall
rules in the data plane this is just
like regular networking except the SDN
rules since they allow you to change
things in the header more things in the
header than might change in a normal IP
network you have to make sure that
you've done more checking with the
firewall people who administer things
that are in your data plane and even
things that are in your control plane if
you're supporting the API the standard
API and Jeanne and the last thing to
notice probably most of you who've
touched sdn already know but this is a
major thorn in our side is partial
implementations so almost everybody who
does an SDN switch still does a partial
implementation and if you're making an
interoperable network with six or seven
different providers you're laying those
all over top of each other and sometimes
it's really hard to find an end-to-end
path that will work with the particular
types of modifications that different
people want to do in their packet fields
so you have to keep a careful eye on
that so here's an example of a real live
experiment that we ran and real life
problems that we had and tim is is going
to tell you what happened one exciting
day when he woke up and found that there
were was an issue on genie and spent
quite a while trying to track that down
so Tim what was it that you saw that led
you to believe that there was an issue
in this network um so yep so the
previous slide was kind of showing the
the paths that we had to deal with the
layer two paths and this particular
slide is more so showing the active
monitoring that we were doing and you
can see the test points attached to some
of the or going off of some of the core
nodes and we could tell that some of the
traffic following the blue line from
that the BBN node up in the top right
corner was not getting through to the to
the test point in the Seattle node and
it was kind of a sporadic drop so I mean
the you know the sporadic problems are
always fun to deal with
and we also saw a couple of problems
with the Chicago the test point hang
after cago of Chicago but not quite as
many and we also had another operations
group who was actually has a little bit
more access to those switches and they
were getting cpu alarms for the Denver
switch so it was pretty clear that
something was wrong and it seemed highly
likely that the whatever was causing the
CPU problems on the switch was also
resulting in the traffic drops we were
seeing in the data plane so next up was
trying to isolate the problem what did
you do for that we didn't rehearse this
right no the next one yeah sorry so we
went through this sort of nice little
diagram here although of course when you
have your problem in your network the
the problem space is more like the world
and you have to kind of constraint it
down so it wasn't quite this simple it
wasn't just following the path but you
know we can do that now so like I said
before we assumed that there was a
correlation between the the high cpu
usage on the denver switch and the
problem that was causing traffic to get
dropped in the data plane and so at that
point we were just trying to figure out
what was causing the the high cpu usage
on the switch and just having dealt with
this in the past before typical problems
might be somebody was overwhelming the
control plane by sending too much
traffic to the controller or injecting a
bunch of traffic into the network from
the controller the switch CPUs you know
they're still not that high grade so the
the agents that are running the open
flow process can sometimes get
overwhelmed by that and you know we kind
of investigated that for a while we
didn't have a good baseline so it was
hard to tell if that was actually the
problem but we thought that maybe okay
it this doesn't seem like it's the main
problem and so then we moved on to
looking at things like the partial
implementations at Heidi was mentioning
sometimes the switches will implement a
feature and sometimes they won't but
then there's a third category which is
sometimes they'll implement it in
software and that's not really well
advertised through the protocol but
usually the documentation can tell you
the data sheet for the switch will tell
you you know
particular features implemented in
software so we had to go through and
look at this particular data sheet and
then check some of the tables in the
switch and see well our is any of this
at all going into the software path and
it was kind of tough to see the obvious
ones that we had seen before things like
people doing IP rewrites we knew that
was in the software path people flooding
a lot of traffic we knew that was in the
software path and we didn't really see
any of that so we kind of changed up how
we were searching for things and we
looked for specifically which of these
correspond to the software table and
then once we did that you know that was
a nice shortcut we should have done that
from the beginning but once we did that
it was pretty easy to identify that
there was this weird forwarding rule
that was sending traffic back out on the
port that it came in on which was
another thing that happens in software
so once we figured that out it was it
was pretty that getting to that point
took the most time and once we did that
it was a lot less kind of flailing
around but it was easy to sort of
methodically go through things like okay
well who does now that we know the
forwarding rule who does that belong to
well we found it belong to us which is
actually a good thing because it makes
it easier to debug we restarted our
controller which didn't help remove any
weird flow rules we we restarted the
Denver switch because this was affecting
other experimenters and we wanted to
resolve it as quickly as possible and
that didn't seem to help either so at
that point we took a step back and we
kind of wanted to walk through a couple
of sending traffic between a couple of
the test points can you back to the
previous mm-hmm we wanted to send
traffic to a couple of the test points
like the one in Seattle and the one
Chicago and in doing that and kind of
tracing through each hop along the way
we ended up discovering that there was
traffic that was supposed to be going to
this Chicago node the test point in
Chicago and it was getting sent off to
denver and that was kind of strange and
we couldn't really explain it so we
started you know we started thinking
well maybe the Denver switch has the the
forwarding rule that's doing the right
thing but you know why the heck is that
traffic getting over there in the first
place so we start looking at the
forwarding rules in the in the Chicago
switch
and can't find anything you know
double-check triple-check ask other
people to check ask the people to
operate the switch locally to check
nobody can see it so it's this phantom
forwarding rule and at that point it's
pretty clear that you know we have some
kind of formwork firmware bug and those
are always fun to debug but once we
figured that out we start the show the
Chicago switch things recovered the
Denver switch is happy again and that
was kind of the whole process so it was
a little bit interesting and yeah I I'm
sure it has some sort of correlations to
things that people do in here that are
non stn and maybe I have some interest
in discussing that of people later on
after okay so um these are some
screenshots of tools open source tools
that we use to look into this problem
and other problems as well I'm sorry
they're really hard to see but if you
download the presentation and you want
to look at how you can find open flow
tables and flow stats these actually
match with the example and also the wire
shek Wireshark OpenFlow tool is really
helpful anything you want to say about
the tools there are probably the same
tools that you use every day they just
have you know that the Wireshark has a
special detector for open flow and all
the other stuff is going through rest so
it's just you know curl and you know
formatting so yeah you have to write a
little bit of scripting and dealing with
it but it's worth it ok so I'm not going
to pick on a particular vendor but i
will tell you HP is a great vendor there
are big partner of ours and this is a
picture from their document and the
reason that I'm putting it up is to
illustrate what we were saying about the
complexity of the rules in sdn right now
so this is a match by the piece of the
packet and the flow type that you'd like
to work on and the conditions for any
one of these things that are blocks to
actually be successful each of these has
limits on it and each vendor has a
different table a lot of the tables
aren't actually published by the vendors
so the fact that i put HP up there
doesn't mean we think HP is bad it just
means they did a better job of
documentation than a lot of other people
so if you take this kind of complication
and then you add multiple vendors you
get an idea of why working on s the end
is is really fun it's a great
engineering challenge it's a great
operations challenge and it's it's early
enough in its development that I hope it
would be interesting and appeal to a lot
of nanog members things that we're
thinking about doing next with this in
genie as I mentioned we we expect to
migrate to 1.3 we expect to see better
support for hybrid networks that means
single switches that will support both
open flow and non open flow flows in the
same switch so isolated by interface or
perhaps by VLAN it's done differently
for different vendors but we're getting
to the point where hybrid networking is
a little bit more of our reality than it
was in stn probably three years ago
where it was talked about but not really
done and that's especially important for
deployment because if you've got one
piece of hardware that can do both
things then you got more resources that
open up to you as being things that you
can try using Sdn for we have a software
project to separate the network slicing
by VLAN from the rest of the SDN control
functions and it's not just only network
slicing by VLAN because we're doing it
in an open flow environment but instead
of having everything in one piece of
software which was the original flow
visor software that came from Stanford
kind of trying to modularize functions
into different pieces so that that's
easier to manage and upgrade and fix
we're also entering the dreaded phase of
policy management again this isn't a
problem that's unique to sdn lots of
other networking people have dealt with
it but once you use Sdn and you have
ability to change what's happening with
the packets in flight you have perhaps a
little bit more variations in what you
need to consider for policy management
for people who want to connect that's
just starting up this year really
seriously as a software and technology
effort we're seeing Sdn start to show up
in some of the broadband and home
networks Nick theme stir who's spoken at
nanog before is involved in some
projects like that on genie and it's
starting to show up in some of the
metropolitan areas so that's exciting
and new especially for the folks who
want to do application development in
homes we're seeing people start to work
on Sdn exchange points there are two of
those that are under development now
right now they're just between research
and engineering organizations but
there's talk of being able to branch out
from that one is centered in
northwestern and one is centered in
Georgia Tech so if you're interested in
either of those things let us know we'd
love to have more participation from
people who are have had experience with
this stuff in nanog before and of course
you need cross-domain monitoring if
you're going to run cross domain
protocols and because of what Tim was
talking about about how you really need
to look into the slice especially at
this stage of open flow development to
see what's going on you need monitoring
tools that allow people to share that
information you don't want to just open
up everything in your network to other
Sdn providers particularly if you're in
a in a competitive commercial landscape
but you need a way to share information
that everybody needs when they need to
debug something like an SDN exchange
problem so this is the little picture of
an architecture that we're trying out in
Jeanne and we sort of have a
standardized process for deploying and
testing Sdn nodes and Jeannie and I put
some links into those if people are
interested in coming up to speed and
participating on this is the last set of
things that we do to kind of
standardized and
the SDN stuff possible to manage we
document all the tests we do we document
the network we run sdn gear through
acceptance testing to make sure it will
at least do the basics of what we need
to put sdn paths across different
resource providers and all of this stuff
is available on the website if you want
to see more details so with that we're
open to questions hi Ralph meulen
internet archive i participated in to
jeannie experiments establishing a
virtual circuit between california and
ohio it worked and i fully anticipated
that i get to know every network admin
in a way to debug it but i didn't
anticipate was that I kind of also
needed permission from every single
network operator in between and it
reminded me kind of the bad old days
before packet switching when you had to
get a circuit from the phone company is
it too late to bake openness in the
architecture to be by default permissive
be by default liberal and what you
accept so we don't need permission and
can just experiment um well I'll say my
opinion then you can say Europe and I
don't think it's too light at all I
think we've been we've been trying to
get that pre provisioning and that
allocation step to be separated from
when people use the network and frankly
we've been running so fast that there
isn't much of a delay a lot of the time
so I think that's definitely a goal and
the administrators are getting more
comfortable with it at the endpoints and
so if we can keep getting them more
comfortable with it and avoid you know
major issues on the network then most of
them have actually done auto approval on
their end points already so I think
things are getting better but I i
definitely understand and have seen the
situation that you're talking about ok
what yeah I mean I think basically
there's sort of two two phases here the
first phases to provisioning and the
second phase is the experimentation the
provisioning typically does take a long
time as you point it out but once it's
there the experimentation should be
pretty simple it should be you know it
just works but the bootstrapping
problems there of getting connected if
you have a new site that you want to to
plug into Genie and the last question
over this Mike damn agree and Johns
Hopkins Applied Physics lab so you know
a lot of operators are very skeptical
about sdn we were having a very vigorous
discussion about this over lunch
yesterday a bunch of us um I you know I
get that genie you know is you know is
an nsf-funded you know testbed that's
run by BBN and you know layered on
internet to dynamic VLANs you know sure
and you know but the what a lot of and
everybody understands the you know the
well-documented use cases of you know
building terascale data centers yep you
know having protein having strange
protocol research by your grad students
yep you know general test bed for doing
weirdness at layer 2 yep you know
everybody understands those things but
you know what what's really committing
in a lot of people's mind is compelling
use cases and and you you really kind of
you had a slide in there in which you
glided over a couple of them without
really you know going into them I get it
as BBN you're the operators of the test
bed and it's not your experiments but
but and also you had you had the
debugging stuff of like okay here's how
I debug something where the traffic
flows all go south but sure what were
you trying to do in the first place sure
we all have to do bug problems right but
what was it you were really trying to
accomplish and that's where people
really get very skeptical I mean so you
know it kind of tends to fall into the
religious camps of people who are either
firm believers in DIY you know and they
really want to write everything
themselves and they have operators
should have strong programming
experience la la all that kind of stuff
and people who like you know and any
other issue is from a vendor perspective
you know Sdn is simply turning into an
API you know they're sort of saying well
you know you don't have to rip the
protocol head off your switch and write
your own stuff anymore like you used to
with open flow these days you know you
can have your cake and eat it too
you can you can run your standard switch
our switches and you know do all the
standard stuff you're used to doing and
then if you feel like doing any of this
extra programming well then that's just
an API to write so that's kind of where
a lot of you know vendors see sdn going
to so I wonder if you had any comments
um all that yeah so I I think you're
right about the applications development
the kinds of things that I've seen that
aren't the most interesting on geni for
applications which you're right I didn't
cover in great detail here because it's
not our specialty are people at campuses
who were using sdn to find and capture
interesting things on laptops that they
wanted to kind of be able to isolate and
do something special with there are
other technologies that you could use
for that too but they were able to do it
with sdn kind of easier and faster than
with three or four different special
purpose vendor tools and then I think
there's been a lot of interesting stuff
happening with handing off Sdn between
different organizations and we're just
in the early phases of that so again
that's interesting from a network
person's point of view and it's
interesting to run an application that
you know has an endpoint Japan and an
endpoint in Europe and a few people in
the u.s. participating but I wouldn't
say there's a killer app there yet Tim
yeah I i agree i think a lot of the
cases where I've seen where it had value
would be things closer to the edge where
it's not risky and maybe you need to do
something specialized or really just in
general special cases where you want to
do something that's more standard I'm
going to give the prototypical sdn
example which is what Google does with
their backbone stuff you know they're
doing vgp but occasionally if they want
to do some traffic engineering stuff
they can just toss that in and it's it's
easy for them to do I guess so it's I
think at this stage it's more about
looking for
are cases where you want to augment what
you have today and again this is another
bootstrapping problem where that code
doesn't exist and as an operator you
probably don't want to go and write it
yourself but I also don't think that I
think that part of it is opening up an
ecosystem such that it's not just the
incumbent vendors that can come in and
write that for you it could be it could
be anybody and as long as you know
somebody's tried it and they say all
this is this is pretty good then maybe
somebody else will try it and if that
gained some traction then then it kind
of opens up the space to two other
smaller vendors to give you some code
that you can run yourself and as an
operator you don't have to just go and
write it all from scratch so that's kind
of my view of these yeah I mean this is
a conference of operators right so I
think I personally would have enjoyed
your talk a little more if you had
instead of saying here's our testbed you
know la la you know if you'd let off
with like okay here's a bunch of things
that people have done on this test bed
that have actually found their way out
in the real world and aren't just of
interest academics you know kind of
thing but that's just a suggestion
alright last question of the mics here
before we cut to the next presentation
hi Paul kinetic epic technologies I just
have kind of one question playing off
the previous comment I understand that
your technology can be used by both
academics and third parties that
register my town recently just got a
genie racket in Flint Michigan my
question is do you provide services for
commercialization for third parties or
any assistant with any assistance with
commercialization of technologies
developed on your platform NSF is
explicitly supporting people who want to
do prototype transition to
commercialization on the genie network
they think that that's a good thing they
want people to have partners who who are
involved with research it's not hard to
find partners you can come to a genie
conference you can actually get support
from NSF to come to a genie conference
and there are a lot of people who would
be interested in working with anybody
who wants to try this out for any reason
even if it's leading to a horrible
commercialization
great I was just trying to make the
distinction on it this was purely in the
academic realm or if they were allowed
you know no it's explicitly open to
other other people startups things like
that we don't want you to use the genie
Network obviously to support an existing
service that you're already paying for
and try to run it on in SF connections
for free but you know as long as it's
not something like that and you have a
good case for engineering integration or
research then it's likely to be allowed
on the genie network we use other
people's networks so we just have to
make sure we don't violate their roles
but the rules are pretty are pretty
tolerant and we intentionally did it
that way great thank you sure all right
that's up
you