okay so welcome back
the second part of my two-part monster
session on that convent yang this one is
more about running code so what we're
going to do here is to take a sliver of
the things that I talk to you about in
the first session and put some code and
pd use and stuff around it we're going
to use a couple of two or I am going to
use a couple of tools that you can see
I've moved from standing at the pulpit
you sitting at the keyboard because i
only have as I mentioned previous a
single slide for this part of the
session the rest will be using these
tools for a net cover rescomp server
we're going to use a product called
comedy or configuration demon it is a if
you want an own device configuration
management framework that used to be
part of my ex-employer telef systems and
it's a very ambitious implementation oh
that's better volume wise now I'm right
through your skulls there we go we will
use that as our netconf arrest calm
server we will use a small python script
called netconf console to send netcom
content and watch it come back from the
server we're going to look a little bit
at a Python library for net called
netconf client library in python is what
i wanted to say called NC client and
we're going to use curl to tickle or to
use the rest come for the rest interface
and again i want to remind you guys and
girls that this is going to be a
protocol exercise so while there is a
lot to say about how to actually
encapsulate all these protocol motions
in libraries that's probably for the
next session or for the next step and
next time hopefully invited back here so
don't be tempted to think that the tools
that i'm using to show you what's
actually coming over the wire are the
only tools you know i purposely picked
things that does expose all the xml and
the json that you can think of in these
things and again there are
many higher level tools to be used
across these protocols that would make
them immediately useful to operations
teams but again that's not the intent or
the what I plan for this session here
this is to teach you exactly what it
looks like for that conference call okay
so we can get rid of power point i'd
like to present my shell this is where
we will spend this this session and I as
much as I understand and have done this
a couple of times I'm going to have to
switch back and forth a little bit to a
demo script so hopefully you guys don't
get seasick when I do that that's going
to look like some something okay we can
take this away as well that's going to
look something like this alright so we
have a recently started netcom server
running in the background here that's
the conf d session that I told you about
where they call the server that i told
you about we're in an aptly named
directory called nano demo and inside
this we actually have a directory called
netconf queries and we're going to start
by using the net conf console program
here right so newly started netcom
server it's running on my localhost so
the only thing I need to add to netcom
console here is how much I want to see
and since this again is a protocol
experience i'm going to ask the National
console to show me everything yep
good question that I would have probably
needed another slide for that so the net
com server that is commonly located on a
router or switch in the distributed
network is for this purpose running on
my laptop so I'm going to talk to see
that's another thing that I maybe should
have put in the framing in the net conf
world we've opted for the client and
server terms as opposed to for example
manager and agent which we talked about
for SNMP so the client sits with the
management software and the server which
takes requests from the client sits in
the network elements right so in the net
cough case netconf servers would be
running in your you know juniper Cisco
alcatel-lucent boxes and the clients
would be located in the EMS or the
service orchestration system how would
you prefer a manager agent or something
true true that server something that
comes from I guess from from compaq or
HP or dell right so good choice then you
awake woke up that's great so the net
comm console then just be very clear is
our client and it's going to query and
manipulate the data that's residing on
the net comp server and that netcom
server instance happens to run on my
laptop and not on a virtualized or
physical network element somewhere else
just to make it more of a of a lab
environment here okay so the first thing
that we would do as I mentioned in the
previous slot is that we would issue
what's called a Hello right so in this
case we're going to use actually a
feature of the net comm console to send
the hello message and start the
capabilities exchange so here's what we
get back from the server so I want to
walk through this in some detail so this
server tells me that it actually
supports both versions of the net conf
based protocol 1 at 0 and 1 dot
and depending on what the client sent
the session is going to be based on
either of those the only big difference
between them is has to do with framing
or chunking actually which we changed
between base 1 at 0 and 1 at one and
then there's a number of let me see if I
can make it more readable capabilities
that has to do with the net com protocol
itself so in this case we can see that
the way the server is set up you can
actually write configuration data right
into the running database so an edit
config towards the running database
would make configuration bite
immediately if you like traditional CLI
style but we also have a candidate which
means that we can opt to edit the
candidate to our hearts content and when
we're done there we can copy that
content into the running so we support
both here and there's actually support
for the confirm commit all these things
I will walk through in gruesome detail
but the confirmed commit is then the
timer based commit that i mentioned in
the previous lot where i can say go run
with this but if i'm not back inside of
a number of seconds rollback and if i
kill the session or lose contact while
that timer is running rollback we
support XPath for queries we support the
opportunity to validate the data in the
candidate before sending it to the
running database we support also roll
back on error so if you find an error
somewhere in the data set that you're
sending the server will actually roll
back we also have some proprietary
extensions so this is a way for the
vendor in this case tail F to explain to
the client that we actually have a new
ability here and in this case is
something called actions so it's not our
pc's the way standard netconf is
designed it's actually something called
actions which is kind of an RPC that you
can put inside of data trees so you can
have our reload action for example
associated with a line card and then
there's a number of yang modules
supported down here you'll see a number
of proprietary modules so triple-a
modules a couple of things that are
with web you is and monitoring it is
also a third party but known standard
module supported so it's something we
pick up from yang central org which is a
kind of a loosely held repository for
useful yang files or yang modules and
there's also some iono an ITF managed
modules in this case largely around
types access control management and some
of the monitoring capabilities that we
have standardized netconf notifications
and general types so this is the
complete way for the server to tell the
client how you can interact with it
using the net com protocol which
extensions which optional extensions to
the protocol it supports and which yang
modules be that again proprietary third
party or standard that can be that can
be manipulated here so this should give
the client developer a complete
understanding of the entire data set the
start structures in tax and semantics of
the data that you can manipulate in this
box you're not supposed to have to query
for other things again like version of
some sort of a vendor name or ID this
should be a complete description of the
entire dataset
okay so the next thing now that we know
what it supports the first thing we can
do for this demo over this session is to
issue a get request on the route right
without a filter this will ask the
device to dump everything it knows both
configuration and state data to the
client this is one of those things that
if you really want to stress real
implementations of net comp let's say
big core routers and things like that
this is usually a very mean thing to do
because it usually takes a long while
for a router a real implementation to
collect both all operational and
configurational data in a timely manner
and shape it to a client so it's
something that you can use if you want
to try and break things now we have a
pretty limited implementation here so
this is pretty snappy so here you'll see
in this or PC reply a set of data and
here you'll also start to see as I
mentioned before identifiers for yang
modules using namespaces so when the
client sees this it knows which yang
module this data is valid according to
okay so here's kind of the back pointer
from the content into the yang modules
that the client should know about at
this point right so here's where
namespaces becomes useful so if we keep
looking for them we will see that so we
had Triple A here's the conf d
monitoring and here's the actual content
of the module that we're going to play
around with which is then from a
third-party environments the yang
central repository here's our access
controls you'll see a role based access
control according to the standard model
from the ITF and here's netconf state so
here's actually another way of getting
to the same data that we got in our
hello but inside of the protocol session
so if you have some for some reason you
want to see these things again but you
don't want to tear down the net
concession you can query for this
namespace there's also types right so
inside of this data model we're
leveraging or reusing a data type from
an external or from
separate module right so if we look at
in this yank file you'll see that they
have borrowed the transaction ID type
from net cough monitoring and they're
using it here right so for completeness
of course we need to point out the
namespace here as well okay so that's
the entire thing the second of course
basic primitive feature we have here is
get config so remember this will fetch
only configuration data right so it will
leave the state data out and just get
the configuration so that would be
somewhat different triple-a is still
configurable we have configuration stuff
in dhcp and ACM but we don't have the
monitoring things for example so the the
the data that i mentioned you could
fetch that we describe the capabilities
is obviously something you wouldn't
configure so that's operational data
hence it doesn't arrive when i do a get
config like this okay
and let's quickly look at the same thing
but using rest cough okay so rest comp
then uses HTTP and the well-known HTTP
verbs to take and format data according
to a yang model and send it to the
client right and we have two encoding we
have XML and we have JSON and in this
case where we don't send any except
headers it's going to arrive oh that's
interesting oh my first snack
see what that is oh there we go okay
let's do that again why would you do
that
here we go so this is querying the top
level of the REST API all right so this
would be the URL for the top level and
of course just as we near the other rest
interface you will have to know what to
look for this right there are trickeries
around using particularly well
particularly crafted urls and using the
well-known name space but you will have
to find the end point for the rest
interface beacon sort wearing it and for
this implementation this is where round
it is an alternative protocol to use
rest like primitives or rest like
technologies to manipulate data that is
modeled by yang so it's got the same
consistent data store in the bottom it's
just another way of getting to the data
and manipulating the data thank you for
asking that's a good question so in
general you know netcom is a a context
specific protocol right it's got a lot
of features into it as primary features
that has to do with the distributor
domain things like the underpinnings of
transactions rest comp is leveraging
rest right rest for example has the idea
that there should be no side effects
hence you can't do transactions right so
for lightweight want line to one server
fetching and simple configuration
changes rest comp is great for
distributed domains where you need
transactions netconf is probably your
best bet so we also see things like rest
conf on top of controllers where there's
this there's there's practically no
distribution right it's just a single
server while there might be a use than
for net conf in the actual distributed
Network evidence themselves that make
sense kind of
okay i'm going to show you then of
course what it looks like over json what
is this this is mean ah that's not it so
here's the JSON it is not very beautiful
we'll look at bigger models but of
course is the exact same thing we just
asked it for different encoding over the
wire right so now it comes down to
programmer preference would you rather
whip out your XML library and parse the
incoming content or would you rather use
your whatever native way you have of
parsing and ingesting JSON but it's the
same data and it's driven by the same
data model
so we can actually look at the running
database of course in the same way what
we saw with the first queries was just
the top level content so here's the
actual running database and you would be
not so surprised to see that it is the
same content as we would have over net
conf it's just that this is the running
database which by definition is the
configuration only and of course you can
ask for it over JSON instead so you will
see this is the same data but it's JSON
encoded ok
okay so if we look at this the way we
fetched the schema again or looked at
the the output of the hello message
right so a couple of modules here and
the one that we care mostly about today
is the dhcp module okay and we know that
it's identifier its dhcp so now we can
do I get schema equals dhcp
so this tells the server to send us the
actual content of that schema so again
if you open up a Hello if you have a
capability to change and help the hello
message from the server tells you that
there are now modules that you have
never seen before or new versions this
is literally how you would go about
updating your disc-based library of yang
modules or whatever you need to do with
it to be up to date right
I would strongly suggest they would have
it textual strongly suggest speed and
because there's no reason I mean it
remember it's it's the schema it's not
the content right so there should be
little need for assemblying things it
should literally be a part of shipping
code should be putting the yang file on
the file system and just serve it
it is an informational piece but it's a
pretty crucial right because it means
that any interested client can acquire
you know the kind of contract between
the network device itself and the client
work right it is almost like a promise
from the device that these are my
current data sets that I support and you
can always go to the source for that
there's never a we cannot close the gap
for slippage for example in release
versions right because you can always
you know if you're a vendor you can
literally always tell the customer which
query the router you can always add you
can you can go to the horse's mouth if
you like and then get it from from word
matters which is the actual
implementation
which I'm sure you know has led to eons
of painful mistakes there were never
away in SNMP to actually query the box
for its MIPS which is a which was in my
mind you know something we should have
done for SNMP as well and you would be
stuck with offline libraries where you
there was no structured version
numbering either so you could never be
sure that the main file i have on disk
is actually with this agent implements
because they were never you know version
strings so this is trying to really
solve and OD solve that problem okay so
let's look at this let's actually look
at this let's look at it in a more calm
no let's move it here so will you get
the headers of course we have a
particular namespace you've seen that
before in the capabilities exchange we
have a prefix so if people import this
you know this is how they would
namespace identify this we use the yang
types module which then obviously also
needs to be present in the capabilities
exchange we use the ITF violent types
and we use a couple of taylor specific
common data types so first of all we
have a grouping and we talked about
groupings in the previous walk right
this grouping is called subnet list so
we have a list of subnets that we can
reuse by name okay this list has a key
called net this key leaf is of type I
NAT IP prefix so it's a well-known data
type and since it says IP prefix and not
ipv4 ipv6 it's actually a union of ipv4
or ipv6 prefix let's get a container
called range with presence so if this
container actually exists if an instance
of data of this continued exists this
box has enabled dynamic address
assignment right in this container there
is a leaf called dynamic bootp and it's
also empty so it has kind of presents
meaning if this is
present but empty it allows bootp
clients to work on this range and you
have a low and a high address and they
are both mandatory which means that
configuration that lack either of these
is not valid you can't create this
container without providing values for
low and high we don't have default
values here we could have default values
and that would remove the need for
mandatory because if you create it and
don't have an input data the
implementation would just take the
default value ok we have a container
DHCP options we have a leaf list of
routers so of course you can have a
number of routers in this container it
is ordered by you sir so there's some
semantics to the order it's up to the
client to order the entries of these
lists and usually in priority order them
you got a domain name and we reuse the
inet domain name here you have a max
least Im the defaults to 7200 it's in
unit seconds which means that if you
create max least time but don't submit a
value just going to pick 7200 and then
we come to Canada meteor the DHCP
container so you have a max least Im for
dhcp the faults are the same thing you
have a default least time and here's
where it gets start to get interesting
here's a must statement that says that
the default each time cannot be longer
than the max waste time right so we can
capture those that that mistake before
hitting the actual instrumentation by
just looking at the data incoming right
and the default for that is 600 and
here's how we instantiate the grouping
that we started out with so here's a
sudden at least here's how we're that is
actually let's say expand it into the
data tree we got a container shot
networks which is a list of shark
networks with a key name it's got names
and it also uses the sudden at least
it's keyed off of name but it's a set of
subnets and we have a container status
which is config false so this is not
configuration data right it's actually
state data so it's the content of this
will not come to naught P
turned if we do a get config right so
it's typically the way I used to think
about it is typically something that you
wouldn't expect in a backup file so
those are the leases that we have yep
that's right config falls on a container
declares everything under that container
to be config false because this is where
it starts to get you know even my head
still spins if you try to put a
configurational parameter inside the
scope of something that is operational
what happens if that operational you
know state goes away and again what
happens if you take a backup right of
something that relies on configurational
state that configures the configuration
state changes and you try to roll back
all right so you're absolutely right
that config falls in a container says
that below here we can have any
configuration and I mention our pcs in
this case we're using the tail f
extension called set clock so we have
some input so clock settings we can set
the time and we won't allow this call to
we don't allow the call to arrive with
clock settings empty or without clock
settings it makes no sense to try to set
clock without clock settings it's not
mandatory though to express it this is
UTC or no and whether we're going to try
and sing for the hardware job and the
output will be a combination of the
system clock and the hardware go so and
they're both leveraging the yang data
type date and time okay we can also use
the PI to my producer wants the season
okay i will repeat the questions thank
you sir so there's a tool called p hang
so if you want to take a quick look at
this structure of any module i could i
would strongly suggest you look at p and
its output format called tree so I just
so happen to have up here the dhcp yang
module hope I can resolve all
dependencies otherwise we'll have to go
work on that so here's the same data
that I just showed you but in a skeet
reform okay and it's got a particular
way of coding things but this is easier
to get an overview of then then
scrolling through the 95 itself that I
just did there are also many other
output modules for this including for
the sewing client a uml output module
that can take yang and I'll put
something that looks a whole lot like
you amount so it depends on your needs
okay
now we're going to start in on the
actual yep it's a that's right it's a
partial validator so the question was
peeing is a tool yeah so yeah as an
input it takes young files it parses
validates and it's got a fairly flexible
output format plug-in environment so in
this case we use the particular output
format called f3 or three and there are
many others and it's open source and
it's available that I think it leaves at
Google go alright now we're going to get
back to netcom console but we're going
to actually start looking at things here
let's do this
no let's not do that let's do this
we're going to look at a simple XML
request for a filtered get request okay
so what you see here is a complete
session so of course every time we start
this up we're going to send a hello let
the capabilities back do our RPC and
then close the session but the important
content is in the middle here so here
you see the layers again right here's
the RPC layer here's the operation in
this case we've actually have additional
layer of semantics which is a filter so
we're going to filter on this namespace
which is the dhp namespace and when a
filter on dhcp so only show the subtree
below dhcp so we would do have
confidence oh
and what comes back not surprisingly is
something that has inside the data
enclosure only the namespace for DHCP
right it leaves the rest out response
from the server right
that's right that's right yeah so what I
just showed you here in the in the
editor session this is the actual netcom
payload that we're sending so I'm asking
the client to send this in rapid
succession and see what comes back from
the server so I like you said I'm
sending a navcom for PCs and I'm showing
on the screen the output that comes back
again this is on the protocol level
which is very specific to this session
here today this is not how you would do
it in your day-to-day operations but to
show you the way the protocol works
right so that was a gap right so it
would get all the things under dhcp also
the status alright so down here and we
happen to know because we've looked at
the yank file that this is not
configuration data this is actually the
leases that we have outstanding so if i
would use another call called PHP config
which uses another RPC and the big
difference here is that we're using the
get config operation and if we use get
config we actually have to tell the
server which database we want to peek at
right so in this case we want to look at
the running database we're going to use
the same filter and we'll see what comes
back
and what you'll notice here is that
there is no status subnet right there
sorry there's no status subtree so we're
only fetching the configuration so again
this content is what you're supposed to
be able to put to the side your boot
your router or in this case the HP
server crashes you take that content and
you push it back and you're supposed to
be back to where exactly where you were
so this is the semantic difference
between operational data and
configuration data
okay so let's go into the more
interesting things we're going to start
up taking things here and we're going to
start with just manipulating the running
data stores we're going to write right
into what it's doing right now we get to
commits and a candidate later so we'll
start by using
actually let's start by yeah set set the
default least Im to one hour so let's
look at what that looks like so this has
got more moving parts and again this is
protocol level stuff so it's an RPC it's
got an edit config and of course the box
wants to know which database do we want
to configure we want to configure the
running data store so it bites
immediately and we want to config in the
dhcp subtree okay so we're going to
address this namespace and what we also
need is actually to express which
operation right so the ways you would
manipulate data or you can do things
like add delete and merge right so in
this case we're going to use the merge
operation which means that we'll take
this input data and merge it what it has
already so it doesn't matter if this
value exists from before or no we're
just going to put it in there so we need
the namespace from the net cough based
protocol we're going to update it to the
3600 and then we're going to close the
session
not much to happen here right we just
had a successful return so the server
said okay which means that that the
value is now updated right so nothing
particularly exciting there now let's do
something more exciting let's look at
the invalid data set so down here we're
going to put the default least Im to
something that we know is higher than
the max this time right and this is not
allowed according to our yang modules
must statement so if we do that we
should get a more interesting feedback
whoops so here tells me and of course
this again is based off of the yang
that's loaded into the agent right so
this should happen far before you upset
the actually instrumentation the actual
router running code right you get an RPC
error with a number of metadata so its
application level it's an operation that
failed it's an error so it's a violation
right and it's a must violation and the
error path in this case is in the DHCP
namespace and it's actually in this
subtree of the data set right and the
error message in English is exactly what
it said in the yang module so it
literally sends what the yang model
describes as the error message because
it broke the constraint now we're
getting a question on the mic great yeah
I'm Richard Campbell them with priceline
just a quick question can you variable
eyes the output messages so you can
actually specify the actual least time
max in the error message so you know
what that target is that's actually a
vendor extension not in the base
definition no variables in the base but
it's a very useful vendor extension as
you can imagine
all right oh one more yay well Ralph
Whelan from the internet archive if I
want to implement one of the new a DHCP
feature say each DP option 53 at which
point would I learn that the particular
device doesn't have that implement it is
that something where I can validate it
on the client and it already knows
because device told me what it can do or
is it something that I would only find
out when i try to load it into the
server on a particular router that is
not supported in a well-behaved an
ambitious implementation you should be
able to infer that from the yang modules
that you can fetch from the box it
should be able to tell you its entire
available data set both configuration
operations that should tell you what
it's possible then if you remember from
the most recent from the previous lot
right it's the feature we have the
feature construct that you can use for
runtime things so maybe it has a feature
that's called option 43 or whichever
option right and you have to check for
whether that's actually turned on and if
it's turned on then it's available but
normally and I'd say it's more prudent
to have that in the actual yang itself
to describe at the bottom can do thank
you
okay so we can look at now is that we
can look at removing things so we just
added something and then we failed an ad
as well let's look at deleting things so
what we're going to do in this case
we're going to so again it's an RPC it's
an edit config targets running the big
difference here is that we're using the
remove operation right so in this case
in the dhcp namespace under shared
networks we're going to remove a shared
network that has a key with the
following name okay so that's all we
need since this is an entry in the list
all we need is an index for that entry
and use the remove operation and that
should remove everything below it in the
list
not much happening here as well so this
is an okay so we now have removed to 249
so of course our data set sorry there
you go for the DA pcs upset is much
smaller because we removed the entire
segment right and since we're doing this
to the running database that happen
immediately right so the books said with
its ok said I'm now running under the
new configuration right away ok so it's
removed so let's look at how to use
candidates so what we can do here when I
start stealing things from this is to
ask for groups is to ask for the content
of the candidate so this is a recently
started netcom server right it was cold
started half an hour ago which means
that when you check the candidate
database if you're the first visitor to
encounter the candidate database it's
going to be have the same content as the
running now if you if you can't trust
that it actually has the same content
that the running because someone has
edited it you do what's called a discard
changes so you make sure that the
candidate database is the exact same as
the running database and you probably do
that under a lock so you can make sure
that no one sneaks in changes while
you're doing these things but again
that's the ambitious round here ok so we
have a copy of the running in the in the
in the candidate so we can now actually
start removing things from the candidate
here
yeah i want to show you this first
so we have another example of an edit
config this time targeting the candidate
that is also using an invalid value of
the default least I'm right so to show
you that also the candidate does cement
or must checking we can send that
invalid value to the server it will say
the same thing it's just that now we're
trying to do it with the candidate right
so some things you can check also on the
candidate while others are checked on
commits from the candidate to the
running there's a single global
candidate
I'd say it kind of on the top three
frequently asked questions and the
really tricky part here is leaf leaf
references right because if you started
here on in the general case I mean you
can have leaf references pointing all
over the data set right and it'd be very
tricky to implement editing on subsets
that you could prove didn't impact other
sessions right and I'm sure as we get
more experienced with this more
implementations more best practices we
will come up with a way that would allow
several writers at the same time because
it just screams for it right but it's
really hard to even you know imagine
what that would look like that would
also kind of satisfy or fulfil the
features of Yang and yeah that is just a
very tricky proposition so looking and
single candidates is what we have right
now and of course the point being that
you know if you have yet and if you have
net phone your editing session should be
sub-second right it should literally be
a very fast thing also i mean if you
think about transactions this is all
going to be in the critical section so
it behooves the client developer to
really keep it snappy and fast and not
look something and spend time in there
that's where low King comes in so unless
you look that can happen but if you make
sure that you discard changes in n log
you avoid that because anyone that tries
to sneak in changes while you're waiting
for a conference committee will be held
back by the log so you see that in your
session and if you close the session
it's going to roll back so you have to
wait in the session it's a session oh
thank you and just what they asked for
as well you have such a booming voice I
just assumed that it reached to the
other end of sorry so my question was
how do you know that somebody else
hasn't done a confirm you know has set a
commit is waiting for the time to expire
how do you know it's a for you with a
separate client to go in and make
changes to ha so you mean if there's an
outstanding confirm commit and you try
to start one so the implementation won't
allow you to do a confirm commit if
there is one already running so that is
by necessity serialized right you can't
have two outstanding confirm commits at
the same time thank you
so we're going to add back the shark net
but we're going to add this back in the
candidate ok so the shark net that we
just removed we just added that but we
have it not in the running but in the
candidate data store let's take a quick
look and you guys know this by now but
here's the big difference so it's an RPC
at it config its candidate and it's the
subset of the data that we just removed
so you remember we removed a shared
network with this as key and now we're
putting it back I just happened to
remember what it said here but now again
it's still in the candidate right so if
we haven't committed to running yet so
the box isn't running on the assumption
that it should have those subnets yet so
what you can do here which can be very
powerful is to send send a validate
issue a validate request right and in
this case again it's nor pc is it's a
primary or busy called validate or a
feature RPC called validate part of the
national based protocol and it validates
the candidates it just says look at the
content here and compare both with your
yang declaration and if you have other
things they want to check as well do
that so this is also part of the kind of
two-phase commit because this is the
preparer face so you can ask the device
to say to tell you that it's reasonably
sure that this is valid right so this is
the prepared step in in common database
lingo and of course we hope that this is
all well in this case so it will return
hoops it would return ok
ok so it's validated so now I have a
high degree of I feel confident that I
can commit these things let's look at
that
pretty straightforward right commit
doesn't actually target any particular
databases it's inferred that it's taking
the content of the candidate and putting
it into running so all you do is issue a
commit like this
and it worked so now we have
put back whip
The Shard network 224 that's 29 into
running okay so we put it back okay so
let's do this i'm going to do this a
little bit quicker we're just going to
remove the shark net from the running
again because i'm going to show you a
confirming commit so which means that we
remove it and we add it to candidate
you've seen that before and let's look
at this set here
it's an orphan see it's a comment it's
got to confirm the flag set and the
confirmed time out is 10 seconds and the
persist ID if I wanted to do something
about this later is the fifth thing Lee
enough nano so in this case I'm going to
let this actually run let's do this
so we committed and let's see if we can
get the use of a config you see to 24 29
here wait 10 seconds you peek at the
load
it's gone ok so the device timeout
expired and the implementation itself
rolled back right so this is useful when
you because most of you guys probably
have done this configure yourself away
from management reach ability because
then you lose the session the timeout
will expire and the device will roll
back itself so if I redo this with a
shark net let me just look at it
they will commit confirmed and then we
do a confirming committed it's going to
buy it so the timer is now taken out of
play here and the configuration will
stick
any questions okay oh so the persist is
if you have an outstanding confirming
commit and you want to manipulate it
later it's the ID ID to for example
cancel the commit you need to be able to
identify that you know which one you
want to cancel even though there can
only be one outstanding
okay good
so getting closer to wrap up here we're
going to talk a little bit about no
actually I think we need to actually
stop here any any questions guys and
girls a lot of x i'm at a lot of pd use
flying back and forth all crystal clear
there's one
so if we wanted to replicate what you
did here today what's the easiest way to
sort of build the set up its at all
stuff that you gotta go build from
source and then you can run these tools
or are they available in the standard
repositories for linux distributions or
what so there's two sides of this right
there's the client tools as I mentioned
in the PowerPoint and the ones that I
use are all actually available for
anyone
so the net comm console you can find
that the anticline and curl obviously
are readily available right now the
comedy in this case the server it's not
right right now it's it's still a
proprietary solution we are working to
change that so I now work for one of the
vendors and we're trying to make this
actually something that will be freely
available but it isn't right now there
are other open source implementations of
netcom servers there's one called Yuma
there's one called lib net conf and
there's one called free net com and
they're all fine and you can use them of
course for these types of exercises to
your heart's content
and you can always use a one of the
major vendors boxes I'm not going to
point one out but you can also ask them
when they're if they don't have it to
your surprise you can always ask them
when they're implementing it just one
more question do you know of operating
system vendors looking to use this like
you know Apple or Microsoft or Lennox to
be included as a default so you can
actually manipulate host configs
remotely save that question one more
time sorry I didn't catch the beginning
of production do you see like OS benders
implementing net comp on their in their
OS so it's not only can you configure
and manage routers but you can configure
image and clients or host okay so so for
that type of environment there there's
an abundance of other means of
configuring right and I'm not entirely
convinced that net conf is a appropriate
protocol for let's say server based or
application based configuration now
there's a big gray area though with
applications like dns and dhcp and
things like that need to be of course
being today's example which is
inherently network-centric that
inherently has a configuration data set
that you might want to manipulate where
there are actually some vendors that do
implement these things for it and of
course one of the many things that we're
pushing for is for for the appropriate
applications things that would be facing
let's say a network service
orchestration environment napkin yang is
fitting right so we are trying to push
for standard models for it we're trying
to push for open source implementations
of it and we're trying to push for
vendors in that space to implement it as
well because again you know having the
basis of transactions and allowing them
to participate in that spanning the
network assets it can be a very powerful
consular yes sir just to follow on the
previous question if we wanted to
reproduce this ourselves
is there some instructions somewhere
about how we could do this or would you
be able to post somewhere some
instructions just obviously not the comp
d part i guess but all the other parts
it's a very far ask actually i'm going
to take on myself to put something
together and make sure that the
appropriate people are now know can
distribute that thank you okay great
more questions I have questions Brian
Knight from nye tell if a general
question you've been showing us a lot
about how the XML transaction itself and
and what it does what I guess how would
we use this in our daily lives what
would be the workflow would we write our
configurations and yang and you some
tool to transmute them into XML and send
it to the server or would we write it in
XML how would that work yeah so I mean
there's two sides of it if you're a
vendor you know if you build network
elements you would hopefully kind of
adjust your tooling to start using yang
as the way to drive your manageability
framework right so when you would spin
any release right you would actually
drive the CLI and the net conf interface
and what have you from a set of yang
modules which would give you the benefit
of being able to serve your customers
people that would that would code for
this you know a young file that actors
accurately reflects with that actual
version does right and for the client
side I mean there are many ways it helps
you all the way from just basic
scripting you know even though as
painful as that is and probably doesn't
help much over tickle scripting for your
lines right all the way to and this is
probably the subject matter of work for
you know Additional Sessions here now no
but what I'm showing here again is just
the raw protocol right and then there is
a variety of language bindings for this
with various types of abstractions so
you have gold language bindings you have
Python of course you know Ruby and many
others so that's great then you can
abstract away the actual you know
creating of XML and sending of XML some
of these libraries also have yang
bindings so they can actually take yang
and produce data model specific ap is
for example so you can traverse data
sets using generated API sore generated
object models right and of course on top
of that there's entire systems that can
consume yang can actually build moving
parts out of it so you could build
something that could express for example
services traversing several instances of
net company I ok so this so the goal is
not a happy yang be that be the language
to to necessarily define configuration
and pick oh I want this particular DCP
subnet to be used that is yang is more
of a data modeling language and XML is
the way to send that to the device
exactly so yang describes the data set
that is available to you to manipulate
and read on the device right and the XML
that you see flying back and forth here
is protocol specific renditions of what
you want to do to that data set I think
hey junkie and poetic so this netcong
from yang looks really good tool but it
looks very static policy pushing so you
know actually network there's a lot of
changes going on so I just want to know
that is there any like support like for
example do you have to make a yang
program and there's some event comes in
like intrusion or something and you have
another yang language and you do you
just have to use scripts to react to
that or is there any support that you
actually can automate that too like you
want to like actually say like oh if
this event comes in i want to just push
this and push another one things like
that so so that's a good question so
young and netconf and perhaps rest
confess buyers to the moving parts of
the kind of read side and the right side
so of course you can write things with
it you can read things with it and you
can also accept or take notifications
but the actual tying
things together on the top is actually
out of soap both from that company yang
and we're eagerly awaiting you know
clever ways of doing that because I
think what you're saying makes a whole
lot of sense and should be a very
exciting endeavor for anyone now that we
have again the formalized declarative
way of describing both the configuration
operational and notification data set
but it's not in scope right now for
napkin for yang go build it will become
thank you hi I'm Brennan with facebook
thanks for pimping the the go bindings
as i wrote that so else but i have a
another question do you see yang being
used outside of a client a client server
model more like a streaming model being
able to describe data being streamed
from the box as an alternative to like
an sn2 people for example right getting
more real-time information i always want
every second i want my interface
counters can you and then have yang BB
kind of the way to describe that i guess
so so the net cough notifications can
can give you part of that right it is a
way of saying for example the client can
say first of all I want to see all the
streams that are available right and I
just want to see these streets the
pacing of it though is of course out of
scope for the client so but that could
be made a configurable now I hear myself
also completely overloading but net
company yang is about but it's one of
those that yeah you could do that I'm
not sure it's the the appropriate way
but certainly you could do that Thanks
Go Go language by the way don't stop
don't stop
any other questions okay for the brave
people that I've announced that been
here for two and half hours thank you
very much thanks for coming
you