all right coming up next we have Narcy
Regas with ICSI here to talk about the
net eliezer program
so
but good morning everybody so thank you
for introduction and before getting into
more details I would like to thank you
for attending our talk and also I would
like to thank the program committee for
giving us the opportunity to be percent
and at eliezer to all of you today so
metalizer is network debugging tool that
tries to analyze the network's beyond
the radial ink especially in the case of
mobile and we try to characterize and
identify aspects of the networks that
have not been quite well explored yet
such as the effect of middleboxes
or even the business relationships
between operators and this work has been
done in collaboration with my colleagues
as reconsideration Kristin Kreuk
Nicolas Weaver and Vernon Paxson from XE
as well as in collaboration with more it
sustainer from mock online so for those
of you who might be wondering who is
this guy talking to you today let me
give you some background about myself on
my on my lap so I'm a research scientist
at XE in the networking and security
group led by Vern Paxson and exist a
non-profit research lab affiliated with
UC Berkeley and before that I was
actually doing my PhD at the University
of Cambridge with John Cockcroft in
collaboration with Telefonica research
and I pitch the topic was about
identifying cross-layer and efficiencies
between mobile applications and solar
networks and how they are actually
causing trouble in the networks in terms
of signaling as well as in the battery
life of the device and now let's move
into the juicer heads so since 2009 we
could see more or less how the Internet
is actually becoming mobile what are
more people are accessing the internet
from mobile applications and mobile
devices but actually this kind of
networks are having limited resources
and actually the deployment is expensive
operators have to pay for their Spector
license and also to deploy quite
expensive equipment but in any case they
are trying to catch up with users demand
but it's still a bit unclear how these
networks are performing in reality
and as we could see in the keynote there
are certain applications and other
organizations that are trying to
benchmark the performance of the
networks but they are usually usually
using classic techniques such as latency
tests trace routes were throughput and
some examples are for instance the SEC
is big test other academic research
projects projects such as University of
Michigan's mobile parts as well as so
class big test but we wonder if this
test of tools actually reveal which one
is the underlying issue that is
affecting morale performance and for
those of you who are not familiar with
his popular infographic it's actually
quite interesting analogy with what's
happening on the internet it has been
designed by Charles Minard in 1869 and
it shows how the Napoleonic troops
decrease in size as they were marching
from town us and if we near to Moscow
when they were trying to conquer the
Russian Empire so here you can see that
some troops got killed on their way some
of them got read it acted somewhere else
and also some troops were waiting for
others in the to join them in the
retreat and as I said this is a great
analogy with what's happening on the
internet if we take a look at what a
user may actually think when they're
trying to reach some online services
that basically think of a cloud sending
bits back and forth but there are a lot
of middle boxes and other elements on
the network that can affect performance
so we may have packet drops in the radio
link we may also have issues because
users are having data plans that may
have volume gaps or threatening
thresholds but there are also other
middle boxes such as been a natural
solver store proxies that may block some
content as well as redirecting it
somewhere else
but as Napoleon discover it the way
actually was hard but it's even harder
the way back we have firewalls we have
nuts and we have also caches so as you
can imagine if we want to really see
which one is the root cause causing
trouble in the networks we have to take
into account a lot of elements so that
was the that was the reason why we
wanted to build a tool capable of
penetrating mobile networks in data in
order
identify all these issues and for that
we took advantage of our existence or
tool and we customized it and adapted it
to the mobile context so this allows us
to have a very little very little
information about the performance
deployment and also about the features
of mobile networks in the wild and let
me also give you some background about
the project for those of you who are not
familiar with NAT eliezer so it started
back in 2009 as a tool that aimed to
diagnose connectivity characteristics
and travel in the network and we
actually aim to use the Vantage sorry
the mobile device as the vantage point
is and we exploit the crowdsourcing
techniques in order to collect as much
information as possible and also to have
as much fidelity as we could on the data
and one of the main goals of the project
was making this tool available for
anyone independently of their technical
background and that's still quite hard
challenge for us as we're trying to
explain to users the different
characteristics of the networks as well
as how they can fix the issues that they
are encountering and since 2009
metalizer was run more than 1.4 million
times in 170 countries
so this basically covers almost every
single isp in the world and as our
initial deployment was based on java
applet we could not penetrate mobile
networks as it was running on the
browser so we decided to port this tool
to as an i as a native Android
application and and it was actually
released in Google Play and Amazon App
Store in October 2013 in the case of the
mobile app we have already around 22,000
installs with quite very quite
optimistic reviews and we have access
already to 400 mobile operators in more
than 120 countries and what we do with
this data is basically what academics do
just write in papers and I will
encourage you to visit our website if
you want to see or to get more
information about the methodology of the
different tests as well as some results
and we have actually published this data
in conferences such as IMC pan or
connects and some of these works works
actually cover from
TLS certificates deployed on Android
devices up to the effect of proxies on
on DSL connections so the tool executes
around 120 different tests and the tests
begin to be executed whenever the users
click on the start button unfortunately
we don't have access to the radio radio
information as this is the control plane
is completely hidden from the from the
framework to the operating system in any
case we have a very comprehensive list
of of tests that are trying to benchmark
and characterize the IP core so we look
at for instance the DNS resolvers we
perform we benchmark the performance we
also look for support of new
technologies such as ipv6 or in a sec we
also run different tests to estimate for
instance buffer bloat or in order to
identify as well certain aspects of
peering NAT behavior I and even for
instance the behavior of hidden proxies
and HTTP proxies but in addition to that
we also look at hansard miss
configurations so we're looking for
instance that what kind of APN settings
the devices are having or which ones are
actually being used by the device and
the APN settings are actually quite
important for us as they determine you
know quite good detail the way that
network is gonna behave and he said that
we also check for certificate for the
routes or of the different devices seen
how mobile operators as well as
different vendors increase the route
store and also other configuration
aspects such as the clock drift then one
once the tests are completed the server
patchers and collects all the
information and we compile this
information to generate
result summary that is sent back to the
device so we classify the results vary
based on their severity and also
depending on the on the type of of test
that actually is is running and then you
SURS can actually clean click on the on
the results if they want to understand
to get some information about what the
test is actually doing and now that you
have a high-level idea of what
neutralizer does let me present a few
preliminary results so first I will
cover how middleboxes and DNS for
instance DNS resolvers and HTTP proxies
are deployed in the networks and how
this can affect the user experience and
after that I will show a few numbers
about how ipv6 is currently supported in
in mobile networks but I will conclude
with some results about the layer 8 so
basically we have identified how
business relationships actually between
mobile providers and also how new
business products such as mobile greater
network operators are changing the whole
ecosystem and also providing different
type of services to the customers so in
any case we will be glad to hear from
your feedback and also we would like to
hear your suggestions so if in case that
you may think that there is something
that is actually inaccurate and for
those of you who are not familiar with
cellular networks I will start by
describing a bit the classic tech or the
theoretical deployment of a cellular
network so more network is divided into
planes
first we have the control plane that
basically responsible for spectrum
management mobility management and then
we have a data plane where we actually
send the users data and then in the data
plane sorry I was missing that thing in
the data plane we have the middle boxes
such as the DNS resolvers or other
elements such as the Nats a mobile
device or a user equipment is actually
connected to the internet after creating
a PvP context so this is basically a
tunnel that hides completely the control
plane from the device and mobile users
actually have very little power to
modify what kind of middle boxes they
are going to encounter whenever they're
trying to connect to the internet so
as we can see in this figure the
position of the middle boxes also
effects the performance in this figure
we compared the DNS lookup time
depending on whether the DNS resolver is
placed before the current line not so in
other words as close as possible to a
device or after the current reynad using
third-party services and this test is
actually instrumental to warranty that
the names that we are looking for are
not caching so basically they are going
up to our authoritative name server and
as you can see most mobile providers
actually well sorry the most small
providers actually deploy their DNS
before the category not but when they
don't actually we it will affect
significantly performance so it can
increase around 90 milliseconds the DNS
lookup time and if you think about the
way mobile applications behave nowadays
fetching content from CD ends and from a
lot of 12 providers this has this can
actually become a significant bottleneck
for mobile performance and in fact there
are also middle boxes that remain hidden
for most users and one could argue that
middle boxes are actually deployed for a
purpose they are usually used for the to
combat other space depletion such as in
the case of nuts
they are also deployed for security as
in the case of firewalls or defied
resources scarcity race limiters rate
limiters are also to improve performance
as in the case of proxies performing TCP
splitting or performance enhancing
proxies for HTTP traffic but this figure
as we can see shows that in the u.s.
most of the operators are actually
having DNS proxies as well as HTTP
proxies deployed and the numbers that we
are seeing are actually way higher than
in the rest of the world so what this
middle box is actually doing to our
traffic
well I will tell you many anecdotes that
we have observed in the last year but as
you can see in this figure most of the
proxies are actually modifying the HTTP
headers and more significantly the
content and if you think of references
the case of a professional photographer
trying to download an image from
hi hybrid solution image from the from a
given website the network is actually
likely to encode and sorry transcode the
image to a lower resolution one so this
can actually affect the user experience
to some extent but the most significant
aspect that we have observed is that
there are a large number of
resignification umber of operators that
are actually having a proxy with a
vulnerability that was already
identified in 2009 so it's a
five-year-old lunar ability and despite
the fact that this vulnerability doesn't
affect the user security it may actually
indicate that there are other bugs and
other issues behind this middleboxes
and now I want to basically present some
preliminary results about ipv6 and
unfortunately the data is not very
conclusive but I would like to hear from
you about what which one are your
experiences when you're trying to the
transition from ipv6 to 34 might be for
2006 and as you can see ipv6 to support
this is still quite a testimonial in
mobile networks we have around 11% of
the sessions coming only from nano
craters in six different countries and
this is actually very exciting for us as
we have the ability to see how ipv6 is
deployed since the beginning and we are
very exciting about what kind of results
we will see in the upcoming months in
any case we haven't seen any difference
in terms of performance so far when we
are saying device is connected through
ipv6 but the problem is that whose IP
core we are actually measuring we need
to take into account the layer eight of
the protocol stack and as some of you
may know there are two types of mobile
operators there there are mobile network
operators who are actually having a
spectrum license and they actually
deploy the whole infrastructure and
there are also more and built or network
operators that run on top of one mobile
network operator and they can actually
use completely the IP core supported by
the main carrier or they can actually
deploy there
in addition to that morale operators
also share infrastructure between them
in order to reduce the network
deployment costs and this happens a lot
in a lot of European countries and when
network sharing is taking place we can
see that some operators are actually
implementing home routing in this case
all the users traffic is sent to the
home network and actually increasing the
latency or they are implementing local
breakout in this case all the users
traffic is sent through the visiting
Network and therefore the user is
vulnerable to any middleboxes
misbehavior or actually their
performance can improve depending on
which the type of network that they are
actually running to but unfortunately
for us all these business relationships
are not publicly available and what we
will show you in the next slides is
basically based on observations that we
have seen with metalizer
so this is a partial view of what we see
of in the u.s. of the mobile ecosystem
and here we can see the forming mobile
carriers having the spectrum licensed at
a at a national level so Verizon Sprint
AT&T and t-mobile and we can easily
identify as well the mobile virtual
network operators running on top of them
and this is just a small subset of the
ones that we have observed just because
of space limitations but the really
important aspect for us is that we have
seen operators sorry devices with a sim
card provided by one of the operators
but actually running completely on a
specific network and actually this is
what I'm what we're actually really
trying to characterize at the moment in
the sense that we would like to see how
this can affect the user experience
perform and performance but in addition
to that there is also a third type of
service and one example is WDS PC and we
try to contact them just to find out
which one was their business model and
according to their website they are
provided or listing IP addresses space
but what really surprises us is that two
of the most or two of the mobile
operators that are having a lot of IP
addresses space are actually taking
advantage of this kind of service
and another type of service is what we
call mobile built on network enablers or
cloud providers to some extent and in
this case we have seen some mobile built
or network operators that are actually
taking advantage of this kind of service
to deploy completely their own IP
infrastructure layer but as a result of
all these recent relationships we are
actually able to identify at Virginia's
behavior within a network so this figure
shows the percentage of sessions of two
operators with a particular network
behavior and as we can see operator one
sessions are always having the same
behavior but in the case of operator two
they can differ and this can be caused
by different network deployments in
different parts of the country or just
by different APN settings so for
instance we have identified one user who
was actually entering by in
inappropriate APN settings on his device
and this was forcing many applications
to crash as the proxy that it was
reaching was forcing compression by
default and if the developers are not
handling this kind of feature on their
HTTP libraries then it's very likely
that if they don't handle the exceptions
properly the applications may crash and
then what we have observed is that when
these users are roaming on a different
network we can see that the users of a
given operator actually getting
properties from the network they are
visiting so this corroborates that the
fact that these of these operators are
implementing local breakout and
therefore they are not warranty into the
customers the homogeneous quality of
service
so to complete let me basically finish
with a couple of takeaway messages and
those are some lessons that we learned
while trying to characterize smaller
networks in order to actually benchmark
and characterize more networks we
definitely have to do it from the edge
of the network if we're trying to do
anything from the cloud then basically
so for instance using traces from
servers we will measure what ever is
happening between the middle box under
server and not between the mobile client
and the under server and then we also
have to take into account a full cross
layer analysis looking at every single
element of the network including as
usual service as you could see the
business relationships in fact these
business relationships under
implementation can also impact on the
network properties so we need to look
for very fine-grained information when
the device in order to accurately map
this information to what we are
observing and we are actually aware of
the fact that we are not able to fill a
lot of pieces of on these basically on
the space and we would like to hear from
your feedback and your suggestions in
case that you may be aware of something
that we are not actually measuring and
we are actually continuously supporting
and deploying new tests on the app in
fact I think it will be very interesting
to characterize for instance the moral
ecosystem Watauga at a worldwide scale
just to identify different policies
depending on the regulatory bodies that
are controlling the market in these
different countries and a good example
is actually what will happen as well for
instance comparing the performance that
we are seeing in the u.s. with the
performance that we are seeing in
motivated lies markets as in the
European Union where the presence of
more brutal network operators is
actually quite significant and also they
are supporting roaming between different
countries and in addition to that we
also like to have a better insight on
what we what will happen for instance in
the mismatch between DNS resolvers and
CBN's so for instance this is actually
caused by the fixed infrastructure and
the limited number of gateways that we
will see on mobile networks and that can
actually for instance for a couple of
operators we have seen that in many
cases the CDN that is being requested is
actually not the ideal one according to
other sources that we are actually able
to obtain and in any case that is at the
end of my talk and I would love to
invite you to try and to run analyzer
and preferably if you can run it on a
wife sorry to learn Network it will be
better so we can collect more more data
and we would like to hear from your
feedback and also in case that you have
any suggestion or any recommendation or
anything that you would like to measure
please get in touch with us through any
of these symbols thank you we have a
couple minutes for questions
thank you nurse they're all right
you