hello everyone i'm venue
uh i'm presenting a three-legged rest
uh it is uh privacy preserving the
entrance method
that can leverage both keys and gpus to
achieve
privacy protection and also the
computing performance
yeah so just a little background about
myself i'm a fourth year phd student
from university of southern california
and my research topics covers various
aspects about you know
privacy privacy protecting in you know
in previous protection
in machine learning training
yeah so before i you know before i
discussing the details about the pepper
let me spend a few minutes on the
motivation
about the work
so yeah so if you see the machine
learning from that privacy protective
you know perspective we can you know
categorize the machine learning in two
classes the first one is using the gpus
and tpus to achieve a strong computing
performance
but if this you know platform like like
sufficient privacy protection
on the data
so attackers can easily get the
sensitive information about the dataset
and another classes is the you know
trusted execution environment cortese
you know by providing a very strong in a
secure environment that he's can give a
very strong you know privacy guarantee
and it is very difficult for the
attackers to access the you know
sensitive information
and during transmission of the data or
you know the runtime in the te
environment
but the cost comes with the privacy
guarantees the you know very low
computing performance compared to the
you know the gpu or tpu
platform
yeah so the problem setting in this
paper is that can we combine gpus and
keys to achieve both performance and
privacy guarantees
yes let me you know provide a little
more context here in terms of the model
in france in terms of the in terms of
the privacy preserving modern
infrastructure training so for the
private model influence
uh we have uh you know very
commonly you have very famous algorithm
called slalom so the basic idea in islam
is that
in these it add noise to the vision data
and send noisy data to the gpus the gpu
is computing the you know the
convolution operations and have this
noisy output and sending this noisy
output to the keys and the keys can get
the original output by decrypting the
noise output
yeah so it's very private in terms of
model influence but the issue here is
that slalom does not support inner model
training which is a more computation
intensive task
yeah so for model training this you know
other method like in know private ml or
dark knight so all of this method have
you know all of this method that they're
adopting in a multi-party computing
magazine mechanism that you use you know
jointly you know collaborating nodes to
support his
privacy protecting
so the
yes we assume that they have you know
non including
you know gpu knows that keying you know
protected the data but assumption the
assumption of the noncloning nodes
might feel might fail in some cases so
if this assumption
fails
any single nodes can reconstruct the
data
so the you know the privacy protecting
is actually significantly compromised
yeah so here we are proposing a method
to you know to leverage that you know
the the keys and gpus to achieve both
privacy protecting and also the
computing performance
the basic idea in the method small is
our method is like
we first
have a symmetric you know decomposition
framework to decompose the data into
local lowering part and the residuals
the lowering part has most information
about in the dataset but if the
computation involving the lower
important is very light on the other
hand the residual csi is not allowing
but it has less information about it
that is it
so yeah so most information you know
computations is actually offloaded to
not to the residuals
so then we accordingly decompose the
model into two parts the first part is
performed in keys and we did the long
part xd
and as second part is performed in the
gpus and avoided the the residual sexu
and if we take a you know a closer view
about sml
the asymmetric data decomposition
happens in the convolutional layers
so we first decompose the data x
into xt and xu and then we have the you
know the convolution t in the t used to
read the xd to the you know secure
conversions in these
and for xu we have you know
convolutional in gpus to read the x unit
and you know do the conversion
operations
so after we get it that would weight in
you we combine that put in these and
apply the nonlinear operations
and before proceeding to the next
convolution layers we will do the
asymmetric decomposition again together
the lowering part and the residuals
yeah so here we summarize the you know
the contributions in this paper the
first contribution is that we develop
this asymmetric data and model
decomposition by using a lightweight svd
algorithm
so the computation complexity in these
is you know
a computational complexity is
increasingly increases linearly with the
number of number of you know principal
channels in t
and giving the you know the long data in
the input lowering structure in inputs
and uh and the intermediate activations
the number for the number of principal
channels in ts can be much smaller than
the number of you know total input
channels
and if we take a more concrete example
uh
where the number of you know principal
channels in t over the number of total
channels is one over 16 we can see that
the computational complexity is much
indeed is much less than
the complexity in gpus
and the second contribution we have is
we have uh is that we have a theoretical
guarantee for the privacy so by adding
noise to the residuals
and sending the noisy uh you know
residuals in the gpus we achieve the
differential private
uh you know protecting on the data and
compared to you know the method that
directly adds noise to the vision data
the noisy recording smell is much lesser
than you know the method that add noise
to the residual data
and add noise to a vision data
so the third contribution we have is
that we have a theoretical analysis on
the luang structuring you know in models
so yeah so to analyze the long structure
we first defined the 3d a metric called
svd channel entropy
and then using this metric speedy chain
entropy we measure the you know the
entropy bond
in the output after every you know
operation in scenes
yeah so for for commonly used operation
like convolutional loop ruling and the
batch analyzing layer we demonstrated
that up output after all of these layers
is expounded by the input
so that is the long structures you know
is well preserved in the
in e
yes so the the you know the
another contribution we have is that we
have this asymmetric implementation
so this uh asthma asthma implementation
this framework can automatically convert
a model into smear format
and then initiate the two parallel
running context which is gpu and sdx
context and the framework supports both
forward and backward process
for most commonly used in the uh models
yeah so we also conduct uh comprehensive
you know numerical evaluations on the
smear performance so the first one we
have we have is uh the you know running
time a master commonly used you know uh
models
so if we compare the training time we
can see that small achieve
like almost eight times faster than sdx
only training in hd
uh network and almost six times faster
than sdx only training on resnet models
and also we also compare the inference
time on games
and compare the you know compared with a
very famous baseline called asylum and
the inference time is almost the same as
thanks to you know the
the long structures in intermediate data
yes so the second experiment were wrong
is that to use the you know is to
measure the training accuracy so if we
compare the small under the original
vest line you can see the training
accuracy is almost
of using small is almost the same as the
original model
and if we compare html with dpx which is
the method that directly add noise to
the vision data to achieve the same
privacy guarantee dpx dpx
you know suffers a lot of you know
accuracy jobs
yeah so we also conduct the modern
inversion text um you know against small
this modern version text is a very
powerful method that you use any prior
knowledge and you know we have to do the
you know to do the modding version
and to measure the you know the
performance of this modern inversion
text we
uh have the following matrix the first
two is piercing and ssim so they are
aimed to you know to measure the
similarities between the training images
and also the reconstruct images and the
last one is accuracy in the top model so
in this metric we input the reconstruct
images to the attacked mode and measured
accuracy
and from this table can see that the you
know psn ssim is very low so that means
there are few similarities between the
training images and the reconstruct
images and as shown in the last column
if we imported the reconstruct images
through the tagged model the qc is also
very low
so that means the attack model can not
recognize the reconstruct images
yeah so this is like some samples and we
can see the difference between the
reconstruct data and the original
training data this you know from this
you know samples we can see that this
you know not a lot of
similarities between this
uh between these two
uh data
yeah so this is the experiment we want
to you know to evaluate the small
performance
and of course smu has some limitations
and one
significant
limitation in the cpu gpu communications
so to measure you know this limitation
we're breaking the running time into
three parts forward backward and the cpu
gpu communication time
so from this figure we can see the
cpu gpu communication
is very significant
especially around in the early
conclusion layers it dominated the whole
you know um training time
yeah so one possible color and one you
know one part
possible solution is that we can
compress the data before sending the
residuals to the gpus yeah so currently
we are working along this direction and
hopefully we can resolve this you know
this issue
yeah so this is a very in a high-level
description about small and yes so i'm
very happy to take any questions if you
have
and also if you read the papers and have
any you know concerns or questions
please you know can take me offline you
know i'm very happy to discuss with you
about any you know potential issues in
esme
yeah thank you