hello my name is johann berger i'm a phd
student in the syslab at penn state
where i'm advised by professor patrick
mcdaniel
today i will be presenting how to build
a privacy preserving smart camera system
a work that was done with my colleagues
acknowledge here below
first
let's see what is a smart camera system
smart camera system are used by people
to remotely monitor their own while they
are away for instance
this system are very convenient
and also very popular as we can see here
on the right on this map of the united
states where each point represents a
location of some of the devices
sold by ring an amazon company
however the use
is not without loss
and over the past few years we have seen
different reports about there about
issues and privacy concerns about this
system
here are for example
i would like you to focus on this
example
question the amount of trust that you
users need to place into device and
cloud provider
for instance users might be worried by
the fact that their device provider is
partnering with law enforcement to
facilitate video sharing
or that employees of some companies are
abusing their access to see user's
videos
what all this example all this example
demonstrate is the fact that users do
not have control over their data and
over the system
so we would like to build a privacy
preserving smart camera system
here is a spread model in which we are
going to operate for that we are only
going to consider the smart camera and
the device controlled by the owner to be
trusted anyone else and any other party
is considered as interested in our
design
to build such a privacy programming
smart camera system we need to return
control to users
and at the same time we still want to
support commercial features that are the
main reason why this system are so
popular
it's going to be this balance between
security and privacy on one hand unlike
usability on the other hand that is hard
to achieve
for instance if we want to return
control to users we would like to use
end-to-end encryption in our system if
we do so we are effectively returning
control to users as
owners are the only one able to access
the videos
however using end-to-end encryption
introduce new questions and challenges
such as how do we establish root of
trust between devices in such a setting
where we can only trust the owner and no
one else
also how do we manage all those
encryption keys especially to support
commercial feature features such as
delegation
now we are going to focus on those two
main issues
first how can we establish route of
trust between devices that are unknown
to each other
to do so we would like to establish a
secure communication channel between
those devices so that they can
further on negotiate encryption keys or
secrets for the life cycle of the rest
of the system
we would like to use authenticated
defeatment key exchange to do so
we are going to do it the following way
the smartphone and the smart camera
system are going to pair through
bluetooth or wifi
and then we are additionally going to
use an out of burn physical channel to
verify that each device is actually
speaking and communicating to the right
device
this is to mitigate any
man-in-the-middle attack
in our proof of concept we use a
physical channel
which is a phys your channel
by using qr codes where that we flash
and in which we embed some details
so this is how we establish this secure
communication channel from where we can
start building the right the rest of the
route of trust for this for the rest of
the system
now let's see
how in our
end-to-end encryption system we can
manage
all these encryption keys
for that we are going to use a binary
key tree that is built the following way
from a seed key we are going to be able
to derive lower keys in the tree by
applying a hash base key derivation
function or htdf
this http function is a one-way function
this means that we can only derive lower
keys from upper keys and not the other
way around in this key tree this is
going to be an important aspect for the
rest of the system and for its privacy
guarantees
so in our system
recall that after initialization and
pairing we have the smart camera
and the smartphone connected
through a secure communication channel
through this through this channel they
are going to negotiate a c key
that is going to be the root of this key
tree
then
this system can go on their own way to
derive the lower keys as they know the
hkdi function
at the very bottom of this key tree that
we are able to derive
are like the keys that are going to be
used to include video frames that are in
the same epoch
an epoch in our system is just a fixed
time window or interval
and in our proof of concept
this length is of
10 seconds
so this means that every 10 seconds the
keys are rotated
and so thanks to our key tree structure
we are able to efficiently manage the
keys and store them as we can derive
them from upper keys
and we are also able to support
key rotation
additionally this k3 structure is very
convenient to support another popular
commercial feature which is delegation
and in our system we are able to
do a very fine grain delegation
let's say for instance that our that the
owner would like to share some videos
with some shared users
what to do so they only need to figure
out which portion of the key tree
they need to
share with the delegate
as illustrated here
on the slide if the owner wanted to
share
the red portion
or like the blue dotted portion of their
video they would need to share the
corresponding only the corresponding key
and no other key and then the shared
user would be from those keys
be able to like derive lower keys and
access the corresponding encrypted
videos
and no other videos that the owner
didn't share with them
right so in our paper we introduced a
proof of concept of a privacy preserving
smart camera system that we call cactus
here is characters at play while live
streaming videos
our systems doesn't support only
initialization live streaming or
delegation but also other commercial
popular features such as video edition
access recovery and factory reset
for sake of time for this presentation
i'm going to defer the details of the
rest of this protocol
to the paper
and i'm going to speak now about how we
evaluated our system
the evaluation of cactus was threefold
first we carried out a secret analysis
to prove the privacy guarantees of our
design
cactus enforces the following three
rights for owners
first the right to not be seen by
leveraging end-to-end encryption
then the right of sole ownership
as owners in our system are the only one
who knows the encryption keys so they
are the only one able to immediate
access to them and to the corresponding
videos
finally owners have the right to be
forgotten on this means that owners can
delete their videos or more specifically
they can delete the encryption keys
rendering
recovery to them impossible even in case
of corruption
then we perform
a performance evaluation of our system
to figure out how it behaved
here in this table we present the
average time delay of each operation
that is carried out by the camera or the
smartphone application while we are live
streaming
as you can see the performance of our
system are reasonable as our latency is
about one second
something to notice is that
the
main contribution to this delay and to
this latency come from networking
operations such as uploading and
downloading the encrypted frame or from
the cloud storage
which is a point that is worth noting
that we haven't optimized at all in our
proof of concept
so further improvement
and perf and better performance is
expected here
all right
so
finally if building a privacy personal
smart camera system is great it is even
better
if it's usable
thus
we perform a functional user evaluation
with 10 participants to try to identify
the potential issues in our design and
in our protocols
here are the main takeaway
the participants
found that our system was usable and
that our application smartphone
application was simple to use and to
follow the instruction
they all
were impressed by the fine grenarity at
which they were able with catches to
delegate access to someone else to their
videos
and i also thought that the quality of
the videos in our
that the quality of the videos you know
of the live streaming was sufficient for
purposes
of a security smart camera system
they noted two potential improvements if
characters were to deploy as a
commercial system
the latin c should probably be optimized
further as discussed earlier and that
they also would like to see
the recording and the live streaming
triggered in cactus with some motion
detection system
these are two engineering problems that
can be solved applying networking
optimization on top of our protocols or
just adding
additional sensor
or
piece of software to the smart camera
device to support motion detection
so as a conclusion to design a privacy
personal smart camera system without
relying on anyone except the owner it's
important to establish a route of trust
that needs to be maintained over the
across the full life cycle of the system
in cactus we have used for that
different encryption and playing
techniques to encrypt and isolate access
to the data and also support different
features such as fine grainer reality
delegation
deletion and access recovery
finally it is worth noting that our
protocols
are not only restricted to smart camera
system but are also readily applicable
to other iot devices recorded time
series data
more details about the protocols are
available in the paper and our on the
implementation of our proof of concept
can be found at the following link