hello everyone i'm xi jiang from the
technical university of munich
today i'm going to present our work on
comprehensive analysis of privacy
leakage in vertical fetid learning
during prediction
this is joint work with shaving joe from
huawei munich research center and yes
growth clocks from the technical
university of munich
federalist learning is an immersion
distributed learning mechanism which
allows multiple organizations to jointly
train am models without revealing the
private data
according to the partition strategies of
local data existing effort frameworks
can be further categorized into the
horizontal setting and vertical setting
in the horizontal setting each party
holds data from different users while
these data share an overlapped set of
features
for instance in a healthcare application
a model for predicting cancer risks is
jointly trained by multiple hospitals
using the medical records of different
patients
in contrast the vertical setting assumes
that each party holds different features
of an intersecting set of users
moreover only one of the parties has the
real labels for instance in a smartphone
scenario a bank wants to train a model
to evaluate customers credit scores
besides using song features such as age
and income it also collaborates with an
e-commerce company and uses additional
features such as purchasing history to
improve the model's accuracy
since it is common for companies to
collect different user features for
their services
vfl systems attracted increasing
attention in recent years
here we present a common two-party vfr
system
which includes an elective party who has
part of the features and real labels and
a passive party who only provides
additional features
moreover several existing vfr systems
also adopt a trusted coordinator to
manage the communication between the
local parties and to defend against the
privacy leakage
during prediction each party inputs the
features of new samples to the trained
models and computes the intermediate
results
the coordinator then privately
aggregates these results computes the
confidence scores by an output
activation function and returns them to
the active party
although the trusted coordinator
effectively prevents the direct data
sharing between local parties
a recent work by law at all shows that
during prediction the active party can
still use the confidence scores to
reconstruct pacific features and cause
privacy leakage
in their paper the authors started with
a simple setting where two parties
jointly trained a logistic regression
model with k classes
they proposed an equation solving attack
which mathematically calculates the
passive party features by solving the
following linear equation system
they show that when the number of
unknown features d pass is less than the
number of classes k the equation system
has a unique solution and the feature
values can be fully reconstructed
however the esc attack only works for
linear models and cannot be applied to
complex neural networks
therefore the authors further proposed a
generic regression network attack
which uses an attack model to learn the
future correlations between both parties
and to generate the passive party
features
nevertheless the attack requests
collecting a large number of predictions
to train the attack model
finally both attacks only considered the
white box setting which assumes the
attacker can access the passive party
model
this may not always be achievable in
real life scenarios
motivated by these observations and
limitations we propose and illustrate
the threat posed by a gradient-based
inversion attack
the attack can be generically applied to
different machine learning models and
does not need to train an attack model e
at once
moreover besides the white box setting
we give the first attempt to explore the
attack under the black box setting
next we will introduce this attack in
detail
start with the white box attack
similar to the previous work we assume
the attacker namely the active fighter
has full knowledge of the entire model
parameters
also for each new sample he knows its
own input features as well as the real
confidence scores
the goal of the attacker is to use this
information to estimate the passive
party features
our attack is conducted in an iterative
fashion
to begin with the attacker randomly
initializes the passive party features
then both part of the features are fed
to train the model to compute the
estimated confidence scores
the distance between the real and
estimated confidence scores is
calculated and used to update the
passive party features
this process is repeated for several
rounds until the estimated confidence
scores are close enough to the real
values
here we use two metrics namely the mean
squared error and the k outer versions
to measure the distance
next we explore the potential privacy
leakage under the black box setting
here the attacker only knows his model
and cannot access the passive party
model
we further slightly relax the setting by
assuming that the attacker is aware of a
small set of auxiliary data
this can be obtained by for instance
colluding with a few users whose data
achieved in both parties
the black box attack can then be
conducted in two steps
first the attacker uses the auxiliary
detail to train a shadow model to mimic
the performance of the passive party
model
then he can use the shadow model to
repeat the white box attack and to
recover the passive party features
for training the shadow model the
attacker first initializes a random
passive party model
then the auxiliary data are iteratively
input into the model and the distance
between the real and estimated
confidence scores will be used to update
the model parameters
finally we wonder how much auxiliary
data is needed to build a good shadow
model
given the number of model parameters and
classes we derive an approximated
threshold top as the minimum auxiliary
data for achieving similar attack
performance as in the white box setting
note that the attack can still be
performed with less auxiliary data but
this may lead to a worse attack
performance
we conduct our attack on four open
source data sets and compare the attack
results against the logistic regression
models and multi-layer neural networks
we respectively use the attacks proposed
by royaltal as the baselines
we adopted two metrics to evaluate the
attack performance
for the attack arrow we use the average
the misgrade error to measure the
difference between the real and
reconstructed features
for the attack accuracy we treat an
evaluation classifier and investigate
whether the reconstructed features can
provide the same prediction results as
real features
we first report the attack performance
under the wet box setting against both
types of models it can be seen that we
can achieve a zero attack error when the
number of passive priority features is
small meaning that the feature values
are fully recovered
although the attack performance
decreased with the increase of unknown
features our attack shows a significant
improvement compared to the baseline
algorithms
we further conduct black box attacks
against the both types of models using
different amount of auxiliary data
it can be seen that the increase of
auxiliary data can in general contribute
to a lower attack error and the attack
error is similar to the one under the
white box setting when the amount of
obstacle data approaches the threshold
here for both models we can already
achieve comparable performance with only
less than 100 required
the results show that even without
knowing the passive party models the
attacker can still use limited auxiliary
data to build the shadow model and to
apply the reconstruction attack
we further investigate whether the prior
knowledge of the model structure is
essential for building the shadow models
to this end we use the two layer neural
network as the real passive parting
model and compare the attack error of
using shadow models with different
structures
it can be seen that building the shadow
model with the original structure leads
to the lowest attack error although
altering the model structure may
increase the attack error we can still
achieve a satisfactory attack
performance when the shadow model does
not differ too much from the real model
the result indicates that it is still
possible to conduct the attack even
without knowing the exact structure of
the passive parting model
finally we analyze the performance of
different defense techniques which are
either applied during training or during
prediction for the defenses during
training we investigated where the
private sector section the commonly used
sample alignment technique can help
prevent privacy leakage
moreover we also analyze the capability
of differentially private training
against the attack
here epsilon is the privacy budget the
smaller epsilon the higher the privacy
protection
for the defenses during prediction we
process the original confidence scores
by rounding the values to limited
decimal places or adding random noise
with different noise skills
we also investigate a purification
defense which uses a pre-trained
purifier to perturb the real confidence
scores
the precessor scores will be decoupled
with the input features but can still
provide a good labor prediction accuracy
here we compare the performance of pure
buyers respectively trained on real data
or randomly sampled data
the two figures report the privacy
utility analysis of different defense
techniques under the white box setting
the red star represents the area of the
ideal privacy utility tradeoff
from the results it can be seen that psa
cannot prevent reconstruction attacks
while training models with dp can reduce
the attack accuracy when eastern is
small it also results in much lower
motor utility
on the other hand processing the
confidence scores can better enhance
privacy protection for instance rounding
the confidence scores to integers can
effectively prevent the attack without
affecting the model accuracy
adding noise with a noise skill larger
than 0.1 can also defend against the
attack but too much noise may cause a
significant utility loss
finally perturbing the confidence scores
with purifiers trained with both real
data and randomly sample data can in
general achieve a satisfactory privacy
utility balance
in conclusion in this paper we propose
and discuss the threat posed by the
gradient-based inversion attack a
generic framework that performs special
reconstruction attacks on bfo systems
during prediction the attack can be
flexibly applied to different machine
learning models and outperforms the
prior work
we further explore the attack under the
black box setting and show that
attackers with limited prior knowledge
can still infer the passive party
features even without knowing the target
model's railways or the model structures
finally we analyze the privacy utility
trade-off of several defense techniques
we show that the proposed attack cannot
be simply prevented by using a trusted
coordinator
instead processing the confidence scores
with quantization and randomization
approaches can be useful for
strengthening privacy protection while
having only negligible effect on model
utility thank you for listening