hello everyone welcome to my talk i am
jigar from the university of virginia
and we are glad to present our paper
today the title is deletion influence
reconstruction and compliance in machine
learning
this is a collaboration work with sandra
mohammed and prashant
here is an outline of this talk we will
introduce two major threat models
division inference attack and deletion
reconstruction attack
recently there has been more and more
regulations about right to erasure that
is individuals can request that they
have to be deleted for example
gdpr in europe allows consumers to
delete their data followed by many
states in united states from this map we
can see a huge map of u.s are
considering similar privacy regulations
we know that the machine learning models
are built on user data so iphone
requests from consumer we will need to
update model makes the model forget this
specific data
and this process is very costly
this fact motivates this line of work
called machine learning
we briefly introduced this machine
learning process here suppose we have a
model h that is trained with examples e1
to e5
now we get this request for deleting an
example e4 in the data set
the goal of machine learning is to get a
new model we call it edge dell that is
ideally the same as training a new
model from scratch with the training set
as except this example e4
we call this ideal case as perfect
deletion
we now post a question
if privacy motivates such erasure
requests that doing this on learning
really helps individuals privacy
this perfect model will get very
training is built without this record e
so it seems to be unable to learn
anything of e here however is that
really the case
an adversary can observe both versions
of the model
here the address will already observe
the model before deletion
and after delete request the model get
updated that user query is the second
model
and here's the problem as a contract
example suppose that our model returns a
summation of records in a set
so for a single record the model
preserve is privacy to some extent
however
there is required both model can then
exactly infer this record
by just applying a single deduction
so in this example the deletion
operation totally destroys the privacy
of the record
come to our work we study the privacy
implication of this machine on learning
and we make the following contributions
first we formally define strain models
including
the reconstruction and inference attack
tailored for machine learning
and secondly we also show some very
simple attack can succeed in these
thread models for different machine
learners
specifically we focus on two-strand
models
in the deletion inference attack address
we want to infer whether an example is
deleted or not
and in deletion reconstruction attack
that user wants to reconstruct the
deleted example
both thread models are very general
meaning that they have various forms
and can be applied to many machine
learning tasks
before coming to our attack we first
introduced some relative work on our
topic
salem medal 2020 proposed privacy
attacks on updating machinery models the
model is updated with the additional
example and they clean the generating
models to reconstruct the example from
the input for
both model before addition and after
addition
a concurrent world trade or 2021
proposed privacy attack on deletion they
adapt the memory inference framework by
training an attack model from the output
on the two models before and after
division to infor whether an example is
digital
and comparing to these two relative
works we give a new formal definition of
privacy in various new settings
also we propose extremely simple but
effective attack on both inference and
reconstruction scenarios
we also present some partial theoretical
justifications of why this attacks work
and study attacks on new models such as
language models
there is also a very recent work study
managing influence on model update with
access on updating models
now let's start with deletion inference
attack
we start with the deletion inference
first thread model introduces decision
inference which is inferring whether an
example is deleted or not
so here in the slice there is a wonder
whether an example e is deleted
there is a get to query the model before
deletion
and then query the new model after
note that the sequence of the query is
fixed because after the deletion the
original model is not accessible anymore
to clarify one thing here that really
knows the deletion happens but just
wondering about what is digit
to highlight that we study a more basic
scenario which is inspired by the
indistinguishability security games in
crypto such as in cpa or cca security
in the scenario
the address is given two choices e0 and
e1
and need to find out which one of them
is deleted
we now formally define the security game
of deletion inference
there are two parties a challenger and
an adversary
the challenger first pick a data set
with sex m
the challenger then pick two examples
yeah and ej and send them to the
adversary
the chinese entrance model is the
learner
the artist will have oracle access to
this model before the next step
then the challenger toss a coin to
delete one example
between yan and ej
and get a new model
and after that the address is given
oracle access to this new model
and finally the address guesses which
one among ei and ej is deleted
the address tell challenger a bit 001
and wins if the guess is correct
we call a scheme drawing skewer against
deletion inference if there exists an
address who succeeds with probability at
least low
so when raw is half it is trivial
because at least you can just flip a
random coin to achieve that
now before introducing our attack we
first see one possible attack which is
reducing the problem to membership
influence
membership influence attacks the type of
privacy attacker returns whether an
input is part of the data set or not
if we have a membership influencer
address that always succeed we can then
use it to get the membership of the two
examples on the two models
and then decide which example is digit
is because the deleted example loses its
membership after deletion
because of this reduction
inference attack is only interesting
when it can beat this reduction
now can we define inference attack that
can leverage this deletion scenario
we propose a simple attack the intuition
is that the loss of the deleted example
should increase
because it is removed from the data set
the attack is very simple
just compare the difference on the loss
that is the loss after deletion minus
the loss before division
so the attack first query the model h
and f del with both examples e0 and e1
and then it
gets a loss of the two examples compute
the difference for both e0 and e1 and
finally the model returns example is
larger loss difference
for evaluation our goal is to evaluate
our attack on large models between a
large data set
our baseline is the reduction to the
membership influence attack from
shockery at all
one of the famous membership influence
attack
the trina attack model with the help of
accelerated data from same distribution
the problem is that the shocking attack
trains several machine learning models
to attack so to compare we need to
retrieve all these models for each
deletion which is very costly
to alleviate this problem
we apply the multi-division setting
so each time we pick a batch of 100
examples and read all of them
we also pick another 100 examples inside
the data set but not deleted
then we perform deletion inference for
each pair of the examples across these
batches
we test these attacks on two deep
convolutional neural network a small
conversion neural network small cnn and
a famous convolutional neural network
regionating we train these models on two
image classification tasks
cypher 10 and 700
we summarize the result in these four
figures our deletion inference attack is
a blue curve here
our deletion influencer attack has high
success rate even in the case when the
data set size is large
we show that the deletion influence can
be done when the data sets and models
are large and when a batch of examples
is deleted
together give the time limit
please refer to our paper for more
experiment results
this concludes our result on division
inference
we now move on to the second type of
attacks decision reconstruction attack
deletion reconstruction is a harder task
suppose example e is deleted and others
will try to reconstruct example e from
the query
deletion reconstruction attack is
stronger attack that can reduce to
deletion inference
as if someone can recontract the example
they can also compare it with the
example given by the challenger and tell
which one is dehu
we also work on wearing of these models
please check our paper for wearing the
reconstruction that we call deletion
label reconstruction
similar to deletion inference there are
two parties a challenger and an
adversary
the challenger first pick a data set
with size m and trigger model with the
learner
the address has oracle access to this
model
and change the pick an example to delete
and change a new model
after that the address is given oracle
access to this new model
the difference here is that in deletion
reconstruction the others will need to
estimate the example and send back to
the challenger
the reconstruction doesn't need to be
perfect
and the addresses performance is
measured by some distance metric
that measures the distance between the
reconstructed example and the example
now i present a reconstruction attack
that is based on the nutrition that the
output of the instance around the
example e are likely to be different
after deletion
in that case
dilute reference compose a set of
instances t which can be obtained from
accelerating instances from the data
distribution
or just random sampling from the input
space
that there is a first query model with
all the instances in t
and after getting access
to the deletion model it queries other
examples on the deleted model
the address reason creates a subset of t
which includes all the instances whose
prediction label changed as the deletion
region t prime
the attacker doesn't compute the
majority of t prime
it is actually a meta attack because of
majority here it can be general and the
reason we can choose an appropriate
aggregation function
depends on the task
example on the majority function is that
for each bit in the data just take the
majority vote of that bit over all the
examples in key prime and return the
reconstruction based on that
as a test to the reconstruction attack
we consider a case when we want to
reconstruct images for nearest neighbor
predictors
we use omniglo dataset with for that
which include 20 copies for handwritten
characters
we use
10 copies of each character to learn
model and the other 10 copies of each
character the viewer accelerates the
process that is available to the
adversary
our deletion reconstruction attack
reconstructed a lot of examples which is
shown in the rows markers too
compared to the actual deleted example
of the row three they show a lot of
similarity and we can see that without
lesion the reconstruction basically
reconstructs nothing
please refer to our paper for more
experiment results and details
as a summary in this paper we study
privacy implications of machine learning
learning we propose two strand models
deletion inference and division
reconstruction i'm ensure that simple
attacks are effective for variety of
settings and models
for future work one direction is to give
optimal bonds on the deletion inference
attacks
another direction is to have probable
attacks and defenses under update
beyond merely applying differential
privacy
that's all if you are interested in our
work please check our paper for the
details thank you