hello everyone my name is bo dawn
kolinic and i'm going to talk about our
paper on disparate vulnerability to
membership inference attacks
so what are membership inference attacks
these are attacks against privacy of
machine learning or statistical models
in which an adversary aims to learn for
a given record x whether this record was
part of the training data set or not
because machine learning models are a
bit like parrots they can memorize what
they have seen in the training data by
querying and inspecting the model in
different ways an adversary can get a
non-trivial advantage at identifying if
a record was used in training or not
researchers have noticed that different
records can be differently vulnerable to
membership inference attacks this
observation comes in two forms
first somewheres have pointed out that
there could be outlier records that are
more vulnerable than others
second other researchers have noticed
that whole semantically related
subgroups of data can have higher
vulnerability than other groups in our
work we study the latter aspect
desperate vulnerability to membership
inference across data population
subgroups
studying this form of disparate
vulnerability is important among all
else for from the legal point of view
legal scholars have argued that
membership inference attacks are a good
tool for auditing machine learning and
statistical models for their privacy
leakage for example under gdpr the
schools have argued that if a model is
vulnerable to membership inference the
model should be considered personal data
and that's treated in a special way
the issue that can come up here is
privacy washing through the usage of
average metrics if we only look at
average vulnerability across the
population we might miss situations as
before and we might miss some records
that have higher vulnerability
if these records are semantically
disconnected outliers this vulnerability
is easy to dismiss as acceptable risk
if these records however all belong to a
socialist selling group this is much
more concerning and for example privacy
auditors might be accountable to those
groups
this is why being able to reason about
and audit disparate vulnerability
specifically across population subgroups
is important
in this talk i will discuss three
aspects of our paper
first regardless of any disparity
considerations we have to answer the
question when exactly the models are
vulnerable to membership inference
second we extend this insight to
disparate vulnerability
and then third and finally i will talk
about how we should measure this part
vulnerability so let's start with
figuring out when exactly the models are
vulnerable to membership inference
it is intuitive and well known that
overfeeding or lack of generalization is
a sufficient condition for a model to be
vulnerable to membership inference
generalization is characterized by this
gap between the average loss in the
training data on the left here and the
average loss on the test data on the
right
indeed if the model has much lower error
on its training data an adversary can
recognize training examples by looking
at the loss
there is a recent notion that
generalizes generalization pun intended
called distribution realization if
classical generalization only considers
the average of the distribution of loss
distribution internalization uses a
probabilistic metric between train and
test distributions specifically we use
total variation distance
moreover not only
we look at the loss but any other
numeric property of the model here
denoted as fee
in this work we analyze the worst case
vulnerability to membership inference
attacks that use a certain feature fee
to conduct an attack most commonly this
feature is loss but any other numeric
function of the model and an example
could work
we formalized the worst case
vulnerability as the best possible
normalized attack accuracy in a standard
formalism by yemen colleagues we show
that this worst case vulnerability is
exactly equal to the distribution
realization gap
so if poor
classical generalization is a sufficient
condition for vulnerability the
necessary and sufficient condition is
for distribution of generalization
next we extend this insight to disparate
vulnerability and for this we introduce
a special subgroup aware adversary if we
can conduct an attack using certain
features fee for example losses before
then a subgroup aware version of that
attack would additionally use the
subgroup to which an example belongs
we showed that the worst case
vulnerability with cyberware adversary
is always equal or higher than the worst
case vulnerability to an address that
does not use subgroup information so
using that is always beneficial to the
adversary in the worst case we use this
insight as a tool to connect software
vulnerability and distribution
generalization
we can look at a subgroup specific
version of distribution generalization
which as before is the distance between
training and test distributions but this
time the distributions are conditional
on the subgroup and as a technicality on
the fact that the trained data contains
at least one example of the subgroup
then we can show that the worst case
vulnerability to a sacrifice adversary
denoted as v sub z
is equal to subgroup specific
distribution generalization gap
because cyber adversary always causes
higher vulnerability in the worst case
startup vulnerability for any other
adversary is upper bounded by this
distribution journalization gap as well
and by the way just a disparate
vulnerability is simply the difference
between the subgroup vulnerabilities for
two subgroups so it is sufficient to
study subway vulnerability as an object
this concludes the theoretical part of
the talk and i would like to now discuss
some practical considerations about
measuring dispersed vulnerability
and i would like to start with the
curious observation that we had
we tried to measure disparity in cyber
vulnerability between two synthetic
groups we fixed the size of one majority
group and vary the size of the minority
group and then we ran some membership
inference attacks in the setup and what
is interesting the models that we were
attacking were kind of dummy models at
the training stage the training
algorithm of these models would take us
into the chain data set and just throw
it away and return the constant model
every time so the models that we were
attacking were independent of the data
and we did the strange experiment to
verify that vulnerability and disparity
and vulnerability for all such models
would be zero right because the models
have not really touched or used the data
they cannot be vulnerable to membership
inference
we ran three kinds of attacks i will
talk about them more in a bit and to our
surprise whereas for some attacks such
as average lost trash for attack and
general model attack the disparity was
around zero which is what we expected
for another attack which is a much more
powerful one the optimum was threshold
we saw statistically significant
non-zero disparity and this should not
happen because the models that we attack
have not used any data there can be
neither any membership influence
advantage nor any disparities in this
advantage
to understand what's happening here why
this is happening uh we first have to
discuss
different approaches to adversary to
model an adversary's knowledge in
membership inference
first approach
the shadow model or reference model
approach
here the adversary is assumed to know
the data distribution and the target
moral training algorithm with this
information the addresser can reproduce
some models that look kind of like the
target model
learn an attack on them and then deploy
the attack against the target
in the other approach which
i'm going to call worst case here the
adversary directly has access to some
information about the target model's
properties on the training data for
example in one such attacks the
adversary obtains the average loss on
the training data
in other attacks the recall optimum
threshold the adversary gets the
threshold on the loss that is actually
carefully chosen to distinguish train
loss values from test values
the danger of this approach of course is
that it goes a bit against the goal of
membership inference because in
membership and inference the adversary
wants to learn something about the
training data yet here the address
already starts with some non-trivial
information about that training data
however this enables us to estimate
worst case vulnerability which is a
standard practice and security
unfortunately it is inherently
problematic for estimating specifically
disparity in vulnerability
um this is because we want the
membership inference to exploit the
model's memorization behavior would
exploit the fact that the model behaves
differently on training examples and
test examples
with the worst case approach however
because the adversary has access to
non-trill information about the training
data of the target model there is
another source of information beyond
model memorization that we do not want
to capture
and it's the sampling bias which is the
fact that define it training data set is
always going to be somewhat different
from the actual
data distribution and this is what also
enables the addresses to think trading
uh to tell train examples from test
examples this bias depends on the size
of data and it vanishes pretty rapidly
except when we are deploying our attacks
on small subgroups of data for example
the subgroup of size 50 is something
that we saw in the literature and the
semolin bias definitely has an effect at
this scale as we see in the blood
thus if we measure disparity between two
subgroups using the worst-case approach
we will always see disparity if the
subgroups
differ in size so the measurement just
becomes meaningless and also misleading
to test the tax for this unwanted
property we propose the so-called
new model bias test which is exactly
what we did before evaluate attacks
against data independent models and if
we see any non-zero vulnerability then
the measurement of vulnerability is
biased and should not in general be used
to measure disparate vulnerability
should not be used to measure
regular vulnerability but as long as the
size of the data is big the the bias is
going to be negligible
so to be safe one should only use a tax
in which the adversary cannot access
anything about the training data when
building the attack as an exception our
experiments showed that the average loss
threshold that was not biased in
practice probably because just a single
average loss value is not sufficient to
bias the results
in the paper we also discussed some
other considerations one should take
when measuring disparate vulnerability
for example because the groups could be
small we want to use statistical tests
to make sure that the observed disparity
is not a fluke
we also apply methods to verify that we
can detect this vulnerability in
realistic settings and we do that with
high degree statistical significance
finally we'll also discuss how one can
prevent the spirit vulnerability we show
the differential privacy bounded and
that some algorithmic fairness
interventions can reduce it but only for
specific adversarial models so they are
not a valid defense
to sum up in this talk i briefly
outlined the following aspects of our
paper
first we have argued from a legal
standpoint that it is important to
evaluate disparate vulnerability across
demographic subgroups to avoid privacy
washing through aggregate metrics on the
theoretical side the worst case
vulnerability to membership inference is
characterized by distribution or
generalization so we showed that if poor
standard generalization is a sufficient
condition for membership influence
vulnerability or distributional
generalization is necessary and
sufficient
and then disparate vulnerability is
bonded by difference in subgroup level
distribution marginalization
finally on the practical side we argued
that one should not use attacks that
have non-trivial access to the training
data to measure desperate vulnerability
something that we have in the paper but
not much in the talk is that we should
use statistical procedures to establish
statistical significance and we
discussed various mitigation strategies
against dispersed vulnerability
this concludes the talk please check the
paper for more details and thank you for
your attention