hey everyone i'm anshuman from uva and
today i'll talk about a research on
distribution influence risks with my
advisor david evans and right before we
get started i'd like to show you figure
that captures the essence of our work
what you see on the x-axis here is alpha
and that's essentially the probability
of a particular attribute being true for
any given sample that you take from the
training distribution of a given machine
learning model and on the y-axis is the
mean square error of an adversary that
looks at the same model and then tries
to predict this alpha so let's say you
have face images then the alpha for
your specific scenario could be let's
say the probability of that person being
a female and this is what we'll vary in
these experiments
and
this quantity here n leaked is a measure
to look at the given model and setting
and try to quantify how much leakage
there is and what we see is
across all the data sets that we looked
at the leakage is quite non-trivial and
that's what most of the work is about
as part of our work we propose a general
definition for distribution inference
that allows us to come up with a metric
that helps measure the amount of leakage
in these cases
we also propose two new black box
attacks and perform systematic
evaluation of risk across different
properties and data sets and that's what
i'll be focusing on in today's talk
let's say you have some sort of
distribution of data from which you
sample some dataset d
the general pipeline in any such
computation is
you perform computation on the given
dataset and that generates an output so
if you were to draw a parallel with
machine learning the distribution would
be the underlying training distribution
the data set would be the training data
set and then the computation is training
a machine learning model which generates
the machine learning model in the output
itself
the most well-studied level of influence
risk granularity is data set inference
and the most popular example perhaps is
membership inference where you're given
a machine learning model and you're
trying to infer whether a particular
point
was part of the training data set or not
and there's tons of work in both in
terms of attacks defenses as well as
theoretical contributions
now coming over to the distribution
level things get slightly different
because the adversary no longer cares
about the particular dataset but the
underlying distribution from which that
data set for example
so let's say the adversary looks at the
machine learning model and wants to
infer whether the underlying
distribution had let's say more
green samples than red samples and that
is clearly a property of the
distribution because there are multiple
parts possible data sets from the
distribution that would satisfy the same
property and yet would output obviously
different data sets and consequently
different machine learning models
set this up as a cryptographic game
inspired by yom and all's work we start
off with this underlying natural
distribution d which is assumed to be
public and then we have these two
distribution transformation functions g
naught and g one
as a concrete example let's assume d is
the distribution of face images
available on the internet g naught could
be something that creates a distribution
from this distribution such that the
probability of something
a female or not a female is equally
likely whereas g1 is something that
results in the probability of sampling a
female as twice as likely as me let's
say
then what the victim does like any
standard cryptographic game is
samples
a random number between zero and one so
it's either zero or one and based on
that number it picks a training data set
from the underlying training
distributions and trains a machine
learning model m on it
and then the adversary's task is to look
at the model itself along with whatever
public information it has and try to
predict which of these two training
distributions the models training data
came from
and this is very different from a kind
of inference list that looks at the data
set level because this is no longer a
property of the particular data set the
adversary is not interested in this part
of the
whole setup it's interested in this part
of the setup so it really cares about
the distributions and the properties not
the exact data set
and of course
even though the adversary has access to
the victims model there's different
levels of access so the black box access
assumes standard public information that
is the distributions and the
transformation functions itself as well
as api access to the victim model so it
has access to the victim model and
whatever confidence values the victim
model generates for any given data
and for the white box setting the
adversary has of course full access to
the victim model that includes the
parameters architectures and all of that
now i'll describe one of the black box
attacks that we
proposed in our work
now this is a very straightforward test
and which we call the lost test and the
way this works is
the adversary starts with these two
distributions which is which it anyway
has public access to and it samples some
data from both of these distributions
and then let's say it has a given vector
model
it will perform inference on the first
set of data and take note of the
accuracy it observes
and then repeat the same thing for the
second set of data
and then follow a very straightforward
rule that essentially says that if the
accuracy observed for this model is
higher for
let's say data from the second
distribution then it's more likely that
the model was from the second
distribution
which is expected because after the two
possible distributions the one that it
was actually trained on data from it's
more likely to be better performing on
that and we do have another variant of
the black box test which we don't the
threshold test that involves another
step for training a threshold and that
performs slightly better than the last
test
here's a look at some of the results so
here we talk about experiments for the
census and boneage datasets the first
one is essentially looking at different
attributes for people and trying to
predict the income group and the second
one looks at hand x-ray images and
predicts the age group of a patient
and in these experimental settings we
said the first distribution
such that the probability of female in
these experiments is 0.5 so it's equally
likely to be a female or not and then
for the second distribution
the same probability said to alpha and
the alpha value is what we vary on the
x-axis here
and what we see is
the metaclassifier which is the whitebox
attack performs better than the black
box attacks understandably and the
second and more interesting point here
is that the influences seems to be
different for different data sets and
there's quite some variation as we'll
see in the future slides
and that is what we propose the end leak
term for and this is what you saw at the
very beginning of the presentation so
what this essentially means is
if you look at a particular attack and
the observed attack effectiveness
it's comparable to what the adversary
could learn if it could directly sample
n leaked samples from the underlying
distributions
so let's say an n leak value of 2 means
that the adversary had the capability to
sample two records from the underlying
distribution then
the best performance that it could get
is what you are seeing with the current
attack so naturally a higher value of n
leak for the same setting means that the
attack in that particular setting is
much leaking much more information
and what we see that even though for
most experiments this number is less
than two technically anything more than
zero is privacy leakage when the
property is not intended to be leaked
and this metric is useful for comparison
across different data sets properties
and experimental settings
as a concrete example consider this heat
map where we
instead of grading just one of the
distributions for the alpha values that
you saw a couple slides ago we vary both
of them one at the time and we plot
those on the x and y axis
on the top right triangle you see the
distinguishing accuracy and what we see
is as the distributions become more
divergent in the sense that the
difference in their alpha values
increases the distinguishing accuracy
also increases which is expected
while in reality the value of n leaked
shows us that this is not the case for
most cases
in fact the extremes are what leak more
information and everything else has n
leaked values of much less than one or
two
now all of the settings that we looked
at in the experiment so far consider
these different possible alpha values
and then we pick any two of them and
then we try to perform this binary kind
of distinguishing task
which is useful to try and understand
what the distribution inference risk is
but it's not very practical
the more
practically useful setting would be one
where the adversary could directly look
at the models and predict what the alpha
value would be
and we tried the setting for our data
sets and what we see here is that the
inference risk for direct regression is
much higher than classification so for
context the dashed gray line here is
what you would get for perfectly
predicting the x-axis is the actual
alpha values for the models that we test
on and the y-axis is what the attacks
predict
and what we see is that not only are the
metaclassifiers very successful
they don't over fit to the models that
they see so it's not the case that they
only perform well on the ratios that
they've seen in training they also seem
to generalize to ratios that they
haven't seen in the training at all
and this is further evident when we look
at the n league values for the
regression case so compared to the
classification case where most values
were less than two the values here can
go as high as 270 in specific for the
bone age data set which is quite high
there's still a lot of open questions in
the field of distribution inference
first of all there's no known good
defenses right now and even though there
are good candidates like differential
privacy and adversarial training which
might work out even though there's no
theoretical reason for them to our
empirical experiments show that there's
no hope for them and they actually don't
seem to work in any of the cases
next is trying to understand if there's
any trade-offs with distribution
influence and other kinds of inference
or even things like model generalization
and our initial experiments seem to
suggest that protecting against
distribution level inference attacks and
membership level inference attacks might
be at odds
and then further trying to understand
how differences in training processes
for these models can impact influence
risk
in summary machine learning models seem
to leak
unintended information about the
training distributions not just the
training data sets as we have known so
far and the factors that affect this
leakage are not very well understood
if you'd like to know more about our
work you can scan the qr code here and
here are the links to our paper and code
base thank you