good morning everyone my name is daniel
thais i am working for the institute for
internet security in gesenkee in germany
and today i will present you the paper
investigating gdpr fines in the light of
data flows
so first off let me give you a short
intro the gdpr is now over four years in
effect and while it surely impacted
businesses and customer related
processes all around the world we are
still well away from having privacy by
design or even complete data protection
management systems everywhere
often we focus just on the big players
like amazon facebook or google and while
they play a critical role as they have
tremendous amounts of users there are
still a lot of other institutions that
need to comply to the gdpr
by now we have over 1 200 imposed fines
and especially those violations to the
gdpr might give us the knowledge we need
to help institutions not just those that
have been fined but any to improve their
data protection management
so we wanted to look at the fines and
that is what we did in 856 cases
as we have a look into privacy
regulations we know finding privacy
preserving solutions for companies big
infrastructures and multiple interwoven
processes is not just a matter of
finding and applying a technical
solution like a software
instead it is an interdisciplinary task
that has to include yes the technical
aspects but also a wide range of
organizational challenges
this may include a redesign of an
existing system
as we obviously know there are at least
856 violations against the gdpr we want
to know what challenges did these
institutions face what did they wrong
but first off a quick note on related
work in this talk i just want to mention
that our paper relied on the enforcement
record by cms law
what they did was accumulating the files
imposed by the data protection
authorities
which resulted in a list of files with a
summary about what happened the
controller or processor the general type
of violation and a list of related
articles of the gdpr as well as some
metadata
so here is what we did we developed a
systemization scheme to categorize the
gdpr files of the enforcement trigger
for extended analysis
the scheme covers a detailed
categorization of the find issue why
dpas investigated it and whether the
issue was rooted in organizational or
technical problems
based on the data lifecycle model we
group the analyzed files into different
processing phases
and finally we analyze which gdpr
principles are commonly infringed in the
analyzed cases
we do so by performing a word frequency
analysis and manipulate stems to the
definitions given in article 4 of the
gdpr
so let me give you a short overview over
the data in about 3 years we have a
total sum of fines of around 1.8 billion
euro and as you can see amazon has a
huge share with about 40 percent
the mean lies around 2.1 million euro
and the lowest fine is in fact zero euro
now that we have our data we want a more
detailed coding on what was find aka the
violations
so we started an iterative coding
process based on the violations found in
the summary and the type of violation
that was given by the enforcement
tracker
let me give you an example for any case
starting with an insufficient
fulfillment of data subject rights we
refined the category to describe which
data subject rights were violated for
example the right to access or erasure
these refined categories give us more
information about why an institution has
been fined
rather than just a rough direction
here you see the distribution of
violations by the top level categories
we have the most common violation with
over 750 cases with the unauthorized
access followed by insufficient security
measures with just half as much
we even have almost 100 cases where
institutions failed to report a data
breach or to cooperate with a dpa and
more than 150 cases that failed to
accommodate the information obligations
set by the gdbr
as you already know we just analyzed 856
cases yet we have more than double the
violations so it's safe to say one
violation comes rarely alone
moreover 58 have an underlying technical
problem and about 79
can be related to issues in organization
so obviously we have an overlap of
technical and organizational issues
but how are these problems reflected in
fines although we have over 300 files
more related to organizational fines the
amount of files is about 25 percent
lower than for files of technical origin
we all wish our private data was not
leaked we want to say keep your secrets
but we already know that did not work so
let's have a look at the causes for
investigations
there are basically four groups that may
trigger an investigation one the data
controller two a third party that is
involved in handling of personal data
three a data subject and four any dpa
but most likely a local dpa
unfortunately we can reliably assign
only 29 of the violations to one of the
previously mentioned groups
data publication seems to be the reason
number one for investigations with a
share of 45 percent
moreover just 12 percent of the
investigations can be tracked back to a
report by the data controller
this low number may be an indicator to a
problem with the reporting requirements
as you remember unauthorized access and
insufficient security measures were the
most violated top level categories
here we have the most fined categories
although they may not be the only reason
for a fine
48 of all fights included processing of
personal data without legal basis
moreover 26 percent of all cases
included an unauthorized disclosure
which ranged from a disclosure to the
wrong person up to publicly distributing
data on websites
and last but definitely not least 21
percent of the fights included a failure
to fulfill data subject rights like
granting access to the processed
personal data
so let's head on to the data lifecycle
according to the abstract personal data
lifecycle model we have a total of 8
phases personal data can go through
these phases are initiation collection
retention access disclosure
usage review and destruction
we applied our codes respectively the
categories to these phases
let me give you an example
the initiation phase describes the
development of a processing plan which
includes the definition of the purpose
and how personal data is collected and
processed this is the phase where
privacy by design and default are
applied which is why we attributed the
categories privacy unfriendly design and
the privacy policy to this phase
according to our attribution the
collection phase holds the largest
number of files moreover this phase is
the only where we found more files being
rooted in organizational issues than
technical
in the retention access and usage phase
we identified a higher number of
technical issues compared to
organizational violations
but let's get into further detail with
word frequency analysis
we already know we have more technical
issues than organizational when it comes
to accessing personal data
thus following our word frequency
analysis of all fine summaries showed
access to be clearly the most frequent
world as it appeared 67 percent more
often than the second most frequent word
use
just a side note on the process of the
analysis we use word stamps like shown
here in order to ensure we catch the
meaning and don't build up piles of
words with the same meaning
so let's have a more in-depth look at
axis the two main issues that correlate
to axis are in fact that too much data
was disclosed
the problems here are that personal data
is accessible without any authentication
procedure in place as well as flawed
access management
moreover there are cases of unnecessary
access through third parties
on the other hand not enough data was
disclosed to be more precise access
relates to the failure to comply with
access requests by data subjects to
their personal data as well as an
insufficiently accessible privacy policy
or information regarding the processing
of personal data
our last step of analysis was to map the
word stems we extracted to the
definitions in article 4 of the gdpr
and i would like to share some of the
interesting findings with you here
for restriction we have found adequate
appropriate and sufficient respectively
the word stems which indicate the fined
institutions tried to fulfill the
requirements but were not able to
for controller we have found enough
occasions of vodafone to be listed
individually as opposed to more general
terms like bank or
hospital speaking of hospital we found
at least 18 percent of personal data to
be attributed to the well-being of an
individual which exceeds the most
frequent word stem name by two percent
to end this presentation i would like to
give you our conclusions
the dpas issue most fines for reason of
an organizational origin
we revealed area of cooperative research
security and legal as 409 fines are
related to processing data without a
legal basis
moreover there is a need for rigorous
data protection management and privacy
by design
we also showed that a high number of
files is attributed to the early phases
of data processing which indicates
widespread data processing issues
finally many violations are related to
issues in access control management
there is a need for refined
organizational processes and continuous
monitoring to avoid unwanted data
disclosures
if you have questions feel free to ask
them here or after the session stay safe
and thank you very much