hello i'm kanov today i'll be presenting
lama a low latency math library for
secure influence this is a joint work
with deepak kumaraswamy nishan chandan
and
let's understand the problem of secure
secure inference
a server starts with a model m and
private weights w and the client starts
with the model input x
we want the client to only learn the
inference output m of w comma x while
the server learns nothing about x this
problem can be solved using
cryptographic technique of secure
computation or more specifically
two-party secure computation to pc for
short there has been much work on
improving the efficiency of these
protocols recently
the biggest bottleneck towards that
option of secure inference protocols is
the high communication cost associated
with them
consider a simple seven layer cnn
oversafe art and data set as an example
even for this very simple model crypt
flow to the current state of the 2pc cnn
inference library costs 340 mb of total
communication 10 seconds of runtime in
345 communication rounds
delphi focuses on moving the bulk of
total communication cost to the input
independent offline phase this model
also known as pre-processing model is
very interesting as the parties can
pre-compute and store some input
independent key material beforehand and
when they have their inputs ready they
can perform inference faster
even then delphi communicates 196 mb in
the online phase in 2.7 seconds of
runtime
furthermore consider an example of rnn
on google 30 dataset here the situation
is even worse due to mathematical
functions like sigmoid and 10h which are
expensive to calculate securely
siren the current state-of-the-art
inference library with support for such
precise math functions
communicates 415 mb of total data and
runs in 37 seconds in nearly 60 000
nodes
in our work lama we use a technique of
function secret sharing to reduce the
online cost in the pre-processing model
we achieve up to 48 x reduction in
communication and runs 19x faster in
these examples
let me draw out the structure of the
talk first
we start with the brief description of
function secret sharing and 2pc using
function secret sharing
then we discuss the drawbacks of
existing works and how lama addresses
those
we start the technical part of our talk
with bit with changing gates then we
discuss how we create protocols for
mathematical functions using spline
approximations
finally we discuss the benchmarks we ran
using lama and how it compares with
other works
fss was introduced in 2015 by the work
of boyle gilboa and ishai
it allows a dealer to split a function f
into two functions f 0 and f 1 such that
when applied to the same input x the two
functions return secret shares of f x
the security requirement states that
each of the f 0 and f 1 hides f
these f 0 and f 1 are called fss keys
for this to be practical these keys
should be also compact in size
in 2019 boyle gilboa nhi provided a way
to realize 2 pc interested dealer model
using fss in this the dealer provide
input independent correlated randomness
to the two parties this dealer can also
be emulated as an expensive two pc
then using this key material round and
online communication optimal protocols
for many functionalities are known due
to previous works
these functionalities are called fss
gates
each fss gate costs online communication
of two times the output bit length of
the functionality that is each property
sends an output element to the other one
in just a single round
there are number of works on secure
computation using fss like bj 19 and bcg
plus 21. ariane is a work which
considered the problem of secure
inference using fss but these existing
fss based solution had some drawbacks
first all of them lacked support for
precise math functions like sigmoid and
h as we saw rnns make heavy use of these
functions and to support them we need
protocols to securely evaluate this math
function due to transcendental nature of
these functions exact evaluation is not
possible in finite bit width and error
bound is measured in terms of alps error
there are some works in secure inference
which like secure ml which provide math
functions but they suffer from high alps
error
repeated use of these high error
implementations can lead to wrong output
with a large probability
second most existing mpc frameworks
don't support mixed bit with operations
while most ml models perform inference
on floating point numbers mpc frameworks
operate on fixed point numbers
existing state of the art flow to fixed
quantizers like shift tree and
tensorflow lite use low bit width fixed
point representations for efficiency
reasons
simple computations like multiplication
required increased bit width of the
intermediate output variable to prevent
overflows without support for mixed bit
width operations the existing wave works
are forced to operate on higher bit
width resulting in bad performance
finally the only prior fss based secure
inference library aryan uses protocols
for relu and truncation that are only
probabilistically correct since the
error is inversely proportional to the
bit with use they are forced to use
higher bit width also as the number of
relu and truncation increases the
probability of overall computation being
incorrect increases
in lama we address all these drawbacks
first lama supports precise computation
over low between inputs by supporting
mixed bit with operations to calculate
intermediate variables in higher bit
width
second we provide a low bit width spline
approximation for math functions with a
maximum error of 4 alps and provide fss
protocols for these
third unlike aryan our protocols for
railway and truncation are correct
lower comparisons are taken from the
previous work of bcg plus 21 and we use
them to build secure protocols for
maximal average pool and arc banks
finally we integrate lama as a
cryptographic backend to easy pc
creating a complete end-to-end infill
system
distributed comparison function
abbreviated dcf is a very fundamental fs
scheme to perform comparisons here the
function returns beta when x is less
than alpha and 0 otherwise
the fss key for dcf hides these alpha
and beta parameters we call this fss key
dcf key
bcg plus 21 provided an optimized
construction for dcf
we start our technical discussion with a
brief description of bit with changing
fss gates as the name suggests they
change the bit width and scale of fixed
point numbers
first we have an extension gate which
increases the bit width over number
second we have a truncate reduce gate
which reduces both the scale and bit
width of the number both of them need
one dcf key and since they are fss gates
they take one round of communication
as we saw earlier we need math functions
like sigmoid and tan a to support rns
siren the state of the art prior work
which support precise math functions
uses gold smith's iteration to estimate
this function
but this approach is not ideal in
emphasis as it would require a round for
each iteration our first design choice
is to use piecewise polynomial also
known as splines
approximation as we have fss gate for it
due to previous work let's understand
how the evaluation of splines work
consider a six piece line as shown we
want to evaluate input x on this spline
we first find the spline interval in
which x lies and fetch the corresponding
polynomial coefficients this step
requires comparisons
and then we simply apply this polynomial
to the input x this step requires
multiplications
bcg plus 21 divides an fss gate for
uniform bit spline which means that all
input and output numbers and all the
intermediate
operations happen in the same bit width
they were able to achieve this in using
a single dcf key
but suppose we want to apply spline on a
low bit with input
if we use the spline of the same old bit
width we fear overflows due to
multiplications which would eventually
lead to high alps error in math
functions
using spline of bit with just enough to
prevent overflows is bad as well because
it leads to high key size and large
runtime
hence we need mix between splines where
the intermediate multiplications haven't
happen over large bit width through
prevent overflows
now to quickly devise a protocol for
mixed bit with spline one could use fss
gate for extension to extend the input
value to bit width just enough to
prevent overloads
and then pass this extended value to the
uniform bit with spline from bcg plus 21
and finally adjust the output to decide
bit width and scale using truncation
this serves as a good starting point on
which we now present two optimizations
our first optimization is based on the
observation that the coefficient finding
step does not need to
the input to be signed extended
comparisons can be done in original
smaller bit width
so we pass the original smaller bit with
input in the coefficient finding part
and use the sign expanded input only in
the polynomial evaluation hence we
reduce the dcf key size
in case of sigmoid this leads to forex
reduction in key size
our second optimization is based on the
observation that most of the output of
dcf evaluation in the splined protocol
it discarded and only some part of it is
used
here is the original protocol for
uniform between spline from bcg plus 21.
to quickly verify this claim observe
that we are generating m squared values
here above while we use only 2m of these
values here
here m denotes the number of intervals
in the spline
to prevent this wastage we found a way
to partially evaluate dcf leading to
reduction of prg calls by a factor
roughly of m by 2. in sigmoid this
factor is roughly equal to 10x the best
part of all this
is that both of these optimizations are
composable with each other overall we
get a forex reduction in key size 4x
reduction in dealer prg cost and 40x
reduction in evaluated prg costs in
sigmoid
we also propose many fss protocols for
functionalities in inference like
convolution relu and max pool but we
skipped that discussion due to shortage
of time
we evaluated lama on a number of
benchmarks and compared with existing
works we ran these benchmarks on both
lan and van setting we present some of
those numbers here in lan setting
we compared the fast grnn model on
google 30 dataset with siren and observe
48x less communication 19x less runtime
and 22x less communication rounds
we compared our work with delphi which
focused on online offline split on a
simple 7 layer cnn we observed 23x less
communication and 5x less runtime
finally we compare with aryan on
resnet18 model on hymanoptera dataset
note that we don't have math functions
in this benchmark
here even in the presence of correct
relevant truncation protocols in lama we
achieved 3x less communication in 1.7x
less runtime we attribute this
improvement due to relu being a two
round protocol in arya compared to an
fss gate in llama
this marks the end of matter in
conclusion lama proposes an fsf-based
solution to the 2pc secure inference
problem in pre-processing model
while lama aims to reduce the online
complexity it remains an interesting
problem to reduce the large offline
communication cost mainly due to large
dcf key size
reducing the size of dcf keys can be an
interesting problem with impact greater
than just secure influence
thank you