hello everyone I'm glad to present our
paper Machinery with differentially
private labels mechanism and Frameworks
this is the joint work with my amazing
collaborators from Princeton University
and UMass Amherst first let me introduce
a definition of Naval differential
privacy we call a randomized mechanism M
with domain D which includes three
feature set acts and labels it y to
preserve apps on digital label DP if the
probability of outputs for any two label
laboring data sets are similar here is
an example of the label labor data sets
where we can say that the fission sets
here are all the same while there is one
label by three difference in a label set
We Now understand what is labeled DP the
next question is why do we study labeled
EP label DP fits for several practical
scenarios will feature the public or
labels to be keep private one example is
ADS ranking while the ad attack notes as
content delivered to the user which can
be regarded as public feature however
the user's interaction with as content
should be kept private another example
is some sensitive survey which may ask
questions about income or medical
history in the meanwhile the profile of
the participants such as gender or race
might be public
as label DP only request label to be
privileged we understand that if a
mechanism ends preserves absolute RDP
then it also preserves Epsilon digital
label DP therefore we can use current DB
techniques such as dpsgd to achieve
labeled AP the problem is that dpsgd may
suffer from a loss of utility
as labeldp is a much more relaxed form
of privacy where only label its private
the key question will ask in this work
is how can optimized utility with this
relaxed privacy restriction
all work on labeldp focus on how to
improve the utility specifically our key
insights are true false first we can
leverage the public feature information
to deny the travel labels second we will
also leverage the most recent
advancements in machine learning to
further improve the utility all
Frameworks leverage on supervised
learning semi-supervised learning and
learning with noise Mabel techniques to
add less noise and also reduce the
effect of noise besides we also make a
comprehensive comparison with existing
works and also make a specific
recommendations regarding our framework
one good property for differential
privacy is proofs processing and this
also holds for label DP that is if a
mechanism and plan which was domain on
the labels is y and also ranging y such
as on digital dpny which also implies
label DP not for any other mechanism and
which take X and M Prime y as input will
also satisfy the epsilometers are
labeled AP based on existing works on
how to generate the differential travel
labels we can proceed to focus on how to
improve utility we use two existing
differential probability label
generation one is a randomized response
which probability replace a true label
with a random label the second one is
party effects match which is the
variation of the part A framework
love as a label DP allows the feature to
be public the partifix match will use
the same public feature to clear the
teacher model and train the student
model
same as part A Part FX match also
benefits from the flexible number
queries of the Privacy to the trade-off
that has low low fuel queries the lower
absolute law particular Flex match is
used as one of our pipeline which is
pipeline three I will if I will
introduce the python 1 to intellect
slides to generate the differential
private labels on the whole training set
by Patrick fixed match we will query the
student model to generate such labels
our first pipeline is based solely on
unsupervised learning which can add less
noise compared to a directly added noise
to the individual Sample When thinking
of the labor privacy an easy approach to
protect the privacy of sensitive label
is to not use them at all therefore we
consider clustery after the clustery we
still need to assign the label for
clusters so we still need some label
information we propose a noise classic
which adds a gaussian noise to the class
count for each cluster on the two labels
and then does the majority voting here
is an example of the two classes space
where all the points here are with a
true label that is the Blue Points our
true label blue and the red points are
with the true label red after the
unsupervised learning we have two
classes while cluster one has most blue
points and cluster 2 has most red points
let's look at a potential two
we know the county in cluster 2 for red
versus blue is 18 versus three although
soon as the gaussian noise to this
country after the majority voting of the
gaussian noise content we can get
success label for each cluster as the
cluster 2 has the most red points the
majority voting of the gaussian noise
content is likely to be the majority
voting on The Noise free Counting
here is an overview of our pipeline one
we refers to the unsupervised learning
to get the classroom model within
generated classes and after that we will
apply our noise class algorithm to
assign a class label on the cluster
model and get a final Model F
during this process no noise is added to
individual sample and after unsupervised
learning no learning process is further
need
our second pipeline focus on how to
reduce the effect of noise based on
existing advancements in machine
learning the noise cluster has a
limitation that its performance is
bottlenecked by unsupervised learning
that is even my Epsilon is very high and
gives almost a true label at private
label set the noise cluster will still
have the same performance as
unsupervised learning
we proposed dinos SSL which combines
unsupervised learning and semi surprise
learning our strategy is that we will
only select samples which have SIM noise
label and pseudo label the noise label
is either by randomized response or part
FX match under suitable is by the
majority voting on accounts of noise
level set for clustering and no extra
noise is added in this process
here is an example the points in this
blue point in this blue area are always
a true label blue and the blue point
indicate that there was two label while
the red points indicate that there was a
noise level red we also had a pseudo
label set with by the classroom which
means I'm most points as blue but still
zero as red due to the performance of
clustering by comparing the noise level
set and the pseudo label search we can
find the mismatch in this set and we
will remove the three mismatch points we
can see that compared to the noise label
set the output of the denoising is a
smaller label set but with a higher
position as we still have the full
public feature set we will consider
semi-supervised learning
besides the noise SSO we will also
consider directly leveraging risk and
advancements in machine learning beyond
the standard optimization
we consider ldp SSL which directly
applies the music provides learning on
the whole training set specifically we
will use fixed match we also consider
ldpl which will barely take a use
techniques from the learning with noise
label techniques this is because on
moderners can learn more label
information during the training process
and learning with noise level techniques
can leverage such labor information
specifically we will use organisms
here is an overview of our pipeline too
we will generate the private labels by
either by randomized response or
partifix match we will also do
unsupervised learning to generate the
Clusters and then generate the pseudo
label after that we will train the
Machinery models under label
differential privacy either by standard
optimization semi-supervised learning or
learning with noise label techniques or
our denois SSO
we conduct our experiments on three
Benchmark data sets for image
classification see if I turn c500 and
significant the number of classes vary
from 10 to 100 and the total number of
images vary from sixty thousand to two
hundred and seventeen thousand
will consider models including 2018 with
gg16 and wireless network 28 and 4.
the first evaluate of python 1 notes
cluster where we can say that the noise
cluster performs well at small Epsilon
for example on safer turn even Epsilon
is equal to
0.003 while the randomized response only
gives the label arches a 10.03 percent
which is too close to totally random the
noise cluster can still have the high
performance as 88.3 percent
and this is also true for 700 and
signature
the next value of the dinos SSO and ldps
so in our pipeline too so here we
compare the noise cluster and you know
Dino's SSO and ldb has also combined
with randomized response we can see that
while the noise cluster keeps the same
performance at all reported Epsilon
which is 88.3 percent Latino's assets
both adenos SSO and ldps so increase the
performance as absolute increases
besides though do you know says so is
always has a better performance Compared
to North class at all reported Epsilon
and ldp I say so it's better than noise
classes at Epsilon equal to 4.
as for the pathway effect match as our
pipeline three we can uh we can compare
we can see that compared to randomized
response but combined with the noise SSO
and ldpsso the pathfx match is always
better than these two approaches on a
randomized response this is because the
Pacific's match will benefit from the
choice of flexible number of queries to
add less noise
we next evaluates the RDP artisans in
your pipeline too which is the newest
noise label techniques so here we
consider the randomized response or
partifix match combined with best
performance of other approaches or the
rdpr distance we can see that a DP
organism performs well in most cases
except for Epsilon equal to 0.5 by
randomized response besides when Epsilon
is low low oil is lower the best
accuracy is filed from the Pacific's
match combined with ldb August or
descent this is because the party fixed
match can provide the label set with
higher accuracy one lab or absolutely is
high the best accuracy is from the
randomized response combined with ldp
Arc distance this is this is because
runway's response can provide more label
information
we also make a comparison with existing
works and we can uh with uh which is
Alaba and lp1c random trial we can see
that our work is better than The Alibi
and rp1sc at all reported Epsilon
besides we can also observe that the
utility of of advantage of our work
decreases as absolute increases not at
Epsilon equal to 4 the utility Advantage
is still significant for more
experimental results please take Cloud
paper
we finally make recommendations on how
to maximize the utility of our framework
when Epsilon is extremely low please
consider noise cluster if a bounded
Computer Resources is available and with
a high label credit earned and a low
Epsilon please consider party effects
match without above specific conditions
choosing randomized response can make
sense simpler specifically when absolute
is high you can directly use standard
optimization and randomized response
already get the label set of high
accuracy well Epsilon is low you can
consider denoise algorithms such as the
noise SSO or oxycinct to reduce effect
of noise
that's all thank you for listening