hi everyone i am jin today we are going
to talk about an slk on the topic of te
assisted confidential smart contract in
this work we will explore plenty of
existing related literature and in
production projects
specifically our work includes the
following contents we first introduced
the concept of de-assisted confidential
smart contracts we then propose our
evaluation from work to give a
high-level view of this work
we evaluate both the desirable
properties for the smart contractor
services and the potential issues for
the blockchain system lastly we point
out the research challenges and give
some research insights
the smart contractor is a computer
program stored on a blockchain and
running in a distributed network the
contract has two major properties of
automatic execution and non-impulcation
automatic execution means a smart
contract can force one entity to execute
operations based on predefined logic
non-equivocation means each distributed
nodes can hold a global view of the
state at a specific height supporting
more efficient settlement
however using smart contracts still
confront many challenges
the most identical drawback is the lack
of confidentiality
the operation code and the contracted
state are completely transparent and any
state and exchanges are publicly
accessible and observable
for instance smart contracts in ethereum
cannot be directly applied to the volume
to applications which is the
victory auction and the voting
application the bid and the vote
required to be hidden from the public
but this cannot be realized for
transparent on-chain smart contracts
different from the conventional smart
contract a confidential smart contractor
aims to help the contractor state so
that the public cannot see any useful
knowledge of the states
currently many technical privacy
preserving solutions have been proposed
such as the techniques of their
knowledge proof multiparty computation
and homomorphic encryption
however the solution requires an
increasing of computation complexity
making executions run slowly
in this work we focus on the trusted
execution environment technique which is
short for the tee
tee can protect the data in use by
performing computation in a hardware
based environment there are four major
features in te namely the confidential
execution sitting technology local
attestation and the remote attestation
we introduced the notion of te assisted
confidential smart contracts it combines
the hardware basically to existing
blockchain architecture especially in
its storage layer
the participants will equip the te into
their operating nodes ensuring every
input output and execution can be
physically sealed
although various tcsa protocols have
been proposed newly released projects
may fail to draw upon the experience
learned from existing protocols such as
repeating known design mistakes or
applying cryptography in unsecured ways
we in this paper aim to
obstruct a high-level framework to
simply and clearly systemize the
knowledge on current tcs6 schemes
we attempt to capture some comments
among this project regarding their
features properties and the potential
security vulnerabilities
here we introduced our unified
evaluation framework we consider two
parts the smart contractor used as
services and the underlying supporting
blockchain systems
based on their operating mechanisms and
the ways of combination will investigate
and the category
set off typical protocols into two main
classifications the layer 1 solutions
and the layer 2 solutions the framework
covers corresponding to a specs
desirable properties for contracted
services and the security consideration
for underlying systems specifically we
discuss the desirable properties from
typical properties that inherit from the
traditional smart contracts and the
featured privacy related properties
meanwhile we emphasize practical issues
pitfalls and the remedies in designing
te assisted blockchains
before diving into specific evaluations
we provide a lighting tour of how a
typical confidential smart contractor
operates
totally four steps i included
loading the inputs into the contractor
engine
computation inside the te
conducting consensus and returns the
outputs we classify current solutions
into lyra and layer 2 by investigating
whether the step 2 or step 3 are
accepted within the same pe
for layer run solutions all the
operations are operated within the same
te whereas for the layer 2 solutions
step 2 and step 3 are separate but still
within the same note
here we present our identified details
in terms of desirable properties we
evaluate each tcsc system from two
aspects mainly from its privacy
preserving property and the blockchain
intrinsic feature
the privacy preserving properties
include specification hidden input
output privacy
procedure privacy and the address and
linkability and the anonymity
the blockchain intrinsic feature
contains the immutability consistency
interoperability availability
decentralization automation
reliability and some specific mechanisms
as for the security consideration we
give out discussions from the following
aspects in terms of ote components t
hosts the security for punishment and
the incentive mechanisms and for
tolerance and
authentication this mainly targets on
the holster level
t security for each sub components
attestation memory timer and related
physical attacks this mainly targets on
t hardware
key program security for workload
measurements flow detection
priority restriction and the chain data
confirmation and the output conflicts
this mainly targets on the code level
t key security for distributed case key
rotation protocols independent
contractor key and the independent de
keys is mainly targeted on the key level
based on our evaluation framework we
provide detailed evaluation results
towards 17 in the world projects
we analyze each of them with our
evaluation matrix and summarize the
altitude with two large tables
here we give a very concise version to
compare the features of both layer 1
solution and layer 2 solution layer 1
solutions are mainly built on the top of
consortium blockchains where the layer 2
solutions are based on the public
blockchains the layer 1 solutions are
good idea is system availability and the
layer 2 solutions for performance will
add the scalability
lastly we point out the research
challenges of tcsc protocols we give
three types of disadvantages existing in
the current systems
the sad channel attack is inevitable
because all types of tea suffer from
such attacks this cannot be
avoided by the software
the key management designer refers to
two specs
firstly putting the application keys in
a single te
will contribute to the key security but
also increase the risk of single point
failure attack
secondly sharing the private key among
multiple tests offer
practical availability but increases the
key as filtration risk
the third issue is the transparency
various
the precise architectures of chips are
still unclear for some tea products
meanwhile the attestation survey is used
to prove that a program runs inside tea
is non-transparent
finally we summarize this work as
follows
we provided a systemization of existing
tcsc systems driven from academic work
and in production projects
we established a unified evaluation
framework for confidential smart
contractor systems we consider two parts
the smart contractor used as services
and the underlying supportive blockchain
systems
we conduct a comparative analysis of
existing protocols based on our
evaluation framework we discuss the
systems
both from the their common designs and
the distinguishing features
we further give a comprehensive
discussion of current designs and
implementations comparisons between the
layer 1 and layer 2 systems from the
perspective of security
efficiency and easy adoption and the
common issues on
public variability we also point out the
research challenges in this field
here are the references used in this
work
we stand for your listening