good morning and welcome uh my name is
rod dusan i'm a professor in stony brook
uh this is joint work uh and actually
primarily the work of my students chen
chen
and xiao liang has also contributed uh
bogdan corbin is one of our
collaborators he's in florida
international university
um so in today's talk this is this is an
sok paper and it refers to this thing
called plasma ability and the problem
i'm facing with this is that it's just
not easy to describe the whole that's
okay a whole is okay paper in in 12
minutes
so my goal today would i would be happy
if we all go home understanding a little
more about plausibility ability and some
of the challenges that are faced here
i'm not going to use too many greek
letters here and i'm not going to talk
about proofs or security models or other
things just not enough time to do that
i'm just gonna try to focus on you know
getting you the essentials uh to to get
a little bit of info on this field
so let's see what's going on here so
what's the problem why do we need this
new thing what is this new thing well
the problem is this right you have
encryption
and use encryption for data privacy and
and the problem that happens right now
is that increasingly governments realize
that encryption is very very powerful as
a tool in protecting yourself and so
then there's increasing anti-encryption
laws in addition to oppressive
governments you see this in in western
governments like the uk government the
australian government the uh there's
hundreds and hundreds of examples where
courts have compelled disclosure and and
laws are enacted that are supposed to uh
you know protect the children but at the
end of the day weaken
significantly the uh the
infrastructure the backbone of privacy
uh uh techniques and tools such as
encryption
and so now the problem is uh what are
you is is there something you can do
about this
and plosive reliability aims to provide
an answer to that and the general idea
here would be uh that
you know when people try when people
have coercive power over you so let's
imagine you have a device here and on
this device you have some data so here's
your data and this this data is
encrypted with some key right and so
what happens is somebody can coerce you
to provide this key uh so here's your
your oppressive government or your bad
guy and and
now you you're being asked for this key
and so you have to provide this key k
right and so the general idea behind
plausibility would be to build a
mechanism that allows you to still
uh respond to such rubber hose attacks
gracefully and
yes disclose key k and so on and
potentially you know potentially
fighting it a little bit and so on but
at the end of the day also allow
yourself to additionally uh
hide uh additional information i'm
talking about plus my ability for
storage deployed my ability has a bigger
story that has to do with with plausibly
denying actions or interactions or other
things i'm talking about storage right
now so you're going to have the ability
to also have some hidden data here
hidden data
and you're going to be able to somehow
store this hidden data on the same
device
and
while still being able to plausibly deny
that you actually have this hidden data
and so now uh and usually what you're
going to do is you're going to encrypt
this hidden data with another key with a
different key that you're not going to
you're not going to reveal to the to the
bad guy
and so basically what you're trying to
achieve here is the ability to still get
privacy guarantees potentially through
encryption somehow while at the same
time being able to be responsive to
rubber hose slash coercive attacks
that's the general idea of plasma
ability in the context of storage
and and the problem we're facing with so
and there's a bunch of challenges here
that are gonna that that are we're gonna
have to deal with so what let's look a
little bit at the adversary so what can
the adversary do if you want to build
systems like this uh you have to think
of the adversary obviously so obviously
the adversary knows the damage system
all right so we're not doing secure web
security uh the adversary can access the
device
and this is a key point once or multiple
times and we'll see where that becomes
important the adversity can coerce this
closure of secrets we already discussed
that
the adversity can question the very
reason for using the uh the the
plausibly deniable capable system and
this is a problem we'll see how
we actually we're not going to see this
but this is one of the things we
discussed in this case how can we uh
deny how can we provide a reason for
using the actual pd system why are using
the system that also provides political
ability you're suspect you can't
convince me that you're not having
hidden data using the system asp.net oh
well my system also allows me to encrypt
data okay great but is that enough and
can you do better than that
and then uh but the adversary is assumed
reasonably so to be computationally
bounded obviously to be rational this is
an important one meaning that okay if
the adversary cannot prove the existence
of unrevealed data
or if you sufficiently convince the
adversary that there's plausible reasons
for for for using this device and for
responding to to a rubber hose attack
there's no further coercion so this
rationality will play out differently in
different scenarios
um
and then very often the adversary is
assumed not to have access to runtime
system state because otherwise uh you're
you're building you're fighting against
against god and you can't fight against
god so the adversary can be there on
your shoulder 24 7 looking at everything
that you do
it's going to be very difficult to build
any system where you can still hide
information and use that information
meaningfully while the adversity sits on
your shoulder even though in certain
cases that's possible so so these are
some of the important
uh uh
some of the important things that the
adversary that you have to consider when
you're looking at adversary in this
context and so now let's see what people
came up with so i'm going to show you a
thing that's called truecrypt you i
suspect most of you guys may be familiar
with truecrypt or many of you are if not
here it is as a 10 second summary on
truecrypt so truecrypt is one of these
systems is very cool it disappeared now
basically uh there's a bunch of uh uh
forks of it uh the the original team
disappeared under a very suspicious
circumstances i mean they disappeared
but they stopped working on it and the
idea of a trick group is this right you
have some device this is your your disk
and on this disk you have a bunch of
volumes these are your your public
volumes
uh public volume
uh another public volume
um and
and and when you're being coerced by the
by the by the bad guy you can provide
these things are encrypted obviously you
kind of provide
some encryption keys that you use for
these uh public volumes so so there's
some encryption here and there's some
more encryption here
with the other key right and that's all
fine and then so you can respond to a
coercive attack and then however
crucially what truecrypt does is says
hey look at all this free space here uh
why don't we store something in this
free space why don't we hide a volume
here
uh this is going to be something like an
encryption with some hidden uh and and
randomized so i'm going to have a random
number there and my data so this is
going to be the the the randomized
volume that i'm storing here and i'm not
gonna provide this key to to the bad guy
so this is what truecrypt does the
problem obvious problem with this and
many problems but one of the obvious
problems is wait a second if the bad guy
can see my device multiple times we
discuss that this is one of the things
the adversary can do
it may see that this region here is
supposed to be three has changed despite
uh the fact that there's no changes in
the public volumes at all and so that
alone will reveal the fact that there's
something hidden here so truecrypt does
not survive
uh truecrypt survived a thing called a
single snapshot single snapshot
adversary
but does not survive a multi-snapshot
multi-snapshot adversary right
and so there's been a lot of work
in people building systems for
multi-snapshot adversaries and so so now
this brings us to some of the challenges
that have to do with plasma and ability
right so here's a couple of the
challenges uh security efficiency
trade-offs exist all over the place uh
in anything you build in security
obviously but in this case specifically
one of the main trade-offs has to do
with single snapshot versus
multi-snapshot single snapshots are
usually fast
but your security is not very good
again why is this important well because
you cross the border three times the
adversary can see your device three
times or you leave your device in the
hotel room
it is encrypted so the adversity cannot
see the data but it could start breaking
your placement deniability mechanisms if
you'd want to do multi-snapshot you get
better security but you're much slower
you either rely on right-only orm as
you'll see in the paper or you have to
make all kinds of assumptions or relax
security requirements and that's that's
not uh as good
then you have a dependency on system
layers most of the
most of the existing work out there
builds flows my ability in some layer
out there oh this is my file system it's
it's possible great but then they the
the assumptions are that the underlying
sys the underlying layers behave
properly and
uh in in a way that supports this and
that's very rarely the case the typical
example is an ssd if you have uh you
build a software block device on top of
it or or you build a file system on top
of
some block device on top of an ssd and
then you assume that the ssd for example
honors an erase you say hey delete this
block why because later you want to
guarantee that the snapshot does not
include that block in that form or
whatever and you're assuming ssd will do
that for you but unfortunately as you
know because we're leveling a million of
things the ssd does not do that for you
and in fact it may keep that data lying
around so if you open up the ssd and
start reading eprom chips you can start
seeing all your transcripts and
everything else you wrote before
effectively breaking anything you've
done at this upper layer so you have to
be aware of this multi-systems layer
story and solve it you can't just say
i'm going to give you a plus an enable
file system when the underlying block
device will keep traces of everything
you've ever written
so you can't do that and we have to
solve that and we show
directions and ideas on how to solve
that and we're providing a general story
for that uh in in the paper and then
there's a lack of unified security
framework what that means is everybody
and their grandmother comes up with some
new ways of defining how secure their
stuff is which is usually what happens
in our community and and the problem is
it's very hard to compare things both
from a security point of view and also
from efficiency point of view because
mind you when you pay a lot for security
uh in security for a performance
trade-off you're going to get a very
efficient system
but it's going to have security and
vice versa
so here are some of the contributions of
the slk paper and again we don't have
time to dive deep but we're happy to you
know please do read the paper and if you
if you're thinking of building plasma
ability using an existing system into
something that you build in a broader
system or you want to build your own
plot-deniable system you have some ideas
don't be shy please reach out so some
contributions have to do with we're
addressing the pencil system layers so
in this sok period we're not only
summarizing what happens out there but
we're also saying
uh can you address this dependency and
we're providing this trace-oriented
security
which basically says
you have to look at the full transcript
throughout all the layers
anything that ever moves on this device
has to be part of the trace
and based on that trace you define what
trace oriented security defined security
game that defines what security means
here it's a meaningful security game
that actually can you can use to prove
things and disprove things about
existing system but we we show that it
comes at the price equivalence to wrm
very slow we address the lack of unified
security framework so we build a unified
security framework that has flexibility
to capture a lot of stuff existing stuff
and new stuff and allows you to compare
things we provide you additional
insights how to achieve what is called
invisibility uh how to
hide data uh how to hide access patterns
to hidden data and also what other
future directions uh some people are
working on uh or you may want to work on
uh this is basically it i'm i'm at the
end of my 12 minutes if you want to
reach out please reach out to rgxr.io
or some any of
us you can you also have the full
version of the paper which is larger
online thank you very much and hope you
got something out of this