so here to talk about a relatively
significant project we've gone through
at links on our land to network who
deployed as hinted by the title an open
networking disaggregated solution so a
little bit of a background on the
project we actually run two networks in
London as part of the London internet
exchange we had the one we call LAN one
which is a Reuter base traditional Cisco
Nokia juniper style solution running
VPLS and run to which at the time was
using layer 2 technology not quite
spanning tree ring protection but that
generation of technology using a
traditional layer 2 vendor we actually
had attempted to move lund to two VPLS
but we were hadn't quite succeeded then
going back to 2015 there seemed to be a
tipping point where the bulk of the
order stopped being at 10 gigs and
appeared at a hundred gigs and we could
see that we needed to do a change in
particular on to with that extra uptick
and also the core was going to need to
adapt to it as well even if we didn't
change vendor something needed to be
done and so we decided we didn't just do
a vendor selection we didn't want to do
a like-for-like replacement and we
started talking to strategy options what
can we do and that was very much the
steer I got from senior management take
it as a open book and we've looked all
the way from a second traditional route
a vendor to something that's new what
was at that time the new innovative idea
of doing
open networking and disaggregated and as
you can guess from the subject of the
presentation it was a second actually an
interesting bit of history it was
actually in San Francisco at and I know
we often combine that knowledge talking
to our local us vendors as the existing
land to vendor communicated that as it
stood with their strategy there wasn't
an overlap so we actually knew at that
stage that we were with a new vendor so
we look for the best strategy it wasn't
I'm still working it wasn't just a
traditional select something off the
shelf except for the less free vendors
as number of requirements that ixps
don't just work i've cover more detail
on that but having taken all the
strategies what we actually then did
because membership led is go toward our
members those in Europe and London we
visited then but then at 66 down in San
Diego we took the opportunity of quite a
few of our members actually being in the
same building to actually talk to them
direct so I said it and we had a couple
of things that are different the first
one if you're care you know that the
porches demarcation if you're running a
hyper scale data center and you have
some and it's basically traffic you call
your server guy and say what on earth
are you doing and figure it out together
as a service provider not an option
so you need a lot more instrumentation
at the Demark than if you can just beat
the other side the other thing is best
practice is you don't create a giant
layer to broadcast domain and connect a
whole road range of speeds and just
connect any port anywhere better than
high speed that's what you sell you have
no choice
but to offer that it also means that
flooding that can be just accidental and
tiny for member with multiple hundred
gigs a member with one gig really does
not appreciate and it can trigger
something that's effectively an outage
[Music]
so the other challenge we come up is Mac
security now if you've ever dealt with a
third-party data center and you report a
fort on the circuit chances are that put
a look back and if you've ever operated
a layer 2 network loop backs are really
bad thing so all I experimented Mac
security so only known MAC addresses are
allowed on boards challenge in addition
with Broadcom is the way they've
implemented learning it's a fixed
pipeline it does certain operations in a
certain order and learning occurs before
the mac ACL so even with the mac ACL
resources will be consumed by the
learning pack it up lifted and all of a
sudden your forwarding capability will
be reduced even though you're going to
drop it and ignore it so with a broad
comm unit we know that s are actually be
switched off finally
like a lot of exchanges we have partner
ports we are actually in twelve
buildings in London but that's nothing
compared to the whole city so for
potential members that can't just order
cross connect to reach us we use
partners for the last mile
they have port or maybe a lag and
present each individual member to us on
a VLAN and we have to do Mac security
not on a port but now and a VLAN we need
to do some form of shaping and policing
to make sure that the right bandwidth
comes in on the VLAN but the thing that
really does ahead in of any traditional
layer to vendor is that you now have for
example
and 721 415 and 1050 to being mapped to
VLAN 100 and having multiple VLANs being
mapped to a common VLAN yes if you're a
layer 3 vendor it's a port unit it's a
sub interface but if you're a layer 2
vendor that really does your head in so
the early steps of the project how did
we get here we hadn't at this stage
decided we're going disaggregated but
the best person found to work in this
aggregated space where the first one was
edge core network as a hardware provider
and they're part of the Acton group
they're quite large odm OAM manufacturer
the chances are good proportions people
in this room have deployed their
equipment maybe not aware of it because
it had someone else's label on the tin
but pretty well respected we went we did
a park with them and it was a failure in
particular the exchange features were
fragile was a polite word I settled on
we called the POC off early there was no
way was gonna pass but very lovely
Cathay Pacific did not have a
variability of the very next flight so
we could have gone sightseeing but
instead we actually talked to them and
analyzed why it failed and figured out
really was required from a nurse and
they went around they didn't want to
give up on the business and actually
through their relationships in the open
networking found and introduced us to IP
infusion little background on them those
who have seen this presentation about
zebra actually happy infusion are
founded by the original zebra coders but
as a strategy having moved away from
specialist stack vendors again somewhere
as label they're trying to sell directly
losses they worked with edge core
provided a demo actually in particular
focused again on the exchange features
and went I think we know what we're
doing it was and I think but that Lee's
got our interests but the other bit was
the commitment and one advice I give to
anyone honored the start of difficult
project is make sure that there is a
commitment of your site and relationship
101 if things are tough when things are
going well you're doomed when they go
hard
so actually believing that we could form
a partnership was key at that scale
right conclusion then is if this works
it's the right choice we agreed a target
solution evpn I think at this stage of
Nanog most people should be reasonable
familiar but the important bit is that
instead of data plane learning which has
a whole load of bugs associated with it
or behaviors you really don't like this
is all programmed as soon as the MAC
addresses known in one location
it's propagated by BGP and at that point
you know that if it's not known on one
individual Rooter it's not known
anywhere so the same way as if you don't
have a matching prefix and no default
route at layer three you can drop you
can do the same thing and instead of
having the default behavior of flooding
unknown traffic you can change your
default behavior of dropping unknown
traffic other advantage because it's a
layer three overlay its tunneled so you
don't need to do a map flush
reconvergence so significant savings
there also had other features that we
looking at
pbut discussed with the vendors agreed
the technical solution the key bit that
we had in addition to evpn is we really
want to reduce background traffic so
wanted to have proxy open proxy and d
proxy are for those who are less
familiar that bit of e VPN is you can
program through bgp not just the IP
sorry the makaritch ability but also the
mac to IP the arc resolution or the
neighbor discovery resolution and that
gets flooded and that means that
whenever there's an arp instead of it
being flooded to 500 or so members that
one ingress route to knows the answer
and give a proxy response but as always
at the beginning of a project option to
fail back because last thing we wanted
is halfway through the migration in
comes a bug it's somehow would surprise
one vendor so all of these features we
came in had the option on a particular
member if there was an interrupt to
selectively switch it off fortune didn't
have to that was the approach do we took
and the other thing is we wanted to
reduce as much background Leaguers much
we spend a lot of time telling our
members switch everything off don't send
us deck mop before was fated for anyone
that's used cisco has one that usually
doesn't get switched off it's far better
if the exchange fabric just drops it now
if someone really is sending bad traffic
we move them into quarantine it's kind
of the naughty step and you go in you
and then we'd actually want to see
everything but in the exchange we want
the ability to lock down to as much as
possible known good traffic's so agreed
features agree target and I've just
pressed back
it was very familiar questions like one
question I often get asked is why did
you not go for more Sdn central
controller and being perfectly honest
it's wrong DNA for links we started as
team of network engineers I mean what
could code but we were primarily network
engineers and our software team would
primarily develop designing things from
internal use
nothing mission-critical and they
weren't set up for mission-critical we
were building a software team and in
particular focusing on automation but if
we throw at that team and now you need
to build and maintain a mission-critical
Sdn controller that would have probably
overstretched the team and the extra
thing is if you want fast convergence if
it's controller base you then really
need it to converge in the data plane
the management plane is really quite
slow convergence so as we couldn't do
data plane convergence we needed to do
the control plane so here we are back in
February started the real work we now
decide who he wanted to with which
brought us to July but as you can see
quite a gap before we reach lie butchers
in June and being honest the bigger gap
than we thought it was going to be
couple of surprises bringing this one is
probably the biggest shock initially
because they had a VPS code and we were
just gonna add the evpn control plane we
thought ok evpn over MPLS a challenge in
particularly the Broadcom ASIC is
there's a limit of how many labels you
can remove in one go and entropy label
which is two labels was a non-starter
even the
yes I labor for multihoming was one over
budget we actually found a way to get
around that but that wasn't true the
latter the RFC sort of has some very
interesting in drops if we went down
that path another thing that was
suggested you can go through the
pipeline twice but you're basically
leaving half your bandwidth behind at
that stage other thing we're getting
from Broadcom is the actual MPLS layer 2
was designed for VPLS subtle difference
but on VPLS pseudo wires are
bi-directional so you have one label for
each remote PA on a VPN it's a common
label so all your remote behaviors use
the same label so will you get and D
capsulate a frame you don't know which P
it comes from you don't need to do data
plane learning so it's no longer
requirement and it makes a protocol
simpler but if all the testing was based
on one implementation they were getting
nervous and finally each LS peak
consumes an interface in the interface
table and because of our scaling our
scaling forecast we realized that N
squared was going to kill us far sooner
than we wanted would come absolutely not
to go at them they were very supportive
but in the end we went for the X land it
already existed we'd already been
working a lot on EVP n so it's really
taking a lot of the parallel bits of
codes you've been working on mixing it
together the we had a few limitations a
lot around convergence but we thought we
could work around them going a key bit
on the conversion so we found is it was
quite dependent on topology because the
challenge you have your control plane
can be very fast and knows exactly what
needs to be done but you then need to
go and program the underlying ASIC and
that can actually take a non decimal a
non-negative amount of time and the
worst is if you need to reprogram the
actual the excellent tunnel so if the
reconvergence at ingress in with seeing
300 to 600 milliseconds and said whereas
it's not at the first hop it was half of
that and to illustrate how you can get
around that
taking an Easterner west dark fiber and
one member facing switch if you have a
cut on the dark fiber the reconvergence
occurs on the members facing switch
Ribisi says oh well don't send it via
switch to Senate verse which one next
hop for the excellent channel changes
these reprogramming if there's any local
replication that needs changing that's
actually quite a slow push to the ASIC
if you put a spine in between it has
advanced on scaling anyway but if you
put a span in between you go to the very
same scenario fiber cut is now the spine
switch which we converges next talks of
the excellent unchanged
it's a spine switch that does the
reprogramming no VX land-tax question is
me ok well you have that reconvergence
if you lose a spine switch but now it's
ecmp we were sending previously to to
spine switches one goes down it's
deleting a nice EMP path as opposed to
reprogramming the the tunnel and that
actually is 50 to 100 milliseconds we
converging and if there's a ecmp flip
that's not on the tunnel endpoint that's
about 50 milliseconds and just for extra
data losing a link in the lag well below
50 milliseconds one text we do have
compared to MPLS MPLS you can have
standby pass and then preemption in the
whole time before it reverts IP routing
as you probably know
arie roots immediately so you can get a
hit if you need to reprogram a tunnel on
restoration but that is below 50 min a
second but in case of churn in
particular we did want to put mechanisms
for flap turning if not we'd get
extended drops but the key bit is it was
better and I we should have said much
better than the previous convergence it
wasn't quite as good as MPLS but it was
close
generally not picked up by remembers and
whereas the previous ones are a number
of failures it were visible so few
details on the technical solution so
leaf inspired I think that's rep welded
relatively well-known but and that
helped with the convergence we went for
a VPN and proxy our that was really easy
for ipv4 between only allocated one IP
address so is actually in our CRM where
all the Mac's were and where all the
ipv4 s were for ipv6 we actually
allocate a range based on I ask them
both and we hadn't released it so we
actually didn't know which of the which
address within the range was deployed
and where we have a data cleanse to do
before we can switch on ipv6 who those
on the exchange if we start asking about
our p v6 that speaks we want to switch
on proxy ND and but proxy arp even
though we have the ability to
selectively switch it off we fortunately
haven't had to another interesting thing
that we picked up while testing as an
extra feature is Mac hold out is
actually not that well expected behavior
do you get on a layer 2 network and the
behavior that you have on the FDB is a
Mac on the egress which will have an
entry saying that mag address will be on
interface 23 and if interface 23 goes
down it's no longer valid
entry and it gets deleted and with the
VPN it'll actually work quite fast it'll
go and send a BGP update much better
than P preview PN P evpn days whereas
time out but there's still a delay as
bgb converges at that time you actually
get pretty bad flooding because rate
limiting of unknown traffic is done at
ingress so the egress switch deleted its
route the ingress switch that should be
throttling that traffic doesn't know
that it's not deliverable so we'll
deliver it absolutely full speed to the
correct egress which which will then
flood it to all the ports graph this was
something we actually pick up during the
migration we had actually a quality of
service probe if we hadn't migrated
until the end of the migration so you
can see a number of the big members
these are 5-minute averages on a gig II
port if you look to the instantaneous
now don't have the graphing system for
that we look at the instantaneous data
it spent a while at 100% each time there
was a port that went down so that was
the old layer to behavior and actually
you still have that without the Mac hold
down on VPLS but evpn plus Mac hold down
that replacement graph basically just
removed the blue and it's just no flood
and then we went beyond we run micro BFD
so that if we lose a link in the lag
that gets detected for milliseconds we'd
spent a fair bit of time finding out how
fast to - now SPF we want it to be as
fast as possible but not too fast fair
bit have talked about the topology
optimization and the linked happenings
have been added an important bit about
the whole project and this is explaining
a bit of kind of what
member-based means the kind of an easy
word is we couldn't deploy something and
say well this is really for lots of
capacity for our big members or this is
just for small members so we had to be
able to communicate why it benefited
everyone and best is to pick at least
the outliers a challenge we had in
particulars 100 gig orders is the
previous ports were expensive sometimes
required chassis upgrades if there was
an unfocused order we were nowhere near
our target turnaround delivery time
whereas new hardware hey there's a lot
more capacity and a lot more inventory
but B we actually can have inventory
sitting with pre-built designs which
means that at worst it's one maintenance
windows so within a fortnight the
capacity will be there but typically far
faster than that so much faster
provision time for big members the small
members is all that thing about getting
rid of the broadcast traffic getting red
background traffic so if you have a one
gig port the chances of you having a
significant amount or even all of your
capacity being hit by traffic that you
really don't want is being reduced and
of course something that is a benefit
for everyone is quite a bit of a lower
cost and throughout the project we have
been and still are passing those savings
on to customers it's not the competitive
pressure but it's still the pressure of
a member based organization the last bit
to go through is kind of similar
projects that what-what happened to
those two years
I'm gonna go relatively fast through
here but there's quite a long time at
prototyping that was when we were
learning fine-tuning the designs
they'd throw something we'd give
feedback feedback on user
send it back that took us up to November
and November we had something that if it
was bug free was deplorable and then we
had a hardening phase where we stopped
adding features one of the reasons that
was quite an extensive process is
whenever we picked picked up a bug we
did a testing fania analysis and
increased coverage of the testing and
because that was a lot of test cases
added very late
they weren't automated or before they
could do the test run they actually had
to write the testing automation so it
took a little longer we found a few
mainly to an approach it was slightly
mischievous as opposed to the testing
that IP infusion did which is automated
I am a lot of the tests that we were
performing as users we trained the
engineer and gave them rough
instructions of duex but didn't tell the
engineer how to do it and you asked five
engineers to do the same thing and
somehow there managed to do it in seven
different ways so found a few dip bugs
that way but that's a good news we then
migrated over just over a month we did
one pilot site waited for any surprises
we actually did pick one traffic type
that was programmed on the AC if we
hadn't tested hadn't thought about his
packet that looked like rip but wasn't
really rip cause to short network events
but the good thing is all the hooks we
did for instrumentation and testing were
there to address that and that broken
rule can be reprogrammed on the asic as
so requiring a software upgrade the old
learn to equipment definitely did not
want to go without a fight
it gave us far more grief than the
equipment that replaced it so we in our
live being brutally honest it actually
went better than hoped I was quite
nervous end of last year beginning of
this year and I'm really glad that so
far no issues we had done one software
upgrade for lost snags the temporary fix
to make those permanent but basically
it's now Drive
any questions
assuming I got a little bit of time
under himeko athenahealth did you use
end up using any automation and if you
did what what is it 42 are using for
automation and we haven't switched it on
yet just to gain resources internally
but it will be Netcom we were initially
going to look at napalm but instead
we've gone for as ghost a pie chart Wow
son github and I've really got a memory
blank of the name of the project but
it's a pie across is basically something
we have it's on github that basically
for openness pushes or configs and is
based on ginger templates okay but it's
basically net comp thank you very much
[Applause]
you