hello everybody thank you all for coming
this is the we've been doing these
hackathons for quite a while and I want
to thank you all for sticking with us
and we hope to have a really good
program for you special thanks to our
sponsor Oracle who is providing the
who's providing the the content the
tutorial our lab sponsor to sudo who
providing the virtual labs for us this
time
so very very appreciated to both of you
for for helping us put this together
so a few housekeeping things before I
start I'm on the nanog PC so if you have
any questions about Anna in general feel
free to come to me this slides been up
if you have if you've had any trouble
getting on the Wi-Fi come to me or
somebody else at this table here and
we'll try to get you sorted there there
is a 802 NX Nanog Aaron base station
you'll have to accept our certificate to
join that there is also the legacy
station which is wide open with no
authentication but also no encryption so
you know use that you can use either one
username password Nana Nana should be
pretty simple
we'll do our meals and breaks in this
room the washrooms are in down the hall
the Georgia for any of the escalators at
4:00 p.m. we will start the Nanak
registration that will go to 6:00 p.m.
that's in the Regency foyer so if you
want to break here and go get your badge
if you're if you're registered for the
conference go ahead and do that
our agenda for the day we've already got
through registration of breakfast so
check that off we'll be doing our
opening and intro tutorial until about
10:30 a.m. at 10:30 a.m. at the end of
the intro we will go ahead break into
teams and what I'm going to do is if you
have an idea that you want to form a
team around or if you want to form a
team around a brainstorming idea stand
up
and I'll go around and ask you what
you're interested in doing and then the
other other participants can join join
the the project that interests them we
will break at 12:30 for lunch you know
eat at your table keep packing while you
eat that's fine and that will go from
12:30 to 1:30
we'll do a refreshment break at 3:00
again here in the room the food will be
out there in the hallway at 6:00 p.m. we
will close the we will close the laptops
for hacks at 6:00 p.m. we will ask each
team to do a quick presentation on on
their project and what they accomplished
at the end of that we will be voting for
the winning teams the top two two or
three teams I think three the top teams
will be then be invited to present
present their work at the during the
main session on Tuesday after the
closing we will have a reception the
reception is gonna be in here as well
we'll bring in snacks and beer wine and
stay out socialize we'll go till 9:00
Oracle dip from Oracle will be coming up
in a minute
to do a talk on segment routing and and
the ways that can be automated we'll
have some samples to get you all started
if that's and you know if we gonna work
towards that theme if you have other
ideas feel free to bring them up too and
on that I will invite dip sing up to the
table with Oracle alright so I am dip
saying I'm a network engineer at Oracle
cloud and I'm accompanied by several of
my colleagues over here and I think we
have one remote participant who's more
colleague will be joining remotely so so
for an opera so what we are going to do
is what we will be looking at the hat
codes but you're gonna be one of the
high goals and then we'll spend some
time in
to covering the background which we need
to solve those at that hag goal and
originally I was planning to give you a
dirty demo of how that hack actually you
know looks like if you don't have a
mental picture but because of the
logistics I'm gonna skip that but if you
still are interested into that I can
come to me and I can show you to my
laptop okay so but that started this is
you know the code of the day list that's
the agenda basically this is just a very
verbose way of what I just told you that
what we're gonna do for that an hour so
and so one thing which I wanted to do
was before you know I really go into the
hack itself is that the motivation
behind it right even though you will see
segment routing is there and there are
some other things but really the focus
itself for you know it's not really
segment routing the main key thing here
which if you want to take out on this
whole exercise is that understand that
how we can use any programming language
with this Python goal line or whatever
the language figure for choice is you
can use that to gain deeper insight
within the you networking domain right
and time to time I here if you know over
the internet like you know people say
that all the network engineers are going
to be software engineers and all those
debates which you know people will start
and they will have these absolutes about
the stance on what they think and might
hit the it is that you should look at
this is one of your tools in your
engineering tool kit that will help you
to be a better network engineer right so
that's my take on this whole thing and
obviously it's my personal opinion it
goes without saying that my current
employer and my past employer does not
hold this opinion so the problem
statement right so the problem statement
is that we all know that how we you know
whenever we're building a network the
network itself need to meet certain
performance criteria and at the same
time what we want is that the network
needs to you know like her before
utilize right so the capacity whatever I
have built in the network it needs to be
fully utilized and the way we can solve
that like he would be using T which is
one of our you know one of the tools
which we can use to make sure that
you're meeting the performance criteria
plus you are actually utilizing the
network or the from a capacity
perspective what you have better right
so few goals around the traffic
engineering itself are listed over here
these are very general goals these are
not all the goals but these are the
three goals which you're going to focus
for the rest of the day
the first one is minimum cost routing
minimum cost routing actually is where
you trying to find in your network a
path we build between point a and point
B with the minimum cost from go from
point A to point B now cost itself is a
very general term over here right cost
could mean anything so in a network if
you have let's say a GP right you can
say hey give me the shortest you know
weight of which is a GP cost from point
A to point B cost could be something
like you can say that give me the
minimum average delay between point A to
point B so cost itself is a very generic
term you know here and it could mean
different things depending on the
context you are using as an example the
next is the flow of air min cost routing
flow of air min cost routings actually
build upon the min cost routing where I
am adding an another extra constraint
that whenever you are computing a path
as an example you need to be aware about
the capacity available on that path
right so you need to be a what what
flows are going through it right if you
compute a path between point a and point
B if the capacity is not available
that's not the minimum path I'm looking
for minimum cost path I'm looking for
right so that's what I mean here by flow
where min cost routing and the last part
is the disjoint path routing that should
be pretty simple right what I'm trying
to do is from point A to point B give me
n number of paths and these all paths
needs to be disjoint with each other
right so these are the some of the TE
goals which we're going to focus for the
next hour sir and whatever goals are so
let me look at look at this picture you
so what you have is you will be given a
network topology right and the next
thing what you want to do is extract
that network topology details
it could mean lot of the attributes
associated with the topology itself and
then you build the model of that apology
how the network itself has then we will
throw look at some of the problems which
we gonna throw as a constraint says okay
these are the constraints which you need
to meet when you are calculating a path
once that's done you have to give her
you have to go and back and program the
network now programming the network
itself you you know the way we're gonna
look at here is using Excel BGP
controller it's a way for it's gonna do
the majority of the tasks basically it
will go ahead and say okay this is the
computed paths are here let me go back
and you know tell through the network
that these are the final paths which you
have calculated and over what we have to
do is we have to figure out a way a
programmatic way to talk to the extra
BGP of whatever the results we have
computed so that's a 50,000 foot view
we're gonna spend some time in looking
at the the deeper part of it so but you
can have is this a topology which is
basically a 5 node topology all those
nodes so our Juniper VM axis and if you
see these are the link details these are
the IP addresses blah blah blah so
that's that's how our topology looks
like it will have an IG P in this case
we are using is is as an example you
don't have to really know anything about
eius eius so these are just building
blocks for the hack itself and on the
right what you see is the cost and the
capacity of each of those links right so
for example if you if I say ten hundred
for the link between BMX three in BMX
one what it means is vm x 3 to vm x 1
the cost is 10 units and 100 is the
capacity available the capacity tus 4
Mbps here the reason i have to use max i
was originally
thinking of inflating those things to
gigs or something like that but the
thing is that these are all gig
interfaces so have to scale it down to
max but those units really doesn't
matter what exam what matters is what's
the you know what's the capacity and
what's the traffic demand we cannot
throw at it
so that's that's the logical structure
which you will see on the topology right
so that's what you will be given the
next thing what you have to do is you
will need to extract all that info and
create a model around it right so though
your model needs to represent all the
information which you need to compute a
path so you will have to extract how
things are connected with each other
what does the cost could look like what
is the IP address if I need to record
that these are the certain attributes
which you may need to record that so all
that should be represented in your model
so that when you really done with your
competition and if you need to extract
some information you can you know use
that to programming back so that's the
problem step number one right so problem
itself is divided into three parts
that's the that was the first part the
second part is that I have given four
set of problems on the left and you
basically have to solve these
constraints which have been given the
first one is very easy the first one
just says go from vm x 3 to vm x 4 and
figure out the shortest path right so if
I if I if you look into it what you have
is then we have X 3 to vm x 1 2 vm x 4
is the shortest path because the cost is
self is 20 right in the topology so you
have to compute that somehow
programmatically the next one is
actually says that ok compute the
shortest path but I am looking for 200
max of capacity available right
obviously now that shortest path is no
more valid shortest path because we do
not have the capacity available between
vm x 3 l BM x 1 so what you have to do
is you have to look into the capacity of
those edges and you will see that the
path which is the valid in this topology
would be from vm x 3
to vmx to vm x 1 dou v maxvill that's
your shortest path or the cost itself is
through her 30 and the there is capacity
available on all the links the third
house is actually build up on the second
one where I'm saying
okay V mx-5 is also looking too far
apart to VM X 4 and it has 60 max of the
traffic it's looking for so can I have
that in the network if I don't have the
traffic demand and without any traffic
demand V mx-5 shortest path would have
been 2 vm x 4 directly but that won't be
the case because the capacity itself on
the edge is only 50 so now if you look
the other way it would have been it
would have gone from um X 5 the 2 to 1
to 4 but since the vm x 3 is asking for
200 Meg as well it would have if we use
that capacity the only path available
from 5 perspective would be good from 5
to 3 1 4 so that is the path which would
be available for so that's something
which you have to figure that out now
the problem number 3 itself falls into
something called multi commodity network
flow problems so these are hard problems
depending on what's your background it
it could be relatively hard so you can
choose not to solve this one you can
just focus on the other problems right
and if you feel like enthusiastic enough
at the end of the day I just think I
have enough time left you can come back
and try to solve this one and the fourth
one is from basically from vm x 3 to vm
x 4 in this case you have to figure out
two disjoint paths disjoint means
basically even whatever the path you
have calculated it should not overlap
with the existing path so in this
example it would be from X 3 to vm x 1 2
vm x 4 and then you will have the other
path disjoint path would be your next 3
vm x 2 vm x 5 in BMX for one thing i
have forgot to mention that if you have
any questions feel free to bug me right
there it's easier for me to answer at
that moment so any questions so far
yeah
was that number three is a hard problem
to solve is a little hard problem to
solve we have to you have to keep track
whatever somebody has asked well what is
the capacity available on that link and
you need to extract those you know so
keep track so it's a little bit harder
to solve now there can be two spectrums
of the people some people can look at
little businesses all this is very easy
and you find all this very easy come and
talk to me i can use some harder
problems to solve and if you feel like
on the other spectrum that this is too
hard just focus on the first problem and
skip two three four just do the first
one right and just go from there and
then you can come back because once you
have solved the first one you will have
an idea and you can come back and solve
the two three four no it should be for
whatever so you have to look at two
things right so if the for the third
problem right you know that there are
two people asking for this much of
traffic I have to if I what do you have
to do is you have to solve for these two
at holistically but you need to figure
out the shortest path for those
individual paths make sense so give an
example let's just say that you started
with saying that V mx-5 I get 16 Mac to
the path which is available on five to
one for let's say you just do that right
what's going to happen is then the you
don't have any capacity available the
for the first one the VM x32 vm x will
be 200 mega well there is no capacity
will so there is something like or bin
packing as an order of argument how
exactly looking at it so you have to
look at holistically
yep yep yep yes yep yep
does it matter uh so you what you need
to figure out is basically the answer is
simple there would be figure out them
assuming the capacity is available for
let's say path one find the best path in
that case okay the second one
Azumi the capacity is available find the
best path most likely if the answers is
the same fine but most likely in this
case the answers won't be the same for a
microsite so answer won't be it would be
very clear-cut just by design I put that
in so that you don't have any confusions
here but always look at from one between
node a and node B give me the best path
which I can get and the same way you
know give me the best path for the other
others from five to four and this should
be the best path in their own regards
assuming the constraints are met does it
answer any more questions I think we're
good
again as feel free to back away now once
as you so once you have computed the
path the next the last step is you have
to somehow communicate this to your bgx
a BGP controller which you can pull it
down is very easy to fire it up those
paths and the extra BTP is going to go
ahead and a program that happens in this
example what I have is three and five as
the two handles we're even a program the
path but most if you are solving one and
two or four you just need to program the
vmx three as a heading because that's
weird
you will not program the path if you are
solving problem number three then only
you actually will be talking with five
as well at the same time so if you just
focus on the first few
just focus on programming it to the to
the p.m. x3 so this is high-level
overview of the three problem components
clear as mud okay all right again as I
said feel free to just bug me at any
time
now in order to cover the first part
which is basically creating the model of
the network right you need to have some
background in the graph theory how many
people has a show of hands would know
already about graphs okay we have some
some representation okay so graph theory
is very important it comes from its base
was the cushion graph theory is very
important actually it comes is a branch
of mathematics and it's used in a lot of
different fields and by the nature the
way the graph theory is it fits very
well with the communication networks you
can model that very easily it's just
like a natural fit some background about
how graph theory really started it
started back in 1736 with healer healer
one of the mathematician visited the
Koenigsberg and what she the problem was
given to him was that you got these this
river and you have seven bridges and
what people asked was is it possible to
start from one place and can I cross all
those bridges without crossing using the
same bridge again and and cover all the
seven bridges right so that was the
problem
origination of your graph theory coming
back all the way from 1736 and the way
you look at it is basically something
like this where I have this ABCD and all
it represents is those land masses and
the blue is obviously the river and what
you have is one two three four five six
seven are the the bridges right and you
could envision these land masses as
nodes and if you don't understand what I
know days we will cover that in
and what these bridges are actually the
edges which connect these nodes right so
what you see is ABCD are nodes we have I
want to go and they are interrelated
with these bridges which are which are
basically some lines that you draw and
you ended up in something like this so
this is the graph right and if that was
the original problem any idea whether
the problem itself was possible or not
anybody can guess what was the answer
for this that can you do that no right
the answer itself is no and the very
intuitive representing about this
problem is that if you think each of the
nodes which are connected they are
connected by odd number of edges right
so a has 3 C has 5 D has 3 edges and B
has 3 edges now obviously if you are
coming to a landmass where they were
they crossing a bridge in and you are
taking a different bridge and going out
its in and out you need to have pairs
right so all of them have odd so at some
point you will end up in a situation we
will come to the landmass but you don't
have a way to go up right so that's
probably the most intuitive explanation
of this they say you can go to the
Wikipedia and understand about this
problem itself if you are more
interested into this now some formal
definition for what a graphs are graphs
are basically you know way to represent
relationship among different objects
right so what I have shown over here is
on the right is the same topology which
we saw that which you're going to use
you have these five nodes and they are
connected by some set of edges and I
just have given some name I have given
them some names right what edges they
are connected what nodes they are
connected to formally speaking you can
say that the graph is a basically set of
node and edges where the number of nodes
and edges are finite and each have some
property called degree the degree
basically means that how many edges are
into a node so for instance number one
node in this case has a degree of three
number three now it has actually a
degree of two right so that's what Inc
graph looks like I say it's gonna be a
ten minute graph theory obviously you
know we're not going to go deep we're
just gonna scratch the surface of the
subject
so water graphs we actually can have two
types basic types of graph one is called
directed graph and an undirected graph
directed graph will have as you can see
there are pointers so there they have a
direction associated with it and the
undirected graph has no direction
associated with it right so what and we
will see well how exactly it's relevant
to us but directed graphs are also
called digraphs for short a lot of
libraries if you look into graph they
will actually use the short term called
digraph so if you see that you know what
exactly that means each of the edges can
have weights associated or prop
associated with it and that's for
instance in the case if I'm modeling a
network I can say the IGP cost is a
weight associated with one of those
edges right so this is the
representation of what a GP cost will
look like between a random graph right
so cover types of graph now if we have
undirected graph you can convert that
into a directed graph and the way you
can do that is by basically duplicate
the edges so let's say between 1 and 3 I
have this single H with no direction you
just create two edges with two direction
and you can you have converted a
directed graph into an undirected graph
in the case of directed graph what we
have is a different term then degree
basically called in and out degree in
degree represents how many edges are
coming to a node and how degree means
how many edges are going out of that
node right so in this example number 3
node will have to in degrees and to our
degrees which is symmetric here there
are some more graph definitions and this
would be the last one of the graph
definitions but I think it's important
so in a graph we call a walk is a term
where we start from a node and we
allowed the know the edges and the nodes
to be repeated in a wall so it's an
example you start in this example if you
look you start from V 1 you go to V 4 V
2 V 5 V 4 again so it's a repeat of a
node and then you go take V 1 which is a
repeat of an edge and you go to V 3 so
that's a walk a trail itself is where
you're not repeating the edges so in
this case V 4 is repeated but the edge
between v1 and v4 is not so that's it
trailed a part in a walk is where you're
not repeating edges and the nodes both
right so look from V 1 you're going to V
5 and there is no repetition of node or
energy
so in general when we talk about in the
network itself hey give me a path or
shortest path
that's what the path definition needs to
meet a criteria that there won't be any
edges repeated and there won't be any
nodes repeated and the last one is a
circuit where basically you start from V
4 V 2 V 5 it's kind of a loop so that's
what the circuit means in a walk in our
case most of the time network engineers
are just focused mostly on a path of any
graph how do you represent a graph you
represent a graph by n by n matrix and
we're and actually is the number of
nodes you could represent it by an
incidence matrix which is an N by n
matrix and where m is actually the edges
of M is the edges of those of that graph
and the third one is adjacency list
which basically if you ha if you have a
aware about length list basically that's
what the representation is where you
really have a node and it has actually
the list of what nodes are adjacent to
me so that's what a distance list would
be over here and this example actually
represents the first one in adjacency
matrix with an N by n matrix so you have
five nodes in the graph if you look at
the rows and columns actually are the
number of
notes and if there is an edge which
exists between source and destination
not what we are doing is we're setting
one right so let's look at from one if
you look at the first row one has two
three four as set as one because as you
can see the graph on the left is
connected with two three four so that's
how a matrix looks like an interesting
property itself is that if you count the
number of rows it gives you the degree
of that graph so we know that by looking
at it
cz that one has a degree of 3 which you
can always compute by the number of rows
the other interesting thing if you are
using matrix representation of an N by
something like a square matrix here you
can just do a multiplication of that
graph and you can come up with the
whatever the how many times you're
multiplying that matrix you can come up
with how many distinct walks exist in
the graph so in this example I have
multiplied a by a so you have a square
and the matrix which you've got actually
represents you the two lengths distinct
box in that graph an example would be
lets say from one to one you see three
right so if you go remember walk is
something where you can repeat the edges
and nodes right so you can go from one
to three and from three to one so say to
length this walk and how many ways you
can do that you can do that for two from
one's perspective you can do it for four
from one's perspective so you got three
to dentistry walks other one would be
let's say from one to five you have to
write so if you look from one to five
how many times how many what's the
length of the walk itself would be one
to five and one four five so it's a two
length so you can only there are only
two ways you can get that so that's
that's just an interesting property okay
so how do you create a graphs at most of
the languages itself have a lot of you
know graph libraries available if you
use Python probably go with netbook X my
favorite library is very rich and if you
are using golang you look at graph or
you can create your own graph library as
well so you can start with structs and
start representing nodes and
different structure for the edges itself
this is just a sample code just to show
you if you want to create a graph on the
right of the representation let's say R
1 R 2 R 3 you have 3 3 nodes in the
graph and you have 3 edges associated
with it and that's the code basically
shows you how do you create a graph of
the graph is undirected graph that means
that R 2 to R 1
there is no the edge itself has no
direction associated with it if you want
to create an undirected graph you have
to use a different form of graph itself
any questions so far
well good am I going too fast too slow
all good good ok so what we have seen so
far is how can I create graphs we can
use graphs to model a network by
creating a bunch of nodes and vertices
and edges we could have certain
attributes associated with those things
to store all the network properties
which we want to the question comes up
is then that ok how do I know a network
we do I go and look for how a network
itself is connected where is that
information sets right that's the one
thing which you want to know so that you
can extract all that info and you create
the connectivity model which you want to
build and the way you can do that is
basically in this is a simple example of
you know how the current topology is and
you can look into something called Ted
database Ted is a traffic engineering
database and you look into it how the
connectivity is an assemble step down
version of the Ted which I have put in
here from the topology itself where you
have all the information so if I want to
read the state database it tells me that
I have five nodes available so I know
that there are five nodes available and
they can be r5 four nodes in the graph
from the perspective of one which is mx1
over here it says that my loop back over
here is whose 1000won I know that
how is mx1 or the router one is
connected to other nodes it's corrected
two three four and two so if I go back
to the topology here look which is
representation of what overlap
topologies one is connected to three two
and four so I know that if I from once
prospective is connected to three four
and two over here and what is my local
IP what is my remote IP I also know that
what is the cost associated with that by
the IGP metric you can say that what
this is the cost associated with that
and what is the amount of link capacity
available is also there so you have all
the info to map take that info and you
can create the model itself and what you
can do is you once you've created the
model the edges which you are creating
you can associate or this Edge has this
capacity this is my local IP here this
could be the remote IP and you can store
all those attributes in a graph
questions here
it's your you know direction so this is
from mx1 perspective if you if you
really go into the router once you go
into the later in the lab you can see
that it from Treves perspective it will
have a different graph so it can be non
symmetric so so that's where you have to
really look into a directed graph where
you have two different edges one
representing the one side of the house
and the other representing the others
other way and the last part is the some
segment routing details which is there I
know that how many people know already
know segment routing some form so there
is a decent crowd right so if we do not
know about that you really do not have
to move segment oddity too much you have
to just know one thing and which we will
cover in a two minute introduction of
segment routing not much needed there
it's just the a to facilitate the
hackathon that's it but if the and I
will cover these numbers later but all
you need to know is that the data exists
so once you unity when when you're
looking for some details you can
actually extract the data from the Ted
that's that's why it's highlighted here
and we will cover later what exactly
this means so this covers up so far the
first problem part that how you want to
build a representation of a network
model right now we are gonna go to the
second part of the problem we are trying
to compute paths based on once I have
the model so that we're gonna move to
the next part and that's where the flow
theory comes into picture because we
start talking about flows as you can see
in the problem number second and third
when it looks at how much flow is
available just don't give me the
shortest path in that case and flow
theory is actually start with basically
what you have in there is that you have
a directed graph now at this moment you
know what the graph is and you also know
what a directed graph is and directions
can see these are the all the edges have
some sort of direction associated with
it and what you're looking for there is
two terms source and as
think sources weird all the traffic is
entering into the network and sync is
real it's the traffic is going to the
right what's their destination and all
the edges here points to how you go from
a source to a sink right and each edge
has some sort of capacity associated
with it so whatever the amount of
traffic you are throwing into the
network it should not exceed the
capacity which should be very intuitive
to us because we know that if the link
is gig we should not throw one point too
big or anything it needs to remain they
kept it the flow itself whatever the
traffic demand we're throwing this needs
to remain within the capacity of the
link right so that's how you look at it
the other way you can think about this's
think about let's say you're pouring
water from the source side here and this
will show you if you are the will how
the water will split so from source it
can go two ways so the water can split
some some can go the air some can go
down and then once it goes to the top
fern it can the water can split again to
the right or to the bottom and the same
way that the you the both rope which the
water is coming in it actually goes to a
single pipe and it goes combined there
so that's how you can probably look into
of one way to imagine the flows itself
would be right so that's that's how a
flow Network flow you know the model
looks like here and the one key property
itself
it follows is called something called
law of flow conservation so what and
again it's very intuitive right so if I
have 10 and 6 coming in at you as a node
the amount it's going to go out a 16
right what the law flow conservation
which comes from Kirchhoff's current law
is basically saying that you know if
you're not the source node and you are
not the sync node the transit nodes
itself you basically whatever the amount
is coming in is the same amount which
goes in so that means in a network if
you translate that there is no traffic
draw right so this is going to be the
same amount right so that and this law
actually allows you to
formed some mathematical basis for
lesson linear programming in network
flow theory if you really go and start
you know looking at the literature
around it is very closely associated
with the linear programming and then
many times you have come come up with
certain algorithms where you you know to
compute it but there are still certain
problems which you if the algorithm is
not there you actually use linear
programming to solve those problems and
this forms this law actually forms the
one of the basis for it to explain you
what I was trying to say so here is an
example of five nodes again and I have 1
2 3 4 5 and what you have is the cost of
those linked in the capacity of those
legs right and what I'm showing on the
left is that demand or the amount of
traffic flow which I'm asking this
network from source is 10 units right so
I'm saying ok I want to find a path
which has actually 10 units of capacity
available at least minimum needs to have
10 capacity but I want to transport 10
units of data and what you on the right
hand side I have converted this
left-hand graph into a directed graph of
how a network flow graph will look like
and I have given each edges some
variable which is called the flow
variables and the way you look at it and
this is a very dirty intro of how the
linear programming model will look like
what you're saying here is I want to
minimize mathematically saying that I
want to minimize the all the sum of the
flow variables here and that's my
problem statement with a certain
constraint the constraints are given
down which says we know that x1 2 on the
top plus x1 3 is equal to 10 because
that's the amount of traffic coming in
obviously if it's splitting out it needs
to be equal to the sum of x12 plus x13
right simple right it's as high school
maths here right so the other ear say is
that the other one says that x1 2 minus
X 2 4 minus X - 3 is equal to 0
so what it means is if you look here on
the top to the second note is saying if
the capacity whatever is coming in is an
X 1/2
it needs to be equal to X 2 4 plus X 2 3
obviously I have moved them into the
left hand side so that's why that
equation looks like so but essentially
it's saying that X 1 2 is equal to X 1 2
4 plus X 2 3 in the same way the third
one says X 2 4 is equal to X 4 5 which
is the first node thing and then the
last one is basically saying X 1 3 plus
X 2 3 is equal to needs to be equal to X
3 5 so that's basically formulating the
problem in a mathematical terms and then
you have added a constraint that the X
as a value needs to fall between 0 and
10 they cannot be negative right and
they cannot move go more than 10 because
10 is the capacity which has it of this
graph right so that's how you can look
at this and if you solve this
mathematically what you can get is an
answer is for this problem is x1 3 is
equal to x3 5 is equal to 10 which you
can complete know that if the 10 is the
amount of capacity which I have asked my
shortest path from s to T is going to be
Y of 1 3 5 and that's what it basically
is showing up it's a very simple way to
demonstrate this but if you go into the
huge you know the bigger problems the
variables and the problem becomes quite
large but this is a very simple
demonstration of how a linear
programming looks like here yeah exactly
yeah that's so the solution itself with
if I said 10/10 needs to take a path
right it should not be split between 5
and 5 but the way to look at it is it
like one wave if you are solving some
sort of load balancing problems that's
where you could look into that part but
yeah that's a that's a good point thank
you so now we're going to look at some
graph travels because obviously you're
not going to use this to solve your
shortest path problem you're going to
use some sort of algorithm to solve that
and the well-known algorithm is de
Guerra
is a quote from Maggie's red cell this
is probably my V favorite coat one of
the favorite quotes in and sadly enough
for some I find it very true many times
too so the digester algorithm itself is
basically a breadth-first search
algorithm you don't have to know how
daggers throw works you just have to
know that your strides used for shortest
paths and you can find some libraries
which actually already provide that
extra implementation to compute the
shortest path few things
highlights about digester itself is that
digester only work on weighted graphs so
what example would be the weight for
instance IGP cost is a weight for the
graph so that's where it you know it
only works for the weighted graphs and
if you of all the cost of the path is
equal it's essentially you know become
more like a breadth-first search
algorithm it's it has a greedy nature it
falls into greedy nature of algorithms
and because of that nature it you know
it does not allow you to work with a
graph which has negative edges and what
I mean by that is basically if a graph
which usually don't see in the network
itself because you know you never have a
GP cost which is negative you start with
0 or 1 and go on but in purely from a
graph perspective that if we have a
negative edge the synthesis grade in
each n is always looking for the best
from my perspective it will never go
ahead and explore that negative edge
because that can be hidden behind a bad
path and then you suddenly have a big
negative edge good which we end up in
having the whole path itself to be not
much shorter but it just never explored
those nodes so because of this it
doesn't work there are other rhythms
which work with the negative edges like
bellman-ford but it has a higher
computational complexity you don't see
that in the network implementation
around there but so that's one and then
there are few other here stick based
algorithms as well but now braiding up
on the question which was asked right
obviously of that ok do we have to
spread the flows no in reality in the
network what you're looking is the non
spirit able flows and that's why I added
is
small snippet of a network flow problem
where you actually asking for hey I
don't want to split the flows so if I am
asking for him the same in a similar
rate graph I am asking about 15 as a
traffic the capacity which I am looking
for going to the sink which is the five
from the fifth node and find me you know
a path right and whichever path you do
that's where the whole demand will go
right and it's a simple way out that is
X Y Z these are the flow variables the
cost of all the edges are verne just to
keep it simple and what you will see
here is the way you form this problem is
you can say you've minimized me two
times X because the X has actually the
cost itself is two times because all our
unit cost plus three y plus 4z that's
you minimize does your goal with the
constraint that X plus y plus Z is equal
to one so that's the constraint which
makes it that whichever answer you pick
the whole flow can is to go there
because if you look X Y Z can be 0 or 1
but they so it it will only be true if
only one of them is 1 and then there are
other constraints of how the cost looks
like you know I'm asking for 15 times 15
as the unit so 15 Z needs to be less
than 20 20 is the minimum capacity which
you will Co for the Z's path and you
solve that problem and what you will see
is the answer itself is 3 as the unit of
cost and the y is 1 so it will take the
path in this one side the best answer in
this case is 1 2 3 5 is your best path
so that's that's how you solve a problem
with non splittable flows if this would
have been a spreadable flow then you
could have picked for the first 10
because this 15 is asked because it's
the capacity is available from 1 2 3 is
only 10 you would have choosen the
answer go to 1 3 5 and for the rest of
the 5 the answer would have come like
you use 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 5 that would have
been the answer for a non for a spirit
able flow problem that's a visualization
which I really wanted to throw for how
this you will visualize um you know
mathematical problems I'm a big fan of
generally pictures because it is make
intuitive sense
if it what it really shows you have
three planes X Y Z of this problem and
the Y itself is way in the Carnot sense
is a 3d graph is hard for me to show you
is we have the best answer for this
problem really yes there are other
better graphs for hospitable flows but I
didn't wanted to confuse you further so
I just kept myself okay let's just show
this one now after the how do you solve
this if you have to solve it
algorithmically right so one way is you
can look at digester again right and see
that okay if let's see if this is the
graph I have given and I have asked you
give me a path with 20 units of flow
right so what you can do is you can
figure out all the edges which actually
does not need that capacity constraints
take them out of the graph you're left
with a graph which looks a little bit on
the right and you can say oh now just
compute the shortest path from source to
destination and that's you will get an
answer there so that's one way to handle
the capacity constraint but I guess if
you want to do that any questions good
all right the third problem is now gonna
look into the disjoint path problems
this general throw loss is gonna be lot
more simpler than the what you have seen
so far if you feel that was too much
it's basically you have source in
destination and you have to find n
number of paths let's just say two paths
pick up the first shortest path and then
pick our hoove then figure out another
path which is disjoint totally there are
two kind of disjointness one is no
disjoint and what the other is edge test
on edge disjoint means that edges needs
to be separate the nodes can be in that
path and no disjoint means okay edges
and nodes they both need to be separate
right so no disjoint is usually a more
restrictive problem then inez disjoint
path because you are not looking only
for in the node you are looking for the
whole node and the H both needs to be in
disjoint so and then you have maximally
disjoint paths where you actually can
afford to have some sort of
an example is over here let's say you
have the same graph and I asked you give
me two disjoint paths from 1 to 6 and
the first thing is what you can do is
you compute the shortest path you
figured out the answer here is 1 2 4 6
ok ok I got that now you can take them
out of the graph remove them you're left
with a graph like something like on the
right and then say give me another
disjoint path and you will come up with
an answer like this and you computed two
disjoint paths sounds good ok one thing
I want to make sure that you know like
that dagger will not be always able to
find with this method right so for
instance if you look here in this
topology itself you have 1 2 3 6 which
is going to be your shortest path and if
you always prune those edges you're
going to end up with a graph where there
is no path from 1 to 6 you there's no
path right so a point here is that you
know just because I am saying here for
the sake of hackathon that you can use
dag Astra of finding disjoint paths in
reality it's not always the case
people look at better algorithms do you
solve that problem so there are
different algorithms that you can look
into it if you are interested in to a
hint would be like a suitable algorithm
which actually works to find two
disjoint paths and if you would run that
algorithm in this topology it would have
find you 1 4 3 6 and 1 2 5 6 students
joined paths so that's but that's a
high-level overview of how you can
figure out disjoint paths for our case
diaster should be enough if you but if
you feel more you know like ambitious
you can explore and then whose other
algorithms that you can help you in
finding better paths in most of the
topologies ok
but that said
we probably are going stepping back into
a network in the Alps question not much
right now for just further is for the
learning sate purpose perspective taiga
probably would feel you know not fare
well in lot of the yeah it's fine just
get the answer
yep and we can look into it if you have
questions we can look into some other
algorithms which are readily available
which you can actually use it for that
ok actually I should have repeated the
question so basically the answer
question was that but you know how much
is the big o important for these tasks
right and the answer here is that it's
not important just focus on the hack
can't answer somehow right
and the purpose here is not really you
know is to start this whole thinking
about how they're you know really the
intricacies and things works internally
so you have a better understanding what
how you know about the network itself
right so is it's a way to you know it's
like a combination of two things you are
using some sort of coding to learn how
to code and now they're also same time
you're also getting better at your
networking domain as well because you
are now since you're thinking about the
problem you know at least that how you
know people will solve this so you are
basically trying to be a better network
engineer overall because you're learning
coding and you're learning key domain
itself so that's the go high level
motive here
now we're gonna really quick cover into
segment routing I'm just gonna skip the
slide I'm gonna get right to it and
that's one thing if you if you have is
in the case of segment or let me step
back how we know people know MPLS a lot
of people so that's good right in MPLS
you know usually you know what you have
is you know there is a in MPLS you know
all you know the label itself didn't
actually originally like the traditional
MPLS when I say MPLS is a very bad time
to say it over here but in the RSVP
domain or LDP do
when the labels which you were given
originally didn't have a global signal
globally significant value right one way
to look at it is think about a loopback
in a network or look back of a router it
always is unique right 10 you know
whatever the loopback is is always
unique across the whole network right
you're not having to separate loop backs
in the traditional label elevation
mechanisms it was always that the labels
were locally significant they didn't
have the concept of being globally
significant and the case of segmenting
what you have over here is that all
those there are similar to like loop
backs you have a label associated which
is unique across the network right and
we curve what we call them as the term
who uses note set and the way you
achieve that is basically each node have
a block of the pool associated for doing
global allocation right so you have say
that in this case you have 100 to 200 is
the pool you have been given from where
you do your global allocation right and
then every then you say that this is my
you know you can say 101 is my global
global MPLS label and that's going to be
unique across it so if anybody is trying
to send it to you they can use that
label to send use that label to send it
to that router so for instance if I want
to send to router 6 I can say that ok
your global pool is this and I can
figure out what your global MPLS label
would be to represent you and I can just
put that label in and I'll send it to
you and it's similar to like if I have
to send it to 6 and if the IP address of
the loop bag of six was 16.6 dot six I
could use that to send it in a normal IP
forwarding mechanism the problem came
around was that some vendor said ok we
cannot have a she you know same
reservation block associated for you
know so if some router is using let's
say you know some vendor says I'm gonna
use from 100 to 200 the other guy says
no I cannot allocate that pool for my
global allocation so I have to use a
different
poor so then how do you solve that
problem in the network right and that's
where high level this they came up with
something called indexing as a format
where you actually looking at what your
global pool is and what your index in
that and you combine that and you figure
out what is the global MPLS label which
it represents of that node right so
that's a very high-level lose definition
which I have explained in simple terms
an example of that is let's say I want
to send in this graph one wants to send
a packet to six with some MPLS label or
global label what I'm going to do what
is going to look at 100 is your starting
point right that's what we call as an
sRGB sRGB is for second route in global
block 100 and your index for that is six
so I'm going to combine that I know it's
106 and I'm going to use that label to
send it to sex right now if you remember
these two details were available way
back in your tag database which I showed
it to you wear it you can grab for every
node what is the global block is and
what is the index at s and you can
compute just by doing the two addition
of your base plus the index to come up
with the final MPLS label which
represents to that node so that
information is available in Ted which we
looked at originally but that's what it
means here so in this example if I have
to send this to six and I want to send
it wire five over here what I'm doing is
106 and one-fourth yeah so what I'm
doing here is I have put two labels in
the example for five I'm gonna use 105
as a label and four to send six I'm
gonna use 106 and I've stacked these two
labels together 105 actually says okay
let me send it to 105 when it gets to
three PHP happens and five only gets 106
and the 106 under actual PHP happens
again and five to six that's where this
how you can forward it right the point
here I'm trying to make here is that's
how you compute label associated with a
node which is basically
use adjust the base label and the index
and you combine these together and
that's it that's all you need to know
from a higher perspective here there is
one thing here which can throw you which
I actually when I was looking into the
lab itself then for structure which we
had there were some nodes actually were
picking up a different block and that's
why it does this slide just to explain
if your lab infrastructure itself has
this problem is that let's say the five
here over here says no look I'm not
going to use 100 200 as my global block
I'm gonna use 300 to 400 right so
obviously what you're gonna do is if you
are have to send something to five you
have to use 300 plus the index that's
gonna be your global label representing
five so in this example you see it's 305
305 and PHP happens at 3 so it's send it
to five and then you know five centers
natively to six so these are this are
like these are the two key points you
just need to know about this any
questions here yeah okay now the last
part is that okay I have completed the
path I know how to you know what we live
started from was this we have a graph we
computed the path now we need to come
unique and we also know what the labels
for the the whatever the hops you have
chosen you have computed the labels
associated for that now how do I
communicate this back to the network
right and that's where you know bgp Lu
comes into picture which is basically
BGP label unicast
at the original RFC was 3 1 o 0 7 and it
was amended by 8 2 7 7 which actually
resolves lot of ambiguity around 3 1 0 7
which was there traditionally it's been
used for in trace option C or a kind of
supporting carrier use cases but
essentially what you're trying to do is
if you are saying let's say you have a
destination 1.1.1 it can give you and
you also send you can send the labels
associated
for that destination right so you
basically is a way to communicate a
prefix and the associated label bindings
if you're already familiar with LD P
RSVP is another way of label
distribution essentially right similar
way the only thing originally with the
original implementation was even though
RFC never said that you cannot have
multiple labels associated with that
most of the implementation turned out to
be you can only use single label and
that's what what happened
you know like got fixed later on where
you can actually people change that
because of the SR as coming up you can
have multiple labels associated with it
so people you know fix their
implementation so now you can actually
send multiple labels this is how a
config looks like in annex a BT P if you
want to send that level stack on the
right what I have here is 1000 dot for
which represents the destination of the
router from and let's see what we want
to do is we want to send the path from 3
to 1 4 that's the path which you want to
sent right and the way you can do that
is if you construct the route
advertisement from XIV GP saying that ok
10.0 0.4 is my destination i have to use
next hop next hop always needs to be
whatever from three's perspective is
where you want to punt that traffic out
in this case would be 1001 1001 7 you do
not have to use a label to be present in
your path for node to it it can it it
you know you just skip that part but now
what I'm saying in the label stack here
is that hey my destination is 4 and this
is basically whatever the sRGB
block was 4 4 and the index number which
I used completed the final label and I'm
saying 800,000 4 is basically the label
which I am trying to use and then the
other top-level on the left is basically
what is the path through which you want
to plan so I'm saying here to go via 1
and then go to 4 right so the real path
itself is
to 1/4 I don't have to use two because I
am defining the next hop as this has
already covered there but I do have to
define that okay from two very neat to
go it could have gone to five or it
could have gone to one so in order to
force it to go via one I'm using the
label which represents one make sense to
hard to Z this is an example of how the
you know the from router three
perspective so before that you know the
1000 for was actually the loopback which
is associated with four and that's the
you know normalize as you're learning it
once you advertise your path to three
you will start seeing something like
this on the below what we actually you
have is 1000 force learn why BGP and it
basically shows up you the labels which
you need to push and you know if you do
a traceroute here you can see here
obviously you don't have all the IP
addresses recorded here but you will see
that it goes to T zero one seven then
1001 to is the loopback of that and 1001
to is actually the loopback of the link
between two and one and then it goes to
the four so it's basically becomes a
three hop without without this
advertisement it would have been just a
to hop it would have gone directly from
three one four now in this case is now
going with three two three two and four
so that's that's how that's how you can
you know except each if we can do it
obviously in this case the next question
comes up is okay how do I communicate
with Excel vgp programmatically right
and this is a laptop where basically
which I have given few examples which
you can look into it and if you really
struggling with that there is a small
code snippet which you can use actually
to communicate between ex-hubby GP and
your whatever the path you have computed
finally but you do have to compute at
least the path what it would be the what
is the destination you are trying to
send and what is the label stack looks
like once you have formatted that path
you J you know you can use certain
examples which are in this in the laptop
to communicate to XM e GP and
some BGP will go hard and you know
program the network obviously that means
that you have to bring up your BGP
session we do an X and the node itself
first and that also all that information
is available in the talk so you can just
copy and paste most of it and if you
have any questions there you can come
come and ask me
so that part should be very clear there
at least in the lab Docs any questions
all good well but that I'm gonna end up
the presentation and I will send it to
Chris yeah sure we do get the part no
okay yeah any more I will be here so you
know feel free to if you feel like your
loss I can give you some directions for
sure right so and if you feel like it's
too easy come and talk to me and I will
give you harder problem so the Geo
spectrum utilize in is all good
thanks tip for the presentation we're
all still here so we have a number of
labs we try to do this one group to a
table if your group is more than five
that's okay we just don't want really
large teams you know just to keep the
size under control
what I'm gonna ask what I'm going to ask
people to do is that if you have an idea
for something that you want to start
work on and get some gets put a team
around go ahead and stand up anybody
okay all right
so okay so self-organized I mean if you
have an idea talk to people you know you
know maybe the people at your own table
mingle if you like
okay yeah but yeah that's that's a very
good point I mean talk to talk about
talk to people about what your what your
favorite languages are what you think
you can work effectively in get some
synergy among the teammates there and
you know that will help things along a
lot if you're not a programmer you can
you can still contribute
I mean ideas will be asking each team to
put together a short side deck with
their work to present so you can help
there or just you know fine you know
find ways to be to be useful or just
just hang out and watch and watch if you
can I mean we won't hold it against the
sized team if if you just like to
observe we have a slack channel if you
have not gotten an invitation to it
please come up to us and we'll make sure
you get access to that we'll be posting
some links in the channel we have a
Google Doc if you want to join that doc
and and post ideas and of course we can
all you can all talk in this room we
have one person joining remotely he's in
the slack channel so feel free to
communicate there he'll make himself
known I'm sure afterwards I said about
two or three minute presentation on what
you've done make sure that you save
screenshots these are all virtual labs
they're going to be shut down at the end
of the day they you know they they
Google Cloud charges by the hour so and
then Tuesday at 3:30 p.m. we'll be
picking the the best afterwards we'll be
opening up a voting tool and the last
people give people a few minutes to vote
for who they thought the best team was I
ask that you avoid voting for your own
team and then at the end we'll announce
those and then the winning teams will be
able to present at 3:30 and we'll follow
up with you afterwards to prepare those
slides that
said I think we're ready to go we're all
at the front tables you know all the
Oracle folks are here
Nana PC folks are here as well if you
have any questions concerns feel free to
come up to us we are distributing
pods using this high-tech method called
paper pad pen and paper there is a
Google Doc in the slack channel with
instructions on how to access the labs
and once you once you have a team
established come up and we will we will
give you a will give you a pod number
and you can get started with that you
know the lab topology is is in the dock
that is in the channel so you can look
up that and again come to us if you have
any questions you ready all right thank
you
let's get started
okay one one more bit of housekeeping
when you come up to get up HOD I would
like you to come up with a team name so
we can track which teams have are using
which pods and we'll be using those
later when we do the presentations thank
you
[Music]
all right it is a few minutes after 6:00
time is up
do we have I believe we got another team
that was going to give us their name I
said all right these the switch is hard
to move so we can get if every team can
let me know who's right who's gonna be
coming up to do your presentation we
will start in a semi random order
although based on who got their pods
where is team bus all right are you
ready okay come on up team buffs now
just a quick note we have HDMI and mini
displayport for for hooking up your
laptop to the to the monitor if you
don't have either of those please let me
know asap and we'll try to get you set
up about two or three minutes if you can
we've got what eight nine teams
presenting and an hour to do it so hello
everybody we are team box this is
segment routing in one day this is how
we approach the problem the first thing
is we collected the relevant information
using the Ted database we converted into
a graph we use an SPF algorithm based on
cost and we generated labels which we'll
use for segment routing this was then
given to X of e GP using an API and we
used BJP LUN lri to push it into the
routers
we mainly use peyten for all our coding
so we used the Juneau spicy library to
make a remote procedure call on all the
devices so we connected to each device
and we got the pet database information
in terms of a JSON format and then we
pass through the JSON format to get the
relevant information which was the
source switch and the destination router
source out of destination router
reservable bandwidth and the cost which
we were looking for a discrepancy we did
notice when going through this was that
even though lldp information did not
have two links connecting between mx3 to
mx4 and mx4 mx5 when we pass the
information from the ted database we
notice that there was that connection so
that is the information that we got from
it so we proceeded with the problem our
focus was on solving the problem so we
went forward with this information that
we gathered to run the shortest path
algorithm so for the shortest path we
achieved all the three objectives as you
can see this is the first objective
where we have the shortest path once we
computed the shortest path we also have
the command ready which the XR BGP needs
to send information or this is a second
thing this is the disjoint path links so
what we did here is as you can see in
the previous diagram we had one extra
link so we have three disjoint links
between our MX 1 router 2 m Xfire router
and once we compute all the possible
links if you can see the last message
there we get a message no more house
possible finally what we did is we
allocated 50 Mbps bandwidth for per link
and we computed how many possible links
are possible between two routers as we
can see between MX 1 to MX 5 we have
about seven routers exhausting 50 Mbps
bandwidth yes so for XM EGP we actually
spend a lot of time just trying to get
the exhibition up between the VM which
was hosting the scripts and router mx3
so as you can see from C SPF Al Gore
them we were able to generate the string
which is actually the labeled unicast
route which gets pushed onto the routers
so that's there on the first screenshot
and the next screenshot explains the
route which which was pushed so on the
second last line you can see the the
debug output that route was added to the
neighbor with so-and-so IP and so-and-so
peers so we were able to generate a
route based on the CSP F algorithms and
we were also able to push that route on
the routers this so again because of the
discrepancies which we my colleagues
have mentioned before we weren't able to
see the trace route of the ping or trace
out of the ICMP packet according to the
path which you wanted so we went to the
each and every router to see each and
every hop and on each and every router
we were able to see the exit interface
so that's how we confirm that our routes
were being actually pushed through the
topology to conclude I would say yeah we
need one more week in Vancouver we
really like it here and I can very
proudly and happily say that we were
able to achieve all three objectives
with a very high degree of success
obviously there was fewer discrepancies
but we were able to tackle them and we
were able to achieve all the objectives
so yeah congratulations to all my
teammates and thank you so much for
having a wonderful hackathon thank you
everyone
[Applause]
you
can we get missing semicolon where is
miss I semicolon come up to the front of
the room
all right go ahead hi so we basically
are going to do a coding demonstration
you're very quickly instead of using
slides so as you have probably seen
they're the format that will be returned
when we get the information from the
router will be this format but we can
also get some more manageable or
possible file which can be Jason and
then from here yeah we were able to
actually extract the right notes
which we will need for the actual
creating of the graph so here here are
the notes we generated two-dimensional
arrays of each one of them which linked
to the appropriate nodes and then after
that we generated the graph with the
right edges and the right costs and
capacities which from there we
calculated the using like bashers
algorithm which yeah so I I took the
graph algorithm part of this and and
basically just just fed this graph into
Network X in Python so there we were
able to use the shortest path function
and then I wrote a little algorithm for
the multi commodity problem as well
which will will display here and we can
talk about that whenever that goes on
yes I can talk about the multi commodity
path algorithm so we wanted to find the
shortest path from I think it was three
to four and five to four simultaneously
and the issue was they wanted to use a
link at the same time and so to get
around this what we did was we it's not
very efficient we calculated all routes
from four to three and all routes from
five or all routes between the two pairs
of things and then just sort of greedily
took the cheapest one and combined them
to see if they were compatible and they
are there exist two compatible paths and
so we we stitched them together using
that alright so right now we're just
going to calculate the shortest path
from em X 3 to 4 and what we're doing is
whatever we do we're gonna append it
with the correct format and we will
automatically push it so it'll force the
packet to take set route
all right uh-oh I don't have it okay if
we if we had the other slide it would
show how it actually did push it and we
were gonna have a the ping that that
shows that the route was actually taken
but you know we don't have the luxury of
time I know yeah and then for the barity
problem
Oh Oh No so we just did the parity
problem yeah so depending on what we do
this will be returned if we say we have
two different end points and we have two
different payloads then that will return
both parities and depending on which one
we pick here it'll push it and it will
assign the appropriate thing but if we
want to solve the second problem you
just comment this out
and that should push the different route
as soon as you see the sort just thing
yeah actually did everything except for
putting that into slides I don't know it
was fun the lost pod come on down
can we at least get the problems to even
slide up on I'll just talk to it okay
all right we'll get started here so
we're part of the The Lost pod team and
our overall solution we split it into
three parts so we started with the data
collection then we had another team
member that was working on graph
solutions to the problems and we have a
third team member that was working on
the exit BGP so we can advertise all the
routes to our routers we use Python to
collect the data or to write all of our
scripts and for the data collection we
use the NCC client in Python and just
did a xml RPC call to get the Ted
database and convert that into the XML
into a Python data structure and parse
out the data that we needed and then we
use the network X module to generate our
graph file we end up to solve all four
problems we used four different or two
different types of graphs we have an
undirected graph and then we have a
directed graph because problem three was
easier to solve with a directed graph
than undirected so we have up here just
logged into one of our routers but for
the first problem we just did a simple
SPF algorithm in network X to calculate
the solution that was pretty simple
for problem number two which is where we
had some bandwidth reservation we just
generated a graph we removed links from
the graph that didn't have enough
bandwidth and then we calculated the
shortest path on the remaining edges for
our solution for problem number three we
actually implemented it in two ways so
one of our team members took the
solution and he split the stream so he
found the the path that had partial
bandwidth and he provisioned that then
removed those links or the the bandwidth
from those links and then computed
another path for the remaining bandwidth
so we got
dreamz splitting on those and we also
did another simple solution where the
more straightforward one where we
basically computed the first path
subtracted the the bandwidth from the
links and then computed the remaining
path for the the second 60 megabit so we
got that problem and then for the fourth
one we just implemented a simple
solution where we computed the first
path we removed those edges and then
computed the second one so once we
computed the path results we loaded
those modules into our main program and
then we wrote them to a log file and had
X a B C BGP push them out to the network
so yeah cool so I'll just quickly go
through and kind of demo all the
different things that we have it's a way
to hold this better so this is just kind
of showing that there's nothing on here
right now so it's traceroute no labels
as you'd expect XE BGP is running here
but there's nothing going through it and
it's fine I got it so we're gonna run
this with problem 1 so problem one will
go through figure everything out figures
out the path and then if we go over to
the router we now see the new kind of
labeled path and you can see it routing
across it if we run this for problem -
you're gonna see the same thing so
there's a new path and a new way across
the network problem 3 I'm going to skip
because they have to run those separate
problem for I'll run but we weren't able
to get to figuring out either the ad
path or what was going on here because
it's writing both paths to X the BGP if
you look here
well that would explain why this flips
back and forth between routes if we sit
here and watch it cool and then so
problem three so this is the first way
kind of solving it finding the two
unique paths through the network
so kind of the output there the other
version of three is well I'll show you
this really long version of it that's
probably not very useful so this one
shows how it splits up using like the
hundred Meg in the 50 Meg of the lower
latency paths first and then split it
off and use the other paths for the
additional bandwidth and this one was
not written index of EGP because it was
only peering with one router and ran out
of time anything else thank you thank
you lost pod
next let's have the newbies and cat5e
hurricane will be next up
quick reminder to everybody make sure
that you get screenshots of your
solutions
the winning teams are gonna be I need to
make slides to present on Tuesday and
the labs probably will not be running
and main session is pretty dangerous for
doing live demos anyway so please don't
forget those screenshots all right we
are team one team newbies and we named
our project waterfall you're our team
members we approach the problem in a
little bit different way one of the
things that I'm very interested in is
how to take a very high bandwidth greedy
flows and try to try to route them
around the best path in the network so
typically the in any network is is you
tend to represent latency in terms of
cost so the idea is what if we can take
individual flows that are coming through
that router feed them into a an SPF
engine and generate for those flows some
alternate path away from the from a
perhaps congested a congested best path
so we've the way we approach a problem
not dissimilar from what has been
presented already there's there's
something that figures out what that
best path is then there's a way to get
that information into the X of each P
and then exit each piece shares that
with thee with all of the routers so our
program flow gather the topology
information gather the flow information
actually run the shortest path algorithm
constrained shortest path rebuild the X
of each P configuration with the flow
information
have the EXA bt announce those rounds
okay Wow sorry uh-huh so part of my job
was I was the communicator so we took in
the information from the like the brain
of the operation the part that figured
out what was the shortest route and we
translated that so that it could talk
with the exit be GP sorry long acronym
um so in order to do that we had our
three steps so we've received the data
we translated it and then we sent it off
so when we received the data from the
computational engine we took it into a
loop and we broke it up into a couple of
variables we had our destination IP our
next hop and a label one and two and
these were the steps essentially that
then we would process in the X of the GP
so then we had to translate it so we
took it through we broke up it in two
variables and then we saved them into a
library and we then looped it through so
it would print out all the informations
that we could then cycle it through the
configuration file so we created it we
input the configuration file we
implemented the code we converted the
documentation and then we sent it off to
the exome eg P readable format
yeah so I work on the XE BGP player I'm
loading installing and the dev
environment was pretty simple just
cloned it from git but they had to
create the in and out files and the
environment variables also pretty easy
it kind of just told you what to do with
the error messages where we struggled
for seven hours is to format and load
the configuration the correct way like a
configuration that can actually digest
so I eventually got a configuration to
actually work with some dummy data real
IDs real stuff but like nothing that
actually came from the shortest path
computation and so it you can see there
it's actually loading the configuration
successfully well I didn't get to was
figuring out how to push that
configuration to the head end to allow
it to transmit those programs shortest
path
and the topology side we struggled quite
a bit to to get that information we
didn't have a lot of Juniper expertise
so the gathering the information be RPC
was was a tough thing for us to to
consider so we thought yeah let's just
create a flat file even creating the
flat file had its challenges as well
where do you find those labels
it's just struggled with that for for a
good while of learning code for a
network X also was it was a factor
trying to figure out how to filter the
edges such that the optimal path was
removed that one was was does a
difficult one for us to to figure out so
you can see my comments there the
comments unfortunately don't translate
to working code not yet some of the
other challenges we face just just
connecting into the environment we had
some you some Windows users here so some
of them were using putty okay so you had
to figure out how to convert the keys so
if that one took us a little while
programming languages I've been doing
Python for probably five or six years
now maybe a little longer the rest of
the team didn't have hardly any Python
experience I don't think anybody walked
in here knowing Python so the team
learned a lot today in terms of just how
to use the language that's those are the
main challenges that's all we have
I would just like to say that we deserve
a huge shout out because all of us
except for one of us was first time
hackathon participants and we did so
much we learned so much we had a ball
and we are walking away with a lot more
knowledge than we walked in with so
thank you so much all right next up
let's get cat 5e hurricane where are you
hi so without much ado we are team fight
at five hurricane and just a brief
overview we did not want to restrict
ourselves to any specific routing
engines or libraries which are vendor
specific so we used in a Pam to fetch
all types of data which runs across wide
range of platforms and has more commands
more command set now before like before
it was limited kind of we used network
xbg plu and the controller to provision
tunnels and we believe that waiter will
obviously impact your MPLS cloud so this
was our topology so while we achieved
all the objectives which we wanted to
and which were provided at the beginning
we also wanted to look at IG P which is
your underlying protocol to run any kind
of MPLS or any BGP or anything so what
we wanted to do is programmatically
aggregate flows for interface and also
ensure that bi-directional traffic from
A to B while you choose your best parts
you push your labels but you also have
to think about how VM x4 will go to VM
x1 or three whatever your head end and
your source and destination are so we
saw that when while we took RSVP into
consideration and all the other bitch
factors which we had to take we also
took into consideration the core raw
input/output packets which you get at
the interface level so that when they
take more traffic you
also take that into consideration and
use a dynamic approach and don't prefer
those particular parts if they are as a
part of your SPF calculation so how do
we achieve it we use this path
computation algorithm we periodically
poll it and this gets pushed into the
route logger file which has a set of
commands through a final advertisement
our test script will pull for it every
15 to 20 seconds which is configurable
and this then pushes to the XR b TP
engine so yeah I think all of this has
been covered before but I'll quickly go
through some of the hacks so we start
off with XR BGP so the first one was the
SPF calculation which was pushed as one
three one four we saw the routes we also
got the labels on traceroute so this was
the path which was taken three vm x
three to vm x one and then to vm x 4 we
have largely routed on node s ids we
would love to check adjacent es ids as
well while configuring s R so now
considering let's say this is
oversubscribed or RSVP he takes kicks in
and you have some bandwidth which is
controlled so not a worry so we ran ping
tests continuously to check the health
of the current apology we chose our
other route which is the second run the
second objective and which it takes this
way again if there's an issue with that
and constant monitoring on all the
interfaces we go for the third run of
the controller we announce that
particular label stack of labels now it
goes through three to five for what did
we learn
provisioning s are tunnels on the fly
and integrating a lot of these different
components which every one of us used so
to conclude I think it's it's very
important to also look at your IGP while
we do have complicated approaches of
MPLS segment routing and everything
possible to ensure our flows go
correctly but we can use a similar
approach to ensure that our path costs
are dynamically calculated looking at
the IGP
as well as RSVP in your topology or
infrastructure and this could be used in
any MPLS large-scale core infrastructure
and takes care of link failures and
oversubscription so thank you
[Applause]
next team failed to route kin team
failed to route get up here do we they
cancelled okay no failed the route
failed the route all right
next team is 5s come on up
so I bullied our team into not doing
something on Sigma routing because I
didn't want to deal with graph theory
because I left college for a reason so
we did all automated OSPF
troubleshooting also I work at cumulus
we have a cisco employees so the idea of
touching do dirty juniper routers wasn't
very fun so we used a cumulus lab to do
all this so we went way off script so it
was a combination of cumulus ansible and
Python so it was a cumulus Network
ansible would configure both the healthy
and broken states so we could push
ansible playbook
- totally provision the network we could
push another playbook to break it and
validate what we're doing and then we
would use Python to pull and parse the
JSON outputs of the box so we built some
Network wide checks across the team so
we check that empty use match on all the
links in the environment we make sure
that there are no duplicate router IDs
and OSPF we check interface States I
didn't put it up here but we also make
sure that there is matching OSPF network
types on each side of the link and it's
not
that hard or sophisticated so we you
know this isn't really about walking
through the code but we connect to it of
ice we run a command we loop through the
output parts the JSON so it's really
just the idea of saying look
troubleshooting is a programmatic thing
that we're doing anyway as network
engineers why not actually turned it
into a program it's all on github
columbus it's me flashing on neon are
like 74 so let's see it
so we'll connect into every device and
the network all for six devices checking
links checking LSBF network types and
then finally checking that the MT use
match on both sides and then after this
passes we'll break it and run it again
one thing that I'll note here is that
our code is extremely inefficient so it
takes a little while
so like I said we're just using an
antelope lay book to break the MTU so
it's going to go in and break him to you
on a couple of boxes apply the change
and then we run our test again and we
can see that all of the link state stuff
is just fine don't be a hater but now we
will sit and turn through and check the
m2 use and we should see that there are
MTU mismatches in our environment
oh no oh okay I can fix this
so it was pointed out that we're
changing the MTO on every router so
we're breaking the MTU equally
everywhere so it doesn't actually break
anywhere so we're gonna unbreak Andrey
break it all right try this one more
time everybody gets a mulligan right if
it doesn't work I'm blaming you
no whammies yeah so that was what we did
that's all I got
thank you you next team up Oh ABC where
are you
okay hi everyone so we're team o ABC for
Oracle arista and we have a person from
BC here so we have wanted to name that
and so our overall strategy is very
similar similar to how everyone is doing
it using the graph so basically first we
gonna use the show Ted database
extensive to basically get the network
topology and extract the data and then
we basically list the router name with
the destination the IPG metric the
reservable bandwidth and from there we
eliminate the bandwidth lesser than the
reservable bandwidth yeah so so okay so
we started brainstorming about this the
first question was how do we come up
with the shortest path algorithm where
you have the shortest path and also the
path has enough bandwidth so we we were
going to run the iteration twice or
iterate over it twice and then the
second idea that we had was you know we
actually change the shortest path
algorithm where we find the shortest
path and then if there is no bandwidth
we run one more iteration of it rather
than you know changing anything so then
we came up with an idea of why not just
take out all the links where the
bandwidth is lesser than the specified
bandwidth because the shortest the the
narrowest part of the pipe is what you
don't want right and then you run the
algorithm or the rest of the network and
then you have the shortest path with
enough bandwidth so that was the idea
and then populate the shortest car the
the matrix with the you know the the
cost of the links and then shall search
for the shortest path and then use X a
BT Peter Streete distributed
unfortunately our you know software
development team is still working on it
next quarter will have the release out
with this okay we don't have we don't
have a working model but we have
snippets of the output so we didn't
include it so that's where we are thank
you
[Applause]
all right last team up is rpki fixers
come on down so these are some of our
thoughts on the state of rpki and BGP
we've seen that there's some problems
and that anybody can pretend to be any
ASN when they're plugged into a lot of
people and our PTI depends on our IR
stability to actually go back and verify
their Pig guys stuff as well as to issue
more and things along those lines
there's not a secure fallback
it also doesn't allow end-to-end source
verification when you're trying to find
all the routes all the way back to where
stuff comes from there's not a sort of a
chain of trust all the way back to the
beginning also men in the middle is a
specific problem for a lot of things
that's been talked about being addressed
a lot more in standards nowadays and the
solution that we came up with is just
using a whole bunch of blockchain to try
and you know attack the problem because
it kind of seems like something it could
attack and blockchain is probably the
wrong word for it because there's been
chain of trust with SSL Certificates
things like that for a million years
that's something more along those lines
but we make it so there's a nice Genesis
block you know from I Anna actually say
where everything is in the world and
make it so the rars can assign and
revoke but with all signatures along the
way in a ledger have a majority of the
non-authoritative ones countersign the
ones that are authoritative so that one
can't accidentally mess something up and
then the IP holders are then
authoritative to a sign and countersign
other re O's and impairing agreements or
just basically along the way and so when
the first ones that anybody right now
can pretend to be any ASN and so a pure
authorization between bgp partners and
they can counter sign there re O's
that every time there's a handshake
between the two you know they're trusted
trusted trusted trusted and the re OHS
can also propagate revocation so if you
don't want them to announce your ASN you
know five levels deep or whatever it is
you just turn that off and problem
number two is it depends a lot on the
stability of the IRS with this is it's a
peer-to-peer transport of the ledger of
all the sign dario's and piays along
with the global routing table and so
because all those things propagate
already you can add a little bit of
information to it and it'll still
propagate throughout the whole world so
there's a five rars plus I Ana majority
of them B three required to sign to
revoke and reassign and then if more
than like 1% of the ledger has changed
like all at once like somebody
accidentally deletes the whole internet
then have a little bit of manual
intervention or verification at least
problem 3 is that there isn't right now
a good end-to-end source verification
this chain of trust ledger all along the
way allows that and so that's ourselves
that and then problem 4 is the man in
the middle mat Mac SEC is an Ethernet
level point-to-point encryption there's
a lot of different ways to configure it
there's a lot of hardware that's coming
out or is out that has it available when
it's integrated with this chain of trust
you could use it as a layered encryption
that will allow more protection against
man-in-the-middle attacks and that's it
thank you to all the teams all right so
we are going to be posting a straw poll
link give about five minutes for
everyone to put in a vote for their own
team for the best team please do not
vote for your own team it's an honor
system but we want you to vote for some
for a different team than your own so
so
michael is posting the link in the
channel and he can send it to me all
so the link is and the link is in the
hackathon channel so go forth and vote
yeah
while we're doing that let's we have a
raffle so we got some prizes to get out
while we wait from the voting to finish
so sure
all right
let's try to start with the let's try
start with the smallest things for
all right
thing does everybody have your ticket
out all right
the first prize is a lever gear tool
card Pro it's a wallet-sized multi-tool
ticket number is five nine one six zero
one five five nine one six you got it
okay thank you
[Applause]
then the next prize we've got here is a
Merlin solar puff it is a solar-powered
lighted light cube ticket number five
nine one six zero five one five nine one
six zero five one got one okay
sorry moving quickly trying to go in a
little bit over time right now so good
next up we have a tile combo pack I have
a couple of these are pretty handy you
stick them in your wallet and anybody
who's running the app nearby can can tag
your lost thing but the ticket number
five nine one six zero one six six zero
one six got it okay yeah thank you okay
next up the venerable echo dot ticket
number five nine one six zero three two
got it
all right great thank you okay we have a
temperature-controlled ceramic mug see
here that does it have Wi-Fi it has
Bluetooth Bluetooth enabled coffee mug
alright number is five nine one six zero
two zero five nine one six alright yep I
think it's Bluetooth alright more more
swag from Amazon we have an echo spot it
say echo dot with a video camera ticket
number five nine one six zero one one
five nine one six zero one one anybody
[Applause]
all right next up we have a portable
video projector dr. J professional but
not quite as powerful as that thing but
I'm sure it gets the door I've done five
nine one six zero two six five nine one
six zero two six okay okay
if you haven't voted yet please do we're
trying to finalize that so we can get
get some winners the final prize the
Atari flashback gold deluxe so if you're
if you're of a certain age you remember
these games and the ticket number five
nine one six zero zero two five nine one
six got loan all right
Gracie you'll take me a ticket sorry all
right so how's their voting
so we have the top three teams are cat5e
hurricane team buffs and the lost pod
congratulations all the teens if you
could get us all of your contact info so
we can follow up later and work on
getting slides for the Tuesday
presentation that would be great thank
you
Oracle thank you the desuno and beanie
we are done the reception is
you