well good afternoon
and ricotta I'm going to talk to you
a project that in lagna key we feel
something like proud about this
basically is identifying DNS open
resolvers as you can see in the title
which is quite a specific well as all of
you know to identify DNS open resolvers
in the ipv4 world is quite easy because
the ipv4 addresses space is not that big
in AP six it is more difficult and we
needed to take a different path so what
we did basically we are taking with a
very specific tcp dump command we're
creating a pickup file in group server
actually these are reverse DNS root
server it is not that good server that
traditionally will listen but it is
somehow a server that receives a lot of
of queries the queries that are getting
in that we can identifying a step one we
can safely assume that our recursive
servers in the internet so and what what
are we doing after that after we have
the pickup file we process it we work
with it we are using pie-chart to do
this we remove in somehow duplicates and
ipv6 addresses and so on then after we
have the ipv6 address identified which
we know that it is a recursive DNS
server we perform a very simple query
trying to see if that ipv6 address
allows recursion okay this is actually
the way that we identify ipv6 addresses
I am doing some emphasis here because
traditionally when we present and we
show this project the main question that
we receive we receive is how do you
identify the ipv6 address there are many
other ways of doing this and well
finally the last step of course is
processing the data
showing results a publishing and so on
I'm going to escape this slide since the
results I'm going to show most of these
okay there is a summary may be this
slide is interesting you can see by
arrear the total of ipv6 DNS server that
we have identified for airing let's talk
only about the first line we have
identified almost 2000 ipv6 DNS servers
while we did will run a simple query to
all of them and we were able to get 51
open resolvers ok as all of you know
maybe this is not the expected behavior
most of the time open resolve verses are
not good in Internet of course we know
that some providers in somehow they have
have DNA's recursion enabled to
everybody like Google and many more
so what else this is more or less the
same information that they previous in
detector that was shown in the table
let's talk one more time about Aaron
since wearing Aaron region in the first
the most left bar chart you can see in
the blue line the total number of
servers that we have found and the
orange line more or less chose the DNS
that were open in somehow okay it is
allowed recursion this graph it is only
for lag neck region sorry for that I did
this I did this is light last night and
since we are getting data since March of
this year we were able to create a time
table however we can do this for any
area and for any country actually that
that we wish basically you can see that
the first graph the amount of Open DNS
resolvers ipv6 that we have found in our
region in latnok and in the second graph
you can see the
illusion of the non Open DNS servers
that we have found later you can see
that Brazil they have the most amount of
DNS servers and the same case for open
resolvers in ipv6 and we have found
something that is interesting at least
from my point of view we we have
identified that certain has large 64 per
a fixes the there are a lot of resolvers
in each for example in the first line
with we found 62 servers in only 1/64
ipv6 prefix we believe that this is
because of the you know the privacy
address a addressing that some operating
system have implemented but this is from
my point of view this is quite
interesting to you what were we looking
for this type of results that we have
you can see at least yesterday I did
this a couple of erring results from
Canada and from the US I only took no
servers that we were able to find that
were closed and in the end on the very
right just on the left was of airing we
were able to get the owner ID of that
ipv6 address so after that we are able
to contact the owner of that ipv6
address and tell him on auto tell them
sir you have an ipv6 open resolver
please take care of that and this is an
example of what latnok members-only
latnok members are receiving in this
moment this is an email that we started
sending about six weeks ago you can see
that every Monday you can see something
like dear remember name you appear to be
running a DNS open recursive resolver at
IP address blah blah blah blah it
explains what it is there are two
examples in how to fix this for bind and
unbound
and I'm happy to tell you that we have
already got evidence of people that
receive our email and fix the server
actually we have a very nice example
last week one member of lugnut received
the previous email he had two servers of
course we were able only we only found
one of them and the member fix the two
servers that they have so it is a very
interesting example that now we were
able to do this and we are very happy we
are not sending the mail to other
regions for right ethnic or any other
one if you wish to contact us and
somehow to go in detail how we are doing
this please feel free to contact me
our netic next steps is integration with
with some latnok systems you know when
the user and enters username and
password automation of some statistics
publishing open data and something that
we think could be quite interesting is
trying to find out if some of the DNS
servers that we were able to find
probably are in a squad prefixes you
know
prefixes that has not been assigned by
any area or Ayana even and that's all
what I have I don't know if there are
time for questions
oh hello good luck
West Gorge with bike grid um curious did
you see any sixty-four addresses in the
analysis you did 64 addresses you mean
map ideas like 2002 : : / 16 ooh
actually that's a terrific question
unfortunately I did not pay attention to
that but if you have the data so I'm
going to do it now that you happened I
might suggest that you look at that
because I was analyzing earlier this
year I was analyzing a v6 DNS dictionary
attack for a large DNS provider and out
of let's see out of the 400 or so open
resolvers that I found out of the list
of querying hosts that were
participating in that were in that
dictionary attack more than half of them
were from 6 to 4 space and I couldn't
really determine whether that was some
sort of weird vagary where because there
was a six to four functional address the
DNS server was just doing that because
it was configured and it was using
whatever available interfaces or if
there was some sort of an explicit
effort there or if this was more the two
were unrelated like you had a v4 open
resolver that also had a 6 to 4 address
and was talking via that interface but
there's probably some some analysis to
be done there because one of the one of
the questions that might come out of
this is is it time to just stop start
configuring authoritative and recursive
DNS servers to reject queries from 2002
colon colon slash 16 as sort of
overtaken by events and no longer useful
and thus just closing down an attack
vector I don't really have a good answer
to that but that's the the question
raised in my analysis well terrific
interesting believe me I'm going to my
to my to my computer I will try to find
the list of ipv6 addresses are in that
54 transition mechanism and if you want
to see the the
on mine it's if you go to IEP G or gets
in the March 2018 presentations okay
let's talk about the later thank you
[Applause]
you