um i think that introduction covered the
ring well so i'm not going to spend too
much time on
this slide uh if anyone wants to contact
me
um my twitter's there brains933 email
address and also
um if you ping me in them uh
on the swap card app i'll be about all
day anyway so
i have feel free to uh to ping me there
let's get rid of this
and just for anyone who has ocd my desk
is an
absolute mess so um
i'm sorry you're just gonna have to deal
with it unfortunately
so make myself smaller so this is where
we're going to be working for the most
part i'm going to be going through and
doing some demos of rf
attacks usually i try and do these talks
with
the expectation of no prior knowledge
required i am still going to try and do
this but i don't have a lot of time
to go through and do a preamble of okay
what's rf what's
frequency all that stuff and so
hopefully
i'll just try and explain things as and
when i get to them and uh
again hopefully you don't need to know
anything to see how these attacks work
so
uh hopefully we'll all be okay uh
quickly going through what i've got on
the uh
on the desk this here is the circuit
that we're going to be attacking so this
is our
our victim device effectively
and this is just a simple remote control
circuit um now i'm using lights
to demonstrate when a signal goes off
and when it doesn't so just in case
anyone has
any um photo sensitivity issues or any
issues with flashing lights i'm going to
make sure not to strobe them or do
anything like that but just
i'm using flashing lights just so you're
aware but whenever i press
a key fob you can see that i've got red
blue
green and yellow and each of them
corresponds to a different signal
so that's the um device that we're going
to be abusing
the kit that i'm actually using um is
things like this so this
is an rtl sdr this is a software defined
radio device little usb device
you plug into your computer and it lets
you to view uh
signals and capture them uh something
like this is what an attacker would
typically use because these are quite
cheap they're about
20 quid or so um to transmit our signals
i'm using
this it's a hack rf1 an attacker
typically won't use something like this
just because they're expensive this is
about 100 pounds or so for one of these
and generally an attacker is going to
make these devices throw away
so um this is type of device is good for
us for testing and tinkering and
breaking things
an attacker isn't really going to use
something like this typically
and they're probably more likely to use
something like this and this is a little
device that i made on um the b-sides
london badge for a few years ago
and it's cheap it's throwaway i mean you
can make about five or six of these
devices for about 20 pounds it's just an
arduino
and a little um transmit module to
preload these with their attacks
stick them near the device that they
want to attack and away they go
this i'm going to talk about a later on
same with these
so the first attack that we're going to
look at is called a
replay attack and it it works very much
like it sounds
you capture a signal and you replay it
at a later date
so in this case i would hit that
and i want to capture that signal and
repeat that action
a a common defense that companies use
whenever they
are um presented with
this device as vulnerable to such an
attack they they usually give the excuse
or the argument no
that's not possible because my device um
the the communication is encrypted that
does not help you here
because the way that these devices work
especially remote control devices
they have a physical effect in the real
world so
me as the attacker i don't need to see
what's in the in the packet of
information i just need to see the
effect
so i look using a sdr or similar device
look for the signal and look and see
what it does in the real world so in
this case
if i look for the signal and hit the
button i can see
that it turns the red light on that's
all i need to know i don't need to know
what is
inside that packet of information i just
need to be able to see its results
so let's actually have a look at what
this looks like and for this i'm going
to take away my face
and we will go to
here now hopefully you can still
see the desk okay i just like that up
yeah there we go so this is a little
tool
called um universal radio hacker
and it's fantastic for
people who are wanting to get into
fiddling about radios and stuff like
that and attacking things
because it's this is almost like the
equivalent of a script kitty
for radios it's a really simple tool and
uh it can be um it can be used by anyone
believe me if i can use this anyone can
and it allows you to capture signals and
also replay them
and also do some analysis but i'm not
going to cover analysis too much
now because that that could be a whole
talk in itself
but for this we're going to assume that
this is a simple signal which it is
and we're going to uh take a look at it
at what it looks like
on the rs spectrum and then we're going
to replay it but
just before i go to the rs spectrum you
can see here i've got these labeled blue
green
yellow these are all the signals that
i've captured um offline
because i trying to avoid falling victim
to the live demo
demons so i know that these work
and that they're all good so these are
the ones i've saved earlier
but i'm going to show you what it looks
like on the rf spectrum
as to when i'm actually trying to
capture a signal so
if i get rid of this
there we go and i'll make you a little
bit smaller there
so this is what my sdr is seeing
this is the uh what the radio waves
around us look like
um the the fuzzy lines that you're
seeing there at the minute
that's just background noise that's just
their ambient radiation
and what i would do as an attacker if
i'm looking for a device i would do a
bit of research on the device to find
out
roughly what frequency it operates on
which is sort of like the address of it
um and this this is all usually well
documented
and and for the devices in question this
little key fob i know that it
is roughly in the 433 megahertz range
which is quite a common one for remote
control devices
and i would watch and wait for the
signal and if i press the button
you can then see that signal and you can
see that's fairly easy to spot
you know if you're looking for a signal
and you're watching for something
you'll be able to find that quite quite
quickly
now what i can then do is
see if that signal so you can see down
here a little uh button hopefully it's
it's visible and basically it says start
recording and i just start recording
what i see this gray column here
it'll start grabbing everything that's
in there and then i can take that
um signal analyze it and do whatever i'm
i'm
needing to do with it
now if we go back to this you can also
um capture the signals
in universal radio hacker the reason i'm
not showing you that right now is
because
it's simply for recording purposes it's
the screen is not the best for
viewing but it works in exactly the same
way
but we want to now look and transmit one
of these signals so we've got here
blue which is here's one i've i've
captured earlier and if i go to replay
the signal
and i need to choose window capture
hopefully this will there we go
so this is the window that will appear
here you get a more exploded view of the
actual
signal that you can see and up here i
select my device that i want to
use to transmit in this case i'm using
the hack rf and
you ask for the frequency that you want
to transmit on so you can replay these
signals on a different frequency to what
you picked
up on typically you're not going to want
to you're going to want to use the exact
same frequency
and if i hit start it will then replay
the signal
and what i'm going to do is i'm just
going to make the desk a little bit
bigger
just so that you can see the light going
off
and if i hit run on that
the signal turns on that's it
hit it again and it'll turn it off it's
as simple as that
it really is um now i mean i slowed that
down for demonstration purposes but if i
was an actual attacker one thing to do
that
you could do that in you know a couple
of minutes it really doesn't take a long
time to do
and a lot of devices are vulnerable to
this style of attack
the scariest uh that would be
uh vulnerable is likes of industrial
equipment so jcb's diggers
likes to them cranes so those uh you
know construction cranes
and possibly most scary of all i was
talking to an australian at another
conference
and he mentioned to me that the
demolition equipment that they use in
quarries
is also vulnerable to this style of
attack so an attacker could
in theory detonate explosives while
their workers still in a mine
if they were that way inclined no
completely
a dick move and um i don't see any way
to get any monetary value from that
but you know there could be industrial
sabotage or just you know a threat
you know give us money or we're going to
blow up your minds or
destroy your building site or things
like that
so um quite scary attacks i think and
also very very um easy to do
they um they can be defended against
and if i get rid of this
they can be defended against and a lot
of people is probably going to have a
device that will defend against this in
your home
and that is your car keys your car keys
use
a thing called a rolling code and
and that can defeat or at least help
defeat
this style of attack and if i turn
myself back on we're back to the screen
so a a rolling code can defeat that and
it basically means that you're sending a
different code within the signal each
time
so whenever i press the key fob here on
this
and press it again it's sending the
exact same signal there's no difference
between the two
it's just the same code each time a
rolling code there's a pre-shared list
or a pseudo
random number generator between the car
and the
uh car key and so each time you press it
it's a different signal
there is a way to defeat that as well as
with everything there's there's always a
way around it
and it's called a roll jam device i'm
not going to cover it much here
google it it's a very interesting um
device
and it's basically a way of getting
around rolling codes
so the next attack we're going to look
at is
a replay attack sorry wrong repeater
attack we just looked at replay attacks
a a repeater attack is
as it sounds you take a signal and you
repeat it and it's usually done in real
time it's not a case if you store it and
then use it later
this type of attack is commonly used to
steal uh keyless entry keyless start
cars
so you might have seen some of these
things where you know they they run a
device near the start of the
car and it then transmits
the car key signal to the car the car
opens
and to show you how easy this is to do i
have a little
demo here anyone who's in that mature
radio i apologize but yes
i i am using bofangs which are cheap
chinese radios
and most people in the amateur radio
world hit them
because they're cheap and a bit nasty
but i have two radios here and a little
relay box
in the middle and what this is going to
do is quite simply
one of these is going to receive the
signal and the other one is going to
transmit it
now typically whenever they're doing
this they're going to send and receive
on the same frequency so they're just
trying to amplify the signal
for the purposes of demonstration i'm
going to go back to the radio
and the sdr spectrum that we were
looking at earlier and i've got them to
transmit on slightly different
frequencies
just so that you can see the the actual
replay effect
taking place so let's get back to the
sdr
there we go okay
oh and uh you're in the screen let's
move you away
all right this is up here in there so
we're back on the sdr spectrum and as
per usual if i press the key fob you can
see the signal coming through
now if i turn these radios on
and hopefully don't upset any amateur
radio people in the local area
and i press the key fob now
you can see the
signal going also when i'm hitting this
uh fun thing with electromagnetic
compatibility which is devices
interfering with each other
something is disconnecting from my
computer when i press this key fob
okay good example of a jamming attack
there this is messing with my computer
somewhat
so we'll press this too much but you
will see whenever i press and hold this
in
and let go you can see that the signal
is actually being retransmitted here
which is where i've programmed
it to so the original signal happens on
frequency 433.92
give or take and i'm getting it to
retransmit
on 433.1
that's it it's as simple as that you're
taking a signal
and replaying it and in some cases
you're amplifying it to give it a bit
more range
again predominantly used to defend or to
steal keyless star keyless entry cars
but
there are other styles of attacks for
this um and there is also
um legitimate uses for things like this
so your mobile phone effectively uses
repeaters like this
and so does a new likes of amateur radio
and things like that you
use a repeater to get a signal to go
somewhere that it typically wouldn't
so there are legitimate reasons for
using things like this but this is
obviously a malicious way of doing it
there are defenses and uh one of which
which i believe tesla have done is that
they have put in
a sort of two-factor authentication with
the car key
there is a low frequency signal and a
high frequency signal so the frequency
that we've been looking at at the
minutes high frequency actually it's
it's uhf ultra high frequency
and what they've done is it essentially
waits for the low frequency signal to
come through
before it begins transmitting the high
frequency or the ultra high frequency
signal
again that makes it a bit more difficult
but all it means is that an attacker
needs to have
two transmitters and receivers one for
the low frequency signal one for the
um uhf signal so it makes it a bit more
difficult but it's still not
a uh you know it's not a perfect system
it just makes it that little bit
more difficult now how we did for time
cool we're good so the last attack that
we're going to look at is a jamming
attack
and a jamming attack i'm sure some of
you might have heard of or know what
that is
you're basically jamming the signal
you're stopping the signal from working
now jammers are illegal in
almost everywhere to either own or to
use
um the little device that i talked about
i said i would talk about a little bit
later on
which is this one here let me just show
my desk
this little one here this is a
commercially bought jammer
okay i do have permission to have this
by the way before anyone starts calling
the fss
fcc i i see not going in the chat i do
have permission to have this
um i am not going to turn this on
because
this sets off my house alarm and this is
a good example of why these
devices are illegal and it's because
they're indiscriminate
um if you've ever heard of mines or
grenades being called equal
opportunities killers
a jammer is the same thing it doesn't
care what signal is on there it will
jam it and interfere with it another
issue part of the reason why my alarm
system
gets set off is because of a phenomena
called harmonics and
direct pickup don't worry about what
they mean
the the basic gist of that is whenever
you use a transmitter that isn't well
designed or well filtered
it will also transmit on other
frequencies so it won't just jam what
you think it will
it'll also bleed over onto other um
ranges and other things so you don't
know what else you might be jamming
and the direct pickup is just electrical
cables any cable can be an
antenna and a device like this can
cause interference on it and an alarm
system it then triggers it
so that is what a jamming device a
commercial one can look like they can
get a lot bigger
um or a lot smaller there is also um
discriminate jammers so there is the
um get rid of this nut
the way to jam like mobile phone signals
some of you may have heard of the
uh american military around area 51 when
they were doing the area 51 raids or
they were attempting to do the raids
a lot of people started losing signals
and they noticed drones about and what
they were doing is i believe it's called
a stingray attack
where the um they set up essentially a
mobile phone tour
and they have a predefined list of
devices that they allow
on that tar to communicate
so it's effectively jamming it's
stopping some devices communicating
and letting others through but it's
discriminate it's very targeted
those kind of jamming devices are legal
under the right circumstances but
generally speaking
um most jamming devices are illegal
so for our very last demonstration
just going to make that a little bit
smaller
ah come on live demos
could do them so hopefully you can still
see the light there
and as i said jamming devices are
illegal so i can't really demonstrate
one but
if for sake of argument a signal
magically appeared here
um we could demonstrate what a a jammer
looked like
now what are the odds of that that's
that's handy so this signal has appeared
and it is stronger than the signal
of the key fob so if i start hitting
this and pressing the button
nothing happens the signal's been
interfered with
if the jamming signal was away like it
did let's hand it
and i press the signal it now goes on
and goes off
that's it simple as that jamming attacks
like this
in a cyber security way or in a cyber
security mindset
generally speaking it's not that useful
uh a d auth attack a wi-fi d auth attack
is probably a lot more
um usable or considered
but it can be used to actually interfere
with wireless security cameras so if
you've got a wi-fi camera
that is only sending a a stream back to
a a dock or somewhere else where it's
recording that it's not recorded luckily
you can actually interfere with that um
camera feed
just by jamming the wi-fi and then it's
useless you've just got a garbled image
so that is it
a little bit rushed but i think we got
there in the end and
no uh demons came in
uh so hopefully that's all good and if i
get back
up this and move myself back over
hide the old picture myself any
questions from that
okay let's see there's any questions
none have come in yet
there was a that's good i'm fine with
that there was great discussion going on
in the chat though
yeah i seen the spaceballs reference yes
just throw a thing of jam
at it that's it that's all you need to
do uh there's one question actually came
true
how would you go about analyzing a
signal captured in the wild
i.e is it possible to figure out
protocol type
payload encryption enable etc it is it
is
and um the the little program that i was
using universal radio hacker
uh can can do a lot of that for you it
does have some automated things to work
out like
it's called modulation and um stuff like
that and you can you cannot you can't
analyze it
uh check youtube there's plenty of
people on there who have done it um to
actually go through and show you
analyzing
uh that would be a good r i think and of
itself
but yes it can be done certainly okay
um actually that question came in from
somebody i met at the sound course hi
pablo um
so another question uh grant
just how good our key fob faraday bikes
bags the sword that you find on amazon
for people like me
who own a portable bus
i've used a couple that are really not
good um
it really depends what um what one you
go for but
to be honest your your best bet for
my opinion for securing a device like
that is keep it away from your front
door and windows
because the the receive devices that
they use are fairly short range and the
frequencies
struggle to get through solid objects
like walls and stuff
so honestly just keep the key upstairs
even you know not beside your front door
that'll help a lot
other than that um something i made a
faraday cage out of recently is a
the the metal tubs of formula like baby
formula
um one of them put it into a little
ziploc bag
and put it in there they're entirely
metal and they've got a foil cover
they work pretty well
so if you know anyone with kids
we have two more questions so
one is could relay attacks be coupled
with the replay
relay the signal on a different
frequency than the one
seen at the known offset and then
replayed later
this was not look suspicious uh you
could do it depends on
yeah i mean you could do it it depends
on what it is you're trying to attack
because
um as i said the replay and relay
attacks are sort of used for two
different scenarios one
is in real time to try and get around
the likes of things that maybe have like
time clocks or stuff like that to try
and
stop you from replaying a signal whereas
a replay signal if it's the same signal
each time you can you can just save it
and keep it until
whenever it'll never expire as it were
but yeah you could sort of do a
combination of the two
um we have a few more questions loads of
questions
that's good people were listening then
that's good the next one
is what resources would you recommend
uh for learning more about this sort of
thing
uh youtube to be honest there are plenty
of channels um
i can't remember what they are i will
look them up after the
thing and i'll put them into the chat um
but there are plenty of people who know
way more than me
um who do some really great youtube
videos
uh hack spy i believe they're called as
a blog website they've got lots of stuff
on there as well
um yeah they're they're all pretty good
okay i i think we'll just have one final
look
in case there's any final questions
um we asked this one we asked this one
we asked this one we asked this one
um no if there's i guess we can give
everybody maybe
one more minute in case something comes
up
sure uh oh i've seen someone asking
about the the software for the waterfall
it's
a cubic sdr but i think someone else put
others in the chat that you can use
they're all they're all the same for
viewing the waterfall
i think that was in the chat not a
question maybe that's my language yeah
yeah i just looked in there you're right
actually i've got screens open every
work so it loses different chats open
for other things
okay um there's no more questions coming
true
so um you get three minutes back grand
you can go and
socialize yep and uh yeah go get a cup
of tea thank you very much for your talk
it was
really interesting and now i can i
finally know what i can do with the sdr
that i wanted some competition
there you go yep now you know
brilliant thanks very much all right
thank you