this presentation is called pissing down
the leg of much of our collective
careers why are you people still buying
firewalls and IPS technologies or as the
file itself has been called firewall and
IPS suckfest want to give just a little
context into this talk today I've been
involved with security over 20 years 15
of that was as a part of the IDS IPS
industry so a lot of my experience had
to do with of course building and
supplying those products with security
content six years of that was
development in both sea and regular
expressions you might be asking yourself
see yes writing parsers state machines
that sort of thing I was a part of ISS
x-force for 12 years and I ran DV labs
in zdi and I now and the director for a
cert at arbor networks I'm Elizabeth
Martin had been insecurity about 17
years so my first job out of college was
creating a process for firewall change
control management so I was all
knee-deep in firewalls so I would say my
first skills are firewalls and
networking but truly my first love was
IDs picking apart packets at the time
was a the love of my life and that had
led me to the rest of my career in
professional services so Dan and I I've
been in professional services now about
I think 13 years so a little background
dan and I used to work together and
while he was actually writing signatures
I was deploying the products out in the
field and using the the products in a
production environment so Elizabeth
mentioned we work together we actually
didn't we worked at the same company and
actually didn't know each other at all
we've only been friends now for three
years the reason why we're doing this is
because we'd like to provide you all
with not just a bash fest we all know we
can do that certainly when we've you
know worked with the technology it's
easy to pick on it but what we do want
to do is give you two different views
and our experiences along this fairly
long career in this industry and and
with these particular technologies want
to give a few disclaimers
we we do have quite a few friends in
this industry we're not trying to well
well a good portion of this is bashing
the technology it's awesome and to again
provide you experiences and get you
thinking all right if you leave this and
think oh you know I want to hear a
response from my vendor you shouldn't do
that if you're watching this on youtube
don't bother your vendors already know
these issues there is no original
research presented in this anything that
we show you in terms of evasions is
easily Google you can look up any of
this stuff yourself so there's there's
nothing new here you know we're going to
give some ideas to wear things of course
don't work and do work each one of these
technologies i can tell you we're built
from the ground up completely
differently one of the common
misconceptions especially with say ids
IPS is you might know snort therefore
you think well they're all the same none
of them are the same whether you're
talking open source of commercial not
all of them are snort they are quite
different if you asked me a particular
vendor or even open source I would tell
you you know it's good at this it's not
so good at this they all have their
strengths and and weak so there's good
the bad and the ugly with each one of
the technologies and products right so
certain products work well at certain
things and other products competing
products work better at other things but
one point I want to sort of make is
there's a lot of claims out there right
so many vendors make veni claim any
claims many resellers make money claims
integrators etc some of those claims are
true and some of them are not
necessarily so and what I see most often
in my field and my line of work is
integrators our resellers that don't
truly have an understanding of security
and sort of maybe over selling these
technologies which i think is a large
part and what's creating you know an
environment where people don't truly
understand what the products and
technologies should be doing so that's
kind of the good and bad and ugly so why
might you all by these security
products and this is just a small list
in our experience you could probably add
more to it but there's of course the
feature set is the GUI pretty how's the
UX management one of the most important
things can the product produce pretty
reports that you have management that is
unfortunately a gigantic 1 i've seen you
know the rfp response is that come back
what you hear from analysts perhaps what
you've used before in the past and of
course a lot of it comes down to price
and also in regards to features there's
each one of my clients I talked to a
wide variety of clients on a weekly
basis and with each and individual
product and technology everybody wants
something different and honestly what I
see most often is that people actually
want a technology or a product that will
compensate for a failure they've seen in
a previous product so they get a little
bit of a tunnel vision when they're
picking their product they just want to
make sure it does this one thing that
the last product didn't do so in regards
to analysts this is something that the
vendors have to deal with they generally
have to pay for these analyst
relationships you might have different
stock in these analysts but buying
decisions are absolutely made based on
analyst you know opinion and the thing
you have to realize with analysts is
that a lot of their analysis is not
based on the product or the technology
at all but based on the business where
the vendor is in the market what is
their vision these sorts of things it's
not necessarily does the technology work
or not or what the feature set is or
does it actually you know do anything so
you have to take that with a grain of
salt and of course you do have companies
out there that attempt to be the
consumer reports of the industry and SS
labs ICS a SC magazine you know does
these sort of reviews right so there are
you know none of these are perfect but
you you have to look at a lot of
different criteria so I think a large
predominantly a large portion of
purchasing decisions are made by
relationships right so there's a lot of
different
relationships I myself I pick our
products to partner with honestly at
this point maybe I'm little jaded but I
focus more on business and sort of how
they run their sales organizations and
and you know sort of the professionalism
but we see a lot every day we see a
CISOs or directors of security or CIOs
picking products because favorite
relationship with this reseller and
that's the only product that that
particular reseller partners with within
that technology or maybe you have
friends and buddies maybe you have a
go-to guy and say hey what are you using
for blah and you know if your buddy
likes it and thinks it's okay you kind
of go with it so I think that
relationships actually have a
significant influence possibly more
significant than the technology one
thing to mention on testing you know I
would certainly recommend that you
always do a proof of concept if you can
/ taking a third party I know everyone
likes to have a third party opinion you
don't want to take you know what a
vendor saying on their data sheet you
know to be fact but your own proof of
concept is certainly going to be more
valuable than a third party and if you
are looking at third party make sure you
actually take into account what they're
testing criteria is right everything is
is judgment based on a certain criteria
if you only look at the judgment and not
how they actually did the test its kind
of move and be wary of the false sense
of security so if you have a reseller or
integrator that tells you this is all
you need then I would question that so
how do most organizations pick these
products on an average week i would say
i talked to somewhere about five to ten
different clients within a week ranging
from 500 employees to the fortune 500 so
what I see most often I see scenario
number one clients that we've been
talking for talking to you for two years
that have done nothing in security and
they call us and they say all right this
year we're doing security for reals I
swear I have $50,000 what should I buy
and so we kind of go through the process
and help them figure out what to buy
second scenario is the cio marches into
the CSO's office and says these audits
are killing me go buy an IDs and this T
so says well but we don't have any
people to manage it I don't care go buy
it we need the FFIEC off our back well
but we don't have a skills in house just
go do it so that's a second scenario and
then the third scenario is they don't
really know that they're buying IDs or
some type of monitoring technology they
just call us and say why do i keep
getting infected I have this firewall
and why are all the attacks getting
through and so that kind of leads us
down that path of increasing monitoring
so how do i pick products if for my
clients when I'm helping them what's
going to work so essentially i need to
look at the threats and the pain points
and i figure out what will actually be
the most effective so you're wanting of
course to stop the threats you have to
first ask yourself alright not what
technology should I be buying but what
I'm up problems of course am I trying to
solve and this is where we segue into
picking on fire walls because I a couple
years ago at a mobile conference in New
York made the statement that i didn't
think firewalls were security why
because I look at security as being
threat centric now a lot of people
moaned and hissed and booed and many of
you might disagree as well but let me
tell you what I'm thinking about here so
the security industry has always use
these ridiculous house analogies and so
if we're going to do that I look at the
firewall as the front door right you can
open it and it allows access this might
look familiar this is 10 Downing in
london england one of the most famous
addresses in the world and i can assure
you there's a whole lot more protecting
10 Downing than just the front door all
right so I look at firewalls more like a
saloon door right we know there's tons
of access people walk in and out all the
time so I think that's a better analogy
now of course we learn here every year
from Skylar town that this is real
security locks or security doors I
question that all right but you can add
more than just your locks of course you
can add you can add dogs which I think
fantastic one of the greatest things
that if I ever happen to mankind dogs
are pretty neat because of course you
can use them to let you know if perhaps
exchangers at the door similar to your
IDs you can also train them to sniff
your bags like Airport dogs right let's
liken that to maybe content security and
you can of course also unleash them on
the perpetrator and so that's also a
very nice way to help mitigate so pretty
useful security then of course I think
you've got the original and hack back
the gun which of course was a business
from Chicago so she doesn't get to have
this but in Texas this is used quite
effectively as a hack back technique so
perhaps a better analogy is not the
house but all the various ways that you
would seriously defend a compound with
all the various a Kuchar month that you
can have insecurities not just simple
doors and windows all right so
continuing to pick on firewalls I we
kind of feel like we put ourselves in
this this position right we all said
well we have these 65,000 fantastic
ports back in the day when we could look
at Etsy services and know what
applications were running and then we
said well you need to cut all those off
right if you if you diminish the attack
surface because you have few reports
well then surely will all be more secure
well not so much right now we operate
over mainly three ports 84 for 353 that
sort of thing and we're worse than ever
so thanks Charles doing nice job for all
of us what 15 20 years ago when we were
all saying everything had to go over 80
and 443 we got it we're there great so
now all the attacks are coming over 80
and 443 so the answer you hear from the
firewall vendors of course is buy more
firewalls now they're just called next
generation or as many people call them
now generation so now that we're all
running over the same ports now of
course you need to be able to do deep
packet inspection to be able to pull all
the applications out of those ports all
right so I guess that's the answer that
we or the problem that we created still
not sure that that makes so much sense
so let's look at some of the problems
that firewalls actually introduced
because of course the idea is you by
security technology and it should be
solving problems not creating problems
but it does we of course have the CIA or
is steve war be called it earlier the
AIC and firewalls actually introduce
issues well they might help with
confidential your integrity they
actually can cause availability issues
right actually I want to jump in and say
that i've decided that i'm taking the a
out of the CIA so I don't really care
about availability anymore I've got 99
problems and availability one of them
it's just not my problem but but Dan
tends to care a little bit more about
availability so I'll let him go ahead
and talk about it but just this time
which is actually the issue I mean we
are so wrapped up with confidentiality
and integrity that we oftentimes forget
about the availability and what did the
C&I matter if course you're not even
online or the the you know the asset
isn't even available right so this is a
very common issue in the industry and I
will tell you that I think these only
you know become intersected and closer
as time progresses even some of the
attacks against availability are now
intertwined with other types of attacks
many times application level so let's
look just real quick what is of course
stateful mean well I'll staple means is
that you are tracking a connection for
validity and that you are tracking that
it is an active connection right so
stateful was a great idea before you of
course had botnets now that you have
botnets of course state can then create
a problem because every single device on
your network leading up to your business
critical asset is a potential bottleneck
for an availability issue right that's
how DDoS works right so there's many
other ways that you can do this of
course ACLs work great you can put these
in your routers switches you might say
oh well then you know I have management
issues know there's in modern routers
and switches there are certainly ways
you can do the management
so there's ways around this firewall is
certainly not your own answer you might
be saying oh well that's of course all
fine and dandy but I don't really think
that's an issue well Arbor actually does
a a report each year called the
worldwide infrastructure security report
where we ask all of our customers you
know what was their experience we D das
and as you can see over half of them had
issues with their firewalls and IPS
falling down before the application
server or the application itself fell
down right so these certainly do
introduce availability issues alright so
now that we picked on firewall let's
move on to ids and IPS which is actually
even more fun IPS has the problem even
worse way worse because you're doing
serious deep packet inspection with IPS
you're having to do all your TCP
reordering you've got multiple packets
that are out of order you've got serious
deep parsing of the big protocols of
course that we all work over things like
HTTP regardless of whether you're using
a regular expression is your signature
the parsing for that regular expression
of work is you require are seeing to get
to that point think of all the encoding
you have to deal with around the world
utf-8 utf-16 there's tons of stuff that
an IPS has to worry about just to get to
the point where they can actually match
your signature right that's the whole
point of evasion testing against IDs and
IPS and there's a tons of it you know
you can go back a dozen years with the
whisker tool it's been around for a very
long time and is only getting worse so a
quick review here Gartner likes to say
you know the threat landscape changes
every five six seven years I would tend
to agree back in the late 90s early
2000s right we had nice very clean
network issues this is I would say when
firewalls and IPS actually worked
slammer IPS worked great at stopping all
the worms could be effectively mitigated
quite well actually the problem is the
last worm any of us saw was in november
two thousand eight with conficker and
that was a pretty late comer right so
the issue is and this is really what I
think we're IDs IPS died and firewalls
essentially with it is when everything
moved
you had botnets were extremely
distributed all right a signature can't
track anything that's distributed and
everything moved to the application
level right everything we access is
through our web browser it's even more
so now that the cloud is here Java Docs
cell right all the various issues that
we have to deal with of course anything
Adobe and now of course we have all
sorts of various aspects that now come
along with the multitude of these
threats with various motivations which
of course signatures have no context or
ability to match right they don't know
whether you're from Russia or China or
what matters or when or why which is
kind of the point right that's why they
increasingly match against things that
don't matter right you have high false
positives or you have high false
negatives and to be honest with you you
probably have high both and it's very
difficult to measure we would say
probably the most difficult part is the
fact that no one is measuring it so I'm
embarrassed to use this picture because
I know everybody's used it since the
dawn of time but it is a pretty good
analogy for what attackers do right they
understand you have firewalls they
understand you have IEPs I understand
you have a V right you actually put it
in your compliance they can read PCI
standards just like you can so they know
what they have to work around and that's
exactly what they do so let's look at a
couple examples here javascript this was
probably one of the largest Bane's of my
existence is a signature writer this is
a very easy and simple example you can
see that there's a simple function hear
the alert function in JavaScript is how
you pop up the little box right so
that's why we see a box here and you can
see they're simply converting a numeric
string to text in this case beef again
I'm from Texas all right here you have a
fantastic website this is out of Japan
you can google this right now and you
can see a simple hello world program
written in javascript alert hello
JavaScript it actually turns it into all
the characters you see below if you look
at that that sets forty thousand letters
from those few hello world words that's
a lot of characters for a very short
program now what happens of course when
you get realistic because this
is what your JavaScript really looks
like I actually tried copying and
pasting this exact JavaScript into this
program and it actually crashed my
browser which was surprising you know so
try writing a signature for this it
becomes very very difficult i can tell
you this has been a challenge for the
ids IPS world for quite a long time you
know there are some aspects of it that
can be covered but not all certainly not
all it's extremely difficult because the
attackers have a lot of different
methods here all right now there's no
talk complete without picking on anti
virus while this talk is mainly about
firewalls an IPS we got to go there
because it's fun this is simple DDoS
tool you can see evasions built in right
into the the bot builder panel there are
services of course you don't have to do
any of this yourself just outsources for
twenty bucks per baat you can have a
crypt or service that does all this for
you you can see here's a crypt ER with a
zillion different options for how you
can set up your malware to bypass
antivirus and of course just to make
sure it actually works there are
services that will tell you how
effective they are right the bad guys
used virustotal just like you do and
here you can see right one out of
bazillion different you know one's catch
it right so they can actually predict
how successful their programs going to
be right so they can look at this they
can judge how good am I going to be
against your AV how good am I going to
be against your IPS and of course the
firewall is easy because I know what
port to go over all right again you can
google any of this yourself if you
google how to bypass I Vav things pop up
I'm sure you're all familiar with
metasploit there's a fantastic utility
for metasploit cold she got a gun I
pretty much means in Japanese you're
screwed and it's very effective at
bypassing things like AV and IPS it's
extremely difficult right that's what
pen testers like Elizabeth use all over
the place I see people in the front
smiling because they've used it all
right other things that really make your
life difficult as a signature writer
legit JavaScript compression everybody
uses a JavaScript compression right all
the streaming media Google uses
JavaScript like crazy so not only do you
have to look for what the bad guys are
doing from an obfuscation standpoint
fact is JavaScript has obvious Gatien
because that's how the language works
right that's a feature and that's a
feature that's only gotten better and
better over time of course javascript is
allowed in PDFs all right so then you
put you want to email someone something
you're one of these pen testers it has
high success rate of fishing you can put
javascript in your PDF the exact same
you know exploits we saw earlier the
PDFs can even have PNG's of course
images but the PNG isn't PNG at all it's
an x fa form and guess what that
includes javascript so you have multiple
layers inside of the PDF in order to
hide your javascript there is no way as
a networking device moving at multi gig
speeds with no proxying capability that
you are going to catch this right so
what is your problem in 2014 is it still
slammer funny enough still around in
some parts of the world or is it PDFs
and javas attached to email or that
somebody is clicking on so ask yourself
why are you still using a technology
that was built for a problem in the
early 2000s all right to further that
point all right early in the industry we
all talked about well we write
signatures for the vulnerability not the
exploit this had to do with well if you
write one signature that's good for the
vulnerability all the various ways an
attacker can craft the x-point one
matter well that worked again great when
you were you know going after things
that were warm based because you could
actually see the vulnerability being
triggered in the network traffic again
the moment you move to content can't do
it parsing those things again is very
difficult and very slow I mean the
performance goes down the crapper quick
so what a lot of vendors did was the
only thing they could do while they
start looked looking at more heuristic
behavioral type signatures let's start
looking at the exploit it actually
reversed some of your most effective
signatures right now are not
vulnerability based they are not going
to have a CV associated with them it's
actually the problem with IPS is that it
was meant for these vulnerabilities and
now of course compliance is asking you
or your boss is asking you I read about
this you know heartbleed vulnerability
so I can feel better we can check the
box you might have a signature for it
but when you get owned and you go back
and say why did the signature not
trigger that's the wrong question right
your vendor will give you an answer and
it won't matter what you should be
asking is did that signature ever
trigger ever at all I mean like ever
maybe in the world right you have
signatures that flat out don't work they
just make you feel better I mean if you
get owned look it up check out the CVE
look and see whether that signature ever
ever fired if there's a user group or a
community that you can ask whether it's
open source of commercial IPS ask a
question anybody ever seen the signature
fire tons of them have never fired
guaranteed half the signatures you get
every month from for Microsoft Super
Tuesday I guarantee you'll never see
fire regardless of whether you're
getting targeted by those attacks or not
promise you that all right so signatures
don't matter it is not about how many
signatures you have it's not about how
many signatures you have turned on what
you should be looking at is do they ever
actually fire all right moving into
application detection right because
that's the new thing well I PS isn't
standalone market anymore we don't buy
that stand alone anymore now we've
shoved IPS and firewall together right
you take two crappy things and you put
them together and it makes it better
you're still using the exact same
technology right how do you do
application detection deep packet
inspection a lot of signatures a lot of
deep parsing it's the same thing a
matter of fact I PS was doing
application detection before next-gen
firewalls were right you just had to go
actually find the signatures and turn
them on they weren't there by default
they weren't wrapped into a fancy policy
where you could manage them based on
application right so the issue is this
actually opens up a new field because
you are now whitelisting applications
potentially right the whole idea is you
don't black list or whitelist you gray
list what is the policy that we're going
to allow well if you whitelist an
application most of those
next-generation firewalls led all of
that through well what if there's a
vulnerability in that application you
just let it through so it's kind of moot
you've basically whitelisted the whole
thing you're now no longer looking for
those attacks
of course you can make fun of all the
naming criteria here but I think the
question for Elizabeth and I and so many
has been is this really a security issue
right when she's doing pen test is she
using facebook for those not generally I
would guess so that's kind of the big
question about the ng firewalls what is
an ng firewall right what does it by you
so when we're talking to people and you
know they're talking about their
security plan for the next 12 months
they I think they actually think that an
ng firewall will protect all layer 7
threats and and minimize you know
infections and things like that and I'm
like actually I think what it does is
all the stuff that I really couldn't
care less about I don't care if people
are out on facebook to me all of the
applications are really just an HR
productivity issue I just don't care I
care about the threats that are coming
through those applications absolutely
and do I think ng firewalls the best
technology to protect against those
threats yeah maybe not maybe not so much
so it's it's sort of a this whole
concept with the ng firewall that it's
buying you better security and I don't
think it is I think it's buying you
better control over your employees so
the other thing about IDs is what which
I'm seeing which i think is a big change
from sort of the IPS Azure IDS's of 15
years ago 15 years ago you can open up a
policy pretty much every you know
product that was available you are able
to view your signatures you are able to
view details of your events what I'm
seeing predominantly and I'll just pick
on maybe the uTM's and some of the
managed service or cloud-based services
you have no visibility into the product
right so I feel like the management and
the policy setting in the reporting has
severely degraded over the past 15 years
I there's so many products out there
that have sort of turned into the set it
and forget it so my big joke is well if
an ideas triggers in the woods and
doesn't tell anyone does it make a sound
I mean I see so many you know products
out there that it'll trigger an event
and it tells you security event you
don't know what it is you don't know
what poor
of the packet triggered the event you
don't know if it was you know part of a
content filtering event or an ids event
so I think that that's part of for
myself at least when I'm trying to use
IDS's the you know the challenge is if I
can't see what it's doing how do I know
it's working and maybe I'm a control
freak but I need to know that and I need
to have visibility in addition a
significant portion for me of the value
in an IDs or IPS is being able to create
custom signatures so what I want to be
able to do is if I see some anomalous
DNS traffic I want to create a signature
and I want to pick and choose to
specific eye peas and things like that
well guess what a lot of these products
you can't adjust the policy you can't
creates custom signatures these are very
scaled-down versions of the technologies
and I feel it's just degraded the value
of those products and you actually saw
it in the market right in ids because
you weren't in line you could afford to
do deep packet and meaning deeper packet
and you could actually provide context
behind the event right you would have
tons of little data as to why it
triggered where of course when you went
to the IPS world you were blocking so
who cared well the problem was of course
then you didn't know why you were
blocking right because you couldn't go
as deep as you wanted to write you
triggered you blocked you moved on just
because you're generating events of
course as we all know now doesn't make
them exactly valuable and actually
there's a quote of the day which i love
p kappa door it didn't happen so if i
don't get a packet capture the data
portion of the packet or some portion
whatever triggered it to me it didn't
happen and it means nothing to me
couldn't agree more so let's take a walk
down memory lane I like this part
because I get to pick on Dan a little
bit so let's talk 15-20 years let's just
say when I start in the industry may be
about 17 years ago I worked at a 160,000
employee company and we were evaluating
IDS's at the time the market was not
even defined so we had semantics coming
in and selling us vulnerability
assessment programs as IDS's this is
back in the day symantec had bought like
layer 7
which is a technology or company that
has long since gone away but when I was
out in the field and I was actually
doing assessments and doing pen testing
those signatures that Dan was writing
they didn't work they didn't stop me
there was not a single and because we
were an IDs vendor our clients you know
very often had our products running and
if they if they hired us to come in and
do the testing on a quarterly basis or
something like that they had a pretty
good security program and you know I had
some really good visibility well
everything that I did to own their
network they could not detect it or stop
it we used to have cat-and-mouse games
where at the end of the day what they
the only way that they could actually
detect us is to put pork control on the
switches right so as soon as they saw us
plug in and see a little bit of activity
they would physically come and find us
so why didn't they work that well if we
go back to the previous few slides
looking at the threat landscape they
worked really well for the conficker for
the for the Code Red and the worms like
that those you know five to ten really
high threat very prevalent type
signatures that we're using predefined
you know exploits that signatures could
detect well I was working in a
production environment when I'm breaking
into an environment I can't run exploits
against the domain controller are you
crazy I mean the exploits did not you
know necessarily they were but they
weren't in a production manner meaning
you run you ran the really good chance
if you ran an exploit against a domain
controller you're going to bring down
the domain controller so we had to get
creative and find different ways to
break in and in doing so you know we had
to sort of find the needles in the
haystack and pug her out you know plug
away well the IDs we just look like
normal users there's no amount of
signatures that would be able to see us
on an internal network so i think that
there's a big misconception that IDs and
IPS worked great you know at its
inception 15 years ago but guess what it
never worked that great nothing has
changed it's just that the threat
landscape was smaller and it did detect
those more prevail in attacks now we're
in a different world right so we've got
you know much more attack many many more
attack vectors many more infections and
botnets obfuscation and things like that
that are hindering the detection all
right so if any of you saw Rob's talk
yesterday he didn't have issues with
these kinds of threat based or
networking based technology stopping him
it was sneaky auditors that were busting
him all right which it's the other
technology and the one thing I will say
is the ids and IPS as they absolutely
give you visibility there's value in
them in those technologies and I don't
care what technology it is any
technology that gives you visibility
into the the activity on your network
that has value right we all want to have
eyes and ears but with ids IPS
specifically i would ask you how much
value so this brings us to the
fundamental issue of course you can't
trust your vendor can only trust
yourself as ice cube told us on the
album predator who do i trust me that's
who so so what I'm seeing in the field
so it again forgive me maybe I'm a
little bit jaded but I talked to a lot
of different clients and there's a lot
of lack of knowledge out there so these
are just a few examples of what I've
seen in the field an example is a small
health care clinic they have about it's
a non-profit great organization
something around 15 to 20 clinics around
the city and they have a managed service
that runs their firewall which they
always thought oh this managed provider
you know they take care of all of the
security and so they had an incident it
was a an attentional malicious breach
and the IT dude called up the managed
service provider because his account was
locked out and the service provider said
you know what's those mine me too I mean
come on huge misconception they had no
eyes and ears and you know in the
network we really could not figure out
what was what had occurred there was no
logging
you know none of those things were
defined and part of that sure shame on
the client but come on it's a managed
service provider do you mean to tell me
that you don't even talk about saving
logs so that was one example the other
situation can you go back one the other
situation was a small 500 employee
company in the financial industry they
were sold uTM's by an integrator and
literally told the CIO that this is
everything you need right because it's
not all in one that definition means
everything you need so they're like why
the hell do i keep getting infected they
didn't have any workstation hardening
they didn't have any other solutions in
place just that UTM was going to cure
all for them but then I see of course
you know the larger companies say a
10,000 person company and in this
situation they had a serious mail where
problems so they they had something like
I want to say tenri images a day so as a
big problem they actually did they
recognize those failures and they sort
of cleaned it up they did deploy IDs and
IPS i don't i think one is running in
true IPS mode and one is just in
promiscuous but they truly do get the
value out of it they use it for
investigations they use it for
visibility I can't say exactly what
portion of their security budget they
spent on it but it wasn't a lot and they
do a lot of other things and they're
actually using it properly and it was a
good purchase and it's working well then
I have like a fortune 1000 client that
just spent 7 figures on ids and IPS and
basically are doing it there in you know
a heavily audited or governed
environment they bought it for the
auditors and that just kind of makes me
sick to my stomach I don't know they
don't have the team to manage it seven
figures how much can we do with that
much money and for a security program
right but they had to do it because the
auditors said so so that was definitely
a compliance check box
alright so some of the things we would
do so of course as you hear many times
do pay attention to HD Moore's law it is
a pretty good indicator for of course
what is out there and available two
attackers the IPS vendors do that right
the third-party testers all do that not
only they use metasploit their soyuz of
course things like canvas core impact
there's a company that actually supplies
all these companies with both malware
vulnerability and even signatures so now
the industry is getting so commoditized
things are so you know now rolled into
one you have price pressure the
technology a of course is now actually
getting worse because things are now
being even outsourced at your vendor
level right so this isn't you know like
i said i wouldn't go now question or go
beat up your vendor they know all this
stuff it's a fundamental technology
issue and of course at the end of the
day the way these things are deployed
and used so again you have to look at
what you're protecting and what might
best protect it Steve were be I think
earlier today had some very good
examples as to how to do that
outsourcing is one of those potential
things I've certainly seen outsourcing
that was a good idea because of course
you didn't have the resources you didn't
have the expertise you didn't have the
money sometimes that's a good idea if
your only reason for outsourcing is
saving money probably a bad idea all
right so i would certainly avoid the you
know your mess for less because then
you're just going to get a bunch of logs
and a bunch of logs doesn't really get
you out of anything and these two bolded
items up here the Badger success over
time a measure failure constantly those
are two key messages I try to really
drive home with my clients you know I
and again maybe I'm old and jaded but
we're not looking for utopia and most of
the organization's i'm working with
they're building a security program
right so they're a little bit less
mature so my advice to them is to just
constantly improve right look to make
improvements or over a period of time if
you go into it trying to have utopia
utopian environment you will fail and
then in terms of measuring that first of
all measure whatever you can write is
whatever statistics data you can gather
and collect and report on that's great
and as you implement different
technologies monitoring etc I would
expect that your reporting in your data
would increase right so if you deploy
more tools and more controls you should
see an increase in the incidence or
events and and sort of like a bell curve
right as you become more mature you know
there's going to be a period of time
where you ramp up and you increase
visibility and you should see a lot of
events and that's a good thing and your
success should be measured by how many
uz where success is an increase and then
over time as you you know implement more
controls and get more mature the number
of incidents and events you see should
go down but that's going to be a period
of time really you've got whether you've
got an act of deployment of an ids IPS
or whether you're looking at purchasing
and again this doesn't matter if its
standalone or not right it doesn't
matter over if to you TM or next-gen
firewall right they're all doing the
same thing measure the events you're
getting right look into those and see
whether there are false positives or not
look at your proof of concept you know
if you want to sit there and fire a
couple things at it with metasploit
you're not testing the capability of
that technology at all you need to test
it in your real-world environment and
measure that if you do want to screw
with the IPS vendor and use metasploit
it's hilarious and awesome all you have
to do is change the exploit guaranteed
you will bypass them it's not an issue
they are writing exploit signatures
today it's all they can do don't blame
them but if you want to see a bypass
just go mess with the exploit a little
bit throw a little JavaScript ovulation
in there you'll scoot past them every
single time all right you want my
opinion I think you heard it earlier
today from others knock it off of this
defense in depth crap I generally hear
that right from vendors with very broad
portfolios that want you to buy more
product that's what it sounds like to me
stop you know asking what your
competition is doing these ice axe are
very very useful and have helped with
that level of ability right but you know
did target really care what TJ maxx had
done years ago I mean it it doesn't
matter right so many of these attacks
are targeted at you right being in
line with where the rest of the industry
is it doesn't really help anything
industry standards as I mentioned
they're published everybody knows them
including the attackers we all know
compliance has now been proven to be
near useless and at the issue you know
at the end of day I think if either one
of us received so you know your your job
time is a ticking clock you know the
first person to get fired is to see so
you know that happens all the time right
whether the company's stock price is
affected their brand reputation is
affected your job is affected right so
you buying especially from these large
companies where you that used to be the
safe move right that's no longer buying
job security that's going to produce
what's called a resume generating event
and your IDs does not have a signature
for that so I'm just going to tell Dan
just shut up it all still works so what
frustrates me quite often let's just
refer back to my previous case study
with the client that just cannot stop
getting infected don't ask me why your
firewall doesn't block an autorun
infection go disable auto run on your
workstations I mean come on defense in
depth works muaks is talked yesterday
about talking talking about using proxy
servers and and canary accounts there's
all types of creative ways that you can
implement controls at different layers
so defense-in-depth still works don't
think defense-in-depth means firewall IP
sav anymore no no no all right which is
exactly what people continue to buy
uTM's that's exactly what they are
next-gen firewall at the end of the day
really all that is is an
enterprise-grade UTM all right you're
shoving a bunch of technology into one
thing and when you do that things suffer
you're no longer good any one thing
you're mediocre at a bunch of stuff and
performance is hugely affected SSL is a
great example oh you want ssl on your
security device good luck when you
actually turn it on you might gain a
little bit more visibility I'd measure
that but your performance is going to
suffer incredibly so the good vendors I
I talked to all of them it's exhausting
the good vendors that sell technologies
that do multiple things they will be
honest with you and and tell you maybe
it's me because I'm a partner and you
know they feel like they can be more
honest than they are with the clients
but a good vendor will tell you
precisely what the box is designed to do
the resellers or maybe certain sales
people or you know certain characters in
the in the mix they may not understand
that and they may be over selling these
technologies so you just have to be
careful about that and always ask the
question and keep program probing if you
don't feel like you've gotten a good
answer not saying people are being
dishonest I'm just saying they may not
have the knowledge I know if you hear ya
should we say it together if you hear
the words this is all you need run
shikata and I all right so really what
would we do again your your technology
does not have a signature for when
security fails right so I'm with
Elizabeth if you can packet capture
everything man there's there's a lot of
technologies and just human power that
of course can really dig into things
deeper there's just so much more you can
do so you know really you know PCI gives
you compensating controls for all these
you know issues that they think might be
solved with these legacy legacy
technologies what you really want is a
competent control for all those stupid
compensating controls you have to deploy
so most of what I see the most effective
security programs are those that
implement controls and technologies to
plan for the other technologies and
controls to fail right so my content
filtering will catch what my ids and IPS
doesn't my IDs and IPS will catch what
my firewall doesn't my endpoint will
catch you know what well not much but
something right macro viruses maybe so
but in short these solutions each one of
them all have value how much is
questionable but plan for and implement
your controls for all the other controls
to fail
it's not a you know- lifestyle the live
it's just kind of smart planning and
designing I think so thank you very much
I don't think we have any time for
questions but will be around for a few
more minutes here and of course you can
always abuse us on Twitter that's what
it's for thank you thank you