um thank you uh very nice to see all of
you here today uh so what I would like
to talk is about uh using side channel
for Blackboard starting this work uh was
done as part of X-Files project
this is European project for forensic
research
um
pausing part it was mostly done by risk
so what's the idea uh for this topic
when we are in a white box setting and
we want to do vulnerability research we
want to find some uh marks in the
product there is a lot of different
methods and you probably use a lot of
them for example if you have source code
we can do source code review
it will have binaries we drop them into
our favorite tool we can do reverse
engineering and understand how it works
behind the box
maybe we can do debug for example if it
is software you can just connect with
your debugger if it is Hardware maybe
you have jpeg or something so you can
always try to find a way to make it
easier to understand how the product
works
where other bars and how to explore them
you can do advising yeah
pause maybe it's some binary for a
specific platform you emulate all of
these there's quite a few methods there
but what if we are in a lack of setting
so we have some sort of device and we
really want to try to understand how it
works
we probably don't have any stress we
don't have the implementation we don't
know how it's supposed to work what's
the design of the product we don't have
the source code
we don't have the binder if there are
OTA HD probably updated we cannot just
get the binders from updates as well the
memory is protected maybe it is the
small equipment so nothing really
in this case it is much more difficult
so indeed the product plan for you is a
black box
so can we use pausing in this case to
try to help us to explore the target
even that we have it in our heads so
that's one of the things we try to
leverage because we have a device we and
all this we can connect all kinds of
equipment to it uh and we can try to
understand what it does based on the
side channels it leaks so that's just
that word for example what kind of side
channels can we talk about
uh so the classic one when we talk about
side channel in general we have a power
choice or em Trace
and that's used a lot uh in attacking
devices mostly for technical
cryptographic Secrets but here we can
try to use the same information the
traces the equation traces to understand
uh what kind of code is
maybe there is a flash memory and if we
try to see if a specific code tries to
access flash and just all the
flashlights or we can see the USB if
it's used here in the specific execution
uh DDR memory the gpios even LEDs all
this information
if you can collect it and process
appropriately you can try to use to
understand
uh what the target actually does and
so
today's simple approach we have our
python engine this is quite standard if
you have your software is the same you
have a custom engine we use AFL in this
case we'll make it more complex
because an engine can produce us the
data which we're going to use for
projects or the requests are coming from
requests here coming from the attention
or whatever it tells us we have sort the
harness to first we need to send this
data so ideally when we talk about
Blackboard flashing it's still not agree
there is some sort of interface
for example if you have a smartphone
there's maybe a proprietary coverage
patient about there's no information
you can still send something once maybe
get something
to try to understand what it does
so the hardness can send the requests we
hopefully get some responses maybe the
target is silent and gives us nothing
back but you just try to see if there's
any data
and we can get a bunch of different size
channels
[Music]
so for example if you talk about em
Trace we will connect
em
if
gpio the same way we can just see if the
signal changes there and all these
traces somehow in our harness we have
the coordination
even the request it wants to tell us it
wants us to tell if this was the same
path foreign
so the idea is quite simple
um just merging these two approaches
together for implementation there is
quite a bit of different details so
first of all
uh responses uh that part so I needed
you can get new response
you can deduct that we'll see you have
uh the same with timing if you cook
different time lightly at different
executions
foreign
and so on the only problem there is we
don't just have these different
responses independently all of them all
that collected different side channels
or each execution uh path needs to be
processed together so what we have here
is a here of different site channels for
example if you got different responses
it matters for us more that they're
different than that of the same timings
so we don't say about the same timing it
is the same path say the responses were
different that means it has more High
precedence than some
so we have to Define for ourselves there
uh which ones are more important
uh that's kind of how it looks in a
simple case for example imagine you have
only two uh sources you have responses
the day to get back and you have time
and you try to come up with a unique
label so
the nice thing is this is extendable so
we can always add another layer of
different side channels so here we can
put for example uh em trace or command
line of the flash memory let's see there
is a new command
but for these layers you see we got
different response and go into sub
branches and for example for the
response one the timing one we get label
one at the same time in one for the
response to we get different label label
four and that approach that's quite
easily create this graph of all
different labels and
you can just check the tree go here
check if the response is present this is
quite simple foreign
with timing it starts to be tiny bit
more difficult still uh not because of
course we have Jitter and that's always
to be the problem
uh so the traces are noisy the time is
never precise uh for that still you can
tackle quite easily by having like
Pockets saying we have timing plus minus
some percentage and that's the same one
if it's much different than even
uh but the moment we go to Power traces
it becomes even more difficult so it's
not uh one-dimensional anymore uh the
traces are a two-dimensional we have
Jitter on the traces as well so we're
gonna have some noise there this is just
for my smart card you can see that the
start of the command there is a bit of
different operation happening
it has never precisely done
and the thing is when we process it we
also need for the traces uh tackle this
problem with noise so uh what did we do
so the idea is simple as well we we do
faster we have different choices I want
to say is it the same label if so that's
the clustering classic
although data is noisy we on top of that
extra problem for us we have to Cluster
them randomly so we get the new Trace
one morning Trade Center we have to say
it doesn't belong to these clusters and
if it's not we have to recluster
everything again so we can add this new
path
and unfortunately not a lot of
algorithms are implemented in my
classroom
foreign
with um devices we have one setup maybe
two or three but you cannot just say I'm
gonna have hundred thousand setups and
relatively variable the
much effort to
handle
so and of course we talked to the Target
on the device single executions and
maybe we have uh joints maybe 30 maybe
just few executions per second depending
how fast the target is and we don't
really want to slow down on top by doing
our cluster so we need to have some kind
of
so with that we went to try to explore
how we can do a clustering so we've got
some traces of a smart card just to
start a story these are actual traces we
added some noise artificially and
applied it to different
so hdb scan is one of the two candidates
which we're considering for clustering
you can see here
uh there are actually five different
commands in this uh
based on the trace only it can
distinguish two different classes and
they're quite separate so one of the
traces was different than others all the
others are similar enough so you can
actually do that
the problem is the moment we have more
noise which work you should add here we
got more mistakable traces and that's
something we really don't want to have
in our case in some place uh cases when
we do clustering in general
it can be all right here if we mislabel
the trace for example we have the same
cost but our custom algorithm tells us
that was A New Path we will tell the
father it was the new execution path and
will create a new favorite execution uh
adding to the set of data and that will
reduce the effectiveness of the project
so if we will create a lot of uh false
positives it will just slow down and
render out the addition of other users
[Music]
so
um what I eventually uh ended up using
is Yuma uh just for passion because uh
two benefits of it it does damage
allergy reduction so we can get rid of a
lot of noise just focusing on the
important parts and it handles noise
quite well due to that reason as well
even before a lot of noise
you can see it's still attacks
classes properly and it displays just in
this case one percent of the traces we
can live with that this is never a
problem it is never gonna ruin entirely
our project can be where these labels
addresses but we'll try to avoid it as
and of course on top of that
um it is not a Magic Bullet you still
need to have very good signal so we
cannot just say we got any Targets we
connect this mode somehow to random
capacitor and see
there is a lot of uh processing which
needs to be done here
if they have Amo Power Trace to explore
the world of different combinations of
using filtering uh maybe problems
frequency domain using free access form
that was actually quite a useful uh
method for some targets if there is
different leakage in the time domain in
the frequency domain then we don't
really care about zero damage jader will
not be shown on the transport frequency
phases so that helps us to kind of avoid
the whole misalignment noise Market
leakage of course it only works if
you're different paths different
execution paths will link in the
frequency Center they all kind of have
the same frequencies it's not going to
give away
[Music]
uh with all these things together so
having the labeler having uh the message
for uh clustering the traces uh labeling
the timings and the data all together we
could actually go and explore how
efficient is
an actual targets
so we tried a few use cases uh the first
one uh simple smart card use case so we
had
uh Java cards we put some Outlet on it
uh we wrote that with ourselves just uh
so we can use this applet to understand
how efficient with others of course we
don't use this knowledge or whatever the
commands are or anything for their
passing itself we didn't give any Corpus
empty
and to make it even more difficult we
did not give any data responses from
different commands all the responses are
the same sport is
always 90. so uh in this case father can
actually rely too much on the data it
has to rely on the sidechain
just to see how it is
so that's more or less
code you can see here
uh so all these series return the same
uh status code there are some different
amounts or for example one of them will
feel their right Instagram
right another one would use the user
provided value and that many bytes and
so on so it is quite simple but it just
does a bit of different uh usual uh
operations but a lot of products
if we just get the traces with a scope
just to see how it looks like you
already see uh that there is a potential
for using these traces or distinguished
ones you can see these are all different
commands
and uh that traces to human already look
quite different so the uh cluster
algorithm you shouldn't have too much
trouble and the timing for the traces
also
so uh in this case having like a small
Target which is not too fast and often
smart cards are
black boxes so you don't even have to
source code so for this use case it is
quite actually it can be useful to apply
these method to explore
and yeah that's the results so for the
Benchmark we compared it to just sending
randomly
without any feedback just throw the data
at it and see what kind of costs you can
cover you can see that the random
approach is not really going to explore
in depth because the moment you cover
all your basic uh inputs uh you have to
move towards values entirely and then
you don't have the average situation
also it will just Flatline for very long
time sometime later you might pump just
by accident reversing some constant
which have to go uh we'll get a deep
coverage but for most of it it will be
users or they're passing approach you
can see there's already quite a bit of a
tiny bit of difference on the first 20
000 executions these are the number of
executions and this is the average
percentage
and
eventually it also slows down
further executions uh the study takes
but still eventually you would expect to
yeah
so that was already uh nice of course we
wrote this code ourselves so it is not
too much of a challenge for the
Blackboard scenario
we were considering trying to do it on
some kind of lack of targets the only
problem is it is quite difficult process
the results so to see how capable the
record uh did we find something useful
or was it customized so for this
presentation we
tried to use a real life uh ish Target
so this is a pine cone uh it is open
sourceful it has
the code is available it has used as one
double stages so we try to use it uh for
assessing all the visual Studio
and we the nice thing is it has the
Dapper the pine64 has the same socs
phone itself so we can run the code on
the dashboard and try to explore it
there see how it can be useful in a more
realistic scenario
and having the source code in the specs
can help us to understand what we found
with the buzzer was an actual
differences in the code or was it just
uh
so yeah we have the source code and it
is real life but it's not necessarily
superval so so you will see later this
uh
you both implementation is
this phone doesn't have security so it's
just you would uh
using that for
um that's how the setup looks uh quite
simple and elegant
um if I say so
uh it uh these three main components
while the scope uh we have a few uh
serial interfaces here on top you can
see there is relay board
targets sometimes it will crash
hopefully or it will hunt so we need to
reset it so
continue watching and we have the target
here with a
yeah
and you see contrasting here because I
use
to hold the rules
um so with that we can do our attempt in
passing the target
um
this is some of the results we've got
yes and too much time in it but first we
started with no purpose at all so we
didn't tell the buzzer whatever the
commands are uh gave the embassy Corpus
and it starts to explore and just after
a few hours it we already find 16
different formats
placed the
only responses from the Target and the
timing so in use traces uh powertraces
here because the target is much noisier
with a smart card use case we see very
distinct traces here the EM trace of the
saw is not really useful what could be
useful here is using some other sites
and for example
um
lines to the flesh so if you connect to
the command line of The Flash you can
see if there are more commands and
because there are some paths in your
boot which will trigger or using some
other side Channel while using the em in
general
and yeah execution is not super fast we
get six attempts per second on average
which is not amazing but
and yeah that's how it looks not really
anything new to you I guess
it's a bit of a special game but for the
rest it does
he doesn't really have one of the things
which actually struggle a lot is
stability so normally when you have
traditional clothing unless you have
some weird code like the Mystic or
random stuff you're coming from Target
you'll probably care about stability
for us even that we have traces and it's
all a bit of a delivery noise and stuff
uh you can see if we are not careful in
the processing it can drop almost to
zero so nice probably useless that's
something you
will see how useful your section of data
if specific side channel is not useful
you can always swap with another
sections
if
em doesn't give me any additional
information
maybe just like we did here for some
time you know which was useful
uh another time to try it is to do it
with all the available commands you
would it's not too difficult to guess
what the commands are going to be so we
gave it to the mother let it run for a
little while and see how well it will
score
um
it could find a bit more things uh
that's uh nice and uh the best part well
of course eventually the bloodlines
so here it is not long execution only uh
few hours
and given the speed of course as good as
per second
like ideally run it for a few weeks and
see how far you have to actually get
some Industries but as I mentioned
before this is not really very secure
protected Target so even after a few
hours you can see that and that is
actually very nice so if you're familiar
with your boots this is the command
puzzles and this MD memory display
which will supposed to print some data
but
is actually
thieves
[Music]
um
what nice about this target is that we
got these crash tops and that's a great
thing we didn't know the purpose a lot
in this research on handling their
crashes which is the whole different
problem in generic level of scenario
when you have just for example no
information and only the trace and you
try to understand if the target crash
but that would be uh all different story
to figure it out ideally for this use
case it is very simple every time we get
the crash we got a beautiful down and
you don't have to worry about
so that was nice uh we could see that it
actually works of two different targets
uh being very happy about ourselves and
then looking at the
one of the runs of the father we found
something interesting that we already
believe her so this is your signal and
other commanders that's the CRC of the
memory for whatever
that's probably not something you want
to have
uh this index is simple you have uh
CRC commands you give it the address and
links and it will compute source and no
surprise you've got a few different
parts because the data required
but what we've also found that the time
to execute these commands is also
and that was a bit unexpected because
you wouldn't expect CRC really be time
dependent on the date itself much you
would expect the lengths
again a lot but even the same length
length of CRC you would expect close
enough times
so we explored it more Run for the CRC
come on only this is just a few hours of
execution but a lot of different ones
and if we plot the timings we work from
the buzzer that's how it looks like and
you see this is not really complete you
have to run it for a few more hours but
you see there's some artifacts you would
expect from the closer this line is a
lot of different lots of a lot of
different attempts with other food on
this line so this is actually where the
timings increase on the bottom we have
the addresses
normally it takes just about uh just
below a milliseconds to you compute CRC
of 4000 X bytes and
for some addresses it takes much longer
so it looks somewhat like this and this
is not really the behavior we expect
but
we run it for longer and one of the
benefits of this target we've got the
data sheet of this target
what we can see there are different
members at this
so for example we have uh
or we have different srams or later on
we have DDR and although CRC computation
itself is close enough for different
data
we get the different timings just
because the hardware underneath is uh
for example here as well we see at least
address somewhere at 41 000 we start to
get two different timing this is not
even in the memory map but uh exploring
a bit more there is some peripherals
some control registers we can still
compute CRC of this memory you can just
see that it takes longer than when we do
it
and that was uh one unexpected result
from this uh research we were planning
to try to use side channel for getting
information about software which runs on
the market but we also could see the
differences in actual Hardware
underneath and that was
nice service
um and yeah just gonna uh to see how
actually different it is you can do it
separate later and check how much the
difference or different memory uh
uh difficult different physical numbers
so for example you can see there are
some SRM which is much faster than
another restaurant or EDR of course is
much much faster than any other battery
and this information actually can help
you explore and you can see the
difference is quite big so you can
actually
rely on the timing information we are
quite
like
and that's uh most of the presentation
so a few takeaways
will try to do and apply coverage guided
buzzing to blackbox targets it works for
multiple different targets not all the
side channels are equally useful for
different ones but uh with enough of
manual exploration there can be used if
you have to explore Target about which
you don't know anything
um
The Crossing is very slow that's very
important you know so if you have if you
can help the Corpus make it better and
give like useful things for the other to
start that helps a lot and the syntax is
also a big thing so if you get illegal
syntax uh like for complex commands and
you can help deposit with the syntax
that can also improve your performance a
lot and sometimes the software you don't
really have to care you can ignore the
Throne of course or away could be longer
here you would have to wait long long
time if you have wrong signals so if you
can help that uh make it last black box
of the father that always helps
and finally something we didn't even
expect so we don't only detect software
differences with this approach but also
the hardware devices which is a nice
thank you very much that's what I
represent today and if you have any
questions
thanks Sergey uh do we have questions to
Sergey from the audience
this video
thank you very much
I found this a very fascinating approach
and the reason is that
uh software fuzzy we associate the idea
of coverage to look through the coverage
of software
so that's basically the spaces we're
exploring and we assign this to the
meaning of we are going through the
different software branches and
exploring it for fuzzy what we are
exploring here is something a different
space
the Eastern Dimension is the dimension
of the difference we can perceive to say
challenge so for example if you actually
hit two different software Parts in the
code
that actually at the same timing and the
same such unknown response they would
not be distinguishable in what you see
is this correct you want to say yes yes
so the question sorry
how do you think this could relate so
this because the real version codes
while the Leo is fuzzing to information
that may be not exactly related to the
actual the code College uh how do you
think this which direction will bring us
because I think this is between
something very interesting there's
something quite different
about these two Notions of coverage
matches already done okay yeah so indeed
a wireless software will most focus on
this uh separate blocks like separate
execution blocks here we focused on the
whole execution Trace so it was a bit of
a different approach what one thing we
could uh borrow from software so
normally you focus in separate blocks
here we take the whole Trace we can also
subsplit different uh traces like side
Channel and also focus on parts of it to
see if there is more information we can
recovery so it can get a bit more from
software like rolling for basic blocks
of uh if we can detect this information
inside chat also timing you can also
just how long it takes but maybe for a
trace you can see uh you know there is
access to flash in the first millisecond
and there is access to USB in the next
in a second and that will give us the
notion of basic blocks like in software
and that would be maybe one nice thing
just saying is that
implements instead of rather than
clustering traces let's say clustering
soft blocks in order to say this looks
similar in general and this would be a
problem would it be visible well visible
part is a difficult question we consider
that the problem is uh we start to get a
lot of noise very quickly so if we
substitute it a lot it's gonna
put more pressure on us to be very
precise for each of them but indeed if
there is a target which doesn't give us
too much trouble with side channels
that's something we could do like if you
see is separate very clear parts of that
we can subsplit traces and try to
Cluster them separate we will get more
but do we have any other questions from
the audience
we lost okay uh another round of
applause to Sergey