hello everyone thank you for coming uh
Welcome to talak My name is
[Music]
see
after that we'll give you any
information
these examples
lastly we will talk about attack and
so we have used the NBC 1353 it is part
of the NBC family we have the
Olympics
can see this instructions
uh some of the previous work that I've
done in their disease
so our main goal is to try to study the
LBC about working mechanism then we will
try to Target
the LBC series they have something
called Accord protection CRV CRP is the
conclusion name in the nxp some other
things
such as excuses
uh they have available actions so I'll
be one two and three all of them will
disable the JPEG and each of them will
have a dedicated value so the main
difference between them is related to
the ISP minus destruction the ISP is a
Serial uh protocol to access the memory
action
NBC to do some operations such as
so reviews are easily just
just by writing the crb value here
a specific address
and it will let you get the opportunity
and for the LBC 13 series is
the address is the 0x
and in this table we can see remember
the CRV is set
and here we have the nbc13 lab
exists
the second one is
yes and the third one is the right side
respond to the system before register
which is actually recognizable
it gets used to
do a disabled
and here we have the Boost process
we have two area where the CRP will be
checked the first one is the green area
which will be targeted this is just
simply reading the filter of 0x square C
and paste it is
in case of any matching it will disable
the JTAG in other cases another case it
will just
area where the ispu commands should
happen and there is
again to do the ISP
that's
nice
okay after we've done that because
it's basically nothing
so we did reverse this part of this
process
as you kind of did as you see at the
beginning it will load I needed value
and prepare the register then it will
load the function of 0x to a c e to r or
register
and this in that content
that we have the three main scenarios
let's start with the COPD
and there it will lower the crp2
throughout the resistance as you can see
here and after that it will store the
auto register resistance register to
disable the jpeg
today
and here it's been again
then
after register will distort the system
doesn't register okay type
and so again let's help you evaluates
used here
and other cases including crp2 which
will follow the WR
and this is
the distance equal to the crp2 it will
disabled Zeta in other cases it's
enabled
uh so we can notice here it's like a
magic value
which is
okay in this slide you try to abstract
produce process
it's usually
uh
foreign
so we have an attack
while regarding the application memory
somehow the integration value or
registered value or bypassion
and as you can see in the excusework
most NPC have I will know exactly the
CRV configuration
uh
you can see it's a 32-bit register where
the only key values is used
so we have much chances
is
hello again in this slide in upcoming
our brief of what is Fault injection
techniques and some examples so both
injection is basically a hardware
corruption during the execution on a
normal device this Hardware corruption
would cause
defined behavior and
sometimes it's a h flip
even instruction or even changing in the
structure the interesting interesting
thing is sometimes even though if you
execute the same exact exact glitch
again the causes May differ especially
in the case of a lot of stretching and
clock glitching and it becomes more
accurate to the Advanced Techniques
speaking of techniques we have clock
glitching as you know every CPU contains
the clock
clock is known to be steady so messing
with the crop signal could lead to a
glitch and it can considered to be an
easy low cost and doesn't require High
skills if the device is using external
also about this glitching is a technique
voltage glitching is simply by tampering
the supply voltage
for example pulling down the right
amount of voltage with the right amount
of time could lead to a glitch and our
talk is based on this technique
another technique is electromagnetic
bleaching em basically it's a strong em
alls to cause a ball usually the am
pulse is generated by a coil of wire
which will generate a strong current and
cause the fault this technique is
usually considered to be a higher cost
than voltage glitching also good
understanding is needed to be able to
get a successful glitch
another technique and consider to be an
advanced technique which is laser
glitching
laser glitching happen by applying
strong pulse
laser pulse to a decapsulated IC this
kind of dark require High expertise and
expenses however has a high accuracy
results
and also we have other techniques such
as per device and rejection and
temperature lens Etc
is it difficult well it depends several
years ago or this could release the city
of challenges and there were a specific
challenge called Fiesta which is based
on a pulse injection one way to solve
this challenge is only using a jumper
wire you can show the external clock
terminals on the jumper wire to mess
with the cloud signal and cause a glitch
to solve this challenge
and also it could be more complex with
the encapsulation and the double or even
the throttle based appearance
examples we have the famous Air Tech
attack attack smashing advantage to
voltage against the attack
s last year in the talk here in Hardware
also we have another example the
bypassing Android MDM using electron
magnetic Earth injection and the tool
was a gas lighter
and also here is the famous disco
knowledge several people mentioned below
they were able to extract the pin number
of the wallets by applying voltage or
electrical graphic glitch
now with the code read let's move on to
our attack
Recon 2017 taught by Chris grinski he
was able to bypass the ISP which were
the security feature on nxplpc by
applying for voltage fault injection to
access the flash memory this stock
inspired us to go further and look for a
variability that will leverage re-enable
movie The debug interface and have full
control of the microcontroller
and I can hear the NPC saying I'm ready
to get charged again
as you can see here this is our actual
setup
the LPC 1343 on the left the power and
the glitch comes from the cheapest pro
which is the device on the right and on
the top we have the default probe
connected to the LPC to check whether
the debug and spaces happen or not we
also use the PCB bytes where the glitch
will come through and it's called the
poison needle uh BCP fighters from
cinepic company and help us solve the
rest also we removed the decoupling
capacity on the v-core to make our image
more convenient as shown in the
schematic in the rights
here's the setup diagram setup the PC
was connected to the both
the checklist for as a powerful other
Source Hardware from New Age
technological side Channel power
analysis and let's
so from the full form analysis
we have a team basic Solutions
and as you can see here
two dollars and
this is the CRP when it's set
you can see in the middle there's a
little bit shift and uh it is
the CRV one will execute the different
scenarios
and here we overlap a few traces so that
it should be more obvious
um
so now we have the right range to apply
the image the setup is ready about the
code to
start creating our trigger was based on
a recent spin so we are visiting the
device wait until the range glitch and
so on however with no luck
then we decided to change the setup and
paste the trigger on the power on cycle
so we power on the device Waits until
the range bridge and fall off and so on
after a while we successfully were
able to unlock the debugging space why
was it successful when we changed the
setup
[Music]
because it's shown in the 300 candle
that after each reset it will check the
debugging space therefore our initial
setup was based on this diagram however
when we change the setup based on the
power one off cycle the glitch succeeded
and able to unlock the debug interface
and now we can recovery
so we here have uh
CRP
you can see after each Village we
shaking the window
if the controller is enabled or not
eventually we
exceeded to re-enable because it is
try to access your NBC electricity
and we try to read the content of 0x2 FC
which contains the crp3 value
and this is a trace screenshots from
glitching crp1
crp2 Village
this is a proof that we are able to
manage all CRP values and able to unlock
the debug interface
let's start a little bit about history
before 2006 NBC Microsoft
Phillips time they developed the LBC q14
series
so we searched documents for ellipticals
crosses
the Boost process
as you can see it's almost the same the
XP is used
from the ecology detection it seems the
magic value used is the same as the CR
the LBC family so based on
user manuals we look to all the LBC
controller and always list sharing the
same mechanisms
so we assume you might have be having
the same
and in the following is we changed the
Boost process and let's see Direction
mechanism so this is used for something
called ecrb which is detection
in the LBC 546 series which has
different approach to enable the JP card
by sitting into
investigated
and the last one is the NBC 55 series
which is
different uh
so to conclude we reverse entry with a
blue film and talk about consumption
traces and
comparing we figure out the range that
we should apply the glitch we apply the
glitch based on a reset Trigger or to
the knowledge change the setup to paste
our trigger on a power on cycle then we
were able to successfully re-enable the
debug interface and helpful control of
the microcontroller another thing to
mention is the CRP locking mechanism
existence Phillips time
we also contacted nxp to discuss they
were very professional and past think
that's for highlighting the news feeding
step under this process diagram
and I hope you learned something also
and thank you for listening
all right thanks for leads and bondar
uh we have some time for questions do we
have some questions from the audience
yes we do yeah
might have missed it but I don't think
you said how you actually got the jump
for the Google was it just unprotected
and you could just read it out of memory
or was anything special actually it's
just uh connected everybody
and just leave that address
do we have any other questions
okay I've got one uh you mentioned in
the end that you consulted in a speed to
disclose this problem uh they fixed the
documentation of this let's see what
else did they do
hey I'm not sure they increase the
documentation already because we
discussed it two months ago and to be
able to
litigate this kind of attack Solutions
foreign to be able to
start this Mission did they inform you
that they plan to do some mitigations to
introduce the mitigations to this
um
thank you do we have any other questions
from the audience super I hope that's
one
hi guys thanks for your presentation
it's fantastic just a simple question so
you changed the trigger reset trigger to
have all
uh was it just time that you used as the
basis for actually when you did the
trigger the reason I asked this question
is
I have exploited the ear tag which much
more
um and what I found was
I actually used the oscilloscope to
trigger on just before the sort of dip
and it made it way more accurate so I'm
wondering if you sort of was it just
purely on power on any time or was any
other sort of
foreign
all right
last question
so let's give another round of close to
the guys