thank you sorry for the delay um so yeah
we wanted to present you uh some
research with the hardware attack
against sm4
and first of all I'm Sim I'm a security
researcher at pdfc security I'm mostly
work on a bright cryptography project I
used to do Hardware attacks in the past
and I'm occasionally a CTF player and I
had a lot of fun playing this CCF here
at Harvard Ohio and if you have any
question you will be able to ask at the
end of the code but if you want to reach
me you can do it on Twitter this is my
number and I will let Nicola introduce
himself
so hello everybody it's me again uh as
yesterday uh still work in a minute
system evaluation security evaluations
doing Hardware attacks
in my spare time I also organized a
conference in Switzerland called black
amps so feel free to try to come it will
be that will be great
I'm also working on an open source
projects called Idol bus which is an
interface to communicate with a various
different Hardware protocols and we have
my Twitter handle
foreign so several months ago I was
discussing with the rajama was talking
with me yesterday and he got very
excited with a new chip which is a
microcontroller with a risk 5 4 with
lots of various high-speed peripherals
Etc
and I think that triggered me was the
red box on the lower level
right which was first AES and something
that was called sn4 never heard about
this
so first thing to do is Google Voice you
find the Wikipedia page which just tells
me okay it's a block Cipher I use the
Chinese National Standard blah blah blah
I have no information about this so I
found the document some documentation uh
some reference implementations
and some papers about attacks on this
Cipher but no apparent tool or anything
published
so I'm not really good at crypto so when
I read papers usually when there's maths
looks kind of Chinese to me and
unfortunately most of the papers for sm4
are written in Chinese so it's even
worse for me
um so all the implementation I basically
did the research on the c or python
implementation of sm4 that you can find
but to do the actual attacks what I
would really need is somebody that knows
crypto way better than me and that's why
I asked Siva to participate with this
so I volunteer to to do this part I
didn't know this black Cipher as well
before this product I figure out that it
was a standout for from People's
Republic of China
the freezer is a drafter ETF available
in English which is really helpful to
understand how the organisms work so
basically if you use a g size and
backside of final 128 bits it works on
32 runs most of the operation operates
on 32-bits world
and to this point we figure out that
it's interesting to study this Blood
Cipher because it's used more and more
in the field for example in a rm64 since
version 8.4 you have Hardware
instruction dedicated to this encryption
as well as risk 5 now and if you want to
deploy some project in China now you may
need to implement this algorithm it may
be mandatory so here we figure out that
it's interesting to evolution
so let's look how it works in practice
so like as there is a key schedule uh
invertible
It produced 36 run keys so 32 bit world
called arcade and they are completed
from the secret key store with another
constant each time in the standard
we don't know from where you come from
and
um and like yes if you have a memory
them of the key schedule the
resurrection between the wrong key so
you can identify them in an in-memory I
will come back to that later
so this is one round of the schedule uh
all the capital uh cases later are
worlds
so it's quite simple at each one only
one one key one neuron key is produced
should produce here those one are just
shifted on the left
then we have the sl4 Run themselves so
uh it works on 120 bit States separated
in four words the initial stage is a
plain text itself and
one one thing is that the encryption and
decryption are identical only one keys
are taken into the Riverside
this is how it looks uh sm4 run so it's
quite similar as a as a key schedule
except here the G function is slightly
different than the key schedule and now
we have the state of the algorithm which
is uh given as input and again we
produce at each one of one world of new
States
now the G function itself so I speak to
the world into lowercase to its right
lower case later on rights and each byte
is external one key byte then it goes to
the s-box then the L function and we
have the out
so it's not that complicated
um L is a linear transformation I use
mainly for diffusion to spread the
modification among rights we have Xbox
we have a very similar construction as a
yes based on inversion of in
transformation
and one important thing and not that
important but at the end of the
algorithm the output is reverse it does
not change anything to our attack but it
can make you lose a lot of time during
your implementation and debugging
sessions let's keep that in mind
so the first thing we did on this
algorithm we implemented the Yahoo rule
because when you have a firmware you
want to know if sm4 is inside this
camera or not So based on the constant
and the s-backs which are usually
penalty will be recaptable we can detect
if a self-risingly firmware on that
and there's another thing I speak about
is a key schedule so if you have a
memorandum of your key schedule you can
search that either now with a command we
have implemented into a Hada too it was
already done for AES and we just added
this relation for SL for any interest
used for the identification phase of
your of your project
now let's go to harder attacks
so
usually except for Hardware reverse
we've seen before but usually in
Hardware you have to approach a
sectional or fold and we run two so we
splitted the work like that so we
collect to the side Channel
and we started with a software
implementation just try our attack and
then we move to Hardware implementation
part of accelerate so now we'll just let
equal represent this up
all right so the section and Analysis uh
website channel is is a way to recover
the secret key by looking at some
leakage information while the key is
used to produce the central text
so there are different ways to get this
kind of leakage you have the power
consumption electromagnetic condition or
timing intervals
again there are a lot of implementation
of sectional analysis or power analysis
or AES this is
everybody knows that there's a yes but
for sn4 unfortunately uh I'll write some
papers mostly in Chinese there's no tool
for this so
what we will do first is get some traces
recognize the slide it's the same as
yesterday because I use the same choices
I did last time so I took an sm4
implementation C then
you can make it run on an esp32
and collected power traces using the
listener and a lot of various Trace I
took about 50
000 average traces so again every Trace
is a mean of 1000 encryption with the
same index the principles about 15
million encryptions to get increases
the traces look like this so you can see
that there is 32 same patterns and just
for the ease I showed the first three
right the first four rounds and the last
one you can see in yellow here this is
the first round here
now that we have those traces how do we
process them and what kind of tools
you can use so instead of creating a new
library what I did is I took an existing
one and just implemented the sm-4 module
for this Library
I chose cats made by ishan because it's
open source the code is quite clean uh
and it's in Python so it's easier for me
to to implement everything with this
so I started first by looking at how the
library was using which kind of data it
was required as an input and output Etc
we implemented sn4 uh just for this
Library so every function of this info
is implemented I also added more helper
functions so ways to calculate the round
forwards the wrong backwards the key
schedule you can go forward backwards
Etc
and with all this python what I need
then is a way to detect when the key is
used in this Trace right what we want to
find is the key
so to do this you have to implement what
they call selection functions which is
basically you given hypothesis so and my
guess is that the key light is let's say
0 1 and you try to find some correlation
on the expected output value and try to
make it work on the traces
foreign
I'm using the s-box as a selection
function
Works quite well with the correlation
core analysis
so for the first round of sn4 uh the
paint text is directly
mixed with the key so you have the plain
text here
that we input
the key that we don't know and this
value is those two values so together
are then switched to a different value
using this Xbox
so what we can do now is that since we
know the plain text we can say okay
my guess is that k0 for instance is
equal to 0 by G is U so I will calculate
the output of the X Box which will be
some value then try to find the Hamming
weights of this output value and try to
match it with all the traces I collected
so far so good so here you have uh on
the top right you have the python codes
using the scan Library the function that
I implemented is this one so it will
directly search for the first Xbox
output
you tell the library to look for the
Hamming weight in the traces and display
the results and here you can see that in
my traces I have for one key byte one
value that is really Rising above all
the others that means that the
correlation for this key guess looks
quite okay
so now we can do the same for the for
the first four key lines because
remember we are only working with 32 bit
words so for the first one it will only
encrypt the first 32 bits then we'll do
the next round with 32 more bits
thing is as this season said to recover
the master key for sm4 you need at least
four consecutive round keys with just
one round key you cannot do anything so
because we only have now the first round
key what we can do is calculate using
the functions that I implemented ask
python to take your plain text say okay
so just one rounds with the key that we
discovered
so then you can do basically the same
attack using the Xbox but on the second
round
this will give you mute 32 units of key
and then you have to do the same third
time for the third rounds and then a
fourth time for the fourth round and
then you will have four words of the
schedule that way you can go back in the
schedule to recover domestic
once you have this master key again you
have to remember that on sn4 you have to
apply absorb mask with a predefined uh
value which is in the standard and if
you do this correctly you should get
back to your masters
then the second one I implemented was
the same thing but from the last one so
let's pretend that in your Acquisitions
you also know the paint text but you can
you know the cipher text so the outputs
of your encryption
you can do exactly the same so from the
ciphertext you try to go one round
backwards so you try to get the output
of the Xbox data on the opposite way try
to recover the last round the last round
key
main problem is that after
trying that for I think two or three
days I was still not getting any
correlation I spent a lot of time a lot
of time and if you remember what Silva
says the outputs of the ciphertext is
Switched so once I just start this
function so keeping the the ciphertext
backwards
works exactly the same as with the first
round keys and it worked perfectly fine
we were able to recover the kids
so let me show that
he will prepare the networks
stop moving the traces
the choices are here it's the same one
I'll show you in the slides
here
we will tell the library to try to find
the first uh the first round key
I uh especially uh
shrinks the the window size for the CPA
just to go faster so basically I'm just
looking at not the whole Trace that's
only the Yellow Part here
and then that
should show the correlation and you will
see that you have a correlation for the
first round key you have one value which
rises above the rest
for the next two bytes it's exactly the
same with the third round two guys the
same fourth part right same and you will
get
the first donkey
that you can do the same so you apply
the around four words to ask for the
outputs on the Xbox One the next round
etc etc into the full demo if you want I
can show that
okay so now let's move to the other part
so it's called analyzes so now we're
trying to subject forward to the cipher
so uh there are some academic paper but
for the attack against sm4 the first one
was introducing in 2006 which is in
Chinese again but this attack is really
the building block for all uh further
attacks which was explained again in uh
other people in English
in order the paper iPhone uh there was
there were a performance analysis
chapters that the code was not given so
it was really painful to verify the the
claims in the paper I could just find
one guitar repository applying this flux
for the attack so I started from the
from that
uh the idea of this attack is quite
simple you fold a world at the last
round right is rightful and if you are
the last one you will observe directly
the full as a at the output because the
world is not changing except if you
inject food here in this one as well and
then the fortune inject will go through
this G function go out and disturb with
the iffusion the full world and we'll
also observe the output in yourself in
your 4G cycle
this is nice because when you collect
foods from a practical uh Hardware or
software implementation if you solve the
correct cyphotech with the 40 ciphertext
you'll see a nice pattern so one bytes
modification and a full world
modification so you can easily say okay
I'm injected the correct support model
I'm expecting so this is nice
now let's see how this attack worker in
in practice so it's a differential
attack basically you're injecting a byte
board so if you saw the output of the 2s
box you will have the input byte so all
together with the key slide you don't
know and on the other side you will have
the 40 bytes so with the correct input
and the key byte as well if we rewrite
that with X we don't know because it
depends on the Divide we'll have this
nice equation s of X so s of X so Alpha
and then we can go the other way around
from the output of the of the of the G
function so we can take the word uh the
other word we can throw them together
apply the inverse function and function
and we'll obtain uh a word we which is
all zero except for one byte which is
the byte we have 40. so now the problem
we are looking to solve is to find the X
which depends on the T byte which
satisfies this equation an alpha and
beta window because we can collect the
14 side photos
so then we did a static table and for
index Alpha and beta we will store in
this table uh all the X satisfying this
equation and if you run this is to build
this table for sn4 you will notice that
on average you will only have 2X in each
at each index so this is nice because
now we can collect 40 side protects we
should add some data
you know how to compute them look into
this table
uh and then we'll have a list of key
byte candidates and an average two so
then if we do that for another uh 40 40
type of text and we intersect the two
set of needed we'll hopefully have only
one key byte remaining which is uh the
the one key byte we are looking for
so then we do that for all the bytes of
the wrong key and we have the first one
and as for side Channel
then we reverse the the last one with
the one key we apply this prototype
again we cover four one key iteratively
and we can reverse the key schedule
again and recover the secret
so on average we would need uh eight
foot per round key times for uh one key
it will give such 240.
so this is nice
we wanted to try uh this attack so first
we we started with simulated food which
are perfect that is the foot mode that
we are looking for and then also we
built a firmware implementation
efficient for again and we tried on the
tool we already released in 2020 which
is called the details of 3000 and you
can see relate port on your firmware
it's based on hadap 2 and what we we are
doing is we are skipping some
instruction during the execution of the
channel
and we did that for a fixed key on the
fixed standard
so if you run this tool on this
implementation so here you have the add
the instruction which was skipped and
the corresponding 40th output at the end
so let's look how
well in practice so here I have some
food which are perfect because I'm
simulated so they are nice I have this
nice pattern on the info and if I apply
my
third attack on this set of four
it's it's recovering by byte per byte
Zone key and again I have the full one
key I'm trying to rewrite the world and
apply the GF again but I think have more
folds for the um
but it's working perfectly
but then on foot I got from the my arm
camera if I look at the pattern I have
something else something different
and I cannot apply directly my full data
type on this kind of it does not work so
I need to do something else
so
I continue my reading
and I I feel that there is more paper
about for Attack on sn4
one of them extend the attack I
presented by explaining that if you
apply the code to 100 home audio it will
correct the full world at the last one
and then you can apply the attack
alternative to you before but in
parallel so you will recover all the one
key by with only two phones and you know
it's nice because it transform your
right foot model into a world's third
model meaning that if you for the full
world now you can still apply an attack
and Recovery
so this is how it works in practice now
we introduce it for here one from
earlier still we can observe the output
we will Disturb This full worm here
which will be injected as an input of
the last one but now this is the full
one so and again we have the output of
this code and
uh the input of the sort and the output
so we can still apply the idea I
presented before
and in fact if the papers are going even
a bit further
saying that if you put a wonderful
earlier you can still get uh you can
still recover the last one key and the
wrong key before so this is really
powerful because now you just need a
four-fold in total to recover the
spreadsheet quantity because of the
school for one keys so it's really nice
and still uh if you have this kind of
working practice you have a nice pattern
if you saw the correct Cipher text with
the 14 Cipher text so you can still
identify them and it's really practical
for your product
however there is one limitation
the problem is if you for this one x i
plus one then you won't be able to
observe the output because it will be
solved by value which has been changed
by itself there is one one limitation
uh by reading a more paper I figure that
there is uh even another paper going
even further one of them further so now
you only need a single record and you
will recover the full Secret
so it looks nice but it's a kind of a
good form so there are brute forcing the
attack I present so it takes a
computation and also the pattern now
looks completely random so if you have a
lot of code you need to apply this
attack on all of the 37 text uh you have
we got knowing that there is a hope to
get the key
so it can be useful for when few points
are available
but we didn't implement this attack we
saw that it's uh useful for product but
maybe you would need that for
for some yeah some some music project
but still we figure out that uh
the front attack can be improved
especially for if this world is forget
in fact if you have a light fold here
you can still go back from the output
apply the inverse air function here and
identify at each position you have to
hold and then you just have to refer 256
value
during your GFA to apply so it's not
that big and each works are quite fun
and also what we found during evaluation
is that maybe you want to change this
one which will change the computation of
this function in the hardware then it
means that you have introduced a low
error in the right Branch here so the
text still works you can still
exploit for it happening here so it's
really nice because you you can take
advantage of code you could not uh with
the attack pattern to do the paper
so at the end uh I implemented the two
gflg I combined them because you can
combine them so it's really nice you can
keep track of your key candidate I am
placed as an improvement as well I
explained
and again like for sectional we didn't
want to reinvent the wheel so we created
a tool which is uh which look really
similar to Phoenix AAS I don't know if
you know this tool it's uh it's to
perform foot attack against AES it's a
part of the Great side Channel markers
which is really really nice and it
should be included soon in the in this
Repository
so now let's look how it's performed on
the simulated fault so still I have this
fold so I have only five of them uh
which looks nice I apply my fold attack
so now you see the school run key is
recovered at each step not one by so
it's really going fast and then I rewind
one round I apply the GF again and again
again
then I inverse the key schedule and I
recover the master key so it works uh
perfectly fine which the first four four
data was not working this
so we were happy with this attack and
now I will let Nicola explain how we
apply this attack on Hardware
implementation
right so uh while we were working on the
software implementation
is this nice board which has the the
chip that we were discussing at the
beginning of the project so it's a
riskified microcontroller and it has a
hardware sm-4 accelerator so we got some
and now it's time to apply the same
things that we discovered and try to
make it work on the real Hardware device
so what I did is a simple CPM which
reads as
text
GPA Razer gpio for synchronization then
ask the sm4 hardware to do the
computation and then write the results
back to the uart
so for the first part I try to do some
side Channel analysis on that so I spent
a lot of time getting a lot of different
traces I tried correlation and plain
text and ciphertext I got some
correlation but I think it's more the
memory transfers between the hardware
and the hardware sn4 and the CPU memory
that I have absolutely nothing in
between so I did some g-tests I didn't
see anything so at least like power
consumption I was unfortunately not able
to to get any leakage from the hardware
ID
uh I did some uh some tries with uh some
em probes uh mostly like the magic ones
that you saw yesterday
and unfortunately I have lots of really
good results but again I was doing this
with my own oscilloscope which is not
that fast so I need to take the big guns
bigger oscilloscopes better materials so
I'm still working on this it's not uh
done yet
but from the fault injection perspective
we place the boards uh just below a
cheap Shelter From a new a so if you
don't know this is a tool to perform an
electromagnetic fault injection
so I spent some time uh looking on the
on the chip placing the probe at several
location uh trying different voltages
different pulses and wireless coils just
to have the better results so spent a
lot of time uh collected a lot of traces
and after some time we got
the faulted ciphertexts and now let's
see if I can relax
yeah so we collected uh yeah 1400 foot
uh to I mean in the 300 of them are
unique and we run a GPA tool on them and
hopefully it was working as before for
the software implementation so we were
happy because it means that Hardware
accelerator on this chip is vulnerable
it's not uh and it's a secret equipment
it's just vm30 direction that means that
we verify that it works in practice
so that's it for us we think that it's
interesting to see the sn4 because it
should be more and more deprived in
practice
we've opened Source or we will open
source all the tool we've done for this
project so it should be easy for you if
you if you need to perform sort of
attack on sn4 to use those tools uh so
we have a key schedule finder in other
two we have the product analysis library
in scaled the Phoenix sn4 we should be
included in the sectional model so feel
free to use them and if you have any
remote here I would be happy to take
them and if you you think that this
toolk was useless and you don't want to
see this kind of code in the future it's
easy to prevent that just keep the
shortcut if you have a new attack it
will be easier for people to just test
your claims
so thank you and if you have any
questions