I want to welcome you to buy cans 49 for
public meeting in this amazing city let
start by acknowledging two very special
people who are with us today dr. Yaakov
ebrahim Singapore's Minister of
Communications and Information
enlist early on chem ty deputy chief
executive and director general of
infocomm Development Authority of
Singapore or I da and chairman of SG
Rick
we will hear more from these gentlemen
in a few minutes first I need to tell
you that being here in this room gives
me a sense of deja vu the board
authorizes the president and CEO to
implement the new gtld program all those
in favor of authorizing the CEO to
implement the new gTLD program please
raise your hands
any opposed any abstentions Carrie
this was the formal approval by the
board of directors that I can just under
three years ago jun 2011 here of the top
level domain generic top-level domain
program let me ask cutting off i can see
through these lights but how many of you
were here than a lot of hands and you
still come back this is very good news
that was a big day for us it was the
combination of enormous amount of work
the board's action was really the
smallest almost infinitesimal part of
the whole process we offer a lot of work
went into this let me ask for another
video with your appointment as the new
chair and with a sword passage of the
new gTLDs what sort of new challenges
lie ahead for you this is a very big
operation and so I'm now in the
uncomfortable position of trying to sit
astride and hang on for dear life as it
work
the challenge real challenges for the
organization as a whole to execute on
moving this gtld program forward as well
as carrying on the regular day-to-day
business that it's already has to do
and the information and commitment so
there's a kind of a triple and there
will be both resource and execution
challenges for the well-defined parts of
the program and there will be
anticipated problems or oddball cases or
loose ends that have to be dealt with
and so there'll be a certain amount of
refinement that will be opposed to us
while we're trying to get on with the
main work I'm hearing you say that the
board's work with new gTLDs is not
finished I don't make too big a deal a
little bit but there's always something
that's going to come up we're not going
to go to sleep and say you know we're
done it's all over with
pretty embroiled continuing basis is he
/ charge being cautious the robot was
absolutely smooth no problem whatsoever
we had to increase our regular a little
bit in one cases we actually found the
word that was not an acronym at the
glitch credit came up to create a new
sport called digital our jury once we
abandon actually learned that all the
errors was coming in right into the
board and the staff in the end the
program rolled out we now have almost
200 names in the already delegated into
the into the root and more coming on a
very regular basis and it marked at
historic change withdrawal aware but
that historic change wasn't just as I
was suggesting earlier due to the board
it really was a very broad community
action and so let me ask that you give
yourselves a hand for the enormous
activity and energy and success of that
program
well we're doing great things we also
have a inescapable and abiding
commitment to operate in a the highest
fashion that we can we take
accountability and transparency
extremely seriously and so in that day I
want to commit a word of the second
accountability transparency review team
led by Brian cute his report report of
his team was turned in last December and
in accordance with the rules that we set
up for these reviews we are now in the
six-month period of examining the
recommendations very closely trying to
understand what the impact would be so
that when we say yes if I fully expect
we will do either wholly or in the main
we will know exactly what we have said
yes to and exactly how to proceed with
the implementation so we're in the
process of formulating a response to the
teams report and we'll say more about
this in a session on Wednesday morning
which I invite you all to come to but I
invite you with a certain a conflict of
interest because exactly parallel to
that is a session on my long-standing
interest and support for DNS security so
divide yourselves in two and half of
go to that to one in the other later
this afternoon ova a session that is
focused on the slightly broader topic of
the affirmation of commitments in
general and which is all the more
important in the context that has now
been set with the historic announcement
by secretary Strickling week ago about
the transition of the stewardship of the
technical functions of the i am
accapella function it's been a long time
goal of the US government as well as the
rest of the community that now been
realized because of icam successful
globalization and our collaborations
with our partners in the internet
ecosystem and this is something that
needs to be emphasized at every
opportunity I can as visible as we have
become and I've learned the hard way
that there's no way that we're going to
be able to lessen that visibility
remains but one player in a complex and
well-established ecosystem so I want to
acknowledge the leaders of the other
members of the ecosystem we have the
leaders of the regional internet
registries and deal a Krogan CEO of
john curran president / CEO of Aaron
Raul Roberto CEO lightning axle calling
managing director ripe ncc Paul Wilson
CEO of a peeing those are the registries
Thank You prepares more hopefully
o'clock on the highly technical side of
creating the technology that is the
underpinnings of everything here rush
hands with charity event architecture
board chair in taxes and all important
our friends partners and a soul mates at
the pulmonary society Catherine Brown
president and CEO bob bailey my kind of
our Board of Trustees here in society
where you go iron even though I don't
see him here we're at run good times
actually
I don't think each other never going to
the store next to live GI let me
acknowledge the presence of Larry
Strickling assistant secretary for
communication to the information at the
US Department of Commerce Larry thank
you very much