Minister Yakub thank you again for being
with us thanks for welcoming he's here
chairman Lee Jung thank you very much
for your words your support to us as
well assistants trickling assistant
secretary Strickling thank you thank you
for being with us here today your
Excellencies ladies and gentlemen
friends today is indeed a special day
but let me start with some facts a year
ago I came to Asia and frankly I found
no other way to explain our presence in
asia but to apologize to age and i did i
said i made an apology because we were
almost non present here a year later we
have 14 people in the region we have a
hub we have local services we have
translation of content in local
languages we have transformed our
presence in asia and there's more to
come this is the commitment of I can
we're going to the world as we said a
year and a half ago and this is already
happening and you will see these maps
building around the world because if we
stay in Los Angeles as I said on the
first day then we are not the world's I
can to become the world's I can we have
to go to the world today people in China
can pick up the phone and we will answer
them in Chinese and explain to them how
they can participate in I can same with
many other Asian cultures and languages
that was not cross holy year ago it is
possible now and thank you quick
personally for the superb work you've
done you are now a reference model to
how we need to work across the world
and in that hub today we have people
from the global domain domain names
division that can support our registries
and registrar's and applicants in this
region we have people from the
compliance team so that we can
understand the needs of the region and
how to support them we have people that
support our core mission of security
stability and resiliency now based here
in Asia across the region and finally
and most importantly we have many people
those who are in light blue are not in
the hub there in the region there across
the cities and countries of this vast
area supporting our engagement
capabilities building capacities and
bringing people into the structures of I
can so that we can enlarge our family
this is the second year in our new
season when I started that I can I said
we have to till the ground get things
ready and then hopefully we can get to
the point in this new season to see the
fruit of our work however at this point
in our second year which is about
halfway through my first tenure here or
my tenure with you for the three years
that the board asked me to come and
serve you I stopped a little bit and I
think we should all stop and take stock
a lot is going on a lot is on our minds
we're looking at the work we've done and
saying there's a lot on our plate but it
is an important time for us to step back
here in Singapore and think what is on
hand what is ahead of us and what we
need to do to stay engaged and to be
successful in the phase ahead so to take
stock I asked my team to engage with our
community and to really take a community
view as to everything that is going on
and I can and to do that we decided
we're going to create kind of a
community activity
map so we can start understanding
everything on hand that needs to be
addressed across the community and we
divided all of these things into these
three spheres the core i can activities
the emerging activities related to the
globalization of icon and the
globalization of the iono functions and
then finally our engagement on a global
level in Internet Governance let me
break this down with you as we listen to
you it became clear that each of these
three areas had many cross community
activities let's look at them one at a
time let me start with our core
operations within our cooperations we
have five six major tracks of work that
engage all of us together again I'm not
speaking about the many many areas of
work and activities within our
communities I'm speaking about
community-wide or cross community
activities so in the global domains
division we found that there are five
key areas one of which is about to start
that's why I data privacy is still in
white but we're about to launch that
effort because it's becoming important
that we globally understand that but let
me focus your attention for example on
the ATR to area as many of you know we
have a review mechanism that is cross
community that is independent of ICANN
that comes in and basically looks at all
of our activities to ensure that i can
operates in an accountable and
transparent way the ATR t team came back
to us with 50-plus recommendations in
order to take i can to the next level of
accountability and transparency we must
focus on these things as my chairman
said and make sure we deliver on them
for the global community so that i can
is always viewed as an accountable
transparent organization another area of
activity you would know is all the
efforts like quakes and his colleagues
under sally costerton and Tareq camel
related to engagement we have three
levels of engagement that
intense right now we have regional
engagement strategies that have been
built from the bottom up with our
communities that we need to put in place
we have global engagement activities in
the areas like business we now have a
business function under engagement we
were recently at the GSMA engaging with
the mobile business community bringing
them on board and built a very good set
of bridges with them these are important
activities and digital engagement I
promised you we will have a new website
and the next few days you will see the
new I can website and that website again
for the first time was built from the
bottom up with the community you were
engaged in it you helped us design and
we built it together in order to deliver
value to you an engagement but we cannot
forget all of our common activities to
plan the year ahead so we have
operational planning and budget planning
cycles that need to happen and it is
important ICANN's operational core
budget is close to a hundred million
dollars now so we have to do it together
we have to manage it together we have to
agree together how to direct our
resources in order to meet our
collective community-wide goals and
objectives lots on the plate and lots to
do if I move to the next area that's the
I can and iono globalization areas that
just started for all of us and as you
recall the board of directors have I can
about a month ago issued a resolution in
which they said that these are the five
areas of ICANN globalization we to focus
on this transitioning of the IANA
stewardship I cans own accountability as
an organization looking at our policy
structures and how we can enhance them
and make them more global including the
GAC looking at our legal structure and
how our legal structure can be
globalized so it can serve the world and
finally looking at the root system
system and ways to enhance it these were
the five initiatives to a degree that
the board focused on and in
effort to engage with the community the
board said we're going to create these
advisory groups that will bring the
community together to discuss them now
I'm I have discussed the advisory groups
with the board and of course since that
discussion something happened the US
government announced that it will start
the process of transitioning its torture
to the community as a result we are
discussing right now the board and
hopefully this week while we're all
together the possibility of removing all
these advisory groups and instead
focusing all of our attention now on the
areas that need our attention through
public consultation so we will continue
discussing this with you through the
week and hopefully together we'll make
the right decision so we focus everyone
given also how much is on our plate on
the two key areas we need to focus on
now let me talk about these two areas
because today we are going to start
these two public consultations the first
one is about the IANA stewardship
transition this will be at ten-thirty so
immediately after the session we will
launch the global process of responding
to the invitation of the US government
to transition their stewardship to us to
us and all the people that we need to
bring because it's not just too I can I
can is just facilitating but it's truly
to all of us with many of the
communities represented here and those
that couldn't make it today we need to
bring them into that global process now
i want to tell you now that this public
consultation is about IANA transition
but we have discussed now with the
community with the leaders with the
board as well as with the US government
that we should also discuss how we're
going to evolve ICANN's accountability
as an organization and let me separate
these two very clearly the IANA
functions are very specific functions
that are well defined and we do them
together with other leaders in the
community and communities we need to
discuss how to manage these functions
specifically separate from that as I've
heard from many of you just in the last
few days who is going to keep the ICANN
organization and check well today we
have something called the affirmation of
commitment but the affirmation of
commitments which is a very important
document central to who we are and how
we function is a document that today
through the historical record was signed
between I can and the US government we
as a community should look at that and
should look more broadly at icons
accountability and discuss how do we
evolve these mechanisms so that I can is
kept accountable and in check and that
discussion will be today as well
at 5pm so I invite you all to join us at
5pm for that discussion separate from
the eye on a discussion I want to say
something on the IANA transition first
and foremost in the presence of NTI is
leadership here I think we should all
recognize without question the
stewardship of ntia the stewardship of
the United States over the last 15 years
which has served the internet and the
world very well
and that recognition is important
because it actually starts with a story
that dr. Crocker said when he speaks
about them setting up their first little
network with he and his friends and
giving this to the world keeping it open
what a powerful gift to the world that
has continued with the progressively
less onerous stewardship and more
permissive stewardship to the community
over the last 15 years it is important
for us to remember that the US
government every few years said that the
i kin community is right here now so
we're going to change the mechanisms and
instruments of stewardship up to the
point last friday where NTIA came to the
conclusion that we are ready and this is
a testament of our work it's a triumph
of the multi-stakeholder model and it's
a testament that the United States
fulfilled its commitment which they made
on the first day I can was born that
when the I can and global community
already they will transfer the
stewardship and they did so thank
now the second thing I want to say about
this is that they're not transferring
the stewardship to I can they are
transferring the stewardship to all of
us in this community who must work
together as we have for the last 15
years this is nothing new I don't have
to learn to work with the IETF and with
the rirs and these organizations we have
worked together for 15 years it's been
working thank you very much we have an
Internet that generates trillions of
dollars of value to the planet this is
all because of the work of the people
who labor in the background to ensure
that the technical infrastructure of the
internet is built and is working and to
them the US government gives the role of
bringing the global community on how
we're going to replace that's torch and
we should again take that responsibility
with great seriousness great seriousness
the eyes of the world are on us will the
multi-stakeholder model rise as it has
for the last 15 years and Carrie and my
answer to the world today is at will and
you will start seeing this today in how
we take this responsibility seriously so
with this let me move on with our
activities back to I can the last bit of
activities we have is the circle of
activities related to the internet
governments and as you know many of us
have been saying why is I can spending
so much time on global Internet
Governance we have a lot to do and now
with the u.s. decision we even have more
to do we have to globalize iono we have
to globalize I can so I want to link
things again as we did in Buenos Aires
we are a member of the Internet
Governance ecosystem we have a
responsibility part of that
responsibility is
protect I can in the sense that we
continue to do the mission we have to
maintain the security and stability of
the internet and to do our job and to
ensure that we're not constantly
guarding from some kind of a threat
that's the first reason we do it but the
second reason we do it is that I can at
the end of the day is rooted in its
responsibilities to the public that's
what drives us and therefore we have a
responsibility as well in the global
Internet Governance however as you saw
very well i hope the circle of that work
is smaller than the other circles it
should be prioritized as such it should
be important we will pay attention to it
but it should be prioritized not never
ahead of the core work that you have
entrusted us to do at icon now in the
global Internet Governance area we have
three streams of work we have the global
Internet Governance forms we have the
one net dialogue forum and we have the
panel that we have partnered with the
weft the World Economic Forum as well as
with the University of Southern
California the panel chaired by
President Ilves of Estonia that panel
will release its final report on its
views of the future of Internet
Governance in the month of May and
several of the panelists are here today
and I recognize kathy brown the CEO of i
saw and i think olaf copeman may be here
but he's also with us on that panel now
I want to spend again by the way just
like we did with the other advisory
committees the board is considering
right now removing that advisory group
so that we can focus on the cross
community working group that the
community has put together and ensure
that the discussion on internet
governance is driven by you by us by the
community first and foremost I want to
spend a minute on something on a lot of
our minds net mundial net mundial is one
of the premier forms on internet
governance that will occur this
here it will happen in sao paulo on the
twenty-third and twenty-fourth of april
we have received i believe thousands of
interested participant applications and
the brazilian government and cgi who was
entrusted to the management of the
conference are going through that work
at the moment as well as the fact that
they have received 189 submissions on
proposals to improve internet governance
clearly the world wants to focus on this
issue this issue is important why and
why is net mundial central to it net
mundial is where we will start charting
a multi-stakeholder model of internet
governance it is the place to do it it
is not the place we want to spend too
much time on I can and iono i think the
decision of the US government coupled
with the processes will start today are
the venues and are the channels for
discussing i can and iono of course
people can discuss anything at an open
multi-stakeholder conference and they're
welcome to discuss any subject but we
cannot miss the opportunity at net
mundial to actually start looking at the
broader internet governance issues i can
and its work iono and its work are but a
small piece of a vast mosaic of issues
technical and non-technical national and
global and regional that we must address
in net mundial so I urge all of us to
participate remotely or personally in
this important balam and to ensure that
we do not miss the opportunity to start
charting forward how this world will
come together to govern the internet so
a map we have now what do we do I urge
all of us to go back into our
stakeholder communities and take stock
look at all these tracks look at all
these activities
focus our energies where we can add
value this is important this is the
important work of a community to make
priorities and to decide how we can all
succeed because frankly many of these
activities right now are all mutually
and critically important to our success
it is very hard to pick and choose which
ones to stop where we could we did stop
the advisory groups where we could we
didn't address every aspect of
globalization because we cannot do
everything at once so focus is important
and I welcome during the next five days
dialogue and listening we're going to o
be engaged so we make sure together that
we focus and get this job done finally I
want to go back to some history this is
jon postel the late jon postel John vint
cerf Bob Kahn Steve Crocker names of
people who years ago used to manage the
entire DNS on a small index card jon
postel had a little index count that's
how he managed the whole DNS today we
have I can with hundreds of people a
community with thousands of people and
millions of those to do the job this
great man did with immense commitment to
the internet but this is where it all
started and it started with our first
meeting by the way I cans very first
meeting was in Singapore I can one it
was in Singapore
I can one was in silica and together we
traveled the world we traveled the world
and we find ourselves here at ICANN 49
again in Singapore Singapore has been a
very important stop along the way but
the reason I show us this is to remind
all of us that this has been a long road
to this point so when the US government
decides it is time to trust us that's
because of all the work starting with
John that has happened from day one
until today when reporters call me and
they say oh it was because of this event
or that event that this happened I tell
them my wife was a gardener and works
and Labor's in her garden and tells it
and composts and do all of that if I
tell her that because of yesterday's
rain her vegetables are growing well
she'll be upset there's a lot more to
what we do at I can then an event or a
person it's all of us this is our work
we're here today to receive this great
honor from the United States government
and to show the world that the
multi-stakeholder model works it is
incumbent upon us to show the world it
does work and we will show the world it
does work through our actions not just
our words it's how we start today after
this session to engage with each other
and to build processes with private
sector governments and civil society all
of us together building stewardship to
take the internet to the next stage so
let's not miss this opportunity let's
not miss this opportunity and let's do
it never forgetting the principles that
the US government put on the table which
I believe are good principles and these
are important for us to keep in mind as
we start the next session number one
whatever we do
place the US stewardship must be rooted
in the multi-stakeholder model we cannot
come back to them with a transition plan
that hands our important work to a
government a group of governments and
intergovernmental organization no it
will not work number two the work the
transition model we design must attend
to the needs of the global community not
any one part of the community not any
part of the world all the global
community we must serve everyone with
distinction and equally that's the
second condition the US government put
the third condition the US government
put that nothing we will come back with
will jeopardize the openness of the
Internet the internet we want the
internet Crocker and his friends design
the same principles that they used to
design the technical architecture of
Internet should be used for designing
the governance architecture of the
Internet openness is very key and then
lastly the US government made it very
clear in this fourth principle that
nothing we do should jeopardize the
security stability and resiliency of the
system we were entrusted to manage and
none of us want to see a nanosecond of
interruption to that system it drives
the world it's a global force for human
development it's a global force for the
economy it's entrusted for us to come up
with that model and mr. Strickland we
will come back to you with these
conditions met I have every confidence
we will thank you thank you