hi everybody and welcome to my
presentation about Trinity PSP emulator
escape I'm happy and excited to be on
stage today and talk in front of such an
amazing audience so my name is andy
jillian the hardest last name in the
world and the fun fact about me is that
I'm a Google engineer at the Microsoft
conference talking about the product by
Sony but this is all private research
and is not affiliated or associated with
the companies above in any way so what's
the product it's the PlayStation Vita
which is the successor to the
PlayStation Portable and it was released
in 2012 to me in my opinion it's twice
as good as the PSP it has got doubled
the resolution yet because two analog
sticks it has a touchscreen and a
touchpad on the back and it runs with
444 megahertz and is capable of running
HD games unfortunately it wasn't so
successful and I looked up the sales
information the PS Vita sold 10 million
of units whereas the PSP sold 70 million
of units and in comparison the Nintendo
switch thought 50 million but the home
road seemed great even though Sony led
the console die with the homebrew scene
decided to revive and we brought a lot
of homebrew games applications emulators
and blockings to overflowed at to
overclock the device or increase the
resolution and games and it was all
possible thanks to a JPEG released in
2016 by T molecule now what about the
hardware architecture the relevant part
for us is it runs now arm cortex a9
processor which is 32-bit it also has a
trust zone implemented and there's a
processor integrated for PlayStation
Portable game support
now the interesting part what about its
security considering that this device is
almost 10 years old it's amazing how
many security medications they are they
have implemented address space layout
randomization and execute never bit in
user land and kernel and basically that
means that to exploit the memory
corruption bug you also need an
information leak and as a consequence of
xn you cannot execute your shellcode in
some data segment but you need to use
the rope chain this domain access
control register which is similar
technology to this map and map and
prevents you from accessing user memory
or executing user code in kernel they
have also element in stack protection in
user land and kernel and the stack cook
it not the constant and I have
implemented sandboxing and Cisco random
you see where the main restriction is
that you're only allowed to invoke these
girls from the current process in Furion
you may be able to invoke other syscalls
if you only have a reference and that's
exactly what this current initiation is
trying to prevent they have also applied
coarse-grained locking which is bad for
performance but it does avoid race
conditions not sure if that is intended
or developers but just lazy and to
prevent stupid mistakes they have
removed or unsafe Lipsy functions from
the operating system such as string copy
string printf and there's no cheat which
is not really a security mitigation it
makes it harder to exploit something
because you need to write objects so
what are the attack vectors you should
attack vectors for gaming and source or
file format like lip TIFF corruptions or
so which were used on the PP but on the
PS Vita it's difficult to pull them off
due to a SLR the PS Vita so another
possibility is to abuse safe games
and interestingly it's possible because
old games were compared to without pi
and without stat protection so you can
easily find buffer overflows and smash
the stack PS Vita's got the dev kit app
so it's got the internet browser which
uses a WebKit and given the amount of
public vulnerabilities it's quite easy
to exploit it and it's also at the best
entry point because it offers the
end-user the easiest installation but it
is fully sandbox and has only low
privileges even lo can say safe games
and a remote attack may be possible so
differently from file formats you
usually send some message and expect
some response and if there's some buck
in the response you can leak some
information and use that to further
exploit it and that's a challenge for me
and an attack surface is the PSP
emulator it's especially interesting
because it runs with system privileges
which are equivalent route and also we
can use the MIPS processor for doing
logic now first a bit about the PSP
emulator internals so as mentioned
before there submits processor
integrated and so other frames which are
emulated is out your memory stick or the
media and chain network or to control
and because the MIPS processor has not
access to these hardware devices it has
to communicate with the ARM processor
over RPC and for that it uses a shared
SRAM oath and also a shared CGI Ram
where it's only a subset of the RAM so
basically if you have code execution in
the ARM processor you can easily
manipulate the memory and at code
execution in the MIPS processor but vice
versa is more difficult and that's the
task of the day
so the plan of attack is to start in
mips user ant and somehow find holes in
the RPC server and attack it but for
that we need the ability say an
arbitrary RPC commands and for that we
require mips privileges it's gonna be
villages and assume you were able to
break out of the emulator the last goal
would be to explain villages to armed
colonel alright let's get started so the
security medications that I have
described before applied to the ARM
processor and beat the firmware but the
MIPS processor and the business VMware
is less secure and it's no surprise
because it's almost 15 years old
previous hacks usually exploit the
out-of-bounds writes know about
instructions and the strategy is to
fight indirect jumps in Cisco which use
registers that come from userland and
they know about instructions such that
your army would be picked instead the
ps3 also had a BT emulator however it's
all hype done on high level and
especially the crypto engine is emulated
which contains private keys and
unfortunately the ps3 contact by G or
hot and people were able to derive these
keys to sign executables on the PSP the
same thing can be used for the PS Vita
so that means that MIPS user code
execution is for free
and we can already check market the next
step is to hack the mips kernel so
there's an important data structure in
kernel which is used for resource
tracking using new IDs and each UID
points to a control block which contains
information of the resource and every
control block structured in a tree
hierarchy the problem is the UID is not
random it doesn't really need to be
random but the design is it's calculated
from the Metro block address
so for example if you open a file such a
UID is returned and when you operate on
the file you pass the UID to kernel and
the inverted equation is used to
calculate the control block address from
the UID and the design flaw is you can
pass any UID so the kernel will just
dereference an untrusted pointer so the
way we attack is is similar to a heap
unlink but you may be familiar with like
linkedlist exploitation so we plant a
fake control block in kernel and code it
as a string and then calculated CBD and
the control block contains a function
pointer as parent and I use their
address at next child then we delete the
UID and overwrite the kernel function
pointer with that address and finally we
can just invoke it and enjoy a kernel
mode execution
however this vulnerability was mitigated
with an interpretive check namely by
storing the UID itself in control block
and X or innate with a random seat which
is globally initialized so if we find
out that seat we can craft our control
block and then do the exploit the second
vulnerability is in this vehicle here
their parameters come from userland
and pointers point to use memory that's
a side effect of not having supervisor
mode X access prevention the syscall is
simple it returns an error code if the
index is too large and it returns 5 if
the index is 0 where 5 is the value of
the global global array not a buck is n
points to use the memory
and it fetched twice and there's no luck
involved so that means that there's a
small window where the value of anyone
can change and it's a so called time of
check - time of use and that's how we
exploited respond to threats where the
first execute the Cisco in the second
and the change of plea swaps the value
of N 1 scene 1 and 1 that is advance if
the error code if the result is the
error code it means that we swap too
early if they're if the result is 5 it
means that we swap too late and if it's
nothing in between
it means that we were able to swap just
in that tiny window and the result is
the value we want now we do the
procedure in two rounds in the first
round we want to know where the array is
stored because actually there's some
randomization and in the second round
based on the result we calculate the
index to our arbitrary location now
talking to it together we leap the
random seat by racing and then for chip
and row block with the UID XOR with the
seat in itself and then delete the UID
and redirect the kernel function pointer
and then we invoke this let's go and
enjoy a kernel code execution now we
can't stay too long in kernel mode
because there's a watchdog that will
catch you so instead we install as cisco
bridge to that RPC interface all right
we have exploited MIPS kernel and the
next step is to explore the RPC server
the RPC server looks similarly like that
and it sleeps and waits for inquest and
if there's some requests it wakes up and
fetches the command and the arguments
and translates them to native address if
necessary then handles the requests and
writes back the cache and finally
returns the result back to the client
now there are dozens of commands and sub
commands
and I wrote a dump faster which would
pass random arguments and random command
commands with random buffers and it was
not sophisticated because the only feed
packet God was whether he crashed or not
but interestingly it was able to find a
lot of null pointer dereferences so it
means that this code hasn't been
sufficiently reviewed I black listed
some of the uninteresting commands and
then I found a really promising crash
and for reference the Kermit here is
because they only named the protocol
Kermit and it suits really well because
it's for the buck and the buck is right
here it's a trivial buffer overflow
where buff size is too large it's not
validated and can be too large and the
probability that the fossil was able to
find crash was near 50% now the crash
happened because of the stack protection
and there's that cookie didn't match and
that's something we need to find out for
successful exploitation now common way
to I passed the stack protection is to
find to use some uninitialized memory
read vulnerability of the stack but
unfortunately I wasn't able to find such
a thing and it seemed like Sony made
sure to mem say every single buff that
got returned to the client so instead I
had to find to look for some other pop
classes instead like out-of-bounds reads
and one of the null pointer dereferences
was quite interesting it's in the meteor
and chin color space conversion commands
and what does is it gets ycbcr buffer
and converts it into a RGB a buffer
these pointers come from user memory
from PSP user memory and they get
translated to native address now we have
these
copies here because the components are
differently sized and there's some
adjustment needed and they copied the
content into a temporary buffer which is
allocated at the constant address and
the pop in this coat is that the row is
not validated and it is a 30 bit integer
and as touch we can arbitrarily control
the source pointer now we have an
arbitrary read but the content is
written to that temporary buffer and 10
CSC is applied on that buffer and that's
the formula of CSC I don't really
understand it but what is obvious is
that we lose information due to a
floating point imprecision or 8-bit
truncation so what if can set CP and Zr
to 128 then the rest of the terms would
cancel out and we would be left with
Archie be equal to Y but still we can't
just point to an arbitrary address and
expect to control their values there
because the ycbcr buffers are stored
consecutively and it took me a bit of
creativity and I made the observation
that that frame buffer was allocated at
the constant address and that the frame
buffer was not cleared of the conversion
so that's how we exploited we filled the
cbcr frame buffer with the value hex 80
this can be done by just calling the
command without abusing anything and
then we copy the content of our our
arbitrary source into the y component
and we do that by choosing a size such
that only a third of the buffer is
filled now we have the constellation
where the Y component contains the
information we want to disclose and the
rest Ponte
xat sorry now we want to apply CSC on
that buffer but we don't want to change
content of it how can we achieve that by
choosing the same address for the source
as destination and as such mempie will
not have any effect and we can then
apply CSC and it will gray fully output
the Y component to us and the last step
is to read every fourth byte of the
output Y every fourth byte because our
GP is equal to Y so it's the same
information now what is it all about
again we had a stack smash and we wanted
to find out the stack cookie and now we
have it well we have obtained an
arbitrary primitive and we still need
find out that value that cookie is
stored in a data type meant of some
module but where's that data segment
remember there is a SLR and it can be
our anywhere and we definitely don't
want to breathe somewhere and hit an
invalid page and make the application
crash fortunately there is an easy
approach the piece between where is 12
megabytes big and is stored in the PHP
data segment and it's always allocated
at these two addresses which means that
there's only an entropy of 5 bits and it
also means that can read at that address
safely because in the first case it's 1
megabytes within a segment in the second
it's only slightly of this to start and
from that point on we iterate backwards
and search for some unique constant once
we find that we can determine the ASRs
light and from that point on we can
determine all basis and know the exact
location of the star cookie
now we can put it together we put a
stock key at the right position and
overflow the buffer and get that
exception we can control PC arbitrarily
and that's always something cool to see
that will value here all right we were
able to execute that we are able to
execute Rob chains with system
privileges but we want to stay in MIPS
world and orchestrate arm function calls
instead because we don't want to write
complex rope chains so for every
function call in our world we prepare a
small rope chain that contains set
function and the arguments and we smash
the stack with it and then the Rope
chain will store the context and receive
the execution intent the return value
will be returned back to the client and
for pointers we can just use the PSP RAM
and map it to the native address space
but we need to be careful with the MIPS
cache so before we send the command we
need to write the write back the cache
such that the ARM processor and see the
real contents and we also need to
invalidate it such that we can see that
the changes that were made from the ARM
processor and finally we are able to
write hybrid code which used native API
but run on the MIPS processor now we
have already at the arm userland and the
last step is to attack the arm kernel
while developing I noticed something
weird of the multiple arm function calls
wireless LAN would stop working how was
it possible we oh we only escaped the
emulator and we didn't touch the kernel
yet it turned out that the buffer we
used to smash the stack was passed to a
wireless LAN I have control command and
this command would notice that the
buffer was not valid and bailed out
but while bailing out it forgot to free
some heap allocation and in the baddest
land driver there are only eight slots
available for heap allocations so that
means that after eight function calls
you would already run out of memory with
the same mindset as before if there's
such a buck means that there's potential
for more severe bugs and I found a hip
overflow just right after looking at it
it looks like that so it allocates
temporary buffer and copies use the data
into it and then it allocates a work
butter and paste the data from temporary
buffer into it with a size choosable by
us and then it frees the locations in
last in first out order and this
overflow is on a custom heap now why do
we even have a custom heap because the
network stack is based net bsd 4.0 and
the base Victor doesn't really have
malloc and free in kernel so that's why
they had to implement their own custom
male malloc free API so the cusp
implements a best fit algorithm which is
good for performance which is memory
efficient bad for performance the heap
maintains a free list as well as a busy
list and free chunks are always Qualis
so it means that no two free chunk can
consecutive in memory and the heap
contains heap cookies which indicate
whether chunk is free or whether it is
busy and it also contains a heap cookie
at the end of every tank to prevent
buffer overflows but because these
cookies are instant and because we
control the buffer of the overflow we
can just simply fake it and the last the
last last but not least the heap grows
backwards
high too low which is benefited for us
as you can see later now we have a
diagram which shows the initial state
where we allocated a buffer on the
bottom and the word buffer on the top
and the busy head points the word buffer
and now data from the temporary buffer
will be copied into the work buffer and
overflow into temporary buffer itself
and because we know what we over flow
like we know what chunks there is we
know we only corrupt the chunk header
and that's something we need to restore
after exploitation now after the
overflow we plan to fake chunks where
the first is a basic chunk and the
second is a fake free chunk and they
point to arbitrary addresses now why
does the on the bottom need to be free
because when freeing the preview the
physical next chunk is considered as
free if it is different from the logical
next chunk so if we freed the jump on
the top it will look at the pointer and
it sees that the logical next is same as
the physical next in case it needs to
repeat the procedure and in the second
round the next the logical next chunk
points to an arbitrary address which is
not equal to the physical next that
means that the chunk bottom must be free
and that's exactly what happens when we
free the junk on the top and the
basically busy head also changes and the
fake return now points back to the work
buffer and what do we have above we have
the work point written to arbitrary
next and that's our write limit
now we're not finished
we still need to free the temporary
buffer and after bring that the busy
list head changed again
and now we destroyed the whole structure
null is also written to arbitrary ref
and now we have three chunks left ready
to be merged after merging the first two
chunks
we have taste consolation so nothing
really interesting happened but we still
have two terms left to be merged and
once again we have a right primitive
where the work pointer is written to
arbitrary pref overall f3 writes the
book a pointer is written to our top
null is written to our right and again
work is written to our bottom and let's
use that to redirect a kernel pointer
this code is used to allocate the hex
800 bytes work buffer now we want to
overwrite the value of V 4 plus hex 580
why because by doing that and by
executing that code we can dereference
the kernel pointer from the world buffer
which we control but for that we need to
know where we for it so we need an new
information leak so now we've system
privileges I was looking for sis calls
that are that were only accessible with
system privileges and they found that
one it's a simple bug where hex 40 bytes
are allocated on the stack but only 8
bytes are initialized the whole buffer
is returned back to userland
and to exploit which is caused some
interesting Cisco's before and then
invoke that Cisco
to leak the contents all right we can
use that primitive to leak text pointers
or leak the kernel stack base and most
importantly we can leak the value of V
for now with that information we prepare
a kernel Rob chain which we plant in the
kernel stack and we prepare a small stop
to pivot the stack this stop is stored
in the world buffer now we launch the
unlink attack and redirect the v4 + hex
580 value to the stuff and we can voke
the victim code and kick off our corner
of chain that's it of their exploitation
we allocate a readwrite page we copy our
payload into the page and we mark it as
read and executable and then we execute
it in the payload we restore the heap
data structure and remove signature
checks and load the custom firmware
framework and that's it that was the
whole journey from MIPS userland
to Arkana
[Applause]
sorry now I wanna showcase you the
exploit chain all right so so customized
PS Vita which a friend of mine made so
we now have the Trinity application
which is a PSP application and I we run
it and we have a pool animation and I
will get into the bootstrap called
construct it's a reference to matrix and
now we have the ability to launch
homebrews example Vita shell which is a
file manager that I created and welcome
to head
[Applause]
now I want to show you some other things
that I made for example adrenaline so as
mentioned before like though there's a
MIPS processor you can only play PSP
games and I extended it and lo loaded
the whole film we're into it such that
we have a two in one device and if you
had the PSP you would recognize it and
the last thing we wanna show is Enzo is
a it's a bootloader hack by T molecule
and it allows you to hack the piece B
this bit at the earliest stage and I
will reboot the device and have a custom
logo from T molecule and we put into
Casper firmware directly alright back to
the slide so chief connect code
execution in the me processor by
exploiting a type confusion
vulnerability and by a race condition
vulnerability and we escaped the PSP
emulator by reading arbitrary memory
using color space conversion and by
smashing a stack and finally we
escalated to our kernel privileges using
a kernel stack info leak and a heap
unlink attack the source code and a more
tip right up is available at a blink
please check it out if you want to see
how all the things were implemented and
in my final words I want to encourage
you to join to see there are a lot of
cool challenges so as mentioned before
the network stack is based on net bsd
4.0 which is quite old so maybe you can
search for some box that
have been fixed between 4.0 and the
current version and applied them to the
PS Vita for example a Buckeye found in
ED PST I originally did current on the
PS Vita but then I realize it was still
available in the current version if
you're into reverse engineering you can
try to find vulnerabilities in the boot
ROM or boot loader or you can try to
reverse it in your driver and port into
Linux which is work in progress and
myself I have been working on a safe
state feature which allows you to make a
snapshot at any point and the later
restore it which is technically really
fun and I would like to express my
gratitude towards T molecule for the
driver prior research without them I
wouldn't be able to all to do all this
stuff
I want to thank quick racer for the MIPS
kernel vulnerabilities I want to thank
my manager and my team for encouraging
me and for supporting me
thanks Apache and lip lower for the four
slides ideas and for their friendship it
tends to my family for everything and
thank you for your attention
you