[Music]
so hi everyone welcome to our talk bugs
on the windshield fuzzing the windows
kernel we know it's been a very long day
with many interesting talks and we hope
you enjoyed we thank you for sticking
around
and we hope you enjoy watching this
presentation as much as we had making it
so just a little bit about us my name is
Evelyn I'm the CTO at Oracle security
I've been a security researcher for 10
years it's a bitly redundant and
recently I've been added to nsrc most
secure most valuable security research
list for 2019 I'm a security researcher
at checkpoint research and I'm also in
the same list as you we had a pretty
successful fuzzing campaign fuzzing
binary format parsers in userspace we
found multiple vulnerabilities in
formats such as JPEG PDF wmf and so on
and targeting mostly Adobe Reader and
Microsoft edge if you want to check out
more if you want to read more about this
research you should check out checkpoint
research blog for more details
yeah but at this point we were wrapping
out the previous research and we felt
that we wanted a bigger challenge and
fuzzing Windows kernel seemed hard
enough and as an added bonus we can use
our user space vulnerabilities chain
them together with our newly found
kernel all abilities and get a full
chain which is pretty cool so since this
is a positive fuzzing presentation I'm
gonna do a really quick recap of what is
fuzzing fuzzing is a method for
automatic software testing it's the most
cost effective way we know for finding
real bugs in real software the input for
the process or the targets if to you
what you want to fuss and CPU time and
the outputs are hopefully bugs an
example of a very basic buzzer is W
random it just pipes random bytes into
destiny in f2 STD N and this was a
killer fuzzer back in the 90s fuzzing is
also a very active area of research and
as you can see from the graph the number
of publications for you grows very
rapidly but we're in this talk we're
interested in modern fuzzers
modern fuzzles consists of three things
three major things one is a test case
generator and mutator which is
responsible for automatically generating
inputs a bad Oracle which is something
that detects buggy conditions that
usually means seg fault but it can be
any other thing like asserts memory
leaks and so on and finally we need some
sort of a feedback mechanism which in
modern fuzzers is usually coverage but
it can be any other metric that you can
target like CPU cycles memory and so on
example the modern fathers area fairly
father Hong funds
Hong fuzz and a few others and if we
look back at the example of our previous
father we can see that Devi random has a
test case generator random it's not a
very good one but it exists it has a bug
Oracle it can detect segmentation faults
but it doesn't have any feedback
mechanism so definitely not a modern
fuzzer
so let's see the process of coverage
guided fuzzing and how it works
internally so we start with an initial
corpus which is a fancy word for a bunch
of inputs usually files we take this in
we take the inputs and import them into
the fuzzer cube we take the we either
generate new input or select one from
the two and mutate that randomly and
then we feed it to our coverage
instrumented program then if if if the
program crashed that's great we have a
bug we can triage it and save it
triaging means look for looking for
duplicates otherwise we will check if
new coverage was detected when we say
new coverage we usually means new if
statements were arrived if it was so
we'll try to minimize it and save it
otherwise we'll discard it and keep on
going this is basically how every
coverage guided father's work AFL League
fuzz fuzz I know in all others so back
to our research we were and we said to
herself well we have an experience with
AFL can we use AFL to attack OS kernels
and the answer is yes there's kfl
which is AFL with okay and K stands for
kernel so K FLE is a research father
from the bottom university that
leverages AFL style fuzzing for
attacking OS kernel it KL supports
Windows Linux and Mac OS and it was used
to find real bugs in real software which
is kind of what we're after k FL has a
pretty interesting architecture and
we're gonna review it very quickly
the main father runs on the host and
when it starts it will spawn multiple
virtual machines running the target
target OS the in the agent there will be
a pre-loaded in the VM there will be a
VIP reloaded agent that will cooperate
with the father to drive the fuzzing
process in the fuzzing loop looks
something like this first the father the
agent will request an input from the
father the input will be transferred
through shared memory then the a the
agent will send a request to the
hypervisor to tell him to start
recording a coverage we'll talk about
exactly how in a moment then the agent
will pass the inputs to whatever we want
to attack in in our example its tests s
and finally it will tell the the
hypervisor to stopped racing coverage
and test the coverage back to the father
KF else coverage implementation uses
Intel processor trace for those of you
who are less familiar the Intel
processor trace which is also known as
Intel PT is a low overhead hardware
execution tracing feature in the Intel
CPU it it uses it uses a trace it uses
the hardware to write trace information
into compressed memory and AKL
uses a fast decoder to decode to decode
those traces into full traces finally
how does a FL detect crashes well when
the agent is first loaded kfl the agent
will send the addresses of object in
buck checks to the hypervisor
the hypervisor will attach the addresses
of bug check and bug tracks with a
special shell code that we have a
special shell code that each use a hyper
call when the system crashes the the
kernel will call buck chicken buck check
X which is which
we'll call KVM which in turn notified
the father that we crashed and this is a
screenshot for kfs dashboard if you
blink fast enough it kind of looks like
AFL so what should we attack with AFL or
kfl so from our experience good target
for AFL ok a fella I have a few
characteristics
the first one is they're fast you are
able to execute hundreds of iterations
per second and the second thing is their
parsers specifically for binary formats
those are the best targets so we can ask
ourselves which best binary format
parsers live inside the Windows kernel
and the answer there are quite a few
there are the file system and file
system like formats like registry and
NTFS CLF as fat and so on there is the
device drivers that first binary
information there are there's the crypto
API that uses some of it there's the P
format that we did actually they've
talked about before and a few others but
we looked at this map and we want and we
said to ourselves let's take a step back
let's look at the typical kernel
vulnerability at this case C V 2018 zero
seven four four you don't have to really
read the code you just have to look at
the structure of the code and you can
really see that it has a few properties
the first one this there are many system
calls here there's not just one at the
end they all receive highly structured
data like structs have magic numbers
function pointers strings flags and so
on
and notice that there are dependencies
between the calls that meaning that the
output of one call is the input for the
next phone which means that and this is
this is pretty common for a kernel
vulnerability where we don't actually
parse anything binary but there is a
sequence of calls that reaches a state
where vulnerability is triggered and
these are the kind of on abilities we
want our fuzzer to find so going step
back okay
what kfl provides us
is a binary blob and what we want is a
sequence of semantically meaningful sis
cones preferably in a C file so at that
point and if we look back at the
available attack surface when looking at
K FL and compare it with Cisco father we
can see that the map now drastically
changes and this this VM provides us an
attacker much more room to work with so
we decided to dump k FL and move to a
Cisco father and we did what every good
researcher does we used Google to find
the Cisco father
and so we found this caller and I'll
call it Nathan L to the stage tell you
all about it
thank you sis color is covered guided
structure working on father
try saying this five times in a row it's
also known as a smart Cisco father
it supports running a multiple supports
multiple operating systems such as Linux
FreeBSD Fuchs yeah Android and others
support running on multiple machine
types such as such as qmu gas Google
Cloud engine instances mobile phones and
up and so on it's also support multiple
architectures like x86 64 64-bit arms
and others this collar is also known in
some circles as the hardest-working
researcher in the Linux kernel community
today it has found around 37 hundred
bugs in the Linux kernel one example is
CB 2019 two two one five use of the
frame binder which was found being
exploited in world as you can see in the
screenshot below from sis bot sis colors
online dashboard it was found two years
prior by Caesar color if you recall from
a few slides ago these are the free
foundations of modern fathers let's see
how Cisco answered this material
starting with test case generator
material sis color generates programs
which are a sequence of Cisco's let's
look at an example of a program
generated by sis color this program
opens a file called file 0 and assign
each result to R 0 this weird pointer
assignment syntax our instruction to
Cisco our instructions to write the file
the string file 0 to memory and pass its
pointer to the open Cisco this syntax is
not only used for strings but also
describing memory layouts of struct
buffers unions and so on next the
program reads 57 bytes from the file to
memory and finally it closes the file
but how does this color generate
programs well it uses syscall
descriptions Cisco descriptions are or
how you as a researcher defined two sis
color how to call Cisco's it's basically
the rest
is used by sis caller to bake programs
let's look at the simple syscall
descriptions for example this is coaxial
exit which has only one parameter in the
error code which is which is an int
notice that sees that this color has a
go like syntax where the word where the
argument type comes after the argument
name a more complicated example is the
open Cisco the clause is concerned this
is called receive the file descriptor
which is technically an int however we
know that file descriptors are a
resource or a kernel resource meaning
that bundle number would just be
rejected but sorry I'm oh yeah sir so
the cisco this receive this Cisco
receives a file descriptor as I said
earlier meaning that random numbers will
just be rejected by the kernel that's
why cisco has the concept of a resource
which is a type that it cannot generate
by itself but it has to use other
Cisco's to obtain it an example of Cisco
that generates a file descriptor is the
open Cisco Cisco also supports flags
structs unions and more in the case of
open you know it knows that open mode is
a flag which means it can use one or
more flags together last example is the
wreath Cisco the Cisco receives a buffer
is an input which it will write up to
lengths bytes to it notice that that
buffer and lengths have a semantic
relationship meaning that if the length
is bigger than the buffer the Cisco will
probably fail siskel descriptions are
written to text file since this gem
which is another sis color tool will
take all the say all the Cisco
descriptions and not to magically
generate a go code that will be compiled
into this father this buzzer will found
will then start generating programs by
randomly selecting Cisco's and making
sure to satisfy all the dependencies
Cisco are also able to mutate existing
programs let's look at the flu mutation
strategies insert call well inserts a
call making sure to
satisfy all the dependencies to call
successfully the Cisco muted art will
mutate an argument according to its type
splice will take two random programs and
join them squash and Eve will perform
AFL Stein mutation on complex pointers
such as drugs buffers unions and so so
clearly see scholar has a sophisticated
test case test case generator mutator
moving on to feedback mechanism now that
we know how this caller generates
programs let's look at the bigger
picture
the main binary for sis caller is his
manager when it starts it will do the
following it will load the purpose of
programs and then it will start the
target machines it will copy the father
and executors binaries to the machine
using an SSH then it will execute the
father at this point this father will
establish connection with his manager
and start communicating by RPC then this
father will fetch the corpus from the
manager and start generating programs
for each program it will send it back to
the manager in case of a crash then it
will start the executor then it'll send
in to the executor which will execute
the sales calls and collect coverage
from the kernel Linux kernel coverage is
done using keiko which is a compile time
tracing feature finally sees executor
will report back the coverage to his
father which will notify the manager in
case of a new coverage feedback
mechanism check finally bug or worker in
case of a crash Linux kernel panic and
we can print crash information to the
output console since manager will then
detect the output message and will
report on a crash
this color is usually used with case on
came son Katie son and other artists
sanitizers
too great which gratefully which greatly
improved the scholar ability to detect
pressures
but Oracle check sis caller aims to be
unsupervised meaning it will try to
automate the entire fussing forces in an
ideal world fathers are just like and
play but like Charlie Miller used to say
working with fathers is like babysitting
an army of monkeys in the case of
crushes his manager will spawn multiple
reproducer machine in the process of
reproduction in the process of
reproduction
since caller will decide the crashing
programs from its log and will try to
minimize them when the process is
finished it will either reproduce this
program like we've seen earlier or a C
code which will produce the crash
so to recap this color is awesome but
this color is for Linux well actually
before this presentation we talked to
Dmitriy vehicle which is the father of
six color and it corrected us sister is
not only for Linux but support other
operating system as well so when we say
this color is for Linux we actually mean
this color is also for Linux so let's
wrong Linux and windows what is w SL w
cell is a compatibility layer for
running Linux binaries natively on
Windows it transit between Linux is
called the Windows API it allows to
interrupt Linux Windows and Linux and
Windows binaries for example you can run
the task list from bash and count the
number of lines it requires less
resources when running a full virtual
machine and finally it was designed to
run bash and called Linux commands for
developers let's see how does it work
starting from Windows 10 there is new
type of a process at the lightweight
process called Pico process when the
pickup process issues a Cisco it will
pass the end it will pass the NT kernel
to a dedicated driver called picker
provider in the case of double yourself
the picker processes our Linux binaries
and the and the picker provider Alex
Cinda LexCorp will transit the Linux
Cisco's to Windows and his Windows
system cause at this point we decided to
fast w so because fuzzing w cell is very
similar to fuzzing Linux kernel we can
use we can reuse most of the existing
grammar and the executor it is
relatively new has two driver as two
drivers which are one one megabyte
Accord with little civvies and finally
we wanted to find bugs for full chain
but we also wanted to get some
experience with this color on Windows so
it looked like a good step first step
for us good first step for us looking at
this color architecture we need to
change few things to the files W so we
need an SSH server which is easy we have
a Linux distro for that we need to find
a way to collect garbage and finally we
need a mechanism to detect crashes and
deduplicate them so how to get tracing
garbage windows this close toast
compiled burner meaning we can use a
compile time tracing feature like keiko
so before the few alternatives the first
one was using an emulator like box or
qumu and landing coverage
instrumentation the second option was
using static binary instrumentation for
coverage like in PFL another option
was using a hypervisor with sampling
coverage like in apple pies but at the
end we settled on on using Intel PT for
coverage like in kfo what we did was to
add patches to KVM to support coverage
with interpreting we used large parts of
kfl KVM patches for that in addition we
exposed the cake off like interface
through hyper calls so now when the
executor tries to start store or
collects coverage if we communicate with
the KVM instead of the kernel we also
added support for exporting coverage in
dynamo format also known as the Archon
format we used either in the heart and
the awesome lighthouse plugin to visual
the coverage here's an example of how
light off of how lighthouse visualized
the coverage by adding colors to
executed basic blocks as for ba-gawk-oh
we used the same technique as in carry
FL in case you already forgot for for
garden we patch back check in back check
X with the shell code that teaches the
iPad poll on the trash where the drag X
identified fresh from p.m. your output
and finally we enable driver verifier
with special pools for L Expo and LX SS
to catch pop eruptions a common issue
with phosphorus is its that they
encountered the same bug many times when
the father find a new crush we want our
father to be able to determine whether
it's actually a unique rush or is it a
duplicate in order to decide this sis
caller has to get a unique crash output
in unique output from for each crash in
the case of windows we settled on a call
stack the simple answer architecture is
really awkward and you should really
read the full blog post for all the
details
suffice to say we had another Windows
machine running alongside our father and
reading from the reading memory from the
guest to us and retrieve a call stack
this architecture was heavily inspired
by box pong for Windows so after a lot
of agony we got from these random
numbers to this beautiful call stack so
a quick recap SSH server check coverage
check first deduplication and detection
check so we started fast to start
fasting double yourself and then it
rained bugs
well not really a short time after we
started or the faster we notice the
crash with critical structure corruption
and we were like what the fast
so a quick googling show that it's
actually very good so why did patch
guard came to our life so let's return
to how we detect brushes remember
remember that we in order to detect
brushes we patch
- scanner so good news everyone pet
guard is working what we first tried is
to enable carbide kernel debugging but
that caused random hangs in the guest
so what eventually we did was to write a
small driver called panic reporter which
will which will register with anthos bug
check orbit with Kay register bugs a
callback so now when the kernel part so
now when the kernel crashes enters will
will call the panic reporter which will
issue hyper call notifying on a crash
another issue we encountered is covered
stability this color is a uses multiple
threads to find data races but our
coverage implementation had only one
buffer per process in practice the same
program would result in different
coverage each run garbage instability
hurts the father's ability to define the
new and interesting paths and
essentially bugs what we did TL DR we
added gas fretwork into KVM and
allocated buffer for each thread if you
want all the details again you should
check the blog where the few more minor
issues like Auto loaded program that
would starve our father's few hundred
Windows Update we started our father's
randomly causing Cisco to think it's a
hang Windows Windows Defender randomly
decided that our father is a virus and
in general take time and make sure you
adjusted for best performance so after
two weeks of fuzzing we got a working
prototype for Cisco learn Windows for
denial of service bugs to that fit in a
tweet to that logs that are still not
resolved but zero security
vulnerabilities were found we were a bit
disappointed but we decided to move to
real privilege escalation target so now
will you have will come and talk to you
about our next target
so we we look back at the attack surface
of the Windows kernel and we decided
sets our sights on win32 K so first
things first what is win32 k it's the
kernel side of the windows subsystem
which is the gooey infrastructure for
the entire operating system it includes
the kernel side of the window manager
also known as user and the kernel side
of the GD graphics device interface also
known as GDI and so why we 32k well it's
a very popular target for local
privilege escalation and we want the
local privilege escalation the reason is
very popular target for local privilege
escalation it's because it has a huge
attack surface with more than 1,500
Cisco's and although it be it has been
fast before some would say to the death
we couldn't find any previous work of
coverage guided grammar fuzzing for that
target so we decided to go for it
looking about it the architecture we
need to make additional changes we need
to change the father and the executor a
minor tweak to coverage our first
attempt was just to rename everything to
dot exe and hope for the best but since
did didn't do the trick we just had to
do a real work so for the executor
changes we needed to support up to 12
parameters per Cisco because you know
windows and the second thing we had to
do was to poured some OS related things
like around thread management shared
memory in pipes not really interesting
and we had to expose Windows Cisco's to
a sis color and we decided that we want
to compile everything on linux compiling
on linux was a bit of a drag because we
needed windows - we needed mingw to
create to call all the windows cisco
what we did is we took dealers from
Windows to Linux we use it to name
gender to create deaf files even we use
another mingw tool to create import lips
and we use that to link everything to
our executor so finally we can call
Windows Cisco's the father also had a
few changes around memory management
shirt and doesn't shared memory and
pipes but and
we had to have to add win32 cake grammar
well we'll talk about win32 K grammar in
a few slides and for coverage win32 K is
not one thing about three things it's
winter it's win32 k win third UK base
and win32 k4 so in our coverage
implementation only supported one module
so what we did is we opted out to
another coverage coverage the decoder
from Winnie FL which is by much faster
and helped us and we can see now
coverage traces from win32 k which is
pretty cool so quick recap further check
IPC check executor check coverage check
what we what did we forget sanity check
so we we took our father for a spin and
we try to reproduce a cv 2920 1807 44
which we showed before but the father
wasn't able to reproduce the bug and we
were a bit surprised so we we
investigated a little bit and we
discovered that our father was earning
under session zero not under normal
session user one the fix was pretty
simple we moved the ssh server from
being a service to being a starter
program but the main conclusion from
this is reproduce all bugs and test your
father's because otherwise you're
probably wasting cpu time so after
sanity check we moved to stability check
we added about 15 api's and we let it
run for the night and we got a blue
screen our first thought was that guard
but after but we tested it without the
father and it was reproduced so we
thought maybe it's not that girl our
first bug was actually i use after free
and open clipboard but it only
reproduces on reproduced on some
machines and we were like what the fuzz
looking at the at crash code at the
crashing code we couldn't find close to
white crashes so we had to go to the
binary looking at the binary we can see
that it crashes when it tries to fetch
the process ID from the process
information block
but the process information block is
already free on machines that the that
the crash reproduces the if statement
above the block evaluates the true well
what does it check for well it checks
where we if win32 k trace logging yeah
is turned on for a specific feature we
what we found out through
experimentation is that this feature is
either turned on or off by boot and it
depends by at the install time and it
depends if you install the same machine
a couple of times it would I will be on
or off and it felt like our Father was
part of an experiment so a feature
experiment so we don't always find a we
don't always get a be tested machine but
when we do we found one ability in one
so we went back to stability checking
and we reinstalled windows making sure
that this feature is definitely turned
off and we had another bug this time it
was a denial of service in registry
classy X which is a pretty weird because
the register class is very is very basic
what we found out is the bug itself is
not in wretched class TX but in RT a lot
okay tip apparently when you allocate
specific sizes in specific time of point
in time you can actually cause the
kernel to allocate from reserved pages
and crash so at this point our
motivation was really high because we
found we added 15 Cisco's and we found 2
bugs and with 1500 Cisco's we're gonna
find like 200 bucks right so yeah at
this point we decided to commit to
writing all the grammar so we writing
grammar is a lot of work because there
are a lot of Cisco's and we bit lazy so
our first thought was automation how can
we automate this there are a few
problems the first one is that the
windows headers don't contain enough
semantic information to generate to
generate quality grammar for example
every every single duplicate type here
means different things in different
contexts and the other thing is that
Windows has a lot of undocumented api's
fortunately
Windows is technically open-source
because there is the Windows NT leaked
sources
there's the Windows 2000 League sources
there's reactor waste which technically
Windows 2003 leaked sources
there's the WR K and a few other
resources so what we did was for each
Cisco we looked at the sources plus the
documentation and we try to verify it as
much as we can with static analysis and
dynamic analysis we became get basically
workers in the grammar minds most API is
are pretty simple but others are really
hard with terrible semantic relationship
and complicated structures it's a few
examples of system calls we reported
it's just to see so we let the fuzz run
for the day and we got through new three
new vulnerabilities within the day and
we let it run for the week and it didn't
find everything new and we we said well
we want more so at this point we we had
to go a bit deeper and and I have to
tell you something that not many people
say fathers are not magic what it means
is that researchers have to help father
to teach them by teaching them tricks
and helping them reach hard to reach
attack surfaces our process for doing
that is we start from reading as much as
we can about the attack surface
everything that we can get our hands off
prior work all the bugs every research
presentation we can see we also try and
reproduce all bugs are bugs teach us a
lot about the attack surface and about
the father's ability to abilities and
limitations and finally and we take time
to look at coverage maps coverage maps
tell you gives you a pretty clear map
where your father is not targeting and
we try to take all of these insights and
we try to inject them back into the
fuzzing process let's see an example
which is not so empirical one thing that
we learned through arts for it through
the research is there is such a thing
called GDI shared handle table which is
an array of structured pointer by
pointed by the PB
it contains all handles for GDI objects
if you notice there's the process ID
which is which indicates which process
owns this specific handle Global handles
are ones that the process ID is zero so
we thought to ourselves maybe we can
teach our father to use those kinds of
handle in the fuzzing process and maybe
it with findbugs so what we did is we
created the new self doe Cisco that
returns handles from this list and we
let the father run for a few hours and
it found a vulnerability almost
immediately the vulnerability itself is
triggered by one system call and it's a
use after free and it involves only the
one a global object so our result for
this part of the of the research were
we've we fought for about a month and a
half of CPU time in our spare time we
found eight own abilities
we got assigned six CVE one was deemed
duplicate and one is still pending we
found three denial of service bugs one a
crash in window GaN which we are having
a really hard time to reproduce and a
few dead locks but the local privilege
escalation is nice can we make it an RC
so enter EMF wmfc flag in the 90s it
supports both vector graphics and bitmap
and if I have to summarize the entire
format in one word in one sentence its
what would happen if we took Siskel's
and wrap them up in an image format the
Microsoft extended the format a few
times in we have EMF EMF bus and EMF
spool and if you want to read all about
this attack surface and the format you
should check out Jerusalem more details
so a we looked at the specs and we've
and under the bitmap record types we saw
there is a stretch ability record type
and for those of you are familiar with
GDI there is a stretch BLT called there
and we happen to have a vulnerability
and stretch BLT so so let's see a demo
so here we we try to show the version of
the of Windows you can see it's pretty
new it was new at the time and we're
opening the EMF image you can we're
using in front of you because making it
work inward was painful and that's it so
a bit about future work we want to fuzz
we only touch them in parts and when 32k
that we were able to fuss we didn't
touchdown drive it directly drivers
because they have input structures that
are hard to model in this color and we
also haven't touched on when 32k a
callback functions for those of you
familiar that's that's where a lot of
blogs are we have a huge corpus of
programs for win32 k about 450,000 so we
thought that to take all of them and run
them through other bug Oracle's such as
box one to see if they find new and
interesting bugs and finally we want to
open source our reports and finally fast
the rest of the kernel but that's the
future work so in summary we started
from our user space vulnerabilities but
we wanted kernel we started we looked at
kfl but it wasn't good enough for us so
we moved to Cisco fuzzing and we found
six color we decided to port to wsl
first because it seemed like the first
good step we moved to we haven't we
didn't have luck so we moved to wintry
2k and we had we found eight
vulnerabilities and we managed to make
some of them are seized we want to say
special thanks to the dynamics tool team
at Google for endometrial II
specifically for creating CS color
Dmitry will be lecturing about this
color tomorrow so I encourage you all to
check his talk and to UM greenhouse
cavite which assisted us in creating the
presentation
unmentioned for his special assistance
in the research thank you
[Applause]