hi everyone thanks for the introduction
my name is Susana and I work for ESET as
a malware researcher and this dog will
actually be about malware about some apt
that we found in the wild where the bad
guys leverage some old school protocol
for GSM fingerprinting which is
interesting so let's have a show of hand
do you recognize any of these strings
okay some of you do I didn't
maybe because these are some commands
that are older than me but let's just be
serious here so these are actually
comments from a so called
haze command set or 80 comments and
these were developed back in the 80s to
control some devices such as GSM modems
or mobile phones for example to change
connection settings or to dial-up and
then later this common set was extended
and new commands were added and they
were born above vendor-specific
and also standardized so they were able
to support more functionality and
actually in 2018 there was a security
research that showed that these 80
comments are not only supported by
modems and older mobile phones but also
by most of the modern smartphones and
what is worse that these commands pose a
huge security risk so what these
researchers did is that they extracted
firmware images from several smartphones
from several Android devices from
several manufacturers and then they
examine these firmware images to extract
the various 80 commands because a lot of
them are vendor specific so each of
these Android smartphones had different
set of commands to support some
different functionality and they
actually found thousands of different ad
comments and then they were doing some
tests where they connected the
smartphone to the computer and they were
sending 80 commands to the smartphone
and just by sending these 80 commands
they were able to bypass android
security settings to inject
firmware or touch events or exfiltrate
some sensitive data so this was a
research front way 20:18 theoretical but
actually it's not the only people who
were looking at these eighty cards
exactly at the same time in 2018 there
was another group of people who was who
were doing research on 80 comments and
we were at we actually found these coins
being misused by malware that is
targeting Windows platform is an
espionage platform that we called a
torque and that's actually what we're
going to talk about today so to have
some perspective this platform is active
since at least 2014 and there were a lot
of different versions but what we are
looking at today is this version that
was released in 2018 with a major code
upgrade where our architecture was
significantly changed and improved the
code is now more professional and
actually this is the version of
authorities still used today we have
seen the late samples the last year so
this is what we're going to talk about
and it brings me to today's agenda so of
course I want to talk about this GSM
fingerprinting feature which is then
used using these 80 comments and also I
want to talk about the other interesting
functionality that gave this platform
its name and that is the elaborate
network communication which is a
customized store but before I go into
that I also want to talk about some
context so whoever is looking at where
the targets and of course we want to see
something about the architecture of the
platform so that we are able to better
understand the specifics of the later so
let's start with the targets the first
thing we knew about at our targets is
that it is highly targeted we've seen
less than 30 targets and these included
some high profile users in Eastern
Europe but this is our telemetry
that's like just a part of the picture
so we also wanted to know more about the
intended targets of a tour so what we
did is that we looked at the
functionality and some artifacts in the
code and we're actually able to learn
more so how we did it first you need to
know something about the platform and
then we look at the artifacts so actor
has the main part say a dispatcher which
comes both in 32 and 64-bit version and
then there is a series of plugins for
both of these versions and how this
whole platform comes to life is that the
plugins are first injected into all the
running processes and then they load all
of the the dispatchers are injected and
that they allowed all the plugins and
the plugins themselves then decide in
which of the processes they will get
activated for example the network
communication plugins only get activated
in processes that already communicate
over the Internet of course this is to
hide the malicious traffic within a
regular stream of network traffic so
similarly the audio recording plug-in is
only activated in the processes that
already communicate using the microphone
such as teleconferencing or VoIP apps
and it is also true for other plugins
but we are only interested about a
screen grabbing plugging at the moment
this is the one that takes screenshots
of several applications to be able to
report on the victims activities and
again it only looks at some specific
processes by the process name or by the
windows title and then it only activates
in some of the processes when we look at
which processes it wants to be activated
we know which application
it's interested in and then which
targets its interested in so when you
first look at the list of the targeted
applications it's nothing special what
you'd expect some mail services some
social networks and office utilities but
there's more
there are also strings like progressing
it GT or and export
and is actually all referred to popular
Russian applications including the two
most popular social networks in Russia
or a VoIP application provided by a
Russian telecom operator so this seems
like a tour is specifically interested
in russian-speaking users and indeed
just confirmed by our telemetry most of
the most of the targets of a tour we're
located in Russia but that's not all
there are also other interesting strings
that point to applications like digital
signature utilities or VPN applications
secure email secure browser so it also
seems like a third is specifically
interested in privacy concern users and
again this is confirmed by another part
of the code so see the true rip other is
taking screenshots of TrueCrypt but also
it tries to contact the TrueCrypt driver
if present on the system and then it's
sent an IOC TL codes to the driver so if
I OC deals are actually used for
determining the version of the true
crypt I've installed and the interesting
part here is that these are through
crypt specific there are not standard
i/o CTO cups so not only not only the
confirms that a tour is interested in
privacy conscious users but also it
shows us something about the skills of
the developers because you first need to
be familiar with the TrueCrypt code and
to see how it works before you can use
this rare technique so let's just prep
the target after it's interested in two
main groups of targets we have seen high
profile users in Eastern Europe and then
individual russian-speaking privacy
concerned users now for the platform
itself so we already seen that the main
part is the dispatcher but then there
are also the other parts the plugins
that are loaded by the dispatcher and
then synchronized with each other then
maybe aside now there are four local
shared folder
are used by the components of other to
share information so some of the plugins
create files in these plug these folders
and other read from them so as for the
plugins there is a installer plugin that
of course ensures persistence of the
whole platform that there are others but
the most interesting ones are maybe
these espionage plugins which collects
some information from the compromised
computer and these are information that
gets stored in the central upload folder
and now you may imagine that this
information gets ultimately exfiltrated
to a CNC server but this is not done
directly because it's a third service so
after is using a series of other plugins
to do so so there is a file uploader
plugin that would regularly check this
upload folder and if there's any new
data then it prepares the data for
exfiltration then there is a torque one
plugin
this is not the door eggsy standard
process but it's a customized version
because atour uses a specific interface
for all of these plugins but it is based
on torque and this one makes sure that
it resolves the onion domain and it
generates the circuit and then encrypts
the data and then it uses the last
plugin which is a Sox proxy that would
then contact the server directly and
that was just one part of the
communication but also the server one to
reach back to the compromised computer
so that you can send some additional
code or data or comments and this is
again then using the socks proxy enter
plugin and they stand the comments get
relayed to another plugin that we named
a command dispatcher and if there's any
new tools pushed to the computer then
these get stored in other central upload
folders and these are then monitored by
the dispatcher so if there is an update
for a plugin then the dispatcher can
load it so there is a mechanism how you
can have your malware always up-to-date
and it works this way so the interesting
part here is that the dispatcher never
directly communicates with the CNC
server it always goes to the other four
plugins and that's the same for these
plugins that collect information so
focusing just on the network
communication it split into four
different components and each of them
implements a different layer two of the
components are running local server so
that the other components can contact
these components and relay the
communication through them I also
already mentioned that these plugins get
only activated in applications where
they're able to hide an the malicious
traffic within a regular stream of
network traffic and also the server is a
Tyrolean service protocol and it's it
used is a customized store for anonymity
and traceability so this was the
platform as a whole but also the
interesting part is how the individual
plugins are implemented and how they are
synchronized with the dispatcher so when
you look at the plugins and they don't
have the dispatcher you're not able to
analyze them because there are a lot of
references to some mysterious function
and this function is actually
implemented in the others dispatcher and
acts like a proxy for Windows API
functions or cryptographic functions and
other functions like this so only if you
have access to the dispatcher you're
able to map it with the plugins and to
actually give some meaningful names to
the romance and why this is able to work
is there remember the dispatcher is
injected into the processes where the
plugins are injected as well that means
they share the same address space so
it's a it's possible that they call each
other's function so for this specific
function this is passed to the plugins
onload by the dispatcher and then
subsequently plugins always use the
functions of the dispatcher to do the
basic window API functions and crypto
functions and so this is how the load
looks like the plugins are implemented
as the
else with a I'd say traditional expert
named DLL get class object but this is
not the important part there to other
parts so first this is where the
dispatcher passes the pointer to the
helper function or the dispatcher
function to the plugins and then this is
where the plugins returned the plugin ID
and the plug-in version and this helped
us sort all of the plugins that we had
and to track which plugins are in which
version of the development cycle these
are all the plugins that we have you can
see the IDS and analyze versions over
here and now this IDs look like the
numbering is continuous and you can
notice that we are probably missing some
plugins and that's not so surprising
because remember the platform is highly
targeted so likely they're using
differences of plugins for different
things so we probably don't see all the
victims and don't have all the plugins
but also it was difficult to obtain the
plugins because they're only present on
this encrypted with a strong encryption
so you need access to the function to
the dispatcher to be able to decrypt the
plugin so if you don't have them you
cannot analyze them so that's why we
don't have all the plugins nevertheless
from all these plugins we are only going
to talk about this one the device
monitor plug-in which is responsible for
GSM fingerprinting among other
functionalities so two notes to this
plug-in before we dive in first one is
that this plug-in is assigned ID one is
interesting it's a such a prominent
space maybe it indicates that this is
the most important functionality of a
tour but also the version that we
analyze is number fourteen and that's
the highest of all the versions that we
analyzed and that could also mean that
the developers put some more effort into
developing these in the
this specific plugin let's look at it
closer let's look at the GSM
fingerprinting functionality so we've
already seen these strings now let's
give them some meaning so these are
commands that are referred from a tour
when some device is connected to the
compromised computer a tour is using
this ad command protocol these are just
the commands that are used inside the
protocol so we have this a deployment
that always denotes start of
communication with the device 84
attention then if the computer wants to
use this extended set of extended 80
comments it would use this command and
then there are more interesting commands
such as retrieving model number place
manufacturer software version and then
the IMEI number which is a unique
identifier of the device the IMS ID
number which is a unique identifier of
the device subscriber or owner of the
SIM card and finally the IMS ISDN number
and that's the mapping between the owner
identity and the telephone number so
just to recap what a tour is doing is
that when it detects a device connected
to the computer it starts sending 80
commands to communicate with the device
and by that it's able to retrieve
information both about the device itself
but also about its subscriber identity
and also its telephone number and you
may have noticed that I have used the
term device a lot but I never specified
what kind of device a tour is after so
there was actually the question that we
were asking as well so what devices is
at or trying to fingerprint is it the
modems because originally the ad
commands were developed for modems or is
it some older phones which also have
card and support 80 commands or is it
possible that it targets a more modern
devices that also have SIM cards such as
smart camera smart watches or smart
phones from the research from 2018 we
have seen that smart phones also 480
commands so it would be possible to
exfiltrate sensitive data from the smart
phones just by using 80 comments and
also also much more so that was our
first hypothesis and we checked how
other is actually connecting to the
devices so this is part of the code
where Authority tags that some device
was connected to the computer and this
says whether it would come it would send
any commands to the device or not so
what it does is that it checks for the
device friendly name and then it
searches for a calm substring in the
friendly name and that means it targets
devices that they're either connected to
a serial port or a virtual serial port
so not your standard smartphones
normally when you connect smart phones
to your computer you use the USB port
and then the friendly name looks
completely different so either there's
like the smartphone name or there is a
USB substring but this comes up string
so it seems like although it would be
possible to fingerprint smart phones
other is completely ignoring them if
there is a device device connected to a
USB port it doesn't send the 80 commands
at all so then we considered a totally
different hypothesis maybe this is
indeed just that author is trying to
look for some old modems or old phones
platform has been around since 2013 so
it could be some residual if we remember
that it only targets devices that are
either connected to the serial port or
by a USB to come adapter and also if we
remember that GSM modems and some older
phones do support 80 commands but this
also turned out not to be
right because we've seen the plug-in
used for the first time in a new
upgraded version that was released in
2018 so never before but more
importantly in 2019 we have seen a new
upgraded version of this plug-in
recompile to 64-bit architecture so if
it was really just a resume not used
anymore why would the attackers bother
recompiling the plug-in for a 64-bit
architecture so we don't really think
this is the case we think that the
developers behind a tour do know what
they are using the plugin for and they
do know where they keeping it up-to-date
and so there are different theories and
different kind of devices that could be
affected by this malware so first of all
obviously it's the modems and older
phones which can be both connected by
serial bird and support 80 commands but
then also if you consider the types of
victims that author is after which is
also some high profile users these can
be some governmental organizations and
they can use some specific specialized
GSM communication devices or basically
any other devices that satisfy these
conditions the attackers behind a tour
could have learned about these specific
devices using other reconnaissance
method methods and we can only guess
what types of devices these are and then
there are further possibilities these
are not probably targeted by at all but
there can be any other malware which
will take these other devices as targets
such as ICS devices which do support 80
commands and are connected using serial
ports are as I mentioned before it can
take smartphones at targets and do the
same just by not ignoring devices that
are connected to the USB port and if
this is true then the implications are
huge so first of all we've already seen
that other is doing
device fingerprinting so it queries for
the identifiers of the device and the
subscriber so after it has this
information it can do several things
either it can do geolocation in some
certain scenarios with these numbers if
you have also other resources you are
able to locate the connected device but
also in other scenarios remember there
are thousands of other 80 comments and
they are mostly vendor specific so the
attacker has this information they can
then craft another plugin which is
specifically made using the eight
commands that are supported by this
specific device and that can serve as a
base for further data theft or device
compromise such as pushing some
corrupted firmware or whatever else the
attackers have in mind so to conclude we
have seen three things I would like to
have us free takeout from today so first
of course we are talking about this
utter malware but this is not the most
important one but let me just summarize
the other malware is targeting to rupes
of users its individual privacy
concerned users that are
russian-speaking but also it targets
high-profile users in Eastern Europe
and we don't know who is behind this
malware but judging from the technical
complexity and the unusual functionality
we certainly know that substantial
resources must have been invested into
development of this malware so it's
worth further tracking but more
importantly what we have seen today is
that even these old-school protocols
such as eight commands are worth
checking and looking into because they
still can pose a security threat
nowadays even if you have it supported
in some modern by some modern devices
and most importantly we can see that
it's really important to do both
theoretical and practical research
we need to do more research that is also
looking at what is currently being used
in the wild but also looking for other
possibilities because as we can see the
attackers are also doing their own
research and we need to know where they
are and wait to be up-to-date with what
they are up to so with this I would like
to conclude my presentation if you would
like to read hold white paper on a Turk
and you can use this link and thank you
for your attention
[Applause]