breathe
alright I guess it's about side and I
start the last piece we're going to go
to Hollywood all right quick let's come
to the Hollywood really pretty sure i'm
not that was a hard time Clinton hit a
moose is we're going to juice that woman
like a buffalo I showed up here I get
one well back to work Lars you don't
probably know this team I don't know how
many can help I met this guy sep tember
1966 first day of 9th grade of high
school in New York oh man and we were
really really great friends with her
click and then we disappeared for 27 5
years until high school reunion
disappeared for 10 years then I was
going to produce a Tesla movie he said
no you're not I was right and we say
friends ever since and he came out of
nowhere you go I'm coming to your event
and I got something to say Mike Masucci
my dear friend
high school thanks for whenever I am
very much not and no either with Richard
no I'm not hear that but but I'm in the
last two days I've had a number of
revelations that hopefully I can use
them in to whatever say I'll have a very
short in the context of what I do um but
I first want to say there was a room
realization actually and having a lunch
conversation with this young
professional who serves in our military
that up until this conference I had
previously only had extended
conversations with three members of the
Armed Forces and I have 62 years old the
vast majority of people I have spoken to
in the military are in this room and two
are in the Swedish that gives me a
certain vantage point and hopefully will
inform this discussion in ways that
don't always happen although I suspect
among your peers many of these
conversations do happen ah first
operational definition there's Hollywood
and there is Hollywood I am of off
hollywood there are Los Angeles is the
cultural capital of two forms of world
culture one is the culture we all know
very well popular culture but on Richard
mentioned post-world war two and largely
seated initially and this is absolute
fact by the CIA as a cold war tactic
there was the rise of a wholly American
kind of art form whose name has changed
a number of times actually the first
name they act had and then they have
jumped that was free enterprise painting
they replaced that with abstract
conceptualism he said splintered off
into a dozen different genres
performance art fluxus and my little
world video art video art is a
knitted ly very pretentious term I did
not coin it but the projects I make are
seen by hundreds of people not hundreds
of millions of people but the people
that collect video art are the movers
and shakers of the planet just like the
people who that could collect abstract
expressionism or any other kind of
contemporary art practice are the elite
of our world um the most affluent
current living artist is a guy named
Jeff Koons you may or may not know his
name you may or may not like his name
and believe I'm not trying to sell you
this work to like or not like but to not
know about it is to have a major hole in
psych ops in my humble opinion chickens
up Jeff's Jeff Koons KO ons his last
sculpture sold for about 55 million
dollars he's not yet 50 um China is one
of the largest purchasers of this work
obviously the UK obviously America the
point is though that there's a kind of
visual vocabulary and that's a term I
want us to have throughout this little
talk there is a visual vocabulary of
whether combining traditional narrative
storytelling with the thousands and
thousands of years of image making that
we have done going back to La Scala and
actually they found even earlier cave
paintings in your future so as long as
there have been the modern humans there
have been the various languages that we
use to communicate which of words are
only one of those languages dance is
another visual art and music are the
others um but wouldnt i first talked
about an outsider entering your world
and looking at things that otherwise I
would have never looked at and look at
them with the eye of a curator look at
it at the eyes somebody whose work is
pretentiously collected and stored in
museums
arm I didn't know what I was going to
expect I had heard the common cliches
these videos are really good well as
those of you who have seen them know
these videos are really good there's of
course the suppositions of course us
being you know products of the academic
model these guys must have gone to USC
film school these guys what's about to
UCLA or a afire NYU maybe they did but
they didn't have to because of the world
you've created this networked world
where there are thousands of tutorials
on every aspect of everything including
filmmaking they absolutely did not have
to go to USC force so I don't know who
they are I don't know where they came
from I don't know how many of them there
are or how old they are I just know
they're as good as any other filmmakers
I have ever and that's not good news for
slides just to kind of go through my
little tiny world like i said i am off
hollywood um I make my living making
projects that get shown at places like
the Getty Museum and stuff like that
this around the time the conflicts we're
really talking about began I'm going to
take it back I just arbitrarily picked
2005 2005 four years after nine eleven
three years after Daniel Pearl we could
slice the timeline any one of a number
of ways I am arbitrarily beginning the
timeline with the murder on camera of
Daniel Pearl arm there have been plenty
of videos going back since before the
fall of the Soviet bloc of Independence
using video as a tool for political
terror political change depends on your
vantage point but when Daniel Pearl was
beheaded on camera
for me this conversation began in a
different way um this is an image
created in 2005 by my partner Kay
Johnson um we take those for fun as
she's made some of the largest projected
images that humans have ever made she
makes videos to get projected not just
on one but in some cases five building
simultaneous video art it's not hips are
it's not Disney it's a whole other order
of being on this picture obviously this
is a still from the video but you can
see in 2005 Kate was thinking about a
lot of things what do artists do artists
don't answer questions they raise them
that's what they do any artist who is
decent is not somebody who just makes a
picture they are someone who asks a
question what is Kate asking privacy
information data alienation all of the
things this conference is touched on in
various ways um next slide please we
draw him down her up redwood the same
year i was making this digital animation
again it's still from the video 2005 I'm
sure there's a lot of difference
opinions as to about the strategy our
nation was taking in 2005 I have my
questions my questions are on the screen
um you don't have to agree with them you
don't have to disagree with them but
what an artist does is asked questions
the little group my place is called is
not the bittorrent by the same name
which is much younger and stole our name
to which every day we get email soon I
can't download Nashville I don't do it
dude
why not tell you eztv is now in its 36th
year we are arguably the first place in
our part of the world Hollywood on to
understand the implications of not only
personal video but the digital
revolution and we were very very early
compadres with you guys in using what
became known as the internet um I
facilitated my first project with the
internet in 1983 connecting several high
schools around the country in which
young artists through paint boxes made a
picture together in 1987 I did my first
international and lavaca receive are
linking Sri Lanka to West Hollywood
where a year before the Finns claimed
authorship of the chat room we did a
chat room um we then on to create what
was arguably the first digital art
gallery in the world um so we know your
world but we know it from the other side
of the neighborhood we're the content
makers I don't know how your tools work
I don't know how you protect what we all
do but I really do know how important it
is what you're doing and how important
it is that we protect this fragile
little thing that we have all built
together and I say all because the fact
of the matter is when we use computers
as we think of them today we are largely
using the intellectual authorship from
artists because they were artists that
said to engineers well it would be cool
if community to make the color purple
why would really be good if your
resolution kept tempting so those
aliases those ugly little stepped images
can start to be calm photorealistic it
was a guy like David am a painter by
training who knocked on the door of the
Jet Propulsion labs and I want to be
your first artist in residence Jeff
proposal epson what why do we need an
artist in residence and then
back and forth until he finally said oh
we can do fly by simulations of your
space missions and they team up with a
guy named jam dr. James Flynn went on to
win a MacArthur Genius and much of what
everyone from Hollywood to Isis was
imagined first by artists and then
realized by collaborative engineers I
picked this slide out of a number that i
could have because as a few people have
mentioned before there is a very strange
balance between male and female
participation here not so in my world
this is one of a number of events the
University of Southern California did
last year in recognition of our 35th
year they did a three-month region-wide
retrospective in which they talked about
computer are in an independent video and
they put 300 of our projects into their
permanent collection um this is one
about computer art and all except me are
women many of the beginners of what we
now think of as Pixar and things like
that were actually created by what i
call artists scientists like Rebecca
Allen Rebecca went to art school about a
BFA from Rhode Island School of Design
and then went to MIT and got a master's
in computer science in order to do her
art she didn't become a computer
scientist but she needed that because
back then calarts didn't teach digital
art that horrible generation did that
she went out to create UCLA's school of
media art then the besaurus and another
such person created USC's animation
Department women matter in all Hollywood
most of the kind of stuff I do though is
not about what I think about more or
what I think about social issues
although I have much here a lot of its
collaboration with scientists I've done
another project a lot of projects over
the years in which I collaborated with
physicists this one also from 2005 it's
called rage to know in which it's hard
to see in this image but these are
actually live dancers
from Donna stir Bergen company
underneath is she doing this oscillating
kind of thing primordial ooze it all of
that as we kind of do our little take on
the evolution of the universe um someone
did presentation yesterday about drones
last year as part of the USC
retrospective i did with with donna
alive multimedia piece in which some of
the performers were drones dancing with
with dancers while simultaneously
beaming from the hague three dancers who
collaborated and dancing people live
dancers as avatars that's what I do um
it's not Hollywood but it's right next
door it uses the same tools so how does
this in my kind of little off the wall
world that most people have never heard
of or know exists how does it relate to
the real world the very very very real
world where video is a weapon of mass
destruction imagine those of you who are
military people imagine a tool that can
simultaneously infiltrate any continent
be distributed as many times as needed
and perform both recruitment and terror
at the same time it's called an
eight-hundred-dollar video camera um a
lot of times I hear how state-of-the-art
Isis's videos are and as I said to you
when we first met they don't have high
production value and I'll go through a
little bit later or just what a small
shopping basket you need they have to
use an art phrase high-concept they
really really know how to use a tool in
its most informed way maximizing the
historical legacy of all that's come
before and do it precisely for their
objective what surprised me the most
when I saw these videos and I will put
on you this is not going to be a snuff
film show you are going to see there
very very little of what is out there
but in order to do what I needed to do
to talk to you today I had to go to
where these things are and see what they
were what I was surprised to see is that
they had mastered the art of advertising
they had mastered the art of the music
video of the promotional of reality TV
of documentary filmmaking any heroic
narrative do they have to go to USC to
do that no they might have but they
didn't have to so since everything is a
comparative relative in order to think
how their stuff is good I had to know
what our teen had so I looked around
that vintage around the time that al
Qaeda in Iraq was more thing into Isis
and I said what do we got to show so i
found a u.s. army commercial but first
as you see the depiction of atrocity has
gone back as long as there have been
civilized images look collected this is
a Syria this is the conquering Syrian
Army flaying its prisoners of war now we
are desensitized to this medium stone
carved on the side of a wall but there
was a time that this was terrifying and
not something you would casually pass by
at a museum and not really even look at
but the history of no terror Nick
mentioned we talked a little there has
never been a time when the military has
not known the advantage of art the
military poster the flags the banging
drums are blowing trumpets whose tools
are those guys they're artists tools but
they can be used and have always been
used
as instruments of terror or if we detach
and take away the emotion of instruments
of theatre majin de to someone before no
Hollywood screenwriter worth his salt or
her salt he's not very very aware with a
book that was written so long ago it's
hard to believe it still it's relevant
today and that's poetic spy Aristotle we
think of Aristotle in many different
ways again depending around specialties
some think of him as a father of science
well he was actually also a theater
career um because back then there was no
notion of artists or scientists you were
both and to me a good scientist has the
heart of an artist and a good artist has
the heart of the scientists and the
Continuum's and the similarities are far
greater than the differences and when I
realize how few of you I have ever met
in my life and how guys like you and
guys like us and dies I mean in the
generic term both sexes on we really
need talk there was a time when this
would terrify you this was the way
information was transmitted days later
maybe a week later you would read that
it would strike fear in your heart now
is I mean people read it I think I won't
read it this is today breaking news you
can hear Wolf Blitzer breaking news we
just uncovered another chilling video
and it won't show it to you but it's
very titillating it's some perverted
almost kind of porn the way they want
you with they tell you what's in it they
kind of alluded as to how you can find
it but they won't show it oh they're
above that they have taste they blast we
are legitimate news agency we are listen
so it said I decided to see because i
knew i was going to look at
but first I wanted to see what our
team's guys who run the video so and I
intentionally kept the leader up to show
this is a product by mu ad agency um
it's from native 2006 released 2007
they're strong and then there's already
strong it is not just the strength to
obey but the strength to command not
just strength in numbers the strength of
brothers not just the strength to lift
the strength to raise not just the
strength to give yourself over the
strength to get over yourself it's more
than physical strength it is emotional
strength there is nothing on this remote
stronger than the US Army because there
is nothing on this green art stronger in
the US Army soldier there's strong and
then there's army strong find out more
and go on the gondola /strong what irks
me the most about this is I agree with
every word they say but they didn't sell
me directors talk about two kinds of
truth there is actual treasure actual
truth is I am 62 years old I was born in
the Bronx I'm standing here right now
but then there's emotional truth
emotional truth is Ben Affleck born in
Boston of anglo-saxon parents pretending
he is a Hispanic member of the CIA
getting people out of Iran that's
emotional truth and I'm sorry our tax
dollars paid for this and I
no who in our beloved world okayed this
but they need to find different work or
no it's just or big or go on so the
problem I found initially with our side
of the fence is that we don't play
hardball I'm a softie i live in the art
world i do really ridiculous little
things that nobody cares about I really
appreciate the fact that I guys like you
to defend my right to do that so I am
really concerned that we all together
figure out ways to guarantee that i can
go off and do ridiculous things that
nobody cares about because that is
what's left of freedom and that is even
though the nonsensical pneus of the CIA
selling abstract expressionism and just
to fill a nothing because it's just your
great story so we all know the cliches
of Soviet paintings a couple of very
very fit people standing in front of a
track alright so but that was Sony an
art so what we said is no dudes of
course they didn't say it that way i'm
sure they said it with a Yale pedigree
Oh down to Soho the crappiest
neighborhood in Manhattan where these
guys are throwing painted canvases
that's freedom we allow that we not only
allow that we buy that and who oddly
enough were the first customers of that
stuff certainly not the progresses the
Rockefellers huh liberal Republicans
more than anybody first fueled
contemporary art in this country and
they did it as a weapon of the Cold War
so what's the other side by the way this
thing cost a lot of money you know it's
supposed to be overly put a camera in
the helicopter now now it's too steady
it's a crane shot and they put a gobo
look like the side of a fake helicopter
window and they just brought it down six
feet it is so staged it is so calculated
it is so choreographed it has no
emotional truth the next thing I
calculate costs pretty much nothing to
make and that will be the next next next
video this is the other side coming soon
coming soon those two words that the
film industry's been using for almost a
century to entice you to come back next
week i buy another bucket of popcorn
it's more fear of water and some hot
dogs we know who the heck knows what
they're made of coming soon yeah they
had to rip us off well it's called
appropriation they couldn't come at us
with anything they're wrong oh that's
okay you couldn't be more right when I
said before what this is is a hybrid of
reality TV documentary music video
advertising most documentaries today are
largely using footage not of their
origin it's a completely accepted race
if you're doing a movie about World War
two unless you shot the stuff yourself
you're using somebody elses footage it
is completely that any term is
appropriate that's the politically
correct term for just taking other
people's stuff and it's and in in
another ridiculously overused word
post-modernism um this is the
personification of a postmodernist piece
when I said he cost just about nothing
what I calculated is any one of a number
of very very simple editing programs not
a terribly powerful laptop on some sort
of either they generated the flame
particle itself but more likely yeah
they just stole a premade clip of some
DJ software as a transition but what
they did you where I would say they did
have a voice that scares me they're sad
was so much more theatrical than the US
Army not only did the US Army have
ridiculously stage shots all of which
were clearly fake even though i don't
doubt they're real soldiers they are
real soldiers sir okay look at the
camera look nice okay everybody want you
to cut turn do you don't listen this is
all real and to me I understand many
people and I accept it is true that the
human mind has a very real difficulty
differentiating between seeing a
fictional movie and seeing a documentary
I think that the real thing resonates at
an ever so slight leakage now why do I
think that worked because it used it
used truly the vernacular the visual
vocabulary of the people intended to see
it even though it used all the same
techniques the army one had to me an
over use of something called color
grading that's sort of yeah I was just
thinking about the movie Top Gun yeah
that increased the recruitment for the
u.s. naval aviation and US Air Force
absolutely but from an outside
perspective that's kind of it's too much
right well what I never get in my mind
but I behind yeah it's very different
and also tight back to what you
mentioned when we evaluate the quality
of these things we always have to have
the potential target audience in mind is
it a disenfranchised young suburban mail
or an Arab background or is it an
American Hispanic 18 year old that feels
going the army can give you a shot at
college that's a pretty boy I believe
that's the case but what I'm saying is
that if I were in this time seeing if I
were contemplating being in what was I
guess then still al Qaeda in Iraq and I
said okay who we up against you we're up
against that I joked with you this looks
like
it's an invitation to a cam yeah that's
a tough care if you gotta climb up stuff
you get to fly in a helicopter you get
to jump out of a helicopter doesn't say
anything about you get to the lobby by
the is the ISIS video is all about
fighting no it's not it's about killing
thank you thank you that's a distinction
I would have never said I know we said
that but that was me thank you sir a
distinction I need to recognize yes and
very very interesting i just want oh
i'll do a short quote again from the
wonders of them yeah no dessert
challenge anyone in a volunteer concept
a lot of these young people they want to
recruit are probably me or want their
parental permission so showing real
killing going on and US army recruiting
he'll agree I'm saying this is a tough
one if overcome I completely agree that
this is what they were paid to do and
the audience was not people overseas but
I'm always been the baggage people
overseas that see that and say that's
them I will also say you need to compare
not the toothless big Pentagon big money
recruiting stuff from the domestic
audience need to actually compare the
products were being put out to the right
and populous at that time circuits he
doesn't work it up crafty devil sakes
there was some strong that's just
there's something Heartland wheat ones
I'm sure you would I would love to see
reviews on them well my little
understand you thank you very very true
my little understanding is that they
were actually difficult to access that
that if I were someone if I were over
there I would have to be within certain
communities to actually have access to
that material where is today thanks to
the neural of the internet um that's the
longer the case again just like with the
top analogy we have to assess this with
the playing field of today because 2004
was a very different world and whenever
the heck taco was made 20th century
lucia's baby please Wow so what other
things that stood up your video that you
should was the actual street footage of
the White House yeah it was actually
trying to strike at the White House
little that's right in there that person
that was a good piece of symbology
because right now organization yes yeah
I mean again it's like i'll say this
later when we get to play a game called
fuck the photo shot but um i haven't
joined the college in a long assignment
but if i were going to assess those two
pieces one would been a very higher
grade than the other because it one of
them really uses even in its quick just
because you own mine recognizes images
very fast um it says that whole thing it
says you want to use your correction you
want to kill oh yeah you want to kill
your neighbors but don't you all want
some annika that guy it's its energy its
progression ille it leads to that end
the way that video with when its hand by
it looked like it was a cell phone video
you know talking by so it shows that we
can strike at you and it from the
shadows it's my belief that the higher
the production value with these things
the worst the impact the more they look
like things they could have done the
more is yet another kind of embracement
now artists are always dealing with well
gee what what production level do we
need to make this piece in because we
don't want it to be alienating now a lot
of people love Disney but I'm sorry most
people can't make a Disney film we're
really not huh think it a success of the
Blair Witch Project absolutely
absolutely but let me point out a
problem that I'm sorry it originated in
Hollywood uh the board of what we are in
this example I'm not absolutely devil
incarnate you can't handle the truth is
what you know we have been told since
the 1950s since beaver and all the the
absolutes acronyms
we kind of shows that aren't allowed to
show the belly buttons aren't allowed to
show any sex uh we're not allowed to see
violence all these things that that that
that the video from al Jazeera actually
showed that we are not allowed to see
because we can handle it I agree with it
now I mean I'm going to hold a reaction
to that for a little slide a little bit
later which is also a slide that's going
to reference a question Spencer gave to
me but but I i am not going to avoid
what you're busy i am going to please
respond to a ting and perhaps a very
surprising i'm certainly done you may
address this but what do you see
something package like that yeah how
international is the audience is it work
just here for you change you know
English took Darcy well changes yeah um
my guess is ninety percent of it is very
international again the first one have
the narration I'm guessing I I think
country music's great but I'm no expert
in my guess is the narrator is a
recognizable native country history
that's a guess and I said I'm running on
but it has narration that immediately
cuts off the vast majority apart yeah
most people speak broken English but um
when you take away the language and
start using visual language you've got a
much bigger audience the reason action
films are so so successful
internationally now than they were 30
years ago it's a lot less talking in
there's a lot less dialogue it's like
hey watch out but there's not a lot of
you know it's not like avatar movie
where people are sitting there for 10
minutes having a discussion about us you
know as essentialism um and that's my
design honest I'm like somebody made a a
crack at Michael Bay and I'm certainly
no fan of his as an artist but he is no
fool he knows exactly what he is doing
and there is there's some critique among
the sinister those pretentious Fox like
me who think they understand film
culture um that they talk about the
return to the silent film they would
call transformers aside
film because it is largely action-driven
rather than dialogic and you could take
away the words and pretty much still
good and that is specifically to build
what they have successfully done a
situation where we now sell more tickets
overseas that we saw and that was a
design that happened quite a long time
ago again learning from visual art
saying well what is it about bathing
local story right then I'm going to move
on a little because there are a couple
things I want to get you to deal with
what you guys had so this is again CNN
from last week like a new rock band
storming the music charts Isis benefited
from a music video environment that
amplifies its propaganda the group
quickly reached early recruits through
videos that showcase the fear its
adherents instilled in non-believers
this is like a music review band they're
talking about let's talk about it was
like human being gunfire yes yes that's
why i said before let's not mince words
these are snuff films for decades upon
decades upon decades there has in an
industry that the Mafia has benefited
vary greatly from where you could spend
money to watch an actual human being get
killed then in the probably 80s maybe
was the 90s a.m. they were really
successful commercially Main Street
projects on VA just what were they call
faces of death face yeah yeah where you
could buy a VHS tape where you could see
a Saudi beheading where you could see
some terrible car accident with an ibex
with and a half there has always been
the snuff but the snuffle to my
knowledge was not used as high concept
and as a weapon of war fare until Daniel
but but that's what these are these are
videos that for various reasons
people decide to watch so that they can
see other human beings killed in gas
regrets that's what they are they just
happen to not only terrify us but they
happen to turn on some of the people and
I was in the country of gutter and then
Afghanistan when Pearl was guilt and
there was a violent reaction to it that
was not what they wanted to see that's
why the film's basically stopped because
they've realized said and they alienated
the target audience very very badly and
uh there was a website called I'm sorry
it worked well in Chechnya when these
things started well chicken Russians are
different okay but oh gosh calm was it
was a website that showed all this stuff
okay and then they got bought out by
life leak and all of a sudden um overs
went away and bought out by bought by
lively and for a little while they ran
all the really bad snuff films and then
that went away because there was such a
violent reaction to it so the America as
a whole is not eat Wow I mean I look for
it because I mrs. ache um but hello
America is insulated from violence from
sex from nudity from all the things that
the Russian world you know just as
Dickens and again we'll talk about why
someone other than Disney should be
dealing with this stuff um the hackers
among you would be interested to know
that among the many a book I've got ten
minutes so I'm going to spill all the
slideshow guys um the basic toolkit it's
nothing have you got it sitting right
here pretty much any kind of laptop with
any kind of power old decent any decent
video camera anyone of a shopping was
adobe premiere Final Cut Pro um i would
recommend a couple of graphics programs
the color timing that i see there's
something on this actually go with magic
bullet of da Vinci but after effects is
a good one to like give you a lot of
graphics potential a total shopping list
if you bought it retail auto 10 grand
baby
only a lot less if you shopped around
they're going to torrent the damn saw oh
absolutely I said if you bought it if
you bought it the fact is saying this is
high production value is nonsense your
kids have equipment at least as good
this EV I call this stuff this is folk
art this is not the Avengers this is not
inception this but what it is is it's
very knowledgeable about the use of
cinema arm they also hack video games so
there is an Isis version of Grand Theft
Auto where you get to blow up on people
that you don't like and you get to how
they did it I don't know I'm not a
hacker but there are video games that
are reappropriation so I'm going to
breathe yeah but they don't heckum the
game companies put out different ways of
modding the games themselves to know
because that's what it's like we saw in
life you can make your own kind the
shelf life of the game belonged okay so
that's you know and again girl can do
that without a problem and it's
happening one of the things that I saw
that for time I decided not to throw in
with it was a video that starts by char
some of that stuff and then it says and
it's anthony english um why sit at home
and watch video games when you can be
doing it for real in our battlefield
drunk ill with us say they had a video
game actually back during Iraq in
Afghanistan where they were teaching
people how to put roadside bombs it and
they were showing how to put roadside
bombs and would have planted it was a
video game and you could play the game
and it also showed how to do ambushes
this is the real world this is the world
you're charged with Dale a tu solitary
to the sanctity of us are make fun don't
you notice re-certification madness this
is actually becoming a big problem for
American companies as well video game
manufacturers because the amount a brand
image to you have companies that put out
things like Grand Theft Auto when
there's grand theft auto Isis that come
out is just absolutely ridiculous to the
content
letters are nicely trying to take back
the ownership of the content at idle
period and let the cats out of well I
mean someone mentioned the picture's
worth a thousand words I have been told
all my life I was coined by Confucius an
act that was myth-making that didn't
seem like the the actual author didn't
seem big enough to really give it
credibility has actually done by a
journalist in the early 1900s and then
it was later attributed to Confucius
where it's still taught in colleges
around the world today um and that's
going to get to a point we're going to
have in a minute the notion of what you
saw is real and I absolutely positively
believe that the heading videos are real
but there are guys out there for
whatever reason that are putting off
these bogus on proofs that they're not
and i am going to if we have time for
the clock from its um have you guys arm
deconstruct an image and show how it's
fake but we may or may not get to that
actually again i'll scan through these
kids what kind of like on there have
always been depictions of power it's one
of the many many tactics that the
military has done is whatever technology
was available whether it was a stone
carving whether it was an oil painting
whether it's photography whether it's
color photography and then you get to
this kind of stuff art has always been a
weapon of war l word spears the fura is
a very very tiny part of this image what
is terrifying about this image this
gigantic work of art now it's not art
for nice people but it is a work of art
always among the toolkit has been
symbology iconography sound or to throw
it all together theatre because it
represents an idea rocks is bigger than
the individuals behind and and and
unstoppable it's just scale Andy Warhol
said aren't is sold by behind and yes
the bigger your artwork yeah the raw
materials costs
but it's not substantially different but
it's quantitatively more valuable the
bigger scale matters scale really
matters in art and in politics so in the
past it was stone lithography a lost art
for the most part but the military has
always been trying and I just
arbitrarily picked our adversaries guys
you know they've always been trying to
Schiphol this case they were fighting
Nazis too but on this image which I i
I'm sorry is a bit racist which is one
of ours are to take my that the Japanese
are going to come and who knows what
they're going to do with the young girls
um that's old technology and just like
Top Gun and just like the cost when they
were learned a lot of people who really
could access this stuff this has lost
its mojo compared to a simple relatively
low resolution but obviously real event
when you switch from painting to
photography the mind reaction is off the
charts um these are the things we're
fighting this is costs nothing to make
is that because the mind projects itself
in that picture I believe the closer we
get you something that is resembling a
virtual reality holographic thing the
more the mind is is published there's a
term the more Hollywood guys like among
you would know to uncanny valley so if
something kind of looks real but it
isn't really really real you kind of
like yeah that's crap there were a
number of CG movies of about a decade
ago I ma ma block I forget all forget
all the film star phenom these images to
me now most of these were taken by
western photographers a lot of the
freelancers looking for their full
surprise these guys are not male models
but somebody sure taught them hot pose
one of the things that's going down is
they believe they're not those guys in
the US Army so what do we have to do we
gotta go on we're making a commercial
well I don't want to make a come-on
right ok it's month these guys believe
they believe they are going to take over
the world and they know how to play with
our vocabularies this is the beginning
of the video where the Christians were
lined out onto the beach and beheaded at
the other 30 40 it's like again reality
television and documentary it's so
Americanized and again not I production
value you were going to critique the
topography spin and would make sure you
inform sense of graphic design who cares
they're using the water they're using
the water that Christ walked off across
the water that's what they're using this
involves you I'm scary now look at this
image film school 1010 this is a turbo
composition too much negative space
baloney it's terrifying it's they're
coming here and they're gonna congregate
and you all know what's going to happen
these guys have been informed by the
best thinkers in the visual arts how
that happened I don't know but I see it
and of course someone mentioned gotta
have the kids just gotta have those kids
Hitler did it with it with his pictures
of little little kids and Nazi uniforms
well you gotta it's the bus with one of
your continual French is how in the
world these guys here you just said it
again static cut them isn't that kind of
a fact of having been propagated as
their selves to believe that they're
ignorant savages and the batch works
because why should why shouldn't they be
as smart as we are just like you yeah
why shouldn't they be human being what
should be right with the same brains you
got ya
I by that I by that evil is smart I've
been up I'm going to wrap when don't
worry so we know they're destroying the
past we know a lot of priceless art is
gone we also know they sold a lot of it
to the grey market they're also doing
modern stuff you got to burn the musical
history is music it's like that sounds I
savings like that anymore there's yeah
yeah oh no this is one of their promo
pictures as opposed to the ones from the
feds unaffected by our guys
foreshortened low angle right out of
Hitler's playbook forced perspective
done with a cheap camera taking imagery
like this from the old days of stone
lithography and amping it up with images
like this now there are too many
Freudians left but I got the freudian
just allowed a statement of male potency
I won't have time to do the contest but
I'll just kind of go through it would we
got two minutes there is also a don't
understand backwards all right um don't
get someone mentioned before that
there's a lot of fakery out there so
there's two kinds of fakery some saying
they did do things that they may or may
not have others saying that they didn't
do things that they clearly did I'll
follow the things they clearly did we
know this is real we know this happened
there is no question and the insult to
this gentleman to say this didn't happen
disgusts me so there's some more on out
there who made this image so welcome to
bad photoshop and the fact that anybody
buys this image i'll go quickly i was
going to have you guys do it as a
contest the resolution of this image
Farley is greater than the resolution of
vonage it's not depth of field that was
done with a still camera that was done
with a video
that was also done with a still camera
except it seems to be levitating if you
notice about anything any marks on the
ground it's somehow they not only have
cameras but they have cameras that float
and the blending and feathering of this
when I was teaching if a freshman
digital art student handed that in I
give them Abby but if a junior handed it
in I've give them a c-minus this is
laughable and there are people that see
this as proof positive that you guys are
faking the Mannings it's us doing this
where's isn't really happening why this
is happening I haven't a clue but this
is it it's insane I'll get intervention
this did happen this did not someone
mentioned symptom ro the simulation of
something this is reported to be and
this is being spread all over American
I'm going to say a bad thing Christian
communication places as being proof
evidence of the rape and crucifixion of
a number of young Christian girls which
has happened just this isn't it now
again if I were going to play do that I
would point out and I'm rapping with
this um there's a grain structure on
this this isn't a digital camera this
was filmed not only is it filmed but its
its high great film probably try x 400 a
SI that it's outside during the day
which meant it had to have been done
with a lens that wasn't very fast this
was done a long time ago yeah was and in
fact it was done in a movie called the
auction of souls which was about it was
a fictionalized story of the armenian
genocide and it was done in 1919 and
this image is being circulated virally
as an actual image done last year and
without critical thinking and without
just a
itís knowledge of what an image actually
looks like you will believe also boy
they really took a time to do pretty
nice carpentry on the group kind of like
you see crucifixes in church except and
here's one of the bad ones except that's
what a real one looks like they'll take
a lot of time with the crosses now to
answer your question and Spencers
question this is and you can accept it
or reject it but this is considered by
PhDs in the art history department of
Yale as one of the most important art
pieces of the late 20th century it's
transfixed good trends fixed on the
bridge birds had himself literally
crucified to the roof of his car it was
a year after chris burden literally had
himself shot in the arm with a 22 so to
go to where I think we need to go we
need to D Disney Phi this story and we
need to talk to performance artists we
need to talk to people who say if I am
going to do something I am NOT going to
act it oh it's been shot oh it's been
shot putting a bud oh you know let's get
the understanding to fall back no when a
performance artist gets shot they get
shot and if we want to talk to people
who are gritty and fearless crazy maybe
I don't believe we are going to find it
in the magic kingdom but as you believe
we will find it in the world
contemporary art where this man is one
of the most successful living artists in
the world a world most people don't
think of and you can read the art speak
of how you know this type of painted
vulnerability it shows the familiar
about demystifies hora blah blah blah
blah but they thought a point these guys
can go where you need them to go
and if we were going to make imagery
that combats the honest emotional
feeling of that guy who truly believes
he is going to win I don't know if he
truly believes that Allah is his you
know he believes Islam I can't say it
but he believes he's going to win now
the fact is your guys know more about
the military on there she's probably
dead now but um he believed he didn't
believe he's gonna win he's also dead
now the theatricality their use they
don't just make Hollywood blockbusters
where people get blown up and people get
on fire that's why I said you need
performance art because when a row of
toyota pickup trucks not a Bradley among
them Toyota fucking pickup truck become
the conquering regions and we need to
rethink this argument thank you very
much