if you haven't hit the board now's a
great time to start drinking
Hartman called by spear he brought up
or sort of work yeah devices naked
alright thanks when okay so really is
looking at we've got all these sort of
devices out there and there's going to
be forensics what's gonna be happening
for this analysis what's going to what
our people would be looking at to
determine what you are actually doing
how are we determining patterns of what
give you a little background information
army officer I've been on active duty
the reserves I'm personally was a joint
unit being ready to switch all the way
back to the army full-time take command
of Battalion later in the year I'm the
senior cyber architect for l-3
communications so told billion-dollar
company also research fellow with them
and I'm board president for regional
theater because that completely fits
with all the technology stuff but if you
want to see some awesome social
engineers that's some great folks are I
do have to put the disclaimer out there
I'm not a spokesperson for any
organization or entity not for the
government or l3 or anyone else any tool
or any you know mechanism that you might
use in any form of offensive capability
is of course purely theoretical in the
words of some of my Scion brethren I
would never be Kok doing such a thing
but also my employer said the hey if he
actually gave out something offensive
other than just content that you might
be violating I card and I don't want to
go to jail or lose my clearance alright
so this is what Rudy go through some of
you I know we got a few law enforcement
type people in here yeah okay and we got
law enforcement a lawyer next to each
other
awesome I'm going out that door yep
so I was looking for what's a good
definition of everything that was really
nice light reading like Robert back
there with the beer just go ahead yeah
I'm not going to read that but the
important things and this is a
definition from 2003 about digital
forensics
okay so we got preservation collection
validation analysis interpretation
documentation and presentation of
digital evidence all right well you know
it's a wordy definition but the neat
thing is as I start looking later for
how can i interfere with the forensics
process because it is a process those
are different areas I may be able to
attack or interfere with and if any of
those don't work or they don't work well
for people that are doing the forensics
then it's likely not going to make it
all the way through trial okay so really
when we're looking at evidence there's
going to be two types of evidence that
are out there's gonna be direct evidence
you know what I can find you know I've
actually got the logs I've got dad I've
got pictures of the person stealing the
roll of toilet paper or I've got new
actual files other times I'm looking in
there's inferred evidence I know that
something happened on this system
because when the police came and they
took all of my electronics they can tell
that I'd reset all my devices or I'd ran
something to wipe the different the data
on different devices so you know
definitely have been tampered with
some of you know got government
backgrounds familiar with the term zero
was okay in case anybody's not
essentially that's where doing the over
rights overriding the data and the
different structures made different
standards sometimes five passes seven
passes however many even one times is
all zeros or it's all ones or it's
random combinations some forensic tools
the way they they will look at things
are looking at a sequence of events so
if I can align all of the dates of all
of the files on the system note they're
no longer able to look at that for
sequence events now they have to go
through and they have to look at things
individually and figure out what's in
there and really what I'm doing is I'm
taking up their time or the resources
either on computing power or the amount
of time it's going to take their
analysts to go through and try and find
stack
same thing if you try to do something
with file sizes aligning or altering
those whenever you hear somebody that
they're arrested and they had pictures
of kiddie porn on their computers a lot
of the forensic school tools what
they'll do is they'll go through and
they'll actually be looking at the hash
values and the file size of all the
different images on the computer
comparing that to a known list of evil
things and then they'll do some spot
checking among that list but the
investigator doesn't have to go look at
a thousand pictures they're on their own
which good for them also there's the
encrypted communications question if
frequently you cured from different
government organizations saying oh well
if you're not doing anything wrong why
do you need to encrypt stuff because so
there so there's but and it's actually a
big but I did find a but and I really
regret that I forgot to use an incognito
window when I was doing searches so uh
autocomplete in Chrome is just gonna be
sad for a little while there's a
question of legal or legal so when I'm
centering how am I going to be stopping
or dealing with forensics things out
there it's always easier to kill people
it is to talk especially if you're in
Yemen but the threshold if I'm going to
be doing position or taking somebody in
or dealing with them in court house
there's going to be testimony there's
gonna be witnesses there's gonna be
counter witnesses so that's those
thresholds of what did you go through
and how it's all that evidence there
well that's it's a lot harder hurdle to
clear than it is just to okay I'm
establish you've had enough like if they
did it and G mark is gonna be over there
and the drone will come in through the
window
and we'll have some Russian mobster guy
combined with the Crocodile Hunter
speechwriter talking about how he's
going to take few art out so
just because I wouldn't help you on your
breathing absolutely absolutely
so the Internet of Things everybody's
heard the term what is the Internet of
Things well basically everything gets an
IP address traditional stuff computers
laptops tablets personal things your
smartphone your watch wrist mount GPS or
formal GPS you got in the car things at
your house the nest how many people have
a nest yeah alright see if your hands
they're awesome
TVs refrigerators other items nest is a
Arduino power thermostat so it does all
sorts of neat learning stuff Google
acquired the companies so that gets
pulled in with all these other great
information like HIPAA but searches that
you've done and that that all gets
compiled to help compose this picture of
what somebody is and in what they're
doing
where you are in your house at what time
did you if RadioShack was still as of
about two thirty and it's something I
had when I was looking at some of this
earlier it's like oh okay well so let's
say I've got some nest devices or I got
some other things and what I would do is
I'm just going to create a different
username with Google and for those
Google services I'll run it off a
different wireless access point and all
those devices will communicate through
that I'll run it through tor and then
it'll exit it'll talk back to the Google
cloud and they won't have to associate
any of those devices with trouts
but the big bright again I think that
most of those devices are highly likely
that they're also registering which
other wireless devices or wireless
routers are within range and because
they can see the other wireless device
or routers vices in my house and
the Google vehicle has made a couple
trips through the neighborhood it's been
able to say with a very high probability
yeah you know what I think this router
is in the same house or within 50 yards
so this other person probably is Travis
yeah this little tool called I measure
which would go ahead and do that and
it's just running Java and it could beat
you to figure it out even through torque
and geolocation using that about 50 to
70 meters John strand over Black Hills
very fun to watch excellent
and that's close enough to get the
predator to come okay so please 9-1-1
systems what they're using for their
dispatch smart guns we're starting to
see things getting closer with that body
cams dash cams what I've seen some body
cams are fair amount of them they're all
getting the data files dumped back to a
central location cloud storage and
multiple police departments it's all
stored in this one guy repository
replicated wherever else yeah that's
pretty interesting and I haven't seen
any court challenges on it yet but if
somebody is able to tamper with one
police department anywhere and what
happens where their data store from the
body cam hey they replaced six frames of
footage in this one video from podunk
Kentucky please tell me there's no put
on Kentucky but but you know if somebody
can show that system with tampered with
from you know some part of the thing
then it brings into question everything
else from all those other body cameras
in Los Angeles or New York or wherever
else and well they detect if they detect
that it was tampered with that's a
totally that's a public that's perfectly
fine because you know that you feel that
evidence out if the detection would
and the integrity if the rest of the
information goes into question at that
point it's it's all thing that'll throw
it out like that yeah but the thing the
thing is you don't have to dictate it if
you get a steal a couple of those files
and post them online they cause any
question their whole security program
and everything else and then and it and
it causes major problems and as long as
we're not in Yemen and we're dealing
with the legal threshold that's a great
day so I mean anyway can I spot -
cameras and can I stop body cameras
probably not I could probably be doing
some broad area jamming if they're
sending it back that way
but if I can cause the legal validity to
be questioned just by going in through
somewhere in Kentucky that's an awesome
awesome thing cars anybody to have an
idea how many computers are in a modern
car Wow you know last year there were
people talking to their 70 plus so 60 70
80 that's a lot of different computers
and there's it's really kind of
disturbing they've got both the can
buses running the different systems on
the car some people may have heard about
the Toyota's that didn't respond to the
brakes a couple years ago and lost meter
to recall around that be they think is
charities okay I haven't heard anything
particular about the Jeeps I even know
some vehicles that people have been able
to get in and tamper with them through
like Bluetooth the wheel sensors tire
pressure sensors well and what's
interesting is if you look at some of
the previous years at Def Con somebody
was using a dash cluster from a mini to
try and display the time there's a lot
of research that keeps happening and
it's all this primary research of what
does the data
forms look like on the the data bus for
Alexis or for many or for BMW and
researcher a does it and they figured
out and then they'll know maybe sure you
know with a couple of their colleagues
or a couple of people the same
University but there's not like a common
database or common repository where
people are able to go to and say you
know what i'm i'm working with a
chevrolet corvette and i want to be able
to go in and see what data boxes and
what data files and actually figure out
what's there and what's been tampered
with things and since there's not
published information on what those data
structures look like what they actually
mean what the different header is going
across the bus it makes it very hard for
people to go out and actually do
repeatable things with the forensics
what is kind of nice about that though
is if you are an attacker you have done
all that primary research you can go in
you can tamper with the system and it's
very unlikely that somebody else is
going to come along later and figure out
what you did
industrial control systems
I've heard that Iran had a little bit of
a research project with that yeah Purdue
and then of course
octopuses penguins people warthogs yaks
Newt small versus wildebeest
does anybody know where that line comes
from yes octopuses penguins rats bats
cats and especially rabbits
Tasmanian Devil Bugs Bunny everything
gets an IP address okay all right even
the puppies absolutely most devices
medical technology Travis how you gonna
keep your vet single debut my search
history stood messed up you know after a
while
how'd you know that's not a channel
distributed it has no like the rank yeah
but yeah well I guess one other way you
can deal with the forensics is I'm gonna
have so much stuff that the examiners
really just don't want to look at
anymore they know at your house the
Secret Service FBI they're actually
looking for the internet of things to
try to pick them up and take the which
up for investigations and he says
University because a lot of warrants are
go to this house and steal all their
computing devices
I mean seize all their computing devices
and Alan well okay if a refrigerator and
my washing machines the hot water heater
and whatever else all have IP address
you know I hopefully I've got a tent or
there's an REI nearby because the house
is gone and actually I heavy I have seen
the light bulbs themselves not the
fixture but light bulbs
you
a compact desktop exp yeah kind of had
that long ago where medical device was
actually compromised with use order
payloads awesome well there was the
there was the pacemaker that was running
there was a radiation in any advice or
any technology and whenever you hear
somebody say well who would ever attack
that you you automatically know you know
great that's awesome
Samsung a few months ago they they kind
of got busted their TVs they were doing
voice recognition but it wasn't like you
say Oh
Samsung find the sci-fi channel or CNN
whatever else so everything you said we
can range in the television was being
sent to their servers for analysis
because I'm sure all the options when
they're disabled it's a if you live in
Maryland and you have a samsung TV and
it was spying on you please sponsor next
year's of
so you were watching this one channel
for five minutes and then you left to go
take a nap we may have some pattern of
life things that this side and if you
take a look at the slide Flair you can
see more in depth but this is just an
example of some of the settings from one
control system for one computer or one
car this is actually like 4 mm you know
you mid-2000 something BMW and this is
one of like ten screens be able to go in
and change different settings so what
are we gonna do alright so we could
avoid everything like the original
hipster gonna live in a cabin in the
woods typewriter
send notes to universities and Airlines
Longwood gift packages drink PBR I did
buy the practical pyromaniac last year
the Amazon recommendations after that
were amazing so I just have it
ultimately we're gonna have to accept
some little level of risk and these
slides are just talking through ways
that were could actually there were
presentations at Def Con and blackhat I
would say 16 years ago it may have been
back when black hat or deaf comments at
the alexis park even but they went
through all the equations and how many
exit nodes you need to be able to
monitor to have whichever level of
assurance of water was going multiple II
that means if you're is worrying about
what's going on the traffic yeah
somebody's not figure out everything's a
target last year we saw
different devices we're being used for
Bitcoin line and/or the house okay some
DVRs we're getting popped but they had
such little processing power it wasn't
really turning anything out useful but
with Bitcoin you're actually having a
race it's whoever is going to get
through one chunk of calculations at a
time if I'm not doing something where
I'm actually having a race I just need X
number of processing cycles well then
that EVR starts to become interesting
too okay so some of the things that we
want to do is we want to make sure we're
trying to avoid stupid human tricks
because users will actually do you know
anything we wanted
we know we're trying to avoid something
or deal with anything of electronics we
make the assumption there's gonna be no
major changes in number theory or
mathematics no major changes in
processing power unless I'm able to
scale okay what doesn't actually I don't
say trigger guard magnetic ring but the
pony's ear protection eye protection I
would trust that pony we something a
little bit what's going on with the
currency to be used some of the concerns
I think from a user started out of
privacy avoidance of identification you
know I just want to be able to go search
for hippo but without it having being
immune or maybe I wanted to avoid the
embarrassment of I searched for hippo
but anyway maybe I won't even that
tamper truth devices that I've actually
went out and I try to erase things
because yes but you know if you know the
right be forgotten or they come to my
house and they take a bunch of things I
don't even remember what I was
experimenting with was that old server
from a few years ago I'm can I get a
shell on this server using this tool or
something but under the right
prosecuting attorney they might say oh
well he's got these evil things here he
was trying to do stuff and he was trying
to go in through the powerline
networking and get into the
neighborhoods because they're all
running ZigBee and there there wasn't
another transformer between his house
and the neighbors so he plugged into the
network and he could see the neighbor's
house I don't say I don't know what
stuff is on there but some prosecutors
make the case all the stuff was being
erased hope he's clearly trying to hide
something or we've seen it search
history wishy tried something so
attackers attackers be concerned with
system we have to privacy for a second
in some time in the last couple three
years I've heard allegations of certain
research that is the smart meters odd
stuff it's connected and all those
idiotic that there was some research
done that allege that by monitoring the
power lines I could tell the difference
between a vibrator a refrigerator and a
microwave and using that as a privacy
invasion is the where what do you know
on that space of privacy
sorry not everybody can hear the comment
probably a good thing yes
had considerations for tempest and
vibrators and I did a correlation
between my patterns and they active see
spikes in my day where I moved around
the pattern that was using wash or
whatever else from my power
that's a privacy concern has not been
really blessed enough like six years ago
it was a privacy issue so soon
so two quick questions just to kind of
piggyback on this online who's your
primary power low is actually a little
bitty small power W dark fill on it okay
and second what's their interval and
problem with the UCAV I believe it did
the study the UCSD study though they
they were hanging interval data that was
so small that you could literally detect
from micro second transaction are
members of it without either Hollander
Germany's my recollection okay but the
thing is most of the buildings have much
over in are both because frankly well
they actually like Duke Energy built a
large data center larger providers
biltman data center just sold them all
this data centering stuff to house all
this data from the smart meters that
they don't know what they're going to do
and pray yeah
your hair like that I so a couple
takeaways about it if the power company
is monitoring or if you're using ZigBee
devices other things you're trying to
see maybe DLC what's happening with your
neighbors if there's when large electric
motors are turned on
there's the inrush current and so you
can tell apply those spikes so if I had
three houses on one side of the
transformer I could I could probably get
in a pretty good feel when somebody's
large device air conditioner or
something kicked on if I had the more
fine-tuned we're doing the data sampling
and then thanks the question how is it
doing that data sampling and sending it
back upstream and it's probably going
back through the power lines and can my
neighbors now monitor it because it's
one thing it's that that is going back
there and due to the really narrow
sampling rates the power company doesn't
care and they're already going to save
once every 60 seconds or once every five
minutes but if I'm using my washing
machine in the microwave at the same
time I don't want my neighbor to know or
arguments it doesn't matter that they
can detect our hydroponic growing lab
yeah but let's see what they're going to
do an integer this is where you don't
understand all the steps of smart meters
where it's going is eventually going to
have haunts home area networks that are
all these intercept these devices on
your network and if power comes you'll
be able to my mother already has it
she's in her 80s and she they can
control her hot water heater and other
things her house they paid they they're
giving her a reduced rate to do that and
that's where this is blowing these
meters will be controlling everything
else in your house and be able to send
signals good but you'll have to you know
say I'll allow you to turn my a/c off
when there's a path when there's a power
spike or something so so you heard it
your earth 20 years from now here's how
things are going through at least 20
years that I be this is this
this one here prediction in 20 years
you'll indicate a device to your meter
okay will be charged you you buy the
device you'll have a flat rate or each
device that you're purchasing they plug
again that's and that'll be ultimately
the interval the unstable so imagine
you're not being charged by a volume of
consumption any more if you're being
charged for this thing that has an
energy efficiency rate can we charge you
based on the energy every known all the
time every that yeah the other thing
that I can see I can I will go to the if
I were telling putting a miles on that
leading lady announced that your will
God says 20 years now that's way before
I look like that you know why that are
in solar panel I wanna see you around to
collect them in power and I don't care
about selling it back one must Sheldon
we go so what are the terms awesome on
the 20-year predictions I think what
would be more sir right now you go to a
lot of places that you have an electric
car or however you can plug in and you
know it's a draw that terrible pun but
it's a draw some companies have 401 to
show that we're a green company so we've
got five charging stations for employees
never mind there's 800 they give it to
this building but we have five charging
stations aren't we an awesome green
company has put in the marketing
marketing literature well yeah and it's
essentially free when you show up to
plug in your car I wouldn't be
surprising turn down your device
registration if you register with
whichever power company and where do you
go
in it a station or parking lot or a
shopping center there are you doing that
we can plug in a power company they
charge here where we are so awesome so
I'm talking about tamper-evident I want
to try and change things on the
different devices that I have some of
the concerns I need to be able to do if
I want to lead that if I really truly
want to delete data and I just smash it
with a hammer I need to have some pretty
in-depth knowledge what are the file
structures are data storage mechanisms
and storage replication how George you
know the locations and how its
replicates mostly probably a couple
months ago where multiple people in
Hollywood had their nude selfies that
were exposed and they're like well I
didn't realize that my phone was
automatically replicating my you know
iPhone photos where Android photos
because I deleted it on my phone but it
was back there on my cloud account which
may be why the Macs are still working is
there your apples trying to get through
that thing where you could run a script
in it and essentially brute force of
indication because it never lock people
out yeah so if you don't know where it's
stored or replicated outside of your
home or on that device that's going to
you can't clean up all the copies and
that will leave conflicting information
or somebody'll be able to find the true
information if they are going out doing
the forensics the data storage
mechanisms in particular I've seen in
iOS devices Android devices as they went
through different file structures the
what actually gets deleted or where
there's settings or pieces or fragments
of data that are stored sometimes it's
like okay well it actually he did a
secure wife of all my text messages but
there is a cache that had the preview of
all those text messages that were that
showed up on the lock screen and didn't
do the wipe on that so even though I did
ran the tool located the text messages
they didn't though there was a cache I
didn't know clear everything out and
somebody can actually go back through
and find that
I already talked about it overriding
data the interesting thing I was
thinking about was what if I you started
introducing conflicting data sources I
can't get rid of everything I can't
change everything but if there's stuff
that I can change and it brings in
enough enough of a question I wouldn't
do this in Yemen but I would do it in
the US because more threshold OB statute
but I've got two data sources and
according to the court they're of equal
validity there are equal levels of trust
and the tools and the techniques that
law enforcement is using to get those
they're equally well regarded but one
says any and one says B's well so there
and that's the big thing so if I can get
introduced enough of a question into the
system it doesn't get rid of thee what
the heck was in the guy searches 3 this
is a little bit freaky but it does say
you know what I can't get a conviction
in and so that's going to be you know
traffic ticket you only need 450 so it's
the level that you need in a criminal
matter versus you know Seville your
symbol and if I've got this person
that's examining the evidence from my
DVR my refrigerator and my television
and my thermostat and they they come up
with you know two things say I was home
two things that I wasn't home
and then I have I'm going to be able to
actually what I would be doing is I
would be challenging that first or my
lawyer will be challenged to that first
of all how come you couldn't make a
determination or what other data sources
are you sure you know how to use the
tools you're getting to different
results
what is your training what is are you
the smaller devices no I know cars the
GPS systems portable gps and there's
some of the other data logging that
that's in cars the acceleration I think
some of that's been in there but there's
it's still going let's formally take it
out of the court right yes this was some
that was brought up and another group
much like this not attribution of course
so won't divulge who it was but
basically said that lets that look at it
for an insurance penguin if your
refrigerator if your refrigerator keeps
track of what you have and you have two
gallons of ice cream in your
refrigerator and it knows that you're
eating this ice cream but it reports
that to your insurance company your
medical insurance company and they know
you're diabetic then you they may choose
not to pay or your treatment because
you're not doing the things that you're
supposed to do or life insurance or all
those types of things so it goes back
into the privacy piece that wind was
talking about in that conversation but
not having to pay insurance proof it's
going
so that's another issue that has to I
would I would say that there is already
the ability that information they could
do a subpoena pull some information from
Google be able to parse Google's data
logs that I've been a bit dealing with
some forensics company's going to
forensics conferences for ten plus years
and it's been really interesting to see
I first time you know the iPhone came
out ah it's got more stuff than this
feature phone it's got more than SMS
messages and then the companies came out
with more tools and they get more in
depth into data structures and they find
stuff like the previews where they
continue to evolve every year I think
it's just another wise that's gonna go
through that seems like yes so so you
know everybody's worried about
subpoenaing the yeah ever why are you
worried about it what people are trying
to do is to monetize the sale of that
data so you know talking about the ice
cream and the insurance right
of course if I'm the manufacturer that
refrigerator I'm looking for an
additional revenue stream so I'm going
to sell the the information that I've
agreed to have a like or did I try to
you by breaking the seal on the plastic
or on plug and plugging in the
refrigerator and agree to and you know
all of this now just Google has all that
information they're selling it for a
hundred bucks a record back to electric
company yes now so something I would
throw in with that um an earlier but I
have something I've got this
refrigerator and I say to him but I get
this refrigerator and this is me two
years in the future or three years ago
future I don't have it right now but
there's this refrigerator and whenever
certain things are depleted or get to a
certain level it automatically sends an
order into the grocery store or
whichever grocery delivery service and
that gets queued up and every Tuesday
and Thursday it gets lured
well I'm the only person my house that
happens to drink diet coke and this
refrigerator or Samsung model XYZ within
five minutes
of device or the particular thing being
removed can of soda if it's the last one
you will automatically send the order it
which we'll get at it thank you
great ok so 2 a.m. on Thursday night the
refrigerator that sends a message to the
grocery store
adding Diet Coke to the order well there
you know added to the other things where
I'm going with the drinks Diet Coke in
the house there somebody can start
Freddy to put it together saying you
know what we think Travis was home
because somebody took a diet coke out of
refrigerator at 2:00 a.m. and he's the
only one that drinks that so it was
probably him and we'll add that to those
other things as I'm trying to build a
preponderance of the other so one of the
issues though is we keep running into
the home run lender sales people remain
two mandates being put on utilities to
have that kind of granular information
for rate reduction permissions control
for all these other things where there's
no other way to drive those opens and I
don't necessary that it but the argument
being made by the utilities is unless
they collect that kind of granularity
they're not going to know usage patterns
to drive reductions now we can debate
that but it's the aren't you and so then
you comes out are there other things I
can do that help you know eliminate that
it was just Travis or was it somebody
else in the household or do I have to
have a roommate or and yes my concern is
you know the topic here is seemingly you
know legal or or dubious uses but you
know the reality is the actors if
there's ways for the good guys there's
ways for the bad guys and what concerns
me is when these things fall out of our
control as they often do right and they
get used in ways we never imagined they
would be used you know sorry to go there
but you know I'm here on the Holocaust
for census and the punch cards right
it's things get twisted that seemed
innocent in the future into something
else with that excited I'm within my ten
minutes I've already got the the warning
and say
from when I've got a few scenarios I'll
run through them real quick and then as
people are having beverages later happy
to have additional discussions how many
people grab a rental car or flew in have
a rental car this week okay okay how
many people plug in their phone and/or
taxi their phone with Bluetooth how many
people have any districts entirely well
you know what's interesting is whether
it's bluetooth or you plug it into the
car my time so pop up saying do you want
to sync your contacts do you want to
sync your calendar do you want to sync
all this information some cars will
actually pull the information from the
phone without ask so that's a little bit
spooky yeah does that okay you can hit
explain to us be cables that don't have
the data and water is connected so
you're just getting power which is
always a good thing to have
but anyway so let's say I came to info
work on somebody else came in with me we
hopped in the car and okay they're
traveling all day I need to charge my
phone and plug it oh hell no no sync we
come to the conference we go through a
bunch of things we see some embarrassing
hippo and pony pictures there's some
beverages and discussions that go into
the wee hours and we go back to the
hotel
the next morning get in the car plug it
in again so I've got to plug into phone
last night for some reason I'm putting
something in the trunk and my buddy's
like why is the music not playing what
are this prompted on this phone slap
slap slap it goes like I don't know it
he doesn't know it but he just said okay
and all my calendar and contact
information just synched into the car
alright with my company I'm working on a
four hundred million dollar proposal
right now I go back to the airport
there's somebody from Boeing that
recognizes me and goes that's the lead
guy over there for this thing it's 140
million dollars he's a dumbass and
charges his phone in the car all the
time
and hazley he might it might have been
there and they say excuse me young lady
working here at Hertz I have always
wanted to have a yellow Camaro because
he's
a yellow Camaro or that one just got
true damn it looks clean enough
transformers is my favorite movie
because Michael Bay - just what you has
character development
so let me have that yellow Camaro they
go okay because first service water sure
go right now okay what do we know now
well we know that all of my corporate
contacts and my calendar it was linked
up to the car I don't realize it
happened my coworker or whoever I went
to the conference we're sharing a ride
with he doesn't know that it happened
my company is probably also a little
concerned about the information doesn't
know that it happened and so dad is
there we don't know what happened and
then there's this ownership question do
I still own my data does personal look
does Hertz own it now or is the person
that really rented the car five minutes
after I returned agenda well they have
the right tools they definitely own it
and they probably own you know they're
going to own a Ford or billion dollar
contract in a couple months
this is one area I've been talking with
access data on they are supposed to be
releasing an app
you
pounder storage a few times and
hopefully that's going to wipe it
because I don't know the implementation
in every single vendor I don't know if
that actually does take it out of of
everything they had in the system so it
is one area where there is a tool that's
in development the guest compound worker
and this is one I think that was
actually in the envy agenda in dealing
with an automobile but we had somebody
like ok I'd like to really invite this
person for discussion and happens to be
in a different country they live in a
gated community they work on the gated
compound but I can see their vehicle so
I'm going to use that awesome things
it's being demonstrated later at that
time this year and I'm going to do some
reprogramming of that vehicles computers
because what I wanted to do is go in and
with it it's a certain temperature
rather than you turn the fan on it's
that it changed the fuel air mixture
it'll run terrible and the person's come
home to the side all day I'm waiting at
the gas station two miles away they get
off work they drive car to those
problems they pull in some people in a
nice band invite them for a discussion
and then reprogram the car most likely
with the current forensics tools
nobody's going to know why this person
pulled over what happened and the fact
that he computers and have been changed
on the car twice isn't going to be found
and that's kind of a spooky thing too
that we don't even have the tools to
know that something happened and I'm
probably right at time awesome okay so
with that I'll be around later is when
people have beverages and different
interesting ideas welcome your feedback
like to learn about more things and I
promise not to do any searches from your
computers
the fun with the burner device is having
an old smartphone that I'm actually yeah
I found that picture of Journal Madison
like okay this makes up for the other
surgery