I thank you so hi guys sorry for the
technical delay firstly truly absolutely
epic to be back for a third year opening
up with yet again another history talk I
promise you that this is the last one
that I'm doing for a while I don't want
to get typecast as a historian although
I think it's a little bit too late for
that right we'll let history tell so
firstly I say this to you guys every
single year I must say it again you
should really give a round of applause
to the settee organizers right because
they are one of the best ran and
organized conferences that I've dealt
with in probably a decade of speaking so
a big hat of a round of applause for a
sexy people right so who was here last
year put your hands up right so we're
going to carry on a little bit from
where we are last year those that
weren't here last year yeah it sucks to
be you so I have had the fortune of
talking about three modern-day problems
from a historical context so when I
first spoke to you guys I spoke to you
about the Manhattan Project and the
similarities between 1950 theoretical
physicists and cryptographers today and
some of the issues that they're dealing
with I then spoke to you guys about
state surveillance but during the
Reformation the European Reformation so
state surveillance during the 1500s
because a lot of people find it hard to
fathom that states have been spying for
a lot longer than Edward Snowden's been
alive right so and this time I'm going
to talk about the evolution of privacy
the history of privacy it's quite
difficult and to say the very least
so this is me this is Phoenix I am the
stealer of cakes apparently right I'm
pretty sure that I should get to win
some sort of award in the history
character bereaved for the third
consecutive history talk an info SEC
hacking conference right just in case
I'm the only Scot that you know and that
this is not a cultural thing for my
people to come out and speak to your
people about history just in case you
know don't expect every Scot to turn up
and say here power I'm here for the
history talker that's not gonna happen
so also I'm doing a lightning talk and
this is when I actually do some security
I know it's hard for you guys to believe
that I actually do security but if you
come to a lightning tour later on you
might see me definitely do something for
a change right so let's talk about the
talk I'm talking about the history the
evolution of privacy why well because I
love privacy right like a lot of people
previously is kind of cool privacy is
around in everything that we do but I
suppose like a lot of you my biggest
fear is my search history being read out
aloud so you should confront your free
years and I should read my history are
only kidding but for a lot of people
they are worried there are is a lot of
intimate personal information that's out
there that can be read by other people
it is also doubly interesting to talk
about privacy in Sweden who knows apart
from the awesome picture why I've put
1974 up there you were one of the first
countries to actually have a national
data protection law not you know you you
you are trailblazers
what's interesting though your
trailblazers and something else as well
what seems to be a regular occurring
theme is the privacy laws are brought
into effect a lot of the times out of
the fear of what governments are doing
and in your own case in 1974 well 1973
the law was enacted it came into force
in 1974 and inspired greatly by surprise
surprise massive Aylan of mass
surveillance from the state who would
have thought it right
as I say this is a recurring theme and a
lot of laws there privacy's involved in
what I can tell you is most people have
keep on telling me that privacy is dead
which is quite interesting because I
tend to feel that you you should be able
to describe something that's dead I
don't feel that I'm able to describe
privacy that well so let's try and
define what privacy actually is so let's
ask Google because of course Google No
yeah thanks Google you were really
helpful so basically Google it's not
about being observed by other people
right okay
I mean sure that's a general description
of privacy but does did that describe
what privacy is for you I doubt it right
well maybe we should ask the experts
because they'll know right so Arthur R
Miller X yeah thanks was very very
helpful this is a quite a famous lawyer
if memory serves me I'm not about note
so I kind of give you his job
description right but Colin Bennett is a
Dean of the Harvard Law was a Dean at
Harvard Law same problem as well this is
probably the most dystopian description
of privacy that I've ever read in my
life and I have read 1984 twice privacy
is a value so complex so entangled and
competing and contradictory dimensions
so engorged that I some with various and
distinctive meanings I sometimes despair
whether it can be usefully addressed at
all if this was ever a person that
needed a hug okay
well Judith Jarvis Thompson quite a
famous philosopher same thing you
starting to notice there is a slight
theme in these quotes right and let's
ask the legend himself and Cerf privacy
may actually be an anomaly Cheers Vince
however
this is really unfair so put your hands
up if you know who this guy is but your
hands up if you've ever used a network
and now he's like a Technical Evangelist
the puzzle Factory that we call Google
but he's you know he's involved in TCP
he is a living legend in some ways and
he's an FCC meeting and of course FCC
meetings right the height of modern
entertainment everybody wants to watch
an FCC meeting right so of course it had
hardly these guys prepared for an FCC
meeting of bureaucrats and expected no
one to turn up Vince turned up and
basically said yo look he was history
privacy's only been around for about a
hundred years it's only really been
around since the invention of the wall
bla bla bla bla bla it may just be an
anomaly and of course the media lost its
business right and off they went vint
cerf but even this I've given you four
quotes from for legal or philosophical
people in history that can't define it
whose very job was to defend privacy yay
thanks experts so do you n okay I'm
gonna want people who do talks right I'm
about to break a cardinal rule and that
cardinal rule is no more than six lines
of text with no more than six words in
attacks right because otherwise you get
a wall of text for today.we breaking
that rule so bad this R on the right
through the UN that you can expect to
have your privacy which is interesting
because it's still very hard to describe
what it is but we have human rights
associated with it I'm not gonna read it
if you want to look it up do so ever
find it right okay well it turns out the
animals aren't very good at recognizing
the human rights charter and a little
known fact is that's a trait that's
shared by most governments they don't
recognize the human rights charter
either and
not your privacy this is the other part
of the UN Charter on privacy they're
specifically about the state which is an
absolute nightmare because it keeps on
going on grade how's that working out
for us right I think we're quite well
spied on quite well have our privacy
taken away from us which is quite
strange because we tried really hard to
describe what it is so hands up if you
know who amber rod is if you say UK Home
Secretary don't put your hand up right
but this is a politician who is the Home
Secretary
she is the replacement for Teresa Maine
right and she's a idiot
real people don't need encryption which
is handy because I've got another quote
for her which is real home secretaries
often prefer to access prefer ease of
access to personal information rather
than the multitude of moral obligations
to defend the law of the United Kingdom
but this is true the home secretaries
have always tried to circumvent the law
in the UK there always is a bit of a
strong term but I can show you
historical points throughout history
where Home Secretary who is responsible
for upholding the laws in the United
Kingdom have consistently broken laws
when it comes to privacy and human
rights and privacy so yeah
the Supreme Phoenix of Phoenix tan says
get it right up your amber yeah but stay
surveillance is nothing new if you were
here last year you know I've talked
about it before this is honest a but I'm
sure you don't need me to tell you who
he is great proponent of civil rights
when it boils down to it this is a
letter from the Secretariat the homeland
secretary during the Lincoln
administration during the Civil War
asking for blanket abilities to tap the
telegraph wires throughout the whole
entire country this is not Lincoln's
writing Lincoln's writing is the little
bit right of the
that basically says yeah go for it and
that is nice that is the oversight that
was given to basically literally
wiretapping Civil War America yeah when
the bid wins law today so this quote is
always always something that gets played
out in privacy talks right because of
course Gorbals is the first person to
say that right yeah no this is Elizabeth
the first some people that were here
last you love this by the way this is an
Elizabethan statement that says if you
have nothing to hide you have nothing to
fear right five hundred years before
gobble said it and you know a little
while before we've seen this being said
time and time again it's quite worrying
because it does feel a lot like we're
living in 1984 right if you've got
nothing to hide you have nothing to fear
I mean to be fair HG Wells is also as an
authorization Wells several authors also
mean Chinese very best Warner's at the
impact of privacy just think about the
message in the Invisible Man in 1987 and
this continues going on and this this is
written because of the fear of the
printed press of books of cameras and
fits not they're not feared about you
know the book that is a camera that is
an internet connection right he's not
even writing me that that's not even in
their realm yet he's writing something
like the Invisible Man it's a very good
book you should read it
a Edward Snowden probably the best
soundbite that we've had in their
privacy war right and basically hey
saying that you've got nothing to hide
you've got nothing to fear is like
saying you don't need free speech
because you've got nothing to say
thankfully someone came up with a sound
bite that actually worked but the
problem is is this is nice it's a nice
sum up of that situation but a real
problem that we have with the nothing to
hide our argument and it's an argument
put your hands up if someone if you've
heard that argument said that if you've
got nothing to hide you have nothing to
fear don't be shy the rest of you
we know that you've heard it too right
but the problem is is it is whole
premise is fixated on the concept the
privacy is only used to hide wrongdoing
that previously can't be used for
anything else right so nothing to hide
nothing to fear privacy is only about
defend hiding wrongdoing really it's
akin to saying if you have nothing
secret you have nothing to fear but
privacy is far more evolved than just a
notion of secrecy we've come all this
way of all these slides all this nice
little chat and I've still not been able
to give you a clear definition of what
privacy is and mostly because the
conceptualization of privacy the actual
conceptual like that the abstract notion
of how we discuss privacy is incredibly
hard right what I mean is is that
there's an interesting paper by a gang a
guy called Angus all of the talks about
the taxonomy of privacy and in the whole
paper is about trying to define all the
terms of privacy because if we can't
define what the term of privacy is we
can't defend you can't protect what you
can't describe any wrote this
interesting paper where he says look
we've looked at privacy and in the end
there's no one tangible thing that is
privacy is a collection of similar
minded things like a thanks to that
because you made that really clear but
an example of that is is something that
is intimate isn't necessarily private
maybe private but something that's
private may not be intimate they share
similar notions privacy private secret
intimate all of these things are share
similar notions but they can all live
independently from each other and it's
very hard to be able to describe I asked
you all right
I'm not going to ask you all don't worry
so don't lay out how you dive you can
sit on your hands right but if I asked
each and every one of you to describe to
me privacy in three words I'm probably
going to have 440
different words easily to describe
privacy you should do this yourself to
the rest of the conference you having
these Conference chats
now ask people to tell you what they
think privacy is and you'll be surprised
because you've taken it for granted that
your notion of privacy is of course the
same notion of privacy that everyone
else has right this doesn't seem to be
the case so where's the history you've
talked to all this time you've not
talked about any history so well the
privacy is history is actually in our
architecture it's woven into the very
fabric of how we live how we live
together privacy is an evolving thing if
we take privacy as it sits in our laws
as well and it's also in our religion as
well I'll talk about these things in a
little minute okay so the impact of
urban living upon privacy is quite
interesting I'm not going to go and do
some urban living planning talk don't
worry right we're just going to touch
this so this is kind of how we used to
live and we used to live in this sort of
way because of shared resources because
of safety because of security previously
always tends to take a backseat to other
means rain it's quite strange but the
notion of privacy in a big heart where
you all live together you all sleep in
the same space the concept of having a
quiet moment just doesn't exist because
of lack of opportunity to this and it's
buildings develop this plays the fire
plays such a pivotal role in bringing
people together as we can see ba ba ba
ba ba but the invention of the fireplace
changes internal architecture massively
and what this does is we see the
invention of chimneys and chimneys allow
us to move smoke out of a property once
we were able to move the smoke from the
fire into the sky we were able to start
building
internal walls because otherwise you're
gonna choke people to death so the
invention of the fire of the fireplace
has an impact on how we start to live
together and then all of a sudden we go
from fires to you know Park Avenue you
know don't get me wrong
there was a few steps along the way they
didn't just like here's a fireplace
here's New York but as you can see as a
species we've gone from mud huts and
fireplaces to bathrooms and bedrooms and
single occupancy and so on and so forth
and a reasonably small made a space of
time how we bathed was a public affair
it's quite interesting here's my German
story for you right I live I'm a Scot
that lives in Germany now my girlfriend
is forever telling me that I'm so very
British and I'm forever telling her that
she's so very German and this is a story
that happened to me that highlights
cultural awareness when it comes to
privacy or intimacy intimacy not quite
but previously definitely
so my girlfriend took me into a German
sauna and anyone who's been to a German
sauna knows that this conversation is
over with right now anyone who doesn't
we go to German sauna am I good I'm
getting undressed I'm down to my shorts
and I've got my tell because don't
forget I'm a pasty Brit and my
girlfriend says to me oh you need to
take your shorts off and she didn't even
get to the end of the sentence before I
said no oh you need to be naked no no
and she said it was one of the funniest
things because you could never have been
more British at that moment so you
didn't even get the words out but this
notion of a shared sauna and spa
experience was just a little bit too
much to me but I'm brave I took my
clothes off and I spent the rest of the
day naked in a spa what I realized is
doing a lot better than most people in
Germany right so wasn't too bad but the
this was a public matter bathing so on
and so forth right it's only later on
when the water closet when the bathroom
the internal plumbing happens that we
start to develop notions that I want to
cleanse myself and privacy quotas are
the Romans
attitude towards sex was incredibly
different to our attitude towards sex
Christian ization had an impact on how
we had intimacy with each other
beforehand it's a public affair also if
there is ever a wall anywhere there no
matter what period of time there is
always someone who's going to write on
it
Romans being tagged right I mean okay
cool but you can see how the Romans
regarded what we consider a very
intimate act a very public act and if
you're interested in the impact of
architecture in privacy Rome is a very
good place to look as well because
there's a huge difference between how
group Greece built its dwellings and how
Rome built its dwellings and in Rome's
case they open up a lot of their
dwellings so that they can show their
opulence to other people and in Greece
and in Greece the buildings are far more
designed to cut off parts of the house
that you couldn't see it from the
outside so it's quite interesting in
really a case of privacy versus
publicity Road this is kind of an
interesting study about tribes that
don't have internal walls in their
living conditions right so they live in
a shared environment compared to tribes
that do have private spaces and what
they discovered was the tribes that
without private rooms tribes would
probably preferred to have sex indoors
where are those tribes that didn't have
the ability to have sex in a private
room would actually go and walk to have
their intimate moments so it goes to
show you that the human condition allows
us to still try and find a way though
even though the opportunities are not
there a pooping because we all want to
do that publicly
but this is another thing that Rome is
very famous for there's a notion though
that it's quite bizarre but this is yet
again about access the access to toilets
was a resource was a commodity not
everybody had the access to that at home
we're not gonna build we're not gonna
build 440 public toilets just outside so
that you can all have one each right so
they become shared but the very notion
changes this is like one of these Roman
toilets today the communal bed it's very
hard to imagine but the truth is as a
species we all slept in the same bed for
a very very very long time and yet again
this is because the access to individual
beds the cost associated was prohibited
but put this into context your guests
will come and visit and they will join
you your wife your children and her
mother and their entourage you all just
hop into that same bed to us today how
alien does this seem but to them not so
much right and it is predominantly about
access what's interesting though is that
that has a small impact in medicine what
happens in medicine during the black
death before this patients were all in
the same bed and basically the de facto
rule of thumb being was as many patients
to a bed as you would feel comfortable
with houseguests was their basic rule of
thumb which is a little bit worrying
when everyone's got the black death and
death and death and death death death
death let's all hook up and bed together
and eventually they worked helped that a
single bed might be a better option and
it's hoped mastery but we see this
impact as beds become more available our
notion of the intimate space of the
bedroom changes yet again he's not
proposing I mean I don't know how you do
it in your country but it's not how we
do it mind
well it depends which part of Scotland
to be fur but this is called the
compromised position this is an article
about giving a gynecological exam in the
medical journal and discussing about how
someone's privacy can be protected but
its interest in the terminology that
they use in this the compromised
positions like there's some deal that's
being made between a doctor and a
patient right we've compromised we've
made a deal right okay but medicine is a
really interesting place of where the
confusion about privacy secrecy and
intimacy all kind of coexist right
privacy in the law this will be fun so
the law of privacy can be traced back to
1361 in England anyway I'm not sure you
can find it anywhere else written down
I'm sure there was no shion's and tribal
notions of privacy but the problem is is
there where we limited is his tribes and
countries that hadn't had a written
history such as the Germans it's very
hard to see what their notions of
history were because their history is
written by the Romans right but in 1361
we see a law coming through the British
law books about specifically about
eavesdropping trying to listen to
conversations and peeping toms do you
know what a peeping tom is I take it for
granted that you do but if you don't
peeping tom is someone that's trying to
pee a few through your curtains when
you're getting dressed and stuff like
that it's not me anyway however in 1844
the British government gets embroiled in
quite an interesting scandal now I know
that you guys are not Brits I know that
I talk a bit about British history is
because I'm a Brit sorry right but in
1844 there is a massive issue about
privacy that happens in the UK so much
so then it makes it all the way to the
House of Commons and it's to do with
Mazzini giuseppe mazzini put your hands
up if you know who he is I was
I saw one person put their hands up he
is a Italian revolutionary legal scholar
and yet I think the Italians would call
him a patriot too responsible not
responsible but very much trying to
bring in a unified Italy he's very kind
of cool but what happens is and I think
it's 43 in 1843 he was able to prove
that the Home Secretary the United
Kingdom had ordered for his mail to be
intercepted it's just quite a damning
indictment so what he does is he he he
believes that his mouth is being
intercepted and what he does is he sends
three letters out and he puts sand poppy
seeds and hair in all three letters he
sends his letters off to his friends in
European countries and he sends one of
the letters to himself and when the
letter comes back his letter has no sand
no poppy seeds no hair inside the
envelope but the other two in the other
two countries do and this is when he
knows that the Brits have been reading
his mail and the reason the Brits have
been reading his mail is that this is
the request of the Austrian ambassador
to the United Kingdom and what they're
very very worried about is a revolt
almost happening in Italy and the
consequences that will have an Austria
later on but as we can see it's quite a
serious damning indictment but what's
interesting as well is that the mail is
probably one of the most guarded privacy
you know if you look at laws there's a
lot of laws that protect the sanctity of
the mail this is another example of it
so I don't know why it's gone all freaky
there but okay let's call such an uproar
the the House of Commons had to have a
committee of secrecy and where it was
discovered then the Home Secretary
not only had been doing this
to Mazzini but they actually had a whole
department in the Royal in the mail
whose specific job was to intercept the
mail of troublesome people um it's
interesting because what governments do
when they get caught is they go car
that's terrible we're gonna shut that
down start a new one right now yeah it's
over
is it open yeah it's old don't worrying
right and this is exactly what they do
no no we're gonna close the mail reading
Department let's just start an
intelligence service instead cool but
this is very interesting so yet again
laws coming into place not because of
any other reason than the government
taking advantage of technical changes to
be able to intercept people's privacy
right Jeremy Bantam I have two ideas I
really don't know if I like this guy or
not put your hands up if you know who
this guy is
wow really so you might want to read him
up right he's kind of cool but what he's
really famous for
I'm totally gonna kill this
pronunciation every time I've done it
I've always done it
panopticon he he's basically the
inventor of this concept and what this
is is this is predominantly designed to
how they deal with prisoners beforehand
prisoners tended to take him to the
dungeons you know used to store
prisoners in basements and dungeons the
thing is it's pretty hard to see what
your prisoner is up to if he's in a dark
hole in the mountain right what's he up
to
needless to say you can't afford to put
a guard on every single door right so
bathroom realized that what he really
wants is to have all the cells above
ground well-lit well open known doors
and a big column in the middle right at
the top is a guard tower and you see
these little windows at the top these
guards basically have a 360 unrestricted
view of all the prisoners and the idea
here is that the prisoners can't see in
the guy
Tower but the guards can see out of the
guard tower and that means that the
prisoners constantly have to live with
the concept that they don't know if they
are or if they're not being watched but
what they know is they could be being
watched which basically is the notion of
1984 right so this is a very interesting
turning point I mean it changes the the
you know the the legal judiciary
massively but this notion is panopticon
notion gets used in other places far
more far more mentally than physically
right it's quite interesting
everyone's watching us it's brilliant
privacy in religion well privacy in
Christianity would probably be better
way of describing this right so you know
we take privacy we take religion as
their as a private moment but this is
not something that that happens
organically this is something that as a
result changes and what I mean is the
doctrine of like silent virtue of silent
reflection is only something that
happens in the Christian Church after
the invention of the printed press and
the reason that this happens is access
to the Bible is quite limited so
religion itself is a publicly shared
event it's a public because access the
Bible's is not around because Bibles are
handwritten they're written in Latin and
not everybody can read so it means that
if you want to engage in religion he had
to do it publicly
this changes when the press comes into
play right but it's it's interesting
because you know Christianity is
benefited a lot from technological
developments throughout the years but
what's interesting about books religion
and mystery go hand in hand right I mean
it the mystery is requiring you to
believe in something which is basically
the doctrine of religion right
but of course books really love to
reveal mystery that's basically their
thing so they may have made interesting
bedfellows to start with but what we see
is a warm from there on inwards rail
it's interesting the sanctity of the
confessional is rather interesting too
so we take the idea as a confessional
and most laws are hugely recognized that
what is said between a believer and a
priest sacred cannot break that you know
really the living embodiment of public
and private going on and confessional
however the confessional wasn't always a
public wasn't always a private affair in
fact the confessional was a public
affair done between the whole entire
congregation
my guess is nobody did anything wrong
right as my guess is what happens at a
public confessional who's got anything
to confess no good I'm fine but this
changes and but I can't think of a
greater example of the real dynamic
change in how we deal with privacy than
the Catholic Church and the confessional
right it's very interesting I know that
I'm running out of time so I'm gonna try
and wrap up okay
so the only thing more cherished then
privacy is publicity a wonderful talk by
Jill Lepore if you ever get a chance to
see it just Google just in youtube put
something like history of privacy it's a
very interesting it's the only one
that's done anything recent that's worth
reading but the only thing more
cherished in privacy is publicity or
what do you mean by that a Facebook I'll
give you a second when I first gave a
version of this talk at girl corn
in Michigan last year and in the middle
of me putting these slides together this
story popped up on my timeline the
worrying thing is I'm the one that
blanked out all the names so this is
literally in my timeline for those that
can't read it at the back this is a
young lady talking about they were
playing with a vibrator in a bedroom and
it went north and needed to have surgery
to have it removed from her bowel and
then she decided that she was going to
tell the whole entire world about it on
Facebook so this is a couple of hours
after days you could see 19 hours
afterwards there's 287 2827 shares right
I'm not one of them but I don't think
anything could Facebook is a real
example of our real one for privacy but
our desperate need for publicity
fascinating Jill Lepore also said which
I thought was quite fascinating I find
it very hard to accept straight away but
the cater privacy comes after never
before the exposure and this is a really
interesting notion that in some ways we
have technological developments and
afterwards we go holy
you know the printed press isn't banned
on to you guys about the printing press
for at least two talks right it's
because I believe it's incredibly
important to our species but if you
think about the invention of the printed
press there was some sanctuary in words
because not everybody could read but the
printed press allowed Universal literacy
to become a real thing
all of a sudden the sanctuary of words
couldn't protect you anymore and what
was said was there but the case for
privacy as they say we've done this as
well
we claim privacy once the exposure has
happened never before I can't think
of episodes where this is not case but
she has this this really interesting
notion that much that was a mysterious
became Sutra and then it became private
I let you read the rest cuz I don't
believe in reading off slides right but
I'm gonna guess when you've read it
right and if not just ask the person
next to you and hopefully there are
faster reader than you right no change
but this could really be summed up as
religion science and law God's miracle
of life
the science of reproduction Roe versus
Wade put your hands up if you know who
row versus Wade is right there should be
a lot more of you putting your hands up
I'm sorry to tell you this road versus
Wade do you like civil rights put your
hands up right you guys have to go
because we don't like you right but this
road versus Wade is a legal case about
abortion but it has civil rights
implications Road versus Wade gives us a
lot of privacy now yes it's not a court
case in your country there's a court
case in the super state of the United
States of America that has an impact
globally on all of us but this is the I
think this sums are perfectly religion
science and law mystery reveal the
mystery respond to the revelations
liberty is the right to do what the law
permits as Montesquieu and said which is
kind of interesting because the history
of privacy is actually the history of
technology versus legality if you can't
find a better resource to find the
history of privacy than looking through
the law book books those are your own
lore books in your own countries and
you'll follow your country's history
about the fears that at hand with
intercepts and the fears of having
previously taken away with that and how
elected
officials responded to it there's
probably no better resource but from
letters and words to sentences and
paragraphs the person's innermost
thoughts and desires and fears become
public you know this is the invention of
words that did this for us so here is my
final attempt to define what privacy is
privacy is just the right to be human
[Music]
and I'll leave you with our startled
because all of this talk today would
never have started without Aristotle and
the original works and the private and
public spheres and whatever within our
power to do lies also within our powers
not to do and I think that we should
very much bear in mind that this notion
going forward in technology as our
impact will always we always have an
impact on people's very privacy and with
that I think that I've got ten minutes
for questions so thank you
and that's awesome thank you and we will
be able to keep the schedule running
because you didn't you used to your time
well I think I was fast this is why they
will look tired fine
what did he say now we don't want you to
speak phosphorus that's for sure
what's your question yeah so what do you
think what do you think that we should
try for is isn't what do you think it's
more important I mean we can't define
privacy which means it's very hard to
achieve because you can't define it do
you think that it's more important in
that case that we try to define privates
as something that we can achieve is it
more important with the actual privacy
that we can't define or the feeling that
we have privacy so I've got maybe two
ways of answering this question
privacy is a lot like a lot like
dinosaurs right it will always find a
way
you know like Jurassic Park right but
privacy will it will always find a
notion within people because privacy is
human and I don't think there is a
problem with defining privacy I think we
just gave up defining privacy privacy is
quite hard to define yes but it's not
impossible for us to do it look at all
the things that we've managed to achieve
as a species and we're going to be
beaten by something that's our own
emotion seems somewhat bizarre to me
but for me I think privacy is a lot more
like a force more like gravity than
anything else right the little bits of
privacy once they become bigger and
bigger and bigger have bigger impacts
you know it's something around as it
shapes the world we do it shape the
things around us it's more like a
universal force then didn't secrecy then
intimacy right sort of the same way that
privacy is more of a direction than a
destination there's nice it's something
that we want yeah visit direction we
won't ever be there because you're never
you don't reach or direction always on
the journey right
so then you can't really say that this
is something that we can achieve
critizise not something hot you'd like
that right privacy becomes this
psychosis that we live that we I mean
all I can tell you is is that I do
believe that if we want to work in
privacy we don't get to say chaps it's
too complicated right I don't think we
get to say we're gonna go and make
mistakes because it's too complicated
for us to understand yes it might be
difficult for us right now to get the
notions of so on and so forth but we
don't know where the research will go in
a hundred years time in 200 years time
20 years time history evolved it is it's
just a living embodiment of us in some
ways so I don't think I can answer the
question in the way that you want me to
answer it maybe that's just five
questions from the audience and do we
have microphones running around in the
audience now that's one microphone over
there and there's one person here you
because there's so tight between the
chairs you actually have to help with a
microphone and pass it over you're never
gonna win the Olympics like that right
so I'm called ma'am isn't that it's hard
to define privacy because it's the force
and the counter force when you have this
counter force with government monitoring
you or whatever what Google is logging
or whatever that part of the definition
of privacy and so it's you can't define
it you can't define it for a short
moment and then it's the counter force
changes and then you have to redefine it
I don't think we'll ever have a static
moment with privacy I don't think we get
to an evolution and that's it game over
I mean I just think that it keeps on
changing as we keep on changing and I
wouldn't say the counter forces
government or Google or so on and so
forth it's very nice out and I hadn't
thought about that it that way but I
would say that the counter forces
technology not necessarily organisation
I think you pick on the organization's
because they use technology but I think
but there's always a push between the
two right I hope that answers the
question somewhat okay so one question
down here you can just throw ahem yeah
just some events do that you have to
line up in a line and you put a
microphone out I think that will be
possibly check have you sent yourself
any poppy seeds or equipment I mean I
would have to write a letter to start
off with and I mean let's be fair about
this the issue here is that we don't
write letters and it's a great point
that you make because how lucky is
masini to have lived in a period of time
where he could have detected someone
reading his mail and look at the notions
that you guys have to live today where's
your save the poppy seeds and where's
your cyber hair and your cyber sound
right you're not going to be able to
pull the same stunt the Mersey needed to
find out that you know amber rod is
reading your emails
oh so this is why sometimes the
attachments are missing in my emails
yeah okay
I start sending emails with like poppy
seed PDF head or PDF sand or PDF just
let me know if you got them back right
sometimes it's the the checks in the
mail version of here's here's the stuff
I promise you right there right there in
that yeah your voice is strong enough I
think no no I take the microphone it's
actually are going out to the street as
well okay then I won't yell sorry
I wanted to ask is it even possible to
to privacy as people are fairly
oblivious to all the information they're
given away in extent of where that
information will wind up yeah so my day
job is looking breaches and the impact
and the data involved and yeah you're
absolutely right the
case of privacy comes after the exposure
never before right and and and in person
people's Equifax is a great example
right now people are jumping up and down
about the data breach but the truth of
the matter is yes there is a breach and
yes that information may be becoming
public but no one was jumping up and
down beforehand when aquifers had the
data Hey
like oh this is bad data collecting this
data and then they lost it it was a
little bit late to be talking about this
now it's out there it's not to say that
we shouldn't be looking at how we deal
with this and we do need as a species to
go ahead around there is two bits of us
the public and the private bit and we
should work very much to protect both
sides because without them we're just
half of what we could be so yeah don't
give up it's a long journey right but
yeah I hope that helps have we got any
more questions
all right no more questions then in that
case thank you very much Phenix
[Applause]