thank you very much this actually is not
the whole talk the guy did the research
with who's unfortunately not here he
actually put this together which I'm
really amazed by but I got to say after
some of those demo videos last night
this doesn't kind of pales into
comparison but but yeah so my name is
Daniel Bohannon
as I said Leigh Holmes is the other guy
who did this research with me and today
I'm gonna be talking about Revo Coffee
Association basically detecting off you
skated PowerShell using science so a
little bit about me I'm a I worked for
mandiant based out of Washington DC I've
been there for about two two-and-a-half
years came from an operational
background than operational security and
then IR consulting and now for recently
trans transitioned in I'm a senior
applied security researcher focusing on
detection basically a detection a scale
across all of our clients and then
causing mayhem with obfuscation to
improve our detection z'
i'm also the author of the Invo coffee
station and invoke cradle craft or
obfuscation frameworks and the co-author
of revoke confiscation and my partner in
crime lee holmes he's an awesome guy
he's a lead security architect at
Microsoft out in Seattle and he's also
one of the original PowerShell
developers so it was awesome to learn
about PowerShell from the guy who helped
write it and also when you're writing
PowerShell code and the person who wrote
the language is looking at that code you
learn how little you know about it but
he's just an awesome guy I learned a ton
from him I'm also the author of the
Windows PowerShell cookbook so today
we're gonna look at kind of a treatise
of folly from the blue team perspective
and I feel like I can say this because
I'm a blue team and all these follies
I've made and I intend to share them
with you so that we can all improve
together but what bad assumptions are
being made out there hopefully what good
assumptions are being made well let's
look at it at a very minimum when it
comes to investigating attacks that
involve PowerShell some component which
on every investigation I've ever been on
PowerShell has played at least a
significant part in one of the stages of
the attack lifecycle at the very least
you want command-line argument
which you can find in security logs 46
88 or a system on Eid 1 both of those
are really really great option but what
you really want in addition to that is
PowerShell logging specifically
PowerShell version 5 script lock logging
number 1 which is your Eid 4104 and then
module and transcription after that and
at the bottom here these are two great
resources one from the PowerShell team
and the other from a colleague of mine
outlining all the the first one outlines
all the awesome stuff the PowerShell
team has built into later versions of
PowerShell and the latter one is looking
at what you actually get what are the
benefits you actually get when I say
upgrade to PowerShell 5 some of you may
say that's not trivial and I get that
but what are the benefits you're missing
out on this blog post is an excellent
way of going over that and hopefully
this talk will also be ammunition you
can take back and say hey here's some of
the reasons why we want to get the
PowerShell 5 so we don't have to deal
with this completely blind so how we're
just going to take the first part and
diving into some off eustachian
techniques when it comes to powershell
and again hopefully this is going to
help some of us see some of the follies
that we've been making as defenders when
it comes to our assumptions and then
we're gonna look at how do we actually
detect this in a different way so
oftentimes we'll see attackers launch in
PowerShell most commonly from command
sometimes from off from windward accel
stuff like that but typically a lot of
defenders myself included when I started
was I want to look for PowerShell dot
exe running and then look for the
arguments that come after that and if I
see malicious strings then that's of
interest however there are other ways
that you can actually PowerShell code on
the command line
and as a lot of command line utilities
like command or whim ik they can accept
standard input as the command ask in
PowerShell so for example these two
ladder samples you can have command
echoing your actual command content and
piping it in the PowerShell dash or
PowerShell IEX input and there's a lot
more ways you can do this but these are
the two most common ones and as you'll
see our command runs but if you're
looking at logs then PowerShell
arguments are PowerShell - PowerShell IX
input the actual command content is in
the parent process
so as a defender when you start to kind
of build out your rules that you want to
look for and command-line arguments
don't just look for PowerShell 2xe maybe
you should also look for the parent
process instead sometimes people will
say okay well let me just look for
command or any process for that matter
where I also see a pipe PowerShell maybe
that'll help me out well not exactly
because what you can do here is you can
say I'm going to have embedded commands
so the first command will set power and
then shell and two different variables
and then it will reassemble those in the
next command such that as you can see in
the logs here you never see pipe
PowerShell I'm showing up in that parent
process this is an actual technique from
the wild Fenn a is a financially
motivated threat actor and this is a
sample we came across in February
actually does anyone here know John
Lambert from Microsoft he was the first
one to tweet this he's an amazing person
to follow because he tweets out really
awesome samples that he finds in the
wild it's a really good source of
information but what we see here is what
Finn ate at the very bottom this is
their actual PowerShell command you see
the nice little ix at the end but then
they set to environment variables but
this is one environment variable which
they call Microsoft Update catalog and
then the other one is PowerShell - and
then all this is inside of a macro then
they launch command echo bar one bar to
look familiar
so this is being used in the wild other
ways you can do this that you can pass
stuff from from a parent or grandparent
process down to the child process the
powershell is you can store in
environment variables i'm copter is a
malware that really enjoys this
technique and there's a lot of different
ways to call an environment variable
Koffler typically is going to use dollar
sign EMV colon and then the name but
these are just a few of the ways that
you can extract values out of variables
other things you can do you can echo
your content your payload into the
clipboard and then just have powershell
pull that out so let's go through this
example then let's say that we have our
malicious strings we're looking for and
we're looking for that in powershell on
its parent process what we could
actually do if we're an attacker is we
could say okay let me
let me put a third process in the mix we
have command command PowerShell the
first command let me set my payload and
in this case I set a variable called CMD
in the second one let me echo the
contents of that variable in the
powershell - now this runs but as you'll
see PowerShell - is the arts for the
first process and then we see the entire
command in the parent process which is
good for us as defenders but as an
attacker what if we actually escaped one
layer of escaping to that pipe
so it's escape for the first command but
not for the second one bingo PowerShell
- is the arcs for the first process the
second process just has the name of the
variable now this only works one layer
child process deep because it actually
resolves in memory and this is pretty
cool and we see it hackers doing this so
maybe we should say okay instead of just
looking for the parent process let's
look recursively all the way up the
process tree at all the arguments and
see if we find something interesting
would that work be better than nothing
but there are ways that you can have no
shared process and attackers are doing
this the clipboard is one example I
could have you know process a over here
echo into the clipboard and the
unrelated process retrieve the contents
from the clipboard you could also do
something like this where you can have
one process spawn a command with a
payload in the title let's say and then
use WMI to reassemble that title or like
this attacker a lot of commands with a
lot of titles using WMI to piece them
all back together and then execute the
contents so the good news is that all of
this is captured in PowerShell script
block logging when there's this symbol
up here every slide where you see the
symbol and there are quite a few on the
slide so I apologize but basically this
says all this stuff no matter how it was
launched or you know thrown into
PowerShell it's recorded in the
PowerShell logs so it's just a reminder
of hey this is really important to have
these logs enabled because you actually
see this stuff now will it make it easy
to detect not always but at least you
have a fighting chance of somewhere to
start and the bad news is however that
there is token layer off you see a ssin
which we're just about to dive into that
does persist all the way into even the
best PowerShell script block logs
one other note here when it comes to
looking for arguments in PowerShell Dexy
keep in mind that
hackers also like to just copy
PowerShell to let's say Firefox XE and
then run their payloads so when it comes
to any binaries my advice is if the
arguments themselves are good enough
indicators then forget the name of the
process and you'll actually start to
catch renaming binary attacks so let's
look at an example we're gonna och you
skate the cradle now what do I mean by
cradle well cradle is this one-liner at
the very top here comes the one-liner in
memory let's download a remote content
and then execute it without ever hitting
disk and this is super common because
copy and paste is easy and it's our very
best friend you'll see this syntax in
vail powersploit Metasploit all the big
players out there everyone uses this
syntax so at the very least we should be
good at detecting this out of the box
right so if this is our attacker command
at the top then that's defenders maybe
we can say okay if we see this in logs
or if we see it on the command line if
we key off of the string invoke
expression and new object and system net
that live client and download string
HTTP this would catch this exact command
so now let's look at how a few stations
can really mess this up for us as
defenders
first of all system dot this is not
necessary I want to move pretty quickly
through this material and these slides
are available online so definitely
encourage you to go back and check it
out but I really want to get to to the
really fun stuff in detecting this so
it's not just like a really depressing
talk for us defender it's actually a
quick show of hands who here is blue
blue team defender in a day job awesome
please don't throw anything at me I
promise I'll turn this around at the end
and I'm assuming everyone else is red or
undecided or purple which is like what I
like to consider myself so system dot
this is not necessary PowerShell will
automatically pre pin this and actually
when you look at module logs you'll see
system dot it's prepended so if an
attacker doesn't have to put system dot
in this command as a defender I don't
want to account on it needing to be
there in my defenses so I'm gonna remove
it from the attacker command and from my
defenses make sense
all right the URL this is a string and
strings are amazing if you can get
something to a string you can off you
skate it like crazy so you can
concatenate it in line just like that
you can also use sing
quotes double quotes whitespace etc
download string so download string in
the context of PowerShell this is a
member token when I say token layer off
you station PowerShell token eise's the
command the URL is a string token
download string is a member token invoke
expression a new object those are
command let tokens so from power shalls'
perspective download string is a member
but it's actually a method of the net
dot web client dotnet class so it's
however not the only method it's the
most common ways the attackers use
there's actually quite a few and this is
just a partial list and the ones that
really want to draw your attention to
our download string file and data and we
talked about this a bit of the community
night but these are all ones that we see
attackers using so to cover all of these
why don't we just change our defenses to
look for dot download and we'll be good
so we'll do that next why might this
print to see be problematic in our in
our detection here well some attackers
will actually set new object net that
web client as a variable typically
calling it WC and these have variable
name dot download string so let's remove
that parenthesis from our detection all
right here's where it gets a little
crazy so download string this is a
member how might we actually office get
a member so when I first started looking
at this about a year year and a half ago
I basically just started trying to screw
around with it and see what I could make
still work so I found you could put
single quotes around it now let's don't
make it a string but like kind of I
found however that when you put double
quotes around it you can actually do a
little more and so if you look at
download string this next slide I
promise you works what you can do is you
can just put a tick mark in there
and what you can actually do is put a
lot of tick marks if you'd like but
basically why does this work well the
tick mark is the escape character for
powershell and if it's not one of these
predefined escape characters then it
doesn't really have any meaning at all
so it executes and then it's all still
in the the logs so you can put a lot of
tech characters in there as long as
you're not proceeding a character that
has an escaped meaning however i really
wanted to put ticks in front of those
characters that had escaped meanings and
so what i found is all you have to do is
just uppercase the characters and then
you can put tick marks and
so now we can put tick marks in front
any character that we want and as you
see a persist in the command line
argument logs as well as powers shell
script block logs which means even if
you have the latest version of
PowerShell and all this stuff enabled
you still have to take these tick marks
into account so if you decide to try to
use reg X and I actually would not
advise that for some reasons we'll look
at a little bit make sure that in
addition to this download stuff you also
look for open read because that is also
a memory only way that you can download
a payload it returns it as a byte stream
but it is something we've seen a lot
less often but still we've seen it in
the wild now if you'll notice here we
can also if we add this dot invoke then
we can treat download string completely
as a string and start to do like
concatenation or even like reordering
and stuff like that so that's why I
wouldn't recommend doing reg X because
when it comes to reordering stuff it's
just game over so let's just remove that
for my indicators next at that web
client well we can obfuscate this with
double quotes tick marks we can treat
this as a full-blown string and
concatenate it or set it in multiple
variables and reassemble it so let's
just remove that for my indicators new
object
so now PowerShell is really inviting for
new users I actually kind of
accidentally stumbled into PowerShell I
was writing batch files and one of the
guys in my last job said won't you just
change that to adopt PS one and then run
it with PowerShell
and I said well well actually work means
like yeah like it's really friendly it
basically has all these aliases that
take into account if you're doing make
derp order then you don't have to do the
PowerShell versions of those commands
those are all aliases and so PowerShell
is really inviting but that as a
defender it means you have to look for
all those options when you're writing
defenses because any of those are valid
however a new object doesn't have a
single alias so I thought perfect this
is gonna be a really really good
indicator not so much so there are so
many commandlets in PowerShell that
sometimes you forget what you're looking
for and there's this really nice git
command so in this example there's a
there's a command I want that's new - P
something so let me just say git command
new - P wildcard and here all the
functions and commands that return there
now this is returning not text but
PowerShell objects so what that means is
that we can actually take that object
that comes back and invoke it now if we
pass it to invoke expression it will
actually convert that object into a
string and as long as we're returning a
single object then it will return the
name of that object which is the name of
the commandment but we can do better
than that we can actually invoke it with
a dot or an ampersand now these are
invocation operators which are actually
acting on the object itself so this is
new object now you may say well why does
that matter because if I'm a defender I
still see new object sitting right there
exactly so as an attacker what we could
do is use that nice wild-card
functionality and do something like that
or that in any combination that we want
as long as it returns a single object
that is now a new object and you will
not see new object on the command line
or script block logs where you will see
it is in module logs see I D 4103
but for any script that runs every
single parameter binding like this is
its own logs you could have hundreds or
even thousands of module augs for a
single script invocation so the data is
all there it's just not in one place and
it makes it a bit difficult to kind of
reassemble depending on what kind of
solutions that you have so the problem
gets a little worse get command maybe to
start looking for a get command on the
command line which is actually extremely
uncommon so that might be a good one but
get command has an alias of GCM and
actually if you promise to keep a secret
there's an undocumented alias forget
command and it is command because
PowerShell again being really really
helpful says oh I see you type this
thing and I'll have a function named
command I don't have a command line
named command maybe you meant get -
command and it will check that and like
yep get command is definitely are you
looking for so there you go now why this
is important to defenders as any time
you're writing detection is based on a
commandment that starts with get - that
get - is not necessary and attackers
might not have it in their command so
maybe we look for new object get command
GCM command if we don't want to use
wildcards for any of the stuff we can
just chunk up our command what name into
variables or do string manipulation the
the world is our oyster when it comes to
this PowerShell one not oh this is just
a few ways that you can do this exact
same thing with PowerShell one dot oh
now that's you know kind of ugly looking
code how the later versions of
PowerShell have made it a lot easier to
accomplish this with shorter commands
but attackers don't always choose the
smallest commands if they no defenders
are not looking for this this would be a
really great opportunity for them
my advice is look at posh code.org a
popular powershell script sharing
platform and it's been around since the
beginning of PowerShell so there's a lot
of old and new scripts there and you can
find a lot of really good ones that are
syntax the important thing to see here
is this execution context this is an
automatic variable in PowerShell and
this is really important keep that in
mind because we're gonna see this played
out a lot and as a defender if you're
not looking for that I would highly
recommend that you do I've very rarely
seen this in the wild but that's
probably because most people don't have
PowerShell logging enabled and
unfortunately attackers aren't in the
habit of enabling it for you so I do
recommend you enable it before you have
to deal with attackers so all the stuff
with get command you can do the exact
same thing with git alias although
you're working with the alias name and
not the command line name so git command
you can do that for let's say invoke
expression get a list you can do with
IEX
and get alias has an alias of ghoul and
then the get alias unofficial alias is
alias you know because of the whole git
- thing so so we'll just go with this
option for our attacker command and
we're just not gonna worry about trying
to detect that because there's just so
many options so if you did try to detect
it though these are all commandlets that
can have tick marks put in front of them
oh that's fun another thing you can do
instead of tick marks is go back to our
invocation operators the dot and
ampersand and then you can just say new
objects concatenated this one right here
this is one of the nice ways that you
can reorder content so you basically
take a string like new object chunk it
up in this case two three sub strings
and then set the ordering of those on
the left sides of the dash F so some
people will have said okay well when I
look at PowerShell arguments or event
logs I just remove all the special
characters so in that case if this you
have this concatenated stuff if you
remove the pluses and
the you know quotes and stuff the new
object will actually come back together
and you can apply rules to it here new
object never comes back together so
let's just give up on this indicator
I'll be a realist here so we're left
with invoke expression and again if you
are defender if you're not looking for
IEX or invoke expression on the command
line you're missing some seriously easy
wins out there so what things we need to
keep in mind though about this well it
has an alias of IX ordering doesn't
matter you can have it at the beginning
of an expression or an expression being
piped into it since their command lets
you can just add tick marks in front of
them you can use the invocation
operators and treat ie X or invoke
expression as strings and manipulate it
with any of the string manipulation and
just a fun note I'll be talking here in
a second about the powershell corpus
that lee and i assembled as part of this
research of all the powershell scripts
that we assembled all I'll talk about
the numbers in a minute less than 3% of
scripts actually used invoke expressions
so from a script perspective it's
actually pretty darn uncommon but again
on the command line it's really uncommon
in legitimate powershell the other thing
to keep in mind is invoke expression has
a cousin called invoke command and now
invoke command is really fascinating
typically it's used to run a command on
a remote system but if you don't define
a remote system it runs locally besides
that the biggest difference is invoke
expression is expecting to invoke a
string or an expression invoke command
is expecting a script block we have
invoked command
it's a oasis or ICM you can use the dot
or ampersand invocation operators also
at the end of the curly braces there you
can put dot invoke invoke returns is
invoke with context if your powershell 3
year later a lot of different options so
let's say that we want to look for all
these options here you also have the
powershell one dodo syntax again
execution context there it is again
and the invoke script will handle the
invoke strip method will handle both an
expression or a script lock it doesn't
matter now what's really gonna be
problematic is this ampersand and dot
how could you possibly signature off of
an ampersand or a dot and not get insane
false positives well one thing we could
do is say okay i only want to look
ampersand or dot if there are also curly
braces because the only way to write a
script block in PowerShell is to have it
encapsulated in curly braces right not
quite you can convert expressions to
script locks and here are just two ways
of doing that you can use a script block
class in the create method or you can
use execution context once again and use
its new script lock method and so in
this case you can have script locks
without ever having curly braces and
there are other ways you can get around
curly braces but these are just two and
for each of these you can often get him
with all the stuff we literally just
talked about so there's no easy win here
unfortunately and in an invoke kredel
crafter which i talked about two days
ago we actually I built in eleven eleven
different invocation options these are
the nine from memory cradles and a few
more for disk based cradles but
basically there's a lot of ways you can
invoke content that looks very different
than you might expect and the reason
that I put all this research and codify
into these tools that I spend way too
much time on and ASCII art and colors
and stuff like that is because I really
want it to be accessible to anyone to
look at and to be able to just to say
you know what let me randomly produced
ten thousand and off.you skated samples
and see how many of these my detection
is actually miss and then tweak my
detections so that we can come up with
speed here that's exactly what I do in
my day to day job all right
take a deep breath that was a lot so the
good news is that there's really not
anything else that you can do from
Northeast Asian perspective after this
no I'm just kidding there's a way more
you can do that was just token layer off
you station so let's say after we go
through all this token layer off you
station we then just take the entire
command and say you know what let me
treat you as a string and then I get all
the amazing string off you scan like
reversing the entire command on the
command line and then in memory are
irreversible delimiters and split and
reassemble we can do the same thing with
a replace just say yeah pull those
garbage delimiters out I don't want
those again all happening in memory we
can also just do any kind of crazy
concatenation that we want to do and all
of these are interesting the thing to
keep in mind here is that each layer of
this string off eustachian we
be result of the entire command it will
be resolved in script lock logs for
every single rapper of string off you
station you'll have a separate script
lock log for each of those so now
wouldn't it be awful if someone wrote a
tool just to like automate this the only
one can do it so more or less that's
what I did a year ago to teach myself
and to have a nice way to test my
detections I've heard that some people
will use this offensively so my
apologies for that unfortunately there's
no good way to give this information and
tooling to the good guys so everyone is
is fair game it seems but you can just
produce this exact same download cradle
and a click of a button have it be
something like this you could then say
after this token off you station let me
go for that string off you skatin and
produce something like this now this is
unfortunately stuff we see quite a bit
especially most recently with apt 32
which is the Vietnamese attack group
also known as ocean Lotus and they
actually do about five six or seven
layers of string off you station after
the token layer off you station so I've
I've decoded a lot of my own work
recently which I get a lot of dirty
looks in the office for that but uh it
is what it is I suppose now in boat
cradle crafter will take a different
spin on off you station
you don't actually perform substitution
off you station to produce something
like this instead of taking download
string and putting tick marks are
concatenating it'll basically enumerate
all the methods for the net that web
client class and then choose whichever
one will resolve the download string and
so this is the kind of syntax you get
with cradle crafter you can also do
something like this
100% of special characters now I cannot
take credit for this back in 2010 a
Japanese researcher with a handle amudha
Gucci came up with this and they wrote
hello world and I really want to meet
this person someday because it's just
fantastically brilliant how they came up
with this but again 100% special
characters if you have PowerShell script
block logs this will resolve to about
three different layers and it's insanely
easy to detect a couple of those layers
but if you don't have that and this is
what you're dealing with then that's
really sucky right and this is mainly
just a lot of variables and the variable
names are composed of special characters
what you could also do is make those
variable names different links of
whitespace and come up with something
like that and back in Jane
I was talking with with Casey Smith or
subti and he looked at this and laughed
and said oh this reminds me of a
whitespace encoding and I said what is
that that sounds amazing and so he
explained it to me and so then I went
off and started writing and that's the
second one which is white spaced have
encoding so you can see a tick mark at
the very beginning and this whole
section is either white spaces delimited
by tabs or tabs delimited by white
spaces and the stuff at the end
basically decodes that and invokes it
again this will show up in several
layers and script lock logs but it's
actually pretty easy to detect if you
have those logs so for the blue teamers
out there I share this feeling with you
every day is there any hope well
fortunately I'm only halfway through my
time a little over 1/2 so let's get to
the good news for us defenders how can
we actually possibly expect to detect
this stuff so we're going to try a
little science so as a human we can look
at this and say this is not healthy code
this is really abnormal no one would
look at this in their environment and
say yep let's just let that go on
through unnoticed this is really crazy
and so as a human if we can see that how
can we have a system a machine look at
this and say this does not feel normal
so a year ago after I released the mocha
coffee station Leigh Holmes kind of how
he first met was he released this blog
post about a month later on detecting
off he skated PowerShell code and he
actually took some of the samples from
generated from my tool and what he did
was he took all the scripts on the
Posche co.org the PowerShell script
sharing platform and he looked at using
a kind of a baby step of science and
saying what if we just look at character
frequency analysis because there's a lot
of weird characters here especially that
guy if 100 percent of your script of
special characters like that's not
healthy right so how can we actually
look at this in a lot of scripts and so
on the right you'll see all the scripts
in posh code these are the average
character frequency for the scripts e ta
R and you'll see the dollar sign is the
very first special character that comes
up
3% on average of any given powershell
script on the left we have those other
two samples very different 20% tick
marks obviously this is all special
characters so visually we can look at
this even and say yeah these look very
different but again at scale how can a
system know that these are different so
we come to a math e slide cosine
similarity
I won't nerd out too much but basically
cosine similarity this was really cool
so basically if you have two different
lines points on the line let's say you
have two points point a and B and then
another a and B for two different lines
that have angles like this cosine
similarity o is basically saying just as
you can look at the angle between two
different lines you can say how similar
they are so lines like this are gonna be
a bit more similar but like this is
really different right and you can
extend this concept to three dimensional
lines or four dimensions or maybe
dimensions to take into account all the
characters in the alphabet that you may
see in a powershell script so that's
what we did in this blog post as he
basically used this cosine similarity to
say let me take all the lists of were
called features which are basically just
the count and the percentage of all
these characters and then compare each
script to the average of everything in
posh code and as you can see most of the
healthy normal scripts are very very
close to the value of one they're like
almost topped out as yeah this looks
really normal but then we have our two
samples down here at 15%
37% really low and if you do a scatter
plot on this all the scripts and posh
code you'll see that most all of them
are in the 90th percentile and then
these ones at the bottom this may be
worth looking at and so if you have
thousands of scripts like this like I
think 3,500 scripts is what this was at
the time then instead of looking at
3,500 scripts you could just say let me
take everything below 60 70 % and now
you're looking at a couple dozen scripts
you've greatly reduced the data you have
to go through to manually look for evil
however to do this properly we needed
more data than just 3,000 scripts so
last year Microsoft ran a contest called
underhanded PowerShell for people in the
community to submit underhanded or
you skated PowerShell to try to get
around a certain check they're
performing but we really needed a
massive corpus so over the past several
months we assembled to the best of our
knowledge the largest PowerShell corpus
and actually released it as part of our
research and the important thing that we
wanted to convey is that since Lee and I
are about the gentleman when we only
built this corpus we did it politely now
what do I mean by that well Lee went out
and wrote a script starting with github
to scrape all the PowerShell projects
out of github and as you'll see the blue
portions are the code that actually
retrieves the contents and all that read
this is actually Canadian so Lee is
Canadian and he's so polite and this is
like throttling and stuff like that to
make sure that we're not actually
pounding get Hubbs resources so um Leith
looked at all the the github project IDs
and it was up to ten million and so he
basically started this and after a month
we were almost at ten million and then
it got to 11 million and twelve million
and he was like this doesn't make any
sense
there was only ten million and they went
back and look he's like oh my gosh just
a hundred million and so instead of
instead of waiting an entire year to
finish scraping politely what he did was
he just politely asked github if there
was a way that they could tell us all
the Power Cell projects and github was
awesome they basically ran a query
zipped up all the PowerShell projects
and handed it to us and so big prompts
you to get home so I think the most
polite thing is the first ask the people
with the data and a lot of times they're
really open to sharing it with you all
public data of course so I'll just like
to say thank you to every single
contributor of PowerShell scripts to
github TechNet posh code PowerShell
gallery has anyone here ever contributed
a PowerShell script to any of those
platforms you should raise your hand
awesome thank you so much because
without you this research will not be
process possible and your name is
actually on this slide and it's also
embedded in the code and some fun places
I'll talk about later so so now we have
all these scripts and now what do we do
with all these scripts well we look at
them a lot of times people will think
you know hacking culture is really cool
you have a hoodie and you know typing
away and smoke and fog everywhere but
this is actually like a lot less cool
than that
just like a notepad window pops up and
say yeah that one's kind of off you
skated you know Martha's off you skated
close that pop-up the next one but in
doing that we look at some interesting
stuff some of the stuff we found was
just really sad like this example remove
game's ps1 this is a real script out
there someone wrote to basically killed
processes for any games running on a
system and then removed the game's
directory major buzzkill but in all
seriousness some of the stuff was
actually a bit heavier that we came
across this next one we actually had to
kind of pause our research for a bit and
figure out how to handle and it was
filling up the US House and Senate
servers with we don't want SOPA Stop
Online Piracy Act so some interesting
stuff you'll find you look through that
mini scripts but it's fascinating to
look at at like real people wrote all
these scripts and so there's just this
crazy amount of information stored in
here so how many scripts did we get four
hundred and eight thousand scripts over
28,000 authors and and we also
contributed about four thousand of our
own randomly off you skated versions of
randomly selected scripts from all those
platforms to incorporate in as well now
lead did a little a little math wizardry
here and basically said if you had a
human typing at 50 words per minute
eight hours a day didn't even take
weekends off it would take 30 years to
produce all this corpus so it's an
incredible amount of humanity
encapsulated in this corpus which is
really really cool so the important
thing here is that when you manually
label the 7,000 scripts 7,000 note paths
popping up and saying off you skated not
off you skated bad good so why did we
why don't we label all this data if you
think back at our posh code example what
we did is we took everything below let's
say 60 or 70 percent and we looked at it
and said are you off you skated are you
not how good is just using character
frequency to find evil and the thing
about this is is that what you don't get
with this metric is you don't know how
many off you skated examples did you
miss that actually fell in that 80th or
90th percentile and so when we actually
go through and manually label this data
we actually have
we have an assertive yes it's off you
skater - no it's not off you skated for
us to do future testing on which we'll
talk about in just a moment
and Ryan Cobb did some research on this
as well and you basically see this chart
here that again as you approach that
90th and 100th percentile you're gonna
get a lot more false positives but your
false negative rates go down so you have
to look dig through a lot more false
positives to find more false negatives
in your in your quest to find off you
skated evil so with the character
frequency what we get is a precision of
89% and recall 37% what this means is
that if you have a hundred thousand
scripts and let's say 10% are off you
skated so 10% if I run this script and
it says all right here's of all these
hundred thousand scripts a thousand of
them are off you skated let's say it was
right about every single one of those
then the precision is a hundred percent
everything this script told me was bad
it is truly bad but the recall would
only be 10% it missed 90% of the evil
out there and so these two scores are
related and really important and it's
what goes into what's called this f1
score and with this model we had two
percent false positive rate so I wonder
if we can do better so Lee and I asked
this question and we figured that we
could so Power Cell is a language it
knows how to interpret our shell code
and so as you can see here in this
command power shell can tokenize it and
say yep get command this is called a
generic token the name is a parameter
left parentheses the format operator etc
but what power shall also knows and what
became available in powershell 3 and
later is the relationship of each of
these into a tree which is called the
abstract syntax tree or AST and so now
we not only know what are all the types
we also know the relationship to each
other so not only do we know that this
is an array of a thousand characters but
we also know what every one of those
characters is and if one of those is
also another array and how they're how
everything correlates back to the
overall script I really find an easy way
to explore AST is through this ast
Explorer
which you can just run the very top
install module show PSA st and then i'll
grab it from the powershell gallery it's
just a nice way to kind of explore
what's there so what we did was said you
know what instead of just getting data
points from character frequency analysis
what if we got like a lot more so we did
is we pulled for any input powershell
commander script first we look at the
distribution of aft types
what percentage variables are there in
this entire script and what percentage
of the entire script is variables so for
every one of these we have a count and a
percentage so how many variables
commandlets are raised if your entire
script is you know hundred thousand
characters and 99 percent script is a
single array that's pretty weird
and so all these kinds of things we
weren't specifically looking to say this
is a threshold we think is bad we are
purely just saying give me the features
extract as much as we possibly can we
looked for the distribution of operators
like how many assignment operators
binary operators unary operators etc
look at a race size range it's again a
radius of one to ten characters that's
interesting what about 5000 that's a bit
more interesting and then for each one
of these for the character distribution
stuff that that Li did last year he just
took the entire script well that gives
an attackers a huge window just to pad a
lot of stuff in there to throw off your
detection but we're actually doing this
per type so we'll take all the strings
and do character frequency analysis all
the commands all the functions all the
comments etc and we do way more than
just frequency analysis we also look for
entropy we look for length for all those
the min max average median mode range we
look for white space density character
casing all that stuff and so we ended up
with is for any input command or script
we have almost 5000 features which we
were really excited about first and then
thought well how do we deal with 5000
features what how do we actually have
this help us find off you stated
PowerShell so what we do is something
like this we have for every PowerShell
script we extract 5000 features and then
we also would like to have another list
to say how important their each of these
features some of these are more
important than others that's why you see
up here we basically have these weights
are this weighted vectors what the
information retrieval community calls it
however figuring
which of these features are more
important than others how do we do that
that's not something me and Lee just
figured out and tuned every single one
of these 5000 well there's a way that we
can be a little smarter about it for all
these values we use what's called the
the logic function to basically instead
of having these values that are like
thousands or hundreds the logit function
cramps everything down to say everyone
is playing between 0 & 1 and that's what
kind of brings all these points together
and then we also use a linear regression
which is the weights how I was talking
about basically taking every single
feature multiplying that by its
corresponding weight and then adding all
those together and then there's a number
when you add all those multiplied
features together and if it's above this
number then it's bad if it's below it
then it's good and that was the the bias
that you see at the very beginning so
basically when it comes down to it if
the result of all these multiplications
is 1 it's off you skated if it's less
than that it's not off you skated so all
these features the way that we decide
the weight of all these features is
through this basically we run we take
our label data set this is where that
comes back into play and we run it
through all these feature extractions
and run it against all these at the
beginning all the weights for the exact
same and then at the end for every
single run it'll say hey was I correct
or not because member we've labeled this
data and if it's correct everything's
good if it's incorrect if it said hey
you're off you skated but it's not then
what it does is it says okay which
weights were the wrongest
well the weights that contributed most
heavily to this we're gonna tune those
down the most and the weights that were
the least we're gonna tune those down
the very least and so you go through
thousands and thousands of iterations of
this and it basically is figuring out
which weights are more important than
others and at the end you get 5,000
weights one for each one so now does
this work well we're pretty excited with
these results with this linear
regression and gradient descent what we
got is 96% precision
94% recall and false positives or 1% so
compared to the character analysis alone
we just increased our chances of finding
obviated content by 10 times and we cut
in half for false positives
this is really exciting stuff for us so
another thing to keep in mind is that
sometimes you may be interested in
casting a wider net
maybe there's stuff that is not as off
you skated as you'd like to know right
off the bat but it's still just like
sketchy so for example this thing on the
left obviously this is not good news
all special characters that's crazy but
on the right you know like maybe like
there's using those deaf the - f former
operators maybe if I had the world's
best intern I would like that intern to
say hey you just like take a second look
at this one this looks kind of weird and
so we basically included sketchy stuff
into a separate training and in the tool
you can actually define deep for like
deep inspection and you'll get more
results back so you'll have to look
through more false positives but if you
want to cast a wider net that's totally
an option there and and there's the
sketchy column there of the results from
that again the slides are online I'm
gonna kind of keep pressing forward Lee
did look at some other algorithms to use
and he basically just took all this CSV
data that we produced for all these
features and just threw it up into Azure
machine learning studio and ran through
a couple other ones the one that came
the closest was the boosted this is the
boosted decision tree algorithm but and
the end the gradient descent that we
used was actually the very best and so
it was kind of cool after the fact to
use some of these tools to validate our
manual findings so demo time so anyone
who knows me knows that I love ASCII art
and this function has nothing to do with
finding evil it's literally just my
chance to put some ASCII art into the
project and so it's just looking at a
command at the top and then kind of
showing you a sneak peek of how deep we
can go with extracting these features on
average it takes less than 300
milliseconds for any command or script
to extract all the features perform that
weighted multiplication and then decide
is it off you skated or not as you'll
see here it looks very very similar to
the invoke off eustachian and cradle
crafter menus you can type tutorial
which is literally the readme but it has
really pretty colors so if you want to
do that you can check that out fun facts
again we spent a lot of time going
through a lot of data and there's some
interesting things that you find in
there so we put some fun facts in there
for you too
check out nice little random fun fact
also since I love ASCII art when you
look through thousands and thousands and
thousands of scripts you find other
people also like ASCII art so if you
want to see a random sampling of really
interesting ASCII art that we found just
check that out we can also look at a set
of fun quotes and then also credits so
again every single github contributor
that has contributed a PowerShell
project as of a couple months ago your
name is literally embedded in this
script and you can randomly look at
contributors we actually have a sub list
of our favorite names there's some
really creative names out there so again
this has nothing to do with finding evil
it's just me expressing my creativity so
if you don't care about any of that
then just don't run the function called
Revo Confiscation run one of these two
functions the first one is get our vo
script block our vo is the prefix forget
Revo confiscation but basically a lot of
people don't have a directory with
400,000 powershell scripts sitting
around and ideally you want to know
what's running in my environment so most
people if they have powershell script
block logging enabled how do you
actually extract those scripts from
script block logs because when you have
really long scripts they can be logged
over tens or even hundreds of different
script block log entries so what we did
is we just wrote this function to go
through and you can just query in memory
get win event from all your systems or
just look at raw EVT x files pipe it
into this function it will extract and
reassemble all the scripts for you so
even if you don't have a sim even have
any of that stuff if you get powershell
5 out to your systems enable that log
then you can query it in memory where
the zero indexing cost anywhere and then
just pipe it into this function it'll
basically dump out all the unique
scripts that you have so once you have
that then brings you to the second
function the real function which is
measure rvo obfuscation and that is that
chewing through and determining off you
skated versus not obfuscated as you can
see it's pretty quick even with really
large scripts and again this is doing
all the feature extraction if all those
5,000 features doing 5,000
multiplications adding them up seeing go
or no go and then the results this whole
project is done in formal powershell
object-oriented stuff so everything else
comes back as objects all the the exact
script that hit the hash of it is it off
you skated how long it took to extract
the features how long it took to measure
the features and then all of the 5,000
features are all there now as an
operational guy it was really important
that this not just be something that
researchers can use but that you as
defenders on the job can take this back
immediately and use it today so we did
is we built in some pretty verbose are
pretty robust whitelisting so that you
can basically say okay as I go through
my environment these scripts are v is
off you skated yeah they actually look a
little sketchy but I know they're good
so I must drag those over into the
whitelist folder and it will hash them
and it will never alert you on that
exact hash again you can also whitelist
by strings regex which I would be
caution caution to you to just be
careful what you put in there but again
we wanted to make it an option for
people so with all that being said
there's a lot of crazy office Gatien
stuff out there but there are new ways
to detect against it as a defender it's
still very very very important that we
look for indicators of compromise look
for the non off you skate stuff you know
was bad go download Empire today and run
it and see what does this look like by
default ifs kiddies are using this I
want to be able to catch them
cobalt strike there's a lot of just
awesome frameworks out there that you
can get your hands on and start to I
don't want to say Sig but that's exactly
what you're doing because low-hanging
fruit is still fruit nonetheless then
after you're feeling good about that
look at the obfuscated stuff and see how
can i implement something like this to
look for AA few skated scripts or
command-line arguments a couple of the
references up here I mentioned a few
these before if you've never read
PowerShell hearts the blue team it's a
blog and white paper by the PowerShell
team it is a phenomenal resource that is
continually being updated so yeah that's
that's the end of my talk thank you very
much
[Applause]
it and I did want to emphasize one more
time really quickly Holmes I'm really
sad he couldn't be here but the guy's
awesome and this this project would not
have been anything without him so a
really a big shout-out to Leon this is
he's he's mostly responsible for
Marshall yeah yep one of the original
PowerShell developers so he knows it
pretty well basically the reason why
this is a problem from the beginning but
we we have we started with a very
love-hate relationship but we've hugged
it out and and we're on good terms so so
yeah yeah is it yeah something about if
you're not part of the problem good
money to be made in prolonging the
problem was I he has no sympathy when I
tell him I'll Leo I just spent the past
three hours decoding all this stuff he's
like do you make your bed you lay in it
you know
well fair point fair point but you know
and all right questions from the
audience regarding character
distribution I think it could be quite
easily compensated for by just naming
any variable with a proper distribution
yes would cover the script also the same
thing for objects like if you too many
variables put in some other stuff there
to get skipped to have a normal
distribution
yeah isn't how we do detect that yeah
that's a really good point so yeah it as
an attacker I don't have to use
randomized variable names randomized
casing I can make it look as legit as
possible and the challenge there is to
evade this detection is you're gonna
have to make every single thing look
legit even the percentages of those
things so again let's say that you have
90 percent of your script is variables
even though they're named normal stuff
that's a lot of your script to just be
variables and so you basically have to
evade every single one of these is it
possible to evade this absolutely the
ways to counter that is to basically
produce samples that evade it and then
throw those into the labeled bucket and
then spend all of five minutes free
running the learning and he produced a
slightly modified vector and then plug
that right in and so it's a really good
question and honestly one of the big
reasons that we open-source all this
including the corpus and everything so
that anyone can take it and actually
make those modifications even say hey
like I found this new way that you can
actually have this stuff and it actually
gets by and then you can actually feed
that right into the the loop and then
adjust that wait until it detects it in
your environment so we're always open to
people and pull requests and ideas and
stuff like that but we really want it to
be a community project so that people
can find these ways around it and then
and then update it but I like the way
you're thinking though I thought it was
quite obvious that you start by with the
cradle craft or thing and then you do
the remote obvious keishon at the
obfuscation window isn't it natural that
the next thing the next tool you're
gonna make is something that
automatically makes obfuscated code look
legit so that you can do talk about that
yeah and then you can do people most
people I talk to when they see the name
Revo confiscation they ask me oh I'm so
glad you made something to do if you
skate all this stuff and I'm really
sorry that's not what this does and it
it's a hard problem it really is the
best deal few skater out there is
PowerShell logging because it's going to
remove everything except for that last
layer of tokens of token layer off you
station there's some really clunky
scripts that I've thrown together and
I've done it taking a couple stabs at
I've never really been satisfied enough
with it to show anyone else that code at
some point I probably will pick up at
pick it up again the honestly my hope is
that someone else will do it instead
because yeah it just it makes my brain
hurt just thinking about it but so if
anyone is interested in in writing ways
to diiie off you see that stuff I'll
gladly share all the samples that I've
been working on and the failures I've
made to hopefully kind of let you avoid
making those same mistakes but that
would be awesome so sadly that doesn't
exist today but any more questions from
the audience all the way in the back Ron
Thomas no my only reaction when I was
looking at this is like why thank you
and if you want to fix it why wouldn't
you like go in and fix
isn't it obvious what the problem is you
mean right she needs to go if you know
you mean like a mixed version of
PowerShell maybe should not give people
this yeah that that's a very common
question especially to leave like you
helped write it why in the heck did you
make it be able to do all this stuff and
at the end of the day you look at any
language and you can do crazy stuff like
this
maybe not all maybe not every language
is this extent but there are very
legitimate reasons to use escape
characters and stuff like that
in concatenated things it's extremely
powerful and there's not really a super
easy way to say like your intention is
bad and this thing you're doing so again
the thing to keep in mind is this is not
saying good bad this is saying off you
skated not off you skated so a lot of
times we'll see legitimately off you
skated stuff as part of like code golf
competitions or something but yeah at
the end of the day you don't want to
neuter the language for this fringe case
because attackers will still find a way
is to abuse it
but yeah the question in the back
yeah very much from the stop doing
science slide until the demo slide
uh-huh what kind of language agnostic so
have you had any ideas to try to check
other languages other than PowerShell
and will you be back next year with no
it's a really good question and from the
very beginning Lee and I discussed this
as well can we apply this exact same
logic to other languages the the answer
is the simple answer is yes but the
thing is is that the huge benefit we get
here is that PowerShell is ast is what
really enables us to extract those 5000
features quite easily so I think it
comes down to how robust the languages
you're trying to detect office keishon
in so I think JavaScript would probably
be a number a close second to look at as
well but really it doesn't quite have
the same feature extracting capabilities
just because that ast isn't exposed in
the same way that being said there's a
lot of other ways you can extract
features just looking at you know common
you know objects or function names are
kind of well I think it's called a bag
of words and basically saying these are
all features I care about but at that
point it's al it's not quite as it's not
quite as agnostic as what
was but I'm really hopeful that people
will see this in rise that it's actually
not insanely difficult it's just a bit
time-consuming the most important part
is extracting all those features trying
to do that in a really fast way and then
having labeled data data that is off you
stated that you can say this is labeled
as office cater to this is not those are
the two main things and after that the
last part is just plugging that
information together so really good
question again I hope other people are
interested in pursuing this with other
languages as well because I think
there's a lot of value there more
questions no all right so Thank You
Daniel thank you very much
[Applause]