so this is a challenge that I wanted to
solve today oh now the colors are gonna
wear it again Oh we'll have to we'll
have to do it anyway
so this is the one I wanted to solve or
show you walk through up today but
nuttiest wouldn't let me because
apparently this is a challenge from this
year's Def Con and apparently everybody
hasn't had a opportunity to solve it yet
so I'm gonna do last year's instead
which looks like this that picture is
like unreadable but for fortunately for
us the challenge creators posted a
better image on Twitter so this is what
it looked like and as a good chef
I've prepared earlier a transcription so
that we don't have to waste time on that
so I'm going to you you guys see that or
do you mean do we need to make it bigger
perhaps whoops too big there we go so
the first thing I did was just try to
print this out in a little bit bigger
I'm actually I'm gonna do this instead
so oops
yeah so print this out something like
this two characters at a time just to
have a look at what it would look like
so something like this would probably do
it so let's have a look at what that
looks like okay so since it's supposed
to be a message and we can see that it's
0 through 9 we'd probably have to use
more than one digit per symbol right but
this doesn't really look like anything
that's there are lots of repeats and
yeah it doesn't look very
very promising so let's try three
characters instead plus two and let's
see the repeats were probably me being
stupid so let's do that
okay so now we're I'm just printing out
the digits three at a time well this
looks more promising we can definitely
see some patterns here we can see
recurring number thirty-two you can see
this all these digits up until the point
anyway all seem to be within this
interval of like 32 120 which is
printable ASCII characters right so we
can pretty much guess this this is gonna
be like 71 is going to be a character
for example so we can try printing out
the character so let's see this and
change just concatenating those three
digits and turning them into an integer
and then let's convert that into a
character let's see if that works yeah
that looks pretty good as you can see
this string that we're getting here well
first of all we could see that we have
some digits here that don't really match
up and if we look at the picture we can
see that those digits are the ones here
in blue so that pretty much tells us oh
by the way the red ones here you can
actually just read off it says welcome
to the challenge but the blue ones
probably don't have anything to do with
the yellow message so I'm gonna split
that out so I'm just gonna take the
just the yellow digits just put dollar
in there instead let's see if that
solves our problem yeah now we can see
the whole message so I'm going to
instead of printing this I'm gonna
create a string call it D for decoded
and then print the string at the end
right oops did I do something wrong
there Oh me stupid me stupid
there we go okay so this doesn't look
like English but it does suspiciously
look like rotated English right so I'm
going to guess that this is probably our
old friend rot13 commonly used to
obfuscate text right ah this is a red
herring but you're probably going to
figure this out okay
which means we're on the right track so
let's do the same trick but let's take
instead of the yellow characters let's
take the blue characters and once you do
this you kind of figure out that the
light blue and the dark blue characters
go to are two separate messages so I'm
not going to show how you figure that
out but that's that's what you get okay
let's see what I'm doing here I'm doing
something wrong there we go so what does
the blue message says brought to you by
Caesar Alma sensoric so those are
challenge craters nice let's see the
dark blue characters if we take them use
the same trick we'll see ah this is
interesting this is again not English
but we can cut and paste this into a
file that's called a test
and as you can see from this part over
here
it looks like a URL right it's formatted
like that so we can pretty much guess
since these two DS here repeat this is
gonna be like a simple substitution
cipher where the HTTP has been turned
into QD DL so just start decoding this
manually HTTP and let's see do we have a
D anywhere yeah so that's also gonna be
a T do we have an L somewhere no not
really we have a Q or we have a Q over
here so that's gonna be an H we have a D
that's gonna be a T yeah but it doesn't
give us much of the message right so we
start we have to start guessing a bit so
since this is a URL you can probably
guess that this is gonna be a TLD which
is a common Tod let's like a dotnet
maybe comm is the most common one so
let's just guess 4.com and if we can say
the K becomes C then actually this
becomes C C which would make sense more
than that this becoming it URL that
starts with n n dot something because
the Challenger was called the Caesars
challenge so CC would probably be you
know a reasonable guess there so what
guess for comm which means we have two
to three news new characters we can
start decoding so let's say you have a
kg or an A we have a G over here that's
gonna be a no we have the Q here I've
forgotten earlier we have
we have an a No am I missing something
here there's a tee at the beginning yep
that's right yes okay so we have to
start guessing some more so look at the
message it starts with DQ e x and then e
x so we can pretty much guess that this
one letter word is probably gonna be an
a that's the most common one letter word
in English this is probably going to be
like is yeah exactly front row has got
it already so which means this is right
so this looks very similar to the
previous message that this is this is a
red herring was the first message we got
from the yellow text so maybe we can
make a guess that this is not a red
herring right and it kind of looks
we've got repeating ours here the B
becomes an EE
so this is our guess and it's it looks
to be a pretty good guess because it
ties in with the yellow message and it
also gives us most of the characters we
need to solve the URL so we just have a
get have a look at this the F becomes a
G the G becomes an O the O becomes an
and the be sure about or are we it's an
e yeah so we still have some letters
here that we're unsure of yeah so i j j
is over here as well and you I J and you
we don't really know what what they're
supposed to be in the decoded message
but since this is a URL it's I mean we
can we can look up possible candidates
in DNS and see if if we find something
right so let's take this thing here and
for a in hello I'm just got a couple
pace to make this a bit easier so these
are the letters that we haven't solved
for already so we don't have to try a B
we don't have to try the whole alphabet
we just have to look up the the
characters that we haven't found yet so
let's do this
yep do for B in and do for C in there we
go and I'm just doing good echo first I
usually do that to test and host and oh
no we did add the test file over there
so this was our decoded stuff and then
we have to put some guesses in there so
we had one guess was over here let's see
if I can remember where stuff is in on
my keyboard see and this was B and then
we had two so we had a then C again
right because we had repeating J so IJ u
J so I J I type J stupid me i Ju
yeah and this this will take a couple of
of minutes that we don't actually have
so I'm gonna since it says 1000 I'm
gonna guess that the C is probably gonna
be a Y so something like technology was
my guess there so I'm gonna put Y first
in the alphabet there let's see dun dun
we forgot one do over here right I'm
just gonna I'm just going to go for it
and this is gonna give us a lot of
output so I'm going to filter out with
grep the ones that don't resolve the
domains that don't resolve so that's
running let's make sure actually have
internet here as well that might have
been a good idea
first no we actually don't have okay
excuse me to switch over here and try to
find it my Wi-Fi there we go so let's do
that again now that we probably have
yeah now we have Internet
okay so now it's running and it's trying
all the different combinations to fit
these last few letters in hopefully it's
gonna work yeah there we have bite
Knology and then we can have a look over
here CC dot bite knowledge calm and we
can see two more cryptograms here and i
only have like a minute for this so it's
gonna have to be really really quick so
we have true cryptograms over here and
this one is actually quite simple
you can see that these are all like
common letters in the English language
but they're put in some kind of weird
order right we have got all the tea all
the eyes together and E's together here
and stuff like that but we saw the the
the challenge hint was a five-pointed
star so if you put these into five
groups of five we can start to see ah
already the user name is legion
something so that's just a simple
columnar transposition cipher and the
other one that we don't have time for
I actually didn't solve because it was
quite tricky but the challenge
organisers tweeted out a hint that it
was supposed to say it was a common
phrase and it was supposed to start with
all and then I could pretty much figure
out from the theme that it was supposed
to start with all roads lead to Rome
right because we have this Legionnaire
theme in the username and so I kind of
solved it without actually knowing what
the
what the crypto mechanism was so but
that was the end of that challenge
basically if you want to see proof that
it's the end of the challenge we can go
here it says to put the username as and
then all roads lead to Rome without the
X's X's we're just padding and then we
get congratulations you found your way
the party is tonight
bla bla bla bla so that was all I wanted
to show you
[Applause]