thank you thank you tonight we are going
to use evil devices in order to perform
direct memory access attacks
my name is all frisk and helping me with
the demos I have the Pieta Noreen thank
you
today we are going to bust file vault
open we are going to totally own Mac OS
Windows and Linux by DNA code injection
we're going to dump memory at speeds in
excess of 150 megabytes per second we're
going to mount live file systems we're
going to do some live memory forensics
we're going to execute code and spawn
system shells
my name is old frisk I'm working as a
penetration tester primarily with online
banking security I'm employed in the
financial sector here in Stockholm
Sweden the Master of Science in computer
science and engineering and I previously
presented my work at Def Con last year I
did a demo lab there at this year's Def
Con and I also presented here at sakti
last year and I'm interested in
low-level programming and DMA I need to
point out that this is a personal
project of mine my employer is not
involved in any way whatsoever I'm here
to present PCL each PCL each is the
plx technologies USB 3380 development
board coupled with a custom farmer and a
custom software on image here you see
the PCL each device or the USB 3380
development board in this mini piece
Express form factor to left you have the
PCI Express side which goes into the
target computer or if you wish to call
it the victim computer once connected
the USB 33 8 to ship is able to send DMA
reads and writes over PCI Express
straight into the main memory of the
target computer read them right to the
main member of the toilet computer to
write you have a USB 3 collector which
allows for a connection to a controlling
computer once connected the controlling
computer is able to send commands over -
over USB - USB for 380 it's also able to
stream data at very high speeds on to
use be 3380 which done
then forwarded into the main memory of
the Tauri computer they are also able to
read the main memory of the target
computer this way in speed at speeds in
excess of 150 megabytes per second
what's really nice about this piece of
hardware that it requires no drivers at
the wall on the toriel computer really
it just works on the hardware level
unfortunately it's only capable of
32-bit addressing which means that we
will only be able to read memory below 4
jigs as we will see later on that's not
really a problem this is the same
hardware as the NSA playset slot
screamer device presented by Leo
Fitzpatrick but what makes all this
possible is of course PCI Express PCI
Express is a high-speed serial expansion
bus or it's not really a bus sinister
sense since it's point-to-point
communication it's a packet based and
peace Express endpoint devices typically
consume between 1 and 16 serial legs
depending on how much bandwidth and
device needs for example a graphics card
that requires lots of bandwidth consumes
16 serial lengths while a networking
card might consume one Lane PCI Express
is designed to be hot pluggable it
doesn't mean that what plagued always
work it's designed for it anyway and
it's capable of DMA and with DMA we mean
that an PCI Express endpoint device is
able to read and write the main memory
of the computer without passing through
a CPU core here you have a schematic of
PCI Express you have the PCI Express
route complex and code within the CPU
ship and from the route complex you have
several pieces Express serial lanes
which you can connect endpoint devices
to but you can also connect like PCI
Express switches and bridges which in
turn you can connect endpoint devices
too so you can say that piece Express
forms a small device network within the
computer and actually there is a
hardware built-in here as well in all
modern hardware and why since a few
years ago called an iommu
it's a memory management unit for
devices and this allows for the
operating system or the farmer to
actually protect
computer against evil devices as we will
see later in the presentation that's not
really the case
always anyway these are all PC Express
form factors you have the standard PCI
Express device to the lower left you
recognize it from the desktop computers
on the server you have the mini PC
Express form factor which goes behind
the back cover on older laptops pretty
much you have the Express card form
factor that goes into laptops as well
you have Thunderbolt 2 really common on
Macs and you also have Thunderbolt 3
nowadays which is often Co bundled with
USB C and you also have the different m2
key form factors shown up here and
that's newer add-on cards for more
modern laptops and also the m2 key M
it's really common for and then e drives
so let's start with a demo we're going
to totally bypass file wall to full disk
encryption by connecting an evil device
to a max Thunder both port so here we
have a Mac Peters helping way of filming
here you have it connected with the PCL
each device here connecting it to the
Thunderbolt pocket and once we connected
the PCL each device you can do this one
like a running computer it needs to be
booted it could be in sleep as well it
can't be like completely shutdown but as
long as it's in sleep or if it's yeah
locked or something like that it should
be possible to attack it just connect
the pestle each device and run the PCH
to Mac as we recover command now it says
please press command control power to
reboot the Mac let's try to do that
and now we are dumping memory doing some
analysis on the dumped memory that we
dumped off the reboot and they have a
password candidate here which is Donald
Duck should try that password and as you
can see the map is actually booting
imagine leaving your Mac in sleep or
whatever at your hotel room when you go
out for dinner or if you leave your desk
at work at lunchtime going for lunch or
whatever the cleaning lady might stop by
so what was happening here when the Mac
is starting Thunderbolt is enabled
immediately from the ball carries PC
Express which means the MA is possible
but there is no password in memories we
can't really dump anything that's not
there we need to wait until the user
actually inputs the password that the
password is in memory fortunately for
the Mac users Mac iOS has been enabling
DVD teammate protections for a really
long time so we can't really dump the
memory Mac OS is secure but what happens
if we reboot the computer Mac OS is no
longer running the BTD DMA protections
are dropped but the memory contents are
still around for a few seconds before
it's overwritten with new stuff and it
this is plenty of time to dump the
memory do some analysis and get the
firewall to full disk encryption
password and once you in there it's the
same password as yeah the running user
you probably have access to the cloud
services and things like that after that
as well
so I reported this to Apple in August
last year and they patched it in
December the echo bundle a major if I
upgrade together with Mac OS 10 point
well point to they did not only stop the
PC a leach DMA attack but also option
roms attacks and similar things
BT is now enabled at very early boot
for peace Express Thunderbolt is started
and Apple has been really awesome at
former security for quite some time now
and it really you can really see it in
their product now but what's interesting
is that many PC UF eyes are still likely
to be vulnerable against the main
attacks but on the max it's all fixed
now
Mac's are now totally secure Apple fixed
a few remaining glitches in March this
year and so it should be fixed totally
now but let's continue on to a another
Mac fully patched Mac and bypass DB DD
main protections we're going to unlock
the computer we are going to do some
live mounting of the file systems over
PCI Express DMA we're going to do some
live memory friend 6 not against a
dumped file but against the live memory
of the Mac itself but first we need to
disable the VD DMA protections of the
Mac then you need to boot it like really
boot it from scratch press command or to
go into something called a recovery mode
a recovery mode is not password
protected by default even if you enable
the firewall to disk encryption you can
get into it just fire up a command
prompt and type and Miron boot orgs dark
equals 0 and the BT DD man protections
of the Mac should now be disabled
forever after or until the user who
enables them again and the user won't
really get any notifications that these
ones are disabled so I prepared a little
bit so the V DD Mary protections have
been disabled on this MacBook Pro and
it's a new one with the touch bar so we
need a USB C to Thunderbolt 3 adapter to
old-fashioned Thunderbolt that we used
on the MacBook Air earlier so let's
connect the evil PCL each device
and load a kernel module it's really as
easy as that the kernel module is now
loaded on the Mac victim here
so let's mount the live filesystem do
some live memory forensics so now I
mounted the live filesystem
I also mounted the live ran as a file in
Windows so what can you do when you have
the live Ram as a file virtual file
mapped in Windows of course you can run
Valley tillage against it for example so
let's run volatility against it I'm
going to minimize that movie I think and
volatility on Windows it's a little bit
slow to start and we'll see that the RAM
read will start counting when it's
running but meanwhile we can go in to
check that drive so if you have the live
memory mounted as a file here you can
click into the files folder and you have
the entire Mac LS file system running
here running with kernel level
privileges so you can click into the
users folder for example and spy on the
users files and if you wish to copy some
files just right-click and copy
whatever it's as easy as that now we see
that it's actually counting some bytes
series as well so volatility it's
actually doing its memory analysis here
and against the live memory on the
target computer we haven't dumped any
memory really and you see that I'm just
running a Mac apiece we come out here so
we see the process listing it's really
as easy as that so we really need to get
into the Mac of course when we have
access to like this we could probably
get into it in multiple ways but let's
try to unlock the Mac that is remove the
bosphorus requirement
so here is the Mac I don't really know I
know the password on this one but we can
check that it's it's not blank anyway I
couldn't log on to that one so let's try
to unlock it I need to specify the
kernel module address as well and it
says state to zero is success so let's
see if we can log on it's just this yes
that on Mac OS PC Express and
Thunderbolt is protected by default with
vtd with the iommu
it's not possible to run the may attacks
against the running Mac OS system unless
we trample it previously but it's
possible to disable b2d in recovery mode
unless you set a something called a
firmware password on the Mac then you
can't boot into recovery mode doing it
this opens up for evil made type style
of attacks when you visit the Mac one
point of time rebooted going to recovery
mode disable the VDD my protections you
don't know the firewall password after
that one of course so you need to wait
for user to actually start the Mac again
and put into it and really visit the
computer but goal of PC elite is ready
to make DMA attacks made super easy just
download the software purchased the
hardware flash flash the hardware and
start polling mount the target file
systems as a network drive in Windows
and even the live memory click around
edit files on the target you can even
edit row' these devices and the library
and there are lots of Peace Express form
factors I mean just touches some cheap
adapters on eBay they're really easy to
find there are adapters between all the
form factors pretty much just purchase
some adapters and get going the most
expensive adapter is the Thunderbolt 2
Express card adapter but let's pound the
rest of the operating systems as well
most computers today they do have more
than 4 gigs of memory and fortunately
for us
but if we can get the kernel module into
running kernel the kernel module is able
to access all memory a kernel modules
will also be able to execute code so
what we are doing is that we can search
for signatures in the lower four jigs
with DMA and once we find the correct
signature we can patch into that part of
the memory and hijack kernel code
execution let's continue on to Windows
10 in Windows 10 the kernel is most of
the time located at the very top of the
memory which means that we can't reach
it with the PCL each device since it's
the only capable of reading the lower
four Jiggs it turns out that the page
tables and the hardware exception layer
Hal is often located below for jigs and
specially interesting is the physical
address 1000 it's offer reference at the
Hal heap but it's really the low stub
and it's containing some interesting
memory structures there and thanks Alex
UNESCO for this awesome research anyway
at the 1,000 physical address you can
find the base address of the colonel
paging table and the PML for address and
it's really interesting for us and you
can also find the virtual address of the
circle Hal heap located here so we can
search that with those two memory
contents here we can search the memory
and find some really interesting
interrupt pointers that we can overwrite
with our addresses to up to our evil
code and hijack the kernel code
execution flow that way so we are going
to do a kernel implant on Windows 10
we're going to dump the memory spawn a
system shell and also unlock the
computer so now we need a little bit of
luck as well because we understand might
sometimes angry computer
and by the way as you can see I can't
really log onto this computer with a
blank password here so let's see it
become the kernel module yeah we insert
it and the computer seems to be working
still yeah
so let's bond I system show them it's
really as easy as that
Who am I your system on that computer
damn over PCI Express and once your
system you can of course yeah do pretty
much everything you can disable
BitLocker or whatever you wish to do but
that's kind of boring so let's not do
that let's mount the live memory and the
file system like that and now we're of
course able to go into Windows Explorer
click around in the files in Windows
here you see do windows directory you
see the users folders here of course you
can click into the user folder and copy
are everything pretty much over a PC
Express it's really as easy as that so
let's log on to this computer and unlock
it as well
as I saw previously we couldn't look on
with a blank password but let's try to
log on with a blank password now
of course we can also dump the memory to
a file so let's do that
dump a memory with PCL each is usually
pretty fast it's around 150 megabytes
per second memory remember the computer
is not one big chunk of memory so it's
divided in different parts we have liked
readable normal memory they have like
memory map PCI Express devices in there
which we can't read on other addresses
we have like unreadable memory such as
system animation management mode memory
and so we need to know where the memory
locations are so we asked the colonel on
the other victim computer where those
memory regions are those ones are
reported back to the PCL each main
control program PCL each main control
program is asking the kernel module into
the target to read a specific chunk of
memory and since we are asking the
kernel module to read that specification
Cooke memory it's able to access this no
matter what it is no matter where it
were or and we write it into a memory
buffer that is 2r below for Jiggs
so the PCL each program is able to read
it with normal DMA after that yeah and
as you see we got like 149 megabytes per
second higher sorry for that but you see
we are running to a USB hub here so
that's why the speed is a little bit
lower unfortunately so that's it for
Windows we can also use other devices
than Windows to attack from PC le she's
running on Linux as well and it's also
running on Android that means you can
use it run it from an attack advice from
Android you can use a phone for that
just purchased an OTG adapter and
connect easily to OTG adapter and you're
good to go
and here I have an example of I'm owning
Windows 7 over from an Android phone
there
anyway let's attack Linux as well Linux
is enabling something called kernel
address space layer on my session
it's randomizes the kernel fully in
physical memory at least in 4.8 and
that's a problem for us since the kernel
is likely to better randomized in a part
of memory we can't read it above four
legs fortunately on Linux system MIDI is
often not enabled by default
I mean it's highly dependent on the
destroyer and things like that but on
some distresses not really enabled by
default so we can't reach the kernel
directly on those computers but we can
do we can try to locate a part of the
firmware call dua for runtime services
and patch that part of the firmware in
order to gain code execution and power
in the kernel that way so the efi
runtime services is part of do a file
the linger around after the operating
system is started it provides
functionality such as get and set the
variables rest of the system reboot it
and things like that and it turns out
that is always loaded below for gigs and
this has a really nice function
dispatcher table with the function
pointers that we can try to find it has
a really nice known signatures we can
search for it and located it and
override some function pointers in order
to gain code execution in ufi and so we
locate that table we push the function
pointer to wait for the runtime services
to trigger if Linux calls in to them we
patch the kernel down and we wait for a
kernel code execution and we have
success hopefully atleast so let's do a
demo let's mount the live filesystem on
Linux and unlock the computer by editing
e.t.c shadow last year when I talked
here at secti I used a lot of command
line stuff drivers like pulling the
files and pushing it back and things
like that so no more advanced stuff like
that this year just right click and edit
it
so here we have a Kali Linux computer
I'm actually it's a live image here so
you know the password on this one
hopefully but at least the password is
as you can see it's not working anyway
so I can't get into the computer so
let's try to trigger efi get into efi
and yet linux to trigger it
so it's searching for the eve firearms
and services table once we find it we
will patch it and it says here we need
to do ask linux to call into this efi on
time services and it's often triggered
if you like to do something on linux
system such as switch to user so let's
just press log one that's a different
user here in Cali and yeah we have a
kernel module loaded at this address
once we have the kernel module loaded of
course you know we can mount the live
filesystem so let's do that it's really
as easy as that
and once you mount the live filesystem
go in there files in dtc for a folder
you have a nice file called shadow here
yeah like that rest just right-click it
edit with notepad and in linux you have
the default password hash of tour here
in the indy shadow file and that's kind
of boring so let's replace it with the
hash of key word here and save that file
and let's see if we can get into this
Linux system now with the quirky
password
and we're in it's really as easy as that
and even funnier we can actually edit
row' these devices and things like that
in Linux for example we can open the
best DB here let's have a look at it in
our hex editor here you shall see like
ms-dos here at the top and in fat32 and
these yeah things like that then we can
write to it even and say we did
exhibitory but let's not do that let's
not destroy our file systems here today
so what can you do in order to protect
against evil devices you can keep your
Mac OS up-to-date to the most recent
version of course and set a firmware
password you should be totally secure
against these kinds of attacks you can
also purchase hardware without any DMA
ports of course if you do have the may
porch on a PC I would recommend that you
set your bios password lock down your
DMA port and also like pre-boot
authentication for example BitLocker
plus pin of course the long-term
solution is for the hardware vendors and
the operating system vendors to start
using the iommu DVD in order to protect
against the text like this Microsoft
have some really interesting stuff in
there as well with their virtualization
based security and their DMA guard that
is supposed to be coming in the full
tray to shut it so what are the use
cases for PC LH I mean everyone s I need
to know that full disk encryption is not
always invincible it's excellent for pen
testing and red teaming I know some red
teams that actually love this device
that use it all the time it's excellent
for forensics and also I would urge you
not to do any evil with my tool so when
you leave here today I want you to know
that physical access is still an issue
please be aware of your potential evil
maid attacks for example on your Mac PC
elite is really the main attacks made
super easy for everyone to use
the assertion here today and it's used
for good but I also suspect it may be
used for evil and you will find peace a
leech on my get up and also catch me on
Twitter of course have a blog as well
and also thanks to inception for some
really nice previous work in this area
and also thank you to Alex UNESCO for
the low snob research and also some some
peace elite stability improvements so
thank you thank you
[Applause]
yes thank you very much for that that
was really good and I really loved the
live demos and that actually worked
and as you said the inception are used
inception when you first knew about this
attacks you tried to do them with
inception but this actually seems so
much easier than even working inception
so yeah I tried it to make it a little
bit easier to add some new features and
of course get it to run over high-speed
PCI Express on more devices as well so
it's yeah so one of the things that I've
been doing I did some reading in years
and years and years ago when we used
inception one things they could do with
inception was to freeze the ramps from
one machine and move them to one and
then dump them where PCIe is that still
possible is this something that you
tried I guess it should be possible on
some system still and there are some
mitigations put into the most recent PC
hardware to actually protect a little
bit against the text like test but it
might work still in some cases okay so
you're saying that the Mac is more or
less patched if you on the latest level
and I've said actually a pre boot
password well the firmer password yes it
should be totally secure against might
attack surface streets and on the
windows side I mean if you're running
BitLocker with pen and the
virtualization based security with the
device guard it should be pretty secure
as well okay any questions from the
audience yes I would guess the rest of
you okay
yeah it will work but it will be dumped
the encrypted memory of course so you
can't really make any sense of it yeah
the question was for the stream was well
if you have devices they already have
encrypted memory with the attack works
and yes yeah but it will dump the
encrypted memory of course so it's for
your scenario but it's and yes I have
some attacks I patch into vulnerable
UEFI for example before Windows starting
and then you're like totally able to
totally pound the windows loader and get
from there but that's like ongoing
research here so it's might get some
news on that one unfortunately not
possible if they were actually secure
their BIOS for against me today against
the attacks any more questions from the
audience but strikes me with these
attacks is the speed but are you getting
as well it's like because now it's like
how long do you have to leave your
laptop in a hotel room for this that
should be executed it's like and that's
probably as well yeah I mean if you not
passed your Mac since December it's
really like plug it in 30 seconds later
or like a totally compromised so it's
that's your Mac ok thank you very much
[Applause]