hello everybody, welcome to the
EFf panel uuuhhm >> We are the
EFF or position of EFF who is
here to answer your questions.
My name is Kurt. I am the deputy
(audio drop) I have been doing
this for a long time before we
get to your questions we are
going to giver some brief
overviews. One thing I wanted to
do is put out ground rule. First
of all, most of you are how many
people are much with the EFF but
as you may know one of things
that we do we counsel people and
give legal advice to security
researcher and people from this
community about presentations
they are having. What is
something that we enjoy doing
but now is not the time to ask
those questions we want that
with attorney client privilege.
So if you have questions to your
situation contact us afterwards
and set up a time to talk to us.
So let me introduce who we have
here starting my right we have
Nate staff attorney with EFF and
Corine, legal director and mark
-- and Cooper who works on
technology projects and Nadia.
>> So we wanted to do something
different this year for some of
you have come to panels before
what we have done each of us
will talk about one or two
things that we work on. But I
wanted to give a little bit more
I wanted to talk everything that
we do and I had a interns
prepare the list of everything
that we do and single spaced it
would have taken me 20 minutes
the read so I will not do that
so I will give some highlights
so that you have a little bit
more of appreciation of the
scale and work that we do.
Seventeen lawyers. So it not a
big team but in the last year we
have filed more than 15 new
lawsuits including film maker
Laura -- seeks her detention
more than 50 times and we
represented a patent controlled
victim success fully and a first
time we have done a direct
representation of the context
and we sued DEA twice. We had
major development in more than a
11 of our ongoing cases about
that ranged from major brief
files to major court arguments.
In the last three years we have
done counseling engagements.
This year alone we counseled
presenters giving 10 talks at
the three conferences. And we
filed more than 30A MIC A briefs
probably something like 50 it
courts all the around the
country ranging from supreme
court to federal circuits to
state supreme court to local
courts. We testified in state
local and federal rule makings
and hearings at least eight
times in the last year. So that
those are the numbers. Fifteen
new suits 10 counseling
engagements -- >> I can talk
about a few of them because we
could not review owl of work so
I will talk about a few cases
and situations that I am engaged
in and really we have been
enjoying. The first is we filed
six exception request before the
office in the DMCA rule making
process and for those that saw
-- you will know about it but
what we had found is that we
have this law that makes it
illegal to break DRM even if you
do it for a lawful reason like
testing your security or a host
of otherwise legal things that
you want to do but you need to
break the DRM in order do it and
that is illegal unless you get
permission from the copyright
office so every three years we
get to go to copyright office
and ask a bunch of lawyers if it
is okay the technology do their
work. And this year we tried to
up the anti-because we are
seeing how different places
because we have software in so
many kind of devices to cars to
refrigerator and phone and DRM
suddenly is more necessary than
ever for us to go the library of
congress and asks permission for
you all to do the work that you
do. I wish we didn't have to do
that but we do and this round is
interesting because in
particular the exception that we
ask for which had to do with car
repair and security video game
preservation and jail breaking
not just your phone but tablets.
We aroused the interest of GM.
And John deer. Who felt
necessary to file responses to
exception to say no, no, no we
own the copyright in the
software and you can't mess with
it. So all of sudden I am
fighting John Deer in court.
Infere thought I would have to
reach out the farmers I wish I
didn't. But on the other hand I
think that way you turn the time
because you get more and people
more to that you had this area
of law is effecting them. So the
DMC rule making process is sill
in plane and we will know the
play in a couple of months. We
-- (audio drop) and the reason I
wanted to talk about these two
is because I thought this
audience would appreciate at the
pay tend that we killed one was
a competition over social
network. It is not going to work
too well. Secondly there is pay
tend only pod casting. Somebody
thinks they own that. We don't
think so and turns out we won
that one. And the victor has to
do with cloud flare and what
happening more and more is that
the entertainment companies are
running to court and get broad
injection to require providers
to a website requiring those
providers to shut down service
sites based on nothing more than
(audio drop) that same kind of
idea, the theory is if you
provide any service to website
what is doing something unlawful
you are conspiring with it.
Providing basic service like
they would to any other
customer. Basically making cloud
flare into copyright cops and
this is part of trend which is
why we were worried about it but
we got it narrowed so clear that
cloud fair does not have to be
the trademark cops. So that was
a big victory and I hope that
set president for other
situation down D line. >> I will
do this quickly because I know
people want to answer questions.
I focus on things that we are
doing on EFF. First thing is
updating privacy law right now
was a law in 1986 and it has
been for the congress. For the
first time the house has bill
sponsored by 200 members and
second one we're doing is (audio
drop) where you want the make
sure it is used encourage
security research and not skill
it and proposals we have seen is
disaster yous and not
encouraging it so working on
those two things and the third
thing we're doing and something
that going to move next month in
September combating a lot of
privacy basis sharing bills.
They didn't a lot of new
authorities for attacking users
so what we're doing now and --
with CFA amendment that is just
(audio drop). We're going the
try to kill that in the short
term. The last thing we're doing
which I think if a lots of you
follow the news in the summer
there was one part of it with
performing one of many stated
programs the last thing we're
doing is furthering looking at
surveillance laws and offering
changes in spying. Huge numbers
of mass spying and collecting
America information with
twisting interpretation so also
working to change those. >> So
in addition to legal work we do,
we do a lot of technology work.
We have several technology
projects. This year along we
have unavailable four new
technology projects. Certified
of authority. Canary watch which
was tracking -- and privy (audio
drop) in addition we have
maintained several other
technology projects such as
start TLS every where to encrypt
all of the e-mail observers. And
we have done some tech. The
super efficient -- window spy
wear and the we helped uncover
leak where you personal
information was being leaked to
third party advertiser so those
are some of technology
techniques that we do and I can
do into more details of them. >>
So in addition to litigation we
have activity vim teach. One of
things that I work on the
privacy to addressing things
that happened this year we
worked on letter to I can the
corporation that assigns domain
names so they are wanting to get
rid of privacy services for
anybody that is commercial
website and what deem commercial
is a huge range of websites they
are possible out of touch with
how people with using the
inter-intestine and why they
would want privacy so we I can
with a huge list of signatures
and was a diverse range of
people and people that were
targeted for harassment and
people concerned about security
and it was we think that it had
a good effect that time I have
sort of dialed back on saying
they are going to get rid of
privacy services and we happy to
say that and we think they need
to be more responsive. In
addition to that we worked on
the Facebooked real name policy
so this is something that a lot
of people are seeing this year
they get kicked off of Facebook
and used as a way to shut people
up and get them off of Facebook
so people like international
activist or people in Vietnam
use that as platform for
blogging to political and drag
queens are getting kicked off
even though they use names they
use in everyday life just huge
range of people so we keep
pushing on that. Another
pro-correct we have surveillance
self defense so on we put --
play list which are list of
tools that we think would be
helpful for specific groups so
we have play list for youth for
people working on human rights
and we added more new tools and
do trainings and I would say
this year we trained people how
to use encryption. In addition
to -- that I'm excited about is
street level surveillance that
so project when we'll go out
therein a talk to people who may
be don't have knowledge about
surveillance they are thinking
about (indiscernible) and they
thinking that it is something
far away, that maybe it is
something hey should be
concerned about but in the last
couple of years we are see
proliferation of technology in
the hands of local law
enforcement so street level
surveillance is gave -- we want
it to be something that people
use to take issue in their own
hands so we have partnership
with (indiscernible) you should
check them out. They have made
it possible for thousands of
people to file public records at
request. So we have partnership
with them to help people file
PRAs on the use of -- and we
have talking points for activist
and adding more and we are
highlighting legal work that we
have done. We got a case
accepted to California court and
public records act case around
the use of automated license --
so automatic license plate users
is sort of privacy catch 22. If
you can't get public record
request you are not going to
know how. It's invasive they are
and if they are being miss used
and the information deal was lot
of information about the license
plates being tracked. That is
why we want to make it public
what is being revealed just like
with a lot of surveillance. So
really excited today see that
case go the California supreme
court and lot of legislation at
the state level on license plate
readers and whether that
information can we requested
under the state public record
law so we think this case is
going to be important. And A RBC
are couple technologies that we
have information on but string
rays and drones and shots you
name it going to end up on that
website because we think it is
important for people to have
this information in front of
them so keep it short. >> Where
are we going to have the
question. If you have a question
we will start to line here. Come
forward with your questions and
the others sort of -- ask me
anything. So we're looking
forward to hearing from you. >>
I'm curious on privacy -- some
other actors in the space has
gone out against transparency
perhaps I want to make a website
and I don't want to tell the
word. It is my website. Are
there places where -- how do you
manage cases like that where
there is public interest in
transparency how you balance
those. >> (indiscernible) I
think this is interesting
question and hard to answer. I
think that certificate
transparency is important of I
will some problem was CA system.
A couple and I think that the
benefit that we get from
certificate transparency and
knowing the SSL certificate that
you site is encrypted with is
the one that it is supposed to
be encrypted with is pretty
strong. Maybe there are some oh
work for that. I think the
benefits of CT out way the
privacy concerns. I don't know I
have not done much research on
that topic. You can ask Peter, I
will throw him under the bus on
that one. >> So back in may
there was a circuit court ruling
that surveillance said it wasn't
authorized by the pat trout acts
and say everything is fine were
more or less surveillance and
congress reauthorized the
inspiring section. I hope you
guys could provide context how
it would play out in the courts
will that go to supreme court or
how can congress
(indiscernible). >> So on the
first part, yes, there was a
good ruling about section 215 of
the pat trot act and what the
government had been doing was
illegal. It was not saying that
it was unconstitutional but that
argument was made. That circuit
court decision was not binding
outside of that circuit so it is
not enough that that happened to
require this court the a bide by
that and then things got further
complicated by the passage of
United States freedom which
changed the language of statute
that had prior been the court
interpreted to say they could
noted do the program so think
about program under the new
statute and how that is going to
play out in congress Mark do u
with want the stay something. I
think the questions how it is
going the play out when you have
two court decisions. I think now
we have continuation of program
and we're going to go into this
narrow program. I would be
interested on where
(indiscernible) as well as if
those cases are ongoing because
a part of that we is what
happens to current court cases.
So there are a number of
different cases out there which
where challenging wire taping
program and several ACLU versus
clapper which had section 215
decision. And there are other
ones out there. There is Smith
Obama which was a case what
brought by a practitioner
attorney on behalf of his wife
as the client but adverse
decision at that court level.
That was heard in December so we
have a number of cases ongoing
and have to determine a couple
of thing going forward. The main
question is this
unconstitutional. Goes beyond
the wounds of what was
acceptable under the four
amendment. And your write of
associate. Those will remain
ongoing but for the aspects of
these challenges where it a
focused on statutory language
that has been changed by
modification of United States
freedom. So the originally
statute 215 it was thought to be
the library division. They get
library book records and things
that authorized through the
investigation and through secret
law by courts that were not
known to anybody they determined
that everything is relevant to
authorized investigation which
make irrelevant dead letter.
They expanded the understanding
of in tangible things. It was a
ongoing daily dump of the phone
records prospectively. So their
interpretation was wrong and
that is the problem that does
secret interpretation. So they
changed some of that language
through United States freedom
and came up with a different
system where communication
companies would hold on the
records and starting in six
months they use a different
system to get them and so when
you have statutory challenge and
there is little bit of
procedural monkey wrench and we
have been providing briefing to
court and what the effect open
United States freedom. Those
cases have been doing on for a
long time now. But one of things
that is extraordinary to be
every time we turn around, now
we know we are fighting over
this issue and we're going to
need to okay we are focused now
and then all of sudden we get a
new revelation and turns out
other agency is collecting
records of all Americans and we
have brand new case so we had
the file a lawsuit against the
drug enforcement agency which
nate just mentioned so we are
back down the district court
starting again but a similar
kind of activity. And seems like
every time you turn around your
most paranoid fantasy are true
just another way of government
spying on you. So what happens
with these cases is important
but it is clear that the problem
doesn't is not that confined not
confined to NSA. What the DEA
was doing they were collecting
records and all the other
agencies access them. >> So
there was QA by Bruce nigher
yesterday. I will channel a
answer to (indiscernible) easier
for normal. The response was it
is impossible, so go for pretty
good security and make
(indiscernible) so to that end,
I know that training and user on
end to end encryption is one of
services if I recall, what can
we do to encouraging the downs
by a peer tools to just kind of
get the word out there? >> I
think one of the -- there are
variety of different ways to
encouraging people. So depends
on your audience but I think one
of the things I like the point
out is that we are making
surveillance more expensive and
difficult for the government
when we do that and another
important point if you feel like
if you have or understand how
open source applications work
and you know you are okay using
them that your security is
strong as the weakest link in
your security. So important for
this community to work with the
people who -- you grandmom
(indiscernible) could use signal
and no reason why she couldn't.
And no reason why anybody
counted use signal. Everything
that is share able so -- what's
URL? Shocking URL. HTTPS -- so
please send people there. There
are people across the country
who do these trainings and do
for people of variety of level.
One of the things that I get
excited about doing is trainings
where I know the audience is
going to be so I think sort of
that is very long answer to
simple question your argument to
why peopled should use thing is
audience specific. We try and
make encryption prevalent to get
plane text off the wire and do
policy work to make sure that
(indiscernible) safe and legal
and not back doored. >> So
follow-up to that question. We
have seen a lot for lack of
better word, zero knowledge
encryption systems and services
being provided the private key
they encrypt the private with
the user password on a legal
level this is differ than just
encrypting it with a system that
you control but when there is
messaging act that talking using
protocol to remote server and
things get fuzzy when it is
browser base. Proton mail they
is client and you put your
password word but easy to back
door those on demand and target
the user, my question is is that
for you United States services
and I don't think you can talk
about Germany but for United
States services do you feel
there is legal distinction there
between the systems. >> There is
no law in this what so every. No
court has ruled on this in
United States. We have not seen
and we are unaware of any order
from the United States court
ordering a service to back door
product. Some situation
different. That was not a back
door order but that is only one
that we heard of. What we have
seen a ton of informal pressure
put on (audio drop) so your
question was is there a legal
description no because it is no
law what so every. What that
means what happened when you get
a wiretap order with technical
assistance attached we don't
know the answer to that. Run a
service and you get a order
please in to us. >> So going to
switch gears, so when stuff like
the legislation that won't die
or congress passing retro active
community to questionable
programs, does that seem to be
happening every other day, and
kind of the deck being stacked
against you. How do you deal
with burn out? How do you keep
from knowing your hands up in
the air in a saying fuck it? >>
So working on cyber security
stuff in two weeks I'm going on
a 500-mile bike ride and not
putting on devices. We have to
fight for these thing. We have
people some intelligence and FBI
and fighting us. Everything that
EFF works on so for me
personally the fact that we
don't -- if all of us are not
fighting against it and setting
the standards for better uses
then we're going the have much
worse in my opinion technology
history so I think those are my
two answers. Burn out is
difficult. You saw over the
summer had where working on
national security and we
switched to this cyber
information sharing act so there
is not a lot of rest but try and
take vacations and just realize
that we are in a very specific
and important time period. I
will get to rest later in my
life. >> I would add that
everybody at EFF feels privilege
that had we get to do this work
and that you guys support us so
like yes it is not like you
don't have hard days but really
we are so lucky that we get to
do this and fight this fight. No
one who works at EFF is a kind
of person that doesn't love a
good scrape and sometimes you
win and that feels good. So have
to remember those. >> Just one
other thing to had one of great
things about EFF we have
holistic strategy. And we all
work on a lot of things so in
this year I have seen
frustrating things that didn't
move but the I get to work on
local things like is city
counsel level. I got somebody to
use a program they would have
never used before. I have a
comment and at least two
questions. What do we do about
the problem of demonstrating
injury when there is so many
secret things going on. There
was lack of evidence of injury
and court said and they could
not have obtained the evidence.
That is catch 22 any suggestions
or thoughts on that? >> Evidence
of injury, there is a notion
called standing that is
necessary you have to have
standing before you proceed with
a case. You have to have some
concrete relationship to case
that is demonstrated by showing
that you have been injured in
that case and one of challenges
that has come up is the
government asserts that it is
state secret whether or not they
spied upon you so even if they
have program that is spying on
everybody -- you can't get
standing and case has to be
dismissed. And we have been
fighting on this issue. Anyway
to over come that? >> I think
one of things that we foresee a
lot of work on with national
security we want to see or fix
classification so h is problem
and something that makes it hard
to see cochlea the going on.
Whether there is hope or not,
yes there is always hope. >> My
comment people often in know
will tell you that there is
shortage of good attorneys, a
lot of the qualified and
skillful litigate fors get
lifelong contracts to represent
you might say bad guys. So
assume that shortage of
attorneys it has been said 10
percent of the population will
litigate and let's will be able
to make a argument that is
complete. How do you feel about
your availability of legal team?
Is there assist legal research
or do you feel confidence that
you have enough to get the job
done? >> Well, I would put our
team against any team anywhere
in the United States. And we
often are against different
companies big law firms, big
governments large and small we
will fight them and take them on
and win. So I feel good that we
have set of -- we can always use
help. Help is great. One of the
things that we have if lawyers
in the room we have co-op
attorneys. They take the cases
that we can't. We get lots of
inquiries we try to take the
cases that we can charge the
law. But we also connect people
to legal services. So we have
host of attorneys that we want
more help when people are
willing to take on the clients
that just need advice. So if you
want to join that list sent
e-mail. Give you card to EM IL
and we have group of co-rate
rating technologist who are
willing to help out with some of
projects so if you would like
the join that group same
contract information. >> My
question is about European laws.
Privacy laws. My question is
about the European privacy laws
that are being discussed at the
moment and what is your thoughts
if it is going to be a
difference. >> Are you talking
about the right to be forgotten?
>> That for one but
(indiscernible) the company
location is restriction of
(indiscernible) this is a
growing issue and the law raises
it as well. So I will try the
answer in one. So for those that
are not familiar the right to be
forgotten is in Europe and
basically where you say there is
something on internet about me
and it is not true and it is
invading my privacy so you get a
order requiring search engine to
take down the link and pretend
that website doesn't exist my
more and what has happened is
that in Europe they adopted this
and we had court order google to
apply that right but up until
now it has been country
specific. So if it a French
court then only in France people
can't get to that website. But
(inaudible) drop that is on
appeal said no, no, no we need
you the take down all around the
world so no one could access it
because some portion of the
French population has figured
out you can get around that. So
google is fighting this and I
think write I will so and
because sit very dangerous to
have a world you see a different
view of the internet. I they is
very dangerous path for us to go
down and people come in and have
these stories there is untrue
and I didn't do it but what it
means is depending on what kind
of editing you want you choose
your just direction and you
orders that global implications.
I don't think anyone court
should have the ability to set
the terms for the entire world.
There are other countries that
worry about things like the
right to be forgotten. So Latin
American that I are concerned
about this because they have
history where it is important
for them to remember. If you are
Latin where a lot of history was
erased by dictatorships you can
scared by the notion that some
portion of history will
disappear depend on you where it
is. This is hard problem because
I don't practice law un-Germany.
So one of things that that we're
working on is building coalition
with lawyers, with privacy
groups in other countries and
figuring out way to work
together. In terms of data
localization laws we have
skeletal of those laws but a we
have seen them even more than
not past for a wrong purposes
not to give greater protection
but to force companies to store
data to give to law enforcement
so that scares us. >> So I was
glad to see EFF that was listed
one of the organization against
-- and I hoping that you explain
about why and what the impact of
those international trade
agreements will have as well as
kind of what you see as next
steps. >> I can speak to that.
So we are against the T P P.
Vast trade agreement that cover
all types of thing to dairy and
corn and covers a lot but it
also as chapter on intelligent
property. There is chapter where
they negotiate international
copyright law by trade
agreement. When you talk about
copyrights you are talking about
balancing and figuring out what
the are the rules for expression
and that means you are talking
about speech and that means
doesn't belong in a trade
agreement because not the same
thing figuring out what the
rates for corn. It is a very,
very different things we have
tree speech tradition here and
when you say the word copyright
all of free speech goes out the
window. The other problem with T
P P -- so we sort of know we
have a long history and know
that doesn't work. Doesn't stop
the trade represent of trying to
make other country -- they
occurred in secret. And this
therapy behind trade agreements
secret is because you don't want
people shorting I don't know
cars or manipulate the market.
That is all fine but now they
negating the rules for speech.
So we have been fighting it and
the good news a round of
negotiation and that was
supposed be the final round and
deal fell apart. So have to go
back but gives it any chance to
challenge it. With trade
agreements sometimes people just
give up and that will be a best
thing or they may drop the TP
section. So I remain hopeful
this trade agreement may die in
the vine. >> EFF comments on
(indiscernible). >> So for those
of you that don't know the vas
nor arrangement is four is state
arrangement to control the
export of dual use technology
and what that means is
technology that is useful both
in civilian and military
context. Nerve gas, body armer,
land mines stuff like that. Were
added to control list for the
first time. The United States
didn't implement the rule
instead department of commerce
took eight months to get act
took and it was terrible. It
would have outlawed jail
breaking services or license.
Dependent on how you read it and
for debuggers and this was
crazy, that had nothing to do
with types of software that the
vas nor arrangement to band the
export of. The software intended
to be cover were things like fin
fisher and hacking team. State
sponsor malware to target end
points. This kind of restriction
would be unconstitutional. The
next step commerce has indicate
that had they are going to
revise the rule. So we have won
the first battle but the real
next step is going to be try and
push the states at that meeting
in December of this year in
Europe to try and clarify the
control list itself. John
Gillespie more in 1993 said the
net censorship is damaged and
routes around it. Software
controls don't work that well so
we are going the trial to focus
on end use. So that is where we
are now hopefully we will work
with the state and make sure
that any controls on
surveillance technology doesn't
sweep in really good thing like
pen testing. We need to make
sure they are not chilled and
secure user academics hackers
are not chilled and are free the
continue going about their work.
>> You mentioned indication that
you like to do and third thing
you were talking about if you
have some current development
service and the government comes
with you get something like that
and you get to litigate that and
curious if there is services
that you would like to see
developers set up purposely in
hopes that the government goes
after them so you can beat them
in court? >> Is this being
recorded? Yes. So making a legal
honey bot. We take the cases
where that come up one of things
that has happened the government
is good at identifying good
facts so one of things that we
have done is try to establish
there is protection for you
e-mail. That the government need
to have warrant. 180 days or
older and we think the amendment
should apply to e-mail all the
time and we have won that case
in some jurisdiction. And I
appreciate that because it is
victory for clients in this case
but not larger purpose of trying
to establish the president. So
one trying to create the honor
my bot with good facts attempt
the government to raise this
issue they have some people they
have figured that out and will
not take they battle. (audio
drop) so the question about burn
out got me thinking, that raises
me a concern because it is the
days there a lot of sort of more
distance in accessible intuition
base back because they are tech
companies tend to be more
accessible and more culturally
related but you have like goings
tell come industry what is
looking for new technology and
looking to deploy relevant cloud
based services but when you want
to work with them the first
question they ask under the
table, but perhaps obviously is
this law -- can the technology
do law enforcement request and
you have those sort of very old
tell come institution that are
only willing to deploy you have
the so law enforcement recess
that remain outside of the
culture reach of what the way
they EFF operates generally so
you see things like reports and
you see things like all those
things who is transparent and
who is reaching out. You see a
list of companies like apple
Facebook and google all of the
modern tech companies just in
this case what a modern company
is question of culture and
question of how related is that
company culture to the way that
EFF understands and how we all
understand in this room tech
culture. But what do you do
about the people the standards
that you set is just not
relevant to their way of
thinking because they are coming
from the old telephone way of
doing things. And this is
something that reaches outside
of United States also to Europe.
>> So what is question? >> How
do you deal with that? >> There
are ways that we can pressure
companies and established tech
is still knew to sometimes
improve the practices and hard
to get at the codes. How do we
handle that problem is that the
question? >> Yes. >> So we have
who has your back project so we
go through who has you back when
the government comes knocking
and I will tell you our super
friendly companies got one stars
and they improved their
practices so people like stars
so we have we started out saying
you need to improve you
practice. So I wanted to say
even the people that we are
friends with we had to D a fair
amount of work to get them to
improve -- I don't know if we
are friends with them but we it
took a while to get them in a
better place. So I think there
are some companies they are
going to be who they are going
to be and they will just evolve
over time and we will get a new
guard take over for the old
guard. >> I was going the
mention we have holistic
approach. There are multiple
ways to deal with company. We
have policy and activism. That
is what comes to mind to answer
that question. >> He saw some
things while there and at AT
wiring up a room for the NSA
surveillance program. Figure out
what he had been involved with
he knew that it was wrong and he
wanted to tell somebody about
that and from that we got our
case against ATT for
collaboration in the NSA program
and that was applying some
values that maybe a little bit
different the what you see in
some of modern internet
companies but reflecting a
belief shared by a lot f people
that we don't want the give the
government that much power over
our lives. >> I think companies
respond to bad publicity. (audio
drop). >> So you touched on this
in answer to other questions I
want to ask sort of the how can
be -- let me start again. How
can we prevent and what tools do
we have to prevent the setting
of bad International precedence
so these come in two forms --
parliament pushed through audio
recordings with no treaty.
Because the United States does
it that is international. You
get these standards without the
bodies out of nowhere,
(indiscernible) it is bad.
(laughter) it what hard to
intervene on the international
level. Sometimes we can and make
it possible for people in United
States and outside of United
States to speak up and sort of
international principles that
valuable. So that is one way to
do it and people in this room
the thing is stay tuned to EFF
-- even if it seems doesn't
effect me as citizen. We can
stop bad things but only when
there is out cry. I would remind
everybody (audio drop) right
around the same time
International name protest
stopped A CT A which was a
international trade agreement
and stopped in the tracks by the
international protest here and a
broad so stiff we can do but
required coordination. >> So you
guys have talked about the
freedom of speech issues so far
and I'm curious, so I have heard
some quotes from your
organization about speaking out
against laws what is referred to
as reviewing form and I am
curious if you think in this
space there is way way to
balance criminalizing these
actions with free speech. >> I
think the answer is we have not
seen any legislation that comes
close to that. The problem is a
lot of legislation has poorly
defined terms and in some ways
the (indiscernible) coming from
companies and their questions
about really key terms like
consent that are just not clear.
So if were to see a piece of
legislative that could balance
these concerns we could be
excited but the question of
addressing this issue is
certainly something that we
think people need to think about
because what's happening now
that it is very reactionary and
it is reactionary in a
particular way sort of to
mentioning the companies they
know people are upset and know
that people want to do something
and they are going to do the
things are easiest to do. The
other thing to keep in mind is
that a lot of this legislation
is not thinking about what --
all of this issues of harassment
are coming from a big cultural
context. (audio drop). >> EFF
has come out against
(indiscernible) I am curious if
you can describe it at a high
level of government perspective
sharing -- protection of
individual's information. >> I
think we should start out by
addressing the flaws I think one
of the for important thing to
note is that -- these laws are
addressing or they have been
painted as more information
sharing but when we look at lot
of breaches what happened when
we look at JP morgan chase, home
depot, what it was -- JP morgan
that was due to not updating the
server so the first accept is
ensuring that we tackle those
things and we could talk about
hours what a good policy is. We
focus on the -- the granting of
new powers a lot of people
neglect and the -- often is not
contend and what these bills do
and what we see every bill what
every bill does for the past
three year as try to get rid of
privacy protections and try to
enlarging the scope of the
contend or of the able to
collect private information, but
also increase the powers. So I
think the -- we try to focus
(audio drop) we don't need the
grant companies huge -- let's
deal with the problems that we
are trying to deal with. Let's
look at how this was caused and
try the fixed those problems. We
are focusing on the solution
that not a actual solution to
these problems. >> Have you seen
attend towards law enforcement
trying to force individuals to
give their password. >> So I
will take the portion about the
giving out password . S this has
been a continued area of
litigation under what
circumstances can someone be
compelled to give password. Or
compelled to provide
un-encrypted information the
government cannot compel you to
give away you password but you
may have a order to decrypt the
information but you may be able
to do that. Whether the act
having that password would give
testimony to provide
information. Will it be
testimonial. But if they know
that it is your computer they
know you have access to this
information but the you are not
currently giving it to them that
sometimes courts will order
somebody to give a decrypted
copy. So that was that and I
forgot the second part of you
question. >> It was about
increase in law enforcement
attempting to force people -- >>
Because when the government we
only fine out about it if
someone creates EFF for help.
One of the things that
government does is they pick and
choose the facts of litigate and
their is good set of factors for
us it is often the case we drop
it. And Judges are willing to go
to great length to throw child
pornographers -- so there is has
been some bad law made by some
bad people. >> So you touched on
proposals and information
sharing that would under mine
our rights so I it is easy to
become disa lighted with
political system but there any
proposal that let us sleep
easier. Something that benefit
our right as what can with do to
help. >> So let me by start by
pointing out the win so this is
not all doom and gloom because
we had a Witness here that was 4
million people spoke up and
forced FCC to do the right thing
and rules that make sense and
will survive legal review and
FCC has been trying to interact
-- it would go to court and lose
again and we have world in which
many people have little choice
with respect to high speed
access and EFF believed that we
needed rules of road. We turned
ship and it was amazing thing to
happen. And it leaves me feeling
very, very positive about the
power of the net. So that makes
me helpful and those rules are
being litigated in court but
this time I feel like we can win
this one. We will survive legal
review and there have been
victories and I think internet
user are starting to mature as a
political force. >> I want to go
back years with the
(indiscernible) and how much it
shocked the country. A lot of us
knew some f this but not the
extent. Working cyber security
world -- a lot of people in this
room -- the feeling that I get
when I read something there are
thank you things that come out
about surveillance feel like
people become desensitized to it
now and peers of mine so my
question is, how can be get
people to become more (audio
drop). >> So that is a great
point. I think that people do
feel over then I ask how many
people say it is just so bad
will is nothing I can do about
it. So I think we need to make
it real and sorry if kids in the
room but Dick picks that is
brilliant segment and when you
talk about section 702 people
want to know how it is going to
effect them and really on the
base level people want to know
can they see Dick fix you make
it real for people and we are
still figuring out how much is
still out there and we are
figuring out how to communicate
with people and we want to talk
about the values of work we do.
But we need to talk about how it
matters to people so having that
approach so it is really bad and
I am going to tell you about
something else but here is
something that you can do now.
You can start doing this thing
that is going to make it harder
the government to watch you.
When congress people get calls
it does make a difference. Some
times the difference is only in
numbers if they only got one
call they are not listening but
if they got a hundred calls this
is something people care about.
If they get more than then care
more so all of those things
people need to hear all of
those. >> I would add there is
one thing I love the privacy
bagarre projects part of it I
have it installed and you go
website to website. It is
company surveillance but way to
see I can see all the different
companies that are watching me
now. Where as if I go to this
site it green so this is safe.
So this is important and
interesting way for people to
engage and become conscious of
how much they are being tracked
so those kind of projects key to
keeping people aware. >> We
don't talk about free speech as
only individual issue. We should
not talk about privacy as
individual issue. I care about
free speech for everybody else
because that is what matters.
And privacy is the same thing. I
care about other people having
privacy because privacy is what
is necessary to do the hard work
of democracy. You can't push
social change without advocacy
just like you can't do it
without free speech and you
can't have free speech without
privacy. It is about society. >>
I would like to move the
conversation back to online
harassment. I have had the time
what has had a hard time so near
and deer to my heart. I know
this summer the court came out
with a decision that kicked a
lot of these things back down to
lower courts to redefine. am I
right on that about how -- there
was a ex-husband who went after
his wife and that decision was
kicked back down I would like to
know if EFF are working at the
lower court level to help define
what is harassment and how that
is defined going forward? >> So
I can say that I am not certain
which case you are referring to
but there is bleed between
online and offline harassment
and sounds like the case you are
talking about was about offline
-- it was online harassment he
was putting things on Facebook.
Sorry, now I know what case you
are referring to. I will let one
of attorneys answer that. >> I
this the question was not about
the case I think the question
was what the EFF doing to help
the lower courts define. I think
part of our point is we have a
lot of laws that define
harassment already. We have
number of laws on the books that
can be used criminal laws and
civil law That's can be used
when people are stepping out of
line. We have robust laws and
criminal penalties for criminal
activity. One of the things that
(audio drop) I think law
enforcement needs to be better
educated about what counts as
threat. I think of 10 law
enforcement discounted important
threats that are happens -- I
think something we are aware of
the laws on the books are not
enforced the right way and but
we sort of -- what we like about
the laws on books like with
defamation of law we have
history of courts figuring out
they balance between defamation
and (audio drop) true threats
and just talk and I think it is
bone to continue to be a
struggle. (audio drop). >> I
think recently in a district
court decision maybe in new or
whens judge found (audio drop)
using DCMA as a lock he found
the thing that was being locked
had (audio drop) and using it as
access control list and found
not use of DCMA so h is judge
slapping down over reach or is
that kind of use in decline now.
>> So what we have seen there is
question whether you activity
(audio drop) or tied to
copyright infringement and we
would like the world in which
you have to be breaking
(indiscernible) for there to be
a claim. There is law that is
being represented that would do
just that but courts have
interpreted this in different
ways whether it has to be tied
to breaking a lock or tied to
copyright interest or not. So
kind of mess but in the meantime
if you person engaged in
security research that is not
very comforting so the law is
kind of mess. >> So do you see
this going to supreme court? >>
It could happen. >> Is there any
legal basis -- I see you shaking
your head that is good. Or just
a cable company talking point.
>> Yes. I was not planning on
asking a question (audio drop) I
guess where I want to go with
this we hear terms like cyber
warfare and we are getting
bombarded more and feeling of
having to defend ourselves I
guess is more into something
more than just physical. It
digital (audio drop) on the
first amendment and lot of
answers were based on protection
and we have DMCA1201 -- have you
guys considered application of
the second amendment to this
defense. So second amendment is
right to defend our self but the
kind of idea and the second
amendment was to protect our
several against the government
and the right to bear arms so if
we had some application and of
morph of that second amendment,
maybe that could be a defense.
>> So the notion of second
amendment coming into play have
been raised on the number cases.
There is no court that indicates
they might look at is second
amendment. To say like guns a
knives and weapons of that sort.
And when it has come to software
putting into categories with
weapons that generally been a
problem. So in earlier days of
EFF the first round of war there
is were controls over the export
with notion -- those were
weapons. And in that case it
really the first amendment that
came into play. The code of
speech and you have -- so no
indication that the second
amendment will be a fruitful
application. So the question can
the second amendment be useful,
remains out there. The area in
which it may start to impact
technology things like hacking,
we talked about that earlier and
3D printing with e are bring
these issue to the forum. >>
Last question. Mine is simply
have you seen a increase in use
of (indiscernible). >> H1B
visas. As in -- we don't do
immigration law. I was curious
if you heard anything. >> No.
Immigration is not one of issues
that we work with and when EFF
needs immigration law advice we
hire those lawyers. >> I want to
follow-up with question you
mentioned the secret around
national security, I don't know
if you guys remember the case
Japanese car maker -- >> Hold
the mic closer. >> I don't know
if you remember a Japanese car
because his rental car tag was
expired. He was arrest because
the rental card registration was
expired. >> I don't think we are
familiar with that case. >>
Alabama has a law if you have
car registration (indiscernible)
if you are foreigner and minor
traffic problem you have go to
jail so that was a kind of
(indiscernible) my question is
that the car company used
(indiscernible) we made a
mistake and somebody didn't do
the work. But before that case,
given one of those cars and -- I
think that is kind of -- they
have a program to provide car to
some people so that
(indiscernible). >> This is
about your specific situation --
>> No. I was asking if there is
policy or something like that.
>> Hard to hear. >>So are you
asking whether license plates
are policy. >>They have a
program like a car company
(indiscernible) in the name of
national security whether the
(indiscernible) privacy
something like that, how you
contact that -- something to do
with national security we can do
nothing about it. >> I'm not
positive this will be a answer
to your question but the let me
take a stab. We have street
level surveillance project and
part of goal of that project to
not just track but share
information in the ways in which
people on ground including
things like tracking license
plates. I don't think that what
you're asking but that is
closest in terms of what we're
are paying attention to. >>One
of the things that we encourage
is people file -- you are
mentioning the car companies and
that is -- >> Sorry I could not
catch that. >> Car manufacturing
we have not heard information
that car manufacturing are -- >>
Rental company? Rental cars. >>
Sorry we don't have a better
answer for you. We are not
really aware of rental car
program that is involved. Could
be that there is one but we have
not really heard of that. But
thank you for you question and
thank you all for coming and
appreciate coming here and being
apart of this community and
thank you much.