Good afternoon. Welcome to the
remote access talk. I welcome
you all here, thanks for coming
to this talk I know you have a
lot of choices. Key megsages for
this session, I wanted to let
you know that your current
security architecture is flawed
now. I published everything you
need to know, that's all on the
website. First principles to
demonstrations, full code
releases, the proof of concept
including test framework for at
least the first set of
technologies. People are welcome
to take photos of this and film
this if they want to. The impact
is going to be significant.
There are no constraints to data
theft for remote workers or
off-shore partners today. There
are no easy answers but the
paper has some suggestions. For
my job I've been both red team
and blue team, I'm currently on
the blue team in my career. In
my spare time, this is one of my
hobbies that I'm presenting
today, this has nothing to do
with any of the companies that I
currently work for, have worked
for. I laugh at my daughter's
Barbie car, my poor daughter has
suffered at times for each of
these projects. Her Barbie car
remains outstanding, we'll have
a look at this this Christmas
she shouted out Barbie car in
the middle of the Kiwicon
presentation, she's a cutie. I
want to give credit to
researchers, there's been a
number of researchers in this
field there is this whole heap
of technology that's been
reinvented completely uniquely a
number of times. There's a short
list here of people most
directly related to technologies
that I've also reinvented again.
I discovered them afterwards.
Some of what I'm going to
present is completely distinct
from these. Some of these I've
with other project but I wanted
to give credit to these people.
There's much bigger list on the
website. Let's start with the
problem space. First principles,
my assertion is that any user
control bit is a communications
channel. Any user control bit is
a communications channel.
Validation for this is that the
screen transmits large volumes
of user controlled bits. I want
to you imagine the screen as
fiber optic table that's been
cut through. Huge amounts of
data is being pumped out into
the room. The question then, is
the screen be transformed into
uncontrolled binary transfer
interface. I've heard this. [
laughter ] [Applause] >> We have
tradition at DEF CON. First time
speakers do a shot. This is a
first time speaker very hard to
give acceptance give big round
of applause. >> Thank you. >>
We'll all get one. Yes, we do
shots in every track. >> Thank
you very much. >> This is also
to all of our new attendees.
Cheers. [ Applause ] >> Thanks,
appreciate it. There's a way I
didn't practice the talk. So,
engineering and proof of
concept. [ laughter ] Going back
in time, terminal printing back
as far as 1984, the handbook we
talk about printing as a switch
in the software. Data was sent
to the virtual terminals now
sent to a printer device. Not
really sending data out of the
screen, same as we did with XYZ
modem we switch it. Not
literally out of the screen.
'92-96 VHS tape back-up solution
that I stumbled across in the
spare parts bins of my
electronics store. The way this
worked was data was sent out of
video port captured to VHS
player, you recorded that data
as chunk of blocks that could
then be played back as video out
from the VHS player back to your
computer. Literally backed up as
visual signal but not downloaded
through the display. Pretty
close. The first real screen
data extraction that we get is
Microsoft project back in 1994
some of you may have even owned
one of these the way it worked
there was E-prompt inside the
watch where it exposed window
and actual lines printed on the
CRT, sent signals that
programmed it through the face.
It had to work on CRT there's
been couple of open source
projects that I've referenced
there where they had to use LED
because it didn't work for LCD
display. 20 seconds to transfer
75 numbers. Here is that high
quality ad, 20 years ago the
first computer watch revolution.
Windows '95 had a tool. You
could manage your phone numbers
actually export them to the
watch. Good old days. There he
goes. Out through the CRT into
the face of the watch. Working
in the machine recognition come
1994 we had QR codes, I'm not
going into the complete
background of this, this is much
more technical audience than
I've spoken to before. But the
features that I want to take out
of this are highly distinguished
codes, the fact that they're
easily recognized and machine
recognizable. And 360 degree
scanning. I have to line this
up. Formalized in 2000.
Capability, automatic
reorientation, error correction,
native binary support.Ment
features are one of that error
correction. Later supported to
form them to what encodes,
really recognizable. Large
capacity but see in this demo
that we don't need the larger
capacities. The zen moment if we
consider the QR code as an
optical packet sitting within
the either of the display
device. Then what it now
represents is a data gram that
is layer three. You to get
beyond packet boundary replace
one code for another. I've got
multiple codes going past the
viewer. The receiver then uses
video instead of a photo don't
want to take one then exit. We
want to take a video and keep
processing. Number of problems,
what we mean data is coming out
of the screen, there's no way to
signal the sender I've got no
synchronization, no flow
control. This requires over
sampling it's a picture I have
table able to take pull multiple
pictures like any other Wav form
to sample the screen to make
sure I captured the image at
least once. But oversampling
creates duplicates. May have
been intentional because that
may have been part of the
protocol I may have had multiple
copies. Same data because of
what I was transferring. Now at
the point where we need to
transport protocol. Create the
transport data flow take the
first of the packet, smallest
packet we have in QR code has 14
bites of capacity. Putting a
header in there take one bite
and create a header, now have
the choice of framing up this
protocol as I like. I've
separated it with control and
data frame. The data frame has
the control which is the header.
I've got a flag tell me what
type of packet then a counter so
I know where I am in the stream.
At least so that I can detect
those duplicates. The payload
simply the data, actual packet
size, the control frame, we've
got flag to say whether or not
we control the data. And then a
major type and subtype. You can
see here the types just as an
example I've thrown together for
proof of concept, file name,
file size. With stop code for
example that gives CRC the
payload is the content that have
control message most of these
messages are simply designed to
give me good user interactivity,
a good user interface as you'll
see in a moment. Now this is one
way transfer between two or more
peers, don't forget two devices
can see the one screen. Now have
multiple receivers off one
sender. The features layer four
through seven I have high
latency, I have no support but
to support that because I can't
tell the sender to speed up or
slow down. I support interrupted
transfer because I know my
position in the file based on
how many packets I've received.
And it includes error detection
both within the packet but also
end to end I have a control
message with a CRC I know
whether or not I've got the
whole stream. I've picked there
at layer three a number of specs
to make sure we have good
sampling without making it
complicated. One through five or
ten frames per second. Because
I'm assuming that I got
commodity camera, 30 frames per
second, ten probably the most, a
range of QR code. See where I
have chosen the smallest one.
Binary coding and error
correction. What does this look
like? Well, most of this has no
real impact on the protocol
other than the MTI that we
specified. Here, because of the
ECC compression, the frame will
actually spill over to a larger
size frame depending on some
types of data. He pushed it up
to that frame capacity
accordings to bits. What I've
done selected arbitrary reliable
frame size that makes sure I
don't spill over to larger
frames which interrupt the flow
of the scream, the recognition
from the receiver side. For
reference the smallest reliable
frame capacity there is ten
bites which means rest of the
protocol has been shaped around
that. As quick example, I'm
going to send hello world file
out to the room now. That is
control start, hello world, fit
into ten bites that start
control. There's start control
QR code saying I have 148 bytes
packet. Star control FPS sending
five frames per second. Now, my
client can tell how long it's
going to take for the user to
receive it. There's my data with
counter of zero saying hello
world. Then I'm going to send a
stop frame that says that this
file is complete with this CRC
the receiver can validate it.
What does that look like. This
is what you can see from the
transfer. This is a PDF that's
being uploaded to the room now.
To give you quick feel of data
rates, if we apply the frames
her second to the packet side
you'll see that we've got
minimum of 80 bits per second.
Maximum of 32 kilobytes per
second. If the receiver had high
speed camera be able to proceed
much higher rates of transfer.
This is exam Mel of the PDF I
was throwing you before stored
in YouTube being downloaded by
android phone in flight mode in
realtime. It's open letter that
I sent to the office of the
Australian information
commissioner advising him that
the difference that was made in
2014 between use and disclosure
and the privacy act was actually
not valid that if I can see it
on the screen, I can download
it. You'll see that the top the
icon for icon, the status bar
that realtime scoring this data.
I've almost received that file.
Then there's a message to say
that it was successfully
retrieved. You can pull that
down android, Apple as a proof
of concept now from their
stores. Now, why did I pick that
ridiculously low QR code version
one. It's native resolution
pixels. We know that 80 by 25
will contain 80 by 5 will
contain 20-21 pixels. What
you're looking at here is a same
program that is outputting QR
code using space character with
ANSI codes for white on black
and black on white. We'll see
where that is important when we
get to the architecture. What do
we got at this point. At this
point, transmit software on my
laptop here at the podium then
I'd be able to exfiltrate any
file I want out of this computer
to device you can't see. Camera
in my hand. But the question is,
if -- how did I get that
transmit software on to the
laptop in the first place. User
control bit is a communications
channel, I've got a keyboard,
what we want is a digital
programmable keyboard. Leonardo
comes with USB hid support, it's
been available to us for 20, 25
years that means no drivers
required in the target system
for this to be recognized as a
keyboard, mouse or joystick. I'm
going to use this as a keyboard.
Top is the Digi spark which is
community program, the bottom
one is the Leo stick with 32
kilobytes that means I have 32
kilobytes -- 25 kilobytes of
space that I can use to upload a
file. The question is, what are
we upload. The sensible thing
would be source code because I
can type it in this text. But
that's hard because I've got to
compile it in my target system.
What I'm going to do is G zip a
transmit binary turn it into
Hex, allow it to type the Pex
into the target system in the
strip form, wrap it around as a
pearl or bashed script let it
output that binary on the target
system. This is a HP thin client
with XP embedded that my wife
ordered from eBay, I have no
idea what the administrative
credentials are for this box.
I've used putty to log on to a
Linux system. Now what you'll
see in a moment is I'm going to
save the data but I'm going to
plug in the Leonardo, when the
Leonardo plugs in, there it is
there, beautiful hand modeling
going to pop up say, I need to
-- I need drivers for Leonardo,
I don't have rights for those
I'm going to cancel that. But it
also pop up with the USB hid
keyboard. Leonardo USB hid I.D.
can also be programmed so this
could look exactly like HP
keyboard for example. Now it's
typing the script. Which is the
payload that I want to output
into the target system. It types
and types and types. We'll save
that script. Change permissions
on it. Now when I run that
script it will output the G zip
binary. Which I'm going to
capture to a file. Unzip that
file. Change the permissions on
the payload and I'm going to run
that payload. That's a 64 bit
Linux payload that just got
uploaded through a thin wallet.
Technology check point two. What
have we done at this stage. Now
there's no barrier to get a
client on to the system and
we've obviously got data off the
system which means at this point
I've got to bidirectional data
flow. Let's look at USB hid
interface, it's poled interface
by the system, comes up once
every milliseconds, a packet
full of keys. Unfortunately it's
a small packet contains only six
keyboard keys by code, it's
normal binary. It's also
automatically developing
interface. If you see the same
key twice it will strip it out
that means at this stage the
same problem as we had before. I
need transport protocol for the
keyboard. This case the packet
-- I'm jumping ahead of myself.
It is still Unidirectional going
inbound when I originally wrote
the paper I hadn't seen
implementation where someone has
done exfiltration of data
through scroll lock, cap lock
and Num lock. Can't use the
status which I haven't done.
Create binary payload. That
brings us down to three bytes
per packet per millisecond.
Which gives me -- and we need to
correct for the duplication I've
done my own compression and
rehydration which is all in the
paper that you can find online.
Again, the packet is tiny we
don't want to steal a bite for a
header I'll book mark a stream
of these rather than putting a
header in each one and we'll
ignore everything to do with
file-based transfers what I want
to do get run data into the
system. I don't want to be
limited to that 32K chip. At the
top there I've still got
Leonardo at the bottom USB
serial adapter. The attacker can
see a serial port, binary data
going out of that serial port
goes into the keyboard device
and gets converted to typed
keys. Combined keyboard buffer.
I exposed number of internal
controls for the framework to
make it faster. And now it's
binary interface for the
attacker. Before we augment
TGXF, to stripped out all of the
file controls for that as well
now I've got a treatment for
TGFX and stream for TKFX. We'll
join them together as a single
application. This is what we've
got. On the attacker's computer
on the left, you'll find TCP
socket listening on that system,
anything received through that
TCP socket will be sent out of
the USB serial port heading for
the keyboard stuffer, whatever
is typed in is received on the
organization side, decoded sent
out of a packet -- out of TCP
socket on that side, inside the
organization. Whatever comes out
of the organization is render
the entoday encoded and rendered
to the screen. Output of the
soccer on attacker's device.
This is a through console,
through screen and keyboard,
native TCP socket. The reference
implementation is limited to
example protocols, 12 kilobytes
up on the keyboard side, 32K
down on the screen side. There
are ways that I've suggested you
can improve. We have
bidirectional serial connection
with native socket interface.
Within same portability and
massive vulnerability. I know
guys through PPP example in a
moment. The ESA context. Get
back to enterprise security
architecture, they are a
storage-based channel attack.
Some people referred to it as
overt channel because it's so in
your face. But then where's the
enterprise in all of this. So
far we've been working from a
local computer, I gave you one
example that ran over a thin
client and over the network. But
in the enterprise we ab tract
the screen and keyboard so that
throughout the organization we
stretched that screen and
keyboard to look something like
this. If I'm an off-shore user
today, I'm in that managed I.T.
service provider off shore, what
I see after I VPNed in, Citrix,
SSH, all the way through every
single one of our gates, all the
way through the deepest part of
your organization, the keyboard
key strokes I type in here go
through all these tunnels to the
back, the screen pixels render
back come all the way out to me
off shore. A completely clear
tunnel through the organization.
This is console abstraction. In
practical terms on the bottom of
this picture if you can see it
is an attacker on the left and
enterprise on the right. What
this means attacker device isn't
the end user computer device
that you gave me off shore. This
PC that you gave me off shore is
the one perhaps babe the VDI
doesn't matter which is the
machine where you gave me the
DAP, the AV, the anti-malware,
where you got all your controls.
I'm not going to attack this
device. I'm going to plug in a
keyboard and point a camera at
it, the attacker's device is in
my hand not connected to the
network. Inside organization,
that was on the left, on the
right in the deepest part of
your organization where you have
given me access to manage your
infrastructure, is the other end
of this client which is right
next to my goal which is where
you don't have DLP where you
don't have anti-malware
detection. Example. On the left
in the red is attacker's device
with no network connectivity. In
the green-yellow tags the HP
thin client my end user compute
device, next to applicationer is
R server that SSHed to. I have
the keyboard stuffer plugged in
a camera on a couple of Pringle
cans pointing at it. At this
stage I've run PPP on that TCP
Socket, we just negotiated an
I.P. address. My attacker PC
with no network connection now
on the same I.P. network as the
application server. I'm now
running SSH over that I.P.
connection. Apologies for the
blurriness, I'm not a very good
elbow model. It will come clear
in a moment. You'll see
negotiation, there's the request
on the left on attacker screen
saying, do I want to accept that
SSH key. Another few packets
come and go. That's the request
for the password. Type the
password. That's the log in. The
attacker's PC that has no
network connectivity at all,
just SSH into the application
server. [Applause] Solution two.
New for Christmas 2014. When you
present these things people blog
about them they say, it's
interesting. But I can stop QR
codes that's what I put in the
paper. When I went to Kiwicon I
released something new that was
an ASCII version. So, I believe
this is an unsolvable problem.
This was another variation to
demonstrate that, so at this
stage TGFX is transported
protocol, I've got my data gram
protocol on layer three I'm
changing from QR code to ASCII
character. So, text. 0s or 1s.
Now it could have been graphics,
I threatened to do pixels
because that would be
significantly faster it could
have been images, I'd love to
see organization out there
trying to filter fortune 500
logos. It could be letters,
words, phrases, whatever you
choose I can adapt. In this
particular case I've chosen
ASCII characters to prove it was
possible. This is client list
because at this stage I no
longer need a substantial client
that works up to 300 bytes, I'll
show that you. Minimal service,
I indicators are compromised.
But simply some dash script or
could be PHP or doesn't matter.
And demonstrates futility of QR
code detection. There's the bash
code. All I need is display a
counter and some data and I can
make it run. I've got particular
set of font and colors because
I'm using optical character
recognition. It's just for the
proof of concept you can throw
that away. I've switched from a
camera to the AVA media game
capture media device, anyone
that doesn't know these, so you
can plug your Xbox HTMI cable,
it captures it for your replays.
But it saves to a USB key that's
tiny little key at the front of
that picture. This example is
designed to capture data at one
kilobit per second. That will go
into speeds, I've got 19-10-80
display. I'll show you example
of that shortly. My recovery
runs a lot slower but it doesn't
matter what I've stolen it as is
the kilobit per second. I'm
going to recover this to MP4
file in Linux. Now the red room.
Last year at Black Hat, about
late one night gentleman pulled
me aside I was telling him about
this he said, look, seriously,
but what about the red room. My
organization has a red room. We
see this thing off shore. Red
room is the room that has the
secret sauce, it's got the
special recipes, the place you
have to go to access certain
data assets. Off shore we tend
to have rooms that classified to
certain specification we put
certain physical controls around
them. With variable success.
Anyway, he was focused on the
red room. The rules for the red
room are device can enter the
red room but has to be formatted
everything except the firmware.
Which means we can get the tools
and technology in.Nd the didi
advice can leave it has to be
blanked again, the question, how
am I going to get that USB mass
storage out. My response to him
was, well, be creative. If you
don't note the reference you'll
have to watch the movie. This is
an example of that bash upload.
Been given password just as
piece of content to send. I've
put that bash script on the key,
just popped it in for me. What
you can see on the left is
clearly a counter in binary, 0s
and 1s on the right is data in
binary I'm get one bite per
packet effectively. When we
decode that, you can have a look
on YouTube. Now what I've got is
Linux system, I've opened the
video, I'm processing it one
frame at a time now doing
optical character recognition on
each frame. If you can see it, I
don't know how clear it is on
those you'll see a little
rainbow colored boxes floating
around the letters on the
screen. That's where it's
recognized characters is
attempting to process them. On
the left-hand side this is
indeed bug mode every line of
password that comes out on the
left you'll see another line of
it appear on the screen. That
data is coming up line by line
as it's processing the video. No
need for -- [ no audio ] It's so
slow. I don't care. It wasn't
the point. At Christmas I got
bored I was watching "Deep space
9" I think for the third time.
So I went for the pixel threat.
Assumed it wouldn't be too hard,
certainly wasn't very difficult
at all now what I'm doing is a
pixel at layer three, so, I'm
using HGML java script. I've
left text but now if what I had
that VDI in the environment or
web browser I can now encode
data visually and send it back
out. It uses about 20K, that's
now about 30K of java script. It
feels big to be clientless
that's just a single file and
HTML you can plug in a key and
upload the whole thing. Again,
demonstrates futility of
targeting a specific
implementation. Now I tried the
same box, this is -- 1.3
megabits per second now using
two frames per second one bit
per pixel this is simply black
or white. That's $120 box. The
Ava media I'm using 12 by 720 at
60 frames her second. As you'll
see, we recover at the same way.
Slightly different encoding.
That's me plugging in the key
and typing in the client. This
is a web browser at the moment
it's Firefox it works in chrome
with F11 mode it's full screen.
I'm doing a local file upload to
the browser itself so the java
script can process the file. And
that's what the data looks like
in black and white. Looks like
just a static TV, right? I'm
going to let this one run so you
can see the progress actually
counts upment speed as well. The
content of this file is the 5.5
megabyte I wrote last year on
TGFX. That file has been
uploaded, that was 1.37 megabits
per second. Easy enough to do.
Downloading is the problem. Here
I've got the same program
framework only I've ditched all
the optical character
recognition on the left you can
see the line by line frame
marking, that is each individual
frame of this video and what
I've taken away from it. This is
debug output. First thing you'll
see I upload the big red box.
Allows my software to locate the
region on the screen that
contains the packet. So I can
find layer three. There it's
found it. Then what we'll do is
every single -- control messages
going past that we can't see.
We've got those now. There's
full screen of data. Now,
there's a CRC in this protocol
you can see this 20 lines before
successful line before
successful frame that we've
miscalculated we haven't got
full data. As the over media
captures you have about 50%
through this transfer you'll see
that the picture starts to Res
up it's like it takes ten or 12
frames to completely capture I
think there's internal bit rate
in this. You'll see loads of CRC
errors before we get the one
frame that works. In the bottom
corner you can see the PDF
slowly being restored from this
file transfer. Now I'm getting
more errors, there's loads of
errors I'm also going a full
updated frame. A full updated
packet. Before I get a valid
packet. If I push this one more
frame per second faster it's not
successful. Ticking, ticking,
that's transferring. Very close
to not successfully recovering
each individual frame. Almost
complete. And the last packet
will be the CRC 32. That's
successful. That's a big list of
CRC 32 validations on the file.
There's the PDF. [ Applause ]
But that's not good enough for
DEF CON. That's what I had when
I submitted to DEF CON I
thought, this is pitiful. I'll
show you why this should be
substantially higher. For $30
more you can get professional
capture card, unfortunately I
didn't read the fine print this
is YUV capture card even though
RGB data source is one bit per
pixel without getting whole lot
of mess. However, by being a
better card I can do eight
frames per second that works out
to 4.7 megabits per second. Same
resolution, same packet size,
100 kilobytes per frame. So the
low price of ten times that
much, you can buy the 4K extreme
4G this thing designed to
capture realtime, 60 frames per
second, 4K video frames. This
thing will capture the next
couple of generations of what
you're VPN users will use. Same
resolution. QR but in and out
three bits per pixel, ten frames
per second. So I'm up to 300
kilobytes per packet. And a
total of 12.1 megabits per
second in the demo. Only reason
why I'm not showing you today a
one gigabit transfer because I
couldn't properly pass the AVI
file. FFM peg came closest to
converting the file I was able
to get the three bits per pixel
reliably. I couldn't get ten
bits per pixel reliably. Which
this card will capture but I
couldn't convert. This is where
I've left it. That's the same
file with this card capturing
it. Let's recover that file. You
can see I've already captured
the frame. Resize this picture
fast enough. There's the
control. You'll note that there
are only two CRC only two times
I didn't correctly get the frame
with this capture card. That was
12 megabits per second.
Architecture, look, we need to
leave out the PP example. The
PPP example is not part of the
solution. Because it requires
privilege. Require privilege to
set up interface on system, to
leave that aside before we had
that we already had PCP socket
was working between two nodes.
Just having a bit of fun. But
important thing to note the
technologies I've shown you do
nothing for privilege. They can
only do exactly what your users
can do today. What you can type
and read is what I can type and
read. I haven't changed
privilege at all. Distinct
properties of the delta seem to
be along volume, accuracy,
structure and utility and the
paper goes into a few views on
that in the cat and mouse games
that you can play on that. The
problem we have in Australia, in
the Australia privacy act and I
believe -- there's a distinction
drawn between use and
disclosure. It's considered use
and safe if the user comes into
your system, into your
environment and works with the
data in your system. That is
considered to remain in the off
shore case that data remains on
shore. It's not off shore. Even
though the screen is displaying
it that's use. Haven't left your
system. Disclosure however when
that data is taken from that
system, taken off shore and user
can do whatever they want with
it. Obviously tools that I've
presented today are designed to
completely destroy that barrier.
But I haven't done anything with
the privilege on that. Now in
the Australian privacy act, if
the data is taken off shore,
Australian entity is actually
liable for that data going off
shore if they didn't take
reasonable steps and the only
one of these steps that seems to
make any sense in this context
is monitoring. The questions
what is reasonable monitoring.
In 1973 I wrote a note on
confinement problem, brilliant.
Brilliant work. His conclusion
was, at the time they were all
looking at multi-user systems
and trying trying to provide
levels of difference between
clearance, not being able to
leak data, his conclusion was it
probably cheaper if possible at
all to just to leave it -- to
accept the risk. For this type
of problem. His work was rolled
up in to the TCC specification.
For B and B3 trusted systems.
The conclusion that document
came to was that a hundred bit
per second data leak or hundred
bits per second was considered a
high leak. Because a hundred was
valid terminal. If you had valid
terminal that was leaking at the
speed of a valid terminal, then
they can't possibly be secure.
Now, out of all the example I've
given you today, none ran under
a hundred bits per second. Not
one. Including text one that
will run through SSH. HTMI at
1920 by 1080. By 24 bits per
pixel faster than a gigabit. In
terms of acceptability. The TCC
spec said that the maximum
bandwidth accept for is one bit
per second. And any covert
channel that was above one bit
in ten seconds had to be
auditable. So if you are in your
environment today, the question
I put to you today is, do you
have the ability to see every
single key change, caps lock
light change, pixel change, any
delta in your environment that
runs faster than a tenth of a
bit per second. Not in any
organization I've known. The
business impact. I'm going to
refer to example from April this
year here in theist, the FCC
went after AT&T because if I
remember correctly their off
shore centers in Mexico,
Colombia and the Philippines
lawsuit settled at 25 million.
Which was then reported as the
fine. If I took one of those
users off shore, that works out
to about in rough numbers, $89 a
record. Per personal record
lost. If I took one of those
users working today with A4 page
I'm writing down whole records,
two kilobytes per record, full
bits, eight bits. That works out
to -- a thousand words a day,
five kilobytes a day. The worst
damage I could do to you in four
business days would be ten
records. Multiple output by ten,
still less than 100 users stole
in in four business days.
Assuming the FCC doesn't give
bulk discounts then what we've
done in the last 45 minutes is
take that to 12.1 megabits per
second. I'm now moving in the
same grid of time, 87 million
records with a cost to the U.S.
organization of almost $8
billion in fines. But I don't
have to work in business days
because they're just business
days. They're eight hour days, I
can now work in 24 hour days, I
can start this transfer at 9:00
this morning pick up the results
at 5:00 tomorrow afternoon when
I go home. In terms of 24-hour
days we now talking about one
fifth of the U.S. population
being able to be downloaded per
24 hour day of fine around $6
billion per day. And that would
be entire U.S. pinched in one
week or Australia in eight
hours. [ no audio ] Once it's
been displayed it's been
uploaded to the room. So far as
off shoring, right sourcing,
Bestshoring, whatever you want
to call it if you -- as a name
for remote access for untrusted
users to trusted data on shore,
if you want your data to be
yours and yours alone then this
is not currently an unlikely to
ever be safe. I'd like you all
to consider how many bits per
second data loss is too many to
accept. Thank you very much.
[Applause]