>> All right. Let's jump into
it. The reason we started this
kind of talk, the reason we
submitted this talk like explain
it like I'm five is because,
we're kind of into hardware
security for protective
purposes. Are we up? Yay, no? We
-- anything you want me to do?
Test this. Were in. I can put
the seal back up, too. It's on.
It's off. It's on. It's off. All
right. We saw a couple of talks
that are really deep. There's
like four really -- not today
four this weekend that are
really deep into hardware
security. Mostly around
attacking this is DEF CON that
was Black Hat we're about
attacking we like securing
things, so we wanted to give
like introduction talk that
motivates everyone in the
audience to learn about hardware
security and use that to build
and secure mobile devices, the
general purpose machines that
they have, all this IoT swag.
The main objective was kind of
to simplify like this overly
somewhat complex explanations of
hardware security by defining it
in the form of like building
blocks. We'll talk about like
security primitives, hardware
security primitives how each one
of those are used to build
things like secure boot. >>
Nice. >> Want to start with our
objectives for this
presentation. Then we'll start
going into those building
blocks. Our objective was to
kind of map hardware security
and the uses of hardware
security to something everyone
is familiar with. Like defending
a network service. Most of the
time we know how to defend this.
We have authentication,
confidentiality like trust
relationships. Those are the
things that we use to kind of
protect the services and when we
try to build protections around
those services our goals around
like isolating the application
that is running the service,
reducing the attacker is fas of
the machine, reducing the number
of services. And audited them.
Finding whatever logs they
produce, pulling them back,
aggregate can them finding way
to search them. Cool >> I need
visualization for to but I can
try to wing it when we think of
an operating system and
privilege there's really only
two privileges you get today.
Ring three and ring zero. So
that you have a concept much
users, you have access controls,
you have permissions, bits on
files, that's not really making
-- anything to do with hardware
security. Hardware security
comes in when you make context
switch from user land
application, the web user, so
on. Into ring zero. That's
implemented kind of at the
silicon level. Kind of actually,
really at the silicon level.
X86, Intel producing -- allow
implement both of these modes.
Then you pick your favorite
operating system. Slackware, and
you run a kernel that is
implementing this ISA to switch
between privilege and
unprivileged mode. We get one
little ring. We want to put all
of our security aware stuff
inside of the privileged mode,
the security unaware stuff on
the outside. That comes down to
implementing all of those access
controls, the permissions bits
inside the privilege mode. Any
time you need to make -- every
time you have a question that
you want to check a permissions
bit hopefully enforcement of
that is inside that privilege
domain. Now X86 there are couple
other privilege levels, too.
Kind of call these negative one.
System management mode. It works
in kind of the same way. In the
ISA there is some definition of
how you can set up this other
privilege mode, load some code
into it and then use it as kind
of an Oracle. Use it as an
Oracle in way that you define an
API between the SMM then load
your security context aware code
inside there and any time you
need to check the permission,
I'm talking in vagueness right
now, you'll access the SMM
otherwise, the kernel cannot
modify anything that's happening
in there. Take a step back,
there are definitely attacks
against that. Right there is not
true when these APIs fall apart
but that is the general gist of
it. That is how we define a
privilege service. We come up
with two domains. Now think of
this in the networking mode, you
kind of have a LAN then you have
a service on that LAN running on
a machine. The privilege domain
is like the TCP port that you
have open. If you want to
communicate with that service
you have to communicate over the
protocol that it defined. I
mean, we tested it couple of
minutes before, I doubt
something with my machine.
Definitely. It's probably the --
I can definitely reboot if you
like. >> I'm just going to jump
in here. What Ted is talking
about we're trying to think how
can we take something like
operating system level or a
software application layer to
sort of make a good analogy for
what we're trying to talk about
for the separation trusted
execution states or like context
switching, right, of this idea
of escalating your privilege.
And one of the ways that you can
kind of think about that is sort
of how an API exposes internal
like infrastructure for a big
application to somebody on the
outside that wants to leverage
it and make use it of, right?
You can think if you have this
like barrier, this bubble inside
of this bubble is a lot of
abstracts and complex systems,
not necessarily going to need to
understand or touch. This is
kind of like merging into where
we got APIs type of thing we're
just going to expose a couple of
pieces to you say, hey, here is
this functionality that will --
awesome stuff you take it and
kind of run and just go wild and
do whatever you think you need
to do with it. Well, the way
this is working at the hardware
layer is almost -- very, very
similar way. There's a lot of
these -- these little pieces
that developers of things like
the trusted computing group
they're requiring a standard for
having these pieces and we're
going to expose the
functionality of these pieces to
the people that are writing the
firmware for you. It's an
analogy that you can use to sort
of make it make sense if you're
coming at this from a software
world. >> Right. Let's talk a
little bit about those building
blocks, too. The buildings
blocks are that ISA, it's that
API or it's like the HTTP 11
specification. That's how you
use it. Only instead of HTTP11
this specification these
building blocks are around
protecting information. You'll
see a lot of like implemented
here that you can use, you'll
see some protected storage that
you will have access to and then
you'll have like protected IO,
so network service will have to
put the mode into -- put the
machine into just a mode before
any AIO can be detected --
difficult context to explain.
Let's start with, can I project
now? If we had visualizations it
would be so much better. How
about now? Oh, the Woas of being
the first speakers. I'm
definitely picking up your color
LCD. All right. Yeah, right.
We'll do this. Building blocks
that you -- we looked at all the
kind of hardware security APIs,
the trust zones, Intel ISA as
the AMDs we try to boil that
down, that includes the
Qualcomms, the -- >> Everything
mobile and like, you know,
enterprise level desktop like
all of these different platforms
are going to have some variant
of these blocks that we're --
Ted is going to talk about. It
really kind of reduces down to
having one -- getting lost. We
need to have some type of
dedicated storage so you need to
have some form of a chip that
you can burn things into from
that you're going to get the
concept of this storage also
needs to have some capability
for being isolated. Right? You
want to have the capacity or the
capability of burning a Cert or
key or something sensitive to a
chip with some level of
assurance that nobody is going
to be able to tamper that,
right? >> Yeah. So, from like
this dedicated storage,
something that you can burn in
one time, blow any fuse then
never be modified plus some
crypto algorithm this resilience
we can get this concept of
extendible trust. With a private
key with a algorithm implemented
chip and some reasonable
guarantee that you need about
fight. >> We can use those kind
of primitives -- with those we
can have this concept of
extendible trust. So, with that,
then with that extendible trust
we can start taking affirmatives
up a level. Add couple more, the
directed IO that we mentioned.
And that might include some --
something on the hardware that
allows to you interact with this
outside the regular band. So
that could be another Ethernet
port on the device another PS2
on the device. And that you can
direct input and output to. With
that we can take that up a level
start defining concepts like
trust zone. >> I'll just try to
do the best I can. We had some
pretty awesome images that
helped make these things darks
darks concepts a little clearer,
there this was whole thing with
pokeymon and Legos -- >> You're
missing out it was great. We'll
do the best we can. What pokemon
in general looks like. Or like
Legos, right? The concept that
we use to construct these really
complicated technologies like
security trust zone which we'll
dive into lot further is, again,
using the API analogy we've been
given all of these hardware
building blocks and start to
string these pieces together to
a point where we have technology
platform that enables us to
provide that trust. So, you
start with these building blocks
you build up the capability with
the firmware, that's the next
piece that we need. We're
shooting for secure boot or
trust zone. But we can't quite
get there yet. Before you get to
there you have to have a couple
of other pieces like the secure
boot and also the concept of
these building blocks that we
had before TPM or some sort of
isolated storage device.
Constructing all of these pieces
together gives you the framework
with which to implement your
specs of secure boot. And the
reason that there is so many of
these varying technologies
because secure boot is more of
just a protocol, it's really
just there for to you say, all
right, we have all of these
different pieces and what you
should do is try to take the
Legos that you specifically need
-- [Applause] Now all this makes
sense. You guys are good? We
don't even need to -- [
inaudible ] Start again. Let's
get some Scotch. Are we just
going to -- >> We'll just have
to tell them to advance. We have
the slides down there. >>
Advance. >> Oh, man. Yeah, so
this is our goal. This is where
we're trying to get to. >> There
we go. >> Even know the order of
these. Is that -- that's one
ahead we'll build secure boot.
We'll start there start fresh.
Being a little bit redundant
we're going to take these
concepts of extendible trust,
dedicated storage, monitoring,
algorithm, state, we're going to
with it start constructing the
firmware. This is block number
one that we need to reach our
goal. And the Uwifi firmware is
this protocol that's been
defined that is I think trusted
computing one of the biggest
proponents making this clear and
concise and have a good design
to, right? So that is what we
want to focus on today is the
design of these things. As
opposed to implementations.
We'll talk about the
implementations later but --
first ones we've got Uwifi 2
plus. Now the paramount please
of doing hardware security is
our trusted certificate stores.
The large majority of how secure
boot works or trust zone works
through cryptographic protocols.
Digital signatures. We have to
have way verifying that the
signature that you have that
that you got from Microsoft that
has been verified from them can
be stored on your computer not
tampered with or hijacked at any
point in time, right? This also
brings up a lot of scary
thoughts about well Microsoft
just going to take over the
world, we'll talk about. That
don't get too excited yet. I'm
excited, don't get too excited
yet. Once we have those, the
last thing, last piece that we
need again this comes from
Microsoft but again we'll talk
about that controversy is signed
letter which -- executes the
different components at the
firmware layer gets you into
your operating system. >> That
signed boot loader just an
example of the extendible trust
that we talked about. It could
be assigned to anything. But
with that dash those couple of
building blocks plus the
certificate store you can now
extend that trust. >> You've got
all of the components that you
need, you as individuals are
like a company or corporation,
to design your own hardware
security platform that you can
deploy on your varying devices.
>> Don't recommend doing that,
though. >> We don't, please.
Please use already developed
things. Let's talk about these
individual components and kind
of explore a little bit more of
like what entails constructing
them. After I drink some water.
For the -- secure boot to
function we have to be able to
verify that firmware that we're
executing was actually given to
you from the manufacturer. How
do we do that? Well, we have to
do digital signatures. Digital
signatures work by taking the
private -- public key that
scored on disk or somewhere on a
chip, somewhere immutable,
assigned hash that was computed
by taking the currently
executing. To do this you have
to have that public key, which
is stored inside of your
platform key, key store, the PK
you might see that acronym
thrown around. Then also we have
another key store called the
KEK. Key enrollment key
database. I screw that up. The
KEK is where you can store any
third party drivers or
components that you also have
signed you take the certificate,
is that ever signed by Microsoft
and also came from the developer
of those drivers, and you put
them in your Kek this is just
where those things live so as
you're going through your
execution process of your
firmware you can load these
digital signatures of your third
party drivers up, verify they
haven't been tampered with then,
yep, I'm good. Then also need
signature database, I don't
remember how that one comes in.
You might have to help me on
that one. Two biggest are the PX
and KEK. Let's keep moving. Go
back one slide. Go back two
slides. We'll start here. So, we
want that when we go Pokeyman
battle we're fighting big fierce
opponent we'll throw out those
capabilities, right. This is
sort of a hint to what secure
has capability of offering you.
Go to the next slide. So, when
you don't have secure boot
enables, you're rolling with
running around naked, you throw
out your woke ball might end up
with a magikarp that's a huge
bummer. Might find yourself
surprised or confused or care
filed. Why did that come out?
That's a huge bummer. This is
the kind of illustrate without
secure boot enables you're
missing out on a lot of
functional -- missing out on lot
of security and verification for
what this technology has to
offer you. Go to the next slide.
When do you have secure boot
it's pretty awesome, right? When
design of secure boot is
implemented correctly and we
have some assurances that
everything we're doing has been
signed there's all of the crypto
we need. You have a lot of power
in what you're doing like you
now have much more capability at
the firmware layer. You can do
remote updates, you can do all
of these different things.
Because you have crypto kind of
backing you up and giving you
that validation that you need.
>> That analogy is pretty cool
only because Pokeman is fucking
awesome. But it's very hard to
get a magikarp into a -- only
thing it knows is Flo. If you
are running an enterprise you
need to run weird drivers or
weird firmware or boot an
operating system that has boot
loader that isn't signed and
provided and do you understand
load binary grub. You need to do
a little bit of work. That
little work involves loading up
that Kek with your own
certificate, not entering that
CA, whatever sign that
certificate then distributing it
to all the machines that you
want to run this firmware,
modified firmware on. That is a
lot of work. It's almost
impossible for small
organization. Smaller, medium
organization. But fortunately
they're not doing that. You're
not usually pushing to a mode or
train magikarp up to a Garados.
>> So um, just to kind of
elaborate on that note, if you
think about it this is still a
really new technology. The
capabilities of making this wide
scale where you can roll out
your own custom firmware that's
been signed appropriately that
honors that there is not a lot
-- this is baby technology it's
still coming around. So that's
like just keep that in mind when
you're like seeing this, turn it
off, it's so bad. Bear that in
mind. Next slide. We're going to
talk a little bit more about
other technologies I've been
droning on about secure boot a
lot but this is a quick overview
of the different types of -- I'm
going to say measured in a
general sense but also something
called measured boot. We just
got done talking about secure
boot which is verifying that
everything has actually been
digitally signed before you
start actually executing it,
also -- sorry also something
called trusted boot. Which is
much more often talked about in
the Windows world, actually a
trifecta of three different
types of boot, secured boot,
measured boot also verified
boot. That's right. Thank you.
Trusted boot is neat in the
tense that if you're just
rolling vanilla Windows, that's
what you do in life you're not
looking to customize which I
know everybody in this room
that's how you roll, I know
that. That's a good joke, I
thought it was good. This is
going to give you the
opportunity to verify every
single operating system driver
before it loads, before you get
into the operating system kind
of thing. It's also going to
give you something called early
launch anti-malware. Is trying
to find root kits, things that
are hiding out in kernel land
trying to subvert your operating
system. Again, try to take away
from this the idea of the
technology. It's really awesome
idea, we should start seeing
more of these types of things
deployed. Then lastly, measured
boot. This is more along the
lines if you're like, you know
what, that's cool that you're
trying to protect me and all,
but I just want to run naked how
about you let know know when I'm
naked or when something bad
happened to me. Then still going
to walk through a lot of these
features but just going to do an
alerting, like, hey, you're
about to load malware, you can
continue execution. Next slide.
Cool. >> The words secured boot,
measured boot, verified boot
most of the time they're used
interchangeably. I know in
couple of of the sentences we
had we used them a little
incorrectly. But the big
differentiation is the measured
boot from kind of all the rest.
But in every single scenario,
you have the opportunity to make
a decision. And you can be a
piece of software that's running
or could be remote service
that's making a yes or no
decision, right? That's what --
like the big take away. I used
it incorrect leave, man, I'm so
sorry. >> Like, dude, what did I
say wrong? >> Not yet. The way
that's implemented with those
building blocks that we talked
about is this little psych
they'll you see here. So, we're
going to fetch load code. Going
to measure in a way like a hash
that's always being added,
right? We call that like
extending a hash, so you take
the hash from before and the
hash of the code that you're
going to do now you get this
amalgamation and you load it.
The point there being that you
can't load code that erases the
hash. Then you're going to apply
like an optional signature check
in the case where you're not
worrying about these, there's a
little bit of variance in the
hashes are always coming out to
something that you can't keep
like, this big map of. We can
attach a little signature to the
code that we're about to load
assuming that the code before it
knew how to verify that
signature and also had some
trust extended. So that it can
check that signature. Finally we
have this ability to kind of
push those hashes and those
signature checks to some remote
service that can possibly make a
decision, right? Then finally
we'll make that decision. With
the go forward with with no
still go forward or could abort
the whole entire operation. We
can also set a couple of bits
that identify that the operation
would have been aborted so that
you can still run just in a
different mode. Really good
economical use not decrypting a
certain storage device
afterwards so that the decision
that you make is not to stop
booting, it's just to not reveal
sensitive content going forward.
So, when you think of this kind
of like trust chain, like
whatever code is coming before
the code that you're loading
right now, has to be aware. The
instant that there isn't this
awareness of checking or
measuring, the whole entire
chain is broken. That's what we
call like a root of trust
measurement or dynamic root of
trust measurement. That root is
like this establishment of like
your foot bone attached to your
like ankle, attached to your
leg, so on, so forth up the
body. As soon as you're missing
one of those bones the whole
kind of thing starts to fall
apart. More so you can't trust
the stuff that goes past it,
right? Sorry that interlude. I
like to put underwear on slides,
too, it's my thing. No, sorry.
Can we go? I think we have trust
zone coming up, I can't really
see the next slide. >> This is
me. That was reminder of like
where we are in the thing but we
didn't start with slides, right,
it doesn't super matter a lot.
Nobody really knows where we're
at. We did a big talk about
secure boot and thats great. But
Nick I hear you say, what about
my phone? Well, you common
pleebs there is an answer to
one's phone. >> In 2003. Right.
It's been around for a long
time. So I'm talking about baby
technologies and that's not
accurate with this fall. But
where trust zone comes in is
again we want to use a similar
analogy. We have all of these --
using Pokeman this time instead
of Legos I know you were
concerned. Were using Pokemon
this time instead of Legos. We
have a lot of different poke
balls and different kinds of
Pokemon what you want to assure
designing your trust zone, when
you go to the certain region in
the Pokemon world you want to
make sure you bring the right
poke balls to catch the right
Pokemon but also bring your all
-- going to do very well against
those type of Pokemon. So, it's
a similar concept with trust
zone that you were given a large
amount of hardware pieces on the
board that you can take
advantage of and leverage. But
also given a lot of like,
software protocol specifications
that you can also make use of,
right? So, trust zone varies
from secure boot in the sense
that oftentimes this is less
stuck to you as like a constant
standard. And companies usually
just take the spec, the
guideline, make our own
proprietary version of this and
things like Samsung knox and
Qualcomm has QSE. There was talk
at Black Hat about Samsung knox
or QSE one of them, it was silly
you should check that talk out,
pretty cool. >> Not the talk.
The implementation. >> Yeah.
That's what I meant to say. >>
What did I say? Anyway. >> With
trust zone 2, arm kind of is
built this API like the
protection domain that we were
talking about before and the
ISA. Here is the manual how to
create a protection domain,
please write me some software
that implements this protection
domain, such that I can load
code and kind of secure mode,
also like unprivileged mode
which would be normal operating
system. Then Qualcomm and
Samsung knox will license that
spec from arm theyll
implement this trust zone APIs,
right? >> Next slide. I can
continue on this. If we're
talking trust zone, this is
called like execution
environment. It is that
privilege domain. Anything
loading inside the trust zone T,
right, the trust zone secure
world, is the equivalent of that
like -- not the actual
equivalent but equivalent in the
metaphor of privilege domain in
your operating system and
unprivileged domain in the user
mode. Same metaphor applies to
priviledge service, versus the
network, the LAN itself. You can
leverage this to build something
like secure boot. Right? You
build secure boot and trusted
boot and trust zone. >> Me? >>
You did? >> No. Right, the way
you get -- the way you get
secure boot with this kind of
capability is, you load a small
little operating system, like
your boot operating system. It
knows how to load code in to
this secure world, right? The
room on your mobile device, your
arm, platform is measuring that
boot rating system once it sets
up the secure world it can now
make API calls to that,
hopefully there's some storage
in that secure world with some
certificate stores now that boot
can load a normal operating
system while the secure mode is
auditing it. Measuring. Checking
additional drivers, additional
firmware that it might load.
This is done, right? There is a
secure boot for arm devices for
android devices, and it's
implemented with all these APIs.
>> I think that's coming later.
I don't want to give away
spoilers but we'll -- >> Right.
We kind of skipped like what a
TPM is, missing few of the
slides but the same things that
you would use to build a TPM you
can use with these APIs, too,
they call it secure core. Both a
TPM in what incantation it is
like new Intel platforms the
TPM2.0 in the silicon or add to
your motherboard. Or secure core
they're all using these
primitives that we talked about
and implementing them. >> Okay.
So this was kind of what we were
trying to build up to. Ted
already talked about what this
slide is kind of illustrating,
but it's really just the trust
zone giving you this capability.
Right? You can in some sense
have these two different
environments of operation
sitting right along side of each
other like on your mobile device
so you can switch into a mode of
compute, performing sensitive
operations -- data and then you
can jump out of that context go
back into the normal user mode
where you can check Facebook get
upon Twitter do the things that
you need to do. Kind of like how
goes back and forth from being
crazy and upset and angry to
super happy. Next slide. But,
yeah, implementation of these
things gets really complicated
really, really quickly. The spec
that you can use they're huge
these massive documents of just
constant changes and revisions
to the spec. So this is really
just illustrate -- trying to
make this at really higher level
of design functionality but you
can see how -- this gets like
muddled and very noisy. >> One
way our analogy between the
network service and the
operating -- service running on
the operating system falls apart
sick install a python module
implement like a API give me a
web server if I wanted to
implement UAFI, read over 2,3500
pages of the spec and then go
consult even -- over a million
lines of code of reference
specification. The same would
exist for trust zone, too.
There's lots of applications
here, lots for rooms of error
that's why you see these great
talks about breaking these
things because those
implementations were misused or
the building blocks weren't used
correctly. >> This kind of feeds
into the old, don't write your
own crypto. Very complicated,
very quickly, one small mess up
leaves you have completely open
and totally vulnerable, right?
Hopefully this illustrates that
complexity factor. Next slide.
Again, just trying to keep where
you we're at. Next slide. Cool.
>> Do hardware security tour. So
we're going to cruise around the
region and talk a bit about
these implementations. Go to the
next slide. TPMs, if you want to
buy a TPM, actually I have
couple of discrete TPMs up here
if anyone looking to like play
around with one. And they have
little embedded boards that
speak I2C. I can give you a
couple. Otherwise if you look
for purchasing motherboards that
have Intel small business you'll
get a TPM or get some
implementation might be in the
silicon TPM. These are really
cool. They implement almost all
of those building blocks except
for kind of the directed IO and
execution isolation. So I can't
hand off code to the TPM say,
create me a privilege domain and
run this code in it then I'm
going to make API calls. You
can't really do that. Are kind
of like your poke ball, there
was a reason why I had a bunch
of these emoticons but I'm not
going to explain it now. But
like your Keks or UBHSM they do
various parts of those building
blocks. You're going to have a
certificate store on there,
you're going to have a push
certificates in there hopefully
below E-fuse so the certificates
cannot never change. But on
almost every case you will --
read the private key from those
-- some other directed IO. You
put your HTM into your machine
that needs to access the public
keys for these certs and only
the software running on that
machine or software on that
machine will only be able to
access the public keys. Go to
the next slide. Trust zone and
secure core. Implementing this
privilege domain and Qualcomm
Secure MSM, right? And like we
said before they license the
trust zone spec they can build
towards it and call are the are
their own. Knox at the bottom is
just this trust zone spec. TXT
and IOMMU are a little bit
different. We haven't really
jumped into this domain. But the
IOMMU is going to be an API
around isolating devices and
memory reads. So when we think
back to the primitives that we
talk about and the reason we're
bringing these things up is if
you're interested in these, in
IOMMU or building things for TXT
please do. That is going to give
you that kind of directed IO
plus the isolated execution. Now
I can take that isolated
execution and extend it to
potentially untrusted driver for
like a network card that I'm
testing out, furthermore I can
create that kind of concept of a
secure world that trust zone
gives me on an Intel platform. I
can take a bit of code, I can
push it into a privileged
domain, I can define the APIs
for it and make calls it to. If
I wanted to bootstrap some
protected key material in there
then launch a web service that
is going to negotiate session
keys, it can do that to that
little isolated environment,
right? And it uses TXT for that.
That will push the code on to a
single CPU, set up the IOMMU for
you, you're going to have to do
a little bit of yourself, but at
the end of the day you're going
to get this dedicated storage,
dedicated part of D RAM and
dedicated execution on single
core and also going to get a
measurement afterwards. Then you
can use other measurements that
might already exist to kind of
come up with a decision of
whether you are running in a
trusted environment on trusted
machine or in trusted state then
you can extend that decision
further. To maybe like remote
service. We'll keep going? SGX
is this awesome sauce that's
coming out. But it will take
that TXT, IOMMU concept push it
into your user land apps. They
can do the same thing. They can
set up their own Bastion of
isolated then allow other
services to make calls to that.
We take that privilege domain we
pull it out of of the ring zero
and push it into like whatever
ring we define. It's very
complicated, like concept. But I
hope that we can really start
taking things like large attack
surfaces that we have against
both applications running on the
host used to escalate privileges
but also applications running as
network services and kind of
define these APIS between
accessing protected material and
then serving up that content on
a TCP board. So, we'll make one
aside here. If you wanted to log
every execution of a process on
OSX, right? You could go into
the kernel, write kernel
extension, hook SYS, you use OSX
the Mac policies or APIs. Every
time one of those are called you
create a log right? Start up
some ring buffer, push the ring
buffer that becomes your log.
times an hour for every process
be the processes he's that run
per hour if you're using your
machine hard core. where do you
put that data? So, from the
privilege domain you audited
that requiring attacker to get
into the kernel so bypass that,
what do you do with that data?
Can you from kernel land start
pushing out to network service?
What kind of like arrows do you
need to define. In almost every
example you have to go back out
of that privilege domain to
write that data. That makes a
lot of sense, too. If we're
defining reliable services, I
can't for every Exec TCP call or
throw  EDP call throw this
off to the network. I could
buffer it there, so now I'm
taking memory away from the
system, so if I wanted to
compress that I'm implementing
all these compression APIs
inside the kernel, too, just --
it's not really a lot of fun.
What we end up with something
called like -- we start auditing
to a file in the unprivileged
world then we put like root
access on there. We're adding
these permissions bits that are
enforced in the unprivileged
world an attacker only needs to
go up to root. Well if they went
up to root they just take kernel
extension away or module away to
begin with. What we really need
and we'll go to the next slide
is this concept of SGX where
that blue circle I will is now
become purple that is my little
privileged mode existing outside
of the traditional operating
systems privilege land I can
write directly from the
privileged log of the payoff,
this that can implement my
compression and choose schedule
which it pushes data off. Now I
get all the advantages of not
crashing the kernel if I somehow
implemented my compression or my
scheduling wrong. I still can
log this from the privilege
domain which is the operating
system. The little deep but just
isolates -- or how you would use
something like this isolated
execution, right? >> Yeah. >>
We're almost finished here.
Another thing we didn't get much
time to talk about is this out
of band systems which implement
these isolated executions. IPMI
is kind of the equivalent of the
trust zone, it's the
specification to which ILO and
Draq or AMT or Intel's
management engine or secure
engine, right? That is another
mode outside that has special
APIs to run into this privilege
LAN. They are in the form of
accessing or making Dram calls
or having access to some of the
memory buses that are otherwise
protected by the ISA. We go one
more. We'll go past this.
Failures and use cases. Hit the
play button there. >> It's worth
it. You'll dig it. >> Great.
Most of the failures in the
hardware security come in the
form of like a cat trying to
walk a dog. Where the API wasn't
implemented correctly now you
have some unprivileged mode
commanding what you thought was
the privileged mode. Dogs are
the privileged, that's your
kernel, they herd all the cats,
right? They're the unprivileged
people. They're us. One more. So
the kind of uses of these, the
things that we wanted to impress
on everyone is, one, please do
not turn off secure boot, right?
If you want to boot your
operating system, if you want to
boot a different operating
system, figure out a way, there
is a way, read a little bit more
we'll keep secure boot on we'll
get you -- >> Something that we
didn't mention I'm going to jump
in real quick there's a lot of
talk about like, well, if I have
secure boot on with my laptop I
can only ever use Windows. At
the moment there is currently a
lot of support for things like
Ubuntu, Fidora that will keep
secure boot on and actually
continue to boot with secure
boot enabled. It's performing
all of these integrity checks
that you want to have. They have
a little boot shin that still
signed by Microsoft, still going
through all the Microsoft Certs
hijacking that process with
their own boot strapping
process. Said that weird. That's
kind of more -- secure boot on
is the functionality is there
we're building it. Help be part
of the solution not the problem.
>> Another really cool thing to
look forward to which exists
right now in Windows almost
there in -- we got four minutes.
Right? We have until -- >> We're
going to cut it off for
questions. >> Like four minutes.
>> Until:45D 45. >> Yeah.
Testing these like mobile app
containers right now isolation
happens on mobile devices like
it's awesome, right? There is
mobile platform that isn't
implementing some form much
isolation. Now going to start
seeing APIs for letting remote
service make a decision for the
user, right? It's scary at first
when that decision becomes
remote service saying, hey, we
think you're phone booted a
different firmware, different
operating system would you like
to continue, yes or no. That
kind of friction will end up for
people who are running egg
things like Cyaongen or booting
different operating system. They
already understand that there is
going to be couple of hiccups it
should be the onerous of them to
load like the certificate for
that engine model. >> Relates
back to rooting your phone or
jail breaking your iPhone to run
things as root, and remove the
security protections that have
been place there in the first
place. Not that there is
anything wrong that you've made
that conscious decision. So
having a server end kind of like
give you the heads up say, wait
a minute, something's different.
That would be a sweet feature
even still just kind of skip
right past it and do it at your
discretion. >> We're using these
like, how we all can start using
these hardware security
primitives to push it into
something like a consumer can
use. That decision, hey, your
phone booted in a different way,
continue, yes or no. Then like
more info. Then we can deduce
that down into a better decision
for them, probably don't know
whether to hit yes or no. So we
can have a setting somewhere
that says if my phone boots in a
mode that isn't trusted, here is
the default option, right? Then
we can set that to please don't
continue. >> It's really similar
to like the SSL validation,
right, you go to a website in
chrome or somebody stops you
says, wait a minute, this Cert
is wrong we skip right past
that, similar concept, right?
Hopefully get to a point where
there's enough to say, wait a
minute, this is bad or you
really sure that you want to go.
Kind of has hints that have to
it. >> Cool. I think next slide
will kill it. >> Done, great. >>
If you're interested in this
stuff, if this was a little bit
too high level or too basic of
an explanation for you, right?
There's a lot more to look
forward to. If this definitely
got your interest, go look at
these talks. Or please hit us up
afterwards, definitely love to
talk to you. >> Thank you. >>
Cool. Questions? [Applause]