Good afternoon everybody. How
are we doing? [ applause &
cheers ]. >> All right. Let's
learn some stuff about
Powershell. In my day job I'm a
simple country lawyer but I open
up the computer now and then. I
remember when I first saw
Powershell I thought this is
neat. This is my directory
listing. This is awesome. What's
my ip address. It doesn't do
anything. And then I hate
Powershell. Done with this. So
long those lines I like to use
the power from Powershell and
I'm doing demos on my own
systems but it can be
frustrating. Rich is going to
show us what he has done. Let's
give him a big hand [ applause ]
>> All right. Thanks for coming.
A lot bigger crowd than I
realize. My name is Rich Kelley.
First talk first time at Defcon.
Background on myself. Come
officer officer. Network
engineering software
development, end up in security
mostly for government. Most
recently branched out cofounded
a company out of Virginia. In my
spare time I will release some
utilities. All right. So why
should you care? If you are here
you probably know this. The
first point is that Powershell
is here to stay. It's going to
be on windows in the foreseeable
future. If you are not using it,
you are really just cheating
yourself. It's resource that's
there and don't have to put on
disk usually. I recommend taking
a look at Powershell. Offensive
community is focusing on that.
From the defense side I get the
feeling that a lot of defender
don't realize how powerful it
has. The function within
Powershell, completely
unnecessary. The more we bring
up the more we can secure
things. I was struck by most
mortem analysis, incident
attacker will use Powershell.
Research topic that might be a
good area for focusing. Okay. So
what is the Powershell
weaponization problem? I guess
to put it simply how to get your
Powershell running on your
machine and get your results
back. It may not be obvious but
up until few months ago I was
actually not really that easy to
work Powershell into your work
flow. There's number of script
and tools came out but they are
still vague understanding of how
you would use it on an
engagements. So when I started
this project I was trying to
make it easy for myself and
number of people convinced me to
put in a talk so here I am. So
has this problem been solved?
Yes. The couple of months we've
had interesting and great tools
came out to utilize Powershell.
Excuses are getting less and
less. When I started this and
drove me down this path is
there's this fuzzy area you gain
access, use Powershell and good
to go. And that's where I
started to fill in the gaps.
There's bunch of solutions, a
few days I'll talk about quickly
and everybody should check out
as well. All right. Briefly I
want to go over other ways to
use Powershell, weaponize it. If
you have ipo access you can
bring up the Powershell. If you
bypass the execution policy,
input your script. Copy/paste
your Powershell. It's there free
to use. You are probably use the
line on top there which is refer
to the demo, where you are using
the web client to reach out and
download and staged on some web
server. The next way is if you
have command shell, probably
where you used it. You can't
just drop in Powershell console
like you would normally. The
nature of the Powershell and way
it works makes it difficult to
get around that payload. There's
number of utilities that will
help you with that. Command
argument. Powershell execute and
go ahead and execute that return
some results. That's probably
how most of you use Powershell
on most of your tests. If you
have this shell you can use
modules that make things not
easy. You can use execute
Powershell module. It's been
around. And you can stage your
script on your local attack
machine, takes care some of the
heavy lifting for you. Through
the interpreter section to
execute. I have had few issues
with it. Occasionally opens up a
lot of Powershell incidents. It
was flaky a couple of times.
Most recently April or may,
Powershell payloads. If it was
around when I started it, I may
not have gone down the path. It
has some nice features. You do
get an interactive console. And
pass it extreme of file path
where your local scripts are.
Once it runs it will load up
scripts for you. It's nice you
can use right now. There's cobra
strike. If you have that, I
think this is probably the first
really clean solution to the
Powershell weaponization problem
that I saw. In this case if you
have beacon on a machine and I'm
a big fan of that, import and
local script and does the hard
work for you. Your function is
available there. So if you have
cobra strike, this is really
easy. Some other options.
Powershell remoting. You have to
have enabled. Once it is you can
use Powershell to invoke,
whether it's administrator or
once you get on the machine it's
a nice feature and you don't
have to install anything. Wmi
there's going to be a talk on
that tomorrow. And I recommend
you go to that. And empire this
is the tool I was eluding to.
Just couple of days ago, it's
kind of a game changer post
exploitation agent implemented
in Powershell. It has a really
nice fame work to build modules
for that. I recommend you go to
their website and take a look at
that. Okay. So I'm always hard
on my client to give
requirements. On myself I want
fully interactive Powershell as
the native Powershell
executable. And I want
capability to seamlessly import.
You don't want to stage them. I
just want to import modules give
it to path and be done with it.
Last December sometimes and work
on and off and proved more
challenging than I thought. All
right. I'm going to attempt a
live demo here and see how this
works out. Okay. Harness is the
actual payload. It's interactive
remote, c sharp. So Microsoft
has got a lot of functions that
you can use to build out your
custom host. So if you want to
big into the library you can do
that. The documentation on it
was limited and that's why I
struggled quite a bit at the
beginning. I bundle everything
in the python fame framework.
You can integrate the payload
in. It's got the usual command.
In this case there's not a whole
lot of modules. It's not the
focus of the handler. I have a
number of payloads here. Mostly
just 86 and 64-bits. Executable
and drl to inject into the
memory and I will show yaw that.
So if you want to use payload,
very similar meta display here.
So in practice you probably
wouldn't use the dropper. You
try to avoid touching disk when
you are on mission. You run it
like that and executable and
it's up to you how you would get
it to your target. In this case
I've already dropped it on the
target. And see if we can get a
call back. I want to show you is
you don't need a special
handler. In this case, see if we
can use net cat. We give a nice
call back. So you don't need
special features. This is
running unmanaged payload. One
of the things I also that you
don't get in interactive
payloads is you notice in
Powershell you get the multiline
inputs. So I want the feature in
there. Hallmark of having
Powershell. You can do stuff
like this now. What is doing in
the background is every time you
send something it's doing the
check. And once it says it's
clean it goes ahead and executes
it. You can just print out. This
allows you to build function on
a fly. The buffer can't keep up
with each other. Eventually I
would like to have that problem
solved as well. So that was
getting kind of close to my
first objective. It's not
completely implemented yet. But
I'm working through some of the
bugs. The next thing if you use
handler built in to the
framework here you get a little
bit more functionality. You load
the handler here. Running on ad.
Once again it will execute it.
And we get a call back here. So.
We can interact here. Using the
server and client together you
can import modules across the
wires. So in this case built in
some custom command. The
difference is the module...and
I'll try it send it through
wire. It's through the same
channel you are currently using.
In this case once you in the
memory there you can see the
function from power up
available. See if we can
do...invoke all checks. What I
have noticed so that it does
consume a lot of memory. There
you go. The next thing I want to
show is reflected payload. I
want to show you a video. I
apologize if it's too small. So
in this case you are going to
run your handled like you
normally would. Load up the
reflected dol, from the
reflective pet project. You
should get out those as well.
And reflected drl are built off
the students here. Without those
projects I could not implement
this myself. So now you create
the payload. I've staged an
interpreter call back here and
running the system. And you can
use the reflect drl module and
-- memory directly into l sec
here. Okay. So it inject into l
saas this payload is getting
more to ramp up but eventually
you get a call back here into
your system. Any time now. There
you go. You get a call back and
you can interact with the
session. You can do indoor min
nigh cats. Before you can import
your modules all the way across
the wire. Any special function
require handler there's a symbol
in front of it. Differentiate
the commands. In this case I'll
import minicats. And just to
prove that it's loaded into the
memory you can take a look at
what the current process i.d.
is. Running in l saas. This is
very similar to the capability
like things like empire out it's
hard to detect in the future as
well. So invoke minicats. There
we go. You get your results back
just normally would. Minicats
for your passwords. Okay. So
under the hood the payload is
compiled net 4.0 I think you can
down to 3.5 if you needed to. It
does need system assemble where
all the internal management come
from to built out your
Powershell host. I've tested a
number of systems. As far as the
server concern it's a separate
project. You can build your own.
The listener is a sync io it
allows you to run asynchronous
processes, but tasks in the
thread. That's kind of a pet
project you can implement. You
can easily do that. Why python?
It's for the learning
experience. It helped me to
actually fill in some gaps that
I had. And I have a lot of
appreciations now that it does
behind the seen. No critique
there. It's also my performance.
Payload is compatible. As far as
the defense I haven't done too
much work in this. You can
actually probably stop attacks
in-system automation and trigger
any malicious use and see if
it's loaded and tell whether
something is there that
shouldn't be. And also new
features in Powershell 5.0 has
nice log in features. The talk
earlier today he went through a
lot of great defense techniques.
Okay. That's all I have. Big
thanks to all these people.
Wouldn't be possible. Thanks for
the encouragement. Here's all my
contacts if you have questions.
Thank you [ applause ]