Everybody count off. Good,
thanks. If there's an empty seat
next to you, raise your hand. It
looks pretty full. Anyone know
if this place has a fire code or
not? Don't start fires. If you
start a fire, you have to share.
People who have their hands up,
have a seat next to them so the
smart money goes that way. The
smart money is not in Vegas. All
right. Hi there. I'm Bruce
Schneier. Are there any
questions? It's good. That was
the easiest talk I ever did. If
there are any questions, I'm
happy to take them. There are
actually mics here. There's one
there, there's one I can't see
behind the camera guy there. >>
Do they work, though? >> Yes,
they work. That one works. >>
Thanks for coming out again. The
question is, it's an old
question and I'm wondering if
maybe you have any new insight
into answer on this. With
cryptography becoming more in
the collective consciousness,
especially with people who are
less technically savvy, there
has been an argument for a long
time trying to explain to people
that encryption is not security.
It's very common for people to
say we'll just encrypt the shit
and we're secure which obviously
is total bullshit. Do you have
any insight on how to better
explain to those people why
that's fundamentally flawed? >>
I think you're right. A lot of
people think of crypto as a
panacea where in fact it is just
a tool. And a very powerful
tool, actually it's for a bunch
of reasons, but it doesn't
automatically make security on
any data that has to be used.
One of the things that the
Snowden documents has brought
forward is metadata. So this
cell phone is a great
surveillance device because the
metadata where this phone is has
to be in the clear. Otherwise it
can't ring. Thinking about that
I should turn the ringer off. So
there's a lot of things
encryption can't do. Encryption
can protect data at rest, but if
you aren't going to make a
target corporation, you have a
database of numbers that you're
using, if it's encrypted the key
has to be there. I talk about
encryption as a tool, not as
security, just like your door
lock is a really important tool
but doesn't magically make your
house secure. What encryption
does, I think this is real
important, is it NSA
surveillance, it forces the
listeners to target -- what we
know about the NSA is that they
might have a bigger budget than
anyone else on the planet, but
they're not made of magic. They
are limited by the same laws of
physics and math and economics
as everybody else. And if data
is unencrypted, if they can tap
a translated Internet cable,
they can get everything. But if
stuff is encrypted, they have to
target who they're listening to.
If the NSA wants into your
computer, they are in. If
they're not, one it's illegal
and they're following the law
and two you're not eye enough on
the priorities list. So what
encryption does is it forces
them to go through their
priorities list. They can hack
into your computer, that's no
problem. They can't hack into
everybody's computer. So
encryption is just a tool, but
it's actually a really powerful
tool, because it denies a lot of
the bulk access and forces the
listeners to do targeted access.
And there's a lot of security
benefit in that. >> I wanted to
see your opinion on the back
door that Obama wants.
(Laughter.) I'm not sure Obama
personally has an opinion here.
It's interesting. This is --
this is the same back door that
the FBI has been wanting since
the mid '90s. We called it the
crypto war and now we call it
the first crypto war. So number
three, I'm done. It is you guys.
I only do two crypto wars per
lifetime. (Laughter.) It's
interesting. >> You're referring
to PTP? >> In general. The FBI
director gave an interesting
talk at the Aspen security
forum. I recommend listening to
these talks. This is a very high
level, mostly government
discussions about security,
cyber security, national
security, really interesting
stuff. He was interviewed by I
think Wolf Blitzer who actually
asked a great question. Why
don't you like the term lone
wolf terrorist. That was kind of
funny. He was talking about the
going dark problem and the need
for back doors and this is the
scenario he is worried about.
And he's very explicit. It is an
ISIS scenario. ISIS is a new
kind of adversary in the
government's eyes, because of
the way it uses social media.
Unlike al Qaeda, ISIS does it
with Twitter. And this freaks
the government out. So the
story, and they square up and
down this -- swear up and down
this happens, ISIS is really
good at social media at Twitter
and YouTube and various other
websites, they get people to
talk to them who are in the
U.S., like you guys, except you
know, a little less socially
adept and maybe kind of a little
crazier. But they find these
marginal people and they talk to
them and the FBI can monitor
this and go FBI, rah rah. They
say go use this secure app and
this radicalized American does,
they talk more securely and the
FBI can't listen. And then you
know, dot dot dot explosion. So
this is the scenario that the
FBI is worried about. Very
explicitly. And they've used the
story again and again. And they
say this is real, this is
happening. Now -- >> It's not
going to work, though. >> It's
sort of interesting. If this is
true -- let's take it as it is
true. Another phrase they use,
they talk about the time between
flash to bang. Flash is when
they find the guy, bang is when
the explosion happens. And that
time is decreasing. So the FBI
has to be able to monitor. So
they are pissed off that things
like I-message and other apps
cannot be monitored, even if
they get a warrant. And this
really bugs them. I have a
warrant, damn it. Can can't I
listen? I can get the metadata,
why can't I listen? So if you
think about that as a scenario,
that it's true, it is not a
scenario that any kind of
mandatory back door solves.
Because the problem isn't that
the main security apps are
encrypted. The problem is there
exists one security app that is
encrypted. Because the ISIS
handler can say go download
signal, go download this random
fire encryption app I just
uploaded ten minutes ago. So the
problem is not what he thinks it
is. The problem is general
purpose computers. The problem
is an international market in
software. So I think the back
door is a really bad idea for a
whole bunch of reasons. I've
written papers about this. But
what I've come to realize in the
past few weeks is it's not going
to solve the problem the FBI
claims it has and I think we
need to start talking about
that. Because otherwise we're
going to get some really bad
policy. (Applause.) >> Good
morning. So this will probably
go less in the direction of for
instance crypto. My question is
somewhat twofold but I'm going
to focus more on the first one.
>> Do one at a time. >> In the
course of day-to-day
interactions, both with security
people and with less
security-minded folks, I've come
to the conclusion that
operational security is very
difficult to instill. From your
experience, is there an easier
approach to getting the
understanding through? >> I
think ops sec is pretty much
impossible. If the director of
the CIA can't get it right,
we're all done. We see that in
the hackers that hack Sony. We
see people screwing it up again
and again. I'm not sure there is
a solution. Because good op sec
is really and truly annoying. It
means not using e-mail for
certain things. I've come to the
belief that we're not going to
be able to train people in good
op sec. That the best security
is going to be pretty good
security that's ubiquitous. And
we saw this in some more of the
Snowden documents. How many
people read the recent article
that came out of Germany. Okay
article, really great document
on how it works, the NSA
flexible database for monitoring
the Internet. You can read their
documents and they talk about
how they can find people using
encryption and roll up the
networks. They can't read the
traffic, but they know who is
talking to who. Metadata,
encryption doesn't solve
everything. And I'm reading
this, and it's clear you can do
this with PGP as well. You want
to find out who's using
encryption, it's easy if you
monitor enough of the Internet.
And what that tells me is that
someone would be better off not
using the great encryption
program they wrote or the really
powerful one they just
downloaded, but the average one
that everyone else is using.
That you actually are better off
using an iPhone with i message,
even though I'm pretty sure the
FBI can get at it individually.
But you can hide using it
because we're all using it. You
don't stand out. So I think
there is a lot of power in that.
You had a second part. Make it
quick. >> You answered it. It
was for propers making the use
of op sec less obvious. >> Make
it invisible. Think of SSL, good
security works if people don't
even know it's there. Encryption
from the handset to the base
station, it would be great if it
was better but it's working
because nobody knows it's there.
>> So in thinking maybe not as
thoroughly or deeply as I should
about like cyber terrorist
threats and bad actors that want
to do corporations or
infrastructure harm, these sorts
of things, or just the public,
right, it seems like all the
ingredients are there for people
to do really bad things and
there are a lot of holes and
security flaws. What keeps there
from being enough motivated bad
actors and people -- what keeps
them at bay? >> I think
fundamentally people are good.
Right? Society works because
most of us are honest. You kind
of look at me funny, but none of
you have jumped up and attacked
the person sitting next to you.
(Laughter.) You laugh, but if
this was a room of chimpanzees
that would have happened. A room
full of a lot of strangers
sitting quietly listening to me.
This sounds weird but I think a
lot of what keeps the really bad
things from happening is most
people don't want to do really
bad things. If that wasn't true,
society wouldn't work. So I
think you're right, that all the
pieces, a lot of the pieces are
there. There is a couple of
things. Terrorism is harder than
you think. Yes, technically it
can be easy, but the whole
operation is actually harder.
Which is why you don't see a lot
of terrorist attacks. What you
do see these lone wolfs that
wake up one morning say I'm
going to do something bad,
there's no conspiracy to detect,
there are no mistakes you can
make over the course of the
planet that flash-to-bang time
is so short. So I really do
think that's why. Something
interesting I would mention as
long as we're on this topic,
that a new tactic we're seeing
more of, the notion of
institutional boxing. You can go
into a company, take all of
their stuff and publish it. It's
freaking people out. This
happened to Sony, the hacking
team. The guy who did that is in
this room, thank you very much.
(Applause.) It's what might have
happened to Ashley Madison,
which is a little more awkward
for some people. (Laughter.) And
if you remember a few years ago
it was HB Gary federal. An I
think this is a really
interesting tactic because it
empowers individuals against
very powerful organizations. And
it is the first, I think the
first real counterargument I've
heard to the increasing practice
of hiring a sociopathic CEO. If
you are worried about everything
your CEO says becoming public in
three to five years, you might
not want to hire a jerk. But I
expect to see more of this.
People are noticing that
wikileaks is publishing Saudi
diplomatic cables. Someone
hacked in and is dumping all
this stuff. So that's an
interesting example of a new bad
thing that's being enabled by
technology that's happening more
and more of. But in general, I
do worry about the bad things
happening, but I think it's less
common than we think, because
most people don't do them. It's
the systemic stuff that bothers
me. The Internet of things,
being able to hack cars and
planes and heart monitors and
other stuff. And the
interconnection of those. I
think we're going to see more
unanticipated vulnerabilities.
Because remember complexity is
the worst enemy of security. It
is nonlinear, tightly coupled
complexity and that's really
what the net gives us so we've
got to be real careful there >>
I had occasion to look at it
recently and at that time you
guys had assessed that our
ability to analyze hash
functions was a good ten to 20
years behind our ability to
analyze the other primitives. I
wonder if you think that gap has
closed. >> I think we're much
better at understanding hash
functions right now. We're still
implementing bad ones but that's
more legacy. It's a very hard --
mathematically it is hard
because your assumptions are
squirrelly. I think I revised
that in the revised edition of
that book which is cryptography
engineering. But I do think we
understand crypto -- encryption
primitives better than hash
primitives. Even though you can
make one from the other. Which
is why I don't know if people
remember when there was the hash
function con test that just ran
five years ago, I built a hash
function on top of a symmetric
algorithm because I felt I
understood that better. I'm not
convinced the NSA understood the
hash functions well. Something
they're using in military
applications much until
recently. They didn't have their
rich history like they had with
encryption. >> Thanks. >> The
code in rain Dale is not the
code that's in -- I trust you
more than I trust the feds. Do
you think that AES is a
trustworthy cypher? >> I think
AES is. I trust AES. It is ring
dal. Everyone is happy with
them. It is weird because you
can actually describe the
algorithm in a linear -- in an
equation that fits on one page.
It's kind of small type but it
fits on one page which kind of
freaks people out a little bit.
But I do trust it. I think it is
secure. I do not think there is
a back door or anything snuck
in. I truly don't. NIST did a
great job with the AES process.
I really do -- NIST
unfortunately got tarred with
the new release generator and
they're trying to rebuild their
trust but they've done a
fantastic job of crypto
primitives by and large. I like
AES. Thanks for using two fish.
I like it too. I use AES without
reservation. >> As disturbing as
the current crypto war is,
something that scares me are
lava bid or some of the other
companies getting national
letters. I'm wondering what we
can do to defend against
governments secretly ordering
companies to put back doors into
their products. >> The thing
that should freak us out the
most, and to me this is the
biggest deal revelation of
Snowden and all the stories
around it. It's not that we
believe that encryption was
perfect and nobody can break it.
But we did believe that the tech
rose and fell on its own merits.
And the idea that the government
can go into a company and say
you have to break your
encryption and then lie to your
customers about it is
terrifying. The law can subvert
technology. And we cannot, as a
community, as a society, truly
believe that anything is secure,
as long as that's true. I just
talked about, you know, i
message and we don't know. And I
blogged about this as couple of
days ago. It didn't get enough
play. It's kind of the last part
of a post, but there's a
persistent rumor going on around
right now that Apple is in court
fighting an order to back door i
message and face time. And
Nicholas Weaver has written
about how they could do that.
How they can modify their
protocols to make that happen.
And we don't know. That is
fundamentally terrifying. And I
don't know how to fix that. We
have to fix that through the
legal -- there's no tech fix. I
mean, the kind of things you can
do, I think that if we thought
about it, we could rewrite the
Apple protocols such that if
they did have to put a back door
in, we would notice. We would
say why did you make the change
they would say a bullshit
answer, we would know something
was up. So maybe something
making your algorithms not back
door proof, but backdoor
evident. So maybe think more
about that. But this is a hard
one. And I don't have a good
answer. And it is one that I
think really should disturb us.
More open source is going to be
good here, more sunlight, harder
to subvert. But as long as the
government can issue secret
orders in secret courts based on
secret laws, we have a problem.
And it is not a tech problem.
It's a legal problem. >> Hi. We
seem to be in a situation where
the software industry can
release software that runs on
billions of devices and is
completely insecure and badly
written and there's no
consequence whatsoever to those
companies for the problems that
they create. Just recently what
comes to mind is heck on
android. Can you discuss
generally what you think about
this and from a legal
perspective and software
companies being held liable,
accountable for the bad software
that they write? >> I've always
been a fan of liabilities. I've
written the first thing about it
in maybe '02 or something. Maybe
even before. So here's the basic
argument. That right now as you
say there are no costs to
writing bad software. You read a
software license, it says if
this software maims your
children and we told you it
would do that, we're not liable.
Even security software says no
claims about security are made,
even though they are. So
liability changes that. It adds
a cost to not designing software
properly. It adds a cost to
insecurity. It adds a cost to
nonreliability. And that has
real value. Think about we are
already paying these costs,
we're paying it in losses, we're
paying it aftermarket security
devices, we're paying it in sort
of the entire industry that is
strung up around dealing with
the fact that the software
sucks. But with a liability we
would pay anyway, the cost would
be passed on to us of course,
but at least we'll be getting
more secure software out of it.
I see a collective action
promise, the market is not
rewarding good security. The
cost of insecurity is too low.
The value of insecurity is high.
And liability changes that. It
is a lever we can use to
rebalance this cost-benefit
ratio. And I think it's a
powerful one. It is not a
panacea. Lots of ways
liabilities go wrong. But
liabilities do a lot. They
provide value. And I think they
would a hundred percent here in
software. We know why the
Android vulnerability isn't
being promulgated. They designed
their system, Google produced
the patch but it won't go down
to the phones. The phone
manufacturers don't care very
much. They don't have that tight
connection like you have in the
iOS world. So the patch doesn't
go downstream. If suddenly the
phone manufacturers were liable,
I assure you that the patch
mechanism would work better,
right? And that's a lever we
have as society, and we should
use it. I think it's a better
one than regulation here,
because it's one that's dynamic,
and tend to seek its own level.
But that's why. That's why you
use it, and I'm a big fan of it.
Actually, thinking about this,
hang on. Everybody, smile.
There's more of you than fits on
this screen. That's not going to
work. Hang on. People at the
edges, you don't have to smile.
Thanks. Who's next? >> Bruce, it
seems like less and less surveys
seem to show that Americans are
concerned about the privacy of
their information. Often you
hear terms like I'm not hiding
anything, so I'm not worried.
And it seems like people my age
and younger don't have much of
an understanding of Edward
Snowden or the relevance of what
he released. What would you say
to those perspectives? >> I
don't know if people know I had
a book published in March called
David and Goliath. I spent a
whole chapter on that question
on privacy, why it's important.
And it's not true that people
don't care about privacy. It's
actually young people don't. All
surveys show that they do.
They're very concerned about it.
And you know this is true. You
remember being a teenager. You
don't care about the government,
because who cares, but you're
concerned about the privacy in
your world. And you know, people
who are fluent kids teenagers
who are fluent in the net are
fluent in how to maintain their
privacy. They might not do a
good job but they try a lot. I
argue that it's fundamental to
individuality, to who we are.
Without privacy we became
conformists. We don't speak out.
And I think it's a really
interesting argument in social
change. We're in a year where
gay marriage is legal in all 50
states. (Applause.) That issue
went from impossible to
inevitable with no intervening
middle ground. It's amazing. But
what it means is, and you can
take legalization of pot, you
can take a lot of issues you can
take in this way. Back then,
something is illegal and let's
say immoral. It goes from
illegal and immoral to, you
know, some cool kids are doing
it. To illegal and we're not
sure. And then suddenly it
becomes legal. But in order to
get from here to here, you've
got to be a point here where the
thing is illegal and people do
it anyway. Because you've got to
do it and say you know what?
That gay sex wasn't that bad.
(Laughter.) That was kind of
okay. You know? I tried pot and
the world didn't end. And it
might take 40 years and a couple
of generations, but then you get
to the point where it is legal.
Interracial marriage. Any of
these issues. But if you have
surveillance here. If you can
stop people from trying the
thing and saying, you know? It's
not that bad, maybe we're wrong,
you never get to the point where
the majority of us believe we're
wrong. I think surveillance,
broad government surveillance
will really have a stifling
influence on social progress.
Because it won't let experiments
to happen. Now, the argument you
can make to anybody, but I think
it is probably the most
important one. But really,
anyone who says I have nothing
to hide, you know they're lying,
right? I mean, there aren't
cameras in Scott McNeeley's
house because he has nothing to
hide. I think you have to point
out that those arguments aren't
true and that privacy isn't
about something to hide. It is
about maintaining your sense of
self in a public world. I get to
determine what I tell you people
and what I don't tell you
people. And that is empowering.
And if I lose that, I am
fundamentally a prisoner of
society. So attaching privacy to
something to hide, to secrets,
is just wrong. It's about human
dignity and it's about liberty.
I spent a whole chapter on that
and I do it better in the
chapter. So I offer that up. >>
Thank you. >> Yes? >> Most
people seem to me more worried
about back doors and forced
government back doors, but I'm
sort of more worried about
sneakers where what is your
opinion on quantum computing and
current encryption and also
quantum encryption and its
rebuttal to quantum computing.
>> Quantum encryption has
nothing to do with quantum
computing. Quantum computing is
going to become real. Probably
not in our lifetime. I think we
can factor like 24 now. But it
will get better. It has
potential to change crypto, but
not destroy it. It will break
all of the common algorithms, so
RSA, and those. It will break
those in linear time and be very
nasty. But we do have public key
algorithms that do work. His
early one that the work factor
of a square instead of
exponential. They're less
efficient, but they still work.
In theory, the best quantum
photography does is have your
key length. It reduces your
brute force search by a factor
of a square root. So double your
key length and you're done. NIST
is actually hosting conferences
on post quantum cryptography.
How can we build resistant to
quantum computing theoretical
world. Quantum crypto is really
quantum key exchange. It is a
clever way to exchange keys
using quantum properties. Really
neat, great science, great
physics, something I as a
cryptographer have no need for.
So I think it is kind of
pointless from a practical point
of view. Great science, but I
would never buy such a device
because I would use one of the
math systems and they work just
fine. So that's sort of my quick
quantum primer. But it's great
science and I love the research.
And eventually, yes. We'll be
able to factor numbers very
quickly, which will be cool.
Yes? >> I was wondering if you
caught the previous talk by
Eijah demonsaw. >> I definitely
want things -- this is the
answer about the opsec. Same
thing. The more you make it
invisible, the more you make it
transparent, easy to use, no
work. Even sacrificing some
security, I think we do better.
I'm really liking -- on my
iPhone. It's a great program. It
has a really clean interface. It
works. I can actually all the
key exchange happens in the
background, it's well designed.
I can confirm there's no man in
the middle. I don't have to but
the fact that I can is enough of
a deterrent of people trying it.
So I really like simple stuff.
Because I want everyone to use
it. There's value in it being
ubiquitous. Expert-only
encryption has much less
effectiveness. One last comment
to the quantum guy. One of the
things we know about the NSA
documents, they have a budget
line but it's not very large. >>
First of all, Bruce, you're my
security crush and do you mind
if I take a picture with you
after the show? >> I don't but
you guys all have weird pie
plates on your chest. I'm just
saying. You look like some
embarrassing cult. >> It's
Flava-flav. With the explosion
of software defined networking,
do you have specific concerns
around the security of such
leading edge technology and this
virtualization of router
switches, firewall et cetera, do
you have thoughts on that? >> I
don't have any specific
concerns, just a general of more
complexity, more things to be
insecure, and another layer of
organization. Those are my
concerns. I mean, there's huge
value in this. I'm a big fan of
security outsourcing for
organizations. It's very hard to
do right and the more you can
consolidate the expertise, I
think the better you'll do. But
there are legal risks. We've
been seeing some court cases
that the FBI can survey warrant
on Facebook for your stuff
bypassing you. They can do that.
And that does cause problems.
But in general I think the value
of outsourcing is great. And
there are security risks but I
think in benefit I tend to like
that technology. >> So it's a
balance, no major concerns over
shared control planes? >> That's
it. You've got to know all that.
Those are things to be concerned
about. But are they major
concerns? They're like
regular-sized concerns. >> All
right, thanks. >> First of all,
thank you for everything you do.
>> With the pie plate also, I'm
saying. >> My question is, even
if they wanted to, would policy
makers be able to stay current
with the pace of technology? >>
It's interesting. I think I've
got to the belief that the
United States, probably other
countries are becoming
fundamentally ungovernable.
That's one of the reasons that
technology is moving so fast,
that the people who understand
it can run rings around policy
makers. And whether it's writing
laws that five years in
retrospect you realize whoa,
they understood that and put
that sentence in and we didn't
understand that this is hard. I
like seeing laws that are
invariant. Write laws that don't
have to keep up. Laws about
assault and murder don't really
care about the weapon. I could
write a law about privacy for
communications that doesn't care
if it's e-mail or voice or voice
over IP. I can do that. I think
that's better. I'm not sure it
will happen. There's so much
co-option of the legal and
policy process by people who
stand to make and lose a lot of
money. Right now the cyber
security bill, that's probably
going to get signed, has got all
sorts of amendments and riders
and what it actually does isn't
what they say it does. And
that's an easy one. You start
doing something like health care
or climate change, forget it. So
I'm not optimistic about
lawmakers staying current
because of technology. I think
we're going to have to go
through some bad times before we
realize how to create law in a
society where tech moves so
fast. There's an argument to be
made that the modern
constitutional democracy is the
best form of government mid 18th
century technology could invent.
Travel and communications are
hard so we've got to pick one of
us to go all the way over there
to make laws in our name. It
made since in 1782. There's a
lot of ways that our systems
that were designed when nation
states started becoming a thing
are sort of breaking now because
things are different. Things are
moving too fast. The
communication is different. It's
all different. And I think we
have to redesign democracy. This
of course is ridiculous and will
never happen. But I think we
kind of need to. That wasn't an
optimistic answer, was it? >> A
few months ago there was news
about Chris Roberts being
detained at the airport after he
posted a tweet -- >> Is he here?
Okay. >> And then your blog said
that maybe FBI knew that Chris
Roberts works in the field of
avionics and that's why he was
detained. And there was news
that they had posted a warning
about it even though they claim
it was an IT issue. So what do
you think -- is the emphasis on
security -- the issue was
similar. >> So we didn't know
that Chris Roberts says that he
actually was being watched by
the FBI. That he had talked to
them before. The Chris Roberts
says is very complicated and I
stopped commenting when I
realized it was way more
complicated than I understood.
This is the case of him being on
a plane and saying something
about going into the avionics
bus via the USB port in his
seat. Which would be crazy if
you could, but it wouldn't
surprise me if Airbus forgot
about that. It really seems
every time you put physical
security people and give them an
IT security problem, they
completely forget they should
talk to a security IT person.
Anyone follow the hack on the
Brinks safe? It's completely
embarrassing. They never even
open an IT security book. Oh,
yeah, we can do this. No
problem. I don't know how much
proactive -- it does seem like
the FBI is monitoring more
groups and more individuals. And
we see them monitoring the
occupy movement or black lives
matter. I mean, real social
change movements that might not
be as, I don't know, as
mainstream as they could be. So
there's a lot of that going on.
How much -- in those cases I
don't know. The wall street case
I have no idea. Certainly
there's always a lot of bragging
that might not be true. >> But
then they posted it the day
before. >> Yeah, I don't know. I
don't know the details. And it's
hard to speculate. I think there
is more monitoring than we all
think. This is the point of
fusion centers, this is the
point of information sharing
between the NSA and others and I
think a lot of it is going on.
>> So do you trust elliptic
curves? >> I've been skeptics
for the bunch of years. Most do
trust them. My feeling is that
there's a lot we don't know
about elliptic curve
mathematics. The NSA uses
elliptic curve crypto. So I can
tell you that. So in some
instances it is secure. But I
also know that they have, in
some cases, tried to influence
curve selection. Now, for good
or for bad, I can't tell you. So
I worry about elliptic curves
where the curve selection
process isn't transparent. Now,
if you want to use elliptic
curves in your system, Dan
Bernstein, a guy we all trust
had a public process and they
are available and I would use
those without reservation. The
NSA said here's some great
curves, I would say, you know,
huh? (Laughter.) So that's my
feeling on that. I think the
math is sound, but I think there
are things we don't fully
understand. I'm getting the get
off stage soon signal so I'm
going to take -- do you have a
yes or no question? >> No.
(Laughter.) >> All right. Short
answer. Go. >> So you got me
into security, I've been in this
industry ten years. Thank you so
much. So my question is, now
that I found myself in a
position, hypothetically, where
I'm working with a government
agency, where they use the same
shitty software as everyone
else, they've got the same
problems as everyone else, and
I'm convinced that the actions
of stock piling zero days,
weakening crypto all that stuff
is harmful. >> Quick, quick. >>
What can I do to convince or
show these people that actually
these other arms of the
government are doing things that
hurt us. >> This is hard and a
lot of us are trying to do this.
Keep saying it. This is not the
tech process. I'm doing a book
signing at 4:00. Come by and say
hi. Not all of you at once. I'm
going to go outside right now
assuming there is space to
breathe. Thank you very much for
coming. Thanks for sitting. Have
a good weekend. (Applause.)