i will go ahead and get started on the
next one testing topics oh thanks yeah
i hope you enjoyed it it's fun fun topic
i'm with you on that clicker thank you
sir left right front backwards
so all right so uh we're gonna go ahead
and get started so jared so this you
know this morning we've had a couple
presenters come up from cincinnati
uh we had one uh daryl's gonna wrap it
up for us from the local dayton area but
uh we decided to go a little bit east
and uh we got one in from columbus so uh
one great thing about dayton is uh you
know kind of centrally located between
columbus and cincinnati where there's a
lot of cyber security work and the
larger organizations going on so
we kind of have that reach out to both
areas and able to bring some of this
different speakers in from those
different areas of uh
you know work and type of environment
foreign
we're not just centrally locked in with
most of the bait
means we're able to get to that that
answer a lot more quickly than we were
today
now quantum computing
is not going to eliminate
make that game any better it's actually
going to be
yes
enjoyable experience right when we look
at um
large data sets and we look at churning
through those data sets to come up with
meaningful information that is a
clear-cut practical use case for quantum
and so that's an important takeaway it's
not that we're going to have one or the
other we're going to have both and so
they're going to be some things we do in
cyber security traditional models that
still apply but there are going to be
some things that shift and change based
on where organizations start using these
other um
i don't even know what i'm pushing now
there we go
um pushing these other models so as an
example and this is from
microsoft talking about um quantum
hardware you've got no apps
your classical compute stuff on the top
and then what um
one of the the more common ways that
we're able to
observe these qubits
is we've got to slow them down enough so
that we can actually take a look
and by slowing them down and they're you
know
flying around the uh the atoms we uh um
we're using cryogenics
to just make things really really cold
um now i don't know if you've looked
into cryogenics at all it's a little
more complicated than fry and futurama
just tripping into the the container uh
it's expensive and it's big and it's um
it's one of the reasons that quantum is
limited today
that it hasn't exploded because just a
matter of scale
there has been some innovation where
uh one group was able to use magnets
to slow down these qubits to observe
them
instead of of cryogenics and those
magnets
are less expensive less
cumbersome smaller
um but the way it happens right we we do
our compute on top but we're passing
stuff down to the lower layer and then
we bring it back up for the uh
the good stuff
i think i'm pushing the wrong button the
whole time
um oh and i talked about the the magnets
because um they are less expensive but
then the whole one of the whole
challenges with quantum is uh as soon as
we observe it we change it right it's uh
this is stuff that fascinates me that i
still don't have my head around but i
would just say there are people a hell
of a lot smarter than me who have been
doing this stuff for years and have a
good idea of what do we need to do next
to make this stuff better and faster and
more accessible
when i say years
this chart from devapedia.org traces
quantum computing all the way back to
1935.
although
the items in uh white are some of the
bigger ticket items and the ones i
wanted to mention um in 1980
where we had been looking at mechanical
computers we were looking at the turing
machine for anybody who's seen um what
was the uh the movie was it an enigma
effect
with uh benedict cumberbatch is alan
turing
right uh fantastic uh fantastic story
um
what is it
thank you thank you um and so we we took
this idea of mechanical computing to
digital computing but then when we we
got to 1980 there's this conference and
they start talking about computation
uh as physics
which is where this idea of what else
can we observe
uh
how can we use that for uh computing
um and then in 1982
we had a
topology sorry
um topological quantum order
um
which is again beyond me 1985 um the the
idea of the universal quantum computer
which is like taking that that um
turing computational model and saying
well what would it look like if we did
it with physics components in using
qubits and then in
uh
somebody dropped this the first quantum
algorithm where they say well here's an
example of once we understand how to
make this technology work here's an
algorithm we can apply to actually do
these computations and then 94 was like
the the tipping point
shores factoring algorithm
it's it's it's math i'll leave it at
that but it makes this uh more real
and so from there things start to pick
up and accelerate um i'll get into error
correction a little later because that's
one of the the tripping points right now
but as we roll into
2015 2016 which is when ibm
first made quantum computing available
in their cloud and we're seeing more and
more folks it's 2022.
six years ago
ibm made this available in their their
cloud environment
this is not science fiction
this has been accessible for years and
if i go back to like
and start there how many of you
you don't mind shelf hands uh were alive
in 1980.
all of these changes have happened in
your lifetime
let that sink in for a minute we went
from this idea of could we do this
to making it a commercially available
solution that people have been using for
years
before the group of us got together
today to talk about it
that's how quickly it's been moving and
it's not slowing down
when we look at what's coming next
um
in our
space
post quantum cryptography is all the jam
that's the big scary that we need to
talk about
but i also want to point out from a
a business case
financial services really starting to
use quantum these are projections
um from futuretimeline.net looking ahead
2023 28 and 38
there are
businesses who are financially motivated
to invest in this technology and now
that it's accessible and they're able to
start seeing games seeing profits
they're going to invest more money in
the technology that's the nature of a
capitalist economic system i can make
more money i'm going to invest more
money make more money invest more money
in our world this notion of how do we
keep the secret secret
that's post-quantum cryptography because
all the crypto that we have today sorry
not nft
crypto bro crypto um all of the
cryptography that we have today that
protects data at rest data emotion data
and memory
um it will break
uh when when this
ends up in the hands when quantum
technology ends up in the hands of
people that
we would rather it didn't end up in
their hands mckenzie and company
published some research and they said
industries like finance may begin to
realize gains from quantum computing by
2025 that's a few years away and this is
another important takeaway
realized gains
means that's when they start to see that
profit so that's three years
three years from when they start to see
the return on their investment
that they are making today it's not that
they're going to start using it some of
the folks here in this room may work for
organizations who are leveraging this
technology in one way or another
and
i also saw that there's um
a couple of articles from ibm
they're an estimated two thousand to
five thousand quantum computers that
we'll see globally available by 2030
with uh
mass adoption
by 2035. 2030 is eight years away
and we're talking a high-end estimate
5000 quantum computers available
globally not all of those computers will
be used by trusted individuals some of
those computers will be used by threat
actors to target
organizations like the ones we're trying
to protect
oh gotcha
if you want to adjust the resolution to
try that because
fingers crossed
coming back
[Laughter]
all right while we are adjusting
any questions about what i've shared so
far
nobody's left so i haven't scared
anybody too bad and that's good i'm not
trying to scare people away i'm just
trying to give people perspective that
perspective yes sir helps us do our jobs
yes
didn't see any mention of richard
feynman
you guys are one step ahead of me and
what help me out who's richard feynman
i'm gonna
do my own research and update my
presentation before i share it again i
appreciate that
he's the first one that came up with a
mathematical
model for
uh making a quantum computer and seth
lloyd from mit
made the first
quantum computing component using
chemicals too
i yeah you and i need to catch up after
i need to add like a hall of fame slide
to this to really call out some of these
folks
i noticed in the book
you referenced arthur clark and steven
baxter i recognized baxter's name
i recognize baxter's name here's the
manifold series
manifold time and manifold space okay
uh
take that as a recommend i'm always
looking to something to add to my list
lester thank you was there another uh
another question yeah i wonder if you
could help this out with for me
i mean i know there's a difference
but there seems to be a very fine line
between high performance computing
resources and quantum
computing resources would you say that's
true and if it is true
what is that connection so is there a
connection between
high performance computing resources and
quantum um
[Music]
right
or not or is or what is that
yeah
this is a this is a good question and
and i want to
present it in another way
um and i i can't speak to to that um
like high performance getting into the
details of what's in scope outoscope
there but when i hear the term i think
of the terms malware and ransomware as
an analogy
right all ransomware is malware but not
all malware is ransomware
right i can have this entire body of of
stuff like malware and then ransomware
will be a subset of that what i would
think if if
and i'm just
hypothesizing here when we look at the
idea of high performance computing is
that where you are
uh yeah yeah good to go thank you
that as quantum becomes more or quantum
computing becomes more and more
accessible and available
it it's likely to still be categorized
in that
high performance computing but you you
might still have digital computing
that's also high performance but
um i don't know if anybody has another
uh opinion perspective to offer up on
that that's yeah
there is one more algorithm called
growers algorithm which was uh started
in 1996
so where the non-steps database is easy
to find
in any data so it's called grover's
algorithm that is like
i'll have to look into that one um yeah
what what i am going to ask for the the
the row here right or the column
um if you are on linkedin please send me
a note with these notes uh if you're not
uh protonmail i can get you my proton
mail i've got uh i've got one yes sir
the difference that
until like the last two years quantum
was more very specialized
in the sense that it can only do certain
things
it wasn't really you couldn't like write
a standard program to do just anything
quantum bits were really made to do
certain types of calculations
okay as they've changed over the last
couple of years they're starting to get
into that
like you said touring kind of mindset
where they now are becoming processors
got it i think that's the difference
between like a super computer
is until recently they were doing
different things
but
it's trying to change i mean we now just
have one that's now a thousand times
faster
and now we're starting to do analogs
that they're starting to compete with
that's the same crap interesting
interesting and for folks um on the
the remote
uh i'll do my best to share what i can
with what because i know you can't hear
everybody in the room
i know you guys know
jaspen
they
have a big investment on this already
i know that because they're still a very
high level
scientist
so we're hearing some stories about some
uh poaching quantum experts from one
company to another to
follow the money folks it's it's really
going to drive what what happens um in
this space
um
so uh one one other uh stat i picked up
the worldwide uh market for quantum
computing is predicted
to be more than 10 billion dollars with
a b by 2024
and 65 billion dollars by 2030.
and i know
highly technical crowd here it's
important to take these numbers and keep
them in your hip pocket because as we
hit these milestones
that's when the changes are going to
come into the organization
where suddenly we're investing in these
technologies and we expect the people
working in the organizations to have
that that knowledge
how many folks ran this on your home
computers
if you ran it in a data center don't
admit to it in front of anybody
right seti at home
i i share this as uh you know looking
back to look ahead
um so setting at home for folks who
aren't familiar with the project
pointing radio telescopes out into space
listening
and then bringing back large sets of
data and saying boy now we just got to
go through all this data and look for
aliens
um turns out the folks running the
project didn't have enough computers or
compute power
to go through all that data in a timely
fashion so they crowdsourced it they
just put it out on the internet and said
hey do you want to help us look for
aliens if so
run this program on your computer and it
can run in the background it can run in
the foreground there have been a couple
of assist admins who lost their jobs by
trying to support this project by
installing it without permission on all
the
servers in their data center but this
notion of
i'm going to take a lot of data and find
a more clever way to go through it
really hit me here
but as somebody who
has an unfortunate
family history of of cancer i've seen
more people uh pass
there are good things
from this technology it's it's one thing
to look at
uh you know let's look for aliens right
that's neat that's and i dig it i really
dig it we can change and save lives when
we take this technology
and apply it in a way like let's get
clever about
looking through very large data sets
quantum computing
opens this up right this is a great use
case and i offer this up because when we
talk about quantum in cyber security um
it's easy to think man this is going to
break
all the confidentiality stuff that we've
got in place today right if we can't
rely on encryption then
i i just had an executive at a company i
support asked me this yesterday on a
call because i before we got into the
call i was talking about coming out here
today and talking about this and he said
yeah i heard about that
doesn't that mean that cyber security is
just not going to work anymore
and i had to say well
it's it's going to change how we do some
things
um
but it's important while we're
working on ways to secure
technology while these changes are
coming that we don't resist or fight
against this change i i and that's a
personal uh stance that i take that if
you can recognize the benefits of this
then figuring out how to enable people
to do this securely
saves lives it has a big big impact
so getting into the specifics of how
does it impact us cryptography relies on
random number generation we we count on
uh whether it's hash generation or you
know whether it's very strong encryption
keys
that when uh when we create
um
data sets and and then we're protecting
them by encrypting them that somebody
else can't just guess
that very large random number right it's
it we're counting on the fact that it's
too complex for them to be able to get
to the same data that we just protected
pki
also relies on secure key exchange
mechanisms
and that's an important
one to call out we're not just trying to
protect the encryption and encryption
but we're trying to protect the keys
that we're using to encrypt and decrypt
and we've got to share them with people
if we're going to exchange encrypted
data with them and
um this gsm
standard relying on symmetric symmetric
encryption
it's an important takeaway that it
didn't hit me initially when i think gsm
i think older cell phones right
i think like early
early gen is anybody who goes and gets
the latest and greatest right they're on
5g or lte or whatever acronym we want to
use today they're not using gsm are they
i don't know but
iot
iot devices gsm is incredibly popular as
i understand it as a way for those
devices to communicate with one another
and when we look at iot
and i
am going to ask because i don't know
uh if i look at self-driving vehicles
how how is the
the data that's being sent to and from
those vehicles encrypted
how is it being protected is that gsm
does anybody know anybody
more likely
more more lte good
yeah getting started on that
right
uh usually they're mbiot standards or m1
standards uh lte 1 standards which are
used to communicate as opposed to the
chip sets and that's often
and they use uh lte or inner van lt
good you seem to know a lot about lte or
iot are you are you doing a talk today
on that
i hope now i'm glad we got daryl here to
to bring that that in um but uh even uh
symmetric encryption um which when i
look at uh tls certificates on the
internet they rely on symmetric
encryption
um
there are three examples here
of things that just work securely today
because the people who researched and
developed these algorithms and these
mechanisms for protecting data
spent decades doing it we put decades
deploying it and we've been spending
that same amount of time securing it and
these are three of the the top items at
risk when um when encryption is no
longer available
um there was a
quantum decryption proof of concept from
combo effort between google and the kth
royal institute of tech in stockholm
and um they were using a this is for the
math folks in the room they were using
modular exponentiation
to demonstrate that if they had
a 20 million cubic computer
they could break a 2048 bit rsa number
in eight hours
right the amount of time it takes me to
get my coffee to get my bourbon
and i know some of you will get that
but by comparison it'll take a classical
computer
around 300 trillion years
to break
2004 rsa 2048 bit encryption key that's
according to quinn assessments labs and
i've got the link here if you wanted to
read the poc
but that's what we're talking about in
terms of the exponential speed of
breaking these very large numbers
that data that we thought
was going to be protected for centuries
or
trillions of years
is now potentially
exposed to threat actors in the course
of the standard business day
yeah
all right
i like where you're going yep
i think i think we might be about 100
now so yeah 20 million is
currently
pretty far off and there's another
important um distinction i'll make
when we talk about uh error correction
and whether or not those uh those
um what i want to say
not functions transactions
whatever they are whether they're
error-free or not it determines whether
or not the size of the quantum computer
you can actually
achieve similar results with a much
smaller quantum computer
if uh you have error-free calculations
which is the word i was looking for a
minute ago and couldn't find
but that's a good call out right this is
that's why this is more of a a thought
experiment right they they didn't
demonstrate it because they actually had
it this was more of a projection of this
when we hit this state when we get this
kind of computer that's when it's uh
it's going to break but i mean pac-man
how how large is the pac-man game file
what is it 32-bits not bits
kilobytes
eight bits it's
pac-man right and of course i i'm gonna
age myself here date myself right
that game
was ridiculously tiny and dropped in
what 81.82
what's the latest overwatch right the
latest halo latest call of duty
these are how many gigs and we've got a
a shift we've had a shift from a little
uh character running around eating dots
to
um fully immersive and interactive games
where you just get totally caught up in
these fictional worlds
again in the course of our lifetime when
we get to the point that we've got a 4
bit error-free quantum computer that
they can do those calculations it's not
as far off as that 20 million number
makes it feel
yeah
there is only 127 processor which has
been developed by ibm
one more time
so today 127 cubits is
is the current yeah give it time it it
we'll see that number grow and it's it's
the innovation it's the people who are
saying we don't have to freeze it let's
use magnets it's the things that these
people are thinking about and
experimenting with that they'll find
ways to make this more
uh error-free more
efficient
we're just
i i don't see why not and so the
question was do i think it's going to
follow moore's law does anybody think no
i mean when i look at all things
technology
probably faster that's frightening
why why probably faster you got me
wondering now well
advancements in a lot of areas of
technology outstrip wars laws okay
that was transistor capacity
that's no that's a good point moore's
law was reflective of a different
earlier tech and with advances in tech
you know can have some areas or less
yeah
the ones that are going to provide the
most finance of money
far out
yeah the ones that are getting funded
are going to be yeah absolutely
to the 16 bits and encryption bids
can you raise much safer single future
um
it's a good question so the question was
how many bits do we need to protect
ourselves and i do have some
recommendations later ones around like
jumping from an aes 128 to an aes 256 if
you're using aes encryption
to make your your data quantum resistant
but to protect your data from quantum
attacks
um
we need to think about it differently
i've got a couple of things i'll get to
in a moment there but it's it's like we
can't solve the problem
based on
what we used to do we have to do
encryption differently
this is the the call out it's an article
from insider intelligence.com
they said that um you know you could
break uh
uh by rs they didn't put the key
strength but uh using 4 000 error-free
qubits um you can defeat rsa in seconds
and the stat i have over here on the
right um was
related to uh
um eo that's uh the growth in e-commerce
over the next five years
because every transaction right with
somebody made the comment about buying
from amazon earlier today right
i know how many amazon boxes show up at
my house and i know i need to take the
login away from some people
but
um
and
yes good call out smile.amazon.com
these transactions uh require encryption
to protect the credit card numbers right
to protect the the information and so um
while we're we're seeing this change
right where this this technology is
becoming faster more available
we're also seeing a parallel trend
unrelated where people are embracing all
things online even more and when we look
at advances in augmented reality virtual
reality uh how gaming is impacting uh
the development of that space because
gaming has a huge audience
and is drawing money in there um
all of this underscores the the need to
uh to get ahead of it
another shift is this notion that we
don't have to rely on the little plastic
identification cards that we carry
around in our wallets and our purses
anymore there are multiple states that
already support digital identity and
more than 20 states have either
considered tested or already launched
those including colorado hawaii
mississippi ohio and the territory of
puerto rico
um
when we're talking about protecting
encrypted data we're not just protecting
amazon purchases we're protecting the
identities that we use for applying for
bank accounts for applying for loans for
traveling internationally
for anything that requires an identity
boy it's kind of important to get ahead
of
keeping that data safe from people who
shouldn't be able to use it or abuse it
and then the other uh
uncomfortable conversation
um with a solarwinds hack
we saw a lot of data exfil
and people and this has been true for
people during that hack anybody who's
gone through a hipaa breach of
healthcare data it was encrypted
we're okay
right the attackers got encrypted data
so they got nothing that is not true
if i have a criminal organization if i
have a state-sponsored organization
who has their hands on an encrypted
trove of data
from a u.s uh branch of the the military
pick one
that has uh op information that has uh
contact information
that has
even in police departments undercover
uh individuals right when
that data is decrypted it's not just a
credit card that's expired so who cares
no that's that's stuff that those people
who want to exact revenge are going to
be able to act on
people are going to die
when that date is decrypted
and
we are at a point that
you can't just expire and undercover
identity right or expire the contacts
who helped you in a uh in an operation
against uh the the controlling regime
um
and so that's not just a past thing if
if you at the organization you work with
today
have an encrypted
data store that oh my god i hope nobody
ever gets their hands on this
and it makes its way out the door you're
not out of the woods just because it was
encrypted
so what we're uh seeing and this started
this pro this effort five years ago
right so this is 2017
they said uh we got to get ahead of this
quantum stuff what can we do how about
post-quantum cryptography how do we
encrypt data
securely
once quantum computing becomes more
readily available
and they actually kind of went back to
the drawing board and said we just need
new math
right the the math that we built
traditional encryption models on it's
not just that we can use stronger keys
which is our instinct today how strong
can i make my encryption key no
we've got to do encryption differently
does anybody work with lattices in the
math that you do
i don't know if that's
i i took calculus i was able to squeeze
five years of math into a four-year high
school degree and i don't remember a
damn thing from my calculus class i
tried
but it was it was a stretch and um i've
not been able to retain it
but they took 69 candidates
for
uh a post-quantum computing standard in
round one
and then put them through the paces
round two they got it down to 17
candidates and by this point they said
we're going to do uh pke and key
establishment algorithms and then we're
going to separate those from digital
signature algorithms slightly different
implementations so let's treat them
differently and then in round three they
shortlisted that to seven finalists and
eight alternates and their goal
was to publish a draft standard by 2024
which
is about five years projected before
google and ibm have committed to a one
million quantum uh or one million cubit
uh quantum commuter going live
um
so as john mentioned at the top of the
day and then right before i i
stepped up here
um on july 5th
nish said all right we're good here's
draft one
we have and i love this the nerd in me
you can have crystals kyber or crystals
dilithium uh for pke right km or uh the
digital signature and then falcon and
sphynx plus are available for digital
signatures and then they've already got
um four more candidates for round four
bike classic
elise
um hqc and and psych
so today
if you
well don't do it because it's saturday
go home hang out have some fun wait till
monday
but if you wanted to start reading up
on what's coming what do i need to
understand you don't need to necessarily
understand the ins and outs of these
algorithms
knowing what they are knowing which
vendors are trying to build
implementations around them knowing
who's working in the open source
community to build
uh solutions that align with this
standard that's what we need people to
learn today and that's what we're going
to need in the next three to five years
when this becomes more readily
available and then also keep an eye on
this nist working group because whatever
they release next it's going to be what
another year two years that's going to
drive how we solve this uh this problem
it's not just though that we're building
these solutions
i through the course of my career i
worked everything from hardware support
to help desk to entry-level
security analysts
managing building programs consulting
sales
and i did this on purpose i wanted
perspective of what it's like to work in
all these different roles
and when i put my sales hat back on
and i look at the
cyber security market that micah you had
those two graphs up here it's nuts folks
the amount of money that's being thrown
into this space is
unfathomable and it's because it's it's
that important
it's because that's how our world
operates now with all the technologies
that drive everything from keeping our
water clean to enabling those amazon
purchases
we need cyber security to make sure that
things aren't being disrupted or broken
and so there are vendors who are already
in this space of all things quantum and
post quantum
quantum dice and id quantique
uh are their technology focuses on
quantum random number generators
cats quantum security and toshiba have
the the key distribution uh and quantum
secure communications which gets into uh
fiber optics um pq shield and then um
cipher lock uh have uh post quantum
cryptography and quantum resistant
uh technologies and then xanadu um
uh
has a full stack quantum machine
learning um if this is your jam
and you want to learn more about where
this stuff is going
these people are already moving there
quickly
take a look at what they've published
connect with them if you use linkedin
talk to the people at the companies and
say you know what can you tell me about
what you're doing they want to tell
people they want people to know what's
going on and this is a a short list
these are just a couple of the ones that
stood out to me there are a lot more
folks in that space
but as that money is going into
financial institutions who want to use
quantum computing to make more money
then you're also going to have cyber
security companies building quantum
resistant and quantum
like post-quantum cryptography solutions
to solve that problem
and then
you may not know this but congress
actually passed the u.s
national quantum initiative act in
december of 2018.
didn't get a lot of press there's a lot
of other things that end up
in the news but one of the the
statements was arguably the key
bottleneck in quantum computing
industry will be the lack of talent
while universities churn out computer
science graduates at an accelerating
pace there is still too little being
done to train the next generation of
quantum computing professionals
it's not that we need folks to learn
this today it's that we needed them to
learn it five years ago
and we're still you know catching up and
trying to figure out how do we get there
ahead um
that uh bleeds into uh there's a
resource i want to share in just a
moment
i'm going to ask that if you look at
web3 or anybody who follows jack dorsey
web5
web 2 plus web 3.
um
put put all the buzzwords and marketing
aside
when we see the evolution of what we've
called web one traditional internet
based on the semantic web paper to web 2
where
organizations control the infrastructure
and users are creating the content which
is where we are right now
web 3
is the language we use to describe the
decentralization of these technologies
can i stand up
a device at my house that has the
ability to talk to a device of my
neighbors that has a device to talk to
their neighbors and we create our own
internet
you can do that today with uh like what
is it
i2p
um
like tor
there's there are a couple of of
alternatives to tor that are built on
that peer-to-peer networking well if we
look at the advances in 3d printing
accessibility of some of this technology
the growth of the maker community
there are all these things coming
together and saying look we don't have
to put all our data at facebook or at
amazon we can
own it
and make it our own and build things
that uh from a hardware and software
perspective
decentralize that take it out of their
hands there's even a term doused
decentralized autonomous organizations
it's very common in web 3 about these
these organizations that don't really
have a leader right they don't have a a
board they don't have a ceo but they
still work and this is this is real
stuff that's already happening today as
you look at web 3
and some of the technologies that
are coming out of the the folks working
in that space
we have an opportunity to think
differently about privacy data and now
this is where i'm going to be a little
heretical
and say what if we didn't have to
encrypt social security numbers
i don't think we have to protect them
once we we get to this point if
i can take this notion of confidential
data there are certain data elements not
all of them
certain data elements that i can make
publicly available and i'm not talking
the lifelock ceo who puts his social no
i'm not talking that i'm talking
when we change how people can use our
private data
when this decentralization enables me to
have more real-time control over that
data
then if i go to apply for a car loan and
somebody wants to run my credit and they
need my social i get a notification on
my phone
that it checks some blockchain that says
here's jared's social
we want to use it to run credit do we
have jared's permission to do that
i authenticate with my thumb right or
you know face whatever you want to do
and at that time i can say yes it's okay
to use my data
if we can get to a point where we have
decentralized technology that gives
users more control over their data
we don't have to keep everything
encrypted anymore
we can change uh
pci and credit card encryption now there
will be some things like my private
health information i still want that
protected that's a privacy thing privacy
and security are related they're not the
same
when it comes to those military
operations and you've got
information that puts people's lives at
danger no that still needs to be
encrypted that's where we see the value
of post-quantum cryptography but don't
think we have to do everything the same
as we're doing it today
it's not just a matter of changing
encryption and decryption it's embracing
uh
ancillary technologies
to enable us to do things differently
and if we accept that
if we let go of some of the old ways
that we used to to do this stuff and say
we're going to support
these projects
we're going to build out these
technologies then you reduce the impact
to the folks that
you support and protect every day
whether it's folks you work with whether
it's your family whether it's your
friends
that's the the impact of making these
changes
so some strategic planning questions
um today
right what can we do because i've i've
talked about a lot of big picture stuff
and there's a lot of stuff that
sounds like boy it'd be great if we
could get there how the hell are we
going to get there
i understand that some of this is a
little further off pulling it closer to
the here and now if you go back to your
organization and just say let's take a
look at our data classification standard
let's look at our sensitive data sets
business critical
right what are they
do we know where all that data is do we
know what the elements are in that data
that that kind of inventory is an
important first step and then you take a
look at quantum computing and ask the
questions well when quantum computing
hits
uh from an operational perspective not a
security perspective it's operational
how's that going to hurt our business
are we going to lose business to
competitors because we've got an
advantage now that goes away
once quantum becomes more readily
available and at the same time what are
the business opportunities
where are we getting hammered today as a
company that boy if we had data or if we
had the opportunity to churn through
really large data sets very quickly
where could we edge out our competition
understand how quantum is going to
affect your business before you look at
the security stuff and then the other
question what training do you need
around web and quantum i mean i i
appreciate the the
university space i worked at osu for a
number of years and i'm a strong
proponent
of lifelong learning a lot of that's
from my my stoicism background but uh
i firmly believe that we we can't ever
stop
learning about the new stuff
right even if it's just like spending a
saturday here listen to jared rant and
rave about quantum right that's an
opportunity for us to to take away
something we didn't know or didn't
understand before
we need to have these conversations with
the leadership of our organizations
do you have training for me do i
understand how to build a smart contract
do i understand the difference between
the ethereum blockchain and the solana
blockchain
right there there's some
basic stuff you can learn today that's
going to be the building blocks to get
you to that three to five year goal
of how can we leverage
uh decentralized technology to minimize
the the potential threats of quantum
computing and then who are you going to
partner with to address your gaps and
again this comes from working with
vendors not every vendor is evil i can't
vouch for all of them
but i can tell you
that
if you get in with the right group of
folks
and say keep me in the loop let me be
your beta tester right bounce ideas off
me because this is my day job and this
is a prospective vendor that you don't
have when you're off developing your
solution in a vacuum
right if you partner with these
organizations today the stuff that they
build is going to be better
and it's going to be more
useful
to the people that you're supporting and
that you're trying to protect
this list of recommended actions comes
from the belfor center belfor center for
science and international affairs
research
which is part of harvard
harvard
i'll leave this up here but they had
some recommended actions for if you're
in the government space
here's our our recommended list of
things that you should do today
if you're in the private business space
here's our recommended list of things
you should do and if you wanted to see
more detail
the publication quantum computing and
cyber security is freely available on
their website it's a takeaway that you
could go back and say okay this will
give me a little more direction
recommendation for university i don't
see the theater
oh that's a good call out
take it up i mean they're that's a
higher ed institution that's a miss on
their part that's a good call out
yeah put some university recommendations
yes
this area is not just for computer
science
so what is your opinion about that
about where this lives in the university
space
when i was at ohio state
um and this was
five plus years ago maybe close to seven
they were trying to interview introduce
a cyber security major
and the uh internal argument the game of
hot potato right who's going to own it
right fischer college of business well
no this is cyber security that's a
technical thing computer science no this
i mean has business impact we're doing
research this is more of a tactical
operational thing it ended up in
international affairs
counter-terrorism yeah right blew my
mind but that was the closest lady you
found somebody who had the ownership and
the passion for it from a
a technical standpoint computer science
absolutely has to be involved i'll stand
by that because
what we're talking about from a
technical level can
easily be misconstrued or misinterpreted
once it gets to the business side
but if if i were
if i had my brothers
i would have
parallel programs and i don't know that
universities do this
but it's it's a blend between uh
whatever the college of business is in
the college of uh science and then maybe
you know international terrorism for
kicks that's a
whole nother thing
and i'm almost done here last few slides
if you only do three things right and
these are the if i'm talking low hanging
fruit these are the apples that have
already fallen on the ground
if you've got 128 bit aes keys in play
next time you change them
explore the production impact of bumping
them up to 256
because it's going to take more compute
to do the encrypt decrypt
if it slows the apps down to the point
that they're unusable you've done more
harm than good don't do that
but if you can
um
making it harder
for this data to be
compromised
it just gives you more time to make
those changes kick in the can down the
road
explore emerging technologies like
blockchain blockchain is not just a
public ledger
you can do full compute in the
blockchain
a lot of folks will look at blockchain
and say well that's just a an immutable
ledger where i can put a historical
record of data no
it's more than that
explore those those other options to see
what you can do
passwordless authentication and
self-sovereign identity i think are two
of the things that we're talking about
you see a lot of ssi i read a white
paper from world economic forum a few
years back where they were talking about
ssi
um but uh with the group like the 502
alliance or fido alliance um what
they're doing
with passwordless authentication these
are um again building blocks that help
us get to uh
a different way of doing things and then
um etsy the um
etsi.org
migration strategies and recommendations
to quantum safe schemes
um they've got a a
brief white paper i'll go ahead and tell
you the right the avoid the click bait
inventory compilation prepare your
migration plan and then execute
migration that's what it was down to
figure out where you're going to be most
impacted make a plan and act on it but
those are the three things i'd recommend
you do today
and then for further reading i've got an
article from forbes american scientist
and then
the quantum security
world economic forum is a fantastic
resource folks if you are not following
that group as a cyber security
professional you're missing out because
what they're talking about impacts so
much of what we do and where we're going
but their call out for us a quantum
security coalition
it's a big one
and then
i've got a couple of youtube videos
linked here throughout that i think are
useful and then ibm's got a lot
out there i am wiped out i'm right at
three o'clock um i'm on linkedin a lot
that's how i stay in touch with people
when i'm sitting at home being a full-on
introvert
if you want to talk if you want a copy
of this presentation uh pdf you can
shoot me a note at
jaredbrunninconsulting.com
or you can
shoot
oh and john's already got it you already
got on the website no no no but it will
be
it will be it'll be out on the ois
website lots of ways for you to get your
hands on this information we are not
trying to hide it i want you to take it
i want you to use it i want you to have
an advantage when it comes to getting
ahead of this
yeah oh you've absolutely got it i want
more people to know about this than uh
that i can get in front of
so uh folks thank you i've got like zero
minutes left for questions but we've had
some answers any questions here at the
very end before i shut up for real
all right i really appreciate the time
today please don't hesitate to hit me up
if you want to keep the conversation
going thank you
thank you
put this to use there you will