good afternoon everyone I hope you enjoy
the conference so far
my name is here and together with me on
stage we have a girl and actually our
roots in the industry come from the
field of web application security
ranging from the exciting days of watch
fire and after we got acquired also in
IBM but in the past seven years our
focus has shifted to mobility mobile
security I co-founded Sky Hill and eager
was one of our first employees and we
focused on many areas of mobile security
os security in network security and
application security and today what we
want to do is actually discuss
differently pitting coding pitfalls
we've identified over deals how they
happen how they can may be mitigated etc
and we will start with a very quick
overview of OS level issues ID issues
and then the core of the presentation
will be around application security
afterwards then we will conclude take a
few examples that we cover today and
perform a live demonstration of how
those coding pitfalls might be exploited
so let's start with OS so obviously I
think that when software is developed
new coding pitfalls arise and the same
applies to any operating system I've
ever seen I can show you that over the
years we've seen hundreds of distinct
security issues publicly disclosed both
for iOS and Android and because of the
great value of security issues in those
operating systems the belief is that the
actual number of new vulnerabilities
that are being identified and exploited
is much higher than what is publicly
discussed so I think that when it comes
to OS it can range from esoteric very
weird glitches such as the glitter in
FaceTime that was identified earlier
this year by a 14 years old boy and it
practically allowed to set up a group
call in FaceTime and be able to snow
into the microphone and others other
conditions also to the video even before
the victim had a chance to either pick
up or hang up
I think a more interesting example of
our notable security issue in operating
systems is goto fail
so how many of you are familiar with
goto fail okay okay
so this is a security issue that was
identified a few years ago it actually
existed in iOS for about 17 months until
it was patched and I think for those of
you that would develop it might be very
familiar to you from your own story so
what we seen here is is it is a piece of
the the phases of TLS handshake right
the diesels responsible for forward
secrecy and this piece of code just have
to verify part of the change of the keys
so this is a function it needs to return
zero if everything okay if not obviously
something else and I think the most most
important part of the code is obviously
that function but if you come to look at
this implementation that actually
existed in iOS and also Mac OS the big
problem lies here looks like you go in
like copy double pasted right so because
there is it there isn't any usage of
heavy buckets etc what practically
happens is that the first go-to fail
happens if something wrong happens to
the update function but regardless the
second one will be executed if not that
means that the critical code in here
doesn't even get executed under any
circumstances and a problem with that is
that practically if the first kind of
the first list of functions are just
okay and not fail we get into the
situation where the function returns
zero presumably verified that phase but
it didn't really and that kind of
mistake actually led to the ability of
Amanda middle attacker - not only snow
upon the plain text communication right
but also into the encrypted
communication okay so bit on the IDs so
again another interesting attack from a
few years ago was Xcode ghost in this
case developers mainly from China we're
using a mirror site to download upgrades
for
Xcode mainly because of limited of
bandwidth problems with the official
Apple sites so what happened was that
they downloaded an IDE that would inject
malicious code after the app was already
built into the binary before it was
signed and sent to the App Store for
review now because at the time much of
the review process of Apple dependent on
reputation and those apps had hundreds
of millions of end-users using them they
were approved by Apple and went on the
store and all of those users were
infected and it took quite some time
until Apple realized it and took them
down from the store yes just an anecdote
we've been following those incarnations
for many years and even though the
initial publication happened end of 2015
to these very days we still see
instances of compromised versions of
those apps used by people because they
didn't updates their application
versions so let's jump on jump over and
discuss a few with pitting coding
pitfalls we have seen constantly coming
back and back and back the first one we
call it hospital gown and I want to give
you a quick illustration of why that
happens and later on what are the
ramifications so let's look at this
diagram let's imagine that we have a
development team that develops photo app
right and now the product manager wants
to add an ability to upload new photos
from the mobile app to the servers right
so they go to the developer the
developer says sure no problem
immediately things no problem let's just
take those files upload them to s3 it
then goes to the DevOps engineer and
tells them I need a way to upload files
to s3 Davis regional provides the user
access key and quickly after we have a
new shiny functionality the developer
incorporated that access key into the
mobile app what's the problem comedy of
errors right
what actually happens is that now we
have a mobile app that any hacker can
take reverse-engineer and extract the
keys form and in this case what happens
is this is a very promiscuous version of
an access key that can allow to actually
access all buckets in s3 okay so usually
when we talk about this use case to our
colleagues in the industry to say well
that's terrible that might happen not
likely to happen to me or not likely to
happen at all and therefore what we
decided to do is to actually analyze
millions of apps millions of mobile apps
using static and dynamic analysis and we
looked into applications that try to
upload stuff to the cloud cloud storage
Microsoft Amazon schoolgirls and others
and we're actually amazed to see a huge
amount of applications that did exactly
those kind of mistakes okay as an
anecdote we looked into applications
that upload stuff to s3 and have you
know the utilization of an access token
there and 46 percent of those and these
tokens that allow access to all buckets
not only the bucket you plan to upload
files to ok and just to clarify the
ramifications of those findings are
actually hundreds of millions of users
sensitive records the results are
actually confidential sensitive
corporate files that were stored in
different buckets in the account but
well suddenly exposed because of those
mistakes who actually came across
backups of internal systems again that
will back up to those buckets so let's
try to understand why this happens often
first thing is let's look at the default
policies of AWS if you go to AWS and you
look for s3 this is what you get and the
default policies the main ones are
read-only or full access and what you
might notice is that both of them always
rely to all of the buckets all of the
directories everything and by using
those default policies this is the usual
fail point where the developers make the
mistake
now how you could try and resolve this
first option is to use pre signed URLs
pre-signed URLs is a feature supported
by AWS where you generate a unique URL
to to a specific file it has a signature
it has an expiration date and it's
extremely secure you can go and upload a
single file to the application and it
even goes away after a time the overhead
here is that I'm trying to build
something that's scalable I'm trying to
use the cloud and I still need to talk
from the client to the server for each
file I want to upload so that I will get
this unique URL and permission to upload
this file so let's look at another
alternative another alternative would be
to build a custom policy this time we'll
only give the specific permission in
this case only upload a single file at a
time and we will limit it to our
specific buckets of course we'll build
such a policy per bucket and each thing
should be used only for the specific
purpose now once we do that we still
have one minor issue that you could
override files using that same key you
could easily solve this by generating a
secret or a random token and adding it
to the file name so that others can't
either maliciously or by accident guess
your file name and override it another
layer of security that you might want to
adhere to prevent others from making the
same mistake that you have avoided is to
add the bucket encryption bucket
encryption allows you to attach a KMS
key per bucket which means that not only
do you have to have the specific
permission to access files on that
bucket and write to that bucket but you
also have to have access to this key
meaning that if someone else uses the
default policy he won't have the key
thus he won't be able to list the file
and take them from your bucket that
you're trying to secure okay so this was
one one issue wanted to share with you
another one relies really relates to man
in the middle attacks so obviously over
this men the middle has become a very
prominent discussion in the industry and
I think had a very important impact on
an industry on the positive side we've
seen a significant growth in the
utilization of encryption right in
different services and and and service
and service and it actually is the best
key against men demeanor attacks right
now when you come to think about what
you need to do in order to implement
encryption and protect yourself against
minidom in their attacks when you think
about browsers as an example you have a
situation where the developer of the
browser does not know how the users will
use it right where will they browse to
which kind of service they will connect
to and therefore the challenge is first
of all before you encrypt to make sure
that the server the client tries to
connect to is indeed the server itself
and then obviously encrypts the
communication between the two sites and
the challenge just mentioned led to the
utilization of the concept of chain of
trust right identifying a bunch of third
parties trusted sources we call it we
call them what CAS having them their
certificates already pre-installed or
installed by the browser or by the host
itself and then by giving them the
responsibility to verify the identity of
servers and then mathematically sign-on
their certificates with a nice model
where the agents the clients the browser
can try to connect to a server get a
certificate compare the domain to the
subject in the certificate and then just
validate that the certificate itself is
mathematically signed directly or
indirectly by a would say that's awesome
that works very very well the big
problem is that as encryption went up
attackers started to focus on the weak
point in that model which is obviously
that list of trusted CAS right so what
that occurs started to do more
more either by exploiting security
issues or just by social engineering
they just focused on getting a bad would
CA into the trusted list and then from
that that moment the whole model fails
because that allows a man-in-the-middle
attack you to provide an invalid
certificate that would be signed by the
malicious would CA and from the
perspective of the client-side
everything looks legit because all the
steps that just mentioned are working
okay
now let's think about for a moment about
mobile applications in those situations
that the Vella pel of the client is
usually also the owner of the critical
servers with which the mobile app is
communicated with right that opens the
door for certificate pinning so again as
developers we are used to look at the
let's say the high level and when we
make requests we look at the responses
this is the data part we kind of ignore
this critical part of the handshake that
happens at the beginning and in order to
implement this pinning correctly we will
have to get into this process as well so
let's split it into a few steps we'll
have to hook the handshake phase be able
to look at the specific certificate we
still want to do all the validations
that the operating system does for us
making sure that this certificate is
actually valid it signs the correct
domain expiration dates etc and the last
part will be adding our own validation
layer where we would compare the
specific certificate that we received
with a trusted list that our application
will maintain preventing others from
going around this mechanism so a bit
about code let's say we're using iOS and
we use URL session in order to make our
requests we can register a delegate and
this callback is basically our first
step that we mentioned this is the hook
and here we are in the middle of the
handshake part we received a certificate
and we have the ability to either accept
or reject the specific certificate and
add our own validations second part is
the default behavior of the operating
system we just create a default policy
do the SSL validations just as the
operating system would and here the
third part is the part where we add our
own mechanism to try and add the
additional validation so let's look at a
couple of interesting implementations
for this first one is taking the whole
chain in this case we chose to sign and
validate the leaf certificates so zero
here that you see is basically the first
part first certificate in the chain this
is the leaf we will generate a
fingerprint and compare this fingerprint
with a trust at least that our
application maintains and needs to be
up-to-date all the time now a common
problem with that is that it's again
high maintenance we will usually replace
our certificates once a year that means
that each time before we upload the new
certificate to the site we need to
release a new application in advance and
for those users that do not often update
their application we need to dynamically
pass on the information of the new
fingerprint so that the old application
is still aware of the new fingerprint
exists so one other option that we can
implement is not looking at the complete
certificate but rather looking at the
public key assuming that it has not been
compromised we could earn some time and
reduce the frequency of replacements of
certificates off of the application by
generating for two or three years this
new certificates each year from the same
public and private keys allowing us to
still do the fingerprinting but not
having to
the app each time we replace the
certificate so we've done that and
probably some of you are kind of feeling
that they're afraid because okay make
some mistake we don't update it in time
I'm getting locked out of my server
now I have a useless app it can't
communicate with my server so a bit
about alternatives to overcome this one
of the one of the suggestions is to use
an alternative secure channel that will
allow adding temporary a temporary
fingerprint in addition to the existing
list just to open a single sync with the
server allowing us to fetch the full
configuration again so in this case even
if the application didn't get the
updating time and the binary was not
updated with a new one
containing the new fingerprint we can
use a push notification either from
Apple's APNs or Google's FCM - just push
the new token temporarily unlocking the
app to allow you to communicate with a
server thanks Cal and I think the third
example is actually my personal
favorites and and actually over this one
things I like to do when interviewing
candidates is to ask them a very simple
coding question I tell them that they
have a zip file that they need to just
unpack into the file system so they have
a target directory to which to unpack
and they have some kind of object that
allows them to iterate over the zip
files and usually I get very similar
answers in this case you can look at the
code from Java to do this that is very
successfully by the way too much
successfully and then naturally what you
can see here is an iteration of the zip
entries we've got the destination deal
which is developer controlled this case
my op slash target deal but the problem
is that the zip file itself is user
controlled meaning attackers controlled
in one of the most trivial things an
attacker might do
we're a specially crafted zip file that
will contain dot slash dot slash etc and
practically director which reveals the
whole situation so when you can cut the
two strengths obviously we are gaining
into situation where we actually escaped
from the target directory and gained
arbitrary file right in this case we
likely just took over the host right
I think the interesting part about
Baskerville cell is that it has been
around for decades
ok so in here you can see flag 35 as you
can see it's from 91 and it talks about
WWI V for those of you that are old
enough
this is was a very well known VBS
framework it's actually still being
maintained and what they've shown is
practically part of else'll to take over
that framework okay so this is very old
the interesting part that is even more
interesting is that it's still very very
relevant in the past year we've seen
research by snake and other very
notables Israeli startup that actually
uncovered the huge amount of current
open source frameworks that well
vulnerable to this problem and
practically compromised the ones that
use them another notable research was
zippered down by Pangu that showed a
huge amount of ios and android apps that
well and some of them are still are
susceptible to part of elsa we will
discuss this shortly so how can we fix
it so usually the the approach in
general in application security is just
say you know this does not look
legitimate right dot dot slash is not
legitimate let's just wipe it away but
one of the big problems in general when
you sanitize input as I think all of us
know is that it's very hard to implement
and very easy to bypass in many cases so
please raise your hand if you understand
why that sanitation is actually a
terrible sanitation okay so give you a
very simple example the attacker
just create an invalid path in the zip
file by itself it will not work but
thanks to the sanitization it will be
transformed into a valid path of FL
attack okay so this is a simple example
that shows why that's so terrible so
let's see how we could solve this
problem so again we want to use the
correct libraries given to us by the
operating system in this case we would
like to actually evaluate the final path
by looking at the canonical path and as
long as this final path still remains
within our desired destination directory
we're good
otherwise we would just fail the attempt
to unzip this file okay
so let's try to combine several of those
pitfalls into a modern use case that
happens today so what I want to look at
is a hybrid hybrid application it has
some HTML and JavaScript that is
actually used as a website that I use
without my mobile application and it has
native code that leverages additional
api's from the device to extend my logic
when I want to look at this site so
we'll try to look at the live demo in
just a second let me set it up
so we have a tradition it worked it
worked one time outside of 100 attempts
so let's hope it works ok so we have a
phone I'm not going to attack it yet I
just want to go through the logic of the
application I have an application that
is a photo album manager and I wrapped
it with some native code allowing
basically two main interfaces extensions
one as I don't want to enter my
credentials again and again because it
expires in the website I just want the
native part to store it and inject it
into the web part any time it needs to
and the second part is of course in the
web UI I can add an upload button but
it's very cumbersome and I just want to
leverage the native UI to already look
at the file system see that there are
new a plethora so that have not yet been
uploaded such as the example there of
the crowd here and suggest them in a
very comfortable way to upload them
quickly so the phone is already
connected to a network that has an
attacker on it I have not started attack
yet we will start it now and what I'm
doing here is a model that is going to
look for a cache some cache zip that is
loaded from an unsecured source the
developer didn't think there is any
problem with that he's doing the
authentication correctly everything
works correctly the cache is just some
zip with some images to have a quicker
start up
so let's kill the app and reload it now
the app is going to load the cache again
and what what we can see here is that
there was an injection reported by our
attack tool basically what it did was to
catch this zip that was passed and
inject malicious malicious JavaScript
code with a filename that leverages path
traversal as we've looked at the
application we know that it is
susceptible to path reversal attacks
okay so now look now let's look at the
command and control console okay so the
first thing that we can see here is that
I've already caught the D credentials
but the interesting part here was that I
didn't leverage any network attack
during the authentication again the
authentication was secure I was not able
to catch the credentials at that face
but what our malicious code that was
extracted did was actually to take hold
of the bridge between the web view and
the native part of the application
listening in on any events being passed
through either side so the first thing
that we did was to take a hold of the
credentials but now we have access only
to the web part we want to do something
more interesting want to actually go and
run something on the native part of the
application and taking hold photos that
never left the device so if we send our
command to the device okay we start
getting up loads of photos that have
never left the device so let's go back
to the presentation and have a quick
summary of this demo and understand what
happened here again we have a man in the
middle he sits on the network he sees
the request for a sip that is not secure
he catches this zip this he just
contains at least five
and we inject some malicious code using
again
path traversal again the interesting
part here was that using this malicious
code we were actually able through the
webview to trigger and run native code
that we should never have gained access
to from the web yeah and I think there
was a lot of discussion over there's
about the value of bridges of hybrid
apps but I think it's a good incarnation
good demonstration for the additional
risk of having that model of bridges etc
and the importance of having proper
skill coding within them
so to summarize I think we discussed a
few examples and many of them are
actually repeating problems of their
many years so many people like to talk
about this area as a never-ending
problem but I think there are specific
things we can do as an industry so we
didn't use the damage of those kind of
problems so first one is obviously
education I think from experience those
problems happen a lot but once people
see them and and learn very quickly
about them it becomes trivial not to
fall for that I think our responsibility
is to make sure that in our
organisations we fitted ly provide
presentations such as this one where we
covered the common coding pitfalls and
make sure that any developer and
organization has this in mind we've seen
this as a very power month process to
adduce those kind of problems in our
organization another thing is that I
didn't touch this earlier but when you
would go and look at many of the
processes like even unpacking a zip file
you will go to stack overflow second
flow provides a great solutions simple
solutions the problem is that even to
these very days you will find a lot of
implementations that are just vulnerable
so just copying text from there is
really risky to conclude there is
something we believe that the vendors
themselves can do and that is the
importance of secured by design secure
by default
egle mentioned earlier
the configuration in cloud services that
by default might leads us to make
mistakes the same applies for path to
vessel if you now go to Java you still
have just a way to implement what we
just shown even though the need to
unpack zip files is extremely common and
our expectation is for vendors to
provide a different way to just as an
example