wonderful okay I'll get started so hi
everyone today I'm going to talk to you
about the OWASP top 10 for JavaScript
developers and see if I can find my
mouse I'll just use this then okay so
just a little bit about myself I'm a
senior security consultant at synopsis
it used to be with digital but we've got
acquired by synopsis and I've been there
for about four years
I'm also the angular one of the angular
San Francisco organizers where we do
monthly meetups around javascript
typescript and specifically angular and
I also did a degree in ethical hacking
where I founded the lead ethical hacking
Society and the reason why I'm talking
to you today is because I'm a JavaScript
enthusiast
I love JavaScript I'm sure a few people
in the room also agree with that but a
lot of people tend to hate JavaScript
but I am NOT one of those people so what
is the OWASP top ten most of you know
what the OWASP top 10 is but the OWASP
top 10 is a powerful awareness document
for web application security and the
OWASP top 10 represents a broad
consensus about what most critical where
application flaws are and that exists in
web applications so the reason why
there's multiple colors is because the
items in green are data-driven the items
in orange our community chosen and the
items in red are ever substantially new
or changed since the olaf's 2013 version
so what I intend to do today is try and
cover as much as I can in 30 minutes on
the OWASP top 10 and how it relates to
JavaScript and I can't cover it all but
there is an extended slide deck online
after this presentation with lots more
demos that you can go through at your
own leisure so let's talk about a one
injection first the dangers of mixing
data and code so the main issue that is
caused through injection is when we mix
data and code where user input is
treated part of the code context itself
there are many types of injection
attacks so there's like sequel injection
no sequel injection log injection and
also command injection but
the list goes on and I don't want to
bore you to death because most of you
know the different kind of injection
attacks that exist in common
applications but let's take a look at
two that you might see when you're
looking at JavaScript or node
applications in general so the first
thing that I want to talk about is no
secret injection and the official Mongo
documentation that it's not vulnerable
to the traditional sequel injection
attacks because objects are represented
in vs on query or B some queries are
represented in beasts on objects and
most it might not be vulnerable to
traditional sequel injection it's still
vulnerable to injection attacks if user
input is directly included in a and
collection method so one example of this
might be that you have a find one method
collection method and you're trying to
retrieve a user from the database and
this can be abused if you can include a
Mongo query selector such as Dollar and
E which is short for not equals to if
you can include that or dollar GT to
something that's greater than you can
use this to abuse and login to the
application so let's just take a quick
look at a MongoDB example so we have
this find one collection while its
collection with a fine one query and
this is coming from user input because
we have the request user request or
query dot user and passwords but the
injection here would be if you included
a and dollar
e on the password field because what
this actually would do is convert the
query output to basically say that the
password is not equal to an empty string
so you want to make sure that you're
trying to prevent this in general and of
course under the hood this will check to
see if it's an empty string and 99% of
the time the password isn't going to be
an empty string it's going to be a hash
password or clear text password
hopefully not so let's just take a look
at how that might actually work in
practice
so we have a simple login post route
where we have this authenticate function
its authenticate function takes in the
body and it takes in the user and the
password so from the body parameter and
then it takes into the authentication
and it tries to it goes to connect to
the MongoDB instance so this time it's
localhost and then we have that simple
collection now obviously this would be
vulnerable for various different
collections but in this case we're going
to talk about five one so this will just
try and find one user make sure it
matches and obviously under the hood
this may do some other things but for
all intents purposes this is a very
simple application so obviously this can
be bypassed with it which I mentioned
with the username of admin this could
also just be greater than and then the
password would be greater than and it
will return back the entire collection
but as we can see here we have the fine
one with the user and passwords so if we
include that password with the dollar GT
and we go to the application we try and
log in with a fake password first
obviously you should never do this in
clear text but anyway so as we saw if we
intercept that request and send that
again to the server and we do fake
password again once we capture that
request we can now delete the fake
password and just include the dollar GT
so this will allow us to and because the
password is greater than and whatever
was supplied which is 90 straightened
this is going to allow us to log into
the application so the simplest way to
prevent Mongo injection is to ensure
obviously the safest way is to basically
ensure what you're expecting is either
of a part string so it's directly used
in the global string object directly or
you can perform custom data validation
so one popular library and from happy
and is joy and you can define custom
info validation on on particular on
particular either user inputs or on a
scheme so you can do this by defining
with like it must be a string and must
be required it must be over type and you
know between 30 and 50 characters you
know whatever you want to do you can do
that with joy so even sequel injection
exists in node applications today we
cannot escape that relational databases
are here too
they're gonna be around for a long time
so as you can see Drake is not very
happy when we dynamically include the
object user through string concatenation
and parvis as part of a query string but
Drake is very happy when we're using
parameterize queries to ensure user
input is safe so let's get back to some
serious content as enough Drake what we
when we think about info prevention we
want to make sure that we're doing first
input validation and we want to try and
do data normalization so that input
validation is actually sane and it can
be properly validated but then we may
also want to consider when we're dealing
with xml files or various different
files performing something like output
encoding because that's fit to recap
anyone went to his presentation input
validation cannot be used as a
stand-alone protection it has to be
conjoined with something else such as
output encoding and then we're working
when we're working with databases you
might want to consider parameterised
queries or safe api's such as stored
procedures because you know stored
procedures don't always save you from
sequel sequel injection but if you're
doing it correctly and you generally are
okay so now we're going to move on to
broken authentication so one of my
colleagues I'm envious Ankur reviewed an
Internet of Things application in China
while he was on site and it was built
with node and it was using the Express
framework and they wanted to preserve
memory space space on the device by not
writing not using custom middleware or
an authentication like passport they
wanted to write their own because it
would be cheaper so what you can see
here and obviously this is vulnerable to
node but it also could be vulnerable to
the client-side too but it would be less
impactful but what we have here is a
simple and object called sessions and
then we have this must be authenticated
middleware which takes in the request
response and next and then we take a
look at the cookie and that cookie is
basically a sign to the token and then
we check to see if that session token
exists in in the intercession object and
if it does exist then we'll go to the
next otherwise it will say not
authorized now this looks like it could
be okay but if anyone's looked at
JavaScript for a long time or enough
they're going to take a look at this
comparison table and see some weird
wonky things so let's just say that the
sessioned object contained look at the
authentication session and it was
checking against that value but if you
had an input validation string which
said import which was an invalid string
or against that session object it's
gonna return false which makes sense
because if it's not there it shouldn't
return true the same for if was what all
that was supplied was an empty cookie
and that would obviously return false as
well but then we get to some weird and
interesting concepts where if you have
the session which is constructor it's
going to return to true and the same for
hazard property which is going to return
to true now the interesting thing here
is because when you create a JavaScript
object it essentially descends the base
objects so by default you have these
values such as underscore underscore
proto which can be used for various
dangerous things I prototype pollution I
which is I don't cover today but I'm
sure someone in the audience probably
will looking at you there's also a
constructor and has own property and is
prototype of so what we saw before is
basically saying the same thing as if it
does the sessions constructor equal to
session has got constructor and now of
course is going to be true so the
exploit here would be fairly trivial all
we would do is basically do a car
request and include a cookie which says
token equals two constructor or
alternatively you could just go into the
browser and open the developer tools
add-in and the document cookie and
assign it to the token constructor so
let's take a look at another example if
I can so I've lost the mouse okay okay
no yep okay so let's just replay this
the replay nope
let me just kill it and try again okay
so play okay so let's just say we have
the simple Express application and as
you can see with using the cookie parser
to be able to retrieve the cookie we
have that sessions object which is empty
and we have that must be authenticated
middleware so what will happen now is
obviously we take the request cookies we
assign that to the token which then is
obviously checked to see if there exists
and if the session token contains that
value and if it does go next otherwise
say not authorized and then obviously
we're appending that as middleware so
before it even makes it to the get route
it's going to check that and as you can
see when we refresh the page it says not
authenticated but all we're going to do
is go into the developer console define
the document cookie assign that token
constructor and then refresh the page
and as you can see now it says we're
authenticated and then i zoom in for
dramatic effect so obviously this is
quite bad and this definitely shouldn't
have happened but it's an unfortunate
consequence
so how do we correctly correctly check
this and whilst I would never recommend
you write your own authentication
unfortunately sometimes it's a necessity
so I would highly recommend looking into
using the crypto library which has
timing safe equal because when you're
doing things like sensitive password
comparisons and various other things if
you have a double equals or triple
equals this is vulnerable to timing
attacks so you should never do that
anyway the next thing is of course it
performs a safe comparison so it's not
going to chase it's not going to check
the base object it's only going to check
the input string and then you can also
just do this very happily it's not
hacking actually it's a relatively okay
solution but you can use the object
hazard property or the if you're using
maps es6 maps you can use dot has oh I
repeated the thing anyway that was meant
to be the house so basically these do
not check the base property so these are
safe to use in this context okay so now
let's move on to xxe so we all know that
an extra XML external entities xxe
injection is very common in pretty much
all languages that we see and note in
this context is no different if we want
a quick recap where everyone knows what
XML injection is but we have XML the XML
standard includes the idea of external
external general past entities an
external entity and in during the
parsing process the XML document the
parser will expand these links and
include the content of the URI in the
returned return document and a common
attack is basically to include like a
DTD so a document type definition where
you include some entities you can do and
whatever other malicious things like try
and do denial of service through a
billion lapse attack you can do trying
to access internal resources and various
other you know means like trying to do
port scanning on your internal host and
node is no different it has a lot of XML
parsing libraries
I had an arguable someone told me that
no one uses them note that
now but I mean I beg to differ when
there's 80 48 thousand weekly downloads
and 47,000 weekly downloads so no tax
but a note expert is actually in
particularly vulnerable dub by design
you can its long if user input is being
entered into this into this past
function it's actually vulnerable by
design and you can't do anything about
it you would have to do extra layers of
security on top of that to make it safe
there's also lib XML jus and that live
xml j s is vulnerable if no end is set
to true and this means no entities which
doesn't really make sense from a
configuration perspective maybe there
should be entities set to true rather
than no entities but that thing that's a
generic java or previous standard that
was set in the old implementations
because this is like a port of other
implementation libraries so let's just
take a look at an the DB na which is
down vulnerable node application this
has been created years ago to
demonstrate some particular issues so as
you can see here we have the request
stop files and basically it's taking in
some data and obviously the mime type is
set set to text XML and it's going into
the parse XML string that would be saved
by default but unfortunately we have
this no end set to true which means you
would be able to achieve XML injection
in this context you could retrieve local
local instances from the files you could
do denial of service you could attack
the web server or whatever you wanted
because the source here is obviously the
request dot files going into parse XML
and then the misc configuration and the
sink here is the no end to true so how
would you try and prevent this in note
in general you may want to consider just
using a library that doesn't pass ID TDs
so the sax j s & sax j s doesn't even
process entities you can configure it in
a way where you can do that but by
default it's technically a safe
implementation and when you'll want to
use safe libraries definitely consider
using Lib XM out is over
nodaks part because it is safe by
default but you have to make that
configuration change to make it
vulnerable and then if there are
contexts where you need like the
ampersand or greater than converted into
actual attributes you may want to
consider using lodash or underscore or M
he to basically do an escape functions
on you know technically on HTML but you
know in this context XML and of course
if you can't really approach those
things you want to make sure you're
doing strict input validation and output
encoding before actually passing the
data okay so let's talk about brokering
access control for a second so we now
live in a world where most of the
routing is done on the client side and
the client and server trust boundaries
are started to meld together you know we
have many client-side frameworks and
libraries now that offer some kind of
authorization but this intended purpose
from the client side is purely only for
aesthetics it's not meant to be used for
security so but the sad truth is this is
often neglected when we look at many
applications now from your source code
review or from a penetration test we
tend to see that these server and client
side boundaries have melded together and
you're all they're doing is doing
client-side controls to protect
themselves against an elevated privilege
so when you are working with node.js
there are some things you can consider
for the server side so first you want
may want to use like node Casman for
authorization and so that node node has
been allows you to write access control
lists allows you to write rollbase
role-based access controls and
attribute based access control you may
want to move this over to a framework to
do all the hard hard and heavy lifting
for you so sales j/s allows you to
easily write policies that might be good
to make sure that a person is of a type
admin it's very easy to do this inside
your sales j/s and then finally you may
want to write some custom middleware so
custom middleware is very important when
you're working with things i JWT
or JSON web tokens or job however you
want to call it and
do this at various different levels you
can do this at the actual route level so
as you can see in this example we're
doing like off requires role admin you
would obviously you know verify the JWT
then check against that or you could do
it at if you wanted to make sure someone
was authenticated first you may do it at
the pre route level so before it even
reaches these routes or you may want to
do some things afterwards after at the
after route it's entirely up to you how
you want to deploy that but these are
just some potential solutions you might
be able to deploy in your organization
so just to give a quick angular example
and I've highly recommend taking a look
at the second link here but angular has
some built-in client-side validation
checks which can be used to load
resources or show in hide States you
have things like can activate can
activate child can deactivate can load
resolve and so on and obviously this is
nice from a user experience and what
should be shown to it to a user but
obviously these things can easily be
trivially bypassed and only you know
maybe if they're doing on the server and
only then rendering the data it might be
okay but most of the time single page
applications throw everything to the
client and then depending on the you
know the JSON responses they receive
what data they have that is how it's
represented on the client side but the
one interesting thing about angular as
well I'm not picking on young angular
because it's bad it's actually a super
great framework but you can basically
use it's super powerful energy probe and
that's what the second argument the
second blog post talks about it's how
you can use energy probe to probe the
client side and you can do this
basically to take a look at its
components and if they had like
authentication component or an admin
component you could then basically start
to manipulate the changes and in in that
aspect so now I'm moving on to security
mists configuration so nodejs and most
of the frameworks that are built on top
of nodejs
return verbose error messages as you can
see from the top example if the default
value is set so if you tend to see you
like you know a file is not found or a
certain
era came back you would want to make
sure that this is a set properly and
then you can do this by defining the
production mode and with the node
environment you can also actually set
this up as a middle as a middleware so
you can kind of consider this at you
know are all routes you want to make
sure this middleware is set so before
anything runs it's set to production
with a node environment so that
technically would save you from if your
client if your actual server
implementation changes or it gets
deployed to a new server and the node
environment changes so you can do this
at the middleware layer and of course we
all know about am the dangerous of
running as routes for any Linux
application running as you know running
with sudo has a greater chance of
modifying the underlying operating
system if they have like a command
injection for example they could
obviously just do RTFM forward slash but
there are some things that you may want
to consider so for example and if you
know go through you may want to go
through the default run scripts to make
sure they're not running with sudo
that's the first thing you can do and
the second thing you can do is sudo is
required after the port is bound you can
essentially then you know call process
and set the GID a new ID so these are
some things you can consider in nodejs
so let's move on to my most arguably
strongest topic and I have a lot of
things to say about cross-site scripting
okay so XSS is super easy to introduce
and I think koto and Mike's talk talked
about the same things and I'm about to
talk about now but as we all know dahm
dahm dahm XSS generally occurs when you
know inputs injection sinks in the Dom
or other browser API is a called we've
used as a controlled input so as you can
see here we have a source such as
location dot hash and then it's being
assigned to the NHD ánow which says
welcome username or is being appended in
this case and of course and of course
the script execution context here would
be just to include the username and that
should be a hash
not a not a not a parameter but
obviously if you had a hash here this
would allow for the execution so and Dom
XSS in today's ecosystem is super
difficult to find you'll notice that
most static code analysis tools cannot
identify Dom XSS it's it's pretty
paramount that it's so difficult and
obviously when you're defining variables
in a way if you take a look at these
hacker 1 reports and you take a look at
the code you're gonna go where is the
Dom access s but it is actually quite
difficult to identify and browsers
actually tend to pass and render HTML
differently so the Dom specification for
each browser while there are standards
they're not always conforming to those
standards and they implement things a
little differently so there's a good
explanation from live overflow where he
goes into a lot of detail about the
Google XSS but then he also goes into
detail about why is this thing rendering
this way on Firefox or why is this way
rendering on Chrome and there's some
wonderful examples on shadow shadow at
UK which is basically a fuzzing website
for browsers and insert script known as
Alex and also gareth Hayes have some
wonderful examples on there about how
you can get quirks like there was like
things trying to remove a greater than
character to bring an entire string
together and various different contexts
and of course the dangers of the Dom as
well or the browsers in general is that
there's so many execution contexts
there's wonderful resources like html5
sect org that you can take those
payloads and basically use them inside
your security unit tests five minutes
okay
and of course and there's also character
sets so browsers come with various
different character sets like utf-8
utf-16 pleura six was crazy and just
threw a ton of character sets in there
at some point so there's tons of
different and ways to basically get
JavaScript execution even when it
doesn't look like JavaScript execution
and then you also have script gadgets
where it's basically taking HTML
injection and being processed in a way
where it's executed by JavaScript so
highly recommend taking a look look at
all these resources and then you'll kind
of get to the point why you understand
things are so difficult so have five
minutes and 20 slides let's let's do it
so frameworks like angular react in view
definitely reduce the attack surface but
I'm not going to go through all of these
but essentially there are abundance of
ways that you can introduce XSS by
basically using frameworks in a way
which are either being abused and
various different aspects so the first
example would be to combine templating
engines with and third-party libraries
and frameworks so in angularjs if you
included jQuery text which in general
websites that's actually a safe way to
insert HTML but with jQuery dot text
angular would actually render curly
braces as part of the angular
expressions so you were technically get
XSS you could obviously do all the
others as well one interesting one is
element ref because it allows you to
access the Dom so you get in HTML so I'm
not going to click that so basically I'm
gonna ignore this video you can watch it
online with through the video and but
base owner now it's playing okay so as
you can see here we get remote code
execution and it's quite strange why and
this is because one line of code in the
signal application basically was using
danger to set in HTML and this allowed
you to essentially get various different
execution contexts on the client side or
sorry in the mobile applications
it was XSS on electron it was a remote
code execution
so the general prevention techniques is
quite critical here and you know there's
various different ways to achieve this
so you can use templating engines such
as mustache or pork or ejs and they do
HTML contextual encoding you can use
angular react or view to ensure that and
you're making sure they're using their
sanitization functions by design and of
course they're secure filters you want
to make sure that you're doing Dom
purify or doing client-side sanitization
because whilst it's built on the server
once you can render it in the browser
you can make a better safe assumption
that it is secure or it is sanitized
properly and of course if you can use
that in a text or in code you awry in
the correct context and that is quite
important so I'm gonna skip this very
this next topic very quickly but you
should definitely look at
defense-in-depth strategies so you want
to try and deploy CSP and take a look
obviously Cotto and Mike just talked
about trusted types but I would highly
recommend looking at these as extra
layers of security on top of your
applications okay
so two minutes left and this is the most
important part every one so I'm going to
go over time sorry so this is the most
important thing when it comes to I guess
the node ecosystem and it's using
components with known vulnerabilities so
it's very important to carefully audit
third pipe code and obviously doing
source code review is very critical in
this aspect but if you take a look at an
NPM package list or any kind of package
JSON you're gonna see a thousands of
different kind of packages in there and
it's not going to be feasible to do
source code review but if you do find an
issue in an NPM package you can now use
the new github feature where you can
directly report that issue to the
project itself in a safe way and of
course if you want to implement and
auditing tools in your CI CD pipeline
you can use NPM audit yarn order audit
j/s retire jeaious and sneak tests so
you can use these in different contexts
you would use snick if you're using open
source node you could use retire j/s if
you're looking at client-side JavaScript
you could use bower for client client
side and package manager yarn with yarn
audit fix which basically wraps over NPM
and then also NPM audit fix so these are
some simple examples and what you see
here is that obviously things like next
is next year's is super important in the
react world but in two cases it was
vulnerable to arbitrary read through
directory traversal it was also
vulnerable to an X access which
obviously is quite bad because react
that adds a lot of properties but if you
build on top of that you essentially are
seeing a lot of
Mantic areas so it's super important to
do dependency checking on node modules
so I saw someone was taking a screenshot
so feel free to finish that okay so our
mitigation techniques so this is
probably the most important part that
you might want to consider this is my
last slide actually so you want to make
sure that you track outdated libraries
and components for using snick or retire
j/s or yarn or Bower and so on and you
want to try and maintain a technology
list asset registry list or in some way
but there was an interesting talk from
loco moco sec that basically talks about
you know code province and application
security in applications and what they
tend to do is only do a subset of those
dependencies because if you go too far
down the chain there's less likely of a
code sink actually happening from user
input but then you can build a
technology list through things like the
CL is so you can use it for MPM there's
little s for yong there's yarn Alice and
yarn Y and then of course there's Bower
Bower list as well and one thing that I
also might want to recommend for you to
do but it's obviously up to your
interpretation has basically pin your
dependency versions where possible
because there was obviously an
interesting scenario with event stream
and event stream allow obviously was
affected a lot of organizations but if
you can pin your dependencies to
something that you once knew was safe
and include that in the package when
other developers install it by using NPM
shrink wrap or yarn lock they're going
to use this exact same dependency
version that you were using and
therefore it may actually save them for
being compromised so that was everything
that I had the online version is at the
bottom there's the 30-minute version and
the hour version with multiple demos
there so feel free to go ahead and take
a look at it and if you have any
questions I'll be around so thank you