hello everybody Ryu nice to meet you
I hope you're not starving it try to
speed up a bit
yes welcome everyone to of us and to my
talk about securing web apps with modern
platform security features today's talk
will be about a couple new features in
the web platform that you can actually
use to protect your occasions and users
from common weapon abilities and my name
is Lukas weichselbraun I'm an
information security engineer at Google
I work in the Zurich office and my team
is focusing on improving product
security by targeting proactive projects
with the aim of mitigating whole classes
of parts and today I will split the talk
into sections first a very quick run
through common web security flaws not
like explaining what they are but more
like looking at VRP data and seeing
which ones recommen and try to
categorize them and map them to web
platform security features and in the
second part we'll talk about this web
platform security features that are some
of them are super new actually we
probably not even have heard about them
yet but it would be super cool to start
a discussion about them maybe later
outside as well so let's start with two
security flaws Google has a VP program I
think for over eight years now and it's
not only a great source for you know
finding bugs and fixing them but it also
allows us to actually look at the root
causes and identify new classes of parks
and kind of try to get a feeling of
trends within these back classes right
so there's thousands of parks submitted
every year and in particular the web
application bugs are out of interest for
us if you look at the left side of the
chart you'll see that less than the half
is non web parks like you know server
side miss configuration or Android
applications will not focus about these
today will focus on the right side of
the chart which is slightly more than 50
cent and these are web a Democrat
so of course cross-site scripting is a
big offender in this space right and
it's still around
and then there's other things like
cross-site request forgery click
checking and other web box which we'll
cover in a little bit more detail in the
later sections so the first big category
is of course injection bugs right and
I'm not going into detail about what
cross-site scripting is because I assume
most of you know the only thing I want
to mention is the second type of process
scripting lockdown based XSS is actually
becoming more relevant these days
because more and more code is moving
from the server side to the client side
and it's actually quite easy for
developers to introduce non based XSS by
accident and it's on the other hand very
hard for security reviewers to spot
these bugs in code reviews right so
that's cross scripting and part of the
talk will be about to prevent and
mitigate these bugs but the larger part
of the talk will be about insufficient
isolation and new web platform features
that help you to address this category
so the classical example here is cross a
request forgery right and I'm not going
into the detail how that works but the
very important feature of it is that the
server has not enough information to
actually tell apart a request from your
lecture sites or origin compared to a
request that originates from evil.com
side right like from a random origin on
the Internet so evil.com can put a form
that looks exactly the same on their
side and have JavaScript submit that
form and for the server since the
browser will append cookies to both
requests these two requests look exactly
the same right and one of the web
platform mechanism we want to present
today is exactly about this so and
cross-site request forgery is just one
of these isolation related
shoes there's also cross-site leaks
timing attacks and lately also a couple
of new classes of vulnerabilities that
are have popped up that also fall into
this category of insufficient isolation
in the browser platform the most known
new one is probably Spectre which is a
micro architectural issue and yes so you
could say like this chart looks great
but it's maybe a bit Google biased and
you're right it's the data from our VIP
so it's it has a Google bias but if you
look at other ERP data for example from
hacker one you will see that they
actually see similar trends when it
comes to cross-site scripting cross-site
request forgery etc etcetera right so
this is still a big issue for industry
and also our friends at Mozilla report
similar statistics about these
vulnerabilities so what we want to do
now is to address these classes of parks
on in the web platform in the browser
right and there's a couple of new things
that have been already launched and are
coming up soon which I want to show you
today and as I mentioned we basically
have divided this up into two categories
isolation mechanisms and injection
defenses in the browser and in this talk
at OVAs I will mostly focus on the
isolation part mostly because of timing
reasons but if you want to see the full
fledge to talk you can also get
recording from Google i/o and so let's
start with isolation so you might ask
why do we need isolation and the answer
to that is that because of certain
issues in the way the browser's isolate
different origins from each other
there is move abilities like cross
request poetry cross-site script
inclusion
click checking web timing attacks
Spectre they all fall into that category
and in particular into this subcategory
of attacks on resources so attacks and
resources are usually caused by the fact
that any site on the Internet can load a
resource from your server and your
server cannot tell apart that resource
load from a recess load originating from
your own side right so there's a tax on
resources and a second subcategory of
isolation related attacks are attacks on
Windows more specifically on attacks
based on like having a reference to a
window of a different origin so the web
is very open when it comes to that
regard any site on the Internet can open
a new window and navigate that window to
your document right or to your domain
and that per se is fine but by doing so
that site will still have a reference of
in the reference to your window and
because of that being the reference you
can do a couple of things that are may
or may not be surprising to you right
for example you can count frames in your
site the original window can also do
some other you know side channel attacks
often used in cross-site search the new
cross had search attacks they can do
like tap nabbing etc and especially for
browsers like Firefox that don't have a
full side isolation implemented yet it
also means that they cannot put the new
window document in a separate process
and protect you from Specter because of
this window reference so the second
platform mechanism I'll show in a bit
will be about that particular feature
but before we get into that a super
quick review on origins and sites I
assume most of you know what same-origin
means but maybe not everyone knows about
the concept of same site so same origin
is basically the two
of scheme host and port and whenever
two-year-olds have the same values in
these tuple they're considered same
origin for example dr. dopler google.com
stash foo is same origin to adapt to
deploy Google Chrome stash bar same site
is similar but different in the sense
that neighboring subdomains on the same
ret registerable domain would be
considered same site so mail that
google.com and photostat google.com
would be considered same site but not
same origin and basically everything
else is just cross-site and this
distinction is very important because
based on that the browser enforces
different isolation mechanisms on your
side right and with that we come to the
first new web platform feature to
address the resource isolation problem
we showed you on the first slide and
it's actually quite simple it is just
free new request headers set by the
browser that basically gives the server
a chance to are to reason about the
context and the source of an HTTP
request
so implementation wise it's really
simple it's just free request headers
the first one is fetch site this is sent
by the browser for every request and it
basically just indicates the source of a
request right it just tells the server
this request was made like cross-site or
for example this request came from your
own site from the same origin and that
is extremely helpful for the server
because suddenly in the cross-site
request forgery in case the server can
actually reason and say oh wow this
request came from evil calm and not from
mysite.com so I may just want to block
it or strip cookies or do whatever with
it right you can have custom logic on
the server dealing with that information
the second header is sec fetch mode
indicating the type of the request and
most simply put this means this header
indicates if this was like a resource
load or if it was a navigation and we'll
see in a second that this information is
also quite handy to protect on the
server side against a couple of web
vulnerabilities and the last header is
sec fetch user which basically informs
the server if the navigation was caused
as a direct consequence of a user
interaction like a click or a key press
or if it was you know JavaScript based
or something else so let's look at a
super simple example for this on the top
you see same origin resource load site
dot example loads a file from site dot
example server and by that the browser
sends an additional request header
called sec fetch site with the value
same origin because it's the same origin
request and the dessert the server can
say Belle same origin requests are
allowed that's perfectly fine
the example below is actually a
cross-site request evil.com request
something from sighted example and by
doing so the user's browser will
basically indicate on the request that
this request was made across site
because the host and of the request and
the actual source don't match so that's
still very simple and simple information
but you can actually use these building
blocks to build some quite powerful
server-side logic to protect web
applications against a couple of common
web application security flaws and that
example here is a little bit simplified
but this basically prevents a car
full of resource isolation related
issues and most commonly known like it
will prevent across that request for
tree across the script inclusion click
checking and similar issues right
the logic is actually easy the first
condition just checks if the sec fetch
header request header is available
because if not it's a browser that does
not support this and will just allow the
request because we don't want to break
the side for you know users on all the
browsers for example but eventually when
all the browser's will support a feature
this like dis acuity will also be
available to two more users
the second condition is basically there
to ensure that all same site or same
origin requests are allowed to proceed
right so if your site makes a request
for JavaScript or navigation or whatever
right the server will just normally
respond to it because it's the same
origin or same site navigation and the
third one basically ensures that cross
site navigation top-level navigation is
also allowed if you don't have the third
condition your site will basically be
siloed in the Internet and no one can
will be able to link to your side right
there's some use cases for that as well
but in the normal case you still want
other places to be able to link to your
site so you still would allow top-level
navigation even if it happens across
origin so everything else is blocked
what that means for example if you had
take the XSS I example if evil comm
loads a JavaScript from your site and
the browser sends cookies with that
request right your server will basically
block that request because it's a cross
origin resource load and you did not
explicitly allow this here
so there's actually many many more
things you can do with fetch metadata
but this is like a trivial example
to address resource resource isolation
related issues with that mechanism
usually you would roll out a fetch
metadata based protection in the form of
a middleware on the server side you
would start monitoring blocked requests
not actually blocking them and review
all the requests that actually got
blocked right because potentially your
application has endpoints that are meant
for cross-origin communication for
example if you have a course endpoint
that is meant for cross origin
communication and you would probably
want to whitelist that endpoint from
that logic to still allow that right and
if you've done if you if you have done
that you would switch to enforcement
mode and actually you know for example
block all requests that don't fulfill
this criteria or you can also do
something custom like you know stripping
cookies redirecting to the you know
entry site or doing other things right
and also very important to note here you
would also have to set the Barry header
for sec fetch site and sec fetch mode
and this also has a very nice side
effect that browsers will basically be
forced to have a per origin cache
compared to having a cache for all sites
right and implicitly by that you will
prevent a couple of excess search
related issues just by ensuring that
stuff is not cached across origins and
so fetch metadata shipping in chrome in
the next version in 76 but you can
already play with it by enabling the
experimental that platform features flag
and yes there's also already two
projects on github that provide a proof
of concept implementation for a resource
isolation based middle we're using fetch
metadata give it a try
give us feedback and super curious to
hear here what
think about the approach and with that
I'm switching to the next feature new
feature which is cross-origin opener
policy and that in particular addresses
the isolation issues related to window
references
the second category we had the slides
before so what is this about as we
already said with beginning any site on
the Internet can open your site in a new
window and have a reference to that
window and with that reference they can
you know they can send post messages
they can count frames they may be
leveraged other side channels to you
know learn about something about your
site for example they could find out if
the user is logged in or not based on
some things
and they can also navigate your site
away to an arbitrary other site and
there's a very easy way to prevent that
and that's the cross origin open a
policy response header you basically
second set this header to same origin or
same site and by that any cross site
page that opens your window we'll still
be able to open the window right but it
will not have the reference anymore and
by that it will not be able to navigate
your window on your site anymore
and especially nice the same site value
can be used if you for example have a
cup of subdomains and they you know
communicate through post message and you
would still have on to allow that right
so this response header is quite new
it's already implemented in Firefox
nightly so we can try it
chrome is working on it but as of now I
think there's nothing implemented yet
but we'll hope it will come soon and and
not a very nice side effect of setting
this response header is that browsers
like Firefox who don't have a full side
isolation to protect against Specter
will be able to put
the open window or you know the other
domain in the different browsing context
group which means the browser will be
able to separate the domains the origins
in with different processes right and by
that protecting against specter like
attacks so especially for Firefox users
this header would be quite interesting
as well because I think it will take
some more time for Firefox to actually
natively implement a full side isolation
yes and with that I will do a couple
more slide on injection defenses there
is CSP which you can use to protect
against stored and reflected XSS and
partially dom-based xss it's it was a
long long ride for CSP I don't know I
guess some of you have seen CSP and work
with CSP before and you have seen
policies like that it's it's not great
this type of policies are super bad
because they are trivially by possible
they are incredibly hard to maintain
without breaking things and yeah they're
just not really worth your time right
what we would suggest instead is using a
CSP based analysis because it has two
critical advantage advantages and the
first is that this policy does not need
configuration or / endpoint or per site
as a matter of fact we use almost the
same policy across all Google
applications and the second thing is
it's not susceptible to the right list
based CSP PI passes which the previous
policy and the whitelist based policy
would be so we actually use this type of
policy and almost 60% of all outgoing
Google text HTML traffic and I think on
over 100 domains and it was quite
effective just in the last 12 months it
actually blocked 20 high-risk XSS box
and for us that's very valuable time to
actually fix the bugs and preventing
them from being exploited so I'm not
going into the details how to roll out
this ESP based on ounces but there is a
nice write-up on CSP debrief google.com
that gives you a step-by-step guide on
how to do that and I also strongly
recommend if you already have a CSP or
if you diverge from the template to
actually use the CSP evaluator because
it actually is very useful to spot
common bypasses in a policy that make it
completely by possible so whenever you
have a red exclamation mark in your
policy you might want to do something
about it or to steal into policy and
yeah the till the our is the nice thing
is is like always the same except of the
nonce which has to change on error
response it's definitely better than
widely spaced CSP and it's a good
mitigation against stored and reflects
to X XSS and if the new CSP free strict
dynamic javert you actually can use the
non-space CSP even in the case when
you'll have third-party JavaScript code
that loads
resources right like payment integration
host using javascript obsidians or
widgets right in that case earlier you
couldn't use a nonce only CSP but we've
strict dynamic you can also now use a
non space CSP in these cases and here is
a small pitch for another talk there's
also trusted types coming up in the web
platform and it's an amazing new feature
especially extremely well-suited for
preventing it against don't based XSS
and there's a talk by Christophe Cote
ovitch and Mike Samuel I think after the
lunch break and of course I don't want
to steal their thunder right so you
should sorry whole c130 so you should
totally check that out it's one of my
favorite favorite new web platform
features and what's really nice about it
is it also plays very well with the
classical CSP so you can set a single
policy with trusted types and nonces
and together they are very effective in
actually preventing and mitigating the
vast majority of XSS issues right so
that should be your 2019 goal and yes
with that I will wrap up and basically
you can now wake up again I put
everything on a single slides you can
take a photo and pretend you know
everything about these features now the
TLDR is that you can use CSP free for
reflected and stored XSS trusted types
for Dom based XSS fetch metadata request
header to protect against isolation
issues that are based on resource loads
and you can use cross-origin open a
policy to protect your window references
from tampering and with that I wanted to
thank you for being here today the
slides are online as well and I put some
of the links also here just in case you
were not able to note them down
previously and I will hang around a bit
longer in case you have questions and
sorry ok even have some time for
questions if you are some so yeah
sure
so until the slide until the slide that
you have that it's clickable and it was
a get request clickable was it fetch
metadata yes one second so was it that
slide you just passed it this one next
one yeah yes so so the third condition
why does it have to be a get so this is
mostly for cross-site request forgery
protection so classical cross-site
request forgery case is a postmessage
cross origin and if you would for
example au poste here you would still be
able to protect it against XSS I and
other issues but post based cross-site
request forgery would not be protected
if you would allow post here and you
need to get because otherwise your site
would not be reachable from the internet
anymore so if you also prevent get then
any link from a cross origin domain
would not work because your server would
reject it what you could do is you can
redirect to the main page if you don't
want to allow gate as well but that's
already quite advanced but just use
cases for that basically we are only
allowing a get request clicked but if it
was a post request we are blocking it
yes if it's a cross origin post that
logic would block it if you have a
course endpoint or something that
actually is expected to receive post
requests cross origin you can have an
additional whitelist to you know allow
these kind of requests okay thanks are
you working with the w3c for things like
fetch metadata to standardize the
headers because it's just in chrome you
know yes of course there is actually a
w3c spec for fetch metadata it just got
moved from my quests github repository
to w3c and I think there's like there is
consensus that it makes sense chrome
already just already has the prototype
and
others will follow soon oh thank you
thank you I wanted to ask about the
fetch metadata yeah I didn't really
understand if how does it improve the
security because in case an attacker
wants to for example send a get request
to some resource of another site I mean
it could maybe just I mean equal send an
AJAX request where he controls the
request headers and then he could change
the search metadata
it's a sec metadata is has the sec
prefetch prefetch prefix sorry so you
cannot set this header through the
JavaScript API this is a protected
header by the browser only the browser
can sent and set these headers so which
every bars implement this enforcement
that you're not allowed to set SEC
headers I think all browsers disallow
setting certain headers and that the SEC
prefix prefix is one that is I think
protected in all browsers I think
there's also other headers request
headers that you cannot set in the
JavaScript API explicit or security
reasons sorry yeah sorry can you repeat
that what you said to refer a header you
cannot set an arbitrary valid a okay
thank you yeah and I think we're over
time already or no okay but also hang
around and let Philippe talk so
[Applause]
[Music]