we need to test security in this seems a
little bit obvious and this table will
show you how to integrate okay in this
talk we'll show you how to empower your
QA and integrate more testing into the
QA phase of the development lifecycle
okay so my name is Adi Belenko
I started as automation tester and after
that he worked as a full-stack developer
and done cybersecurity my name is iris
levar
I've been integrating wrapping security
testing to STC for the past 11 years in
this talk Adi and I will explain the
process that we actually implemented in
two companies for the past two years in
multiple QA teams and with great success
and we know what works what doesn't work
and we will show how how to make this
work for you as well okay so as as more
more companies are transitioning from
waterfall methodology to agile
methodology there are more and more
there is a high increase in the number
of releases per year
and as a result and what we had time in
water for methodology we don't have time
in agile methodology we don't have the
time the time slot to do the security
testing therefore the solution that we
are going to talk about is using the QA
phase to integrate more security testing
okay
the security team resources are very
limited they are constrained this is
nothing new
also the result of this situation that
the the versions work going up to
production with no security at all this
is not new either
so who among us in the audience didn't
push an unprotected version to
production in the past it's okay raise
your hand the safe place we will not
judge you because we have all done that
meter okay okay so often we talk about
developer but we rarely mentioned the QA
team so we propose to the solving the
problem by working together with the QA
team and will they help us to perform
the security testing in best of our
experience the QA team and the security
team can work very well together why we
choose the QA team because they are
running the test in every sprint they
sneaking out of the box and they already
have environment ready and they know the
application very well the business and
the functionality and because of that
it's very easy to insert additional test
cases so right now the QA team already
perform some security testing they not
aware about that that is this testing is
also relevant for the security and
because of that the application security
not aware that this test already done so
we want to increase
the security coverage for the Q ATM and
to give the visibility to the
application security team so this is the
list of security testing area for QA for
example authentication and authorization
of such as such and handling password
weak password access to direct direct
access also since sending sensitive data
in get requests upload huge file or
files that contain malicious code SSL
and TLS version and weak ciphers
security response others such as XSS
protection clickjacking and arrow and
the link ok this is the actual process
for a system-level workflow and we'll
take this one by one so the first step
in this first so these are the steps and
the responsible parties in the first
step the application security person
working with the system architect or the
product develop the product manager
review the feature the system features
the high-level overview and the
sensitive data if the system contains
sensitive data all contains sensitive
functionality then there is really
reason to do security testing otherwise
there is no security there is no no
point in doing security testing if it's
relevant then in the second phase the
application security person does the
threat modeling it does the data
analysis the architecture and the
business logic review trying to think
about relevant use cases in the next
step the application security together
with the QA manager or the QA person
review existing use cases test cases
that are in the test suite to review if
the
QA is already doing some testing in in
those areas that we mentioned before if
yes then he can elaborate on that or he
can write new test cases with the QA so
this is the heart of the matter we are
working with them this is a joint
process where in any step of the of the
process we are working with the QA in
the last step the QA person integrates
the test into the automatic test suite
and run it and open the tickets he is
supposed to do to do that and tag it as
security-related
so this is the system level process this
is done on a major version or first time
that you are doing any security review
on the on the system itself this is the
feature level process this is a quicker
than the system level process because
it's done only on the feature that are
in scope in the specific sprint so for
every feature the application security
person does a feature review with the
developer with the specific feature
developer it overview the functionality
and the data if sensitive data or
sensitive functionality is related then
process continues and he does the asset
and the business logic analysis based on
dirty he and the QA fill up a form that
I will show in the next slide that
analyzed the use case and the write the
specific steps to test the next step the
QA performs the automatic testing and
open the JIRA tickets okay so let's do a
quick simulation this is login page it's
very simple functionality the user
insert the username the password and
after that click on the login button so
it's very simple scenario but there is a
lot
test that the QA can perform for example
user enumeration you can for example add
analyze the error message it can check
the lockout mechanism to see the gate
request if it's and sensitive data on
the get request and there is a lot of
test for only simple functionality like
that ok so in the process the
application security person with the QA
person fill up this form in this form
does the name of the test the
vulnerability description remember the
QA there are nice people but they don't
have the knowledge that they need us to
provide them so the vulnerabilities
description is very important because it
gives the rationale it explains what the
vulnerabilities are actually is how the
attacker can exploit it and what are the
possible outcomes in the test another
simple test steps like which are very
common knowledge to the QA because they
are doing this all the time like enter
valid username non valid password repeat
10 times then check again with valid
username and valid password verify that
the user is locked out if it's locked
out wait for the amount of time for the
release automatic release time and check
the automatic release parameter in the
recommendation part of the form we
specify exactly what are the best
practice expected results
what headers for example to expect if
it's okay what behavior to expect if
it's not ok
these are actual tests test cases that
the screenshots that we took from our
test Suites I have in my company many QA
products many QA teams any one of them
is using the difference this test suite
so the test was on variant but the tests
are all the same so the text data is the
same so it doesn't matter if it's the
suite is different but since we are
feeling the same form in the end the QA
person is entering it into its own test
suite so here we can see that steps test
cases who lockout mechanism for exercise
filter for TLS 1.0 check-in and for
click tracking protection and do you
want explain the benefit for the ATM
engine the benefit for the QA team is
that they are getting empowered they're
getting knowledgeable and getting to be
more valuable to the company from my
experience there are feeling pretty
awesome after after doing this phase the
feedbacks are always surprising usually
they say okay don't you need the
developers here with with you in the
meeting no no this is only for the test
persons and then they say okay are you
doing any security testing no we are not
doing any security testing okay can you
show me the login test that you are
doing ah of course and then you see tons
and tons of login checks break out of
logins termination in the middle of
login cookie manipulation which are
they're just not aware that these are
these are part of the security test that
we are actually conducting so
in this cases we are getting very good
feedback from them because they're they
feel that we understand the use case the
we review it we find some use cases that
they didn't think about and we add them
and from then on it's automatic every
sprint we're not touching anything and
they're happy and we're happy and this
is a win-win situation okay so we win we
want to increase the amount and the
coverage of the security testing by
using existing resources we don't do any
change on the process we just use
existing resources in addition we give
the security team visibility to the
effect that found by the testing
questions yes
okay first I think they think that this
is not relevant for them then there are
a little bit surprised that we are
speaking the same language because we
are talking about test cases and about
steps and then when we do a drill down
which we usually take the common common
subject and we give examples and then
they say oh we have that this was really
surprising because I was explaining
error messages and what information the
hacker can extract from error messages
and that they said oh we have that we
have that in two places and then I said
within the same meeting okay so let's
open up the ticket can you show me and
he showed me three places
he opened as a result of the one-hour
meeting fourth JIRA tickets and he
handled it himself
the next version was already fixed this
for geo tickets were already fixed in
the next version so this was very
surprising for me because to get
developers to open tickets it's somewhat
it's not out of it it's not knowing as
it was flowing with the QA so he said
okay I know this I want to push this and
he just handled the whole process from
there on so it was really really simple
for us so it streamlined everything and
I did that with QA team leaders and I
did that also with the team members it
doesn't matter they are speaking the
same language I was like they are first
intimidated because we are the bad guys
we are the bad wolf darth vader's like
and and when they saw talking
communicated they see that we speak the
same language as them and then
everything makes its getting simpler
more question more question actually I
did I did try to integrate you a three
times than an actual question I think
there it's not that QA and testing is
new but the whole point of giving an
actual methodology of simple issues to
find for QA would probably make a good
or a project but I kind of like
producing a document that you can just
hand out as a giveaway to organizations
just something to consider
thank you very much it's a good idea we
thought about doing that we will publish
after the after the conference in our
github and Excel with all the all the
testing areas which are very simple they
don't need to do elaborated XSS test
this is not what we are expecting we're
giving them all the only the tests that
are very simple and more common and will
be easy for a QA to implement so I tried
that doing that turning QA into a pen
tester I felt two times in two different
companies I'm not doing that anymore
no this is not the plan so if they are
checking TLS 1.0 because they are
right-clicking on the certificate if
they are checking headers which is
simple if they are checking file upload
which is very simple if they are doing
login break out which they are doing in
any case so we start by doing the things
that they are already doing and doing a
little bit of variations and then it
looks normal to them because we are not
turning them into a pen testers
full-fledged pen testing is different
okay more questions I'm sorry
you find that it's better to have
dedicated security champions in QA or to
have the knowledge transmitted as
broadly as possible okay
I fall for the broader but you you need
to start with somebody
so my recommendation start with the team
with acuity with the team leader start
with the team leader if if the team
leader is not security sensitive or has
no inclination to towards security then
take another person in the QA team who
is more interested and start
infiltrating into the QA team from that
point of from that door because
eventually we know we want everybody
that the QA teams are getting smaller
and smaller once we had teams seven ten
nine now since everything is automated
three four or even two is more than
normal size so in any case you get the
team leader plus one almost hold the
team I think gradually we're covering
everybody and gradually we can give them
more and more test cases and the best
thing it's automatic and they are doing
this actually in every sprint and I
don't need to tell them
remind them or review anything with with
them because it's automatic more
question
yeah thank you okay thank you very much
[Applause]