so thanks for joining this talk or the
title of this talk is vehicle security
trends implications for the auto
supplier so the brief intro of myself my
name is Aaron Guzman I'm based out in
Los Angeles I head up an automotive and
IOT testing team for a company called a
on I lead the wasp IOT project in the
embedded application security project
I'll be talking about those projects at
11:55 and project showcase so if you
want to hear about some updates and
things that were working on I think it's
Hall G a couple of things as far as
background within automotive space and
IOT help facilitated the automotive ice
ax first tabletop exercise about two
years ago down in Honda in Los Angeles
which is a experience with several of
the OEM manufacturers as well as Tier
one suppliers basically going through a
mock of an of an incident and how they
would respond if you've ever interacted
with anyone from the automotive space
they don't like to really collaborate
too much so it was definitely eight
hours of pulling teeth
outside from that published the book IOT
penetration testing cookbook in November
of 2017
and also edited a few IOT security books
with packet publishing outside of that I
love pizza I am disappointed that I
packed pizza socks but I packed two
different pizza socks and I decided to
leave them back in my room so outside of
that have disclosed some some security
research for automotive analogy products
specifically for Subaru was able to
compromise a Subaru vehicle at users to
the ikaw basically the essential
functions of Starlin Subaru StarLink on
you know unlocking cars and honking horn
flashing lights things like that
had some fun that was a couple years ago
now
so enough about me go through the brief
agenda here we're gonna talk about some
advancements in the automotive space
talk about suppliers and their
development lifecycle go through some
research case studies also also some
field work that we've performed and got
hired for suppliers and manufacturers as
well and go through some solutions
mitigated mitigative solutions and then
if we have time we'll go through
questions so there's some some major
trends going on here within the
automotive space one is electrification
the other is mobility mobility mobility
as a service autonomy south driving
vehicles and connectivity all of which
are kind of in a way dependent on each
other essentially what the automotive
industry is doing is not only becoming a
product product but also technology a
company filled with services in the way
of integrating with not only the vehicle
itself but also third parties and we'll
get to some of those concerns in a bit
but in order for you know full autonomy
full self-driving cars you'll have to
have full connectivity perhaps
electrification moving forward as well
the majority of newer vehicles already
have some of this functionality as far
as connectivity autonomy and we'll go
through some of the levels in a sec but
essentially this is what's going on as
far as you know new developments and I
guess you know first will touch upon
connectivity and what's happening in the
connectivity space for automotive
usually in order to connect a vehicle
you'll have either telematics control
unit or board and usually you'll have
some sort of network connection via LTE
I can even have a via Wi-Fi I'm moving
forward maybe we'll see some 5g and then
what we really have some
you know Thomas vehicles go now so with
connectivity we have these new kind of
alphabet soup acronyms you have vehicle
to infrastructure or your cars talking
to the infrastructure vehicle to vehicle
vehicle to pedestrian vehicle device
vehicle to grid and vehicle to
everything again these are all
requirements for connectivity and
vehicles moving forward again you know
vehicle to vehicle is just basically
exchanging you know certain information
about traffic about distance and
metadata
vehicle to infrastructure similar
similar kind of architecture except you
know talking to me basically
infrastructure for roadside units and
intelligent traffic systems in the
future so a lot of exciting things going
on but certainly obviously you know
expands the attack surface from a
security perspective with all these
acronyms and connectivity requirements
you also have new companies and
suppliers who are developing software
outside of you know the traditional way
and manufacturers so some of these
demands in order for connectivity to
actually work we need you need to you
need the vehicle to be cloud connected
24/7 ability to perform secure
over-the-air updates not only for the
vehicle itself but also components and
we're seeing this with safety critical
components with Tesla which is a little
scary we now have basically DevOps
in vehicles now it's kind of cool but
kind of scary also similarly with ivi
applications so they had unit
applications now I guess being pushed
down from the manufacturers they'll want
updates to be on the fly so update
updates to your head unit applications
are also coming down in the future if
not already I believe some manufacturers
already have that in place and with
connectivity you have more data more
data that's being shared not only with
the manufacturers suppliers and the
infrastructure in state
but also third-party services in order
to you know whatever whatever maybe for
licensing which is basically selling
that data another word that's been kind
of coined in the industry they don't
like to say you know we're selling your
data other licensing your data and of
course not only with you know being
connected all the time 24/7 not only
with secure up updates but also they
want reliable connections they want
resiliency some redundancy and obviously
security meaning you know going through
secure channels whether that's
end-to-end encryption or using other
means
hopefully not through proprietary
protocols which are being debunked now
so with connectivity we talked about
autonomy a TAS is also a an acronym used
but essentially there's five levels of
autonomy are currently around level two
here which is you know the driver assist
a pro pilot assist the the Lane Lane
Departure assistance there are vehicles
that are said to be level three I think
some one of the newer out er eights but
there's there's some some great areas
here with level three meaning if the
vehicle is driving and there is a
there's a driver behind the wheel or
vehicle operator they're supposed to be
ready to intervene at any time but
chances are if your cars already self
driving you're not going to be engaged
it's going to be very difficult at least
to be ready especially if you know the
the vehicle isn't isn't planning for
certain situations so every manufacturer
already has a level two you know a level
two autonomy in their in their model
years you know the the fours the GM's
the Subarus the the Toyotas I think
after 2017 and up is when every vehicle
is already equipped with telematics
units so installed whether you are a
subscriber or not
so you got to think about that unless
you take out that telematics unit but
it's it's it's it's said that we'll have
full autonomy within the next ten years
if not sooner I think there is a huge of
dependence upon 5g so some real scary
situations but essentially there's you
know self-driving trucks already in in
the field so it's also causing
disruption for for the for the economy
so just be mindful of some of these
levels here we'll get to some of the
concerns in a second here but
essentially drivers are fading away and
now becoming vehicle operators and
they're even hiring for vehicle
operators which is crazy so quick quick
a graph here from from Edmunds showing
the active safety features basically
when the vehicle is taking control of
something that will cause safety
concerns which is adaptive cruise blind
spot detection lane departure you can
see on the rise essentially you know
again this is only 2017 pretty much
we're probably in the 80 to 90 percent
percentile for active safety features
with newer cars but what's scary is that
we're giving up our trust to someone
else's code or several thousand people
people's code who are writing the
software you know to keep to keep you
safe to keep you happy convenient
there's even aftermarket autonomy
meaning devices that you can install on
your vehicle cameras aftermarket
basically wheels that will again do some
self-driving functions for you which is
really really sketchy but I wanted to
share a specific quote here from there's
a company called lane cruise and
basically they're retrofitting vehicles
only to be connected but again have
these autonomous features so scrolling
through their page and you know going
through the FAQ and they have at present
and most your addictions level to
autonomy is not regulated and hence
totally legal this is why I can buy a
luxury car or some of these features
built in without any legal implications
it's all right away I mean that's some
red flags and this is just again an
aftermarket this is an aftermarket
company that's developing software
people are using this in their vehicles
already super super scary I couldn't
imagine you know this linkers company
you know even if it has several hundred
employees or developers I'm sure that
there are some flaws several different
types of flaws but just the thought of
this code being introduced into vehicles
expanding that you know you know older
type of vehicle you know this El Camino
for example a 90s 80s car that's now
going to have self-driving capabilities
so you know given the example of the
startup startup company Ling Cruz you're
probably wondering you know who's
building and innovating in this base
like who's responsible for developing
this software and it's just a sea of
partnerships acquisitions and newer
types of OMS who are building south
driving vehicles from the ground up and
fleets
so essentially you know loads of Silicon
Valley startups who you know are
proposing perhaps Ling Cruz might be
acquired by you know a manufacturer at
some point but what's happening is OMS
are essentially turning into venture
capitalists angel investors acquiring
these companies partnering with these
companies and then working with Tier one
suppliers and this graph is purely just
the relationships in 2017 for autonomous
vehicles and who's partnering with who
essentially everyone's partnering with
someone or perhaps a same supplier and
supplier is well we'll get to in a
second so essentially again third-party
companies who are developing this
software it's not the OEM manufacturers
who are developing you know all the
software that had units the in vehicle
networks there's a lot of third parties
involved
so the supplier types and roles if you
ever opened up the hood of your car
you'll see several different names of
the product manufacturers so you'll have
the hardware components which you know
the body control the body control
modules powertrain sensors your gateways
cryptographic modules and so forth
but you also have the software
components which is the platform
operating system it could be Q and X it
could be AUTOSAR that's being used it
could be an older Microsoft but also
there are third-party suppliers who
develop drivers and libraries to help
connect you know certain areas of the
hardware from the software perspective
and then also the supplier to develop
the ivi applications the mobile
applications or web applications you
know it's not again it's not these
manufacturers who are developing this
software it's the partnering with the
supplier a third party essentially in
order for this to happen to be pushed
out so a lot of moving parts right a lot
of you know a lot of cooks in the
kitchen just for one product and this is
this is similar not only for automotive
but IOT as a whole anything really
product are embedded related essentially
has a similar structure of supply chain
and development but what's you know you
know I don't want to fear monger here or
but just kind of get to gain a
perspective the the amount of code
that's in a vehicle ranges from 100 to
300 million lines of code and this is
not only just the in vehicle networks
but also the head units and several
other aspects of a vehicle there's four
there's 40,000 Hardware parts and this
data was taken from Toyota so this is
Toyota's estimates
and think about that there's code and
hardware and software and wireless
protocols essentially code is everywhere
and you know folks like us and oh wasps
are here to help try to gain a you know
insider perspective not only from an
attacker but also for secure coding we
reviewed Anitha an IV I application one
application that's a default application
on several vehicles there was six
million lines of code just for a head
unit application this is the client-side
and server-side code which is crazy six
million lines of code it's absurd and
it's only going to be more code being
introduced moving forward you know with
all the you know connectivity
requirements the v2 vvt-i tana me so
difficult to try and guarantee safety
and security with that much code and
especially legacy code and code that
perhaps a supplier is developing for not
only one manufacturer but let's say for
manufacturers so again everything is
code so this is just an observation here
based upon some of the assessments that
we've done so we've not only done
penetration testing assessments but also
maturity or use for suppliers and this
could be a even a supplier coming to us
and they're partnering with a
third-party company let's say in India
and they want us to review if there s
DLC is if there's if basically if
they're saying that they're testing
they're doing source code analysis
dynamic and so forth they call us in to
verify kind of do you know align with
like open Sam for example a software
assurance maturity model so we've been
engaged with multiple suppliers who are
publicly traded companies who have over
300 developers and zero to three
cybersecurity professionals
which is amazing to me and some of the
requirements to job posting requirements
don't want five or seven years in
security they want some engineering
experience basically you know they're
asking for the world here but yet they
they have no one internally to even
interpret let's say their source code
analysis output
you know reports and so forth so if you
look through a number of different
suppliers career pages they're pretty
they're pretty entertaining but again
shocking that I guess not not super
shocking but that you know the lack of
you know security within a safety
critical area or critical infrastructure
now you know moving forward with
vehicles you know isn't getting much
love but hopefully that'll change moving
forward I know several manufacturers are
now have internal red teams which wasn't
a thing before I think in the last three
years I think the majority of
manufacturers do aside from some Jap
Japanese manufacturers will call them
out but to run through the software
development life supply chain here
essentially you'll start with the OEM
who defines the specifications for what
they need what they want whatever
whatever may be for either telematics
control unit a head unit a body control
module but essentially you'll start with
the hardware requirements you'll have
your board support package that could be
working with a driver company comm or
whoever else a boss whoever whoever it
could be you have your downstream
suppliers your software suppliers
essentially people who are developing
the code your cloud providers whether
it's AWS whether it's ours or whether
it's their own in-house cloud and then
you have integrators who work with these
suppliers in order to kind of ease that
that transition to a production
environment so then you have you know
several third parties several different
teams involved from around the world
and then for me you know looking at kind
of the the overall process
and from the handoffs from team the team
there are several flaws that you can
obviously identify but a number of
different third-party code and teams to
be targeted super simple we could easily
target an open source library or a
software supplier and any of these
stages you know in order to get you know
not only effect again I mentioned 101
OEM manufacturer but several so a lot
going on again very very similar
landscape for IOT devices as well aside
from the integrators but just imagine
this area here branched off into maybe
20 other different suppliers so not only
are you know we're having legitimate
software suppliers via you know tiered
you know tier 1 2 to tier 2 or 3 but now
they're expanding this supply chain with
third-party development services and you
know basically essentially having
cryptocurrency in your vehicle now how
amazing is that or not
Jaguar just released a program where
you'll have a smart wallet in your
vehicle that basically it'll report the
potholes and flaws in the road so
essentially you're getting paid
automatically for your vehicle and also
pay using your car for services whether
it's a gas or you know going for a
coffee of some sort so these services
again are a little bit makes me a little
bit nervous again having cryptocurrency
here in cryptocurrency for your vehicles
and other manufacturers are also
following following the same trend Honda
just released their mobile wallet in CES
this past year again integrating with
third-party services and the
infrastructure of the services being
offered by gas stations and restaurants
and so forth GM has its own marketplace
you can order
again you know Starbucks get some donuts
my personal favorite is Applebee's
there's no Applebee's here but one of my
favorites so this this app marketplace
think of it like a Android Play Store
were essentially previously legacy apps
you know where you didn't have much to
choose from
was just whatever is default and maybe a
few others that you can install but now
you have the opportunity to pull down
the apps from a marketplace and do some
reverse engineering disassembling and so
forth you know with the apps in the
marketplace or you can just develop your
own third-party app using you know their
developers program they supply you with
an SDK they supply you with emulators
they supply you with everything you'll
be you're essentially need to get off
the ground so you have folks like you
and I who can develop software for your
cars and some of the the level of access
that the these SDKs have are access to
the internal vehicle networks so you can
scrape can bus you can you know scrape
maybe a media network whatever you want
essentially so really scared from that
perspective again opening up that you
know traditional kind of closed off you
know no network environment no you know
apps you know that probably never get
updated on your head unit to a more
dynamic landscape and more open with
third-party developers and you know
they'll have minimal vetting for
developing software and becoming a
partner or a supplier but anyone who is
motivated or you know has an end goal
for compromising a vehicle can easily do
it via you know their third-party
developer portals other services like
Amazon's key and car with Ford's and
Lincoln basically unlock your car um for
Amazon delivery drivers so again not
only are you trusting
you know strangers to enter your vehicle
but we also talked about the the sick
the adaptive safety features for your
car you know the lane departures and so
forth
this is a massive target right and it's
easy to to put some attention here just
because you know the getting the many
different hands many different teams
many different services and it's only
going to increase moving forward and
this is already happening again in IOT
anybody here heard of Mariah so it
affected the US but also you know other
other countries around the world but it
took down the internet for a period of
time a couple years back and essentially
what was what happened was attackers
targeted a certain original design
manufacturer ODM which is another word
for supplier there's all these different
same terms for different industry
verticals but odm is essentially a
supplier so they targeted zhong my and
zhang my they created essentially the
the embedded linux platform that then
was built built upon for you know custom
resellers or custom om manufacturers to
use and there were you know default
talonnet credentials and command
injections and so forth but not only
zhang MA you also have you know blue
board and you have crack you have
meltdown specter which are all you know
third-party software that's installed in
safety critical functions in a vehicle
and even IOT devices and there's more
examples but it's already happening also
something to keep in mind is the
difficulty of updating these these these
devices so not only in IOT but also just
general software they're you know
there's nation state nation state or
even malicious groups out there who are
targeting the supply chain i believe
there's even a talk on supply chain
today as well probably more towards
javascript because that's also a mess
but essentially you know we have these
groups here focusing on
installing or developing backdoors and
injecting those into you know let's say
like Asus for example who was affected
by by this group as well as ccleaner you
know or there was backdoors and they
speak compromising one of the suppliers
in order to gain full control remote
code execution this is just you know not
too long ago so you so what I did talk a
little bit about updating or lack
thereof but essentially a vehicle has a
life cycle of our lifespan of seven to
fifteen years a traditional vehicle this
is changing moving forward but you know
a vehicle could be you know vulnerable
for a long period of time or may not
ever be updated maybe there isn't an
over there Update solution for certain
model years which has happened for
several manufacturers well they'll send
a USB stick for you to install an update
I won't speak in that in detail but
probably better solutions so you know
again you have all these third-party
code applications and services that can
potentially be completely vulnerable for
an extended period of time
so some some case studies here that's
happened within the last year year and a
half there was some work done by a a
research firm or security firm where
they shopped around for vehicles to
remotely exploit flaws and what they
chose were vehicles that had a large
attack surface that being a Volkswagen
Golf and Audi
they essentially use the same head unit
again because the same supplier they're
also a part of the same company but they
discovered some vulnerabilities within
the Wi-Fi hotspot and essentially gain
remote code execution in several
different ways one of them was via a
service in town net as well as gaining
access to a certain area of the vehicle
where you can send arbitrary Ken
can messages to the canvas but what they
did was they stopped there they didn't
release technical details because the
vehicles those vehicles do not have
update functionality and they felt that
they would leave those vehicles at RIT
at risk and some of the suppliers there
a note our block is blackberry Q and X
and NVIDIA and here's the the head unit
that got routed on the head unit QNX
neutrino is a common operating system
where platform used for head units
probably there's automotive grade Linux
and Q and X are probably the the major
platforms that are being used today but
essentially manufacturers are partnering
with blackberry in order for them to to
provide that platform security and
updates yeah in order to keep you know
the head unit as well as the safety of a
vehicle kind of in order so there was
some research with BMW last year as well
by Tencent labs who absolutely tore
these BMWs apart separate several
different models were affected but
essentially what they did was exploit
multiple qnx systems that were used by
the head unit and obtained again a
remote code execution after fuzzing not
only the browser not only the telematics
control unit but even the USB interface
had USB to Ethernet so again they have
the they had to connect systems they had
third party Bluetooth stack a custom
browser by Harman again another stuff
another supplier and then the telematic
communication box was also an another
supplier in third party someone spent
too much time on this research because I
want to get into more details from some
of the field work that we've performed
but just again to show some examples in
case studies of research firms or even
attackers focusing in on suppliers and
again how that affects not only multiple
vehicles for same manufacturer but also
number of different manufacturers in
this case there was the Tesla keyfob
research anybody heard about this so we
cool yeah so there is the Tesla Model S
essentially was using a picture and
keyfob system where the research company
was able to defeat some of the wireless
encryption here and they were able to
generate key codes and essentially
obtain a vehicle steal vehicle and
definitely not just you know the
previous security research of obtaining
key codes number of them to start open
up the car stop and potentially start
again now they created we have the
capability using you know I think five
hundred dollars worth of hardware using
a guard stick one on proxmark
raspberry pi rainbow tables proxmox
already like three four hundred dollars
so probably a thousand dollars but
essentially it's possible and this same
key fob system was used in MacLaren's
which are really expensive cars as well
as motorcycles triumph so really
interesting to think about you know as
an attacker I want the highest impact
and something that'll get the company's
attention and again focusing in on a
supplier is definitely the route to go
so some field work that we performed
give an example here for an IV I
application or we perform multiple IV I
application assessments and this was a
default application that's installed on
several vehicles and the platform it
wasn't only the default application and
the IV I but I also had a companion
mobile app so some of these have hybrid
environments where it's connected to
vehicle has some functionality and
perhaps shares some internet
connectivity through that through a
mobile device but in this case or one of
the cases here was six million lines of
code again for the client-side and
server-side code base and you know it's
very difficult to get all the code
the supplier in order to compile in
order for us to do proper source code
analysis and they didn't really know all
the third-party libraries that they had
so for us that was already a light bulb
that we're gonna find some pretty big
pretty big issues you know during the
assessment so we so this assessment was
a gray box so we had not only the source
code access to the developers but also
perform dynamic testing very very
helpful probably the most effective way
to do security assessments but what we
found was loads loads of dead code
unused code common to code with API keys
with essentially user account
credentials database passwords
hard-coded not only their credentials
but the API endpoints which gave us an
easy way to get access to the admin
interfaces of all these applications
I'll get to that in a second and again
in this case what they were doing is
licensing data scraped from the canvas
and I'm not sure if they had these
agreements with the the OEMs I think
they just have the access and they're
like hey yeah we're gonna do what we
want because we have access so these a
VI applications are not only talking to
the OEMs cloud infrastructure you know
some OEMs require intend encryption but
it's also talking to their own cloud
infrastructure third-party cloud and you
can imagine that's this is only one
application in this case again you know
that data being shared in multiple
layers multiple services multiple
companies but with you know identifying
some of the hard-coded application
servers on a server-side infrastructure
these application servers did not even
have authentication we were able to get
remote code execution on these servers
we were able to upload our own
application servers some of the the
pages that we found were status pages
that have the ability to dump memory
from the application servers so
essentially the basics of security
security principles and
cleanliness we're not there what they
heavily dependent on was the OEM to go
and do their own security assessment for
for their application but essentially
it's like a unit test where it's about
two check boxes and if the features you
know are what what they agreed upon then
that's like the bare minimum if they
require TLS that's all they're going to
put is TLS they're not going to ensure
that they're doing output encoding and
they're not going to do some input
validation it's really really
interesting case but once the
application was running it was even
logging the API keys the user basically
coordinates the data from the canvas
that it was scraping essentially
everything it could was log to the
console in this case that we're using a
head unit that was Android based so
logcat super super simple to acquire
that data and if you've ever I don't
know if anyone has anyone done forensics
on an automotive telematics unit or a
head unit load loads of data I better
speed up here loads of data there here's
an example this is what they were doing
again
logging the API key secret request paths
all to the console doing basically
dynamic arbitrary code formation here in
Java you actually see a C and C++
encrypting I'm sorry logging again the
VIN on all the kind of safety critical
functions as well and even logging
usernames and passwords so really really
basic things that there was just you
know wasn't on top of their heads
longitude latitude
here's that application server with a
threat to you can click on any of these
dump the memory see what's going on with
what vehicle around the world because
this supplier not only developed company
develop software for for the US but also
Canada China South America
again this had no authentication here's
the application server that had default
credentials of course and a legacy
patchy access server where we were able
to get code execution so you know very
little effort unfortunately and what we
did is we used standard methodologies
and tool sets it wasn't anything crazy
that we did out of the ordinary we
leveraged the application security
verification standard the mobile one as
well the OAuth top tens
not only for for the web mobile and IOT
you know we did source code analyses
using commercial and free tools listed a
few tools that we used mobile security
framework which is a great tool if
anyone's used it before but was what was
really the key was manually reviewing
the code and working with the dev teams
all this although the dead and commented
out code is not gonna be flagged too
much by by tools it's going to be
informational at best so you know in
those comments we also found github
credentials crazy crazy crazy stuff so
we also do a product assessments for
fleet management companies there's Tier
one suppliers that essentially develop
products that plug into commercial
trucks and passenger vehicles as well
via obd2 in this case it wasn't as
simple it didn't have much of an attack
surface it was using a bare metal there
was an embedded Linux a real-time
operating system but we got lucky and by
sniffing hardware communication via
serial we were able to obtain firmware
over the over-the-air credentials and
pull over 7,000 vehicle details about
maintenance about you know the drivers
about essentially you know critical
details for this commercial company tier
1 supplier but again this is also
retrofitting cars that aren't made to be
connected and again you're exposing all
that data now by pulling that data and
then not only for
fleets and monitoring driver riskiness
in this case but licensing as well and
for case number two here for a fleet
management supplier in this case it was
a IOT gateway and since we didn't
multiple these where it had Wi-Fi
Bluetooth LTE has cameras and basically
drivers connect to the hotspot and the
sensors around the vehicle connect to
the hotspot and we were able to obtain
code execution by having a live serial
connection but essentially what we did
was was expose our exploit open source
components I was using fastboot which is
an Android based bootloader and it had
debug functionality to stack trace we
were able to get a code execution by
essentially using arm assembly to then
give us a shout cess by putting in our
ssh credentials okay let me close it out
some example code here that we used
essentially the the bin sh here that's
what we used to get code execution
mounted the file systems able to input
our user and then get route at the end
of the day another finding we were able
to bypass secure boot by using a
malicious NTP server pushing down to an
expert expiry date that wouldn't be
recognized and we found that this is a
problem with all embedded devices
essentially finding a trusted source of
time interesting problem let me run
through these really quick I know we're
out of time again the suppliers are
reliance upon OMS to perform you know
security initiatives and testing there's
lack of security culture personnel and
folks who understand security within
supplier companies so especially when
you have these startups and newer types
of products that are being developed by
you know Silicon Valley companies
and essentially writing software that
had not been exposed to the internet
previously again we talked about these
clients that credentials and you know
secrets that you know would not normally
you know be internet-facing and now is
and you know lack of transparency
through the supply chain essentially you
know blackbox binaries are given to OEM
manufacturers and that are being
compiled into their head units or
whatever the product may be you know
your supply their suppliers essentially
have their own suppliers so this kind of
trickles down think about kind of the
the JavaScript supply chain issues so
we'll wrap up with some technical
guidance here or at least some
mitigation measures there are several
different best practices to bolster up
security programs for automotive
companies there's a new standard being
released in 2020 as iso standard that's
going to work with OEMs and Tier one
suppliers which is promising essentially
it's going to show their due diligence
for security which right now it's a mess
there isn't a standard for cyber
security in the automotive space so
everyone's using their own frameworks
which you can imagine is like you know
developing your own crypto okay guys you
know wrap up if you have any questions
feel free to find me I'll be in the the
project showcase and thank you for your
time
[Applause]