you yeah
so their murmured yeah
I rather were
a while over early owner
place a the word retired from
use I'm and
were for whatsoever good
you know an awful
girl and I'm launcher
no I'm so we're going to do with the
is are you know
there you probably wouldn't
yeah
also yeah
I'm so semen go
this
time
Rs as a grow
there
so you fun you know the the
yeah is only one through
you this your own Google no
knows more saw a movie heroes a
yeah a for
I Leo you'll
usually not you with a yeah this is the
well as I i'm suppose really
I yeah so I ever meet you know just
gives up
and see what happens and year well
although why are there so that mean
for kobliner view
one or %uh doesn't also way
for us %uh who was very girls is around
your things well and for every word
my number of gears up notes I
was I
you wheels
mu preserve the word
yeah
good
go here her go
Yahtzee
things you might say one
maybe 10 this
K no looooove a
are there to Galway
I love you for greater
yeah
researchers is no I'm certain it wasn't
you can use my
I would persist next thing I know is
that okay
I were for
world
weaver this is funny of yeah
a wat I'm
want this with a
wrong you
record
I'm
I was 10
say I'm is a yeah lunch the 10
our as yeah
home see you yeah I'm
is old people aren't
fire okay for is I really worry was a
R Us share this is the new I love
visit with these are the ones who are
goes years ago
02 search for gruesomely
up the here
driver you %uh whose so
I I'm so use Google
here so through it finds a
measures and owner Ruvo
reso whether the rules
I %uh because you know
pasa was a really good
are spirit world when I'm
over I your mind
so you know you will know I'm
thorough are you for back over
is then %uh the way well %uh the fast
lap
with force %uh goes our
jus over I'm so as a Sr
05 10
for yeah
over I actually with ross also
a I'm very over some people though
you know to a smile back up there are
those morocco's
your water I for say for
so I'm so overtime
there
Yahoo goings
for so oh I so love these
a about to retire after other
500 50 I'm another
reward files up with you so
with rumors change uses I'm here
as mercury morris israeli's where
service back to you
fearsome proposal if I was you
those guys I'm
was a my was
there's a on all we were hanging over us
over o'hare so
is I that is
rule I'm
designed
go
design far was it was a %uh
their live around there are all
his a
more gold %uh the and
Louis you yeah
so overview
law
you know hey
I or real love I
vid yes have her
and Yahoo's shared
has my ways over
on the the not over here
Google everything that's fine I
holes themes third room or services
I wouldn't mind about does either
more 300 heard yeah it is
there's a
president
0 yes
yeah and
this
were all I'm
Jr
each
me
it
though visitors leave no was your
I just I
us I rather hold and by
goldfish you goes here
his car it's very rude
any worse user your the number
we've were mustered you
passwords yeah okay with you
for with a I wasn't rude I'm
so I up with a
paper RRR
Sasa go
I'm so there's a few good
were for us we love you I'm
I'm michael Munger
room third review fellow
a blue you other I'm
cerveza a very very was
not for you I'm
over was a
grizzard so
a you know there's rooms are held for
I'm overheard my yeah
there's just no data being with him
America go share traders are the
so-called
guys 3 you're free services
group of people are and is in her room
it people who are world you over
the and the lady from
yeah for up
oh yeah I
so where you for are
geyer yours worry someone
gave I were around
work on this is a good
any federal whoa
both firms are which is services
goodness
I'm but they are
over third
as a I
good you know it was after
I yeah throughout
I'm the unit is users on
%uh yeah rather
use were fired and their sorrow
you rather than players pictures on this
you pasa one bird
it were visit whatever
I'm your goals you
a result of my for I'm
I'm a wats a
hires Tahoe other though
you got it my a were here
the I
year was a are you I'm peace
for you word see the or
I a
this was voters with a
and those are the ER
movies and so and well
with you are it very
or as it were %uh over 30
for you or know every word was
or so we're good military $80,000
I so I'll
over got
hungover a few over
and the permit
no were outweighs without member
over an investment
I'm you there %uh and it was on
was a and a %uh
we were rude were or no you
were I rock
and for know who over
rules are look to see
your grow but that we're moving
furniture
Armani military with a
you would use also
her goes below
%uh there's are
all this is overall survival of blue
the screws are gone law and 40,000
more wall I it was more like this
remove the mood I for
I don't worry about the world it okay
faster than I her does leave
third years I'm
you know who you with a very long run
how would you know Yahoo good
you gruver I was looking for you
are as a 10 I'm
I'm really was I greater pasa
for customers this error of plus I'm
a number houses more good where
I have no early after that on everyone
knows
for so so ever
going to remember all the that I
your so
just will her well
go well as a reliever
over Spurs for for those a
your cool this is not about overhaul
guys you offered craft hours ago
and the although there was a problem
I'm much rather that he will slow down
was a over so all over you
whatever a
to so so you who are here
for yeah
people over unfortunately it was a
this
I'm this
Cirque hey I'm
you know go
match
there
yeah ever for
other yeah
good I'll you've ever had before
up I numbers but not this time
yeah I he was the Olympics other
%uh a little bit about him for murder
for injured well University I
or holes still have the disease or GERD
up
this is very groundwork to know you
I Martin business unit as ever you
is your my goes my
where's so please
you don't mind 0 I
be alas a up to you
job for here as honest on our
our presentation is done no my this with
the speaker is
were for were so I'm
I'm your on the website is this
were I'm going to go I'm a sucker
you'll see why I'm in my possession
up it is I'm was my first time
over and over song versa yeah
we're long-haul past were overpass
recess yeah we force
a a very bizarre or a special election
self-awareness is a surveyor
I we all say you know a base
are characters I was on december we
expect songs on
some police repair 0
while use your services do you remember
your
a smaller so it was with my Facebook
group yeah it's sooo inspired
yeah are think so are looking for a
solution
this was a I think this is because my
found is our whole life
as a 0 was ace
Verizon murders of three up her
yeah talk about sprays and passwords
all and he said
this is right there are other I was or
he said
passphrase spaces 0
much longer the bass sharam majorities
you
word embraces so -2
so was rules lol cadd9
something like that very well I said
okay well maybe passphrase Mb
the salud to my
user my sued rees et
so I'm go first ever since your own room
Murray was a I was always ask her what
she do something I was wrong I was war
my eyes you know you something like that
I
this is going to be so smart girl 0
but in the back of my
is through it is that really user Lewis
Lew
so I somehow whole
home people users I
real-live you wheels power
users together 0 ass however
0 lovers my users there
but I really want to find out up were
minus
use Facebook better or worse the hackers
you know yesterday finally broke her
asking a lot here
I'll world were Mesa
passes a good complexity centers were
getting Facebook too
the result is on time I
going to about yeah %uh using number
I got ninety percent of weeks I was
yes because I thought you know iran also
or
I'll but how is that fair so
on the severity goes on and on about how
polar ice or are they better or worse
so this is a free service yeah so it's a
little while
loss I because I
professor William this is this is a
Yahoo
resolved what we have here we have a
number passwords
I five years is there's a
her saw and cycle or
across every us BC and their songs
myspace there's be
there's a lot to what was wrong on this
you know this
you know her but there's a you follow
real you well here third yeah they're
beyond their when I saw it
workers are position well I'm
mall working people who it was curve is
it
saw position
no the first position yours is the way
we see
that there's a there's just under seven
percent
0 passwords use offer
livers position here over your said
low I heard yet so
I is this is this is an anomaly for
sewing
resisted solvable myspace
Yahoo it baby rock you
services friend I yes it is generally
the most are you
we're all professionals golf bags as
they really are we're going to do
also there were laws garth I
you you got sister well last year
your your this a las generally
we have you have I this
the are you know here's a hard
over seventy percent 0
as your yes it was he didn't know the
number that
so well how secure are
passwords really I
commerce we for you quite
so falwell good password
what is good for uses really have girl
what
I would know yes we want to know that
Foley
I'm your great work together is
longer is world class well up there's
also
you after retrieving 0 good
what he is good all
goes just yes
he said it overseas you never said well
you know
%uh as long as you were doing with those
oh and also you know wrong gave you know
you don't really know K are almost here
where all where you are all of us
%uh we know only did the the first
for world were back on my
don't we have I called
everyone is is still more no
figures %uh are are people who see it as
to oppose as good I think hold-ups
is are is up got on the bus stop
you do that you regional up the guy
reside was I so yeah or are we just
going to go out of style
you just really don't know the other
thing I was lot of every problem
I'm or software submarines he was there
is a Vincent
or got the hours let you know how it is
you can see their jobs you can see this
is the CSL
so you know I'll
sorrow on the bus so I decided I was a
little bizarre
his what we saw I
arsenal are or are you know this is my
first their
prior I parcel C you know our old
from Gaza I think it was on
I'll I think it was on newt Gingrich
running for president
abuses nomination I
her whole release one 0
I S yeah Russian in retrospect you know
I know you know you're all up to you
goes
113 where r lose weight you know that
your suburbs of
okay yes Yahoo do %uh
fine the time is not a licensed or
a horror those other side so I was
I was really is. over I'm going over
yes this rapper answer
for December it was your night
and free from I
he said strap it up you so I think
merely I elisa don't yeah I'm gonna
I for yeah server
friend right now so I'm now 5
I'm services Jeremy it was a problem
well
a said seventy percent I
probably sure for whoever
are you was it this is my home
concerned about up
Maru lesser worry about me he wouldn't
rule is a rule or a ride home rule
and then I was up yeah few minutes later
you yeah where times and this is your
article to a friend
%uh few crimes wow I was very very much
going on over who were
was one program happens
you something like that nurses have 20
were one back
were from the on the issue well i fix
that problem you know
baths pay GV Grainger as
this is this is a so Sr so
whitewater up researchers well
yeah up where just go sup
he talks about gas prices ass were
just for you this is yes yeah race
spaces yeah word is gone
sauces okay I'm going to close our
standing on this
busy but finder you go
well you for doing this is where of
up you know I'm sorry race are you
more and more water or strap worries
good work just as well
0 yeah your
years of okay resolving good
so we're just for
worth going over over over it I
its and buses are up yeah there's
up it was a version of the iPad allows
you number five there and all
of being over 800,000 ashes you I got a
new star
for sorrow so
drama is otherwise Los up the good news
is we're
sells crack excited for woohoo
by now germany's economy minister Luis
it does all this
I'll so we're all so it was at issue
his job for yeah early awareness
and we've got got no 1831 wells
what we have weed is we've we you know
we've got this winter stuff we've got
this
we're just were running out to a were
I
it your her he said use a loss for words
with them it was a through youth
running out with their I you know well
here's our
you river on level is it good
here it was even worse is
I know what to do yeah Richard
yeah so
you know say less try let stress
we're gonna start time services were
gonna really try
do that don't know a lot of course says
I you know what lessons
books 10 my
books both are alive sources
and hundreds of thousands about so
up I have was over Hoover
I for our a top 100 miles
all overwhelming boss their our
up there glasser the
UK for by all offers while
follow any yeah this
there are for day on I'll
is our it is about time
casa hey you know where yeah is Gus's
serious girls allowed 0
there well
okay what all I heard almost just like
for congress
got in 600 is a you loss
so is it okay he's a great source
plus now a review so we've got real
real-world raise there's
he's using you won't learn this you
these things in mind
I'll OS %uh be easy to
K yeah I'm okay
there's all that he is you scream
okay it's not really a fun way to a you
know
0 yellow there there's an
with she's someplace else last char on
some
of good there's performance
I'm for you media her who it is
there's also operations we've got a
Harry Potter this is the time rafter
water leaving right open Gary Pollard
thats you alright
star don't be phrases from her
our movie and were runners-up her
somebody's
see all over you we didn't want that
so just doesn't pass our whole house
whatever worries all the while tell it
to cease
it was loss I'm holes there okay
I worries the law yes
what okay never leave you with this well
there's 0 or so processes you have to go
through
you're going to do gas prices you're a
worthless
from a book like media Uganda
yet you you've got way to go
at I'll I was going to get
girl or you want where you go respect
for our
all I previous offers you various uses
of
various uses there's general I
what are your if you do not agree with
her
me send the bus I you know
whose close are you I'll with this
included
was me we saw over upward server
slime I heard herself a listed
mister law me everything lower case
feet were Lulu do that everybody here
very sad
sooner or later sorrow
your got is a we've got this long is
words I'll how are you you know
you know you why we're it was our song
I'm
you weeks or so
your yeah all day you eases up for
limit your researchers a lives I'll
and it also you know right you're right
back to you
yes all yes very clear
you like this and I'll of
your desire up so it went for your stars
are you
use that as our up
is our the first thing we do is a big
word
you know it was we go it was a
you know that our I always do
guns are not there you go
Las was a well as they are what are you
was a dinosaur very well
I KR HR AR
or AR Socorro
it is the who were online are scared RR
are or lime and its is not be over
phrases are yeah but this is a
he's more were like yes very soul who
uses
barnstorming I'm up or C&R
store doesn't make sense you're looking
for a great
I are or so
so is my
here you
the weaver you want all my sis your
lottery with its
you love you it was something I
over or so worries or fail to see
it was at times it was the worst months
right
it was it was it was sprinkle over there
we found this out
physically star through these books
was we start with over six do it
a her up phrases
by the phone with mom was only but
changes
deeper you go all is the lady with her
rights but significant
this whole sunday
over bizarre we can read or
show respect one another right rather
you security breach 911
0 reserving of professional
for its information in your face for you
this is 2morrow this is your
you obviously years with handling over
here this is where
the up this is where the phrase a well
yeah
wonderful line looking I missing
something
yeah we started the actual diseases that
career
were not be a yeah eighty percent we're
going on
yeah the group's that I
these is a through pass phrase just for
jobless
my I saw is approved for house purchases
you got me in the face
I might never see your face again well
more
and if you think yeah I rather
for files I venues
okay think back years ago
did you ever yeah I never
36 here over a slower pace
that knowing that
not you walk us through to you get
something like that
for dinner in New Year was work forget
this is a revelation is
right you never Unidos I'm raises
here we are Rossi who says it is just
like it was
alright these passwords
just services a yeah were
does I says
services of a Boeing your
yeah he's a so are
no it was said two years or so from
sister
password ass up shattered
what are the chances that he cracked you
say
yeah
so I went back to the original oversell
yeah are the views were rahal's
the while were where r
I their to everything else that we
that I always see is this you simply if
you notice we've got it
that bill heard racks of your
my numbers delivered
your I funniest thing yeah
was giving up exact same thing we've got
I wasn't
first heard ferries I he lives of others
in the sector
see I workers first love
Gollum so this
believable this baby has I
I reserve it myself your
yeah what we see here
for seeing as well matches what we're
seeing is
up the other house Joplin Mo
%uh uses up mind where
and we're almost yeah this is
writing or up for
crazy were its I you
think about what friendly words today
and will be it for everyone 6 months for
me
right it he there were here
all I'm really yes good
your yell at me this is Leslie modeler
two years in a row probably not but
didn't get it
no truly yours or you know we go back
yet today's today's
or
so was there were only one bus well
mine this good for people her lover I'm
right 0 because it had a let's go here
horseless okay USA all this will get you
Harbor mom is a wire firearms
time magazine for little anyway
bombers so I don't know you I'll
of their Lisa love this guy's a I I
don't know
you on Thursday we use sentences
happy who cares I 0 feeling of
I please I'll live I'm
well the the word who this
to sell well this is my
struck her year 0
we've got some rather some say it was a
prosperous
alone this
I
close
fun I'm Google
yeah I
you
don't even see you know this love you
see this
me that
your I'm
goes machine was called
she yeah as much as I love you
use collins also it so
well up
so that's probably because we were
sure were same hers is basically the
same or
can't
if you let it go Harvey discovered
yeah that's why wasn't there yesterday
his other class data visualization
overlap
for me better visualization but if you
look up
%uh you orlando's on all another
wrong with my
use services copter
yeah want
cell yes well up
we're always looking for new sources I
mean don't know how long we was
a with music we yeah
song are also yeah ever in salisbury
over America
we've done overall survival perversely
the were also resources
00 blessed Java is as a rule out there
fast very vascular I my the Social
Security Administration
were first and last names alas up
1i or something like that I really want
you to know
remove I've never use Yahoo Hey
cool good forces or
class shop points in time
we can use brutus were you I
visualization old receiver has
excellent visualization yessir I've the
looking back in time
%uh love love this important for you
diesem his and you're going back many
years
manzullo mine he did it with a friend
my all your own time well for right
yes you chigney home
my I'm
from home good you
I flowing water from Salt Lake City
well only with only with
good to me I'm hasn't moved yet is
deadly or this is for life
you know how it is got over his
corpses are of course in Bayreuth yeah
also morals years for her
colorful yeah
a his file-sharing networks it or
I with news and level that data here
you through everything was a I'm
you problem skin amazing yes
okay over show
that to my yes your already
police as opposed to the slave named
enter someone's life force you
that your YouTube video slang and Leo
survey global so
hah
so that you we're all who's lagaa other
things
I we hold in the process years ago
using rules senator use the delay a
single word
of yes passed through this is julie is
expecting to
for your friends back anti-civil
we were at issue were presented with the
bases leave
were differences fire up strikes
%uh blackball fast yeah it was all over
all rules based on all I have a bit
forward all my
world my rules on the use of my that
Wow always the relation
I love for a task force because the
birds and the bees
years so I'm or I from
the first for you first 15,000 books
I prom I'll
boomer I city is Alyssa
all asked if you go yet in the end of
pesticide use your
on your I was well
yeah I'm for offers for powerful
plus I've I'm ice for
nobody's else Yellow Sea battles
I my my resolve is yes there's nothing I
S
yes to all the I he is in two days
yes because I things close firm
visions we sure are after this
liaise service sleep I
services I hadn't thought of his close
I'll you
hey for polluter
I yeah
yeah K
yeah yeah good morning
is our customers so I wondered his
and up %uh transcripts their of
safe for our so various comments the
warehouse
on dealer for example has already
resumed
through with a
as though
wound
up
world
300 good
I'm old a room for phone
mind businesses yeah guys
be with you you look great no
yeah the whole from you
thought no single service so
this is grab some other
this infographic this time analyze room
oh my it and they said yes
was for this big hurdles earlier there's
honey 986 2001
Tehran's a business you know here
I you think your arms in the air
30 1500 error Google
yes I these herself eyes hurt my
up over over water how
so we still got lot I
0 even touch the service up here
up I
me too are you sure are asked to do a
lot of people in this room
you also yeah her very much on Versus
not Germany great her
yeah there so it would be rude Bruno
I'll I also love XQ
wrong you we all a
scored
you know if this a few
yeah it's also yeah
you home this is just absurd
here so you can reach me I'm 3700 this
is the
course number I teach clear
I'm rather to agree to drop you know
yeah lol K thank you very much
for