hello hello thanks everyone for coming
out I want to thank b-sides Nova for
having me here on this is my first time
as a speaker so this is me jumping
outside there's a box and getting from
behind the analyst keyboard and actually
sharing some of the ideas and things
that I've been working on in the in the
past and and what I plan to do in the
future so the name of this talk is bro I
can see you moving laterally a lot of
people are confused about the name of
the talk it's not about bros like an
effect of the guys like in the gym
pumping iron I was actually about the
security tool bro bro network security
monitoring a little bit about myself I'm
defender at heart i love defending i'm
an incident responder at chicago
mercantile exchange I'm based out of the
New York area but I've been working in
the DC area on to start on my career so
I'm always tied back to DC Virginia area
which is why I you know put him my hat
said speak at this conference on my NSM
fanboy I love anything NSM I'll go over
security onion which was used to draft a
lot of this data that i had and in this
talk and i have a healthy obsession
sometimes unhealthy obsession with
finding new ways to detect malicious
activity attackers it's some people shy
away from you know attack us ending up
on the network and you know the most
folks is a bad day but I see that as an
opportunity to learn more about my
attacker and about new ways to defend in
general and on Twitter I'm RR Cyrus
like I said this talk is primarily about
bro um show of hands how many people are
familiar or I've heard of bro wow great
um so I'll go over a little bit about
bro logs on the bro SMB analyzer which
was introduced and bro version 2 dot 5
which is pretty new which is the current
version right now and also going over
bro scripting using the bros scripting
language to do a lot of these things so
one issue that we have insecurity is
that we focus a lot on trying to protect
attack us from getting inside the
network and so there's a lot of things
set up where you have a firewall setup
you're making sure you're logging
activity hidden externally when nothing
is really mentioned about when the
attackers are in and that's when a lot
of breaches happen where the attacker
has a foothold in they go dark from
analysis perspective and things are
happening behind the scenes that we are
able to detect it so that's the problem
statement of my clock a particularly
lateral movement so now they're on the
network on that might be from an email
attachment that was you know someone
clicked on a bypass AV and now they're
on actual host in the network and
they're moving from system to system to
carry out their our objectives wherever
it might be whether it's gathering more
information or actually gathering you
know secret data that they want to exfil
out one way that attackers use one
technique for lateral movement is
actually SMB using the SMB protocol that
might be to mount window shares also to
move files across the file share
themselves because this is considered
normal activities within the network you
have a bunch of fire activity going on
it's enabled it's kind of a way to blend
in with normal traffic this you know
printer services going on um folks
usually host
a bunch of company files like in
particular shares or multiple shares so
their movement using SMB is likely to go
undetected if you're not looking for it
a little bit about SMB protocol on this
talk is primarily focused on SMB
protocol to that X primarily with
Windows 7 30 is for Windows 10 and
windows 8 dot 1 etc so typically in the
past when we go about looking for
malicious SMB activity specifically
attackers using who's like a PS exact
and move a file from file share the file
share computers a computer or primarily
like see dollar sign admin dollar sign
typically the methods used are 41 snort
you have a snort rule that might take
the detect usage of PS exec and you know
there's ways to get around that and then
windows login where you have the GPO
setting to audit for file share access
and file share objects and so those are
some of the event ID is created and so
with that because snort rules um you
know depending on how you have our
architecture you may miss something and
with window logs you have to collect all
those window logs and put them in a
location and correlate them and generate
use cases for them and that might be
difficult for some companies to do so
the alternative solution is bro and so
bro network security monitor its able to
grab some of the metadata from popular
network protocols as you may know as
HTTP FTP rdp and so SMB was added to
that on in version 2 dot fog so you
could grab file metadata as well on some
of the hashes about the for some
information about the file what kind of
file it is if there's a Windows
executable these are things that might
be helpful to Anna for analysts to know
I'm also alerting on you have the
ability to send a
alerts to a notice not log and your logs
directory and a custom or a default bro
installation and so you will look in
that notice log for things of interest
that are happening on the network and
with the bro logs themselves they are
easy to pump into a sim solution or you
can grep them you can use tool bro cut
to make it a little bit easier on the
eyes to grab particular information that
is interesting to you and this is an
example of a prologue and so you see you
have a UID and that you ID can be used
to match multiple events across logs and
then you have the ID original h which is
your source ID and then the source port
is the original underscore p seen there
and then the protocol which you see in
this case is UDP this is an example of
the connection log if you've never seen
a bro log before bro logs really are by
default kind of difficult to work with
especially the way sighs the window that
you have so you can use something like
you could pump it through less I mean
dash S and it might make it a little bit
easier you can scroll across the screen
to see all the fields not in this jumble
format so like I mentioned before with
bro version 2 dot 5 they enabled SMB as
a protocol and introduced the analyzer
now it's not installed by default by the
way so what you have to do is if
commented out and your local that bro um
file and what you have to do with
uncomment that out and then use pro
control to deploy that again so it's
implemented and actually monitoring for
that i'm using the SMB analyzer to grab
that metadata and so some of these are
some of the SMB logs that were
introduced on SMB def CMD CM CMD
dialogue some of the CM SMB commands
that are being run
SMB file so any files moved across with
SMB also SMB mapping on any smb3
activity and ntlm log and RPC dialogue
and so bro scripting is based on C and
C++ it also has a notice framework so
what you will see with a lot of bros
scripting is that you can look at
activity that is happening on the
network look at the logs and then create
a script based on a particular use case
you're trying to solve and that's what I
did primarily and the research that I've
done so far um a lot of a lot of sock
teams would do the same thing and it's
kind of repetitive so you would look for
some malicious activity going on and you
would find a way to automate that so
that you can do some correlation between
the different logs maybe SMB logs and
maybe rdp logs and and then create a
different notice that isn't built in by
default you could do that through the
notice framework which allows for
alerting so once you do that it kind of
cuts the time so you actually detect
something malicious like pumping through
each of those looking through each of
those separate logs you can just go to
the notice log and through the
correlation there and if you want a
background information then you could go
into those separate logs to get more
details and the files framework is
something that I used to start to detect
this malicious SMB activity only because
you want to try to catch SMB files going
back and forth so the file framework was
helpful in doing so now the scripts that
I wrote i'll have the get help page for
that it was three particular scripts
just three use cases that i found for
SMB one is if you have an SMB file that
attacker you know they're all the system
already inside your environment and now
they're moving on malicious files
between computers mount them the file
shares so that's something that you
would you know have some interest in
detecting one thing one problem that's
wrong with that is that you have one
particular antivirus solution on your
network right and so if that antivirus
solution mrs. that particular binary on
that particular file then again you're
in the dark and so what I thought what
occurred to me was like hey why don't
you just check the file to catch some
low-hanging fruit if there's known to be
bad you can submit the hash to
virustotal to see ok what other
antivirus vendors are saying about this
file and so what I did with this script
was that anytime there's a file that was
transferred over SMB it'll take it will
use the front the file framework to grab
the hash and take the hash using
virustotal API with the API key and send
it to virustotal and if it comes back
with a certain amount of positives then
it would generate a notice to the notice
log so that's low hanging fruit but it's
a start right and so accessing SMB
shears admin shares so you might have
some administrators that might do this
before the most part this shouldn't be
happening so this is access to IPC
dollar sign admin dollar sign see dollar
sign d dollar signs for like your drives
in a normal environment I tested at home
and like an elaborate vironment but your
if you have file-sharing enabled
throughout your network you would have a
lot of activity between the domain
controller and maybe host on your
network so if you want you could take
the script for the adventure these a
little further and put in some white
listing for stuff that you know it's
kind of normal but in this case this
shouldn't be happening too often and so
anytime that occurs it will send notice
it was sent up alert to the notice log
okay so in most environments everyone
has a naming convention similar to this
and so what I found interesting in the
ntlm log which I'll get into later a
particular a particular tool that are
that is used by pen testers if they're
sloppy and they do not change the
hostname of that particular distribution
then the host name is a random hostname
that doesn't match your company's name a
convention and ntlm log and that's
another way to detect some malicious
activity going on so for this is like
hey Sekhmet is our company name and it's
a Windows device and it's a host and
it's located in Virginia and we gave her
the tagging ideas 001 so anything
outside of the script basically checks
for any ntlm from a hostname that's
outside of this naming convention and
then we'll send it to the notice log and
so I'll get into a quick demo I don't
want to test the demo gods so I
pre-recorded this all right so give me
some background on what's going on right
now so there's a maybe a penetration
tester a malicious actor that's out
there that has compromised a system on
the network and now this is them going
through the process of moving laterally
and look at the files of interest and
moving files from system to system so
this is the view from the attacker side
and then it will switch to the analyst
side where you'll get to see some of the
prologue so the analyst doesn't have any
background about what just happened this
is just a view that we're seeing from
the attacker side yep
and so here is a remote desktop with
some credentials that they've had on the
network so remote desktop RDP to some
machine on their internal network now
you're launching sysinternals PS exact
to kind of blend in with regular traffic
and so they're using pH exec to
basically you know spawn a command show
on another box in their environment so
you see they logged into dot 106 and now
they're going to 1 dot 107 so this is a
PS exec service that is starting by the
way as an as an attacker this is pretty
noisy and a lot of attackers are moving
away from this so they use this stuff
like wmi exec and SMB exec and that
could be detected to with some of the
skills I've introduced and so they now
are on the system they went to the
desktop and now they're looking for
files of interest so they found this
daily list and check out that list you
know there's lunch involved there's
brief the director on bro IDs and then
well at the bottom go home and drink
some beer because who doesn't love beer
after a long day of work and so now
they've jumped out of that and now
they're going to the documents because
hey there are always good things in the
documents folder so there's a text
volunteer called few clear location and
maybe sounds like it might be of
interest what's in there so there's a
business deal going down with Bugs Bunny
and this carrots involved and there's a
location so that's something that hey
now that attackers gain that information
and maybe they could disrupt the deal or
take someone out before they get to the
deal now this is the attacker using
xcopy to move windows windows update exe
to the other system that 107 and you'll
see this activity pretty soon so they
moved it to their arm desktop right the
windows update exe de move it to the
desktop on that same system and now
they're going to execute that windows
update exe
and guess what it is Mimi cat and so
from here they're just going to use the
mimic at school to dump some credential
information I learned a little bit about
Mimi cats with this too I restarted the
virtual machine before this and so the
logon passwords like or no because
there's no it's not cached anything the
credentials are cash so me being a
defender I'm always using some attacker
to move to kind of get a wrap my mind
around what's going on and that's just
something interesting I learned I advise
anyone to who's a defender to actually
use some of these um offensive tools to
get a handle of what attackers are
actually using or even pen testers or
red teamers so now this is kali linux
this is metasploit consult they're using
the metasploit PX exact module to do the
same thing and we'll see what that looks
like surely on an analyst side so
they're using those same credentials
from Daffy Duck that they used to rdp to
the other system and now this is from
the airless slide so as an analyst bio
find on my bro logs let's look in the
notice log see if there's anything
interesting there
whoa that's pretty ugly but luckily
enough I highlighted it so it's better
on eyes so now you see that PS exact um
sec exe and now submitted to virustotal
with a hit count of three positives and
so I only sees that like hey I want to
see more about this file he goes through
virustotal and looks up the hash just a
confirm that is PS exact shots we could
be safe here and so this is just season
arm the script itself just uses the
virus total API to grab the JSON down
and parts it and then get some of these
feels and so we want to see what other
activity using that ID that we saw we
want to see what other activity canceled
in that PS exact and so you can see the
use of the admin dollar sign so you can
call you caught the PS exact and the use
of the admin dollar sign in that case
now we're going to look at the notice
log again and sure enough we see windows
update exe that gotta hit count of 39 we
know that as many cats but as an analyst
he's about to have a really bad day cuz
there's no context around that right
just you hit count of 39 you're like oh
and yeah Mimi cats anytime you have many
cats on your network of that day and so
we're going to look at some of the
activity that I came from the copying of
that Mimi cats file to the other system
it's like a type and demos and so you
see the IPC um dollar signs share was
used to copy that using xcopy
so now we're back in the notice log and
sure enough he is exact and that PS is
that I mean PS exec for metasploit
created that randomized suspicious
hostname that now if flag said potential
rogue hostname on the network and I
found what was interesting this is ntlm
it's different ntlm version that's used
I think it's like version one that's
flag because initially the script was 44
version 2 and it didn't pick it up and I
was like wondering why and I looked and
pulled a pcap and its version 1 which
was weird what and so you see the use of
I can see dollar sign admin dollar side
with metasploit Pierce exec and so now
we're just going through and getting
some more information about the activity
that occurred from the logs themselves
that were used in the scripts so here we
are going to SMB are mapping log and
this gives you the idea of some of the
shares that were don't actually use
throughout that whole activity also the
files log it gives the idea of what's in
the files log um you have the name of
the file and also the file share that
was used so this is an SMB files log not
the general files log this is a general
PE log right here that tells you hey
it's a Windows executable
yes what's interesting about this is
before this this talk is actually a
spin-off of a gold paper that I've
written for sands and before that I've
never worked with bro in an environment
setting or even you know long-term this
this paper was opportunity for me to
actually deep dive and toubro itself and
create some use cases that I would use
in my own day-to-day job as an incident
responder also one thing to note is that
from a detective from a detection
perspective a lot of you know you hear a
lot of red teamers or a lot of pen sets
to say hey oh you know defenders have to
close up all these holes and once we're
in we're in I like to combat that a
little bit if you're in a secure sock or
a secure security environment and you're
very mature you could actually kind of
raise their level two because once that
activity is flagged and then having
carried out all their operations that
they wanted to yes they're inside but
nothing has happened so if you caught
them at the side that hey they got you
know Pierce exact running they got Mimi
cats running and now they just have her
then they got the credential dumped on
they're moving laterally you can now
detect them root them out and when you
root them out and now know hey they pick
that up and so now the bar to entry to
come back in and get to that same step
is a lot harder um and so that's
something macswan from Microsoft
introduced a little while back the
incident response pyramid and so with
this you can track its different steps
that these broad scripts can can be part
of the detection part actually tracking
adversary activity you could use bro for
hunting with some of these SMB logs so
it's literally the bro detecting in this
case the attacker bro because hey we all
like to name attackers
and that's the end of my talk I'll put
the slides out on my blog security never
sleeps net um and the scripts are in
this location so i want to take a
screenshot you could take a screenshot
of that and you have any questions find
me here on and my twitter handle is RR
Cyrus thank you