you're such an asshole
and so consulting from Vegas I should
have said that the LLC I'm gonna do work
all right never mind that has nothing to
do with it McCamey as a consulting com
America's older brother the world's only
professional asshole come here if you
have questions and you act is the
difference see when you ask your in your
guidance counselor's and your parents
your liberal Democrat no politicians you
when you ask them questions you don't
really want the truth you want them to
tell you what feels good you don't like
Steve Harvey and Oprah you girls almost
no wonder well where's the truth which
really true will set you free
wait a minute because you're a fat sow
lose weight what may be more hurtful but
it is also much more productive that's
what we specialize here at Nestle
consulting dr. Khan dear Erin I'm a
recent engineering grad I just got an
offer for an engineering position the
offer is $40,000 significantly below it
most engineers start out at for the same
position 60 to 65 Kaos of living is
above average on the other hand I will
happen to take this offer as I know it
would be a lot easier more pleasant to
network work on my presentation
interviewing skills look for a job while
living on my own NC then living in my
hometown with my parents also I can make
new friends fuck bitches and date nice
girl oh you young boys think it's just
the simple is going to Walmart now the
other hand I just don't know if thinking
this off of me shooting myself in the
foot they gave me a week to decide
salary is non-negotiable I know in
engineering employers look at your track
record and think why did the why did
this guy work two thirds of what people
usually make and question whether I am a
capable engineer also the salary is on
par with that of a technician while the
job description sounds good I have been
in a situation where a company has was
advertising an engineering position but
then during the interview the
interviewer called in an engineering
tech yeah
welcome to corporate America they they
look when corporate America hires from
colleges looking at your resume and GPA
and degrees Maryland
Melanie what they really do you don't
know they're doing this at colleges and
universities they're taking 3d images of
your asshole
when you sit in the chairs and then they
send these rendered 3d images of all the
students assholes
so that corporate employers can look to
see how they can fuck them in those
assholes and that's how colleges really
you didn't know about the butt scanning
3d technology existed many years ago
trust your old brother Cappy here is all
for deaths death sentence if you're in
the position for a year or longer it
would be much harder to walk out of a
job when I am bound to an apartment
lease finally if an employer isn't
willing to pay a veneer median mean
starting salary for a position what
makes you think there will be a good a
fair employer or their employees will be
quality no the technician position I
mentioned above the interviewer was very
condescending about engineering school
in my experience I would fuck her or him
and another interview for an internship
that turned out to be unpaid when I got
there all yeah then you quit you walk
the interview the whole time was playing
candy crush on his phone dude these
these are signs of dating shit mobile
employers you know anything to do with
this like a girl talking on phone on a
date thank you I see yeah that's I'm
afraid of porn I on a good reference
retrieve you with respect if they aren't
willing to pay me what I'm worth I have
heard horror stories of abusive
employers to be a former employees bad
references to keep them from moving out
of the job yeah I should also add that
my resume isn't terrible they could send
you a copy don't need it on most weeks I
get multiple interviews a week there you
go all right so the fish are biting
that's fine you're doing good
I've been going to my interviews and
plan to take advantage of my Career
Center by doing multiple mock interviews
a week good should I take this position
if so should I stick with the company
and hope for raises or should I be on
the lookout for better opportunities if
I should stick with this company how
long should it be before you so I'm
gonna get to it I'm gonna get to it no
no and do you think this position is a
thinly veiled technician position
looking for an educated text yeah I
think do it do not take this job do not
take this job for multiple reasons one
that this disrespectful behavior of the
interviewer I'm going to gather that the
interviewer was not an engineer
and therefore what they probably said
find somebody with these qualification
weren't too busy so that's also an
indication that the management or your
supervisor the hiring manager of the
person who to be working and answering
to he or she didn't have any interest in
putting together their own team so
that's piss-poor management right there
and but above all else look the one
thing I like about the Millennials
except you don't have this trailer
quality you have all the other qualities
of trace we wish you guys had is that
they're lazy and you really have to pay
them what they're worth of ice no I'm
gonna living home with my parents and
that's exactly what you should do you
aren't one of the biggest mistakes I did
was taking a job out of college cuz it
was a job and it was they live in it in
the title they live in the description
of the job and like you and I ended up
in the piss-poor position of having the
lease that I couldn't you know I had to
stick with these assholes and they know
I hate about I mean it was it was
bullshit this is a bullshit job I could
do it in the fifth grade that's a simple
it was it was clerical uh but no you
don't know forty thousand no you fuck
you pay me that says how simple it is
fuck you pay me and what I never
understood on older generations
including my own because they're always
like we should get paid more we deserve
it all with the corporation up you you
can say no you can say fuck you know and
the unemployment rate is under I think
it's under five five percent into the
force it's a tight labor market for
those participating in it and you have
an engineering background and you're
getting multiple interviews fuck didn't
know well you're like oh it's the only
vagina that's offered herself to me so
far and she's bad and I think I see some
boils around there I don't know
it's a job have some self-respect say
fuck you no well don't say that but
don't even call them back if they're
playing candy crush and this whole thing
you're gonna week to decide fuck you
fuck them and fuck that dude and you're
not gonna go to the big city and and
fuck bitches and get laid all right just
knock that shit off right there hold out
for a better job
keep working get get what you aren't
what it's worth for you it and if it's
in the high cost of living area or 40
grand is nothing your fuck there's no
way I would take that job all right got
your questions your older brother of
America you know you may not be in
America if you're English speaking and
you want the captain give you the advice
that your absentee father never gave you
because your mom divorced them or did
know who you why I think it's Joe or Bob
or Fred but but I love you you're the
most important thing in my life that's
why I made sure there was no father run
if you have a father around you're like
shit I gotta learn this quick well we
can do that at asshole consulting as
long as I can yell and curse at you and
not dick around and try to be nice we
could get to get to the truth very
quickly we can help you kids out all
right let's see you guys like tools
you