Hey I guess we're recording their thing
fantastic the one elbow curvy sides
thank you for coming down you know down
the hallway I need the stairs
thousands dark hallway and finally
turning left into in this room
appreciate you guys coming here my name
is square Tony almost knows you well bad
that's my twitter handle and that's my
blog if you want to read a bunch of bull
Harbison so here to talk about welcome
so you want to get started for anything
huh well first off this Beach you know
disclaimer I left half this is not a
presentation it's all based on my
opinion so that ain't doing people I
used to work for may work for the future
currently work for you know anybody else
make sure I jump down head and don't
know what I'm talking about
heads you have this cute adorable
picture history just keep everyone up in
a wait we're just going to have subdued
Catanese I just pictures those mics my
kiddos because she's a lot cuter
sometimes than cat pictures this
presentation provides key theories and
concepts required to be natural our
friend this is my screen input this is
really the core it if you go back a lot
of recent videos about Cybertron
analysis is out there you're going to
come across some please pretty similar
things right so if you're a brand
spanking new beings are analogies are
breaking the seal thanks for coming and
I hope this kind of helps out to be our
on started for our to do this for a
while Bobo this is this is the bar
lesson for you know so the stuff will
find analytical briefs just my personal
opinions on making our lives easier what
made my life easier I'll throw the over
eight years of doing you know when I
first broke in the very first thing is
in for asking questions like okay for
you to be a cybernetic all right cool
what is that like don't worry about just
sit down with charioteers and open up
your browser gathers Linux is awesome
this is great okay so this is Wireshark
there's a full roll pikas are deuces oh
okay cool for the tournament that was it
the Californa to us
that's a weird protocol man I don't want
to tell it it should figure out though
yes with first day on the job right
that's our guy I'm you pat by name is
your report but what the preposition oh
yeah it's really weird I don't look good
at all figure out what it is
mehar we do that on Google all right
hold it oh and it's kind of how it is
continents are forever
honestly bumpkin is was enticing a lot
of this I really didn't I got really
lucky and I got to work there were these
things called
theory topics gives us blocking or
guilty at that point get ec-council
phases of the task and the next talk
about that and it was really awesome as
they have to learn off from kinda like I
can tear down the guys from one guy's
room design model trans Alice's so I got
to learn about that before it was even
published on the outside so I got really
blessed luck it was really interesting
that was at that time they were still
working a lot about to it doesn't
there's been a lot of changes the time
is running out Lonnie's periods of
actually been worked out and kind of
massaged down but looking back be out
eight years later you know fern Mallis
that's kind of was it like I yeah
Wireshark and yeah look at that Jordan
over there have fun
hence the presentation so I do it again
just largest sum we sat down and talking
about and listen no figure out your
environment not like it secure instance
sure that secure yourself can figure it
out every little wolf figure out what
your environment communicated organize
yourself like a business
intelligence higher up whatever think
about it like a business or producing to
take a risk analysis model in stick with
choose your own attack business it does
not matter which is happy to adhere to
just the fact that you understand how
that works
now you can incorporate mitigation
understanding a lot of people like I
have a short back no no why are you
quitting meditation
what does that actually do for you our
organization how do I communicate that
up is all important things good even
mind the only heart once taken to talk
if your brain space engine I hope that
you'll be googling as you walk out here
of your design of knowledge fruit
analysis please not a model of
encouraging us you don't know what that
is that's okay
but anyways you've been doing for long
time so it'll it is it's okay it's just
going to be it's so used you know it's
like doing math on with over the hand
with on key to the paper if you will and
suddenly realize it as a calculator
around the fear of pain we're going to
talk about that and how to actually
latest our analysis and yet if we have
time where I talk about you know trying
to be trying to avoid being Alice's
one-line rundown weird radical mostly
possible some tips that that's going to
work for me may not work for you but
this work for me in the past when I've
managed a lot a lot of other side for an
elephant right I should say how to
sports talking and play matchmaker
without the jury team and finally
recommended courses certification
reading and only the inspector bringing
in so the time to respond this is the
problem right now
there's no in his infancy but we already
right now eight years but no one really
has it because it's all breathless I'm
trying to know is don't say hey by also
going to do you know analysis so
sometimes work as a top as a second-tier
backing up top sometimes you'll get
intelligence work sometimes will do any
exaggeration reform sometimes your work
for CTO some kind of you'll just be
sitting there you know hating yourself
writing short signatures all day long
you know but it's because the industry
still hasn't defined it yet
but that's okay these things these
concepts barely applicable to whatever
you whatever kind of job you actually
run into I played it tied it on the
factors there's not a lot of formal
training out there and the trades my
clients aren't really there yes copy it
just released their CSA that might be
promising I don't know I'm not I'm not
fit to the confuse that is a plus but it
holds all promises it's in between cap
and security clocks is kind of where in
a lot of respects
you are right you're you're still done
very technical but you still have to
explain things to men to a manager who
might have that have their stands for
four or five seven eight it's written
because God actually retired over there
not being in certification for cyber
analysis however obviously I don't have
five thousand dollars it you to that's
also said that's a lot of money to get
them in breaking this field really is
McAfee has these two certification CPI
and PPI see that our grants making new
as well when I'm looking through a lot
of details on those they're they're all
one person page
let's just find if you do law
enforcement but my humble opinion of
eight years of doing this I can't think
of single time right you had to deal
with a bunch of crazy law enforcement
forensic tools that's why we have
frensky but still good thing is giving
to formalise
tree university car courses I've looked
into this I haven't found a really good
University course of action cost of
office so in other words and honestly
I've gotten more people with bachelor's
degree that I go to interview I can't
hire in earth either they have super
super master's degrees or what have you
five years if they don't have the
experience and honestly when I hire
people at masters degree master's degree
for optics master's degrees I see the
computer and afters having exactly power
stage of a pathless
a brand-spanking-new versus one-year
advantage felt like myself illa get is
no prison here not the same there's not
really anything above the literature is
kind of sparse they broke down to
basically three different styles one is
the cyber warfare models those are guys
these mountains even the if you will
talk about more fair did you have the
BOSU extra body intelligence and has a
very intelligent way of doing things you
do have insurance if you're like these
are reading the face insurance is kind
of mid-foot up the stage but in
sometimes you'll find the hips and
pieces in the clothes that are out there
for instance contingent on obstacle we
think about first engineering grab the
alien autopsy book if you don't know Fox
on this Google malware analysis and look
for something with my mailing off copy
yes they have one chapter in there and
it's it's okay if you get your sharp if
you know can never done infrastructure
analysis that's okay it'll kind of it's
just it started you know done malware
searching it will try to get started for
this one chapter in one book it's really
sparse but we're going the Rams all
right according to the efficient of
Bureau of Labor Statistics were eighteen
percent growth that's ten percent more
than the average across the board that
is six points above I seen Jenner and
the median income is ninety K let's rock
the world United Ava's in this job in
here I'm saying it doesn't require too
greedy effective I'm living proof of
that there's hope out there though
and we're going off in the dirty tools
sometimes they help I honestly do they
really do help and they look pretty
imagine love keep you met thank you
Oh Adam Littleton sense fiber happy in
the world
but if I am for which endeavors a lot
lots of my people's people are hurting
for a second and upgraded Cisco's
lifeless specific man been outdated for
years pay for that provides the non
ultra so fart right now house has been
energy is helmets that were producing
isn't going away and coming more and
more valuable
I'll show you exist to it further appeal
remember there's not a whole lot out
there weekend if you come into this
field and you start doing great things
and you find out a way forward
there you go then you can even be Isaac
Newton you can have those series with
law so the things that actually work in
function and every little problem
because DC and generally make sure you
help what we try to have to be right we
love to share one of the guys that I
said I know let's call him sorry Jesus
oh just knows way too many people and
you know interesting items like notice
that is already a church Sharia and it
says trial electing a doctor in the
early nineteen hundred's kind of arrest
where you're going to learn something
and then you have to kind of ask them
lead that place you go somewhere else to
learn something this and then you seem
like a rock drop five seconds minutes or
not like this is this other guy's work
you told me how to do and change how he
hashes Homefront Thatcher and more for
than anything there's actually several
key
series out there and what's suspecting
the world
California guy so I love things that
actually work as they do which is why we
use them all right so there's a lot of
definitions out there against inches of
tissue is talk all right we're going to
say cyber threat analyst is someone's
gathered data and information
everything is the note knows of an
organization or entity provide
situational awareness of any given
threat citrus where is some unfilled
intelligence or specifically you can
call it a starter analysis or a centrist
intelligence all right in my honest
opinion on this and actually a lot of
people quite like I'm over this kind of
stuff and keep it simple keep it as
simple as possible those old things the
first step who the heck are you alright
this is a tortoise Five Forces model is
actually originally done for business
it's for determining probability of the
company but if you keep positive out was
this is actually really really great
apply to yourself think about it for a
couple minutes who actually is getting
yourself where you're buying to consume
what you're putting up for the guys over
the top or kind of doing a very similar
mission to you who are the new insurance
that are just popping up all of the
dainties did someone just tell your CTO
they have a medical solution and if you
just put in an AI often this you can
replace all these fires it can tell the
body or Alice over here times up so
happens you have to know freeze I can
supply you with data apply to yourself
and then apply it to your orders a
Trinity okay I thought what important to
your organization your business alright
so I reckon again you know I'm just work
for me ah
business model why aren't I doing that
right well knowing who your suppliers
are the sure you keep those data so you
don't have to control the little blog or
whatever angel who talked to is the odd
got your America if your manager or not
knowing who also had great summer
missions keeps you in the good swim lane
misunderstanding strategies happening I
will say not even seeing a lot of work
because their phone pink out for you
this why are you so teacup and that's
not doing it was also important to
recognize this organization is listen
your innovation is probably connected to
a lot of other companies that are what
it is true because about your yogi or
CIC is you're actually in working for a
customer for government if you will for
a commercial sector look at you know
you're going to have a supply chain fall
try to need to know who that is
because you shall be sharing in front of
houses with them ostriches you might
actually see the target even though they
hit you know you may pop those we're
protecting something and you produced
those little awesome rocket pops right
the Turner your lip balms right you
threaten their princess and you hear
about those first two ends makes little
stick and first lady stateside pack by
cyberattack that's not you're talking
right I don't need data do because the
real target actually
be sure to front Elvis with that person
because you rely on that first s it's
kind of how it all goes and perhaps just
let this right okay all right so
thinking work like a business all right
a lot of people are kind of going over
this in the area I think about my
intelligence trying to apply and he'll
respond to my suggestions we're going to
look at this slide put your Purdue
system business models that are on for
very very long time okay people if
they're doing so organize yourself into
business okay you're in ologist a
federalist little data feed you're
actually looking at whether external or
internal right are you actually getting
those are you actually evaluating those
those are all the about logistics on out
operations that you do this to the grunt
work the front that everyone gets
excited out if your attorney if you will
looking into something though going down
those radicals look that's what on the
equal playing field is your outbound
logistics how are you actually seeing it
out do you have a method of doing that
what's your splits your your process of
doing that it's actually really super
crazy important it really is any other
marketing and sales are you actually
communicating your information the way
you put it out with someone's can
actually understand it services is
almost question to get from management
all in wait you incorporate those it is
I mean honestly if your service model is
you know box tells other box and then
it's slowly trickle down and your boss
wants something at CNN and so they don't
worry about a threat
that's not a good that that is be
cleaned up right so identifying like
this breaking apart and making it an
equal playing field but all the days are
if you want to get on an externally and
internally is important dropping
treatable all equally maybe you'll
actually spend more money on that puking
map because you know that's going to
give you more funding with that year or
maybe that's actually hire your CTO
really want to see reason he does let's
see he or she is fun to see those little
missiles from Russia and hitting you
over there but he came
that's okay it also graphically depicts
alter card project processes so when you
have to go to tell somebody hey the
reason the reason why I meet fire soul
intelligence is because you just squat
all these incoming data feeds that's
great at all this other section called
operation that's my virus code I don't
have anything at all going into some
support business operations somehow I
need a tool for this and I schools given
me marshal intelligence or you know two
main tools or any number of other things
you can actually get okay and talking to
your leaders like that saying listen
reason why I need this data feed and
uses this data because these are
suppliers and this applies importance
start talking on suppliers start talking
to them on how that's your involvement
istic now you're talking usually in the
whole business realm right most of
people who are above a kind of business
tree it enables you to actually talk and
message actually understand what's the
cracker saying so with a lot of risk and
else models out there they're huge books
and volumes
you can go nuts with it I don't know if
the program you had or are a lecture to
look back I like are yeah this is RMS
gonna be really easy and I looked into
it up like this is oh my god so
complicated so I you know around all the
time when I was in a former life but I
started thinking about it I don't do it
I actually use this little risk rating
going to have here which is likelihood
of effective detecting it hardest to
actually impact somebody is the
miserable set my organization actions
are starting very very simple you can do
this you can choose your own doesn't
matter because the reality situation
into she's talking about phishing email
campaign or the next you know Russian in
torch I knees at if you're not extra
bodies that quantitative we show how we
got there that rinse with all the
potential steps of mitigation aligns
when you push that information up pure
diffusion has
pure traditional fun they're going to
understand what have to say so you know
think about if your sole job is actually
trying to provide information those
people to actually do changes write an
Astra system to find an instructor to
eat or updates finally that Cisco pitch
you need to be able to tell them why and
that's where you get into risk that's
where you actually talked off steps to
MnDOT choose your own attack description
it doesn't matter and it's not a
one-to-one internal key concept what you
need to know about it as I refer analyst
is really that this is your map in
relative time of where data information
could be octave chain and evaluate I'm
trying to accomplish right let's let's
do you like this you're not going to
talk to welcome to patient that's a
ricotta no parcel right if you see that
your to your a triage hacker is actually
implementing and submitting stuff over
in the virus code or something similar
to it yeah you should probably look
English in the top that's going to save
you in a countdown to organization that
person's building something for you the
delivery side you know that the reality
is you're not going to look into a
firewall long for command control
communications not exactly really right
it may be five seconds of space there
might just will show up as just a
connection you actually really need that
full T cap to be able to find out what
is actually going on so this is the way
these kind of parts things up
so if you wanna learn more about
blocking marginal chain and me counsels
on you know make your CH the whole
transformation council walking article
chase free runs down the right car how
do I find you actually get out of here
the question that I love are tons of
people who are regular trippy
how are you sucking in all the data and
really getting it because it's just too
much is going on worldwide when it comes
to pleasure as are you and your team
life and I'll take you they thinking
that revisiting big verdict and what
were you
how are you giving up that workload so
that it's not too long so honestly my
thoughts on that and once that's in
coming with justice everyone's is being
tracked honestly you look at it and you
don't care about its instruction or
targeted present of it that's not being
evil right yeah I can't be like oh well
Chinese are heading out so we should
care all Russians are our fee don't care
about them so when I start prioritizing
I really do look at the rich and I look
at what is actually occurring piece of
malware comes out and I have mitigation
already in place that I know will stop
that and no I'm not going to imaginable
upon premarital course and for a lot of
the things a lot of you can actually
automate right if you company in does
that help enter your questions a little
bit I mean has you would you have an
info very there is a commission to
Russia
you didn't know what we're really going
to affect you know Irish it I talked
about it afterwards I just want to make
it there this to the ha ha ha ha
all right Donna modeled intrusion
analysis listen this is X as a
foundation of doing Cyrus going out if
you've never heard of this that's okay
chances are this actually applies to
what you're doing anyway
a lot of times if you know if you see
actual phishing emails and you see it
tomato what have you waiting edges
you're gonna look it up but why are you
looking it up what do you trying to get
from there and chances are you're trying
to my is Halloween whatever eat some
Albert associated with it and the night
of my life he formed it up international
or formal whole diamond I didn't want
the done here just because I'm here and
but you looking at you for the game
ability right it breaks it down alright
if you think about back over your slides
right you have your products you have
weapons they should get all these little
phases of the regular attack but the
reality of is every single one of these
phases actually has little diamonds
you're always going to have attackers
you're only going to have the
infrastructures we're using you're going
to advocate the builders are start it's
actually just as well to keep spilling
this malware what happens you're always
going to have a victim and it must
change every and every single phase of
that dungeon so it does gets more
complicated as you go to the world
what's really great about Cyril although
is a help you put into focus all the
different pictures right and it puts
yourself into folks I'm looking for
infrastructure and Kingsville and I'm
looking for capability that was you once
they're actually inside them
let's go after doing demand control this
is it helps you organize those different
phases attacks into something that's a
little tiny EVP and it also lets you
expand up so if you find that they use a
particular piece of malware once to
actually get inside of a Windows
environment right you can expand that
out and you have to see other other
victims that are actually stopping the
exact context which is infrastructure
they're using in your attack as well as
the old infrastructure they're using the
elderly you have to try and get more
credits that's how to get down to
radicals we got to start digging into
things but it teaches safe because the
moment you go from researching
infrastructure on one tiny phase of
attack to jumping all over the place
into the capabilities in the Mallards
all that s plus your release focus of
what you were looking for in the very
beginning that's my my I covered a
little later that's actually one biggest
pH state ways of dynamo you keep just
saying you see us doing his bigger names
right away it also lends itself really
really both other concepts if you have
not read them unfold right up on the
thermal analysis completely free and
download it if you really want to ask
questions I know he's probably got a
teeny cutting no I'm - greasing but you
can actually reach out some people
actually wrote this on Twitter and I
know the guy not sure if you remember me
at all but he's a really really nice guy
and he actually has a bunch of questions
and I'll just go so small dome junior
all right so mitigation and defense in
depth so defense in depth is based on
three different things your people for
technology and operation operation
meaning the processes you're actually
doing technology being technology and
the actual people and they say is an
industry standard best practice you
should actually have your mitigation
coming through to the defensive desk
doesn't actually mean up right it means
that you actually have to when you're
reporting the information out you can
just say Ohio sources your fun that's
not enough that's not fair you actually
have to talk about the people develop in
the operation and provide mitigation for
all of those lucky there are models out
there that kind of help you organize
your thoughts right one of those is
actually the Lockheed Martin start a
threat matrix that actually has five the
five g's and really what to do but the
reality is that you can always you know
let's say um what kind of fishing boat
ability out there right de 2012 to run
fighting there's a mess boy launch
module in there right so anybody hit
your mother can actually fill this
videos on how to actually build a
phishing email using DVD joint so the
two are closest well your little pocket
write letter relies on ActiveX actually
running on your Windows machine over the
guy gets master phishing email each
little ActiveX you know warning we got
clicked on it and building homes right
well you know that warning is tough on
all right you can have a cop you can
actually have different policies where
you have to strip out attachments on
your emo yes that is you know same as
unplugging from the internet but you
have to be able to talk to people and
say listen you know we can actually stop
this all these different phases of an
attack we can stop this with technology
we can actually stop this by policy that
actually
implements and affects the operations
right but overall what all people right
that's a whole other how to actually
mitigate the people maybe that say you
know malware or malicious files
ActionScript passion to look the acting
licensed teachers actually malware's all
better of your technology but how you
got to get to the people which brings us
to the secure page if you've ever heard
it the show relationship between the
types of indicators you might use in
basically how your actual affect users
feel it's really funny this is a little
talk about a lot lunch to tell the story
meaning I can throw in something to stop
- by using an item like block IP
addresses into making all they won't
never going to network in a host-based
artifact there are tools out there
telling right the actual tools that
they're using the cop device tool it'll
be generic or not you build rules for
those right well the very pop is TCP get
to those PPP people right most people so
yes it's tough on the adversary when you
get to change this ETP but you know tell
me a good way to stop them from clicking
on that link sentiment efficient even
that's a really hard thing to do alright
so the double-edged sword you need to
understand that as you're presenting all
of your other mitigation ok and honestly
if you ever want to see any indicators
or compromise you hear that term you
will hear that term if you're Cyrus or
an analyst throw it out everywhere the
vast majority of those will really be
sometimes talking about tools
most of those are activity your network
is no space artifacts and you know you
love us chucking around a lot some
domain names and IP address that gets
tucked around
so here here the term IOC labrats gone
and this is actually honestly how you
should evaluate and maybe crops how you
should wait getting those data feeds all
that intention so desperate for summer
alright so GPA of our data and
information from cyber intrusions a K
could be changed
alright that's multiple attacks going on
with a focus on rows change from similar
you a third or could attack their
organization the attacks can be going
down just to there things great each
base at least ones Dynamo composes or
constants and after a victim an
infrastructure when he came through
they're running in DJ well they know
their environment relatively and in our
current mitigation armed with that
knowledge the next provide situational
awareness intelligence that situational
awareness and intelligence if you will
chillin rich based off of a quantitative
risk higher lower the actual threat to
an organization motivation should be
homeless next issued encompass those
wonderful people technology and
operations and if you really want to my
humble opinion and something that might
be really useful to you is break them
down even further into network when you
do after the host base going to use an
organizational policy break it into om
om meeting someone active cashing their
system but it also means the actual
security additional running instance
acting hardness in the first place and
lastly horse trading and awareness to
your users is at top tier of the ear
pain and also always keep in mind that
fact that they do live that beer
toothpaste and know for a fact that a
lot of these will be either
bypass or bypass that certain luck
whether it's going to be really easy
like a cloth or a tea a dress that five
half or if you're actually going to try
and keep on pinning on that really hard
into his top tier which is
Portia's a user clicking edit on student
work and we definitely have time so now
we're going to cover the five operation
in morning GL one web stock and
recommended courses to tips on
collaboration ISM honestly step
timeliness devil operation fees for
hours
Michael moving don't touch it on there
if you're looking into one each one
indicator once you teach that diamond
and it starting to grab information on
that on a piece of malware and you hit
the for you or our lock without finding
anything new top I think people going
week looking into one piece of malware
and they have the entire life story they
got the entire story the first day our
dress the times are just like looking it
is a little like will be the secret Bob
to Britain Russia somewhere
this guy actually was talking about it
laughs go on down the route of all so
set kind of otherwise you will go but in
letter who talks about it Automation is
no substitute for talking with your call
and all right yes you did get that
report in automated fashion fantastic
but if you're actually reach across them
talking on in that report appetize
especially in certain areas you know
you'll type up for report and it will go
out you're looking reporting that stuff
that's missing a lot of context so
talking with the actual analytics near
that report will be able to tell you so
much geyser is easy as a phone call oral
or omission say or email sometimes
because as a Twitter account conditional
right sandy check your findings always
I've seen again there's a certain
detective noise used for blackjack sure
until 20 of us drive malware will take
over my GPS to be bottom mmm on do it
I've seen guys eliminated talking about
that oh my goodness I got it all the
Indians are involved and these
ransomware got your balls and the
journeys are involved up and over
involved and the people is oh my god
it's all connected
no not at all that's not how that works
but sometimes it is really hard for me
with little injury soft enough you gotta
have some kind of manager cause he
lighted at the domina
when he interacted possibly building
something lazy to something up so if one
of Donald's fault or you pull then all
your three does go down the poop so I'm
going to come around in a few fact check
it I'm sorry is report looking to what
indicator to time and one second is I'm
I'm always take lots of notes is to just
kind of still important always make sure
you actually include your links because
sometimes when you change the reddit so
don't leave without ever you like reason
fine this connection the answer we do
all your analysis and ask questions even
Saddam ones in mansions price and of
course housemates even messenger so
despite that little find them miss for
instance alright so the router process
person took the fences make good
neighbors and the reality is is it does
but that pole is actually talking about
two people coming together and talking
about the sentence that's the reality
and talk to your other top your saw
camera topic after doing the data piece
top of people that are outside of that
bubble we already kind of define girls
are all talk to find out how they can
actually talk I import men's the wall to
make sure you're actually packing
nation-building swivelling are able to
talk back and forth it's as simple as
that really is well I should say it as
simple to saying it and then as a
difficult is actually dealing with some
you know people which could be really
difficult and with that don't talk and
anything honestly sometimes meta is not
your best friend only dependent it
really does I'd rather talk to nail at
any date a week over in a shop before
actually talking to a middle manager
because you get fight them in stood up
really quickly and you should be kind of
aware that my question
my suggestion honestly is talking with
me we're just trying to do this your job
who are usually experts over in polarity
it find out honestly what actually helps
them do their job you ever ever again
you're not only the only consumer right
you're pretty good intelligence right
how are the people who thought actually
using it you know I heard very clearly
someone's going okay you keep on says
over and coz you realize we just let's
just pay the button I got third in Excel
and Joanie's bangs and ah it's really is
going are you deciding to CSV now that
nobody got it was you don't want that
because we actually have it all working
onyx Excel we can't print the PSP or you
like that stupid don't ever do that same
thing was like a six hack isn't right
sometimes it's such an extra what self
red sheet is so much better and instead
of attacking server just automatically
send this is you know humanly possible
but sometimes it's just useful as once a
day just shot me an email through Excel
spreadsheet on it I'm a happy camper
compass and again it's hard of those
reviews recommended reading there's a
lot of books objects
listen you can read into those ones that
are more your focus your regular ones
that are intelligent Oaks you read the
ones god help me where this room can
read an RFC and a miss publication all
that stuff is like this is amazing shoes
are amazing some beats
not me all right so I after having all
these other recommended schools to any
study hey read this both reasons manual
and you're gonna share so I'll suffice
to say listen these are things kind of
need to know one that everybody knows or
should know which the change management
intrusion analysis one of those is don't
trust a faculty didn't it yourself back
honestly the best piece of advice I've
ever heard don't drop the packet you
didn't build your stuff we're all tp'ed
carry let's take this is really
important I think this implements what I
watch you watch we know this is minutes
before the 81 report everyone always
trying to point towards abc1 like oh my
god is this bill great they're not these
guys are actually putting out a little
bit earlier not that much on the fact of
the crazy office this man you never read
the state what I highly encourage you
it's a command control system 'i
seriously read it it was done I think is
done action fund 11 and honestly I have
yet to come across the bubble right up
period any rights to the 26 pages your
blog posts that do this like all the
like fires they're aging are pens really
attack on the time you place this pages
pages of article that's like to cited so
there's like four columns there is a
little teeny tiny print so you want to
pop their laptop significant zoom
vintage gold monkey and of course the
one that kind of everyone forgets about
which is a CJ CSM 5500 r65 10.10 one
problem this is actually how the
military's arm isn't in why is it really
important military personal reasons one
military always tries to make it as easy
and it's dislikingly possible someone to
reach right this is easy to digest for
the most part may does illustrate engine
but you know you still read it you so
find out what's going up it also lays
out a lot of the interesante if you have
no ideas come from
how thrilling it to send any kind of
file you don't know how to stock active
runs read the CJC ISM 65 has been in a
lot of stock has caught a lot of folks
and now I've got truth is they hold do
the exact same way to another place
without my thing what we do it this way
here here I guess then we're also doing
it so this will actually show up good
solitaire honestly you're breaking in my
shipping I just want to share well I've
worked on that and hosts at site so
we're not a large web host
so by April or June that won't leave out
everyone on ously if your indulgence
google video is done 5510 will that's
why I didn't like using the problem oh
this is it
aagghh one overarching capability but
you may or may not actually have and you
should really a - question ask yourself
this question are you curious and
honestly are you tenacious this this job
is naughty it's up it's a lot of
reporting a lot of people say oh like it
over a semi-truck the more your toaster
the more you automate the further you
are actions on country on the truth of
lapel action happens
Julie relied on an asteroid fired my
best discoveries have always come from
actually just looking into a big guys
185 LP cap and just scroll it's finding
out connection miscommunication I found
more self that way and with a neighbor
bender
alright starts right this is what all
the guys who kind of coffee turns
relentless is the art of taking one
metal needle and finding a match in a
haystack so let me go for inside of the
wall by a giant warehouse full paint
back bowls very similar-looking metal
needles and then
you know finding out that your arcade
o´clock giant warehouses that also has
giant space actual net legal domination
might issue to each ain't that faster it
might get you in plenary session it's
like kind of dive into that base I
faster but it's no replacement for B cos
on us
brute force annoyance that you're
actually going end up having to do as a
cyber try to Adam if that's where your
noodle otherwise you're going to be
really disappointed and really intuition
with work somewhere else if you want to
try to break in you have that about you
honestly what my suggestion in certain
countries and that's that's in kind of
thing but the reality is we're in we're
close to DT alright that's why I'm
actually saying that right there's a lot
of DC organizations that are a feature
this this major art if you will you can
probably define the job there if you
look at LinkedIn each archiving time
turn analyst you're gonna find Squatch
on job openings out there but Sun and
just roll over supporting us all right
the most part sober banks the remember
them and always try breaking knowledge
you don't go and listen I strongly
advise if you go and listed here's your
baby Jesus go and listed so if you
actually want to be technical in any way
shape or usually officers try to do that
and they leave realize by the Condor Oh
three they never be technical everything
there's a lot of internships you know a
lot of things happening directly in the
DMV area Cristina be area you're very
blessed we have three b-sides and one
shoe counts that are in this area is
easy driving people
this is Mecca for Cybertron analysis in
my humble opinion not off there in
Washington it's not out there in San
Francisco done in Texas actually in this
area because there are so many people
doing this job we have so many
opportunities you have no records you
want me there a very to actually
communicating top back and forth and
actually pick up the day and following
and call somebody there's been a couple
guys who I've never met
outside of email who came in and they're
like oh yeah I'm sorry Tony hey man
let's park okay say to you is only talk
to email back and forth sharing
information it's kind of crazy
I strongly advise users you're not from
this area you're a lot of right into
this job you need to what relocate might
have to do that
how does we might have to do them there
just so many options on here and the
reason why I'm up here today talking to
you is because I would that DC the DTV
side and twice the schema or my bosses I
wasn't on the front row got pretty close
and ever there were less people for that
brief is missile city actually they're
probably more over here because that guy
is real smart and tourism li don't talk
I don't talk so good he watches YouTube
video right here joining the intersect
community around here brief come out
here and volunteer for be size talk to
people joining what a hacking groups
there's all kinds of ways actually break
into its are talking until tomorrow and
and again GPA says we're all enough shit
you really are because we're all trying
to do try to figure it out again all
right and it's 948 so question okay it
talked about the you're at night I've
worked that's how it goes like so what's
really great is if we marry EPA my
content is my pocket generally it's not
a not on walk Joe you were never on call
maybe is what I'll say that century but
sometimes yes sometimes no it all
depends on which all person you're not
just throw it off though you but about
the csa plus I did a beta on that but
it's definitely aimed at style it's more
something spread as well no there there
was no that's okay you know what that's
books I've read recently is actually a
comic book written by Rob Lee I highly
advise to serious bitch awesome
it's called a cyber intelligence and me
and is actually a book for kids and for
Arthur Achilles and we look crazy happen
around America's most like you really
awfully good you know management can get
angry when they agree that they
recognize excelled as a person's being
based on some careful but honestly that
my wife for instance didn't know
anything I'm like this is great
and I'm a kid is kind of close to Gotham
and edgy I could factor in right except
this is what you do is now all your
complaints make sense this is awesome so
I leave I just like 10 box I hope that
he that I don't know him personally but
it may be a big nothing else will
promote healing but honestly that's a
really great book he loved it
that's amazing cyber threats
intelligence and you I think you're
president you know ginger Envy thank you
I titled our children in an area
yeah what would in your career what job
function and rolling have you found very
good for helping the melody of what a
photographer at needle it's somebody
that wants to move into that role be
successful
are there any other skill set that you
found especially valuing this the threat
analyst you worked with so I think kind
of come from two different three or four
different a three different types in
Campinas
what is it 5th Avenue types who you have
to sometimes prove that they mess up a
big big bottle that's cool that's okay
you have a strong understanding of that
even though networks honestly no less
accurate you know how for cults were
doing home so you could actually take on
America
awesome okay you can think on the guys
who just ontology complicit a lot of
politics up the lowest those the guys
that can read it this location cut
exactly was how to change them if only
his worth in Linux bring this this
environment talk about how windows
colossal I know you do this is crazy
how are you I'm back home and some of
those speeding car businesses up the god
truth is I
guys have women especially actually from
the limit actually cutter Sopranos
plus it also has a your curiosity and
your tenacity to Google into research
and that's something I know it doesn't
set up as a plus of an answer man I'm
sorry
that's takanakuy on you true you can
take away and with no experience I think
I had no experience Lillian kid just
went to my class man like that and give
you the second jet say they have a min
you check out this ruler for me and
probably 80 teeth right after it's like
the huge organization and no one even
you know when you produce is work if
people say exactly it'd be possible
and he's like no seriously what my work
is like oh my god so it that's what I'm
saying about this is because a lot of
these fingers still being figured out
those are chances the policies at Burpee
here the theory behind laws and multi
connected connect on I'm holding this
kind of help for these helps you get
started on that as well if you're really
curious about things you can go really
really long and really can decide your
resistance close your home I can't do
that because it hadn't all go through
freedom so I can pop this on backwards
but I'm always a
all right cool well you play again
acting while that car exactly you can
also read my creative shenanigans on cue
ball my calm please forgive me for not
posting all that much coming up really
shares our PowerPoint IDs that they so
may like to be fun show them this one
should probably show me turns out like
nothing Ailey to be on the website or
less you talk about on Twitter and I'll
kind of go jump on Shack which I live
share but we are recording right they
still so you should yell just hold it
oh yes I will call just cheer thank you
ocean they should go to be died
[Applause]