[Music]
all right welcome back everybody our
next speaker is an artist and
roboticists based out of Las Vegas
Nevada who creates machines and
wearables with the intention of
reframing the way that people relate to
technology to that end iteration is a
huge part of their practice so they
document and share all of their builds
on their tech blog and on YouTube this
speaker believes that hardware creators
have the power to reshape the world with
their creations and they hope to
encourage others to create the things
that they want to see please welcome to
the hackaday super conference stage
Sarah pekus
[Applause]
can I take this microphone with me yeah
cool hi guys um so first and foremost
before I get started I want to thank
supply frame in hackaday for having me
back for the fourth year in a row to
talk about my stuff I mean I haven't
totally geeked to be here I'm talking
about something new this year but anyhow
my name is Sara Pettis um like the intro
is great I don't really have to say
anything more than that really but I'm
gonna most of the things that I create
the the robots or the the mechanisms
that I produce are based on my own drawn
content and let's see they're based on
my own drawn content and I realized over
a period of time that everything that I
create um is a reflection of something
that I'm going through in in my head or
in my life um it's kind of like a coping
mechanism
so I'm everything's highly personal but
I usually don't realize this until like
way after the fact so within like I
don't know the first couple of months of
this year I look back on my work that
I've done in the past and I saw that one
of the things I produced I there's this
project called light play that I made
with my partner mark it's a 100 minute -
you're Delta robots that you can control
with your body and I created this at a
point in time in my life where I felt
really powerless and my response to that
powerless feeling was to make a robot
army and that kind of fixed that and I
felt better about you know that that
powerless feeling when I was about 27 28
I started having all these weird
maternal things happen to me where I
felt like I needed to nurture something
and raise something in my image and kind
of I don't know make a mini version of
myself but I didn't want anyone else to
be involved so I created a robot named
noodle feet who's my robotic offspring
and I've been raising him they for the
past four years and he's a
representation of the very best parts of
myself and that was a reflection of I
guess my maternal instincts kicking in
because I'm an animal and I have those
and nothing I can do about him I guess
this year in my life I started a new
project and it's called Chi bond
our she bone that should be reminiscent
of the French like so good but also
a lady boner so that's that's where the
name comes from
and she Boleyn is a a platform that is
meant to facilitate in sensing and
indicating different aspects of my
arousal and let's see um why I can like
scoot over to that alright why why would
I want to do this I don't I'm not making
a utility so I don't actually think that
humans particularly me I don't think we
need help indicating to one another when
were aroused like I think we've got that
under control we can we can do that but
I did want to start a dialogue about
sexuality and intimacy one that um
helped kind of normalize the whole topic
amongst people cuz um I found that um in
my life while I was growing up I had a
really difficult time coming into my own
as a sexual being it was a really
frustrating isolating embarrassing
confusing struggle that it wasn't like a
small period it's kind of like up until
now really like my whole life has been
this strife and I think that in the
beginning like when I was in the
beginning when I was young
this was due in part to the fact that I
didn't have very many good examples of
adults having healthy dialogues with one
another about sex there is nothing and I
grew up in Las Vegas so in lieu of
having examples that I could draw upon
to kind of fill this void really
horrible things like the the media like
movies and the internet and Vegas filled
this gap and I think it was damaging and
I think a lot of this could have been
alleviated if there was just better
communication so this whole project
isn't it's not meant to solve like
whether or not we can tell each other
were turned on it's meant to get us
talking about who we are as animals in a
way that's relatable
so how let's see and by how I don't I
don't mean getting the discussion going
I mean how am I actually going to sense
ioann arousal that's a really kind of a
tricky thing right um like females or me
like a female thing that I am we don't
have as clear-cut indicators as dudes
right right like everyone knows when a
dude's turned on like even if you can't
visually look like you just you know
right generally so there's there's a
there's things we can we can tap into in
our own bodies that do give tells of
when me I'm gonna talk about myself when
me when I'm entering a aroused or
excited state so I knew that there are
sensors that can help do this right like
there's a lot of things that we can we
can grab at that are affordable that
sense these things
like body temperature heart rate
galvanic response blush response facial
expression muscle tension just to name a
few I'm sure you know and have worked
with sensors that sense all of these
things and I decided to uh to do this I
wanted to create basically a suit of
amour right like a suit of armor like I
wanted to become a yeah I wanted to
become a like a sex Gundam basically but
um yeah yeah I like this um but my armor
is just going to tell you whether I'm
interested in what I would I'm feeling
that's not very robot II but whatever so
in order to do this I knew I'd have to
create different augments that would key
in on what each part of my body tells so
they'd each be they would manifest in a
different way and they'd use different
sensors to kind of get different types
of value from each part of my body and
then cross-reference that that data so
that I could tell if I was actually
excited or if I was getting some other
type of false positive which is I don't
know something that I haven't gotten to
yet I'll be honest but um I know that
that's how it's going to work let's see
so the goal of each of these augments
that I'm creating and I'm gonna say
there's nine total like I picked nine
like discrete parts of my body that I'm
going to create these wearables for and
I decided right at the beginning when I
first
declared that I was doing this project
that they would they'd have two main
primary objectives there's the the input
each augment will sense something from
the part of the body that it's meant to
fasten to all right
whether that's one sensor due to the two
sensors doesn't matter whatever makes
sense and each augment will use that
data to indicate something to the world
so the output additionally and this is
the really fun additional anything
there's there's extra credit if the
indication can stimulate me is a
byproduct and create a feedback loop
then that's good but but that's not the
point it's not meant to be a
masturbation suit it's meant to
communicate it's meant to tell people
what I'm feeling right but I can tell
you with everything that I've kind of
brainstormed this this extra-credit
things big because that's that's the fun
challenge to solve for so I'm going to
talk about the thing that's on my back a
little bit
that's the poles pack this is the
primary brain of the sheep on project
this is the thing that it sends out data
it sends and receives data and it's
going to also log it in the next
iteration so that I can make sense of
the data and decide how it's going to be
used I chose to make it into a backpack
form because it's centrally located on
my body and it's a effectively turns the
circuit board inside of it into a
wearable breakout board and everything
that I make plugs into the the edges of
it as you can see around me and there we
go that's everything I just said
yeah but a most important thing to take
away from it is that it's a wearable
breakout board to visualize it better
this is kind of how it works
Hart and then these are the the nine
different parts of the body that I chose
to key in on like specifically the board
that's inside of it looks like this and
it's called the pulse it's got the
Wiggly astray PSA's ever and if you
haven't done that yet you should you
should which means I think you have to
use Eagle right just know the other one
does it F doesn't matter just do it
so this board it fits inside of the the
heart-shaped enclosure and this is up on
my hackaday IO if like you want a
heart-shaped backpack that doesn't act
as a backpack very well because because
you do you can build one I walk you
through how to do it it's great because
you don't actually have to sew anything
it's all made with 3d printed parts and
I got a a bolt of that's vinyl yep and
there are holes in both that correspond
to one another and I plastic riveted
them together with pieces of raw
filament taken straight off of the 3d
printer spool you kind of thread the
tiny pieces in between the plastic in
the vinyl and then you use your
soldering iron to create a little bead
on either side smash it together with
your fingers because you like pain and
then you you have a backpack I think I
lied the part I did so is um the straps
because that makes sense but I'm pretty
much the entire thing is all 3d printed
in like hardware so there's it's not
really very textile II in that sense and
the finished product looks like this I
used a lot of a lot of pictures of it
just so you can see then let's left
what's on my back to get back to the
board I'm going to talk about that just
briefly a little bit more before I move
on to the the augments and all they're
getting good enos the pulse board has
molex connectors around the outside and
they terminate too like it's not cat v
it's the I forget rj45 is that it yes
that's that that's the socket that it
goes to
around the outside so this is what it
looks like on the inside of the backpack
the I mean there's there's a visual
aesthetic that goes to it I wanted it to
look attractive because it is a wearable
and I do want to kind of help sculpt
what that cyberpunk future is going to
end up actually becoming when we get to
it
because we like speculating about it
right but I think the future is now and
we're already making that stuff right
like everybody in here is producing that
stuff already so I wanted to make sure
that it looked interesting visually so
this was kind of what I was going for
and that's another picture of those
connectors I was telling you about
I'll be honest I don't like how that
turned out so it's probably gonna change
in the next iteration but for now they
look pretty pretty stellar yeah and I'm
just cute
scoot along really quick again this is
on my blog if you want to make it and
then on hackaday IO as well but um the
exciting thing about this project like
the part that's worth talking about or
the individual augments and there's
three that I'm gonna cover I have them
with me
here so after I'm done talking I'll
probably go and demo them in action the
the first one that I ended up making
I'll be honest when I when I decided I
was going to actually go through and
build this project I didn't actually
know what I was going to make yet for my
body it just the concept of it sounded
interesting to me it sounded like a
viable way to like achieve the goal of
you know getting people talking about
sexuality using tech as the catalyst
but um I was laying in bed one morning
when I came up with the idea for the
first one that's like a really weird
just way to start that out and I was
laying in bed one morning but I was I
was waking up and let's see I'll just
switch to that
it's called the beatbox I was laying in
bed one morning and my head actually
said to itself while I was kind of
coming to God I could just really use a
whisper right now like it just my
mind said it and my eyes opened and is
like the phrase kind of like
transitioned from abstraction to the
literal I went like whisper and I
was like ah it's like I really yeah and
I jumped out of bed and I ran to my lab
like right away and I got a pair of
calipers out and I started measuring my
pelvic bone because I knew what I wanted
to make cuz that's that's how any good
day starts right and I got these
calipers out and measured my pelvic bone
and I created an enclosure for a device
that I called the beat box and the way
that it works is it basically has a
speaker mounted inside of it and it
whispers nonsense into my nether region
at a volume equal to my heart rate so
the the way that this works is if my if
my heart rate is only slightly elevated
then the volume of the whispers the
nonsense whispers is barely audible and
I can feel it but you can't hear it but
there's that that's where this this
feedback loop thing kind of plays in if
I feel it then my heart rate is going to
elevate and then the volume is going to
get louder and then my heart rate is
going to elevate and then the volume is
going to get louder and then eventually
people are gonna start wondering why
there's a voice coming out of my
underwear and and then it come becomes
kind of performative and involves other
people at that point but only once I'm
aroused or excited or confused so I
designed this thing going back to the
sex condom thing I
I you you you know what I'm talking
about like Mex have this like really
strong pelvic bone thing going on that
is very noticeable
I think everyone's noticed that about
them um I wanted to make kind of not a
lady and lettin them three ladylike but
I wanted to make one that was more
reminiscent of Who I am as a person so I
started spitballing how my my lady
gundam pelvic box would look and I used
fusion 360 and I designed this enclosure
it's based on my pelvic contour and like
the relative slope of like my my pelvic
I think and I printed the thing out and
PLA I used some thin transparent sheet
I think that's abs to curve around the
contour to act as a light diffuser but I
also kind of realized at this point like
early on that it looks kind of like a
fillet of fish like like you know like
there's like the curve to it and there's
kind of like the silver enos looks like
scales
there's just something something to note
at this point so cross-section you can
see the speaker on the inside in the
very very front I have another image
that shows that and another couple of
slides but the board mounts there
everything kind of fits in there is a
nice neat package but the speaker is
aimed right at the important point of
yeah reception
I guess um so to get back to that like
that uh fish fillet thing um me and
everyone I know that I was talking to
about making this project we started
calling it like the the whispering
crotch salmon that became the the
nickname for this peripheral so I had to
take it to that level that that salmon
level and I created some salmon marbling
for the greeting so you can actually see
the electronics on the inside and it
lights up it's it's the future
it's the cyberpunk future salmon okay so
uh when I am when I designed the circuit
board um I knew that that had to go I
had to go full salmon at this point so
the board had to look like um salmon as
well I wanted to either make it look
like nigiri or I don't know what that's
called
is that a fillet steak it's a steak what
do you think I went with the steak yeah
I mean of course so um I designed a
circuit board called the fillet oh it
looks like that and basically what's
hooked up to it is op-amp SD card reader
to uh you know hold those delicious
whispers the speakers and then of course
LEDs cuz that that thing lights up like
it's got to and it looks like that it
was also made in Eagle and I don't know
if anyone okay I'm gonna say this is if
anyone knows where to get orange solder
mask please tell me cuz they're red they
I got them made in red because I was the
closest thing I could get to like a
salmony Orange I couldn't find it but um
this is what the board looks like front
and back once it's assembled and it
mounts in the very front of the salmon
so if I take the little shield off then
you get this nice little like backlit
you stake state outline I don't know
yeah I've done three iterations so far I
have like the the working one with me I
had to slim it down significantly
because it chafed it was huge it was
like a giant box and it looked very
beautiful as a designed object but it
wasn't very functional as a wearable and
I do want to wear these one of these
days
that is the end goal so I I made a like
salmon Lite or salmon slim and it's with
me and it still fits everything inside
of it so I will definitely demo that
once I'm done giving her a chat but back
to um I'm gonna move on to like my next
peripheral like right after the the
beatbox came into existence
I had a bottom piece that worked I
wanted to make something for the top
half of my body so now that I had my
feet wet on working on these these body
augments my mind was already kind of
like juiced up on how to approach making
this sort of I don't know
tongue-in-cheek like visual it's like a
joke but you know there's a narrative
going on there and the next thing that I
created was an augment called the
propeller Pacey's hey some of you guys
got stickers for me right like well we
were here yeah um okay so the propeller
pasties are super fun I love them I
wouldn't live I don't I would never wear
them as they are right now for reasons
that I'll get back to but um this this
project started because my partner Mark
had a large number of these I our
distance sensors laying around the lab
like a lot of them and the IR distance
sensors are notable because they're
really great at reading fluctuations in
size within like five or six millimeters
like a really tiny amount of fluctuation
which is roughly the operating distance
of a nipple roughly probably not me but
like theirs yeah so I decided to use
these sensors since we had a bunch of
them and create a device that measured
nipple diameter and nipple with just
just to see if it was possible and I
made a pasty stand off and I used the
data that was received from the sensor
to spin propellers on the outside of the
pasty item so that the speed relates to
the the stiffness now the spinning
wasn't enough I knew that there would
need to be a gearbox involved in order
to spend
nipple right to get it to go the right
speed that I wanted so um I consequently
had just gotten this really cool toy
from from Tokyo it was this little Rover
and I had assembled it and there's this
really kind of if I click on it will it
play oh no it's a it's a gift it should
go well it though od
yeah okay so um it has this really showy
kind of unnecessarily dramatic spinning
planetary gear box that does its thing I
really liked this and I decided to use
this implement to make the propeller
spin but there's also this really like
delicious motion going on there this is
what it ended up looking like so the
gearbox does its thing it spins the
propeller
there's the little motor mounted on the
top that does the spinning it has its
aesthetic but um there's that there's
that whole thing with extra credit right
right like the stimulation is a
byproduct yeah you got a harness that
glorious motion of those spinning motors
or not motors I'm sorry gears right
there just I had to do something with
that but you're you're you're thinking
this already
um nipples and gears don't ever go
together like they shouldn't go together
I'm not saying they don't go together
they shouldn't ever go together
ever like don't do this if you need a
reminder I will give you a sticker and
it can remind you put it on your mill
[Music]
but um I I made these bumpers for the
backside of those gears and
is that nice um it does it does it does
it does its job it's just I don't I
wouldn't want this I'm not brave enough
for this to be my body in there but it
had to be done for I'm not gonna even
gonna say for science for art it had to
be done for art but moving on um this is
what the finished pasty standoff looked
like I ended up only using the the front
the top mounting sensor it was easier it
just worked I didn't want to complicate
it yet the really really difficult part
of making this thing was creating a
universal mount for my assemblies
because one of the reoccurring issues
that I ran into we'll developing the
augments for this project was that I had
to mount things to my body and I made
out of meat so and boobs are like a
different type of meat they're like is
really soft meat and nothing stays put
and I needed to have two different
assemblies seat slightly differently
from one another and I didn't want to
have two separate types of like pasty
mounts so I had to come up with a
universal one and I did each of the
assemblies they screw on to a similar
Universal I already call that I guess
just a pasty mount and they're threaded
so I can just screw them in and they
consequently seat at the correct
position relative to the the nipple the
thing that they're either like I guess
massaging or measuring but that was the
hardest part of doing this whole project
this augment so yeah to test the nipple
proxy to the product the nipple proxy to
sensor propeller speed
I guess test situation I again used
earplugs which come in like girl flavor
I guess
um I don't know I just had to add that
and they're pink so they're I guess
perfect and I made a test fixture that
does do exactly that it utilizes
cardboard but um they it it gets the job
across it's a job done
um let's see I'm gonna talk about this
very briefly um after I made the
propeller Pastis I had a long break and
I came back and I decided that I wanted
to make a user interface that would
allow me to have a quick sense of what
was going on with these sensors on a on
a screen something that was visual and I
ended up creating something that's very
I guess it's fallout esque it's like an
arm mounted like user your user
displayed I ended up calling it the pop
girl instead of but if you think of the
the backpack is the the computer tower
the arm mounted user interface is kind
of like the computer monitor so that you
go together pretty well I designed like
a cheeky little menu screen so if
something starts happening like to my
body the little like gingerbread girl
starts blinking in that part and if I
see if I look down and I see like oh
like like my little boobies are blinking
or lighting up then I can press nips I
can poke that and it will like give me
the discreet sensor values and I created
an enclosure for a what is it it's a
touch screen that uses the Raspberry Pi
it's one of the ones readily available
on Adafruit but I take cram a bunch of
stuff into it to get it to work and then
still be thin enough that you'd want to
wear it on your arm which I still don't
but it looks cool I'm gonna iterate on
it I actually have instructions on how
to to build this thing also on my
hackaday io so if you want to riff on
the enclosure cuz um I'll tell you this
when you get the screen it comes with a
bunch of modules hanging off of it that
don't want to lay nicely relative to
everything else so you have to jump
through some hoops you can check out
what I did if you're interested and
I can help you skip some of those tricky
doing yeah there was a Boop easily if it
does work by the way
this is it working yeah so moving along
I'm gonna this is like the last thing
I'm gonna talk about there we go I'm
wearing this right now
okay so this is the last augment I'm
gonna I'm gonna discuss a little bit
about this is the thing I just finished
like probably a couple of weeks ago like
I have it on before before I explain
what it is and what it does and how I
made it at this point I want to point
something out that's very important in
regard to this project every single one
of these augments happen because if a
conversation that I had with my friends
like you know like late at night where
you're just talking four hours into the
night and you talk about a weird thing
longer than you should this particular
talk was that not all ass crabs are
equal which they're I don't know I guess
they're not and this kind of divulged
into what what is the most pleasurable a
pleasurable aspect of having your butt
squeezed which I don't know if anyone's
thought about that like what is
pleasurable about that action we decided
that there's a couple things to take
into to account though the challenge of
making this augment became how do you
properly or how do you mechanically
replicate a proper tissue squeeze the
thing that we we decided was that it had
to manipulate your thigh meat in some
capacity and it also had to create like
sufficient gap so there needs to be some
separation like some pulling apart that
happens like when this occurs and again
like since this is in in vogue with all
the other arguments I'm creating it has
to be in response to my physical state
so some challenges arose there's first
and foremost the the how how am I going
to do this so I knew at some point in my
life I wanted to create like a butt
winch I don't know what your life goals
are but that was one of mine and I knew
that if I was going to use a winch to
pull on my
it would make sense that it would be
mounted above my butt relative to it to
pull it up and anchor it out so I I
realized I was going to make a winch
belt in fact which is roughly something
that looks like I'm guessing look would
look like this and it would be mounted
above my butt and it would you know help
ratchet that up and once I realized that
I was going to have to make a winch belt
the second challenge kind of arose which
is um the whole problem of meet again
I'm gonna get back to that winches are
usually mounted to solid things like
like jeeps and trucks and stuff right
and they don't move a whole lot but like
I'm a female my body meat like
especially around my hips and my butt
moves quite a bit there's a lot of it
and I wanted to work with my body
instead of against it and I didn't you
know didn't want to force anything so I
I decided that when I created this belt
it made sense to leverage a part of our
body that is pretty stationary luckily
we have skeletons and my pelvic bone
doesn't move a whole lot so I made a
belt that wraps are above and below my
pelvis and if I tighten it down that
bone pops kind of right out and the belt
isn't gonna move anywhere it doesn't go
up or down or left or right and I wanted
to mount the the winch directly on top
of this this hip bone which kind of
brought me to my my third challenge
which is don't hurt yourself making a
winch that spreads your butt apart right
basically to create the artificial thigh
gap
that's dangerous i I had to specify a
motor that would be strong enough to
actually separate my meat but it was
weak weak enough that it didn't actually
split my butt in half like and I had to
defer to one of my friends or several of
my friends that know a lot more about
actual math and engineering than I do I
don't have an engineering background so
we had a couple sessions where we mocked
up a test like a test environment
and I was able to determine through
their their math my friend Tony he's
actually known as like affectionately as
my but technician now because he's
helped me so much with these problems we
determined it takes ten or ten pounds of
raw force to lift one of my butt cheeks
which is like a really I don't know an
interesting thing to know which I could
get I don't I don't have a lot of time I
can't explain how we figured that out
but it involved like Springs and weights
and scales and I guess ten pounds of raw
force translates into roughly a hundred
and fifty ounce into inches of torque so
I was able to specify which motor I
needed and I went up a little bit and I
picked a motor that I think it's two
hundred ounce inches of torque and it
mounts inside of these enclosures that
I'm wearing on my um a body right now
and this bracket is responsible for sort
of holding the winch at the right
trajectory so that the angle of approach
from the spool of the winch to my butt
is appropriate that there isn't any
weird resistance which again is kind of
a tricky thing to pull off because we're
talking about the body and there isn't a
very easy way to do this and it's still
not very ideal but it works I mounted
the thing in there and I used some thin
wire I added spools to it and I kind of
created this dark spacer that you see
there that black piece underneath the
bracket because I have to have to
actually boost the motor up a little bit
just to allow for a better angle going
from the top of my hip down to my butt
once the enclosure was sealed up I was
able to test it out and I was very
pleased to see that it worked because I
honestly didn't think that it would I I
thought I'd have that tractor-beam
problem like in space where once the
beams established the two things kind of
move towards one another rather than one
thing staying put and pulling on the
other but um given even
even with skin and flesh it it ended up
working pretty well and here it works it
did exactly what I wanted it to so this
is supposed to act in response to my
temperature in between my thighs so
given the temperature sensor F if the
heat occurs like are the heat raises in
between my thighs the winch's will
slowly spread that meat apart and once a
certain threshold is passed
this isn't mounted on here yet but the
goal is that a light will illuminate at
the back of my legs and it will make
that triangle that artificial gap
triangle glow from the front and this
augment is called the hot spot for that
reason yeah I should give it a hot spot
- that'd be better so the important
thing to note about all of these things
and like I'm gonna go into my closing at
this point I'm using technology and
engineering as a catalyst to get people
talking about sex and intimacy and I
think that over the summer that I worked
on these projects and then I involved
different people in doing so it
definitely happened I got people talking
about these things in a way that felt
very organic and I think that if we can
continue to encourage this sort of
interaction through like unrelated
topics like engineering or art or other
things we can slowly kind of correct
this weird taboo culture that that are
taboo that is still kind of embedded in
our social culture right now and in the
future we we won't have people like are
less people like me who grow up and have
moments in their life where they feel
isolated or alone or confused or any any
of those things because I think that um
our sexuality should empower us as
humans it shouldn't be a negative thing
so I think we can do that we just have
to talk I believe that our technology
can add a more personal layer to human
interaction I think that all of us are
really good at creating utilities and I
I think that in the future more more
people like us will create things just
for ourselves that will help Express
aspects over our physical state that are
subtle or otherwise go completely
unnoticed and that doesn't necessarily
have to be arousal it can just be
something about you that you you could
you could tell in a beautiful way
through technology the things we
personally create for ourselves enhance
our perception of the world and help a
help expand our ability to communicate
to one another those will ultimately
make day-to-day encounters with people
more exciting and more memorable and I
think that that will improve our quality
of life and I think that's something
that we we could think more about to how
to make life more awesome so the thing I
want to leave you with before I take off
is on using your knowledge and expertise
what would you create to communicate
something about yourself that would
otherwise go unnoticed yeah and thank
you to my patrons on patreon some of you
guys are here thank you for backing me
up your your support is actually kind of
what's fueling it's the lifeblood of me
making things like hip winch's and stuff
and if you want to follow my doings this
is where all my stuff is posted I owe
you too badly but I also post all of my
progress on this stuff on Twitter quite
a bit so again thank you for having me
back here and keep making awesome stuff
out there and thank you for watching
[Applause]
thank you so much