it's a very promising I really looking
forward to it thank you
good luck Thanks Cheers so yes so good
book everybody my name is URI yeah so
I'm worried shaked I'm a front-end web
developer I my day job is I worked part
time for blackberry yes they still exist
and in my free time I do a lot of fun
stuff which I'm going to tell you about
right now so these are the slides I also
be quiet mister feedback I also share
them on Twitter so you can find the link
to the slides on my Twitter it's going
to be up here if you can see the mouse
it's going to be up here for the
duration of the talk so let's start my
story starts a few about a year ago or a
little more when I found this 3d printer
on Kickstarter and of course I begged
this printer it came with a lot of
promises and I decided I want it I want
to have it how many people in the
audience have 3d printers so it's fun
when it works but unfortunately this
Kickstarter process a problem progress
project came with a lot of promises but
failed to deliver the real thing behind
the real story is that tourists earlier
I ordered another printer from the same
company on Kickstarter and it was pretty
much a failure this software didn't work
at all and the hardware was pretty good
so in this new campaign they said we
learned from the past mistakes and we
are going to do it so much better and we
are also going to open source the femur
and everything and I believe them
luckily for the older printer the micro
printer the micro 3d printer they all
the one there was some guy from the
community who created an open-source
framework and a better software which
made the that printer work perfectly so
when I got my new printer my M 3d Pro I
was hoping for something similar to
happen and then I saw this comment on
github basically it's the same guy who
built the alternate femur for the meat
the micro D alder printer and he said
getting our femur to run on the micro
plus or the MPD Pro that was my new
printer first requires figuring out how
to decrypt an 3ds official femur he also
included a lot of information about how
he did it with the previous femur and at
some point here we mentioned they used
the substitution cipher so anything
funny about substitution ciphers all
right perfect
everyone should use it and we're going
to see why right now so I said okay
decrypting em 3ds official fumer
accepted
challenge so I had his femur and I
wanted to decrypt it how would I go
about it I had two options first of all
I needed to get to put my hands on that
femur
one option would be just to try to
connect with the hardware with a
microcontroller inside the femur and
extract it somehow the problem is that
it would void warranty and there is a
good chance I will destroy my femur so I
tried to see if I could somehow get
through the femur update mechanism and
extract the femur from there which was
supposedly encrypted as the guy said on
the github comment so I tried to
download or I downloaded this
where and how many of you know dot pic
not too many am I in the right place
anyway dot pick is a nice tool that
allows you to take dotnet projects D
compile them so I loaded their software
which was written in dotnet into dot
peak and I found in one of their file
this resources section which included
very promising files called M 3d
embedded femur I found four of them they
only had three printers I filled out
later why they had four here so after I
extracted the femur we had a fun part of
trying to figure out what kind of
encryption be used and whether we can
defeat it somehow and this is what we
are going to do now together we are
going to walk through the journey of
decrypting this femur so initial
analysis you get a new femur you start
looking at the file first of all it had
no readable ASCII strings so obviously
it was encrypted I hope maybe it would
not be but it was the file size was
forty fifty four kilobytes but when I
try to compress it it was smaller so
this means this was not some kind of a s
encryption and that substitution cipher
was very likely here I also find found
another comment on get up saying that
this was an SDN 32 CPU which is armed
little india and i found the
documentation for the cpu which will see
how it turned useful in a bit and then i
also found some mention that there are
actually two female files which
explained why they had four fumer files
in the software for only three products
so we are going to use both of this
ephemeral file through our firmware
defeating process so the first thing I
did was taking the file and trying
to analyze it basically I used Jupiter
which is repple for Python how many
Python reading people do we have in the
audience all right so I am in the right
place indeed and Jupiter is a very nice
tool used in the data science community
so let's open Jupiter and I hope can you
see the code here is the font large
enough please say yes yes I get likes if
not please move to the second row so
basically I have here a little code that
these imports we are going to use later
the tweets the fumer from the encrypted
filmer from a file and the first thing I
did was simply to create a histogram
that shows for each of the byte values
how common they are so we are not going
to go over all the code I will just
explain what each what each block of
code does so we can get to the exciting
parts faster so let's run this and we
can see this histogram which has a very
nice this spike in the middle so there
was one byte which appeared much more
than the other byte one value that
appeared one more much more this is the
value the zoom is too large so we can't
see it here but this was 138 139 I still
remember this so my guess that was that
this was not this was 0 0 is a very
common value in a few more files because
it appears in memory address s a lot of
pointers every now terminated string is
obviously terminated by now so my first
guess was that this spike that we see
here the most common value 139 was
actually 0 so with that in mind I
started creating a small table let's do
it together here that map's 130
nine to zero that's our first guest for
today then I went to the Fillmore file
and I started just you know going over
it and then nearly this is the Fillmore
file the encrypted one and near the end
of it I discovered is one F one F one F
one F actually have a slide for it so so
yes you can see those one F 1 F 1 F 1 F
near the end of the thermal file and my
guess was usually when you have few more
files they are padded with f FS because
of the way flash memories works that's
the best value for padding because it
can be overwritten later so my guess was
that this sequence of 1 FS actually
stood for F F at the end of the file
so with that second guess let's update
the table and say that one F maps to F F
not F F F and I already guessed two
characters 0 and F F which were the
easiest and now I started like trying to
explore a de fumer see if I can find any
patterns and interestingly I don't know
if you can see it here but I have a
slide for this I found at the beginning
of the femur so this 8 b is actually 138
9 in hexa which is the zeros but then we
have a lot of twenty fours and by
reading the documentation for the CPU I
found at the beginning of the femur
actually contains interrupt vector which
is just a list of pointers to functions
that handle specific events that happen
on the system and I also learned from
the CPU documentation that everything
all the flash memory all this femur is
loaded to 0 0 0 8 so there is a lot of
repetition here and I know these are
this or should
the addresses that are mapped into the
femoral code so I and this is zero zero
and this is a little endian cpu so my
next guess would be that ninety four
would be zero eight so this would be a
legitimate memory address so let's add
this guest to the table as well that
would be nine ninety four would be zero
eight and we have those we have those
three bytes we guessed so let's check on
our progress we have about 1% of the
firmware and this was about two hours of
work into guessing and at that point I
was like okay there is this huge file
with a lot of zeros and some other
random bytes how do I continue from here
and I had this idea what if I look for
strings you know but the thing is you
won't find the strings in the file but
if I knew one of the strings that is
likely to appear in the fumer and it was
long enough perhaps I could find a
pattern of repeating letters in that
string so before we see that I went
began to dot pick and looked at the
software that runs on the computer and
found a file called femur controller
which sounded really promises promising
where I found is unable to Hindi in it
hardware check micro micro motion cable
connection and I took this string and
the first thing I wanted to know is how
many repetitions are you having this
string so hoping that this string would
appear in the femur
I wrote the following snippet it's a
little bit long but basically let's run
it what it does it creates this nice
plot where you can see each star each
different height represented the
and character different letter so this
one is above a so the green one
represents all the a and we can see the
eight characters repeats for time and
basically this chart visualizes how many
characters are being repeated the
pattern of repetition of characters so
we can see there are a lot of there are
a lot of repetitions like these above
the sea this purple one repeats 16 and
then we have these Oh red one above the
O which also repeats like six times so
this string had a very distinct pattern
of character repetition so we know the
spacing and how many times they should
repeat and with that in mind we can
write some code that we look for a
pattern of this repetition and try to
find a match so I went ahead and let's
add a new block yes and I crafted some
code that would try to find this pattern
so this is the string again and then I
have this code that basically goes over
the entire framework and goes over the
search ring and tries to find a match to
the pattern and if it does it's it's
print hey I found it and updates our
table with the corresponding keys so as
you can imagine I debug the rotate debug
date ran it and it ran no output nothing
found but if you look at the string it
says me micromotion caliber cable and
micro was their older model so perhaps
this string was just not relevant from
my specific framer they had the same
software for all the models of this
printer so I went to look for other
strings with a lot of repetition and
luckily I could find another one that
was repetier protocol and you can see
how many E's and O's
and ours we have repeating here so less
repetitions but still unique enough so I
said okay why won't I just copy paste
this code and try to search for it and I
copy paste of the code run it again and
yet again no match
so so far I spent like more more more
than 10 hours trying to figure this out
and I only figured out around 1% of the
dictionary for decrypting this fumer but
I decided it was not a time to give up
yet and I tried to look at the code that
I used for the micro Treaty so the guy
on get up posted the exact process that
he used for micro Treaty and he also
open sourced the code that encrypts and
decrypts their femur so looking into
that code I actually found on github
this is the code and nothing is
important here I just want you to take
my word for it if we find the right line
so yeah this is the line that actually
does the description from the table and
what you can basically see here this
little expression basically swaps any
pair of adjacent bytes and take my word
for that we are not going to spend time
on that so in the micro femur they swept
any pair of adjacent bytes and I wanted
to see maybe that was the part I was
missing so I went back to my Python and
I added another method just before
loading the femur that would just swap
the pairs of bytes so let's go over this
let's run this method
and if you are really quick python
reader you can identify this expression
from the C code that we saw earlier just
written in pythons way and let's run
this and run this so now we have
reloaded the fumer but with every pair
of bytes swept just like they did with
the micro and i prayed for the gods of
the cryptid Froome encrypted humorous
and run this code again searching from
unable to he need the hardware bla bla
bla bla bla
ah no not that code the one below so I
ran it again and it found it
so well thank you first sign of progress
and since I already copy pasted the code
with the other string I also ran it and
it found it as well so I wrote another
method so I could easily measure my
progress and I call it obviously call it
progress so we have 8% of the femur
figured out and oh another thing I want
you to notice is that the offsets for to
these two strings is 48 something and
this is also 84 something and this is
also 48 something they are both very
close so I figured out this part who
could probably be where they have the
strings so the next step for me would be
for us would be to try to look there and
try to see if we can guess some of the
letters there so I wrote a small hex
damped method you can probably some of
you can probably recognize these escape
characters that will put colors in our
exams and I will show you in a moment
what this does let's run it first so
this is our super-powerful hex dump and
[Music]
we are going to try to dump the area of
the string and make some guesses so that
would be first SK and now you can see
their output of this hex dump and as you
can see it prints the bytes that we
already know and for those we still
don't have the translation it prints
them in purple so we can easily tell the
difference between bytes that we already
know and bytes that we do not know yet
and by looking at these strings we can
make a few wild guesses here like this
ear more name you could probably guess
what the first letter would be right
yeah shout it out it
you're right right right so let's update
our table rerun the code and we can see
it says formal name framer Ian Aryan any
ideas
yeah yeah yeah I just need to copy paste
this correctly so we have this say it
louder I couldn't hear the ass it sounds
like F but it's an S right actually no
this is V that's okay that one was
incorrect and that would be the 23 I
guess alright so we have this guesswork
and now it reads three more version and
we also have machine to pool why I also
asked myself why why am I doing this to
myself
you know anyway so type and then I took
the liberty so we can see serial number
which is another string and this gave me
the confidence we are going through the
right path and we also have this M D
yeah three that's right so let's put our
tree that would be sixty something so
that would be a tree and then table is
not good you only want a table okay so
we have M 3d underscore P something and
since this name of the product is M to
the pro I would guess that this to
Carter's are our and O so let's try to
add them as well so for T a and F 5
would be for our and oh and by the way
thank you for helping me
love that we are doing this together so
yeah so at this point I took a few
guesses and I have most of the letters
it starts to look promising like we are
onto something so I went over both
femurs and I was looking for even more
ASCII originals with ASCII characters
when I found this nice thing next to the
end of the second femur and as you can
see it figured me out a lot of
characters we are going not going to do
them by hand but basically this is what
is so when I started h o bo d any
guesses all right so I guess I started
by guessing that this Bo AR D would be
bored so I guess it's a guest a and D
and made a lot of other gases which
revealed this string said hello board hi
nice to see you today try D and then it
was cuz I really wanted to know what I
needed to try so I tried to google it
but no results if you know where these
come from I would love to learn from you
anyway with that in mind I went and
looked for more ascii and i found a few
more regions and fumer strengths that I
added to my dictionary and at this point
I even found % and at this point I was
pretty happy I type I type progress and
we are only almost 20% just by doing
some guesses we got 10 more % so where
can we take this next we are I scanned
files a few more times we were out of
ASCII strings so I started looking for
other predators when I found this
mysterious table I found in the smaller
femoris some offset where I had an
interesting pattern let me show you this
so this would be the mastery table and
you can see here this is a table and it
has this see II ll be T WA WI and this
is an ascending sequence of letters and
then we also have an ascending sequence
of lowercase letters and at this point I
said okay I have most of the uppercase
letters let's check which letters I'm
still missing and try to figure out if I
could just put them in missing spots so
I wrote another small snippet that would
go over the table that will be in so far
and look for all the escalators and
prints the ones that are missing and we
have only a few missing letters we can
see we have G and J Q X and Z so we have
C e something something L and since the
only letters we don't know are G and J
and these are also the only letters from
this list that happened to be between e
and L and we assume that this is
actually an ascending sequence we are
going to make another guess and say that
and say that these are G and J and let
me say so this was G 95 and J would be
just next to it 27 so that would be G
and that would be J and I have a little
OCD so excuse me for that and then we
have L Oh something T and the only
letter we are still missing our Q X and
so that must be cute so again a table
position what was that e 8 0 XE 8 equals
to Q
and then just to run it again we have
this nice sequence I did a very same
process with the lowercase letters just
trying to deduce what letters we could
have and we're not going to repeat it
right now I'll just write a result and
we had this nice sequence there was one
letter here I couldn't figure out
because we had both let's update the
list of missing letters we had both P
and Q which are next to each other so I
couldn't guess which one would fit here
between M and s and at this point I was
looking at the beginning and I found
this interesting pattern where you have
0 0 0 a lot then something something
something something something something
a lot of repeated bites and then 8 8 8
which we figured out at the beginning so
I thought to myself perhaps this would
be 1 1 1 2 2 2 3 3 3 etc perhaps this is
again ascending sequence and I just
tried to match and there was 7 different
values between here and here so it seems
like a good match so obviously I updated
the table with these guesses as well and
okay and let's print this again with the
new guesses and it seems like a good
match so we have the start of the
beginning of the double table we have
some D values at the beginning of the
middle of the table and it seems like
it's some sort of curve represented here
because we had this value 0 repeating
for a lot of times and then we had less
number if you want less toothless tree
like it seems to reduce the number of
repetitions and then in the middle we
have every other letter so approving in
this table and near the end we can also
see FF and a few more repeating
characters I could try to do more
guesswork and try to interpolate the
values in the sequence but I decided to
turn to
Google at that point and to Google this
string hoping hoping Google would open
of course I do all my searches incognito
hoping I would find something and I
indeed found this string in a lot of the
results results but if you if you look
closely you will see it looks promising
but then the lowercase letters are ACF
or ADF and I had different lowercase
letters so it looked promising but I
couldn't find anything that matched the
other letters I had in this table so I
ran a few more searches I tried to
search for the lowercase letters and
then I try to search for you know the
hex values maybe they are represented as
X values so running this hex value
search with quotes or will find exact
matches and basically I found do you
like riddles but it's not the riddle I
was looking at when it occurred to me
that if I just add 0x at it before each
of the characters each of the X numbers
I may have a better chance so I googled
it correcting nonlinear brightness LEDs
interesting the printer had an LED that
was blinking like fading on and off and
this seems like this could be something
useful for the femur and it's from
electronics s tacky J exchange so it
must be legit trust me on this so I
opened this answer and started blah blah
blah blah and nice this is a curve and I
was expecting to find some care of and
here is a table here's the full set of
256 levels that I used so somebody
posted an answer how to control the
brightness of the LED LED on Stack
Overflow so I was really pumped I just
could be pasted it into my jupiter
notebook let's close this incognito
thing
and paste it so I just copy-paste the
entire table and I wrote a little
snippet of code that would just go over
each of the bytes try to match them with
the bytes on the table if this is a
value that we already know we already
have it in our table we compare it with
what we expect to find there and if it
fails we die miserably with an assert
otherwise we just update our table and
to my surprise I run it and we had a
perfect match
so time to check on our progress and we
see we have 70% of the femur we are
getting there this at this point I
started to develop new hope so I found
this mystery table which turned out to
be the controller for the brightness of
the LED and then I found I googled it I
found a table and we saw some light at
the end of the Fatimid tunnel and then I
went to look for other patterns in the
femur where I found another table so
let's have a look there that would be
the second table right so I found this
table and you can see there is like this
nice column here which read Chrissy
something we don't know that repeats all
of time 3e and then something we don't
know again so a wild gas would say that
if this is Christy and this is 3e this
would probably be 3d like the printer
and this one would be 3f and I also had
another guess that since we had another
column here that started with Christy
but it had these 22 it could be 3 be the
value before so I ran this guesses and
now with this guesses the table looks
like 3 B 3 C D looks legit and at this
point I was started to wonder what the
other values could be represent like its
group of 4 bytes
actually it's little India and so we
read it this way these are groups of 4
bytes and they they seem to be
increasing that when I try to convert it
to a D word it didn't mean a lot to me I
would like seeing an increasing sequence
with some difference between the numbers
but they had no meaning and then could
you guess what it could be if it's not D
words so
I had another guest this might be
floating-point numbers so I wrote a
little code I basically just copy pasted
some of those some of those numbers like
this one from the sequence and tried to
ask Python to print them as little
endian floats and I found out these were
all floating numbers between 0 and 1 and
they were increasing they were in a
setting sequence so it seems to be like
a function that goes between 0 and 1 and
in order to know what his function looks
like I decided to plot it so I wrote a
little code snippet that would just go
over this table from the float offset in
jumps of 4 go over each set of 4 bytes
see if we have all of them in the table
if we could find translation for all of
them we would just add them to an array
otherwise would put none so we'll have a
plot with all the points that we know
and spaces where there are points we
don't know so I found this table I
figured out how this could be floats and
now I'm going to try between 0 and 1 and
now I'm going to try to plot them to see
what it looks like oh I have 10 minutes
I thought I have 7 thank you in bar so I
can breathe and take a sip of water
before we blow to these numbers
I love title so this is the numbers that
we found it's indeed an ascending
sequence it seems like another kind of
curve why am I wasting real estate on
the address bar I don't know it seems
like a real nice curve and at this point
I was like okay I have those points I
have the missing points it's Python it
can help me find a missing points and I
remember there was a way to interpolate
if I have a function I could interpolate
but to be honest
not too much into data science so I
turned into two of my friends I can't
see if they are here in the audience
avi I mean of and Yanni Rosen shine were
more into math and data stands and they
told me yeah there is this package
called Syfy and it has this amazing
function called interpolate which can
take a list of numbers with some gaps
and fill the gaps just what we need here
so for another snippet called
interpolate basically there is this
interpolator that builds the list of the
points that we already know there X
values and Y values and we called Saipa
interpolate in Terp 1d which should yes
create a function that guesses the gaps
and then we plot the original points and
they interpolated points so the
interpolated points will be yellow and
the original ones will be green let's do
this and just to see if yeah if it
guesses well and these are the
interpolated points the points that
Python guessed for us all the can you
see the difference between green and
yellow yes yes like like like like okay
let's actually make it even easier yeah
let's change these ones to an X so yeah
so we have all these guest numbers now
since these are floating-point numbers
and these are just guesses we could be
off by one by by like one or two because
these are just guesses and floating
point is not super accurate but I try to
so we know the most significant byte of
each of those numbers these are like
this like this 3 e 3 F 3 D and 3b that
we guessed and we want to fill the gaps
in the second most significant byte so
even if there is an error
there is a lower chance of an error in
the more significant bytes so basically
I wrote another snippet of code that we
are going to run now and that snippet of
code would know that we already run that
we try to predict the missing values for
the second most significant byte in
places where it's still missing and
basically it just takes it goes over the
points we are only going from the tenth
point since we can see that at the
beginning we only have two data points
and the curve is kind of high so there
is a better chance of errors so we just
try to interpolate the values between
this point and the end of the curve and
basically we're trying to see whether
our predictions match the actual bytes
there just to check how close we are
I'll close our predictions for bytes we
already know and then for bytes we don't
know we just update our table with the
prediction so let's run it and we are
trying to predict the second most
significant byte for each of the few
Moabites and this had no errors which
means that thank you in bar which means
that we still have five minutes to do
the next byte amazing which means that
all the predicted values match the
values that we already know and for some
of those values these values that did
not appear in our original points array
because they had other bytes missing so
this is a good signal that our
prediction function works well and we
also fill the table even more so now we
are 85% it feels like we're all almost
there I think we are also up 85 percent
of the time so that's a perfect match so
the next thing would obviously be to do
the same let's update the plots let's
plot them again
so this is now with the new bytes that
we predicted they are already in the
table so we already see them on the plot
and we can update our predictions as
well and just a moment let's run this
one again so yeah so we see a lot more
green and less yellow and we are going
to do the same now with a third most
significant byte and hope we still get a
good amount of matches even though the
precision drops as we go to the least
significant bytes so running the same
snippet again and again and again and
again predict missing bytes but this
time we are going to go one byte back to
the byte number the second byte
it's little endian so the most
significant is three next is two and now
we're going over byte number one and
here we see that there was one error
that could be expected because the
precision went less but we spotted that
we already had read translation for the
value that we guessed incorrectly so we
just skip that one and we see that we
have ninety-eight percent of the femur
and no other errors so we are probably
doing good at our guesswork and at this
point I felt like we are still missing
20 values and that would be a good time
to stop doing data science and looked
for patterns and actually try to look at
the code so I opened I da and I wrote a
little script that would go over the
disassembly and whenever it found a line
which had a missing bytes it would color
it red and then I created a keyboard
shortcut that would allow me to cycle
through the possibilities because we
only had 20 possibilities to fill in and
after about three hours of finding small
functions trying to figure out what they
do I mean with this function you can see
it touches it load something into r1 and
then it compares r1 to zero
and then it does something and then the
missing byte obviously it doesn't make a
lot of sense here where we compare our
six with rst with where we load
something into our six because we don't
have our six mentioned here and the next
thing we do is compare our one so we
would there would be much more sense to
have some opcode here that would do
something with our one that would load a
value into our one and going through all
the twenty possibilities I found only
one that loaded something into r1 which
was that one so I did this until I
figure out the rest of the missing 20
bytes which finally revealed this secret
of the femur and the end of the story
so he takeaways before we when we wrap
up when you are doing such a thing look
for patterns everything was found I
found here was just because I found some
patterns that code my eyes and I decided
to dig into them use data science tools
Python rocks it helps it's hard and
frustrating so don't give up thank you
Wow thank you