♪♪
-So, thank you.
It's a great pleasure to be here today.
As Daniella said, my name is Yoshi Kohno,
and I wanted to spend a little bit of time
talking with you about computer security
and the Internet of Things.
First off, what do we actually mean
by "the Internet of Things"?
We can give you a few examples --
things you might have thought about,
such as door locks, thermostats, furnaces, refrigerators,
children's toys, automobiles.
Essentially, I like to think about
the Internet of Things being any connected device
that a consumer might try to purchase.
And so that's the definition that I'll use for the purposes
of today's talk.
Now, when we think about the Internet of Things,
it brings numerous benefits.
I mean, there's a reason why
the Internet of Things is coming.
Of course, when we also think about technology,
we also have to realize that there might be
some associated risks.
And there's a wide variety of the types of risks
that one might think about,
but for today, I really want to talk
about what could the security and privacy risks
be with the Internet of Things?
There are a number of topics that probably immediately
come to mind.
For example, does the Internet of Things
affect people's safety?
Or are there privacy risks with the Internet of Things?
You know, what do these sensors actually reveal about us?
And these are things that I'm gonna talk about,
but I also want to broaden the definition
and include other types of issues as well.
So, for example, not just what are the direct privacy leakages,
but what other information can be inferred
about a person or people
from these Internet of Things devices?
What financial risks might arise?
Can these devices be used as stepping stones?
And, of course, zombies and the uncertain future.
If you don't know what that means,
you'll know by the end of this talk.
And so this talk is a sequence of examples of research projects
that have come out of The University of Washington
as well as with collaborators.
And my goal in presenting these things
is try to help encourage a broad range
of thinking about the issues
that can arise in an IoT environment.
And again, of course, all this work
was made possible due to wonderful collaborations
with students at The University of Washington, other faculty,
students and faculty elsewhere, and our generous funders.
The first example I wanted to give you
is that of a modern automobile.
The modern automobile
is becoming increasingly computerized.
There might be 10, 30, even 100 computers
inside the modern automobile,
and these computers are connected to each other,
and this brings numerous safety and other benefits.
For example, you might have a computer
attached to each wheel
that's detecting how fast each wheel is spinning,
then it will send a message
over the car's internal computer network
to another computer that will determine
whether one wheel is spinning faster than the other.
If that's happening, you might be getting into a skid.
And so that computer will send another message
to the brake computer, saying, "Brake computer,
slow down the back-right wheel."
And it's through this process that we get increased safety.
For example, traction control.
So numerous benefits, but what are the risks?
This is Karl Koscher, one of the PhD students
on the project.
To try to explore this question,
we, in collaboration with UC San Diego --
you'll hear from Stefan next --
purchased two 2009-edition modern sedans,
and we subjected them to
basically computer-security analyses --
tried to figure out what we could do.
The first thing we needed to figure out
is, how can we communicate
on the car's internal computer network?
That's the first thing an adversary would need
to be able to do.
We found numerous ways to do that.
For example, our car has an exposed diagnostics port
underneath the dash.
So an adversary or unauthorized party
could just connect his or her own equipment
to that diagnostics port
and communicate with other components
within the vehicle.
Our car also has a built-in telematics unit.
A telematics unit allows the car to effectively call 911
if it gets into an accident.
What this means is that as an adversary,
we are also able to call that car's phone number.
We found that we could call that car's phone number,
play the appropriate tones to switch to an in-band modem,
play another modem tone
to bypass an authentication vulnerability,
and then some more modem tones to get our own code
running on the car.
Our car has 3G data,
it has Internet off the lot,
and so our little piece of code
opens up an FTP connection to servers
at The University of Washington, which downloads an IRC client.
We then run our IRC client
on the cars, actually both cars.
They connect to servers at The University of Washington,
and we have an automobile botnet.
Once we could communicate on the car's internal computer
network, we could start affecting other components
within the vehicle.
Since a picture's worth a thousand words,
I want to show you a video.
This is a video of us driving one of our test vehicles
down a decommissioned airport runway.
For this experiment, Alexei Czeskis is driving.
Karl Koscher has his laptop connected
to the diagnostics port underneath the dash.
He'll press a button on his laptop
that will forcibly apply the brakes
as Alexei is driving,
basically exploiting properties of the car's brake controller.
-2, 1...
-So you can hear, Alexei's talking on the radio.
We're kind of coordinating all this.
Numerous safety precautions in place.
-Hit the brakes at 3, 2, 1, 0 -- now.
-Karl presses a button on his computer...
sends a message over the car's network, the brakes are applied.
-That was cool.
Really scary, but cool.
-So we have a lot of fun, of course,
doing our research.
This is us disengaging the brakes,
so Alexei's gonna get up to 20 miles an hour,
Karl will send the message over the car's computer network
that will disengage the brakes.
And you can think about how this might arise
in the sense that our car has anti-lock braking,
which means that it has the ability
to override the driver's brake pedal,
and we just exploit that.
-3, 2, 1, 0.
-So Alexei's gonna be getting up to speed.
This timer isn't working, by the way.
It still says 30.
-Delivering the packet at 3, 2, 1, 0.
-Karl presses a button on his internal computer network.
-I cannot brake. -Alexei can't brake.
-Okay, now I'm at 20 and I still can't brake.
-And so he's pushing full pressure on the brake pedal.
You can see the end of the airport runway, by the way.
-I'm gonna try the parking brake,
in case someone actually might be in this situation.
-For this particular vehicle, the parking brake
was under mechanical control.
It did stop the car.
We didn't want to test faster than 20 miles an hour,
and I would say that for other vehicles,
the parking brake is under electronic control.
So, the lesson from this is that there are potential safety risks
with computer security issues with IoT devices.
That doesn't mean these necessarily are gonna manifest
in the real world.
So there's a difference between, you know, the fact
that someone could do this and someone will do this,
but this is the type of lesson I wanted to extract.
One of the other things that we tried to explore
were are there other things
an adversary might try to do with this vehicle?
So I'm gonna turn to another example.
Our car has Bluetooth hands-free calling in it.
This means that there are microphones inside the cabin.
In this video,
I'll show you how we've called the car's phone number --
again, an unmodified car off the lot.
Called the car's phone number.
play the modem tones to switch to the in-band modem,
bypass authentication, get our own code
running on the car, our car then connects to our servers
at The University of Washington for further commands.
In this particular video, we will show
how we can basically,
once we've connected to this car,
we can enable a theft program.
So we can learn the car's GPS coordinates, you know,
where the car is, and then our code on the car
can do things like unlock the car's door,
start the engine, disable the shift lock solenoid,
so that a thief could just go to those GPS coordinates,
get in the car, and drive away.
-We're going to steal this car over the Internet.
-So, this is Franzi Roesner.
She's now another professor at The University of Washington.
-This car has an IRC button on it
that will let us communicate with it.
-She's connected to this unmodified vehicle
over the Internet, again,
with the car's built-in cellular connection.
-And then it's just a simple matter
of executing the theft program.
-Running the theft program.
In a moment, you'll hear the car start.
[ Engine starts ] -And then my colleague
can just drive the car away without a key.
-And you'll soon see Karl Koscher, one of the other
PhD students on the project... -[ Laughs evilly ]
-...walking up to the car.
The theft program unlocked the car's doors,
already started the engine, as you heard.
Like any good car thief,
always remember to buckle up, which Karl will do next.
-Do-de-do-de-do.
-We've disabled the shift lock solenoid,
so you can shift out of park.
No key in the ignition,
and we've bypassed the immobilizer,
which keeps the car running. -Here we go.
-And I was confused by the timer,
so I gave some of the examples a little bit differently.
So the next one -- so this is an example
of the financial risks.
The next one is one about Bluetooth hand-free calling.
So our car does have microphones within the cabin.
Adversary can turn on these microphones
and listen in on anything happening inside the vehicle.
So in this particular example, Steve Checkoway,
one of the PhD students at the time
at The University of California San Diego,
has compromised the UW car.
Alexei and Karl are gonna walk into the UW car
and have a private conversation.
So here they are walking into the car --
again, unmodified car. This time,
compromised by the UC San Diego folks.
-[ Laughs evilly ]
King Bowser's gonna be super excited
that we finally kidnapped Yoshi.
-They came up with this skit on their own.
And so, meanwhile, you'll see what is happening
at Steve Checkoway's office.
In Steve Checkoway's office,
you can see that he can observe the GPS coordinates
of the vehicle,
and pretty soon --
Alexei and Karl are driving around --
pretty soon you'll start hearing the real-time audio
that is actually being recorded in Steve's office.
So it is of this high quality.
It starts just about now.
-[ Laughs evilly ]
King Bowser's gonna be super excited
that we finally kidnapped Yoshi.
-And so the lesson from this is
that there are potential privacy risks
with computer security issues in an IoT environment.
This time, you know, there are microphones in the cabin.
If an adversary can get access to that,
they can learn private information.
I want to move on to example number two,
very briefly, on children's toys.
One of the things that we're seeing
is that there are becoming increasing computerization
with things that we are giving to our children.
In fact, these are some dated photos, now,
from 2008 and 2009,
of some toys that you might get for a child
that have computation in them.
These two particular ones, here,
have both a built-in webcam and Wi-Fi.
One example usage model for this might be --
a friend gives, or a child receives one of these toys
for their birthday,
assembles it, connects it to their home wireless network,
and then when they go to their friend's house,
they can connect back over the Internet to the toy in the room
and make sure their parents aren't in the room.
Unfortunately, we found that these webcams
are also accessible to other parties.
So other adversaries over the Internet who can then also
see what's happening inside the children's room
or wherever the robot might be -- the toys might be.
So one of the key lessons from this is that there, again,
are privacy issues with these IoT technologies.
We can also think about other issues that might arise.
So, for example, if there's a bunch of webcams
in our environment, could an adversary some day
use those for financial gain?
Maybe blackmail and so on.
The toy example also brings up the question
of who administers these devices.
You know, in the future, we might have
devices connected to our home networks
that are being administered by children,
maybe sometimes they can't even read yet.
And, also, who is affected by these devices?
Not just the user of the technology,
but anyone else in the device's environment.
For my third example, I want to come back
to the modern automobile.
I mentioned that there was a lot
of communication already occurring within the car.
And so, for example, we have messages being sent
from the brake computer to other computers.
We have messages being sent on the car's internal computer
network, when someone turns on the lights, and so on.
One of the questions we had is,
what private information could someone learn
about the drivers of these vehicles
just by running analytics on top of the messages
that are already being communicated within the car?
So, for example, what if information
and analytics of the messages going on within the car
was being sent from the telematics unit
to the telematics service provider?
Or what if the car's owner
bought one of these insurance dongles,
connected it to the diagnostics port
underneath the dash -- you might have heard, for example,
of the Progressive Auto Insurance's dongle.
Well, what if that dongle was sending information
about the communications that were already occurring
on the car's internal computer network?
What private information might they be able to learn?
To kind of push on this further,
we found that someone monitoring the existing communications
on the car's internal computer network
could, for example, identify the driver
from the set of small possible drivers in the vehicle.
For example, which of the family members is driving this car?
The reason I wanted to give this example
is to show that there's information
that can be inferred -- private information
that can be inferred from these devices
that might not be directly exposed.
For example, not like the microphone
and the video camera, but there's information
that someone can learn by just running analytics
on top of the information already there.
For example number four,
I want to talk about home power line monitoring.
We're seeing more companies,
and also academic efforts,
focusing on how can we more effectively monitor
the use of the home power line?
So, for example, there are products out there
that will give you essentially an itemized bill
of how much power each device is using within your home.
So, how much power is a toaster using?
How much power is a stove using?
How much power is a washing machine using?
And so on.
And there's numerous reasons why someone might want this,
but the question we asked is, if someone wanted to,
how much more private information
could they learn about the activities
within the home by monitoring the power line?
What we found is that an adversary
monitoring the home's power line could even go so far
as inferring what TV show someone might be watching on TV.
To give you an indication of how this might be possible,
this figure on the right shows measurements
that are being taken from a device connected
to the home power line shown in the frequency domain,
so monitoring the power line in the frequency domain.
And the part on the left --
you can see very visually
when the washing machine turns on and off
and when a CFL light bulb turns on or off.
And you can see that little wavy line by the TV.
It turns out that as the TV
is going from light scenes to dark scenes,
it affects this signal that appears on the power line.
And since different TV shows have different characteristic
patterns from light to dark and so on,
we can use that to infer information
about what show someone is watching on TV.
So, again, the lesson from this is that information
can be inferred
that might not necessarily be directly collected.
For my final example,
I want to talk about home automation systems.
Home automation systems are becoming increasingly popular.
You might've seen advertisements for them.
These are systems, for example,
you might drive away from home and say, "Oh, shoot, I forgot.
I don't remember if I locked my car door,
and so you pull out your cellphone,
connect to the home automation system over the Internet,
and then, from that point, lock your door,
make sure you turned off your lights, and so on.
The question is, what happens if there might be an adversary
wanting to exploit some properties
of this home automation system?
This is a picture of Tope, one of the PhD students
on this particular project.
It's well known that if we can compromise
the home automation controller,
then the adversary might be able to access things
like control the door locks -- unlock or lock the door --
affect the furnace, affect the dimmer,
the light switches, and so on.
But one of the things we wanted to know is, you know,
how far could we push an adversary's capabilities?
Like, are there other things
that an adversary might be able to do
besides just affecting those devices directly connected
to the home automation system.
And we found out the answer is yes,
there actually can be things an adversary can do.
For example, imagine that someone
has purchased just a regular,
from Home Depot, a CFL light bulb
and plugged it into a light switch controlled by a dimmer.
This is not something someone should do,
because it's known that if you connect a CFL light bulb
to a dimmer, there's a risk of a fire.
Well, let's say that someone has done this.
Well, then we found that an adversary
who can control the dimmer can make it go back and forth,
back and forth at a fast enough rate
to actually cause a CFL light bulb to pop.
And so this is a picture that we have
of one of our light bulbs
in our experiments with a little bit of charring.
The reason I give this example is several-fold.
One, to highlight the fact
that when we're thinking about security
in an IoT environment, we don't need to think about
directly someone just immediately
trying to compromise the car
or the children's toy or so on,
but using these devices
within the environment as stepping stones.
So first compromising the home automation controller
to thereby access the dimmer, to thereby access another device.
Now, you may not particularly care
about this specific example,
but I think the stepping-stones lesson is real.
And, second, I think this is an example
of thinking about the fact
that when we're thinking about security for IoT environment,
we might actually be affecting other devices
that actually might not traditionally be called IoT.
For example, when someone created the CFL light bulb,
they were thinking they were just creating a light bulb
that was gonna be plugged into a light socket.
They never really thought about that light socket
being controlled by an adversary.
Similarly, when someone created this IoT dimmer,
they probably didn't think about what happens
when you connect a CFL light bulb to it.
I'm gonna also use this figure
to talk about the zombie problem.
So, what is a zombie?
If you think about purchasing some of these IoT devices,
such as a furnace or refrigerator,
those devices might live in your home
for 5, 10, 15, 20, 30 years.
But how long will those devices be maintained
and receive security updates by the manufacturer?
Maybe two years? Five years?
Zero years, I see someone saying.
So what we call a zombie is an IoT device
that is living in this environment
that is no longer being maintained,
no longer receiving security patches.
So I think it's a big challenge to think
about what are we gonna do with these zombies
for the remaining 28 years that they remain in service?
And, finally, I want to highlight the fact
that in an IoT environment, there is an uncertain future.
We don't necessarily know what types of IoT devices
will exist in the world in 5, 10, or 15 years.
And so how do we start thinking about security for IoT now?
I want to close with two things.
First, I want to thank all the wonderful collaborators,
some of whom I see in this audience,
on these projects.
And I know you'll hear from Stefan next
about computer security for automobiles
and a little bit more about the timeline there.
Then close with this final slide.
Again, I hope that this talk has encouraged you
to think broadly about what computer security
and privacy might be in an IoT environment.
I've given you some examples.
Of course, many, many other examples are out there,
and if you pay attention to the news,
I'm sure that within the next day or two days,
you'll begin to see more and more examples of IoT issues.
So, with that, I think I'll close.