♪ ♪
[ Applause ]
-Hello.
First of all, I want to thank you
for the much warmer weather here than where I was previously.
Snowmageddon wasn't so fun.
So, today, I want to talk to you
about how cybercriminals are using
and targeting rewards-program accounts
to make money these days.
I'm gonna take you some through some real-life attack, defense,
and dark-market exploration.
What I'm about to share with you is something that came out of
my firsthand experience fighting cyber fraud
and then my passion of wanting to understand how it works.
About six months ago, my colleagues and I were alerted
to a bunch of simultaneous increases in strange traffic
to multiple customer web properties.
When we dug into the traffic,
we found that customer-log-in URLs
were being targeted by scripts that were rolling
through large sets of log-in credentials.
Automated account checkers -- we've seen these before.
Now, typically, they target e-commerce, retail,
travel, those sorts of web properties.
And what they do is they use log-in details
gleaned from breaches of other websites,
and then they will try those log-ins
again and again on these customers
that they're targeting.
Now, what they're doing is they're counting on people
reusing the same log-ins across multiple websites.
Nobody here does that, right?
All right, so, we've seen this before,
we know what to do, we've got the playbook for it.
We're gonna run it.
We see that the I.P. is spewing out
all of the malicious traffic.
What they are mostly is virtual-shared hosting,
you know, vulnerable WordPress, Joomla!, and other CMS systems,
Mac botnet I.P.s, and consumer I.P.s.
Most of these consumer I.P.s, we were able to figure out,
were actually popped home routers
and NAS devices that were hacked.
So, now we just find the solid request patterns,
we drop some geoblocks in place, we fire up our I.P. blacklists,
and then we start serving up some 403 responses --
easy enough and finished in time for lunch.
What more could you ask for?
Apparently, a lot more.
So, what we ran into this time
that was different than the previous times
we fought off these guys is,
unlike the times that we did before,
now they're not just buzzing off and finding softer targets.
They're coming back at us with new techniques.
Our geoblocks and our I.P. blacklists --
they were met with a flood of new, rotating I.P. addresses
coming from VPN services and a series of different
open and private proxies.
Hola, I'm looking at you for one of the big contenders here.
And the previous request patterns that we set in place
to match against their traffic became useless to us.
They started switching up their user agents,
and they started switching up the actual order
of their headers.
All right, fine. Emeril Lagasse time.
Bam -- tightened rate controls on the log-in URLs.
Bam -- valid refer checks.
Come at me, bro. I've got you.
So, the illegitimate traffic to the log-in URLs
we were defending starts dropping off pretty quickly.
Awesome. We've got it.
Well, not so much.
So, now they just start hitting the mobile ABIs
and starting hitting the really,
really interesting legacy log-in paths
that the customer developers left in place
and didn't realize were still publicly available.
So, now this tit for tat isn't really working for us,
and we have to get smart about
how we're responding to these guys
because they're meeting each of our ways of blocking them.
So, what if we get a little more subtle
in how we're dealing with them?
So, what we're gonna do here is we're going
to stop blocking out the requests
so they switch I.P.s or go through another proxy,
and we're gonna start tarpitting them
or long-routing them.
We're gonna make their traffic really slow,
but not be stopped or timed out.
And then, when they get to the end of that route,
we're gonna serve them up
a fake "You've successfully logged in" page.
So now they think, "Oh, these log-in credentials work,"
and they move on to the next set of credentials.
So, after this, we saw some smaller, follow-up waves,
but no further pivots sin techniques
because this gave us the time to work with the customers
to fix their API log-in logics,
and to nuke the legacy paths that were being exploited.
Finally, the siege was lifted.
Now, this was curious.
This was a real break from the past
for these types of attacks.
The attackers really put a lot of thought and effort
into responding to our defensive maneuvers.
Now that we were no long in shit's-on-fire mode,
I wanted to figure out why they were using all of this time
and these resources to respond to us
instead of just going after easier targets,
like they have in the past.
So, the data in these types of accounts --
PII, rewards points, miles, partial credit-card info --
this isn't anything that's changed from the past.
All that is about the same information.
And when I look at the legislative landscape
or the industries themselves,
there haven't been any significant changes
that should make the intrinsic value
of these accounts higher such that people want
to spend more resources going after them.
I guess that leaves the resell market
for these types of goods.
So, how did they monetize these accounts?
Now, the initial obvious path, of course, would be to go
for the credit-card information in the account.
But even when you log in
as the customer in these accounts,
you don't necessarily see the credit-card information in full.
So you can't just take it out and sell it that way.
What you'd have to do is go in
and use the card attached to the account
to buy more rewards, to buy points, to buy miles,
and sometimes to buy tangible goods
through the rewards store.
Now, they can take those purchased goods
and services, and they can resell them --
you know, things like watches, designer bags, gift cards,
that sort of thing.
After they changed the user's address info --
the shipping-address info --
then they can ship the tangible goods
to one of their drops,
and then they can go ahead and resell it -- you know,
something like Craigslist or eBay or Wallapop.
So, they could even use work-at-home mules
to do this reshipping for them
so they don't have to deal with the actual, tangible goods.
But then you run into issues like the mules flipping on you
because the cops are really looking hard
at these kind of reshipping schemes right now.
You also have to run the risk of your mules
just stealing your stuff and taking your money.
So, instead of dealing with all of that hassle,
is there a market for just the digital part
of these rewards accounts?
Is there a large enough market to make it worth it?
And looking for markets selling these types of goods,
I wanted to make sure that they met a few conditions.
It needed to have quantifiable transaction histories.
That's where I can go into the website
and actually see a history of a seller's transactions --
which ones have gone through, which ones failed,
and the reviews of those transactions.
I also needed to have a way to make sure
that I wasn't funding crime directly.
If I went to a pay-to-play closed forum or IRC channel,
then I would be paying directly into criminals,
and the legal department at my work wouldn't be so happy
with me about that.
I also needed to make sure that the barriers to entry
weren't too high or too costly.
And what I mean by that is there are a lot of these forums
that have markets attached to them
that require another criminal to vouch for you.
And usually the way you do that is
by proving your own criminality to them.
I didn't want to get into that.
I also wanted to make sure that these markets had
high enough traffic to make it worth the research.
This set of criteria led me to focus
on the darknet onion-router markets.
There are a lot of markets to choose from
with varying degrees of uptime, activity,
and volatility.
So, I chose to further narrow down the target markets
by selecting for those that were currently active
and that had an uptime greater than 95%.
In terms of activity and interest,
they needed to, as of November 2015,
have Google search impressions of greater than 60,000
and Google keywords greater than 100.
This led me to look at these top three Tor markets --
AlphaBay, Dream Market, and Nucleus Market.
I knew these markets had a lot of drugs on offer,
but when it came to hacked goods,
I was admittedly surprised with what I found --
credit cards, accounts for Netflix, Hulu,
HBO, Spotify, stolen PayPal accounts,
Steam accounts, and a lot of porn-site memberships.
Across the three markets, there was a total
of 14,183 digital goods for sale,
things like hacked accounts, malware, e-gift cards.
And there were 15,426
specifically fraud-related digital goods for sale.
Those were things like
personally identifiable information --
we'll talk more about that later --
credit-card numbers, and bank drops.
Here's what I found inside of those numbers --
that there were whole accounts for sale --
these are rewards accounts --
where, specifically, the rewards or points balance
was called out as a sales feature
for these accounts.
I found 20 listings of these across 7 unique vendors,
with 2,014 confirmed sales.
What about the vouchers and e-gift cards
that you could get through these rewards accounts?
54 different listings across 13 unique vendors,
with 3,136 sales.
Now, when we're looking at just the rewards points,
there were only three listings across three unique vendors.
But they had a total of 698 sales between them.
Talk about cornering the market.
What about air miles? Those are worth a lot, right?
Here I only found 4 listings across 4 vendors,
totaling in only 100 sales.
What's going on there?
Well, I went to the different air-miles programs
and started to look at their policies,
and it turns out, within the past few years,
a large number of them have really cracked down
on their transfer policies
and make it very difficult to just transfer it.
Thus, its fungibility is lost.
So, out of all of this,
there is one section that really blew me away
that I wasn't expecting to be as large as it was --
personal criminal travel agents.
These listings offer highly discounted custom bookings
for flights, trains, and buses, cruises, hotels,
car rentals -- you name it.
They even have their own cancellation
and refund policies.
The way that these sellers assure you
that your travel won't be canceled
is they promise you they're not using stolen credit cards.
They're just using rewards points.
So, it might seem pretty sketchy and easily stoppable,
but something must be working
because I'm looking at 93 general listings,
94 custom orders across 31 unique vendors --
that's a lot of people in the marketplace --
with total sales of 4,808.
On top of this, the majority of them had rave reviews.
That's crazy.
What kind of timeline are we talking here?
Let's give some context to these numbers.
Well, these sales numbers are only since March 2015.
So, across 10 months,
in only 3 darknet markets,
there were 10,756 confirmed sales,
and these are all rewards-account-related goods.
And this isn't even counting the listings
that have been taken down
or the vendors that have since closed shop --
10,756.
I'd say there's a large enough market.
All right, so, these pushers of purloined points
are making Bitcoin hand over fist.
Now they can use these Bitcoins to turn around
and purchase other things on the darknet market,
but how do they get cold, hard cash
without winding up in jail?
Here's where the cash-out technique is crucial.
The darknet markets aren't just full of drugs
and hacked accounts.
They're also filthy with guides on how to cash out safely.
Many of these guides claim to have unique
of obscure processes for doing so.
Most of these guides start with the suggestion
of using a Bitcoin-tumbling service.
This is where your Bitcoins are mixed
with a lot of other folks' Bitcoins
so that you get out new, fresher Bitcoins
that are harder to trace.
Some of these guides also suggested,
when you tumble your Bitcoins,
to do it in a series of small transactions
with differing amounts over a long period of time
to make it even harder to trace through the block chain.
So now they've got some "cleaner" Bitcoins,
but they're still traceable by a decent forensics expert.
In fact, Damon McCoy, who spoke earlier,
has done some excellent work in this area.
I highly suggest some of the papers
that he's written in tracing Bitcoins.
So, they can't just open up a Bitcoin exchange account
with Coinbase or Xapo or Circle.
All of these now comply with anti-money-laundering
and "know your customer" laws.
They require extensive background and identity checks.
So, if they can't verify their own identities,
how do they set up an exchange?
They can use somebody else's.
After all, in the United States,
somebody's identity is stolen every two seconds.
$16 billion worth of identity fraud
has affected almost 13 million people since 2014.
Since 2005, there have been about 5,700 breaches
of unencrypted personal information.
And within this, there has been
about 855 million of these records stolen.
So, naturally, what this means
is that back in the darknet markets,
there is a plethora of affordable listings
for something called fullz --
f-u-l-l-z.
One set of fullz costs between 10 and 20 bucks.
And what you get out of it is a pile of personal information
for somebody else,
things like Social Security number,
mother's maiden name, date of birth,
their physical-address history,
phone-number history, and more.
Okay, so, now they're on their way,
but they can't quite pass a hard-core I.D. verification.
What do they need for that?
Well, they need not fret because, on the darknet,
lots of vendors also sell
expertly and custom-doctored scans
of passports, I.D. cards, and utility bills.
So, with the fullz and the forged documents,
they stand a good chance of passing
a rather rigorous I.D.-verification system.
So, now they'll need a bank account to attach
to their Bitcoin-exchange service.
They can head back to the darknet markets,
and there, there are vendors that actually sell
pre-made bank drops just for this.
But most of the guide suggested you make
your own clean bank account.
That way, you control it, and you know its history.
Many different financial institutions
will allow these crooks to set up these new accounts
all online, all from their home,
and just using the same information
that they got from the fullz.
Now, when you're paying for a guide
on how to set up these bank accounts,
what you're actually typically paying for is a walk-through
on what to expect for certain banks
and what sort of challenges you'll come up against
and how best to pass them.
They'll also need a new phone number to do this.
So, here, the suggestion is to get a burner phone
with exchangeable SIMs.
And on top of that, it's often suggested
to not use the SIM number directly,
but to attach it to another phone number,
a VoiP number like Google Voice.
Now, if they don't want to go through the process of verifying
and setting up a Google account, the darknet markets also sell
pre-set-up Google Voice accounts.
So, they've got their exchange account set up,
and they've got their clean bank account set up.
Time to cash out some Bitcoins.
How do they actually get the cash out of the bank account?
So, here there are guides for getting the ATM card
without getting caught and how to securely get that
by avoiding cameras.
There's also guides for wiring to Western Union, MoneyGram,
Ria, those sort of services, using an alias.
Or they can just keep it online, and what they can do
is they can set up a PayPal or Google Wallet account
with the identity that they've already stolen.
Those, of course, were not the only cash-out methods
that I ran into.
There are vendors who will ship you silver and gold
in exchange for Bitcoins,
though it's at a hefty premium, as you would imagine.
There are vendors who will go ahead
and sell you a bunch --
like, I'm talking a huge stack --
of stolen gift cards, and it's usually at at discount.
And what you can do is turn around and sell
those stolen gift cards
to legitimate gift-card buyback services
like Gift Card Granny or Raise.com.
That way, you're then being paid by that website.
There were cash-out techniques
for setting up two accounts
on freelance sites
like Fiverr, Guru,
or Upwork, something like that.
What you would do is you would set up an account
as a servicer,
an account as someone who needs a service.
You would act as both parties
and transfer the money using the website
and then get paid out through the website.
There were other methods involving setting up
bogus projects on crowdfunding websites.
Some of these crowdfunding websites,
conveniently enough, took Bitcoin directly.
So that made it easier.
There's also a way to cash out using things
like Vanilla, MoneyPak.
These are prepaid cards that are typically anonymous.
And what you can do is you can buy those from darknet vendors
that have set them up using other identities.
There are also some interesting methods
that involve using a gambling or bookmaker site.
What you'll do is you'll transfer your funds
into the gambling site.
You'll do a bit of low-risk gambling.
You might lose a little bit, but not much.
And then after a little while,
you cash out into a different currency.
A lot of these sites will also send you a check,
or they'll ship you prepaid cards.
There's also some rather skeevy ways
that you can set up a charity.
There are even guides for getting your 501(c)(3)
to look legitimate and set up your own charity
that's connected to something like a network for good
or a GiveWell account.
That way, you can receive funds into your charity.
And they give you the guide
to actually get other people to give you money,
as well as launder your own money.
Those ones felt rather slimy.
There were more almost legitimate-looking guides
for setting up your own shell business
and then connecting it to something like Square,
Flint, Stripe, or Spark Pay,
and then funneling funds through that.
If you didn't want to go through the process
of setting up a whole new corporation,
there are people on the darknet
who will sell you an aged, off-the-shelf shell corporation.
So, all of these methods seemed rather convoluted,
and I could see different areas in them,
no matter what they promised,
where you could easily get popped.
The easiest and most straightforward methods
that I saw, though, involved just using LocalBitcoins.
On LocalBitcoins, you can convert Bitcoins
directly into gift cards, prepaid, or reloadable cards,
postal orders, cash.
There are also options for wire transfers, PayPal,
Google Wallet, and Square transfers.
These can be done in person,
or they can be done completely online,
even the wire transfers.
Oh, and if any of these cybercriminals end up finding
that they need to get a custom, physical I.D. card
for any of their plans,
they actually don't need to go back to the darknet.
They can just get those from Reddit.
So, with all of these cash-out methods,
there's also, as mentioned before,
the option to deal in real, tangible,
physical goods.
If you're dealing with rewards points
and e-gift cards instead of dealing
with stolen credit cards,
you don't have to worry about the charge-backs
or credit-card-fraud investigations.
You do, however, have to deal with shipping
and finding a way to receive these goods.
Well, on the darknet markets,
there are shipping-label services
that will help you out with that.
There are also mini guides
on how to safely set up shipping drops.
Many of these guides suggest not dealing
with actual humans as drops,
but to seek out houses where folks are on vacation
or the house or business is recently vacated
or even how to set up
a series of P.O. boxes using other identities.
There was also a lot of advice for spotting
and dealing with controlled deliveries.
Now, what a controlled delivery is --
it's when law enforcement will act as the postal carrier
or the deliverer and will deliver the box,
wait for you to sign it, and then slap on the cuffs.
So, I did run across a clever method
for straight-up bypassing all of the hassle of dealing
with these reshipping schemes.
It was a play on the old eBay triangulation fraud.
Here's how it works.
An e-commerce customer would place an order
with an individual offering to sell a luxury good,
typically through eBay, through Amazon.com,
through Alibaba, something like that.
And what they would do is, the seller of the good
doesn't actually have the purchased item in stock.
They would go ahead and change the shipping address
on a hacked rewards account to the customer,
and then they would go into the rewards store
that is a legitimate rewards store,
and use those stolen points
to buy what the original customer ordered,
and then they would ship it to that customer
through that account.
Now, the customer actually gets what they ordered.
It seems legit to them.
But what happens when an investigation starts?
Who do you think becomes the main suspect?
Not the fraudulent seller.
Their information wasn't involved
anywhere in the process.
It's the customer that received the item
that thought it was legitimate.
They're the one that becomes the target of the investigation.
So, as you can see,
rewards-fraud business is booming, and it pays.
I expect we will be seeing more of these attacks in 2016
and witness another expansion of the criminal markets
for these goods.
Going forward, I want to start expanding my scope of research
to look at forums, IRC, and Jabber.
I also want to look at these trends over time
and start doing analysis.
This, coupled with looking at how different attacks
are evolving in these spaces,
will be very interesting
and will help us to be more proactive in the ways
in which we deal with these attackers.
I also want to look at how to actually do
a market valuation in U.S. dollars for these markets.
With miles, vouchers, and e-gift cards,
it's pretty easy to tell how much they're worth,
but rewards points don't technically have
a monetary value.
This is something
that the cybercriminals are counting on
because if it doesn't have a technical monetary value,
chances of a fraud investigation are much lower.
This is an interesting and ever-evolving area
that calls for much more investigation and research.
Thank you for your time, and I would like to take
some questions and comments from the audience.