-Thank you for the introduction.
I'm here to talk about reshipping mule scam.
And this is somewhat related to what you have just listened to.
And funny enough, Brian Krebs is one of the authors
of this work with me and other people.
So, I want to talk a little bit about financial data.
Cybercriminals are out to get us,
and one thing that they're really fond of
is our financial information,
usually debit-card information, credit-card information,
anything that can be turned into a purchase.
And they do this by,
for example, performing large-scale breaches,
those that go in the front pages of The New York Times,
like Home Depot and Target.
But there are also many, many small breaches
that are never disclosed,
sometimes because they're not disclosed,
sometimes because they're not even detected.
In addition to that, there is also
a very active community of fishers
that are out on the Internet,
try to trick users
into volunteering their own information,
and this is another source of this financial information.
Finally, we have malware.
There are specific families of malware whose only goal
is to sit on your computer,
wait until you go to an e-commerce site or to a bank,
and collect your personal information
and send it somewhere,
wherever the bot herder is located.
And actually, a few years ago,
me and my team captured one of these botnets.
We were able to sort of leverage a little mistake
that one of these cybercriminals made,
and we were able to control this botnet
and collect information
that normally would be sent to the cybercriminal.
We collected more than 60 gigabyte
of personal information,
log-in to website, credit-card information,
banking information.
And we published a study
on how much could be made with all this data.
And we found out that it was quite a bit.
But then, we went on and said,
"Okay, now you have this financial data in your hand.
You're a cybercriminal.
How do you turn this into real money
or into real goods?"
You need to have that,
because, otherwise, information is just information.
So, how to monetize this?
How to monetize credit-card information?
That's not so easy.
Once upon a time, it was easy.
You can just take the financial data, find a way
to transfer some money into a bank account,
or, for example, clone a debit card
and physically go to the ATM machine
and start getting cash out.
That's awesome.
This guy seems to be very happy.
Of course, this doesn't work for a number of reasons,
mostly because you have to be present in front of an ATM.
And, in fact, what you see here is Albert Gonzalez,
one of the most notorious cybercriminals of this kind.
And, interestingly enough, he was responsible
for some of the largest financial breaches
in the history of the Internet,
but he was caught, because, around midnight,
he was in front of an ATM, putting one card,
another card, another card, another card, another card.
Around midnight, because at midnight,
they will cycle the limit for a certain card.
So he could extract twice as much the money.
It didn't help that he was wearing a female wig at the time
to avoid being recognized by the cameras.
And a cop noticed the suspicious guy
and apprehended him.
Another way to monetize, then, is to use money mules.
So, their way to recruit people --
So, they will go on your behalf at the ATM,
extract the money, the physical money,
and go to Western Union, for example,
and ship the money to the Ukraine.
Of course, the bank soon got into this
and are very good at identifying these type of accounts,
and they shut them down very, very fast.
Then they decided, "Okay, we cannot make cash.
Let's buy goods."
So the next step was, "Let's buy very expensive objects
that I can buy on Amazon,
and let's ship them," for example, "to Ukraine."
There is a war there. You cannot really ship weapons.
But, you know, this is a rifle infrared scope.
This costs around, you know,
five times more than the rifle itself.
So, it's very useful to be able to buy these goods
and then buy a cheap rifle somewhere else.
Of course, merchants realized that this was
the source of a lot of fraud,
and decided to stop the purchase --
or the shipping, to be more precise --
of these kind of goods to the outside world.
Oops.
Okay.
Sorry, this is the wonderful Hyatt network.
So, of course, the idea is now, "Let's do a reshipping scam.
Let's use the same model that we used for financial data.
So, let's recruit people
and have them ship these goods for us."
And this is something that has been going for a while,
and, in fact, there are several documentations,
several warnings from the government saying,
"Please do not fall for this scam."
So, it's a known scam. So, what is our work?
Our work was focused
on analyzing the largest amount of real hard data
that was ever collected on this type of operation.
We stumbled upon a huge amount of information
that described the internals
of how reshipping scams are carried out.
And we decided, as scientists, "Hey, let's understand this.
Let's measure it.
Let's see how the different actors interact with each other.
And maybe we can find a way
to actually intervene in these operations
in a way that is effective" -- sort of similar
to what Damon did with credit-card processors.
And so, what are the actors?
The actors here are, of course, the drop --
we'll see, is the person
that is actually asked to reship the goods --
the cardholder, a reshipping scam site,
somebody that we call the stuffer,
which is the guy who actually have to move these goods,
and the merchant that is the target of the fraud.
So, the first thing that happens
is the reshipping scam site --
the site's to publish a job ad.
And you have seen these ads.
It's like, "Work from home. Make a ton of money.
You don't have to do pretty much anything.
You will be one of our fantastic employees
that are able to do $4,000 working one hour a day."
And my wife, for example,
used to work at a city college, in the career center,
and she was responsible for the job ads.
She would see variations of these scams daily.
And, of course, since she's my wife,
she was able to filter them correctly,
but that's not always the case.
So, you can go on Craigslist, but also on university website
and find these type of ads.
So, the next step is, one of the drop --
so, a person applies for the job,
and, you know, trying to make an extra buck.
Maybe he's a working --
it's somebody working multiple jobs.
And at this point, the stuffer then has stolen
the cardholder information by phishing,
by using breached data, and so forth --
contact the scam site and say,
"Hey, I need to ship some goods."
And say, "No problem."
The stuffer -- so, the guy who stole the credit card --
buys something at the merchant
and, as the recipient of the shipping good,
specify the drop.
So, the transaction happens.
The goods are sent to the drop.
The drop actually open the box and takes pictures.
And these are real pictures from the data
that we collected on these scams.
These are pictures that the drop sends
to the reshipping scam site, say, "Look,
I really received your PlayStation --"
I hope it's a PlayStation -- I cannot really tell --
Or "some very luxury good that I will have to reship."
They take the box away --
I mean, they take the good and put it in another box.
They obtain a new shipping label from the scammer site.
Say, "Oh, please send it to somewhere in Moscow."
They go to the USPS, and they ship the good.
The stuffer receives the good,
and then they resell the good on the black market
or even not-so-black market, as we have discovered,
making a profit, because, of course,
they bought the good with stolen credit cards.
So, it's very, very...
They can make a lot of money out of it.
So, we collected all this data through a series of sources.
Brian Krebs has some data. The FBI had some data.
An anonymous concerned citizen
dumped on us a lot of this data.
And of course, you know, being in academic research,
we had to do a lot of checks and balances.
I can detail that later.
But fundamentally, we got months and months
of real-world data, complete dumps of the databases
of the shipping-scam operation.
We had even their message logs, their bulletin-board system,
the discussion about setting up contracts
between stuffer and scam site.
And we saw a lot of logs,
a lot of actual transfer, with labels,
with full information about who was involved,
including their passports, Social Security numbers,
everything.
And so, we started looking at it and say, "Okay,
the question's like, 'How do they make this work?
How do they split the profit?
What do they really send out?
What are the type of products?
And how do they actually ship the stuff?'"
Because eventually it's the U.S. Postal Service
that moves the parcels -- and --
move the parcels from one place to another.
Sorry about that.
So, the first thing, it was pretty simple.
We found out there are two main models
of sharing profit.
If it's something really expensive,
the scam site wants a cut of it -- 50%.
If it's something not very expensive --
could be fashion or things like that --
then usually there is, you know,
sort of a fixed fee per package.
And they just set it. It's just a normal reaction.
They know that they're doing something illegal,
but, of course, this is not a blocker.
And these contracts have concepts
like customer-service level, customer satisfaction.
They promise they will monitor the performance
of their drops, the mule,
and make sure that they will pay back
in case somebody's misbehaving.
It's pretty sophisticated.
And what is actually exchanged in these type of scams?
Well, mostly, I would say tech.
And with technology, Apple products are very popular.
Video games, consoles, camera.
Like, lenses are very expensive,
and they're very small, so they're a good candidate
for this type of activity.
Also, fashion is very important, apparently especially in Russia.
We think that in part is because of the various sanctions
that created some kind of attrition for certain goods
and make them very appealing for these type of scams.
So, for example, there was a site
that was almost exclusively dedicated to Apple products.
We found another site that was more focusing...on fashion.
And as somebody from Italy, I was very moved by that.
But, in general, about 70% of the goods
goes into these two main categories.
So, the other interesting thing is,
how do they actually send a package
from one place to another?
Because there is -- the mule, the drop,
is in someplace in the United States,
receives the goods,
has to get this label to ship this thing to Russia.
And so, what they do --
Initially, they decided, "Hey, we have stolen credit cards.
Why don't we use the stolen credit cards
to buy the labels to send out the goods
that were bought with the stolen credit cards?"
Fits perfectly.
Here, these were called black labels.
They did a little bit of black-labeling,
and soon you had the post office say, "Mnh, no.
We have to check this a little more."
And so these became unavailable.
Introduce white labels.
So, immediately, this crash in the black label
created an opportunity for the cybercriminals,
who said, "Oh, there is a new service.
We can create something
that looks like we are actually a company
that buys a lot of USPS labels and then resells them.
But we're gonna buy all these labels
using legitimate money -- or legitimate-looking money --
so it looks like we are just intermediaries
and we're selling labels
to people that need them at a lower price."
And the difference is that, actually, while black labels
were outrageously less expensive than USPS,
white labels are just a little bit less expensive
than actual USPS labels.
Another thing that is important is that a lot of the labeling
can depend on the type of goods that you are declaring.
And as part of the scam,
the cybercriminal declares something slightly different
for the package than what's really inside.
For example, they might say that it's a used camera,
while instead it's a perfectly brand-new camera.
And so we did, actually,
an analysis on the distribution and cost of the labels.
And for sites that had high-value goods,
where the cut was sort of like somewhat proportional,
we can see that the distribution of the label
tends to be more linear,
while, for others -- we'll see for the blue and black here --
it's more around -- you know,
it's more sort of an almost fixed price.
And we find out that the white labels
were around $100 per package.
So, they have a good thing going on.
So, we started looking at,
who is sort of like the victim in this scam?
Who's losing money?
And how much money is actually in this type of scam?
In terms of the victims, we look at the main victim.
I would say the main victim is the merchant
because, of course, they lose the goods.
It's very difficult to return the goods to the merchant.
And also the drop that, as we will see,
is left with no payment
and sometimes is even the victim of identity fraud.
And this is really terrible.
These people are oftentimes people in need of extra money.
They apply for this job somewhat in a state of desperation.
They never get paid,
and eventually they use the information they collected
when they set up their job, their account,
to actually steal their information, their identity.
Sorry.
Other victims, however, are not to be left out.
The cardholder has to go through the hassle
of reverting charges and things like that.
The card issuer, of course, also is affected,
and the destination country of the goods,
because, oftentimes, certain taxes
cannot be applied exactly because of this.
So, how big is the market?
We had so much data,
they could actually plot and interpolate
how many packages were sent.
And we could determine
sort of like the trend of these different websites.
And we did an analysis of how many packages
were sent each year by interpolating the data.
We looked at the cost of the median packages,
and we identified that each of these sites
was doing, more or less, $7 million of revenue per year.
But how big is the market?
Well, in order to understand that,
we had to understand how many cardholders
are out there.
And we did this using a capture/recapture mechanism.
This is something that biologists do
to determine a population.
They got a group of people. They tag -- a group of animals.
They tag them. They send them in the wild.
They get another group of animals,
and they see how much intersection
between these two sets there was.
So, we use as this two of the members of the two sites
that -- two of the sites that we had,
and we estimated in a conservative way
that we had 1.6 million victims,
for a total of $1.8 billion per year
for this type of scam alone.
We also look at how drops were recruited.
We found out, very interestingly --
and somewhat unsurprisingly,
since we had already anecdotal evidence --
that people are hired, used, and then thrown away
exactly when they are supposed to be paid.
And we had even the messages from the forums
that say, "Hey, where's my check?"
And that was the last time
that that particular person, the particular mule,
was actually contacted.
So, people think that these scams work.
Well, they work for the cybercriminal,
but they don't work for the mules,
that are left without any pay.
In terms of where are the mules, well, we did an analysis.
We found some kind of correlation
with higher-than-normal unemployment.
And this is normal and expected,
as this type of scam actually obviously tried
to target people in need,
people that are looking for an extra buck
because maybe our, you know, depressed economy.
So, what are we gonna do about this?
There are several intervention approaches.
One first round, interestingly enough,
is tracking who is tracking,
meaning that, why somebody from Russia
is going to the USPS tracking website,
do reload, reload, reload, reload
to find out where the package has been moved
at this point in time.
And if we can identify, use patterns
of who's accessing this information,
in order to identify an anomalous situation,
we can at least track the package
even before it is reshipped.
Another thing that we can do
is to do analysis of the shipping labels --
why a certain account from one guy
is used to pay for shipping
that goes from many different guys
to the same guy in Russia?
There are many patterns
that can show that this is actually fraudulent.
And, finally, we can use destination
as a target for this.
And our analysis show that
the vast majority of the packages go to Moscow.
Of course, this is not a single signal that can be used,
but it's obvious that, you know, 85% of the goods
that are shipped with this scam are out there.
So, what are our conclusions?
This is a big scam,
and that's why, for example, the FBI was interested
in collaborating with us
in trying to map and understand how this was carried out.
But we need something new.
We need a new way
to use network information and graphs
that represent how the different actors
and objects being shipped interact with each other
in order to be able to do an effective job
at stopping this type of scam.
Unfortunately, this information is spread
is so many different places.
There is the United States Postal Service.
There is the FBI.
There are, you know, the IRS.
There are the credit-card processors.
There's the prepaid-card processors.
There are the merchants.
And it is very difficult
to have all these people work together
in order to identify, in a clear way,
who are the cybercriminals in action.
This is not just my work.
It's work with many people,
including Mike Eubanks from the FBI
and Brian Krebs, who provided us with some of the data.
And with this, I'm ready for some questions.
[ Applause ]