ZHU: Hi, everyone.
So, I'm Yan, and this is Peter.
We both work at The Electronic
Frontier Foundation,
although I'm
a mere lowly technology fellow,
and Peter is the chief
computer scientist.
So, today,
we're gonna be telling you
some scary bedtime stories
about the encrypted web
and how Let's Encrypt
is helping make things better.
So, how many people here
have heard of Let's Encrypt.
I barely see anyone whose hand
isn't up, which is great.
ECKERSLEY: How many people
have used it?
ZHU: How many people
ECKERSLEY: A few of you.
ZHU: Fewer. Cool.
So, horror story
number one, I'm sure,
is familiar to everyone here.
It's that we don't yet
in a 100% HTTPS world.
In fact,
a few years ago,
when I logged into Quora,
which, at the point, had like
10 million users or something,
they were sending my passwords
over plaintext.
Oh, man.
Yeah, everyone boo them,
and then I didn't
use it since 2014.
But I did check,
and it's fixed now, right?
So, but some sites
are not Quora, right?
They don't have
engineering staff.
And so, if you're
a small website operator,
setting up TLS
today is still tedious.
Just to give you an example,
this is a screenshot
from the DreamHost Wiki
on how to set up HTTPS.
They've actually made
this process
a lot easier recently
by integrating Let's Encrypt,
but before that, you had
to go through this,
like, 12- or 14-step process
and make sure you weren't
accidentally copying
and pasting your private key
into your web browser,
et cetera, and a lot of people
do mess that up.
So, let's assume you've
got a cert finally, right?
Then you might find
that TLS configuration
is really confusing.
So, as cryptanal--
cryptana--
ugh, cryptanalysis gets better,
you know, we discover algorithms
like RC4 are no longer secure.
People like Nick Sullivan
at CloudFlare
write these great posts
that are like,
"Hey, server operators,
it's time to turn off RC4."
And unless you're keeping up
to date
with the latest
TLS best practices,
you may not realize that your
server is now vulnerable to --
ECKERSLEY: Right, we can't all
be hitting "refresh"
on Nick Sullivan's blog
every day.
ZHU: Yeah, although I do,
so, you know, it's -- Yeah.
So, and, you know,
and, similarly SHA-1 is being
deprecated by browsers,
and so you have to go
and make sure
you get a SHA-256 cert chain,
and all that.
But this is solvable, right?
Like, what if we could all just
use good TLS configurations?
And this --
this is actually a problem
we'll talk about
how Let's Encrypt is solving,
but, basically, there's --
you know, there's books
you can go out and find,
and there's wikis about, like,
the best TLS configurations
at any time.
So, what if you could just push
that to all the clients
who need to upgrade
and so forth?
Okay, so, let's assume
now you've set up TLS,
and finally you're ready
to switch your site
over to HTTPS.
You type in
"nginx -s reload,"
et cetera,
and you go to your site,
and it's horribly broken because
of mixed-content blocking.
Mixed-content blocking is
where you've switched
your top-level site, Lenovo.com,
over to HTTPS,
but you're loading these images
and scripts and iframes
and all these ads
and other resources over HTTP
because those sites
don't yet support HTTPS.
So, the browser's like, "No,
we're in a secure mode.
We don't want to,
like, pollute
that with insecure HTTP,
so we're just gonna block
those HTTP resources."
So, as a result,
scripts aren't running 'cause
those are getting blocked,
and your site just
looks completely broken.
This is actually
a very large reason
that new sites aren't able
to switch to HTTPS,
because they're using
ad networks
that don't support HTTPS yet.
So, last year, the W3C said,
"We're gonna fix this.
Well, we're gonna try
to fix this
by adding in
a new content security policy,
HTTP Header.
So, for those of you
who aren't familiar,
this is just an HTTP header.
The server can say --
The server sends,
and it says, "Upgrade
and secure requests."
And when the browser
sees this,
it starts just automatically
trying
to fetch the HTTPS resources.
It still blocks them if HTTPS
isn't available,
but I actually had to use this
a few days ago
'cause I upgraded WordPress,
and my blog, just, like,
all the HTTPS links
were converted back to HTTP
by the updater somehow.
So, I freaked out, and then I
fixed it in 20 seconds
'cause I just set this header
and modern,
like, Chrome and Firefox users,
their browsers would just say,
"Oh, these resources --
we should just try
to upgrade them."
So, my blog looks amazing again.
So, and finally, I'm sure
this is a familiar story
to many,
but there are a lot
of certificate authorities
out there.
So, Peter,
how many certificate authorities
do you think there are?
ECKERSLEY: It's actually kind
of hard to tell,
but the number from a scan that
we did maybe five years ago,
late 2010,
there was something
like 1,500 certificates
that could make a --
'cause CA certificates
that could sign something
for Google.com or Facebook.com,
and your browser would trust it.
Probably controlled
by somewhere between 200
and 400 organizations,
but it was very hard to count.
ZHU: Yeah.
ECKERSLEY: So, it's time
to fight back
against the unencrypted
and insecure web.
You know,
let's gather our forces,
go out into the night,
and confront these --
these demons
that we're up against.
You know,
we decided to try
and address this
by starting a CA.
Basically, you know,
there are too many of them --
too many CAs out there.
Let's make one that's
a little bit more friendly
and use it to
do things better.
So, it's called Let's Encrypt.
It's free.
It's automated.
It's open. Both the code
and the data is open.
It's in Public Beta.
You can use it today.
It was created as the merger
of two projects.
There was a project at EFF
and the University of Michigan
and a project at Mozilla.
We joined forces.
We got a lot
of financial assistance
from Cisco and Akamai.
We got
our CA cross-signed
by an existing CA
called IdenTrust,
which means that it's compatible
with all the browsers.
And it's housed
in a new 501(c)(3)
called the Internet
Security Research Group,
or ISRG.
We've been getting
more sponsors since we launched.
This is the current list.
If you are thinking about it,
please come and sponsor ISRG.
Help us make this thing
bigger and more effective.
Now, fundamentally,
when you run a CA,
you're gonna have to make
this really important decision.
Every time a website,
a server comes along
and asks you, "Hey,
can I have a cert?"
you have to decide,
is the answer yes,
or is the answer no?
And the way we do this,
you know, looks something
like a scene from
"Monty Python and the Quest
for the Holy Grail."
We're kind of the Knights
who say "Ni."
You come along, and you say,
you know, "Can we have a cert?"
and we say,
"Mm, bring us a shrubbery."
And then you come along,
and maybe you bring us
a shrubbery,
and then we say, "Well,
bring us another shrubbery."
And the protocol
for this conversation
is called ACME.
It's a new proposed standard
at the ITF,
and the shrubberies
are called "challenges,"
and they're sort
of an extensible set of things
that a server can do to prove
that it controls a particular
domain name, and therefore,
deserves a certificate
for that domain name.
We currently support a challenge
over Port 80,
where you put up a file
at a special, well-known URL.
We support a challenge
over Port 443,
where you put up
a synthetic certificate
on a synthetic domain name
in a TLS connection.
And we support a DNS challenge
where you put a record
in your DNS entry.
We may support more challenges
in the future.
Now, this thing
launched quite recently --
private beta in November,
last year.
Public beta -- open to anyone
without a sign-up in December.
As soon as we did that,
we were starting to issue
a lot of certificates,
one cert every three seconds,
you know,
in the first little while
of public availability.
We're at close
to 400k certs now.
This is the graph.
If this keeps growing
like this,
we'll be doing
a large fraction
of the HTTPS web within a year,
and we're hoping that
the graph will actually
get steeper
as large deployments
start to integrate.
Now, some more statistics.
If you go and look at the things
we've issued in the certificate
transparency logs,
'cause we publish
all of the data about
what we're signing,
if you scan all of
those domain names,
you'll actually find that
there are 547,200 domain
names right now
that are answering with one
of these certificates --
more than the number
of certificates
because you can get a cert
that has multiple names in it.
About 85% of these names
have never spoken HTTPS before,
so we are, like,
helping a few people
who already have TLS
and a whole lot of new people
who have never been able
to do it before.
And we feel like
we're winning here.
There are also quite a lot
of certs that aren't
being served yet.
That's a combination of people
playing around with the thing,
people playing around
with automating renewal,
people taking certs
and putting them up
on SMTP servers, IMAP servers,
other kinds of mail servers
XMAP servers,
whatever you want.
You can use these certificates
for any protocol
that uses TLS and some people
who probably are not
serving a public service
on that domain name.
We're doing not too badly
on the cipher-sweep front.
If you look at the machines
that are answering connections
with the certs,
they look like they're speaking,
by and large, modern ciphers.
There's predominant forward
secrecy on these machines.
It looks like, in this place,
we're winning
against the forces of darkness.
This is, of course, forward
secrecy is super important.
If, as the snow
in Revelations showed,
you have
a whole bunch of adversaries
who may do things
like steal your keys,
you want to have
your connections
safe against those kinds
of attacks
or at least somewhat protected.
There's some deployment
starting to happen
inside the top Alexa domains.
We wouldn't really
have expected that at all yet.
To be honest,
we're still in beta.
We've only been out
for two months.
It's a little bit
crazy to be using us
on a really important,
high-value production service,
but we expect to actually
become less crazy
as we come out of beta
and have been able
to demonstrate good
uptime and reliability
over the next months and years.
Now, deployment
of the certificates
and getting them actually
installed
on web servers is kind
of a layered problem
for the web.
If you look at this,
we're cropped at the bottom,
but you can think of the web
as being --
sites as being a combination
of different types of hosting.
At the bottom, you have
cheap hosting,
where you don't necessarily
have a shell of any sort.
Maybe you have
a WordPress instance
that's hosted
by someone for you,
or you have an FTP upload
that you can make
to some directory somewhere,
or you have, you know,
a Facebook page
or a Tumblr page
or something that's basically
provided for you.
Then the next layer
up, you have people
who run their own servers
in some way.
Maybe they actually
have a physical server,
more commonly, perhaps a VPS
of some sort
like Amazon or DigitalOcean.
Or you can have,
you know,
managed hosting
where someone will rack a box
for you and you
run your websites on that.
Going up the stack
further, you start to get sites
that have multiple web servers
with some type of load-balancing
or round-robining around them.
Then you go up another layer,
and you hit the Googles
and the Facebooks
of the Internet --
people who have very, very large
and sophisticated
server infrastructures.
Now, it's actually kind
of a different problem,
how to get Let's Encrypt in use
in each of these layers.
We kind of want
to be used by
all of these layers
where appropriate.
But they're gonna take
different solutions.
So, we have a client
that we have been shipping.
It's basically an EFF,
an open-source project --
Let's Encrypt Python client.
We're probably gonna be,
actually, officially branding it
as an EFF thing
in the coming months.
It is intended primarily
to server
the single-server case --
people who have a Unix machine
that they can log into.
They serve a website off that.
It is capable, to some extent,
of handling
multi-web server deployments
but isn't primarily designed
for that case.
There's separate work
to be done for the people
who are in the top
and bottom tiers
of the cake,
where they basically
need to have
some operator
of those hosting platforms
implement their own version
of the ACME client
or use an ACME library
to deploy across -- You know,
at the bottom layer,
there are millions of websites
that they have there.
The top layer,
it might be
a million servers
answering for Google.com.
So, these
are all separate cases.
We have these diverse clients
speaking
the ACME protocol already.
There are over
a dozen clients out there
that you can choose from.
If you look at the ones
that are issuing,
broken down right now.
This is the last two weeks.
About 70%
of the requests
are coming from the fairly fully
featured and complicated
Python client
that we have,
and then you have a spread
of different requests coming
from these other clients.
This is really cool.
One that's
worth mentioning is Caddy.
Caddy is a web server
that has a client
for the Let's Encrypt protocol,
the ACME protocol built into it.
So, it'll just automatically
obtain a cert anytime
it's serving a domain name.
That's probably,
in the long run,
the place we want
all web servers to be,
but it's -- it'll take
three to five years
before we could imagine
an Apache or an Engine X
having that on by default
in all of the places
where it's running,
and so the Python client
is a solution
that's available in the meantime
for people who need it.
If you dive in
and say, "Okay,
within this 70%,
what does it look like?
Who are the people
who are running this?
What platforms
are they running on?"
you get
incredible diversity again.
There are over 20 operating
systems
that have significant market
shares in there,
mostly Linuxes,
but there are some BSD
and Darwin in there,
as well.
It's also worth noting --
this is kind
of a little terrifying --
but a lot of these are
really old operating systems.
You know,
Ubuntu 14 and Debian 8
not so bad,
but we have giant chunks
running Debian 7,
Ubuntu 12, CentOS 6.5 and 6.6.
Debian 6 is close
to 1% still.
It's not actually on this graph,
but it's pretty large.
And so,
we have to confront the fact
that people are running
web servers
that have old versions
of Python,
old versions of Apache,
and so we're doing
quite a lot of work
to make sure
that our code runs decently
well on all of these platforms.
It's a lot of fun.
And this Python client is sort
of a Swiss Army knife.
It's intended to be able
to run all of those platforms
and to do
an increasingly good job
of just automated,
end-to-end deployment
for all the cases
that people have.
And this is daunting,
but we're making
pretty rapid progress on it.
So, the way
it works internally is,
it has these plug-ins
that you can use.
It has two important types
that are worth talking about --
an authenticator
that's basically a thing
that produces the shrubberies
and passes the challenges
to get a certificate.
If you want to make one
of these things,
you just need to implement
the little three-function
Python interface
that I've got on the screen.
We have maybe four
or five implement--
five implementations
of that that
are pretty widely used already,
and people can make
more of them.
And the we have
the second interface
if you want to hook
a TLS server into it
and automate
installation of certs.
You can implement this
slightly longer set
of functions, which include
things like rollback.
If you've made a configuration
that tries to install a cert
and then there's a problem
with it, you've got a guarantee
that you can revert back
to the state
that you were in beforehand
so you don't break
people's servers.
It handles requests
for enhancements
like upgrading insecure requests
or STS
or redirect from HTTP to HTTPS,
all of these things.
And if you look in deployment,
what are people using?
They're actually already using
quite a lot of these plug-ins
in diverse modes.
We ship with the Apache webroot
and stand-alone and manual ones.
The Plesk one's
a third-party one
that's already -- This is data
from the last two weeks.
Thousands of people
in a two-week period
were using Plesk --
the Plesk plug-in on Ubuntu 14,
so it's getting real usage.
We have an Engine X plug-in
that's in the works.
We're not shipping it yet,
but there's a team
at ThoughtWorks that's trying
to get this into a MVP state,
and when it does,
hopefully we'll see
that popping up right up here
and will be --
The Swiss army knife is working
for all the different diverse
operating systems
and web servers that people
are trying to deploy certs on.
How well-configured are we?
You know, Yan talked about some
of the demons we confront here.
People -- I'm sure
you've seen talks earlier
in the conference
about the other things
that can go wrong.
We're not doing too badly.
The demons are here.
You can see the classic ones
like incomplete chains
or incorrect name.
So, you haven't configured
your SNI appropriately.
But these are small percentages.
By and large,
when people get a cert from us,
either our automated tools
or the configuration
instructions we give them,
these are working fairly well.
But we do have these features
we know we want to deploy,
and some automation
might get us further on these.
ZHU: Great.
So, nothing ever
ships without vulnerabilities,
as you all know.
So, Let's Encrypt,
for what it's worth
is fully open source.
So, this is the GitHub issue
tracker from Boulder,
which is the Let's Encrypt
certificate authority server
that issues
people's certificates.
So, you can see there's, like --
This isn't even
a complete list.
I know there's, like,
an issue Chris Palmer found
and some that I found
that aren't on this list,
but people
have been opening bugs.
Although, most
of these are from our own team.
So, I'll give you two examples
of security vulnerabilities
that were reported
by outside contributors.
So, the first one
was from Andrew Ayer
in last August.
So, note that this was
before we shipped,
and this was
when we were still, like,
working on making
the client usable
and revising the draft
of the ACME spec and all that.
But basically,
he found an attack
that would allow mis-issuance,
but we hadn't shipped then,
so we actually
fixed this before shipping.
Basically, how it works is
that an attacker,
which we'll call
Mallory, wants to --
wants to get a certificate
for example.com, and she says,
"I'm gonna do that via
the DNS challenge."
You know, that's the shrubbery,
is you have to put something
in DNS that proves
you own the domain.
So, she goes
through this protocol
where she registers
an RSA key pair
with Let's Encrypt
to sign the challenges
that Let's Encrypt
gives back to her.
So, Let's Encrypt's
like, "Here is your shrub--
Here is your DNS challenge.
Go get a shrubbery."
And then so,
in this situation,
example.com had already used
Let's Encrypt via --
with the DNS challenge.
So, example.com
had provisioned
a DNS TXT record
with its own challenges
to get a certificate.
So, what Mallory --
Mallory does something
very clever
in step four,
where she goes to example.com
and gets example.com's
TXT record,
and she constructs an RSA key
such that she can make --
she can make the thing
in three a valid signature
of the challenge she was issued.
I'll go --
I'll explain this a little
better the next slide,
but basically,
once she's constructed
that special malicious
RSA key pair in four,
she says, "Hey,
Let's Encrypt,
I've actually lost
my original account key.
Can you use this new key?"
And Let's Encrypt's
like, "Okay, cool,"
and then Let's Encrypt
goes to example.com
and checks
that that DNS thing
is a valid signature
with the key
that Mallory just gave her.
That was a mouthful.
But...
So, this was really clever.
It was, like, a series
of really cool tricks
that led to mis-issuance.
That was kind of subtle.
But as Andrew points out,
there's a fundamental problem,
which is that we had
been assuming
that a signature uniquely
identifies a public key,
message tuple,
but that's not mathematically
a guarantee of RSA.
So, this was fixed
in September by,
I think this was Richard Barnes.
We decided, okay, why are we
even putting signatures?
Like, we can just put
the challenge token
in DNS directly with
the public key of the user.
Right?
So, the first vulnerability
that we got
and that was reported
in production was in December,
so this was
shortly after we went live
and public beta.
But someone basically found
that we weren't really checking
CAA records,
which can say,
like, you know,
"The domain owner only
wants to be issued certificates
by certain CAs."
So,
because of this,
we had mis-issued
six certificates,
but this was fixed.
It was reported at like
10:00 AM,
and it was fixed by 1:00 PM
on the same day.
But, yeah,
it's an ongoing process.
We've actively worked
to address these things.
So, what haven't we solved yet?
ECKERSLEY: So, one problem
we talked about before
that we haven't solved yet,
unfortunately, is mixed content.
There is this "upgrade-
insecure-requests" header
that we were hoping was going
to be the magic cross
you could hold up
against mixed-content problems,
maybe not in all cases
but in the cases
where there was some way
of getting to the resource.
If it was
a script, this would help.
The problem is,
it does help for JavaScript,
but it actually
is hurting us for images.
So, right now in a browser,
by default,
if you're HTTPS,
the scripts will get blocked
if they're HTTP.
The images will be let
through as kind of a like, well,
it's not great
that they're HTTP,
but the images can't actually
steal your password
and post it to some other URL,
so we'll let them in.
This header
as it's kind of been deployed
is fixing the JavaScript problem
but actually blocking
a bunch of your images
if they happen
to not be upgradable.
So, you wind up --
There's a demo
at this URL
where, without the header,
everything looks fine.
With the header,
you fix the JavaScript,
but you break the images.
So, we're gonna work on trying
to get this fixed at the W3C.
The other thing
that we can do
is potentially use
some kind of CSP
reporting mechanism
to generate a data set
for site administrators saying,
"Hey, here's all the --
all the pages on your website
where you have some kind
of mixed-content problem.
Here's, maybe in some cases,
a way to fix them
using HTTPS everywhere rules."
The problem is,
this header exists,
the technology's out there,
but we need to have a web server
somewhere that collects all
of the reports
for all of the mixed content
that's being audited,
and doing that
in a privacy-friendly
and scalable way
and giving people
the reports they need
is going to be tricky.
So this is stuff we're gonna be
working on in the coming months.
If you'd like to help,
you can help us
with the spec,
with this Python client,
the fully featured one
or any of the alternatives
if you want a simpler,
smaller one.
And the server code,
it's all open source.
Come and get hacking with us.