[ Applause ]
-Good morning.
Is this thing on?
Can you hear me?
Excellent.
That is good.
I didn't sleep tonight.
I'm super unprepared.
I'm probably gonna do overtime.
I'm not a native speaker.
I have no idea about the topic.
But I hope the topic's
gonna be fun, so let's see
where we can go with this.
I want to talk
about toStaticHTML for everyone.
That sounds a bit cryptic,
and probably not too many people
in the room might know
what this is about.
So, that's a little bit
of a story.
This is Alice.
She's like a superstar
in crypto papers,
so everybody knows her.
And she wants to write
an encrypted message
and send it to Bob.
And this is Bob.
He wants to receive that
encrypted message from Alice,
and it's gonna be
about NASCAR or some stuff.
So, this is a bit weird.
You don't have to be ashamed
about these things,
but you could consider
that already privacy-sensitive.
So, what the two want to
is they want to exchange
encrypted mails with each other.
But they're not
too super tech-savvy,
so they don't want to install,
like, Thunderbird
and connect all their connects
and do these things
and set up Enigmail and whatnot.
So, they want to have
a comfortable solution
that even works
on the mobile phone
and on the road.
And they decided
to use ElectronMail.
I guess you all know
what I'm referring to.
So, if not, Google it out
or Bing it out.
It's a fancy tool
that allows to encrypt
and decrypt mail messages
right in the browser.
So, they can log
into a web interface,
receive the e-mail,
and it's encrypted,
and they decrypt it
and it shows in the browser,
which is pretty cool.
So, that's a great software.
And it makes sure that no one
can read that message
that the two are exchanging
unless they have the proper key,
which is a good thing.
I guess we all know
the principle behind that,
and the only way
to actually crack the code
and get access
to those messages and plaintext
is pretty much
if you're very, very,
very good at mathematics.
And the approach
that is being chosen here
has often been referred to
as end-to-end encryption.
So, Alice encrypts something,
sends it out as encrypted text.
Bob receives this, decrypts it,
and then he can read it.
And that's pretty awesome.
And he can even reply.
So, end-to-end, E-to-E,
or however you want to call it.
So, from a technical standpoint,
that is very easy to explain.
However, something happens.
The story has a twist.
It actually has
a bunch of twists,
but this is the first twist.
The next day,
both Alice and Bob
receive a message
from Mallory, malicious Mallory.
And they both open that mail,
and -- boom --
the account gets compromised.
And they don't even notice.
Happening inside the browser,
not in the browser core,
but in the HTML
and in the JavaScript.
They're like,
"How is that even possible?"
Well, the interesting thing
here is that Mallory herself
gets access to all the e-mails
that Bob and Alice have been
exchanging in the past.
She also gets access
to their private keys.
to all the contacts
in Alice's and Bob's
address book.
And she installs a keylogger
because, just in case,
you never know.
And this attack
really happened
and it is possible
and was demonstrated
by a fellow researcher
that I know in a presentation
given in France
on Hack in Paris last year.
Now, the question is,
how's that possible?
We mentioned already that
if you want to crack the code
and if you want to get access
to the plaintext
off that message,
you have to be
really good at math.
Mallory isn't
that strong at math.
I'm not, either,
so that's not a bad thing.
And she doesn't really
know too much
about buffer overflows
or use-after-frees
or all those fancy things
that Ben was talking about.
She has no idea about these
things, and I don't, either.
And she's further
not in possession
of a vast attack infrastructure.
So she doesn't have a bunch
of number crunchers or GPUs
or whatever setup
that would be helpful
in actually brute-forcing
or cracking
that code, getting access
to the messages and plaintext
and then even moving beyond.
She can't do that.
But how did she do it?
Well, she's pretty good at HTML.
I'm also pretty good at HTML.
She's also pretty good
at JavaScript.
And I would go as far
and say that HTML and JavaScript
are pretty much the modern
cybercrime action pack
because you can do
whatever you want with it,
as long as it's happening
in the browser
or something browser-like.
So, what Mallory
was doing here --
she was using
a cross-site scripting attack.
Who here knows
what cross-site scripting is?
Almost everybody.
If you don't know, look it up.
It's super fascinating.
It's not boring.
So, what she did --
she was using
a cross-site scripting bug,
in short, XSS.
And she managed to smuggle
executable client-side code --
HTML and JavaScript --
into the message
she sent out to Bob and Alice.
And this code executes
in the DOM,
in the Document Object Model
used by ElectronMail right
in the browser.
And that's a bad thing
because that is
the same platform
where Alice and Bob
are acting on,
in the browser, in that DOM,
on that page that has been
loaded on that URL.
So, Mallory can do pretty much
whatever she wants there.
She can pretty much impersonate
those two perfectly well.
It was pretty hard to do
these things, these kinds
of cross-site scripting attacks
in the past
because in the past,
before the dawn
of cryptography in the browser,
servers had the possibility
of sneak a peek into that mail,
have a look at the HTML
that was being sent around,
have a look at the attachments
that were being sent around,
and sanitize them, scrub out
all the bad stuff,
leave only the good,
and then everything is fine.
So, there was
a server-side filter,
a server-side sanitizer
through which the HTML
had to go before being
shown in the browser.
But the bad thing is right now
that is not possible anymore.
So, the server
cannot see these things anymore
because the HTML
that is part of the message
is being encrypted.
So, the server has no clue
what is going on.
So, this old
protection mechanism
that we used to rely on
and still rely on today
doesn't work anymore because
the server only sees garbage.
The first time
when the HTML actually unfolds
is when it's being decrypted,
and that sucks.
So, goddamn encryption.
We need to end this, right?
It should be forbidden
or regulated or back-doored.
Well, maybe not.
Maybe there is something else
that we can do.
I hope there is something else
we can do.
The initial problem
that we want to isolate here
before having, like,
a more advanced look
at what other problems
might be lurking in that space
is we cannot filter,
we cannot sanitize
on the server no longer.
It's not possible
because the server
has no idea
what is going on.
So, what we have to do
is we have to sanitize
on the client itself.
So, we have to do it
inside the browser.
Sounds easy, right?
Just, like,
use some prepared function
that is offered by the browser
that says, like, "Hey,
clean that chunk of HTML
for me and do
something good with it."
Should be easy, right?
Well, one would assume
the browsers
give us tools for that
and that those tools
are really mature
and have been existing for years
because that's, like,
a super-common problem,
sanitizing HTML
in the browser directly.
But unfortunately that
is not the case.
These tools
do not exist, not at all.
Well, we have a lot
of security tools,
and you might be jumping up
right now and saying, like,
"Well, we have
all those amazing things
that have been invented
in the past years.
We have sandboxed iframes.
We have CSP.
We have HTTP-only cookies.
We have cross-site scripting
filters
that I installed in browsers
and detect attacks.
We have web workers
to isolate stuff.
We have the same-origin policy,
that ancient thing.
We have Subresource Integrity
to make sure
that no malicious JavaScript
from a compromised server
can come in.
There are so many things.
And last but not least,
the biggest thing that we have
is the Content Security Policy,
that policy that controls
what kind of script can execute
and what kind of script cannot."
And Mallory
would have a hard time
to get something
in if CSP's working there.
However,
all those technologies
are not really perfect
for that particular use case.
They're all quite nice,
and if you intersect
and overlap them nicely,
then you might be lucky
and it might just work.
But if just one
of them is broken
or just like one of them
is slightly damaged,
the solution
is not usable anymore.
I've been researching CSP
for quite some time,
and you don't want to know
how many bypasses I've found
and reported
to the browser vendors.
So, we cannot fully rely on CSP.
We can't also fully rely
on sandbox iframes.
There is not too many things
we can fully rely on.
And this particular use case
we have here --
sanitizing HTML
in the browser --
is not covered,
and we need it.
So, we need to have that.
We need to get that.
We need to kind
of be able to do that.
And I saw the need.
And I remembered that there was
something like that in the past.
It's what's called toStaticHTML,
and toStaticHTML was
an interesting artifact
because toStaticHTML,
contrary to many other things
in the browser, is nonstandard.
So, someone just, like,
came up with the idea,
the same idea
in the past, said,
like, "Yeah, we need
this kind of function
that is globally available
and we feed it some HTML
and what comes out
is like non-dangerous HTML
that cannot execute
any scripts."
And the only
browser you would find
this magic function in
was Internet Explorer.
And I think it started
with IE8, 9, then in 10,
then they have it still in 11.
And then they killed it
in Edge because they were like,
"Ah. No one uses this any more."
So, too bad.
We can only use it in IE.
We can't even use it
in Edge anymore
because it's nonstandard.
No one ever took the work
of writing down
what it really does.
There was no configurability.
There was physically nothing --
It was, like, throw in a string,
get another string out,
and hopefully everything
is fine.
I contacted with Microsoft
for a bunch of years,
and we also pen-tested
toStaticHTML,
and guess what happened.
We bypassed it.
It had to be fixed.
We bypassed it again.
It had to be fixed, and so on.
So, that was not perfect.
If you run Firefox
with no script,
you also get toStaticHTML.
But it's following
completely different rules
and did a good job
in implementing something
that is fairly safe,
but you don't want to use it.
I mean, no other browser has it.
Either just IE or Firefox
with a very specific plug-in.
So, there is no good reliability
that you will actually
find this thing.
But we need something like that.
So I decided to build it
because why not?
It was actually the project part
that was following
my PhD thesis,
where I was trying to fight XSS
and actually defeat XSS
and almost made it,
but that project was missing.
So I created a library,
and that library
is called DOMPurify.
And it does
exactly what I was describing,
only that it's like nice
and configurable
and you can throw HTML in
and you can throw MathML in,
you can throw SVG in,
and whatever you want.
It takes that.
It puts that in a virtual
isolated DOM,
iterates over everything,
sanitizes the trees,
the branches,
and the leaves,
and then gives back
another string or an object,
depending on how
your configuration looks like,
and that is then sane.
It's quite good.
Throws out the bad,
leaves in the good, returns
a sane string,
and you can work
with that thing.
It's open-source.
It's free.
We have,
like, super permissive license.
I thought at the first time
when I started
implementing this thing,
that it would be an easy task --
just create a virtual DOM.
Just iterate over the branches.
Iterate it over
all that stuff and sanitize it.
But that wasn't true.
So the DOM
was a huge mess.
Like, it's absolutely
almost impossible
to kind of know in advance
what kind of death traps
the DOM has for you
because there are
so many weird stuff
going on independently
of the browser.
There's weird stuff in Chrome.
There's very weird stuff in IE.
There's pretty damn
weird stuff in Firefox.
And, well, guess what --
other browsers also have
weird stuff, as well.
And these weirdnesses,
these artifacts on the DOM,
always shoot us in the foot
because,
effectively, they
created bypasses,
so we had to work
around these bypasses
and these weirdnesses and kind
of create something
that we could trust
in the DOM as a sanitizer.
I notice that there is not
Donald Trump emoji again.
I wanted to the entire
presentation as emoji,
but not yet.
We will see.
Anyhow, we believe to have
solved all those problems
in the DOM,
all those weirdnesses.
We've maybe, hopefully,
detected all of them
and worked around them.
And we're actually quite happy
because we haven't received
any bypasses for months,
despite even generous
bug bounties
that we give out thanks
to a bunch of amazing partners,
like, for example, FastMail,
that said, "When you find a bug
in DOMPurify,
you will get big cash,"
which is quite nice,
and this is as far as we can go.
So, we have unit tests.
We have C.I.
We have good coverage.
We have bug bounty.
This is all open-source.
It has permissive licenses.
And it's really great.
You should all use it, right?
Many websites
are actually already using it.
In Germany,
we have this failed project,
but it still exists,
that is kind
of a government-approved
e-mail system,
where you can do
your taxes with.
Like, nobody uses it,
and that's okay.
And they call it De-Mail.
And they have
the very same problem
because they recently
implemented E-to-E,
end-to-end encryption,
and guess what,
they have the same problem.
They also realized that,
"Oh, darn,
uh, what do we do with
that markup that is encrypted?
That's really bad."
And we had
a cross-site scripting.
We even had
remote code execution
because it was using
the extension
that is called Mailvelope,
and there we had an RCE because
it was running in an extension.
And when you run JavaScript
in an extension
that you can control
as an attacker, you have RCE.
So, they're using DOMPurify.
And they're good with it.
They're fine with it.
And I would estimate,
without being,
like, too bold
that there's a couple
of hundred of millions
of users per day
that are being protected
by my library, which is good.
Which is great, right?
So, I guess
the problem is solved.
We can be done here.
We can go home
because we don't have
that missing part anymore.
It's all there.
We have a good library.
It's well maintained.
It does what it's supposed
to do, and everything's fine.
And I'm now kind of standing
here and just,
like, producing myself
as the slayer
off the cross-site
scripting dragon,
as an awesome person
who created that library
and saved everybody
from these kinds of attacks.
But is that really true?
Don't we have, like,
a much bigger problem?
I'm turning
into the evil guy now,
so I think I don't have
to be formal anymore.
I'll just, like,
get this jacket off.
Fly, little bird.
Hell no.
Now have to do something
that you didn't have
to do before,
because you have to trust me.
I am the maintainer
of a library
that is being used by many,
many websites out there,
that is protecting many,
many people at the same time,
every single day, in and out,
and you have to trust me
that I don't fuck it up.
Or even worse,
I could turn rogue --
just so --
and build in a back door.
Mmm. All that money.
And that would work.
And no one would notice.
Of course I would,
like, never do that,
but I could turn rogue,
and I think I could write in
a cross-site scripting exploit
that you wouldn't
see immediately
that would even bypass,
well, my own tests.
I've been writing
cross-site scripting exploits
for the past 10 years.
I think I could hide something.
I would probably hide it
in the compressed version
that we also deliver
because no one ever checks that.
I mean, just, like, no one
had to look at this thing,
and it's compressed.
Like, who wants to audit that?
There's just like a bunch
of bytes that I have to change,
and -- boom --
I have a back door.
And I have cross-site scripting
for hundreds
of millions of users.
How awesome would that be,
at least for me?
But I would never do that,
right?
I mean, I would absolutely
never do that.
You can fully trust me.
I'm standing here.
I'm just like --
I would totally not do that.
Or would I?
Oh, God, that money.
I would have to hire
a person for money
that tells me how to spend
all that money
that I would make.
God, I love that.
So, that kind of sucks.
I can get the jacket on again,
but maybe later.
Now what?
What kind
of options do we have?
We see that there's a problem,
and it's like an actual,
real-life problem.
And we see
that there's a solution,
but the solution was created
by one dude and a bunch
of people who helped.
And that one dude --
me -- has full control
over the solution
and can do whatever the effort
that person wants,
me wants, to that solution.
And with one click,
with one commit on GitHub
I can do really,
really nasty stuff.
That's not good.
We need more eyes on that.
We cannot rely on people
just creating, providing,
and maintaining
security libraries.
I think there's a solution,
and that solution is
that we cannot rely
on these libraries anymore.
We have to have that stuff
inside the browser,
inside the DOM.
The DOM has so many APIs.
Some of them are useful.
Some of them are super useless
and are never being used.
But that doesn't matter.
They're still there.
But we need another API
in the DOM.
We need a sanitizer
We need something
that is working out of the box,
that is fast,
that provides a secure default,
that has nice templates,
and that prevents developers
from shooting themselves
in the foot.
And we don't need this
as a library
because then we have to trust
someone or a bunch of people.
We need this in the browser,
where everybody can have
a look at it
and notices
when something happens.
We need DOMPurify
or something like DOMPurify
inside the browser core,
despite CSP because CSP
doesn't fix the problem.
Rather, the contrary --
It makes, sometimes, things
a bit worse,
sometimes a bit better.
So we need something
that is covering up for that.
We need to fill those gaps.
We cannot rely anymore
on these accidental
intersections
of existing
protective technologies.
We have to have something
that is covering
that particular use case
because that is getting
more and more common.
And that is good.
That's a good thing
that it's getting more common.
So, now you might sit here
in your comfort zones
and you might have a look at me
and say, like,
"Why didn't you just
write the specification?"
I'm like, "Well,
why don't you write
the specification?
I already did
all the dirty work."
I identified the problem.
I developed a fix.
I hardened that fix,
and it's really working well.
I set up all the testing
infrastructure,
tons of test cases,
literally tens of thousands
of test cases of attacks
in the past, future attacks,
combined attacks,
weird character sets,
mutations, and whatnot.
I did all that already.
I think now it's not my turn
to write a specification,
but it's actually our turn --
What's that?
-Use that, please.
-Okay.
Sorry, I lost focus.
Like I said, I've done
the dirty work already.
Everything is there.
But if you also think that this
is like a realistic use case,
that we want to make sure
that encrypted communication
in the browser --
where stuff is being
decrypted in the browser,
right in the DOM,
and needs to be protected,
as well, then let's do
something like that.
We're not starting this project,
we're not starting this spec,
but we're really, really happy
to help with test cases,
with implementation,
with support, with experience.
We've helped countless users
to actually set up
DOMPurify on their websites.
We kind of know
what developers want.
But we're not gonna get into
this battle
of writing the specification.
It would be great
if someone else did that for us
or with us.
So, my call to action
here is that I would really like
if you could take
all those ElectronMails
and all those other tools
that do the very same thing
and all those plug-ins
and all those add-ons
and those extensions and make
them a little bit safer
by giving them the only API
that is still
missing for them,
and that is client-side
sanitization.
We shouldn't and we can't
do this on the server anymore.
We can't do this with
some obscure application,
firewall, or IPS anymore.
We can't do this
on the network anymore.
We have to do this in
the browser, and that is, like,
the only place because that is
where the action happens.
So, that
concludes my presentation,
and I hope some of you
liked it and see it as,
like, a call to action
and don't see it as,
like, too useless,
what I'm proposing.
And if you don't, then just,
like, talk to me
after the presentation, and
maybe we can find something out.
Oh, there's good news.
Actually,
I spoke about this issue
with two Googlers,
with Dave Frost and Mike West.
That's why they were referenced
on the slides without knowing.
And they couldn't help --
They couldn't keep
their fingers still,
and they actually
started working
on the specification already.
And there's a mailing-list
thread where it's just, like,
people are doing Cakefiles,
the usual mailing-list style,
and discussing the issue,
and it's moving forward.
So, the first step
is already done.
It just, like, happened
yesterday or the day
before yesterday,
so that is good.
Let's see what's
coming out of it.
And that's it.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]