♪♪
Why do you work in security?
Why are you here today?
I work in security
because I like the idea of helping people.
I think that, at its core, privacy and security
are about helping people get control over technology.
I have privilege and you have privilege
because we're security experts.
We know how to tell the difference
between HTTP and HTTPS.
We know how to tell where a file came from
and that it's the right file.
We know how to avoid being scammed.
And we have that privilege because we are security experts.
But not everyone can be a security expert.
Doctors are busy helping their patients,
parents are busy raising good kids,
and artists are busy making the world
a more beautiful place.
But I still think that they deserve to have
the same level of control over privacy and security settings
and features that we in this room do.
This is why I work on usable security for end users
and why I think you should, too.
Now, what is usable security for end users?
There's many ways to define it, but, in my opinion,
a security feature that a user has to interact with
should be invisible when you don't need it
and helpful, even to nonexperts, when you do.
This is easier for some classes of security features.
For example, if you're isolating
different principles and different processes,
that's easy, to always be invisible.
But if you're working on something
that has the user in the loop, like authentication,
or anything with an exception or an alert,
I believe this should hold true.
But this is really difficult.
This is really hard.
To pick on my own work, for a minute,
and the work that my team is doing,
here are some recent tweets
that I've seen about Chrome's HTTPS warning.
Both of these people had the same problem.
What's going on here is that they were trying
to load a web page over HTTPS and something went wrong:
the certificate chain failed to validate.
And so, instead of being able to get to the website
that they were trying to go to,
they got an error message from Chrome, instead.
This is not a good user experience.
It's not helpful. It's not empowering.
And honestly, in this situation,
it wasn't even really protecting them from anything
because there probably wasn't a real attack here.
Now, I'm picking on myself here,
but this is not just a Chrome problem;
it's a problem that we see across the industry.
We see these types of problems in other products and areas.
People have trouble with the unlock on their phone;
people have trouble with authentication;
phishing is still a big problem, et cetera.
Why is usable security so hard?
Why are we still having difficulty with this idea
of invisible but helpful?, which I think a lot of people
agree is what usable security should be.
Now, this is a very complex problem
and I don't want to diminish its complexity
by giving a glib response.
But today I'm gonna talk about one thing
that comes to mind when I think about this problem,
which is that usable security is a science,
but not enough people treat it like a science.
At Google, a motley crew of people --
a mix of engineers, designers, researchers --
have been treating usable security like a science.
And, today, I'm gonna tell you three different stories
about how we used a scientific approach to security
to tackle really hard, usable security problems in Chrome.
Two of these stories are gonna be about successes
and one of the stories is gonna be about a failure,
but I hope that we can learn from all three of them.
IF you don't already believe me,
that usable security is a science,
I'm hoping that these three stories
will convince you that it is.
If you already agree with me,
I hope that you can use these stories
as talking points to bring back
to help convince other people who you work with,
other engineers, other security experts.
And, if you work in academia, I assume you probably
already do science and maybe even science on usable security.
I want to illustrate some of the gap
between the science that we find useful in industry
and what we're currently getting from academic research.
Now, what do I mean by treating usable security like science?
Well, first, I mean look for specific research.
Look to see if there's existing research --
at SOUPS, at CHI, at USENIX Security --
that could guide
how you're building a feature that puts the user in the loop.
But if you can't find this research --
which, honestly, we've found you might not be able to --
you need to run your own experiments.
You need to have defined controls and conditions
and hypotheses that you can test.
You need to take things that are nebulous,
like the idea of users understanding a warning,
and turn them into something that's concrete and testable.
And there's also a few things that you should not do.
you should not trust your gut.
Your gut, my gut --
we are not representative of regular users.
Things that seem understandable to us
or convincing to us will not generalize.
And similarly, you should not trust common wisdom,
unless it's backed by data and research.
The first story that I'm going to tell you about
started about a year and a half ago.
An engineer came to me and started telling me
about the problem of wanting to bring rich APIs to the web.
So, currently, we see very rich APIs
on platforms like Android and iOS,
where apps can do lots of things that websites currently can't,
but, in many cases, web developers want to.
Take notifications, for example.
Until fairly recently, websites were not able
to send notifications, whereas an app could.
So, if you were Gmail, you could build a Gmail app
and the Gmail app, even when the users closed it,
can still notify you about an incoming email message.
But websites weren't able to do this.
So, this is an example of one of these new APIs.
And what do you think about that idea?
Different nerds have differences of opinion
over how cool this type of new API is.
If you're a web developer, it probably seems pretty cool:
you can drive user engagement back to your website;
you can provide features don't require
than to be looking at your website at that moment.
So, from that perspective, it's great.
But if, strictly hypothetically speaking,
you are a paranoid security person --
purely hypothetically, I'm sure that doesn't apply
to anyone here --
you see a lot of things to be afraid of in this setup.
So, just looking at notifications,
specifically, there's the concern
that they'll be spammy and obnoxious.
There's the concern that they could be used
for better phishing attacks.
There's the concern that it just sort of might confuse people
about their relationship with a website,
like "I closed it. Why is it opening again?"
And one of the ways that comes to mind
to fix this fear is the idea of having a permission request.
So, what you can see here is an example
of a permission request where Facebook is asking
for access to the new notifications API
and it tells the user what website it is --
it's Facebook; it tells you what it's requesting,
which is notifications;
and then, you have a choice between allowing or blocking.
Okay, so we've kind of solved this first problem.
We've given users control over a website
can actually do this potentially scary thing or not,
but, now, we have a new concern,
which is the fear of annoying users.
And we've probably seen, from our own experiences,
that like I don't really like it when stuff pops up
on the bottom of the screen when I'm trying
to use a website; that's kind of obnoxious.
And there's also a good amount of prior literature
telling us about a phenomenon called habituation,
which is that when someone experiences the same stimuli
over and over again,
they pay less and less attention to each subsequent iteration.
So this prior literature is telling us
that there might be a negative side effect
of asking people these questions over and over again.
But it's not entirely clear.
What does that actually mean in practice?
How many permission requests is too many permission requests?
What are the costs?
Like are people gonna stop using Chrome,
are people gonna stop using their phones,
or are people just gonna be moderately annoyed
for a split second before they move on?
And does that prior literature even apply here, right?
It's hard to say, because prior literature focuses
on full-screen warnings and showing people them
over and over again in a really short period of time,
but in our actual scenario, people are seeing warnings
over a long period of time.
We're, luckily, in a good position
to be able to actually test this,
to answer some of these questions,
although not all of them, but we can answer some of them.
What this is showing you here is that we've taken all the users,
in aggregate, on one specific day,
and saw how they responded
to a notification permission request.
And then we looked back over the previous three months
to see how many prior requests they'd seen
in the previous three months.
And what you can see here is that for people at the zero --
so people who have never seen a permission request, at least,
not in the past three months -- there's an almost 40% chance
that they'll grant the permission request.
But, by the time you get down to 5 or 6 permission requests
over the last 3 months,
the acceptance rate has dropped to about 10%.
What this is telling us is that there is a very real cost
of websites requesting permissions,
perhaps unnecessarily, spuriously,
at bad times, for bad reasons,
because people are less and less likely to grant the permission
as they see more and more permission requests.
And this holds true across different types of APIs,
not just notifications.
We see the same thing happening with geolocation,
where, as people see more requests over time,
the likelihood that they'll accept drops
from a little over 25% to well below 10%.
In this situation, the common wisdom
and our gut feeling that lots of permission requests
were annoying and cause people to pay less attention to them
turned out to be true.
We substantiated that idea.
But, if we hadn't actually tested this,
if we hadn't actually looked at it,
we wouldn't have known how rapidly that occurs,
and this is information that we're now able to use
as input to our engineering projects,
to try to decrease the rate at which people see spurious
or unnecessary permission requests,
so we aren't spamming people with things
that less than 10% of people are going to say yes to.
The next story takes place in the land of malware warnings.
Chrome relies on a service called Safe Browsing.
Safe Browsing tells Chrome when a website is known
for being malicious or deceptive,
and, when that's the case, we show one of these warnings
about the website.
The warning tries to convince people
not to proceed forward to the website.
Safe Browsing is very accurate,
so we know with fairly high likelihood
that the user is gonna be at risk
if the proceed through the website.
We don't just block people. We could, right?
We could make it so people can't proceed through the website,
but we still want to give people the choice.
However, we want to convince them to adhere to our message
that you should actually turn back and do something else,
instead of visiting the malicious website.
About 2 years ago, the adherence rate was only about 70%,
and we wanted it to be closer to 90%.
A higher adherence rate, in this case, is better,
because that means more people heeded our advice to go back.
So, we wanted to test a few different things
to see what the best way is to raise the adherence rate.
And, today, I'm gonna talk about some experiments
with the headline text --
the headline text is the larger text on the top --
and also experiments with the malware download warning,
which occurs at the bottom of Chrome,
when you've downloaded a warning.
I'm sorry, when you've downloaded a malicious file.
We started off with a literature review.
We went to look to see what are the main recommendations
for what you should do
if you want to increase adherence to a warning.
Some of the literature recommended really useful things
like, for example, you should aim
for a sixth-grade reading level.
This is really great advice
because it's extremely specific and it's measurable.
We were able to take our text, we were able to reduce
the warning level, using a tool, and then run with that.
But other pieces of advice were a little harder to follow.
For example, on one hand, be as brief as possible;
and, on the other hand,
be extremely specific about the risk.
How do you do both at once?
How brief is brief enough?
How specific is specific?
It was kind of difficult for us to follow,
but, nonetheless, we still tried.
We ran a series of A/B tests,
also known as randomized control trials,
to test out some of the different things
that we gleaned from literature
in an attempt to increase the adherence rates.
Here are two examples of experiments.
In these specific experiments, what we're testing is the idea
that we should give people a command to follow our advice.
So, for example, at the top,
the control is "The website ahead contains malware!"
It's a control because it's the existing text.
And then we altered it slightly, so that the first condition
adds "Go back" to the end of it.
We did the same in the second set of experiments.
We added commands like "Discard this file.
Don't run it," to that control.
And so, here, each set of experiments has a hypothesis,
which is that the alternate condition
will do better than the control, and we randomly assigned
small groups of Chrome users into each of these buckets.
And then, over time, we could look
at their adherence rates for the people who fell
in the different buckets and compare them to each other.
I'm emphasizing the fact that we had a control
and we had various conditions
and we had random assignment, because these are key parts
of scientifically running an A/B test.
Unfortunately,
these two particular experiments had negative results.
We found that adding the command
didn't actually make much of a difference.
There are some small differences
between the different conditions here,
but they fall within the normal fluctuations
that we see on a daily basis in this type of warning.
I know that negative results aren't superexciting,
but the reason I'm sharing them with you today
is because I still think we learned a lot
from this experiment.
What we learned is that, even if you do your best
to follow previous literature and even if, in your gut,
you think "Oh, yeah! This is totally gonna work,"
it might actually not work and you don't know that
until you've run the experiment to see whether it works or not.
If we had just gone ahead and made this change,
added "Go back" and been like "Yeah! Mission accomplished"
and rolled it out,
well, a few months later, we would've been surprised
when we discovered it didn't actually help.
Instead, because we ran the experiment
and because we got to find out that it didn't work,
we were able to learn
and, instead, we tried out other things.
We tried changing the background color of the warning;
we tried changing the icons; we tried changing the layout.
And, in the end, it turned out that changing the layout
did have a positive effect on adherence
and if you'd like to learn more about how that worked,
you can read our CHI paper from last year.
For the third story, we're gonna talk briefly
about internationalization.
Traditionally, historically, most previous research
on HTTPS warnings, like these up here
and like the malware warnings I was just talking about,
has focused specifically
on English-speaking Americans from college towns.
There have been other studies on, for example,
some Canadians in college towns,
and also some that have used Mechanical Turk
to look more broadly at Americans,
but, in general, it is still centered
on English-speaking North Americans.
And I can understand why, for practical reasons,
it's much easier to run a study with the people around you.
Most of my prior work has looked this way, too.
And this work has yielded positive results.
It steered us away --
"us" as in the broader security community --
it steered us away from using passive indicators
that were really small and kind of just in the corner
of the browser, to instead prefer these larger,
full-page warnings that do, in fact, work much better.
But we still see a real gap.
On one hand, studying
people in North America who speak English,
and then, on the other hand, browsers serve global audiences.
So we decided to take a look at this
and see what regional differences we might find.
We were able to slice
the malware warning adherence rates by country.
And one thing I want to point out, first,
is that we're looking at Android and Windows
separately here, and this is important
because the type of device you use,
your operating system, is actually a confound here,
because we see that people on Android
adhere to warnings consistently
at a higher rate than Windows users,
so we have to look at them separately.
But our hypothesis here was
that warning adherence rate would differ across countries,
and it does turn out to be true; it does differ.
In fact, you'll notice that we have a problem
specifically in Japan, where Japanese users
are not adhering to warnings, at least on Windows,
at the same rate as other countries are.
We took a look at the same thing for HTTPS error warnings
and, again, we do see differences between countries,
with Turkey having the highest adherence rates and,
again, Japan on Windows having the lowest adherence rates.
Why Turkey and Japan?
I honestly don't know and I actually would love it
if people in this room could help figure out why.
If you speak another language or love to travel,
I think this would be a great area to look at,
an important area to look at.
For example, I think that, looking at Turkey,
we could learn maybe there's something
in the way it's translated
or something in how they're perceiving the warnings.
Maybe we could learn from that and translate it
to help the rest of the world.
And also, if we look at Japan,
maybe we'll find specific problems there
that could improve and bring Japan up
to the rest of the world, in terms of adherence rates.
The reason why I told this last story
was because I again wanted to highlight the importance
of how your results can be surprising
once you actually dig into data.
If you had asked me before we started looking
at statistics sliced by country,
I would've guessed, "Well, based on stereotypes,
Germans are very privacy-sensitive,
so I would expect higher adherence rates for Germany,
and that's not actually what we ended up finding,
so I'm very glad that we actually took the time
to dig into this data.
Usable security is science.
At Google, we test ideas with clearly defined hypotheses,
with experiments, and we use the results
to determine what we should launch.
We use experiments to figure out
how to settle technical arguments
about the right way to build a feature
and we look at our data over time, like in the case
of those international charts I just showed you,
to look at Chrome's strengths and weaknesses.
If you're in industry, hopefully, I've convinced you
that there is merit to taking this type of approach
and given you some stories about things
that are surprising, or negative results
that you can take back to your colleagues
to demonstrate why it's important
to actually test things, instead of just making changes
that we feel in our gut are good for users
and then launching that, because it doesn't always work.
And, if you're in academia, I hope I've convinced you
that there's still a lot of ground to cover
in usable security research.
There are companies, like Google, that are hungry
for specific and actionable recommendations
backed by your research
that we can use to improve our products.
Matthew Smith, who'll be talking later today,
is an excellent example of this.
So I appeal to you: please respect end users
by going and doing usable security
as a scientific field. Thank you.
[ Applause ]
♪♪