next up we have coercion Harry teaching
us about the beginning things of CDF
thank you hello everybody to our
talkback on beginner CTF introduction so
we have or all you so first we'll talk
about what is CTF then we will show you
the two kinds of CTF styles that
jeopardy and attack defense and then the
last topic is like the Balkan beginner
suggest we organize for you so who we
are we are students at Tim Vienna both
of us we are playing at the CTF team of
the University called we own you and
thanks to the SPI research that is
hosting our infrastructure where the
mostess services are running so I will
give the crushed F part what is the CTF
hi so when you think of C CTF or capture
the flag you probably think of some
shooter games we just have to shoot the
enemies and kept to the flag for us it's
a bit different when we talk about
capture the flag we mean internet
security competitions where we solve
some challenges and find some flag and
the flag is usually just a text string
the proofs that you solve the challenge
why is this fun because you can manage
to play in a team and you can challenge
yourself on internet security challenges
there's also global ranking and overview
where you can compare teams of different
countries
it's called CTF time it's also basically
a central hub where CTFs are announced
for example the Falcon beginner CTF is
not announced there because it's not
exactly public but if you ever want to
play a CTF you can just look it up at
CTF time and check it out and you'll
probably find a CTF every other week so
there's no shortage of CTS there so what
does playing CTF look like from our
perspective when you look at hacking in
the movies it's like oh okay
I'm gonna hack this and 10 seconds later
everything blows out and when you look
at reality it's mostly just one person
sitting in front of a PC staring at the
screen then you think okay I might be
able to exploit this then you think okay
no that's not gonna work so you're gonna
play CTFs in a team then there are two
people sitting there you're gonna stare
the screen together and do you think you
could do that you'll find out that won't
work but your colleague might have an
idea and if you play CTF online for the
first time it's probably gonna be pretty
frustrating if you don't know what to do
so there's basically two distinct styles
of CDF's
with minor variations available one of
them is jeopardy the other one is a tech
defense
property is the most common form of
CDF's mainly because it's very easy to
organize or easier to organize an attack
defense it gives you have basically a
list of challenges in different
categories you pick your favorite
category you work on a challenge you
solve it you get the flag and then
you're done you have a flag this
challenge is solved you won't have to
solve it again and it usually takes 48
hours or up about 48 hours the different
categories are usually pawn which is
exploitation mostly binary exploitation
but exploitation in general reversing
where you either reverse binaries or
weird file formats that aren't very
common web challenges where you exploit
web services
forensics and mists misc with forensics
mostly falls in the category of
reversing and miss can be any challenge
can be completely unrelated can
contribute to trivia questions for
example or flex and sharpen for self and
Internet or it might be not even
security related for example we had one
challenge at the second CTF where there
was a nine hour video and basically you
had to find the flag in the nine hour
video so we thought maybe it's just one
frame in the nine hour video but instead
of one frame it was a blinking light
that bottom corner and it was a webcam
of Tokyo so someone had to go up there
every hour and turn on the light or turn
off the light to produce Morse code flag
but they forgot that it would that the
Sun would rise eventually certain idea
they had to improvise and open the
window and close the window we basically
were just sitting there with post-its on
the screen so we can have the region
isolated with the light going on and
often just sat there and decoded the
Morse code which was pretty painful but
still a fun challenge yeah in jeopardy
once you solve a challenge you get the
flag and once you get the flag you won't
have to look at the challenge anymore
and compared to attack defense CPS
because attack-defence CTF is usually
are shorter in a time range of about 8
hours and japanese-style CDF's are in
the time range of 48 hours that gives
you a lot more time to solve the
assaulted challenges and that means the
challenges are also pretty mounting
recent CTS for example the Chaos
Communication claps if they have set
camp or
at Congress are notorious for their
zero-day categories where you have to
use actual zero days or find actual zero
days to solve the challenge it hasn't
always been this way
there used to be easier sit yes but now
it's all about going getting more
complicated and producing harder
challenges a small example challenge
from this year's Def Con qualifier CTF a
challenge I worked on and like this we
basically had given a small OS partner
and we could perform some basic
functions like it was an interactive
shell where we kept list the files and
we could catch some files and it had
basic support for environment variables
we know there was one file that we
couldn't leak and we had to find a way
how to leak it it was called honcho and
we couldn't just cat it because it was
forbidden in the code so we had to
somehow find a way to circumvent to
check in the car after reverse
engineering we found out that
environment variables were stored in a
simple data structure for the values of
the environment variables it was
basically just an array of pointers
which put points to the memory location
where the value of the environment
variable was stored now what was
interesting was that you could do a
variable expansion with a dollar sign
just as you could in actual bash or an
actual environment variables but unlike
with the normal environment variables
this wouldn't result in a length check
so you could basically just take one
really long variable and then create
another variable and use the dollar sign
to expand into this variable and the
expanded variable would just override
the balance check and produce a heap
overflow
fortunately this was pretty simple
because right after the heap
there was this array of pointers so if
you managed to put a chunk right at the
end of the heap and then overwrite the
environment variable you could write
into this array of pointers and then
basically get an arbitrary read because
he could many clear the point in any way
you want it and read and write at every
place in the memory now what it is look
in real time it basically was five hours
of painful heap layout creation which
resulted in some drunken drawings on the
whiteboard in the end we actually solved
if we thought but what we only managed
to dump was the honcho file which was
basically a hypervisor that ran the
kernel and the flag was outside of the
hypervisor so this was actually a second
stage which couldn't have been that bad
but the hypervisor ran on OSX and none
of us had a Mac or any maxixe beer
making experience whatsoever
so we basically spent 12 hours
exploiting this challenge but didn't
solve it in the end but we still have
fun well then then there is the attack
defense category the biggest difference
is that there are no challenges but our
services service is like a web servers
or some ftp server whatever that is
running and each - each team has their
own server with running services
normally have like around 8 6 6 to 8
services during attack defense is DF and
each team has the same service with the
same data and a room is like I have the
same databases and normally it's like 8
hours long I mean they're all so there
wasn't a day that went 24 hours attack
defense it was really a tough time some
guys - team didn't even sleep today
heck the whole time 24 hours they were
really broken afterwards and like that
the play time is split in two ticks
around like one tick is around five
minutes and in this tick multiple things
happen so let's see how it works so in
one tick the game bot distributes the
flags to all the services then the teams
run automated exploits or manual
exploits so if you have some really hard
service value or is it hard to like
automate it sometimes team just manually
exploit the service to get like first
first blood whatever and then the first
third thing is that the game would
checks whether the disability flag is
still there unlike that says okay the
service is still running and is fine
yeah if some flag is missing in the
service then you will get some points
removed from the score because there is
SL a service level agreement score and
this one is criest
and so the thing is also sometimes our
services where the team finds exploits
that they can delete flags so they
exploit the service get your flag and
deletes it so the other teams won't get
any flags and you get even points
reduced because the flag of debate about
our teams so the ideas in the end that
you steal the flags for other teams and
pet your own service so houses in
pictures so you have you have a big
network and there is the orga part of
network with the game bots and the whole
network is put together with VPNs and
then there is like team one they have
also a VPN connection to the team or
Gannett work and there is the
vulnerability box that's the box with
all the services running and there are
other clients well normally you
shouldn't like add these clients or
acted to the to the VPN because it will
also be probably attacked so normally
you don't really connect the clients to
the VPN directly only the boom box but
you can do it but probably if you have
that lack the other teams will attack
your personal computers so not
recommended and of course also other
teams like team to free mm and so the
first in the first round yet the wool
box and they're just different services
running on one box and that can be
really there can be a web server some
binary that is running with the service
so there's really different all of them
really obscure languages that are
compiled to something some flask service
so it's really the whole range of
service it can run on on this boom box
so in one game tick so we call it game
to kicks the first thing is that the
game bot deploys the flags to the
services so there is every time this one
like API or one one thing how he can
deploy the flags to the service and it
can be like some API or it can be like
that he creates a count on a service and
stores the flag in you know data field
of this account so it depends on the
service how it stores the flag then well
then the wrote then the team start to
exploit the other services of other
teams and steal the flags of them and
then they submitted to the game server
there is some API where you can submit
all the Flex you've got and then in a
same tick and the end the both also
checks if the flags are still there if
some service is reachable if the service
is working one thing is order to know
that normally flags are only valid for
like 5 ticks so if they have all their
flags that are from 5 a lighter older
than 5 ticks they are normally not
accepted by the game but its attack
defense so they're only like only 5
ticks are valid the flags that you catch
from other servers so that's like one
thing about one the explanation of ticks
in CAPTCHA flags and the other the major
thing is it's not just only the
exploitation of services but also how
you play this like the gameplay because
in
you played as a team you need an
infrastructure so some city some CTF
organizers give you a virtual server on
a network so you don't need to have own
infrastructure and some CTF so just
provide you our VirtualBox image and you
need to have your own computer to run it
and to set up the network so it depends
on the CTF and how the team will react
like everybody can read the network
traffic so if you attack other teams
they can check out the traffic and see
what we're doing so in the end if you
have a like a bad exploit they can read
exploit what you did on it on it in a
traffic and they can just be played for
example or also exploit if your exploit
other teams so why are fact is a really
important tool and at this kind of CTF
and others of course a rule set for for
CTF and all that the gameplay is also
then depends on the rule set and yeah
also as in real life there are no 100%
fair rules and also you need to enjoy
the game and sometimes it also happens
that sometimes teams breaches the rule
and and also get punished so one time
one team DDoS the whole network and the
whole city effort broke down at the end
and the consequences was that the team
got disqualified
it was first place and it tried to DDoS
one team and in the end the DDoS the
whole network the whole CTF network
break down they got disqualified and the
organizers made a really cool write up
what happened and how they found that
this this team was
DDoS the network we have some examples
of online attack-defence CTF today's
Russia TV it's a Russian CTF it's a
pretty stable
TTFN it's is done every year and it's
hostile towards end of the year like
December November in this area then
there is AI CTF also known as the
cottage picture well it's
it's a really good CTF it sometimes
really caught Dickens in some parts of
organization or during the CTF and
normally it's happened happening in
March and it's one of the first attack
defense suggests that started to to make
city s in this style and then there is
fast ETF that were quite newcomers and
it's usually in May June that's just an
example there are even more
attack-defence CTF but if you compare
with jeopardy style CTF the thing is
that they are not a lot of
attack-defence CTF like I would say like
10 or 20 per year and jeopardy is like
every week or every two weeks
some suggest in jeopardy style so if
also some example of a service so we
played the in Avars attack-defence CTF
there was the service called cheater
it was backed saw work written
completely in bash a completely webs are
written in bash and well the thing is it
has custom it has custom HTTP return
codes it's really screwed us up so we we
said ok we found some something how to
get flags to just register account there
and you can like get all the users and
then you can get from a user the flag if
you visit the profile and ok let's
ok let's just make a simple title to a
piping tool ok import request the
request library makeover al request to
this web page reduce for a count and
then we wrote it down and start to well
we just get the error message because
the customer should be returned code
import the request library just breaks
it just gives us an error and doesn't
work with the custom HTTP return cards
and so is it ok what to do next because
we like screwed up and then we like used
curl we called coral via patent on a
system command line and did it with
coral in the end when it was really a
really bad heck because they did screwed
up the request library of the custom HD
return codes
so what is the the service first Twitter
and it's like a Twitter clone said like
and you had in the end like a
log of Teeter messages like
messages you can check out the whole
source code of the challenge on github
before with a writer and f they built up
multiple abilities so normally in
attack-defense in a service normally
they put up more will abilities to
exploit like just liked one or two or
three ways to get the flag normally even
sometimes you have to post a bit so to
get the flag over a different service
like cross cross exploitation is also
something that's possible and in this
service you notification bypass was
possible there was a info leak and there
was the admin bypass and the example for
the admin bypass was this one in the end
I realized it's really late
even it was nearly at the end of the CTF
because we had a lot of registered
accounts and there was this called a
middleware middleware stood a sage and I
I checked the log and every time people
residual accounts if la-la-la admin one
two three four and it wasn't really
suspicious for me but in the end there
is all fact they make registering admin
accounts because there is this check if
user is equal still the admin and this
means if if that's like lalala admin
1-2-3 it's also equal as admin user and
there is also and debug flag except then
the user admin and the thing is in the
first you check not all the config of
some web service and there was this was
a config file and the worst the debug
equals one and the first we will do is
like okay just set it to zero but the
thing is that this services if you set
it to zero the minus M still ever less
so true because it checks if there's any
value in this in this variable so even
if you set the debug to zero it will
still evaluate to true the muse and
debug
so reduce the combination if you set
like deep back to 0 and hit like a
registered account with lalala admit one
two three you've still got the admin
flag set so you had to read devil a
relation of if Colossus in bash to
realize that you need to delete the
whole debug string in the config that it
don't relate it through that was one of
the of the box we found and then I at
least patched the user is admin tilde
that was then not working anymore so the
bakken beginner CTF yeah our beginner
CTF is the Joker D style CTF because
it's basically easier to host and we're
doing this for the first time so if this
works maybe we're doing an attack
defense next year
this also means you'll have the
different categories and you'll get
specific challenges for the different
categories we mainly focused on writing
simple challenges for pickiness as in
you have some kind of some kind of
programming background background or
computer science background but you've
never done any exploitation stuff or web
stuff or reversing stuff and we wanted
for once to provide simple challenges
really simple challenges and we wanted
to hide the scoreboard because usually
if we just put about simple challenges
they will be solved in no time and then
the more experienced people will
instantly take over the scoreboard so we
decided to hide the scoreboard but we're
not hiding it for the whole CTF because
of some annoying Slovenian people here
now that our initial idea was really to
have no scoreboard at all but in the end
I know people want to compete here and
we say ok we will take it no score and
tomorrow evening and then tomorrow night
will enable it for the last hours but in
the end it was like really Internet
Concord at all but still well let's
compete in the evening tomorrow so for
everyone wanting to compete and showing
off their skills where we'll have some
really hot challenges we'll try to give
them an appropriate score account to
make sure it will be possible to
differentiate them from the simple
challenges
yetsko bots will be available tomorrow
evening and then you have still have the
whole Sunday and challenges you solved
now will also show up in the scoreboard
later so just in case yeah for everyone
wanting to get completed competitive and
we at least I won't release all
challenges at the beginning I will add
more challenges especially for reversing
and pawn and we have people contributing
challenges like Greeley's who's writing
challenges right now at this moment just
in time so there will be more challenges
at it over time and yeah the CTF will
start soon in about 15 minutes if
everything works and it will end on
Sunday at 6 p.m. the important part is
tomorrow there will be workshops for
people who have never played CTF before
and - or want to get into it we will be
available there at our CTF area in the
heck area most of the time and you can
also ask us stuff you're interested
about outside of the workshop hours so
if you have questions come to us ask us
if you like meetings maybe we can give
you some person beers whatever up really
if you have some struggles don't come to
us and ask and speak with us we have no
problems to help you out unless you're
trying to compete
so the Slovenian guys you love if you're
not here if you come to us and ask how
to solve the heart challenges well yeah
I'll be holding a workshop for binary
exploitation and reverse engineering
tomorrow starting at 12:30 in the CTF
area it will take about two hours and
will roughly cover the basics because
there's you can't cover everything in
two hours but I'm there the whole day so
if you're interested in something more
you can still come around and ask me I
will have the workshop for web
challenges will also be a rough one hour
thirty two hours and show you like intro
what you have to start for web challenge
what to check out what tools you can use
like some simple Python intro with
request for example and it will be
tomorrow at thirteen fourteen thirty I
was in the CTF area after the reversing
workshop so what to bring bring your
laptop
preferably running Linux or BSD we also
accept people's windows it's not a big
deal but it will maybe have probably
some at some challenges if you attend at
least if you attend my workshop because
there are some tools and the binaries
are usually running on Linux and you
don't you only have a Windows machine
you can ask me and I will create your
account on a virtual machine we can test
the tools and sausages so we'll have a
server where you can connect and have a
Linux environment and work there if you
like that's not a problem so basic
knowledge about programming is probably
needed for some exploits especially in
the binary exploitation of brass
engineering area and bring motivation we
wanted people learn some stuff that they
try stuff out and if of course if the
affection comes and ask us but the
biggest thing is we are doing it because
fun with it and we like to motivate
people to also enjoy the capture the
flag stuff and it's it's it's an
interesting thing because you learn a
lot of stuff sometime the learning curve
is quite quite high but but after you
you manage to like Seoul for challenge a
hard one you're like really into it and
say oh nice I really managed to do it
and so we recommend you check it at
least out and have fun we have like our
webpage so before the CTF we say ok what
we have like we want to do mine for it
and we just found it was founded instead
was for feel free so it just bought
domain and set up on Connecticut polar
Institute the CTF page with the C TFT
interface and yeah see you at the CTF
area or on at the venue
if you won't need something just speak
with us and have fun yeah are there some
still questions in case you didn't
remember the website you can always ask
us there's QR codes on the info Bheema
there should be purchased with QR codes
hanging around there is propaganda
around the venue and you can look it up
at the bottom website where which has a
CDF yeah there is a CT f sub page on the
bottom of page other still questions
here we are here and can answer probably
your questions
what could possibly go wrong that's why
it's written that's why it's virtually
well made so we will see but maybe I
will give you access to my real laptop
that I have with me like one we will see
what could possibly go wrong but and
maybe if you need to get root access to
this laptop no questions at all all
right then
enjoy the conference enjoy the capture
flag and see you at please tomorrow a
key Alex
you