so next up we have careless with the
leak of billions of passwords cold
winter morning in Russia Ivonne comes
back from his work to his family he
spent his whole adult life working this
trade working in this business it's been
dealing with copyrighted works he's
creating added value creating written
documents creating authorship and today
he found out that someone has stolen his
life's work and is reselling it at the
cheaper price this is a story of Yvonne
or maybe he's called some other way in
real life and how he lost control of his
stash of passwords so before we get to
that story
let me explain for those of you who are
new to the criminal underworld of of the
IP how passwords leaks work any end
users here anyone who would consider
themselves not a hacker not a programmer
just you know interested in computers
yeah we have some ok so some of the end
users would say that you know strong
password is important and everyone says
that ends true but the leaks don't
happen from your from your end device so
mostly it's not your phone or your
laptop or your computer that gets hacked
by sheer volume most passwords come from
your service being hacked like for
example in in in the old days well
actually we don't have to go back to the
old days Facebook gets hacked together
here and there right so large companies
do get hacked and they they did get
and then it happens even more so that's
where the leaks come from the the normal
scenario of how password lists come to
be so we can't even or or whomever I
don't know his real name
but according to the candles it appears
it's it's it's a male but who knows so
even if I was gonna hack stuff but
before that we have a user let's call
him Bob you see him on the screen user
would register to one or more of online
sites let's say he's a blacksmith so he
frequents blacksmithing forums he would
create an account Bob one two three this
password let's say password one because
you have to have digits in your password
and he would also create you know some
more accounts at some other forms for
example he loves to ride horses the
coursing forum maybe maybe a social
network like Facebook or something else
Twitter lights whatever you have but
then a hacker comes along and hacks one
of those services and the password
caches or the passwords are depending on
the configuration of the service will
get leaked the hacker will manage to get
them now what I have a small problem
with these days as a small side note is
is that researchers do not really
differentiate leaks and and open open
broken open databases anymore right we
just had this Facebook leak which was
scraped database not actually owned by
Facebook I'm still not sure if it's
actually a leak today because maybe you
just found it and didn't download and
and assumed okay there it is so there's
a different view that between that but
but leagues do happen and hackers when
they see that look like that they will
download the whole database and that is
a league that's what happens and a
different hacker might download some
other database and see our Bob here that
uses his username Bob one two three
because that is his username and his
password password one because that is
his password on all the sites will get
compromised on all the sides because the
password is the same right but there is
a site that Bob doesn't use and the
hacker gets that gets a database out of
that site so what happens then well in
the old days hackers was just you know
shared password list with friends these
days we have economics of crime not only
not only crime on the street also crime
online it's all quite well structured
quite quite a good here he actually said
what happens is they would sell in this
case for some rubles because I came to
the conclusion that that this leak
originated mainly or altogether in
Russia so for some rubles this would be
sold to someone who would then combine
all the leaks all the data in a huge
database and then go sell it on the
black market on the dark web usually
usually these these databases are not
readily available like to you and me if
you're not researching that you can't
just Google password database and and
get that you can get something else you
can get some some smaller databases some
leaks that have been reprocessed but
these original ones it's quite hard to
get so dark web or at the very least you
have to have knowledge you have to use
this grey grey web where you have to
know someone to get inside it's not on
darkened percent but you know it's hard
to get and then in this case it was
being sold for some dollars from two
other hackers and they have different
use for that they might use password
stuffing which means they take your
password and try it on other services on
all the services they can they will try
you username and password and see if
they can get in they might want it
because they won't steal your identity
or because they won't take over your
social networks anyone remembers the
hacks of around five years ago I think
we're we're Twitter users were targeted
for their short usernames so that
happens and these people are ready to
pay the the price it's not a high price
it's it's usually under a hundred
dollars for for this compiled password
user list without credit card numbers
and stuff like that but you know as it
happens in in free market especially in
free market that is a crime market some
users some hackers might do additional
illegal stuff and
illegal stuff on this picture here is
denoted by the red lines so they they
might you know try to resell it black
back on the black market say if it's
forty dollars I'm going to resell that
for twenty dollars of it if it's ninety
dollars okay how about $40 a better deal
same data everyone wins
right except the original creator of the
data well the users lose anyway so what
happens there and the last step is at
some point someone is going to also leak
the data somewhere outside the dark web
and it's gonna become available that's
when researchers get more easy access to
it and that's what happened here so
we're gonna take a look at some
screenshots of of the gray forum cracked
up to where where this stuff was
happening um so here with the profile of
a hacker named corpse he called himself
ethical hacker and coder and there's a
line going through his nickname which
means that he's banned too bad you can
also see that that he's been there for
for less than a month we'll see what he
was doing there a bit later on
um this is advertisement for for the
leaks so it says you can buy cloud
access with combos which usually means
user name and something like user name
and password which is about one terabyte
of data and you can actually see all the
all the folders there that that are in
there and the access for life I mean for
for for eternity not for not jailson
it's real life so access for eternity is
$45 here so that's that's how it was
being being sold
this is Sonics here selling selling this
stuff not anymore I think it's not being
sold anymore and and Clorox was doing
something similar on the forum so now
back to corpse here we can see that
corpse has posted collection one
collection to collection to collection
three four and and so on and all of the
collections here the links are available
to four members only but that doesn't
matter what's interesting here is the
note he added so he says
I'm the creator of these collections the
reason why I leaked my own collections
which I used the cells because sanics
were sold them and scammed people so
yeah he decided to take soundings out of
business out of out of stealing his
business and out of his business and and
got wild medias he says himself and then
we have a different different user here
with some interesting comments toward
Sonics as well but some people some
hackers on the forum also also made my
job easier by actually combining
everything into into one needs download
so that made stuff easier that's how the
leaks happened this happened in January
it started end of 2018 and happen in
general 2019 but the question is one of
the questions that we have when
researching stuff like that is how old
is a database if the leak to the gray
area to the gray net or the open
Internet happened in January this year
does that mean that the passwords are
actually if January this year no it
doesn't necessarily mean that so that's
one of the questions we can look at
before that so we download everything we
take a look at what we have this one we
have mostly text files yay so 4/5
our text files which means they should
be easy to process and and then we have
some archives which is no she's not that
nice because for one that means that if
you say but I want there by Drive to
analyze this and you field almost one
terabyte was this you can't really
extract anywhere and and the other
aspect is that the text files usually
compress quite nicely which means that's
going to be a lot lot daytime before I'm
compressing it of course we look around
if you look again at this slide here we
can have a bunch of other formats 0.4%
other and the question what kind of
things we have there all we have
interesting stuff in there for example
we have a word document it says in
Russian we are renting out this website
not selling we're renting it out and
what we see on the slide actually is
rankings for different keywords on
different search engines so you
you know by by the step and do your
dirty business or maybe legitimate
business if you rent this hopefully
heard of companies
legitimate companies a newspaper in
Latvia that are renting their domain
name like not from not from the registry
from some third party so maybe somebody
is no business medusa - so why was it
there i'm not sure i have two equally
likely possibilities either someone was
trying to advertise their site business
or they just don't care what they put up
there because because the quality of
that stuff is quite low there's
everything in there for example the
rules of this war document it actually
has active warhead active links to to
the database administration system of
where this was copied out from so we
open up that attacker opened up the
system control AC control v in the
document and there we go
there is also pictures and just random
random pictures in there because you
know why not the the message there says
in russian fight me then we have some
Python scripts i would love if for every
separate database there would be a
script to process it so this opens up a
specific dom DHD and processes it in in
in in a format that's easily easily
usable in python later on unfortunately
there are only like four or five of
scripts like that and the structure is
basically we have all dumps from
everywhere as we will see in in a minute
and since it all happened just by
holding data from different leaks which
overlap in time because as i told you if
a leak happened you don't know how fresh
that fresh data is and sometimes data
gets leaked again it happened once again
in Latvia where I come from so there was
a huge
but there was a huge storm in the press
press was saying oh my god the
government was hacked because the
passwords of their system leaked and
it's through their leaks yes and they
had the email addresses of their
customers
so mostly Latvian citizens and they had
the passwords associated to those
accounts but the leaked happened for
them years ago and we already talked
about that four years ago but that's
someone font again sent to the press hey
a leak so that stuff happens and it
happens too - black hat hackers as well
they they also sometimes we include the
same stuff again in the league because
filenames changed cache Sims may go may
change if you had a carriage turn the
end so if we don't look at these small
changes right if we just look at the
files as such using hash Sims one force
was matching something already in there
so basically that's good for me because
I have less the process but after
removing duplicates at this point I
extracted everything of course and even
better picture appears almost everything
is text which is good because text is
easy to process I will tell you about my
method to process them in one of the
slides so you can do that as well for
other data or for this date if you want
to repeat the the the research we do
have 0.1% empty files so that that's a
hacker thing
those of you who have been hacking for
for let's say 20 years know that in the
so-called scene sometimes sometimes you
add files just for the filenames like it
happens in the piracy scene it happens
in cracking scene as well for your tool
we just put your message in the name of
the file and that's it in the files
empty so that happens a lot here as well
0.1% empty files so file size wise what
do we have we have after after the
extraction we have thirty seven
gigabytes collection one these are
before the extraction actually we have
10 times more collections two three four
five and auntie public apparently auntie
public is the name they use for database
that has never been published outside
the darknet
which is not the case anymore then we
have 12 billion
which is one file that's one file of 90
gigabytes and it's super clean it's like
username/password it's perfect so easy
to use then we have big DB big database
which is around 600 gigs obviously and
so that totals to about one terabyte of
data this is before the extraction when
we extract it we have one terabyte more
so we have two terabytes of data to
process it does take some time I've been
doing this research since since the lake
since February this is not the first
time I give a similar presentation but
this presentation has more data
different slices I'm looking at it a
different way because it takes a lot of
time to process for example extracting
one country entries for one country out
of two terabytes well out of the
database
I wouldn't call database out out of the
dump can take around four to five four
to five hours just just extracting one
one small country not like calm but like
data we so but in reality we have 900
gigs because once again we look at the
duplicates and what we see is that
there's a bunch of stuff wasted a bunch
of a bunch of space is being wasted just
because they don't care but that's
that's not their job that's my job to to
analyze the data to clean it up first
so that's how we see if after the
extraction duplicate data
dublicate files not entries more than
half so there you have it when you this
happens with potato chips a lot right
you buy the bag of potato chips and cow
food is there that's same same logic
happens here so how do we process them
after we have them down to these around
nine hundred gigabytes it's still a lot
of data the the first idea that people
who work with web development or
Microsoft tools have is usually hey
let's import it into the database which
is a super bad idea I didn't try it but
but I've my presentation collided with a
different different guy's presentation
at a closed event where I was presenting
this and he was doing a database style
even though it was highly optimized
databases his speeds were lower than
mine
so my answer is of course no quarrels
and some more utils so those are super
nice if we're talking about hard drive
or or even salt solid-state drive it
gives you gives you line speed so the
bottleneck is usually usually the actual
the actual media or social connection to
the file that that you're working with
so it gives you super super nice speeds
I was working on a USB 3 a USB 3
attached hard drive of 4 terabytes or 3
turbos I think so the speeds were where
what I could get like a hundred
megabytes per second which is which is
as good as it gets
so anyone used find yeah yeah we kind of
people right anyone use any of these cat
grep WC yeah super super cool come on
they actually helped a lot then said
anyone anyone you said ok almost the
same amount as the previous that's good
said it's a bit more complicated but
it's also super nice and and and then we
have then we have the last one here
which which not that many people use but
in this audience I think I think we're
going to have more fans than usual so
who's heard couscous youth progress yeah
Thank You Martin yeah you told me about
that at this conference to earth tour
couple years ago
hey definitely ok I I managed I managed
to live without a wk
yes so but but I did use cut with Cu T
which which is not here
cut cut is oka WK is useful when you
have to swap field around because the
maintainer zuv cut do not want to
implement that yeah
but progress is super cool and a lot of
people have heard about it I that that's
great
I I heard as I said from from Martin
about about progress so it's a cockatiel
T you launch progress - M when you get
this on your screen so you don't have to
wait around indefinitely not knowing
what this what's the speed of your
operation is you can actually take a
look at the time remaining at the speed
because when you are launch a command
like that cut something something
Gaullist big emails which is like half a
terabyte file well not in this example
but in general then you don't want to
wait for 24 hours to find out that oh it
still hasn't finished
maybe my algorithm is bad so that's what
progress is cool so after processing all
the text files and I'm just talking
about text files here because I decided
I can I can just ignore the one percent
of of the files which are not not txt we
have this amount of records that is 26
billion seven hundred thirteen million
eight hundred sixty two thousand six
hundred eleven and if you if you stumble
upon any other presentations on the leak
and on the topic the number may may
differ because data quality is poor with
the exceptions at 12 billion file data
quality spores some text files have
binary data in them
zero zero characters zero s keys and I
had to filter that out and it might have
it might have changed the number of
entries so but still 26 billion entries
is is a lot right if you look at it from
this perspective it is basically three
and a half populations of Earth so
that's that's quite a lot and what do
you think what is the most popular
password amongst the 26 billion
huh bastards nah not password and now no
one has it yet come on this is gonna be
the winner it's it's one two three four
five six it's still that so it already
tells us a couple of things nowadays
majority of systems would not accept
this password there are still systems
that would but majority wouldn't five
years ago the largest commercial bank
and let me accepted that as a password
and that is why they were attacked but
but nowadays nowadays there's there's
change so 0.15 percent is is one two
three four five six but in in in the top
we see the other passwords that you
mentioned so we have we have a password
here and we have one two three four five
and estoppel I said password one is
actually not that common it's like top
top 50 or something so it's it's a
relatively secure password depends on
the resources of the attacker
so one thing one thing we did was the
data is we took a look at at the
distribution so some of the entries
actually had the IP address of where the
user was either logging in or
registering from but since there was no
no guarantee that it is a registration
IP address word that it is there at all
or that it's not a phone number instead
of an IP address we didn't go that route
also only minority of Records like less
than 10% had the IP address that's why
contrary these muscle researchers we
decided we should go ahead and look at
the email addresses which is not that
cool but we can't get answered one of
the questions that that we were asking
where did the link originate from so
dot-com domains more than 13 billion
entries so more than half where dot-com
email addresses that is obvious that
comm is the oldest one of the oldest
domains this TLD sorry
around six billion dot are you so Russia
then we have the next category which is
more than 1 billion they have Germany in
there and then we have some some more
countries coming in for example here for
more than half a billion we have net we
have France we have UK and and so on so
we see where the concentration is right
here for more than hundred millions we
have Italy Poland Czechoslovakia Japan
and Brazil of course and here so Canada
Ukraine Spain China Australia Taiwan and
dot e-d-u
so those are the popular ones and it
clearly begs the conclusion that Russian
hackers hacking Russian users it looks
like like that because that come is used
by ruin right and we have we have
somewhere here and and of course the
rest which is less than thirty thirteen
million now looking at the slide
even though looked at a couple of times
I'm not sure if if Antarctica actually
had then saying but isn't there well
anyway so if you zoom in on Europe this
is this is how it looks so you can try
to find your own country and and/or
understand the the probability that
you're in there that you're the man is
in there if anyone actually uses their
national dot dot TLD for email yeah we
have fifteen people doing that so yeah
you can you can take a look if you don't
want to download the two terabytes so
then of course it's interesting to look
at the government's because governments
use their national TLD for emails that's
what governments do and the u.s. is
number one with 44% then we have a UK
Australia and stuff like that right so
that's that particularly coming from
Latvia we have this rivalry between
between the Baltic States between
Estonia Latvian Lithuanian please don't
mix up Latvian to any
unless it's on purpose then it's funny
so so I want to take a look at at the
three Baltic state this is what I got so
these are unique email addresses and
this is the difference I've given a
similar talk before for this talk I've
actually done it right finally I mean I
had I had scientific explanation valid
explanation I think for why I didn't
remove duplicate duplicate entries
because it is quite possible that Bob
one two three uses the same email
address and the same password with
multiple sites it is quite quite
plausible but the date didn't make much
sense so I decided for resist
presentation I can filter all that out
and I only include every every user name
once right every unique user name once
in this this slide here um so
unfortunately when we can look at the
users and passwords it didn't make much
more sense just a bit more sense but
here Latvia is still the leader so we
still have a bunch more addresses from
from Latvia if you look at the Russian
population then Latvia leads Estonia
closely follows not like here Estonia is
is more than 50 percent under and and
loopy and it doesn't have almost doesn't
have Russian population so so it kind of
makes sense that Latvians are Latinas
are more targeted because much of the
information warfare of Russia extends
into into into Latvia and a bit into
Estonian as well ok but but since this
is a conference in the Balkans I
included now I'm struggling at how to
call them I'm gonna call them countries
I'm sure I'm sure you will forgive me if
any of those isn't the country but I
think it's safer for everyone if you
just call those three countries so we
have Montenegro Serbia and Yugoslavia in
there and we can see that compared to
the Baltic States it's nothing so Russia
is quite far away relative to to the
Baltic States so you know not that many
hits and for Montenegro it
me right so everyone well not everyone
but a lot of people have taught me just
because it's cool domain and not because
they're I feel like this Montenegro per
se this conclusion can be corroborated
by by a different set of evidence that
we will see in in some of the next
slides now here are some slides and in
the slides we'll finally for the first
time ever in the history of me
presenting on this topic will be made
available today on my site so you can
take a look at all that later but here
we have top domains for every TLD of
those 60 lbs so we have of course e we
have Elte of course
for example 1lt here is is a top it's
quite popular 102 any code OTE is
popular email to Roger in Estonian for a
lot to inbox at LV is basically the the
popular one
but the thing singer here is that one L
way which is placed number two has not
been functioning as an email provider
for the past five or ten years and and
we have quite a lot of females coming
from there so we I would like to
conclude from this data that that means
data is super old and crappy but it also
might mean that users don't care
updating their email addresses they just
create an account 10 years ago and they
use it daily but doesn't matter that the
emails wrong
maybe that's the case because email
revalidation isn't the thing in most
accounts these days which is good I
don't like machines annoying me by
sending me random emails so for
Montenegro we have a pink dot me here
and drop mail dot me force there be a
hotmail dot arrest is actually run by
hotmail default mail or something else
is it local
no one knows no one is using that but
that's number one interesting
then open tell cameras and SBB RS as
well and forty Gestapo you have ever met
dot you and PTT dot you now let's
compare the government's we didn't see
any of these governments in in the first
slide so let's compare the government
between themselves so if you feel
throughout all the governmental
addresses from these six countries
Latta once again is number one you would
expect Serbia to be number five but
surveys number two so it would indicate
that Serbian government well because of
the nature of
of the leek I wouldn't use the word was
attacked was targeted I couldn't is that
but was less careful or using the wrong
site or or using their email the work
email address for private purposes once
again we're gonna have six slides which
you can take a look at later after after
the talk which governmental addresses
for Estonia which for Lithuania then for
Latvia for Latvia you can see a huge
huge huge part is other right so it's
only the tool only includes top ten
addresses and there's a bunch of
addresses if we look at them so we have
Estonia number one I think that's a
ministry for information look any
statistics institution Latvia the
foreign affairs ministry for Montenegro
I just got me I guess that's because
that's how they set up their email lists
mostly I'm not sure then we have this
for Serbia what is that
and as the any Serbians here
unemployment office okay lots of free
time on their hands for Yugoslavia we
have a circle that's a you see okay and
and yet we happen so looking at that
statistics that way is of course
interesting but what actually brings
home the the message on the validity of
the data and the validity of the
approach of looking at the email
addresses of the domains rather than at
the IP addresses is the user names so
what they think is top one user name for
let's say I don't know and Latvia
okay let's start easy top one use them
for Serbia good you know I've never
registered anywhere with my Rhodes email
but I still get spam like a bunch no no
it's not true so for for all the
countries top one or two email is info
but but obviously for
for Serbia and Yugoslavia here its
office but top two is info anyway and we
also start seeing some national names in
in top 3 so we have undress and Martin
for stony kept Thomas and Andrews for
Lithuania and yon is for what for Latvia
and has been of course for Larry as well
and here's here's the rest of the top
ten
I think it's top 10 so we do see quite
quite some national I'm Xia sure you can
even take a photo but the slides will be
available in in one hour as well for
your use and so it makes sense right and
what also makes sense is that Serbian
and Yugoslavia names are basically they
match right
it also makes makes a lot of sense we
see an overlap in there now the next
slide will be what yeah top passwords
same countries again so number one
password is one two three four five six
yes that number one password except
except for Montenegro and Serbia we'll
get we'll get back to that in a minute
if we look at number one password this
is what we get
percentage-wise and this is where this
approach makes more sense than the
previous approach filtering out by
unique unique accounts because
previously these percentages were around
1% or under 1% now we can actually see
the real prevalence of of the bad
password and we also see that Latvia is
is safe because it's only 1% but on a
serious note it's not because I don't
think it's because Latvians are more
more intelligent in choosing their
passwords I think the thing is that
Latvians had much more data leak so many
more records were released for Latvians
so I guess stupid users get a good leak
more often so that's that's the message
there number two all right we have some
some some original passwords this 1 Q 2
W 3
is-is-is quite common these days and at
number three we finally see some
national passwords appearing so some
passwords that include a dictionary ward
of that language so here for example in
indicate in red is lieutenant word lo
opus which which means the animal and
and if you look at the rest of the top
we also if you look at the rest of the
top we see some more word from the
dictionary but only in the Baltic States
I mean maybe I don't now know the local
did the Balkan language is that well but
it didn't find any any local words in in
there so yeah yeah I don't think that's
another thing that's a lot of work but
but still if you look at at the the
column the last column and second to
last once again we see quite an overlap
which means that people may be using
email addresses or were using emails
interchangeably or maybe at some point
they switched over to the Serbian TLD
and and reuse the same old password so
now of course we have to ask ourselves
what is this right what what are these
top ten passwords and well the answer is
simple
I don't know this this place right here
is actually why after presenting last
time I decided I have to look at the
users uniquely so I don't so I don't see
a password in the top if it has been
used by a user and the users simply
included in the leaks 1000 times I
didn't even see that
so I removed all that and each entry now
only appears once when calculating the
top and they are still there so I mean
maybe it's the data quality but yeah I'm
baffled so in QA this this will be a
special Q&A you will have the option Li
to not only ask question you can do a
comment so you're welcome to comment on
what the hell was that
now let lets let's wait for the key name
so one more thing that I was really
looking forward to is some other things
that we had in the dump I showed you
some pictures I showed you some Excel
files stuff like that but my daily job
involves the consulting pen testing and
stuff like that including software
engineering and I couldn't find any
recovery questions leaked before so now
I finally found one I mean I found a
couple and there were a couple leaks in
there in this large lake that had to do
with recovery questions so now my my pen
testing mind switched on and I thought
yeah finally I will be able to
understand how users think how they
answer results recovery questions
because that's an easy way to get into
your account usually if you have those
enabled right so this is from from a
side that allowed users to specify their
own recovery questions and usually I
would say right it's it's safer that a
user can specify their own question if
the alternative is that you choose one
question out of ten from a list well
looking at these answers and questions
here I have to doubt that and and you
have to make a decision when making this
your system if you have recovered
questions do you have them preset or
they allow a user to type in whatever
they want because this is this is what I
sell so for example there was a recovery
question who are you and what that user
specified in their account and the
answer is this mess wait for that is
it's me the original writing is on your
left and and there was a recovery
question nil the answer obviously is
yeah that's me yes Who am I
camel which is a name in one of the
russian-speaking countries and and
finally QWERTY
and there are two possible answers that
people would give to this right if you
were a hacker and you were wanted wanted
to get in and the system said please
answer the following questions QWERTY
right you could type a is D F G H or you
could also type QWERTY which is the
correct answer here for this one so I'm
not sure if if if we assume that users
aren't inclined and will never be
inclined to waste their own time and
comfort for security I'm not sure that
offering them okay you can type more and
have a secure question is a good idea
now maybe you have some extra option I
want to be secure and then you can type
your question because than that you can
offer them to choose from a list now in
the final slides I want to talk about
the obvious things you can do to prevent
this stuff don't do password reuse I'm
not gonna ask you to raise your hand
because no one will raise your hand even
though almost everyone reuses passwords
for example for throwaway accounts but
don't reuse passwords obviously use
strong passwords one two three four five
six is not a good password if you use
strong passwords your friend is a
password manager which helps you
remember the strong passwords just
remember the main pilot the master
password okay that's the important part
there and finally if you have any
developers in the room you should use
salting you should salt your damn
passwords because the leak here came in
different different formats we had email
addresses some user names not all were
email addresses but we have email
addresses and then we had a password or
a hashed password and a password this
hash is out salting it makes it super
easy for a person with lots of money to
just crack all the passwords or all the
terabytes of data quite quickly now I'm
gonna talk for two minutes about what
salting is because
smart people are simply experienced
people or overconfident people like me
just come and say do that do that do
that and go away right and don't explain
what they mean by that so I thought okay
I'll explain what salting is for those
of you who are not sure what that is
exactly or have never heard that so we
have a user for your newlymet's system a
user chooses their secure password which
is one two three four five six and you
being a good developer of course you do
not store this password in the database
you cache it first you do not store it
plain text that's the first step
you also don't encrypt it with a two-way
encryption function that is second step
shares Microtech yeah now they fix that
they fix that capable months ago
so you cache it right you create a cache
here's a super simple Lane short cache
doesn't matter for just for an example
right now a different user comes by and
creates an account and thinks I need to
select a secure password what about one
two three four five six and then you
catch that password and even the
password is cached in the database it's
the same cache so it means the attacker
instead of spending twice as much
resources just cracks one of the caches
because they are both identical they're
both the same caching is good compared
to not caching but salting is better so
how do we solve same users they come to
the system they select randomly look at
the top passwords which the password
revenues today are number one so okay
and select the password what your system
does at that time you generate well-salt
can be called a random random system
generated password additional password
I wouldn't call second factor not that's
complete not that but your system
generates a random additional password
and once again important note it has to
be generated when the user enters their
new password you cannot have it just for
the system you can't you cannot have one
salt for the whole system in my job as a
pen tester I've seen systems like that
it's just a bit better than not salting
South has been it because now before we
hash it your system can combine the red
and the blue into one string and then
hashing it will result in completely
different cash and then of course the
question is how do you verify that the
password one two three four five six is
legit when the user comes back in year
later
and types in their secure password code
do you see if you switch it because
cache is completely different right you
can't you can't cash it again well you
store this in the database you stored
together with the salt and even though
everything is in the database and it
takes almost the same processing time to
verify the password for an attacker it
means that each user has to be tracked
separately and that means that even in
secure password like one two three four
five six might not get cracked if you
use a good hashing algorithm and if
there are lots and lots of users so this
is the top password and overall we've
seen it in 0.16 percent of the 23
billion entries the question is with the
database being old apparently because of
all that till these we saw because of
the names we saw because of the
passwords we saw database being gold
what do you think about the top password
this year the password January 2019 yeah
good what does River five six seven
eight yeah that's a good guess the top
password for January 2019 could be
determined because this lifetime
subscription to the password database in
the cloud included free weekly updates
and up to the leak updates were
happening so you could download the
folder with passwords that were gathered
just this week so I looked at the folder
of generators in nineteen and the top
one password for genuine person nineteen
is one two three four five six
with 0.32 percent of the entries thank
you
now if there are any questions I or
comments I asked you to wait for the
microphone before you speak and the
presentation will be available on 20/20
one place and you will work thank you
thank you for the question
so there are 858 passwords that include
zero 2009 in dot RS so less than
thousand which is let's see which is so
we had we had 20/20 800 sorry 280,000
and about 1000 of those include 0 21
Oh
just dearly haha without deal and yet if
I may ask you a question
since says the bottom like is a disc how
does that help yeah of course of course
you want to have a sissy but I couldn't
afford to Porter but this is these
that's what I did is on a yeah on the
hard drive any more comments or
questions maybe about those passwords
yeah
they forced us to
Oh
but the new of course I knew
that's that's nothing question should
government's regulate technically how
secure the systems be it's an
interesting question because I'm I'm the
author of of the Latvian national
legislation that that regulates
technical minimum security measures but
it only applies to to governmental
systems and it makes sense in a way if
we talk about salting or not salting I
mean baby steps right one of the points
I wrote in in Latin legislation is that
a system must have a password that's it
so baby steps I mean caching caching is
already better than not catching so
maybe maybe in ten years we can talk
about something I mean I'd love to have
it immediately but it all it all has
costs and I wasn't sure from from your
question if if this includes all the
systems if government says all the
commercial systems or even private
citizens must use caching that's a
strange thing for for a European if
that's the case but in anyway salting is
of course is of course battery and but
for example Latvia and the Latin
legislation doesn't have that as well it
just says it has to be scrambled and
while we look for the next question
getting back to the previous question
there are no dots
Givi addresses for those six countries
and I presume the other part is a
birthday so could be that's where they
ascended 30 or something because I
thought gee this is using
so this originates I see yeah yeah thank
you thank you thank you for the comment
Oh Jo yes sometimes I use that none of
none of the six countries that does
through somebody's do use that I did
find a user named evil guys go fishing
at something sorry
Oh for my own hmm
[Laughter]
no no I haven't I haven't but I don't
have I don't have the data here because
I don't I I don't have the research hard
drive is me for comm I've used my
dot-com domain for for basically my
whole life so yeah I could look at I
could look at that but I regularly well
not regularly but like once a year I go
to Troy hunts website and and take a
look at some my email addresses it's
never there because for all the shitty
websites I usually use some throwaway
email or mail matter or you know I don't
even try to make an account but yeah I
mean we so getting back to the start of
the talk we can never be hundred percent
sure that it's not gonna be there I
can't I can't say that there's anything
I can do to make sure that my email
address will will not appear there like
in a year or two or ten because it's out
of autumn our hands it's the security of
the systems
education
you
that is one of the solutions passwords
that there are there are companies and
there are individuals and
non-governmental organizations that
their mission is killing passwords
passwords are bad let's kill passwords
I don't mind passwords I think I think I
think it's ok right because if a system
gets hacked right the the data is
usually available anyway so the problem
is password reuse if you don't help us
for the reuse the system being cracked
the data is there you can access it with
with a result identification doesn't
matter so I think password reuse is a
problem educating users I think I think
is is possible to some extent for users
that are uneducated will to fight
certification isn't gonna make things
better because they kind of too afraid
that I like my governmental ID that I
put in my laptop a users aren't gonna
set up first time I set it up ten years
ago it took me four days to set it up
last time it took it took much much it
was much faster it was four hours right
actually the time before that it was one
hour but then they changed stuff and it
stopped working on Linux so it was four
hours again so users want simple stuff
like for example when you talk about to
a Fae for you to users they will say
awesome s that works right but it's a
mess is damn broken and I know I've been
getting I've been getting crap on
Twitter for saying that do not use a
semester fact certification with
different security people saying now
something is better than nothing but it
depends it depends on how how the
provider implements it right Google has
fixed it Facebook has fixed it but if is
the provider can say to your question I
forgot my password why don't you send to
my SMS says yeah sure here's nice mess
with your password then your additional
two-factor just becomes a loop called
right with ss7 attacks
okay I think we are kind of kinda out of
out of timing here thank you so much
there's not a presentation on Sunday so
come take a look
you