hello next up nothing to hide from
carols
[Music]
some citizens complain about being under
surveillance but they are told that if
they have nothing to hide they have
nothing to fear still news media
regularly covers cases where citizens
with unusual behavior are put on
suspicious lists even though they have
broken no laws this is actually a quote
from a book not a news article yet a
small book Edra grams edition number 300
written by Jesper lund but I invite you
to take a look at this short collection
of short articles and see what the
future holds
privacy wise now the main confusion with
nothing to hide the argument is this
right here
if anyone the view still remembers this
this notation right here if not what it
means that for everyone who is a
criminal that everyone has something to
hide then the middle line here says from
that follows that for everyone who has
something to hide that everyone is a
criminal and that of course is wrong but
if we don't put these words in a
mathematical representation then for
some people that makes sense on daily
basis we think yeah yeah that that's a
good argument all right only criminals
give things to hide so if you have
something to card you must be criminal
all that is not the case and I'm also
bringing something new to the table at
least at least I think it's new
I believe I caught punch I'm right but I
believe I created the concept that that
I call our Schrodinger video camera
so what's rolling girl's video camera
imagine you have a nice apartment like
this one here in Paris and you live
there one day you notice that outside
the apartment on the wall
someone has installed
PTZ camera dome it's it's not
transparent it's an a PAC dome so it's
it's a black one you don't see word
cameras pointing you're not even sure if
there is a camera but the feeling you
get is it a good feeling like the does
it matter to you if you're being
surveilled or not or is privacy maybe
just a little bit about the feeling of
thank privates
maybe such the cameras there maybe it's
being rotated to you maybe they zooming
in on you maybe there's nothing in there
maybe just a security door like a fake
camera a prop you don't know but still I
think for most of us the feeling is not
a positive one so it's not about
actually being surveilled it's about
feeling private and what is privacy
privacy has multiple facets I'd say
first of all it's an autonomous right to
choose who processes my information like
maybe I like to let's go in t let's talk
about IT right maybe I'd like to work
with Google but I but I hate working
with like that go
I don't want doctor God to have my
search queries so I just go to Google
it's my right to choose how is my info
processed right if I give someone money
information my home address to send me a
postcard that doesn't mean I consent to
that home address being published on the
Internet
that's the cow of data privacy and what
information is processed right if
someone has my common dress it doesn't
mean I'm ok with them having my phone
number or vice versa
and a different facet of that is right
to decide who I interact with right the
the classical right to privacy before
we've had so much information around we
can call it the the right to be left
alone if I don't want to talk to anyone
I I don't talk to anyone
that is reason why I don't have a phone
number
I do have phone not-not-not like some
other guys here kudos to those is there
at least two guys two speakers the
conference that that don't that don't
use the phone I do but I don't have a
phone number because I don't I want to
be left alone when I want interact with
someone I'll go and ask if they won't
talk to me I'll talk to them I don't
have a doorbell for reals I won't be
left alone and I don't give people my
address as well so those are the
fundamental aspects of privacy to me now
I've given a presentation on the topic
of privacy in the past year I've given
one here in bulk on a year ago I've also
given one at 35 c3 chaos list and I've
gotten some reactions from people in all
the presentations I've given on the
privacy topic so let's take a look at
some of them this is there's both the
reaction of course five thumbs up I'm
feeling like use reCAPTCHA take a look
at my previous presentation I I tried
not to include any slides from that
today because York has passed but but
it's also I hope entertaining and and
eye-opening
so yeah
then we have stuff like that interesting
and also not worth it at all your time
on this planet is limited you know then
gotten some comments after presentation
like it's pointless anyway you have a
phone you're on Twitter blah blah blah
and and of course this this was the best
here what are you presenting your
presentation without a face mask if you
care about privacy so much well if you
listen carefully you know the answer to
these questions privacy is about consent
and and I'm ok with you taking photos of
me or my slides or filming me and
putting me online while I'm standing
here when I'm gonna go and sit over
there I don't want to be filmed or than
one like photos to be taken so it's all
about consent but let's let's take a
look at this rather good argument your
time on this planet is limited I do
think about it a lot and and yeah I have
to make some hard choices right we we
aren't here forever like maybe 15 years
hundred years if you're lucky so it does
cost a lot of time and money um so you
have to find some balance but then again
if you got nothing to hide they have
some more arguments for you right one is
data hoarding and so someone that just
collects a piece of information about
you that may be not a threat not not
much of a threat but if someone say
government is in that position usually
collect a lot of information about you
then they hoard the data about you and
can lead to various consequences like
for example they can impersonate you
which is not what the government usually
does right but blackmail we don't know
no one no one is admitting off like that
but but oh that did I think US
government admitted blackmailing
who is that Martin Luther King yeah so
yeah that stuff happens so data hoarding
leads to problems like and not only
government raw large corporations can
core data you and they can they can
impersonate you or hackers can hack that
data stash and then impersonate you now
back to government most of us are happy
enough lucky enough to live in countries
with relatively good governments that
don't go killing people or or putting
them in jail for no good reason most of
them most of the people sound some some
get to end up in jail for no good reason
unfortunately but today's government
that we have today might not be there
for long government doesn't usually live
for a hundred or even 50 years it looks
for like four or five years and you
don't know what you will get and it
might be replaced by the tow terrian
were simply inhumane regime and now that
it has all the data on you what we'll do
is the data now that it knows stuff that
is okay luckily to know today like
someone's sexual orientation over
political affiliation might and might
end you up on on on watchlist or a kill
list and then herd immunity finally this
is the most important for me this is
actually the real reason why I why am I
not wearing a face mask giving this
presentation I don't really care about
on privacy so much I I care about people
who really need privacy
people who are not in the position to do
as I do who cannot fight their
governments on or or who cannot come to
a hotel in Serbia and tell them I'm not
I'm not allowing you to copy my ID here
you can see it but you're not copying it
right because I know I have like up
friends here here here at the conference
who would really like me to speak or or
if if they kick me out of the hotel they
would provide something else for me so
many people are not in position like
that
so I want to support the people who
really need that because many people not
hiding anything will make the few
that do have something to hide stand out
more and that matter draw suspicion just
because they are hiding something and
that is that is important now for the
next part I want to talk about privacy
nightmares so some of the things that I
observe around me or online that that's
not so good for privacy
well my presentation a year ago had had
this slide the presentation started with
my words privacy is dead and a year ago
I presented how how in May last year
people daily try and tweeted that hey we
found a new use for surveillance cameras
let's point them at our children that
are learning in schools and then we can
you know have this nice menu for the for
the teacher then you see how many pupils
are concentrating how many pupils are
not paying attention coming you're
afraid right please don't call me out I
haven't done my homework and I see that
immediately so that's a cool tag they
had last year now in January 2019
there's a new thing from China so
Chinese school scanning children's
brains the scenes they're concentrating
apparently the last system didn't have
enough data quality maybe maybe it had a
lot of false positives or false
negatives so this this should go well
but it's not only it's not only China
specifically all right we have we have
this this thing here where people are
students is still in small small
children are getting into the schools
through a face scanner and so basically
the marketing ploy and this one is it
makes schools more secure because you
can find missing children you can I'm
sure you can reuse or abused information
in a myriad of ways but as of if we talk
about keeping bumpers out at the school
I mean it's not hard to jump that that
barrier for an adult male or female so
yeah then we have Hong Kong of course
this happened in June 2019 people were
being aware of tracking their movement
and they were kinda afraid to use their
MetroCard so what what what they were
doing there
buying paper tickets even though they
usually use this digital system in
Latvia where I come from we also have a
digital system for for traveling in the
public transport and we actually had a
case it was parts of parts of the case
were public unfortunately a driver
driving public transport a Rundle red
light and and killed someone so the
police pulled the record of of all the
personalized cards used on the transport
and interrogated the rewedding I mean
I'm all for resolving crimes in in the
reasonable manner but I believe in a
society where everybody who who has
something contribute to an investigation
of that kind would go to the police
themselves and say yeah I saw something
and and if they didn't see something
they would not go to the police so I
kind of look look down upon police using
using this data like that but I mean it
can be in other ways for sure if they
have the access to the data here for for
protests in Hong Kong people were afraid
that they will end up on some watch list
because of going to the protest so they
were smart enough to use paper tickets
luckily we still have the option to buy
paper tickets if you look at my last
year's presentation in Latvia for say
high school student or university
student the difference between using
subsidized tickets or buying a paper
ticket is a six hundred and sixty six
percent increase no joke in in the price
let's talk about Facebook everyone loves
Facebook anyone here is on Facebook yeah
we have some people any one of you buy
their own free will I get I get live we
have some I guess my friends threatening
me all the time we're gonna make you a
Facebook account if you don't if you
don't join yeah sometimes they do but
then then I talk to them nicely and and
they you know they remove the Facebook
account to get to get get back access to
their computer so this is this is a
quote this is an article actually that
has some quotes surrounding a court case
where Facebook was was either put on
trial or being put on trial I'm not I'm
not
experts on American legal system so what
they said what representative said is
there is no privacy interest in using
Facebook because by sharing with a
hundred friends on social media platform
which is an affirmative social act to
publish to disclose to share ostensibly
private information with hundred people
you have just under centuries of common
law under the judgment of Congress under
the ACA negated any reasonable
expectation of privacy so once again
this here is about data reuse their
argument is you publish it to your
friends so it's public domain like we
can copy it we can we can do it everyone
does it if someone has if some of the
Facebook users here have actually read
the agreement they have his Facebook
maybe legally that's the case I'm not
sure I haven't read it but just because
I'm not a facebook user because I
actually have read all my license
agreements with Twitter and and other
software they use some ten years ago I
was working for an international company
that had an office where I live and on
my first day when when they had this
onboarding meeting they told me this is
a software he gonna use I looked at the
software tried to launch it it it
presented me with an agreement and I I
went back to my superiors that case
there's there's agreement for for almost
all the stuff for what do I do it's an
American company so they said well I
mean you have to read it so they were
paying me for almost four full days to
read fleiss's agreements for where the
software is gonna use so that's kind of
cool the since then I read the license
agreements so but here in this Facebook
case they are in my opinion
misunderstanding a basic fact about
privacy it's still about consent it's by
Mark consent if I have consented to
share this piece of information who is
one of my friends or with a hundred of
my friends or with ten thousand of my
friends it doesn't mean that a different
person has the right to read it
yes the reality is such as it is hard to
control and the argument has some merit
because the article also has has some
quote like from that relates to to the
middle-ages I think
or after that when you go to a public
square and just shout stuff outright no
reasonable special private you there
well I mean with today's technology it
has drawn looking at who is hearing what
you felt in maybe it could help them
hold them accountable and not propagate
the information any further one more
thing about Facebook suicide prevention
if you read an article about the little
prevention on Facebook anyone thinks
it's a it's a good thing a cool thing
something we do need that yeah yeah some
people do that's it the bad is that it
is a bad thing yeah some people do as
well so yeah I also personally have
mixed feelings about that
I mean suicide prevention is an
important task that that needs to be
carried out at some point but the the
way Facebook carries it out is is quite
creepy maybe even unnecessary creepy in
my opinion so this is from their
official official description of of the
of the tool of the algorithm they also
have this nice picture in there about
how it works so we have some signals
right for example what you type when you
type it what day you type it on with a
also analyze the comments that people
add then they have some magical
algorithms AI basically machine learning
that decides if the post should be
reviewed by a human or not and then it's
reviewed by a human and then the human
can take action and there are a couple
actions they can take they can send tips
or resources or they can escalate to
local authorities and now I would prefer
to see an algorithm like that even
though algorithms are creepy even more
creepier than humans in my opinion
because you know it's it's not a human
you know what it thinks so
I would prefer human not to be involved
in this because one of the two actions
sent tips and resources is this so
basically this stuff appears on your
Facebook screen that that's it that's
the action so false positive wouldn't be
too damaging to the user and I mean
Facebook is investing a lot to draw
people to continue to continuously use
it so I mean
users wouldn't stop using it just
because they get some false positives
like that I think so involving a human
is is maybe not that necessary at at
that point now continuing on the topic
of Facebook there's new cool thing
called Facebook dating it appeared in
the in the u.s. it was rolled out just
now and this coming to you at the
beginning of next year yeah I can't wait
so actually from the article because I
haven't haven't taken a look at it yet
from the article it seems that Facebook
is rolling out some additional privacy
features alongside Facebook dating which
is something that people in u.s. don't
get people in EU get the gdpr thing and
the Facebook is really tough on on
things right which is which is making
life harder for stalkers and other bad
people um in the u.s. they don't have
such a tight application to do that but
with Facebook dating they're bringing
some of the EU features - to the US
which is good but one thing that
Facebook dating is bringing to the US
and most likely to you as well is
location confirmation so in order to be
able to every use the feature you have
to have a GPS enabled device and it has
to have been on at some point if you
want to change your location for some
reason well likely you have moved so we
have traveled the GPS has to have been
on at the new location again so we are
actually gonna be providing the security
conscious of us are going to be
providing more data to Facebook if we
decide to use the feature then for CCTV
I had this slide in my presentation last
year this is from UK all of those three
are real posters from the streets of the
UK government watching you but what I
have to add well now they doing this
stuff facial recognition and man was
fined 90 pounds for refusing to show his
face the police trialing new facial
recognition software
I read the article carefully I read
alternate sources that's it that was the
crime not showing face - the software
and he was forced to show the face to
the software and find he he wasn't find
anything else he wasn't under warrant
warrant or
nothing nothing he just was walking by
pulled his jumper above his chin and
that's it and they a you suspicious you
scan your face at them so that's where
we're living in then we have that saying
the end of the under fan to end
encryption it's coming
unfortunately GCHQ suggested that we
need to end this thing they even called
it warrant proof encryption which again
it's it is in a way weren't proof but is
it better or not that is that is
debatable thing
GCHQ isn't the only one trying to do
that basically five eyes is is on two on
twenty encryption and they wanna then
one end it and the first country the
first large country was with enough
impact that that's actually doing that
already is of course Australia they've
had the the law which is not like 100
percent hard law saying no but it's 99
percent like no end-to-end encryption
like or you have to give access somehow
it's been it's been in an in power for
half a year maybe a year so yeah we've
done struggle we sent an encryption now
because I certainly has that Firewise
want that in a year I bet one of the
large whatsapp so sorry
messaging applications are gonna
implement something about that so
speaking of whatsapp this thing happened
so an article appeared saying that in in
the whatsapp help saying that routed
phones are not supported by what's up
anymore so you you can't is rooted phone
wonder why well they say because that
way we can't provide the security that
we're supposed to provide you or in
there were and they were in their word
what's up security model cannot function
as intended wonder what their model is
we also have the same of course for iOS
same stuff don't jailbreaking phone
sorry not gonna work so if you can't use
rooted android phones and if you can't
use jailbroken iOS devices what do you
do because web doesn't work without
mobile do
for what's up well obviously you use a
third-party app for what's up oh wait
but you can't really use that and
they've been doing that for five years
but but they're doing that like every
two years and and beginning of this
year's I started this new cycle again
warning everyone do not use on official
apps you're gonna be blocked right and
it's it's been their in their
information materials for quite some
time right your account will get
temporarily banned that means you used
an unofficial app please don't do that
so use an official app so we're screwed
we can't block what's up from doing bad
stuff through routing our phone we can't
install third-party app for another loud
- luckily we have other services but
we'll see what happens
with them because personally I'm I'm not
so sure that government would hesitate
to block a whole service if they run out
of options
or maybe block VPNs for example like
some countries have been doing Russia
China and one of the Saudi countries
VPNs are banned Latvia where I'm from
has started the debate on blocking VP
and even though four years ago I was
part of governmental discussions saying
this is slippery slope you're gonna end
banning VPNs if you do the censorship
stuff that the censorship stuff and now
they gonna wanna ban VPNs now it's a bit
depressing right I see lots of frowny
faces let's let's talk about good stuff
GDP our GDP our is good especially for
those living in the I think actually you
can kinda you can kind of pretend to be
in the you to to to use GDP are in in
some circumstance I haven't seen any
research done on that but if someone
wants to do a presentation next bulk on
maybe you can do some research like can
you can you use UDP air for good if
you're not a EU citizen anyway so some
of you what many of you not cough but
what many of you are EU citizens and
then tell you what you can get and those
of you who can become
EU citizens either by joining the the
great union that were or by by by simply
becoming citizen of an e state this is
what we get this is this how we can
protect and IV protect our data and I've
used many of those quite extensively
the thing is we've had GDP or like
legislation in Latvia for the past 18
years before GDP came along so nothing
really changed except it's fines we had
maximum fine of 500 euros now it's a
million or whatever so that changed so
you get the right to know who is
processing what and why and there's a
list of things that that you can get
from the date processor the next couple
of slides have have been legally taken
from the European Union they said you
can use them as long as you quote the
author so copyright European Union yeah
so you can get all a bunch of this stuff
and what I do is that I mostly base off
bad data processors so if they if they
abuse my data I just send the request
for everything when you get it who did
you get it how do you process it do you
have any automation stuff like that and
then and then they have to write the
answer to that we'll have questions in
the end please write it down so we
remember that then you can also have the
right to object you can say nope I don't
want you to process my data anymore
yeah in case you've given it to them you
also have the right to have the data
deleted it's a bit different from the
other one right one is if they
processing it based on the law the other
one is if they processing it based on
the contract or if you have a contract
like you can even have it they delete it
for example if you submit a photo to a
non-governmental entity for some reason
before a contract you can have it
deleted nice huh
and you can also access your own data
right you can ask give me everything you
know about me and those things lead to
of course the right to move your data if
you can get your data and you can delete
your data you can move it to a different
provider and this right specifically
tells it has to be in a reasonable
format so they can't send you scanned
handwritten notes with your data if they
have it in database they have to give it
to you in a database like format so you
can port it easily the right to correct
your data of course is very important
credit registries are a huge thing in
the US and smaller thing in the EU if
they have wrong yet about you you can't
you can't do anything unless you like
cash a lot like I do and and then you
don't care about the banks think about
you
having the right to correct your data is
a good thing and and this is the best
one you have a right to have a say when
decisions are automated so we have a
bunch of startups doing all this AI
machine learning crap and basically you
submit some data and they say okay
you're going to use the app you're not
going to use the app you can do that
you're not gonna do that you gotta have
credit you're gonna have smaller credit
and you have a right to say I want human
review on that unless it's government
mandated then then you don't have the
right to do that so I've exercised
that's right on the service it was
providing taxi it was a taxi app it was
providing transportation so I said hey I
don't I don't like you banning my
prepaid payment cards I need a human to
review the decision because it's not
fraud that's my prepaid payment court
yes I have ten of them because the limit
is a hundred euros and I buy them each
month and yeah they basically send me a
letter saying okay since you don't trust
us to do automatic review we are
deleting your user so we going to court
on that one right now we touched we
already touched the story's part so last
year I gave a bunch of stories about how
my life is going doing doing privacy
enforcement for myself I have news
stories for you including we'll talk
more about taxi app as well but let's
start with certification I mean I don't
I don't personally I'm not a big fan of
certification but I have to have
certification because of reasons so I do
certification exams I do a lot of them
usually like two or three new
certificates per year and every time
they want to take and store a photo of
my face and I can't understand why so
every time I write them it's not a gdpr
but that's there's this eu-us agreement
called privacy shield which is supposed
to protect citizens when data is
processed in the u.s. so write them a
privacy shield request every time after
successfully passing an exam saying hey
great exam delete my biometrics
including my face
and every time they delete it after
after some discussion and and then they
take the photo again like they don't get
tired of that every time I suggest maybe
next time don't force me to take a photo
ignore that so okay that's all right my
right is the requests deadly
so one time this is what happened I
requested the data deletion they deleted
the data and then my certificates were
gone so we can't we cut long
conversation it took about two months to
restore the certificates and you know
what they asked me could you send us the
list of certificates you enter storage
I of course tried not to of use that I
just have nope I'm not sending you I
could send you anything you find the
certificates so they restored almost all
the certificates except some that I've
taken during BET exams and I said hey
you haven't restored all of them look
look deeper they looked for a couple
more weeks and they restored all
certificates yeah they sincerely
apologized and and now I'm thinking if
there's a good lawyer who would talk
that pro bono because I mean it's it's
yeah I mean they apologized so it's all
good right
okay mobile apps so this thing here
right we can we have an app iOS model
currently also available on on the new
versions of Android when you when you
have power to decide on permission to
permission basis if you want the app to
have that access or not so here we have
an app asking you to access the contact
socratic would like to access your
contacts and iOS well Apple iOS
developers meaning Apple of course
provide a nice ability for the app
creators to enter some custom text to
explain what's going on so socratic has
done that they saying it's only for
chatting about homework don't worry okay
cool
so of course you you select the right
option I mean the left option you press
don't allow and of course socratic says
we kind of need that
sorry go to settings so that's what many
apps do and more and more apps will be
doing if not for gdpr so that's kind of
good then we have the de taxi app so our
our fight started kind of is this they
they change their brand and updated
their visual identity and you you
totally cannot see it in the picture but
under this white pop up in the left
corner there's a menu button where you
can access all your write history your
email address your data logout stuff
like that the button cannot be pressed
because the problem is over it since
they update so I submitted the
submitted the support request and they
asked me what is your email address our
first test why do you need my email
address it's a bug in your app they said
sorry we can't process we can't process
any support questions on email risk so I
said I wrote them
sorry I can't access my email address
your app doesn't work I don't know what
any motorist is so but the good thing is
I could still use that I could still
press the pick up manually button on the
bottom there and I could I could call
the taxi so what I did is I I came back
from conference to my airport I I call
the taxi I wrote down the taxi drivers
name the the license plate the time I
called for the taxi time I got in the
taxi the time I get out of the taxi and
I send this to them hey you probably can
you know look in the database this is me
that's me that's a guy that's my driver
that's the license plate and so on and
they told me nope we don't have access
to that so I created a different support
account I wrote them an email hey by the
way do you by any chance store
information on which user drives which
which car is the passenger at what time
they said yeah so then I went back to my
first user reference the other support
they kept saying hey you have the data
and then they disappeared so then we
went to the paper paper trail thing he's
starting writing to them and and that is
basically that's basically when they
wrote me wrote me an official letter
it's missing a signature though so we
still have to allegedly they wrote me an
official letter we still have to find
out if it's they or not saying that
since you have lost trust in our
application we are here by removing your
user from our application which of
course followed from my side by I
exercise my right which was not one of
the not on not on the right slide this
is also right under gdpr
the right to temporarily block all
processing of data so if there's a
dispute about your date processing you
have a right to ask the company to not
do anything is they to put it away and
just wait for the court decision so
that's what I asked so yeah no I don't
have a taxi service too bad but we have
another taxi service in Latvia it's
called Yandex taxi
it didn't work from the beginning when I
when I when I installed it just to try
it out I I was flying I think to Ukraine
I use foreign SIM cards in outside EU so
I I wrote the taxi to the airport in
Latvia I saw the driver put me five or
five stars I did the same to him I
turned off my phone turned out the turn
of the app turn my phone put in
Ukrainian SIM card
come back to Latvia put back my sim card
turn on the phone
open the taxi app taxi app says hey good
news you can ride with Yandex taxi next
time in 2022 December 31st you've been
bad I don't know I mean crazy stuff so
now only this year they actually publish
the privacy policy outlining what kind
of information they need and for some
information they say yeah we need
location to provide you better service
but you can't turn off location through
the settings and then so fine now but
there are categories of data that you
cannot not give them right for example
it's super important for them to have
user interaction like scrolling clicking
and dragging this menu otherwise app can
not work it's super important for them
to know who made your device what
operating system is and what version is
what your screen size the sensor
information like what sensors do you
have in your phone this camera sensor
may be device identifiers and so on
amount of disk placed list of installed
apps and it all goes to to an app that's
owned by a company in Russia so and you
can't turn it off
there we go um continuing with mobile
apps messaging Konami mostly last year I
told year I found a way to message
naanum asleep well actually I told it's
hard to message honestly I have no way
then then I spoke to some people and now
I have all the messaging apps each of
them has a separate phone number I
travel lock the cons so I just take a
conference conference mobile cards I
register an account and I have my
account so that's great
the problem is when it expires someone
can go and rewrite it so what they do
you use lock codes you lock down your
account but what happens then then every
like months or even more often the app
says hey do you still remember your PIN
now I don't remember my pain I've
written down somewhere just in case but
I don't want remember it it's a
throwaway account but you get these
reminders so it's a bit annoying that
way
how they actually buy apps anonymous
link well I haven't given I use this
this is an iPhone here I use an iPhone I
haven't given my credit card I don't
have a credit card I haven't given any
of my information to Apple so it's it's
a fake name don't tell them and and the
fake address and doesn't have a credit
card so sometimes there are some good
apps that you wanna or need to pay for
doesn't matter I I want to pay for good
apps how they bar them well gift cards
obviously you ask a friend to give you
to give you a gift card and the good
thing is you don't actually have to
answer a real email at all
you can enter local cos at local cost
and email gets sent to nowhere but the
people the person buying it gets a
prompt do you want to print out the gift
card and there's a code in there so if
you take the gift card code and you and
you use that yeah but I mean it it does
it does come at all my friends I mean
they get they get tired of me asking for
all the time
so privacy privacy is hard can idea then
last last year I told you I've been I've
been interested in privacy for five to
ten years well apparently that's not
true
turns out I've been into privacy for at
least 15 years this is a voucher to
access conference for free from
thousands before on top there's my name
and afterwards there is an address which
is on the rest of the hotel but I've
never rented a room in so apparently
somehow 15 years ago I thought it's not
a good idea to give these guys my home
address speaking of home address I still
don't give people my dress but I
love to receive mails so I use post
office boxes I don't know how much it
cost in your countries in Latvia it's
around 15 euros per year
and you get a post office box it's
amazing but we are getting these New Age
people like I've actually had I've
actually had a situation with government
agency this month they apologized to me
saying so a young a young lady talked to
me in in in the agency and and told me
sorry I'm not from
Soviet times I didn't know what that
address means so I we were we were
communicating with current agencies
through postal mail as I do and I had my
P o box on it as the return address and
they didn't send me the reply through
there instead they googled me and said
to be an email so ya parently that's old
people's stuff using using P or boxes
but I mean it's nice secure and you can
send me send me stuff so yeah airport
scanners they're the new ones those are
very good right it's fast secure and
safe and no radiation toll or not so
yeah you can actually opt out of those
and I suggest you do and I think it's
almost like everywhere except UK I mean
the oh really also you don't get that
yeah so yeah it's under the Queen right
so obviously um maybe they did at the
same time right because UK had an
opt-out then they decided nope no
uploads and I mean you you have they
positioned like that you have an opt-out
you can go through scanner or you can
opt out and not flying that's your
choice then European Court went and told
nope UK you're doing it wrong you have
written right here that is not the way
you do it so now you can opt out but
well not for long if brexit happens then
they they have already announced plans
to put it back as well mandatory opt-out
thingy where you have to have to do it
yeah don't do it one thing one thing I
dislike about those alongside radiation
is of course the automated decision
which is interesting on under gdpr I
mean you could ask you could ask on GDP
are to say I don't want a taking
decision on whether I'm suspicious or
not I want a human to take the decision
because that's once again I find out
which is creepy I prefer humans when
when possible and the finally boarding
passes in shops in the airport it's
gotten worse since gdpr I don't know why
before gdpr I've had problems like maybe
20 30 percent of the times when buying
stuff in in in an airport like they they
ask you for the boarding pass I
no thanks then they thought I didn't
hear what they said so they repeat again
I said no thanks and I don't wanna give
you my boarding pass blah blah blah a
longer one so and then they go away well
then they they back off about the
boarding pass
now since GDP are 100 percent of time I
have to call supervisor I don't know
what's going on they're like no we have
to scan because the system is made in a
way that it won't let you let you buy
anything so my question of course is how
are you gonna use my name and how are
you gonna use my frequent flyer number
what are you going to be doing with that
so they can never answer that question
when you call supervisor say the system
only stores your flight number so I say
my flag number is BT six for one then
they say ok supervisor knows the
employees don't know how to track their
own system there so it's a bit sad so my
idea coming here to this conference and
almost not being able to buy a thing
again is let's make a barcode app for
shopping how about that I'm I'm on board
I'm gonna work I'm gonna I'm gonna help
I need some more people come talk to me
let's make an app of course we wouldn't
be using it to get into business
launches or or or to get into an
airplane or security zone but for
shopping right so let's make an app
where you can just just select what you
need press the button show them the damn
barcode and they're happy you're happy
everything moves along right and and
yeah people aren't mad at you so the
question the subtitle of the
presentation of my talk is should we fix
privacy or not so it worth it should
they work on it
well let's take a look at what have been
done so far and how successful it was
the user demand I mark it with a
negative sign the users are not
demanding privacy we have not been able
to fix it so far too bad we had the
cookie law in EU in 2012 I mark it with
a negative sign as well that's annoying
thing I don't actually know if people
for example from the US if coming here
and using the local or not here but
coming to the U and using a local metal
summer in the EU makes makes those
things pop up and you don't see them at
home or they pop up for everybody I'm
not sure but in the U it's a pop-up
saying hey we use cookies press ok
so that's that's a fix and it hasn't
fixed anything well but now this doesn't
in we have gdpr and for big data gdpr
hasn't fixed anything because GBP are
only applies to data that can be tied to
your identity it doesn't have to have
your real name isn't % but it has to
have enough real actual data to be able
to identify that that is you big data
doesn't qualify if they can identify
that that is a male between ages of 20
and 30 livings they're liking that that
could be like any of the 10 males
fitting the description so that's not
personal data under GDP are so fail fail
him there but GDP are in general for
everything else including some online
things and many offline things I mark it
with a plus it has done it has a lot of
good things so it has given me some hope
maybe fixing privacy if it's a legal way
to do it or it's a technical way to do
it or it's a hacker way to do it maybe
it's not a lost cause and maybe we
should should just try for 6 more years
to see what happens in 2025 thank you
so if we have a mic here we do have a
mic we can we can take some questions I
can answer the first question already so
I'm not wearing a hoody or or a mask
because I consent to me being filmed we
have the second question over there okay
I have a question under gdpr how do you
know that all your data has been given
to you I mean you have no ways to check
yes that's true and the problem for
Latvia is the Data Protection Authority
doesn't have the right to start criminal
cases and then the real Ministry of law
it's not really allowed just to go
ransack in their databases in the
suspect company's databases so that is
problematic maybe in some countries that
do have the authority and then it's easy
but I don't have a story about that it's
an ongoing story death protection
authorities looking into it
I do love our DPA actually when when
they were looking for for the head of
the DPA I had three separate friends
mailing me saying hey apply to that
that's your thing so but the story so I
recently noticed that in the inter in
the bank of my bank there's a section
saying your date I pressed your data and
there's just one button saying request
your data so press the button it said in
a week you'll get your data so a week
later I go to the intern banks there's a
PDF to download that download the PDF
there's some data well but I look at it
and it's like it's like some data I mean
I know there is the data in the intern
Bank itself they do not have to give it
in the PDF because I can access it and
then there's some other data that's not
in each intern Bank and that's in the
PDF but I realize I know from my
experience as as a pen tester including
working with financial institutions that
they have to store failed attempts for
credit cards and I did use credit cards
like 10 years ago and that wasn't
included I know for the of the law on
counterterrorism financing or
counter-financing the third
that they have to store a photo of my
face and a photo of my ID and it's not
including either so that's an easy case
I go to the DPA and I go to the
financial Commission I said I say to
them so either they broke gdpr by not
leaving the data were they breaking the
tourism law by not stirring my data so
now they have to make a choice
sometimes that happens yep
so about that Facebook algorithm you
mentioned one for suicide prevention do
you think it reads also the private
messaging or just publicly post date oh
I think it's very the private messaging
and I don't think it's the only
algorithm betrays a private message yeah
can I get them can get the mic to the
comment guy does a plot for those guy I
have two friends that work on that
suicide prevention team in Facebook and
it reads absolutely everything including
and that this is just this is not
specific to them face book reads
messages that you never even send like
it reads things that you type into text
fields and then erase so it's all it's
all part of the machine and I've told
both those friends that they're working
for a bad company and they should quit
and I advise anyone to tell that to
their friends who work for Facebook to
okay some more questions
hi so thank you for your talk two points
one is that I got an Apple iPhone from
my work as a business mobile and I had
the same problem I didn't want to create
a personalized and entity and I didn't
want to give my credit card stuff like
that so I bought in the trip in a
business trip in Germany to Apple gift
cards and when I go back to Greece I
couldn't use them because my Apple
identity was register in Greece so I
cannot use that so the workaround of
thought is I created a second anonymous
account register in Germany to use the
Germany Apple gift cards to to my phone
so I don't know if that is the case with
you because a gift card then you
encounter transfer to a different
country user and then use it yeah gift
card yeah yeah that's the other thing I
mean I got the same thing with what's
that a similar thing is what's up but in
in Latvia we can't even have a
possibility to buy prepaid prepaid Apple
cards so we don't have that problem
yeah and the second thing I'd like to
have your opinion in Greece there's a no
but the CPS the Reuters that the ISPs
gives to customers and now they cannot
change the DNS settings of the router so
they have to be it's a gray text post of
the ISPs should only provide to the
customers their own DNS services this is
under regulation law so the customers
cannot visiting sites that are not
approved from a government yeah
if you know you intend to the initial
settings on your computer of course but
what do you think about this is this
something about privacy
do we need to I don't know make a
statement do something else
well my first reaction was that cannot
be a law but you seem to know what
you're saying so if it's a law it's a
law
i I don't think that's a good idea but
there are multiple ways to circumvent
that right you could you could tell the
the telecom company I don't want your
stuff in my house
so they put it in the in the corridor
not in your house and you can always
change route errs right they can have
the router you can have your router so
in that scenario
and and I mean I've had similar things
in Latvia working of working with
consulting clients and to make their
life more safer so we don't have that
law but still I space push for that they
want their stuff on your premises so I
have multi multi step program which will
not work if it's a legal requirement or
it might so the multi step program is as
follows I ask that be nicely to please
remove or remove the router because
we're going to put our own router if
they don't cooperate we we just put our
own router after their router and then
if the router has Wi-Fi antennas which
is a problem then we once again ask them
nicely to remove the router what are we
gonna break off the demo tense and short
them and and I've done that for four
clients
yeah more questions
first thank you for the good
presentation if I understand well gdpr
is used to protect my personal data that
can be linked to me and what happens if
say a big company can stalk or buy data
in which the data that is accumulated so
that it can be linked to me so well
yeah so GD pair for big data that's
that's a problem we haven't we haven't
fixed that but I mean as soon as I have
your email address many DPAs in in
different European countries say that's
that's already identifiable it helps to
have your full name your email address
than that then you know then it then it
works for example I am working on a
complaint where where someone has is
referencing my domain in their latest
work and since it has been my domain for
15 or 20 years and when you open the
webpage actually says that's my full
name that's my email address so I'm kind
of trying to put them into the direction
that it is that is private data but yeah
for big data in general there's there's
nothing we can do under GDP or if if
it's not identifiable it's actually I
don't know if we still have time for for
questions what do you think five minutes
okay
yeah so couple more questions about how
to make your life harder by by being
private what's your experience with the
GDP our entity in in your country are
they are they complete are they
adequately staffed are they adequately
knowledgeable because in my home country
this this is a big mess so GDP is
basically a lot because they have they
can't do anything oh yeah so GDP our
rent entities responsible for GDP are in
in European countries are called data
protection authorities or DPAs
our DPA is not adequately staffed but at
least they finally have a good a good
leader a good a good head of the DPA but
they do have problem with staffing and I
haven't I haven't worked with them for
for I think two years now but I just
recently about a months ago which is the
the window they had replying to you I
haven't I haven't sentence it to them
but now I have sent a bunch so what they
have been doing two years ago I think I
still can do that when a month passes
they send you a letter saying we
apologize we cannot answer right now we
extend the deadline there is a provision
says I can do that but it cannot be
because of understaffing it's because
they have to collect more data so
technically at least by Latin law I
could go to court and challenge that
extension and I've asked the previous
head of the DPA do you want me to do
that because I can do that the court can
rule in my favor and then you can go to
the government ask for money but they
said no so I haven't tested the current
head of the DPA if that's if that's what
they want because if I want I'll do that
and maybe maybe we get some money for
that but it's not a priority financially
yeah that's true
right so you can ask me some more
questions if you manage to find me in in
the conference somewhere and thanks
follow me on Twitter the slides are on
curls that work you can take a look at
them so thanks bye bye
you