so next up is McClement with emojis how
the do they work and you should be
afraid of them thank you okay thank you
see it seems that I have a reputation to
meet now that means no pressure
yeah if you have never seen or heard of
me I'm Mike lemon you can find me on
these interweb thingies some of the most
comfy instance of the fairy birds
available I'm still somewhere on Twitter
it's intentionally not readable because
I really look into it
England fairy Wars or somewhere else you
can find me if you want to use these
social media things about my talk please
use the Balcom hashtag and mot what the
that will work and we'll be having
a look at emoji and how do they actually
work so quick question raise of hands
who thinks that the the things with
emoji started about ten years ago and
there's one into me okay that's a very
very few hands twenty years ago
still very very few hands okay
fifty
like okay few more century ago
okay everybody is laughing no hands
anymore more than a century one hand two
three you'll be in for a surprise
okay yeah at that's time when these
multi things started the Sun was shining
and will shine some light on that
question now like three thousand six
hundred seventy years ago before f40
being IT people we use a proper point of
zero which is a port of course the Sun
was shining at the land of the he
titties that is roughly where turkey is
now so this is a rough map of back then
in the time to the left hand corner you
have the blue thing is the sea that's
water okay you with me
let's the Mediterranean Sea on the upper
right hand corner you have the Black Sea
and this alla Xia Island is now called
Cyprus so that we have a rough
orientation where we are and in the city
of karkemish drinks were stored in in
clay jugs empty cans like ground chuck
with a wood handle that wood rings him
and this chart was found unearthed
rebuilt and they found a smiley face on
it and scientifically we can actually
prove it it's actually a smiley because
there's no other markings drawings or
anything on this one or any other jug so
this is probably one of the oldest
smiley faces ever reproduced in the
world
this was unearthed by people in
University of Bologna and this
particular chart was used for sherbet
which is a sweet lemonade drink so
people are happy with sweet things fast
forward
to two hundred twenty nine years before
that's like fast-forward three thousand
four hundred years in a city in Slovakia
a signature was found in a book about
the city treasury and that someone was
really satisfied with the results so
they make a smiley face in the Treasury
books I will not pronounce try to
pronounce that proper name of an abbot
and notary in a sisters in closer I'll
probably totally immerse myself so I'll
spare you that I come up to me if you
actually want to know who that was ten
years before a park getting closer to
our IT reference of zero people began to
work on asking the American standard for
information interchange so we're getting
to modern times so let's move our
timescale a little you have the zero on
the right hand side we'll just move that
to the left and events are coming a lot
denser now in the 70s we have the
plateau for which is a computer system
it was used to view microfiche archives
probably many of you have no idea what a
microfiche is it's not related to fish
like animals and basically a fish is a
piece of analog film and you basically
take a photo of a newspaper or a
document and put it on a film and
because film is very reliable as a long
storage long term medium for storage and
also very high resolution so you can
really reproduce fine details in a very
small scale and this device was used to
view these things that's a plateau v
it's I could not get a free picture of a
plateau for it had a transparent plasma
display 512 pixels squared resolution
touchscreen programmable graphics fonts
a back projection for this film
microfiche viewing a voice synthesizer
audio recording audio playback a four
voice music synthesizer and that was in
the 70s that was really really really
ahead of it
I'm back then and what else was there on
this particular machine these things it
was possible to print characters over
each other like if he is a typewriter
printing type of character go back one
character type another one it lands on
top of it and with that machine it was
possible to do that on screen and on
print and by typing weird sequences of
characters you could actually make the
pixels line up to build up a smiley like
this Viktor or objects or Victorina
Smiley's and people were using that and
sharing like oh you need to this this
sequence to get the smile and yeah
thanks to Brian deer for sending me
these natural 70 screenshots wonderful
and in the early 80s we have a person
named Scott Fahlman he proposed using :
- closing race to mark ironic postings
in a scientific context because it was
the Carnegie Mellon University in the
United States he also proposed for
things that were too close to reality to
make a frowning smiley the frowny was
invented so yeah we have emoticons isn't
it wonderful
we have emoticons yeah and these tilted
to the left side faces they're called
the so-called western style emoticons in
the southern hemisphere so if you're
from Australia or New Zealand you might
see them the other way around
yep so shadow to our Aussie friends what
else happened in 1982 any ideas shout it
out to me
emoticons huh what was have you attended
my last year's talk probably not
email SMTP and message format RFC 81 821
and 822 they were invented in 1982 as
well as oh emails really old if you want
to don't get into emails just no don't
come serious there's other emoji
especially emoji styles now this is a
Japanese style usually the Japanese do
emoji up front facing and up right so
not tilted and on the side these are
called cow Moo G from the Japanese word
cow meaning face and moji meaning a
glyph for character so these are
literally face characters but the pretty
fitting term for what they actually do
and these came up in ASCII net in Japan
in Japan in around 86 ish then there's
the Korean style interesting thing here
is they don't use any ASCII characters
anymore but they use Korean characters
called llamo and Hangul being the Korean
script type and Yama main character in
Korean and they look like this for
example they had already extended ASCII
characters of course our skis 7-bit and
only has 127 characters that's not a lot
and they had to use certain encodings to
make that work and when it comes to
encoding many people think of this one
of course this is absolutely not
possible in ascii if you want to have
the breakdown there's three different
types of parentheses and other
characters you actually need a lot more
characters to make this string work and
when you have emoji and a lot of them
you need to find the user interface to
pick them so somebody came up with the
idea of emoji pickers in 1987
back then they were not really
characters but graphics that were
inserted into messages
but it did work you could pick an emoji
and attach it to your message this is a
string job actually from back then from
the cocoanut bulletin board system and
if we want to do that as characters and
use more scripts we actually need a way
to describe more characters
so yeah Unicode came up in 1992 Unicode
is a standard for characters and
encoding characters it's brought up by
the Unicode consortium which is a
nonprofit organization it relies on
donations so they don't make any money
from it and they released Unicode 1.0 in
1992 they were already smiley faces in
there not a lot exactly three of them
which is of course not a lot what we had
a frowning face and two different smiley
faces already in these article points
you can see when something interesting
happened in Japan of course Japan being
wildly crazy from our point of view the
J phone appeared J phones a was a
Japanese mobile phone carrier back then
they brought a phone to market that
could display 90 proprietary graphic
characters there were already pagers
which are basically if you have never
seen what a pager is it's a small
electronic device that we can receive
either a string of numbers only like a
phone number you had to call back back
then or a very short string of text like
one-way SMS with no way to reply and
that was the future back then so this
phone came up with a we could use
characters now this of course is
Japanese on the screenshot but you can
see a whale in there pointing arrow to
it let's whale emoji a tiny it's looking
towards you with an half open mouth and
spewing water
it's a terrific idea but it was only
available on this very phone on this
single device on one carrier in Japan so
the general impact was rather negligible
but the set of emoji characters they
used these are the most important ones
the really important emojis they were
already there that's hard there's
different persons of course cats cats
are always important no no talk is
complete without cats coffee beer cake
was already a lie back then and of
course everybody's darling pile of poo
was already in that set of characters
you can see it in the first row third
from the right then in 1999 chic
attacker carita he was working with NTT
DoCoMo which is a mother Japanese
carrier chic otaku Clarita and his team
which consisted of one other person
created a set of symbols which were
rolled out on multiple devices this time
he's often credited with having created
the first emoji set which is as we
already know now obviously not true but
he created the first interoperable set
of emojis that was rolled out in Japan
across multiple characters across
multiple phones so people could start
using them actually in everyday life and
be sure that the receiving end would
have a way to understand that and of
course the Japanese use picks that up
pretty quickly and being Japan more and
more people found this useful and of
course entertaining around 2000 these
online messenger thingies came up you
maybe remember Microsoft network Amazon
or a.m. or
you might have used that one and they
started bringing their own graphics set
of emojis in and then in 2006 Google
started to put emoji characters into
private parts like private set
characters into Unicode so they started
to standardize this a little and try to
do some effort and then it really took
off Apple introduced iPhone OS 2.2 with
emoji support but only if you
like a Japanese Softbank SIM card and a
soft back email account configured which
is a ridiculously Apple luckily that
nonsense came to end pretty quickly and
they were apps on the App Store
available that you could download and
start and they would do some magic to
enable the emoji keyboard even if you
had not as Japanese SIM card and people
were actually paying money for this to
just just get emoji and with Unicode
standard 6.0 up until now the unicode
character standard and the emoji
standard were two different things
brought out by the Unicode consortium
and with Unicode 6 it was merged to one
standard so now emoji are officially
part of the Unicode text standard and
when Apple came up with iOS 5 and
released the emoji keyboard for all
iPhones on the planet to use which was
wonderful people were experimenting with
that two years later
Android came with 4.4 KitKat if you
still remember that and they also
implemented in 2013 the oxford
dictionary thought well let's put emoji
in the official Oxford Dictionary of the
English language so emoji is now
officially a word and it's described as
a small digital immature icon used to
express an idea or emotion emoji live in
of your text messages with tiny smiley
faces much pretty accurate description
in 2013 also came up the emoji Padian
you know Wikipedia you know yeah
emoji pedia is just four emoji it's like
an encyclopedia exclusively for
everything emoji if you need to look up
anything yo you'll find it there then
since 2014 we celebrate world emoji day
it's a thing it happens on 17th of July
Y on 17th of July you can see the answer
up there there's the official unicode
emoji character for a calendar
and it displays a date of July 17th this
is why we have this but why is that date
on that emoji blame Apple because on
17th of July in 2002 Apple released a
calendaring application called iCal and
that was the release state so they had
this date on the application icon while
it was not running and the current date
while it was running which confused a
lot of people so they had to fix it but
apples pretty much a reason why we have
emoji day on July 17th now every year
and 2015 for the first time an emoji was
declared world a word of the year so
smile face with tears of joy is the
first emoji to become word of the year
world one interesting since 2016 you can
use emoji as a ad targeting selector on
Twitter also in 2016 we had the first
emoji con a conference multi day
conference about emoji you see this
starts to escalate in some way and also
the first interoperable emoji set by
shiki taka carita from 1997 was
exhibited in the Museum of Modern Art's
so now emoji are officially art as well
since 2017 you can search for emoji on
Twitter even if you're not doing our
head targeting but just as plain user so
it's a democratization of emoji search
and in 2018 several larger vendors
agreed on this depiction of the pistil
emoji we'll hear more about that in a
moment and now that we have 2019 so what
do we do since we're working with
Unicode and stuff we need to have a look
at encoding and how these are
implemented well encoding of course
you'll think of this again let's start
simple ASCII the American standard for
information interchange
was invented for teletype terminals in
the 70s 60s 70s they were derived from
the from the teleprinter or Telegraph it
was seven bits only so it means 2 to the
7th 128 characters 1 byte of memory in a
computer equals exactly one character
that's reasonably simple for a computer
to work with the from 0 to 31
you have control characters like a
carriage return line feed escape the
bell character it's what makes your
terminal beep when you press tab to
autocomplete control sequences like
moving your cursor they are not part of
a ski but letters printable characters
a-to-z math functions like plus/minus
division multiplication they are but no
accented characters like we use in
Serbian for example there's a lot of
accented characters so if we take the
text string bow hunt words out on here
so we'll use that as a example and use
the bit representation for those
characters in ASCII in you see it in
binary in decimal in hex just ignore the
lower two lines see look at the binary
they all start with 0 the first bit is
always a zero because we only use 7 of
those 8 bits but in 7 bits we can barely
fit enough characters to type any text
even if it's only latin characters so we
need a lot more and if you want to have
a look at your complete ASCII table just
get out your computer pretty much any
modern operating system has a man page
for ASCII on any bsd or linux or mac and
you can look at that table so what do we
do with those remaining bit characters
from 128 to 255 well you can use those
it's called extended ASCII and this
upper half can be localized to represent
for example accented characters like
there is in French or hot chicks like in
Serbian or other characters but do not
fit the very simple Latin alphabet of
course you have to somehow declare which
characters are presented there because
you only have a limited space and some
other alphabet like Greek would use
different characters so how do you get
by well it's called encoding and it
describes what how to understand this
upper half of the encoding interesting
enough there are several hundred code
pages different code pages that make use
of those remaining bits and some
encodings differ by only eight
characters you might have heard of iso
8859-1 it's also called latin one you
may have heard of ISO 8859 - 15 it
differs by exactly eight characters the
major difference being they added as a
currency symbol for the Euro this is why
if you want to put up a euro somewhere
you need the different encoding so if
you have different encodings sometimes
you need to translate from one to the
other this is a really really
non-trivial exercise and it's that kind
of non-trivial there's even a special
word for when you make mistakes in
translating like from one code page to
another and you get the wrong one that
word is multi pocket it's Japanese we
already know the word emoji
it means character and baka is a
Japanese verdict derive zanpakuto and
that means to change something with the
implicit meaning of changing it not for
the better so you're changing something
for the worse so much ibaka means yeah
pretty much exactly what results from
mistranslating stuff and you can do that
with multiple mistakes and end up with
terrible things in text if you ever had
to migrate a mailing list from mailman
to to mailman three you'll run into
those
problems in German I noticed many of you
are speaking a little German at least
there's this funny thing it's called
chess encoding of course it means
encoding that s is a sharp s already an
extended character for asking so you
need proper encoding for for that word
to work if it doesn't work you may have
seen people wearing this t-shirt because
some thing with the encoding went wrong
now this is not possible in ASCII you
need unicode to represent that special
character it's called the replacement
character so there even is a character
to okay I have no idea what this is
let's put this into designate I have no
idea what it is so what do we do can't
we find a standard - that works for
everything you know standards there's so
many to choose from
yep let's invent one that works for
everything that has proven to work what
actually does work it's called UTF the
Unicode transformation format and it
comes in three flavors utf-8 16 and 32
utf-8 is an encoding method with a
variable length so a character can be
either one byte in memory - three or
four utf-16 is either 2 or 4 bytes and
utf-32 is always 4 bytes but if you
don't need all those 4 bytes is wasteful
so you need a loves memory or storage
space that is unused so utf-8 is
actually what you want to use it's a
very versatile format it delivers over
90% of the world's webpages and the
second most used is jiff cheese which is
a Japanese format and if that is less
than 1% already so utf-8 is really the
dominant encoding format these days and
it's what you want to use how does it
work with multiple bytes I mean how do I
know if I using one or two or three it's
quite nifty it's a surprisingly simple
solution if we look at that code point
that's what power unicode characters are
categorized the first 127 characters the
first bit in memory is a zero like in
ASCII so
utf-8 is 100% identical to ASCII for
those first characters which is great
because it means backward compatibility
it's easy to use it also means if we
make that first bit of one instead of a
zero we have a flag that tells us wait
there's something different coming up
you need to pay attention and for a
2-byte character we start with the one
on the leading bite telling you hey pay
attention there's something different we
put in another one meaning one another
one that's two ones now we have a two
pipe character and since binary has this
wonderful thing of another character
called zero we have a way to terminate
the series of ones that we send so one
one zero means two bytes and now we
start with the next thing three bytes
you can already imagine how this works
you have one one one zero now you know
it's three bytes so you use the rest up
for your remaining data that you need to
convey and every subsequent bye it
starts with a one and an immediate zero
so you know it cannot be a living byte
because the first one always has at
least two ones so if you find the byte
sequence it's clear if you're on a
leading byte or if you're on a
subsequent one so you can easily
synchronize to where does a character
start because it's totally easy to find
and four characters they work just the
same one important takeaway here is all
emoji of four byte characters of course
the codings and you tff being a
universal encoding encoding zli to
problems that's just the nature of
encodings you might have worked with
databases like mysql or mariadb it comes
with an encoding or collation mean
sorting order called utf-8 I put that in
quotes because that utf-8 as they call
it only does
three byte sequences meaning if you want
to put a comment on that WordPress blog
with an emoji it does not work I mean
you can send it but it doesn't get
stored properly in the database this is
why in 2015 MySQL added an encoding
called utf-8 multibyte for so now you
can represent emoji in the database for
your postings or comments
luckily the MySQL installer now defaults
to using that but if you have an older
blog you need to convert that have fun
with that of course WordPress being
written in a language called PHP PHP
only can work with eight byte characters
yes it's 2019 if you want to check your
calendar what if you want to use more
than this archaic
set well there's the multipied string
PHP module extension and unless you load
that you cannot do anything but it's
that extension is available since PHP
for point 0.6 of course you have all
your applications updated to seven point
two which is the current supported
version I'm pretty sure you don't have
any legacy code around monie anymore
it's also not security supported so
there's really no excuse to not use that
if you use JavaScript it uses 16-bit
so-called code units meaning every
characters at least 16 bits and if it
does not fit in there you use just two
of those 16-bit code units it's kind of
wasteful but it's safe to use with emoji
that's fine
if you do Java it also uses 16-bit code
units but they can only use one code
unit with 16 bits to encode a character
not too so no emoji in Java I'm sorry
there's a separate library called emoji
Java if you need emoji in your
enterprise applications Python 3 all the
strings of utf-8 and is fully supported
so that's fine if you're using rust it
gets more complex you can use it in
strings that's fine if
you want to use it as identifiers for
your variables you can only use two byte
Unicode characters so no emoji as
variables in rust Catalan is pretty much
the same if you go for gold line
the Google language to byte Unicode
characters in identifiers yes you can do
that but only if they start with an
ASCII character whyever that is but if
you need to use model-view-controller in
chinese this is how you do it I will not
try to pronounce the Chinese Swift being
a quite modern language invented by
Apple it's used for iPhones and Mac's to
program applications it does fully
support emoji what does full support
mean you can write code like that I mean
who doesn't want hearts and swirls in
their code is wonderful what is that is
still not enough for your emoji
programming needs use emoji code it is
the most emoji compatible programming
language is open source language and
it's written exclusively in emoji it
does support ascii legacy characters in
streams but not for identifiers so it's
pretty much your emoji singularity for
programming code let's have a look at
implementations how does how does
Unicode implement emoji in in the
encoding standard for unicode for each
character you have a code point that
uniquely identifies the character it's
you plus and then a number and you have
utf-8 byte sequence that you can use to
encode that character for example here's
an example a hamster face not the
hamster dance if you remember that but
people want to talk about more than
hamsters so with persons it already gets
more complex
you have noticed maybe on your phone
there's person emojis like Smiley's and
people and they're totally yellow you
might you might think yes that's where
we're going to most people do not look
like Lego figures you might have noticed
that when working around here they're
not yellow in their face so something's
not right with your keyboard this is
where you can start combining multiple
emojis there's something called a skin
tone modifier which means you can take
emotive a person emoji add a second
emoji which is a skin tone modifier and
you get a person with a different skin
color so you can represent all people in
the world that's a great thing now
nobody's exclusive exclude it anymore I
mean the world's not Lego figures but
you still can
you don't even exclude like a fit you
can you can use those for everyone it's
a two code point sequence you have the
person emoji and the modifier and if
your font understands how to use those
it will combine them into a single face
with that skin color that's great
it ends up with emoji being for white
characters for bytes for the person for
bytes for the skin color so you have an
eight byte sequence for a single
character now it's vastly different from
ASCII if you remember and of course
there's a standardized scale it's called
the Fitzpatrick scale it's named after
the person Thomas B Fitzpatrick who
invented that scale to standardize the
expression of human skin colors and such
a modifier always alters the appearance
of the character that came before it so
the modifier always works to the left
hand side sadly these skin tone
modifiers can only be applied to person
emojis of course it would be nice to
like have them work with coffee some
people like their coffee black some
people like their coffee lighter with
milk
or beer there's different types of beers
you could it toast what totally makes
sense sorry they don't work it's it's
tragic but yeah you can only use skin
tone modifiers with toast they also
don't work with milk the milk could have
in theory some skin but no they don't
doubt you may also have seen there's
flax there's a lot of flags and emoji
that's probably even multiple pages of
flags like the checkered flag it's
usually waved when you end a race so now
we have a goal to reach that is
understand how flags a unit hold work
they are very nifty two examples I
traveled to here from a country called
Austria yesterday and we're here in
república sort of young and these are
the two flags for these national
countries of course the Unicode standard
being very thoughtful wants to have
implement flags in a way that is future
proof so countries come and go
some countries disappear they get split
up into other countries into multiple
countries how do you make a standard
that works for countries that do not
exist yet not real problem but they
found a very interesting way there's an
iso standard which gives every country a
two-character
shortcut its iso 3166 - one that's not
really important but it designates the
characters RS for república serbia and
80 for Austria now we have a simple
identifier and when a new country comes
up we can just take two more characters
and the unicode standard has the special
set it's called the regional indicator
symbols they usually look like a
character with a dashed outline like box
around them and if you type those
characters
in succession your font will say oh well
that's a regional indicator are a
regional indicator
si no RS is Silvia I need to replace
that with flag your font will start
putting away those characters and
putting a flag up you don't want to know
how long I set to make my slides display
those characters without making it like
I don't have hit just those so that I
could show you but this works for
countries non-existing so you just need
an update to your font but not an update
to the standard so this is a
future-proof it's very nifty there's a
few flags for not really countries but
geopolitical it makes sense to have a
flag for the European Union and if you
use the regional indicator symbols even
you for you you get a European flag nice
thing there's a few more but you can
look that up yourselves or find things
on your keyboard you might find Scottish
things as well there's more flags like
this one I've written the code points
beneath it it's a flag it's for Unicode
code points but it's just one character
so why is that I adds up to actually 14
bytes of UTF sequence month lag 14 bytes
why is that so complex
well let's decompose that flag and see
how it's actually built there's a
there's a character for a white flag
it's just a plain white flag then
there's some magic and there's a rainbow
and the you +200 de it's called a hero
with Joyner it's a character that has no
width and it joins the characters left
and right to it to one it combines those
so that's the magic it combines a white
flag with a rainbow and you end up with
a rainbow flag
and the white flag itself already
consists of two coat points
so now you know many flags can be
combined like that the white flag itself
is already too cold points why is that
white flag well it's there multiple
white flags I mean how much artistic
impression can you build into a white
flag not a lot more than you think
there's a white flag text character
which is not an emoji that's really a
text character but there is a white flag
emoji characters as a character as well
and that other modifier tells your font
please do not use the text
representation but use the emoji
representation it's called the variation
selector 16 with a wonderful name and it
tells your font to that last character
please make it an emoji same way you can
put up a skull and crossbones pirate
flag you just start with the black flag
and skull and crossbones and skull and
crossbones actually exists as a text
character and as an emoji and you use
the variation selector 16 to tell your
font which one to use okay so no now we
can build pretty much any flag in the
Unicode standard with emojis what else
is there who has a modern phone like
last two or three years or so you might
have see there's gender modifiers okay
have you seen vampires I mean not the
movie but an actual vampire the rafter
are cool one with a key okay you can
take Dracula the Dracula there is a
Dracula emoji to start with and but the
other one that's not Dracula Dracula is
a male person and the other one is
clearly a more female person so how do
we get there we already heard the 0 with
joiner that combines two characters
together well this is what we do here we
take the emoji for Dracula the emoji for
female and voila
you have Buffy the Vampire Slayer isn't
that great I mean you can represent more
people in the world I mean pretty much
exactly 50% more people of the world Oh
actually hundred percent more because
maybe yeah it's important everyone
should be able to use emoji what about
those Fitzpatrick's skin tone modifiers
now yes we can adjust the paleness of
our vampire by using a skin tone
modifier and make the more pale or more
black so emojis really versatile in
combining and allowing for many many
things because people want to express
many things people are diverse in the
world and Unicode standard wants to
enable all people to be represented by
emoji it's an important thing the zero
with Jonah can be used with multiple
person emojis to represent a family of
course there are certain things and
brain constructions that states think
what a family should look like but the
reality is families can be very
different but they are a family and no
family is illegal so Unicode can show
all families that you can think of and
that represents your family yes that is
a font limitation technically you can
combine more but I don't know of any
font that allows for more than two
children in a family and yes you can use
skin tone modifies with each of those I
have not made an example that took me
already an hour to show that much
so our emoji a language we've seen the
Moche being used in programming language
what about emoji themselves are they a
language Trevor Noah
who does the daily show called them
contemporary cave drawings
it is a multi-language in itself
our emoji hieroglyphics hieroglyphics
being a rather unspecific term
consisting mostly of pictograms
schematic graphics emoji are close but
they are not hieroglyphics
because in hieroglyphics a pictogram
maps to a very specific term and only to
that term so if you take a cow it can
only mean cow but people want to talk
about more than cows most people do I
mean more than factual cows so imodium
or a meta language they're not a
language in their own but they augment
our languages all the languages we speak
at last night's karaoke party we had
songs in seven languages so emoji no
there was no emoji song but emoji are
used in the abstract context of words
and extend that context within that
context so if you take a cat cat is
relatively straightforward as a
character but what you want to do with
that cat or to that cat it's not really
expressed from the emoji itself can be
more calming complex this character in
the movie is called tropical drink it
might be a tequila sunrise it might be a
third Long Island iced tea
does that really matter the next morning
we don't know or that one when sending
this character to an astrophysicist they
ask what about that planet other people
will not read a planet into that emoji
it's it has a name it's called cookie so
it's a very friendly emoji
it certainly Cookie Monster's favorite
character it looks like a chocolate-chip
cookie to most people what about that
one any ideas what this is cracker
you're wrong that is Samsung's
interpretation of what a cookie should
look like so meaning if you send a
message to your friend hey we're
watching movie tonight bring cookies
bring emoji cookie and they have a
Samsung phone and they brings the wrong
snacks to the movie the horror you can't
do that I mean you have translation
problems now depending on which platform
your friends are on like it much it
looked different on different phones but
even if the emoji looks the same okay is
your smiling faces in the crowd you know
what I'm up to this is called an
eggplant in English in German we usually
say Milan taani or aubergine it's a
vegetable it's an edible vegetable it
was forbidden to be used as a hashtag on
Instagram for someone I don't know why
Instagram discriminates against
vegetables it's not really
misunderstanding because it clearly is a
vegetable unless you put some textual
context around it that alters the
meaning it's still the same emoji but
you can read other things into it sorry
you cannot unsee that another one it's a
peach it's a fruit it was not banned
from Instagram as a hashtag it's not
been censored in the United States these
are usually very prone to censoring but
they can have different interpretations
so a peach is often used as an
interpretation for your butt
what about that one I already hinted at
it
it's called pistol if you know a little
bit about guns it looks like a pistol if
you receive a message like that hey we
see this next weekend and bring them hmm
might you be worried when you're
receiving such a message maybe the
message of friend actually sent look
like that and it was an invitation to a
garden party bring your water pistol
let's have some fun summer outside so
you get translation errors from the
emoji depending on which iPhone or
Android phone or samsung phone or online
platform you're working with especially
that one is super problematic because
I'll show you a few different graphical
representations among different
platforms
it varies from water pistol toys toy
guns super soaker revolver to space
zapper and some company said while we're
having a gun promotes violence let let's
make it change it to a water pistol
while other company said well our space
separate does not really represent
pistol properly let's change it to a
pistol now depending on your version
your operating system their vendor and
your platform you have multiple ways to
misinterpret that and you have no way to
properly convey a message with that
emoji so that can be really dangerous
well because your invitation to a garden
party may lead up to having a SWAT team
kicking down your door so that's a
serious problem because emoji are also a
mirror of society 70% of emoji used are
usually happy 15% are rather neutral and
still 15 emoji 15% of emoji are sad so
but we know that not 70% of our life is
happy
our online communication is some kind of
idealized communication we like to give
more of the happy and give less of the
sad away emoji are also stereotypical
I'll show you a set of emoji and you
shout out to me where those emoji might
be used most what do you think
holidays okay take more of a regional
location on the planet
waterboarding on Cahokia that's a new
one
the solution to this is really actually
Hawaii
yes it's stereotypically of palm trees
sunsets tropical drinks surfing what
about those
hmm okay
Lutter any any location you can think of
that would somehow match that
the solute solution is Lisa Las Vegas
Nevada and we all know what happens in
Vegas stays in Vegas another one the
association is drugs okay that's correct
but why and where school Oh interesting
okay yeah
a solution to that one is Portugal in
Australia okay
some people have paid attention to drug
laws in 2011 Portugal started
decriminalizing all drug possession and
use for recreational use or for medical
use like everything's legal everything
the result of that political decision
was actually less use of drugs less
abuse of drugs resulting in less people
needing to be treated for drug abuse
with an overall increase in health
across the whole country
of course police forces don't want to
grab your bag of weed now but can use
their time more properly to fight
corruption and other or other criminal
activities and the health care system
considers a drug addiction like any
other illness and starts treating it the
result is great savings for the taxpayer
a better working health care system in a
more healthy society just by allowing
that and also that's really really
helpful drug you policy is mirrored in
emoji use because there's more discourse
about drugs people learn more about how
drugs work and what is dangerous to
their health and what is not so that's a
very important mirror of society that
you can see in the use of emoji
something different have you heard of
Markov chains yes that's a good answer
Markov chain is a series of characters
that only go together
all that often go together or series of
words that often go together you can
have that with emoji like these tears of
joy three times must have been a very
funny evening they're usually very
homogeneous like two or three times the
same emoji there's very few that
have a set of different emoji that
always go together like these hear no
evil see no evil speak no evil monkeys
or hearts in different colors and
depending on how sleepy you are you
might repeat those so how do we
differentiate the language used with
emoji now let's have a look at it
there's spoken language that's written
language and they both come in an
informal way and in the formal way of
course um a formal spoken conversation
is like having a presentation or speech
radio moderation a written example for
formal language is a book or printed
newspaper or maybe even a blog posting
where the informal language is your
everyday spoken word your local dialect
that you use your local words that are
maybe only known to novice at language
uses intonation gestures grimaces and
emoji are that representation in a
written context of informal language
they augment that so this is where the
emoji are located and the repetition of
emoji also represents time like if you
had just a funny moment you might have
won laughing smiley if it was really
really really funny you might do three
so if you had a longer time of fun you
might use more emoji so in the string of
emoji represents time clapping hands it
was a clue that was applause one pair of
clapping hands there was a huge ball
three clapping hands so they give a
special and and timely context they're
written motions and written emotions in
time what about things that there are no
emoji for I mean no emoji I mean are
there things that were that there's no
emoji for
huh there are things that there's no
emoji for like sex
I mean it's complicated there's also no
emoji for vanilla but humans being
creative beings and emoji being a meta
language depending on the context the
cultural background humans do find ways
to write about sex with emoji you
already know at least two emojis that
you can use and some others I also know
that few of you are for some or many of
you are with an ite or even IT security
do emoji have an IT security relevant
aspect I clean yes and that is a strong
yes there is no emoji for IT security
but you could make it work in some way
ok it's not officially but it kind of
fits charge but
what else can be used for emojis you
have may have heard of a messaging
system a network called matrix that's
the riots client for it of is an
end-to-end encrypted messenger and you
know with end-to-end encryption in to
authenticate your your peers and compare
fingerprints like are you letting your
print yes I am I am this give ratio of
hex numbers and Rio uses a funny way
which translate your hex fingerprint
into a series of emojis that you
compared if you have the same series of
emojis
we have technically just compared a
fingerprint
I really need to speed up of course
emoji being interpreted differently in
New York translation problems so they
write the English names below it to make
it easier but that works quite well
there's smart TVs we're probably not so
smart you can hook them up to your Wi-Fi
unless you have an emoji in your SSID in
the Wi-Fi name if you have a Samsung TV
that will scan for your networks and
when it has a list it will cache that
list to disk and then will display that
list and while displaying that list it
will crash you now have a denial service
attack from your Wi-Fi to your TV when
you reboot that TV and go to Wi-Fi again
it immediately displays the cached list
before scanning again
now you need to factory reset your TV to
make it work again and don't hook it up
to Wi-Fi Apple had a very interesting
way with emoji and really improving
security you can set a passcode for your
phone that when you unlock it you have
to enter a passcode to unlock it and
then you can use it works with many
platforms this problem was iOS specific
you could enable the emoji keyboard for
entering and setting your passcode I
have a super secret I put emoji in my
passcode you lock your phone you want to
unlock your phone you cannot switch to
the emoji keyboard anymore
that phones really secure now happened
they did fix that so sorry they did not
fix it by allowing it the emoji keyboard
on the lockscreen but by not allowing
emoji to be set as passphrases it's a
bummer I like emojis you might have a
monitoring solution that might run some
role old Perl code and you can have a
lot of fun by putting emoji in your HTTP
response headers that might lead to
false down alerts even if the site is up
it happens so what's the future of emoji
what's what's coming next probably not
really next some things are already
here's an emoji animated emoji they move
if you have a face tracking camera on
your phone they can mimic your face with
an emoji and you can record that as a
video and send it to someone so you can
have like a little tiger or a unicorn
talk like you it's a lot of fun I don't
see the business application for it yet
but yeah you could share that there's
MIMO G like you build some a character
that looks like yourself but as a
drawing is a emoji style drawing if you
have an old Nintendo Wii console you
might remember those mean characters
they basically already work that way
several years ago then there's custom
emoji especially messenger platforms and
online platforms try to use those to get
more emoji that specifically are
targeted for their audience for example
this is a list of the special emojis
that are used on the chaos that social
mastodon instance because anarchy is
always more fun with friends and there's
some special characters relating to that
very special community like the fairy
dust which is an iconic rocket character
used by the CCC what else is interesting
and coming with emoji court cases
they're increasingly mentioned in court
documents people are having legal fights
over emoji or over messages sent with
emoji and it's about how to interpret
those emoji I mean
this this can be very difficult
linguistically there's also the emoji
mashup but it's a Twitter account if you
still use that it basically takes two
emoji theoretically combines them with a
zero with Jonah and ends up with a
combination like that like party and
vomiting should you really combine each
emoji with each other probably not
the Unicode consortium also explicitly
tells you not to but technically that
would be possible and these are possible
representations of absurd combinations
if you want to use emoji on your
computer and you're not using a Mac or
iOS because they have really really good
support for typography fonts and emoji
there's the open moji project it's an
open source and free Libre and gratis
font that you can use a new operating
system to get a full unicode 12 set of
emoji on any operating system for free
to use so you can finally put those
emoji into your terminal to represent
your get status if you know things that
should be emoji but that are not yet
existing as emoji you can make your own
proposals to the Unicode consortium like
oh I have this sport or recreation or
thing or person type that should be
represented by emoji you can enter young
proposals you can see what's already
been proposed if it has been rejected or
approved there's a lot of documentation
and guidelines on how to write and what
to think about before making such a
proposal and also understanding the
technical limitations that are possible
within the unicode standard and you can
also study other proposals that have
been successfully submitted so one day
your own emoji that you came up with
that you think is important for the
world to communicate can be on
everybody's phone
click but you can you can help people
communicate about new things by
submitting that and coming 20 20
we're now at Unicode twelve point one
twelve point all was the last change
that included emoji twelve point one
edit a single Unicode character so we
need to need it to update the standard
because Japan started a new era with the
new emperor and they edit the kana
representation of the Emperor's name so
that's why we had to update emoji the
Unicode center with Unicode 13 coming
2020 meaning next year we get a lot of
new emoji and here's the park with IT
security relevance people will update
their phones to get those new
emojis and instantly like this is
important I need this new emoji on my
phone now I don't care for the security
content of that update it's in there as
well ok fine I'll take it I want those
emoji and this is why emoji are
important for phone security people will
update for the emoji not for any
security problem be as bad as you can
imagine that's a reality of IT
departments these days already but run
large amounts of phones and mobile
device management systems and what's
what new emojis are coming ninja of
course important a potted plant a
mammoth a magic wand you might already
have an idea how that might be
interpreted or not screwdrivers very
important thing elevators and as a world
exclusive I can now link the graphical
representation of one of the upcoming
emojis it's the ninja emoji
wonderful it's great isn't it if you
want to take a picture you can but you
get the slides anyway and with that I
want to close I want to say thanks to
Brian deer for sending me the plateau
and coconut images and screen shots from
the 70s especially from the emoji picker
he created back then very many thanks to
Kate Ian McCulloch she did the
linguistic and semiotic studies on emoji
like how do they work
with language and to the SwiftKey emoji
report if you have been using the
SwiftKey keyboard on your phone the
emoji you typed were statistically
analyzed into an emoji usage report
worldwide that gave us a lot of insight
about how people use and communicate
with using emoji so thank you for to you
all for using that keyword so I could
give a talk and rant an hour about emoji
are there any questions
we'll we'll take two quick ones question
I can speak up a little
Tomita
bye moochy in domains are already
possible because we have
internationalized domain names so if you
go to like a monk a snowman is a Unicode
character but not an emoji character but
there are already emoji domains
they're usually Punic code encoded with
this xn - and then the hex
representation but if you go to I don't
know one PI mark now but there are
unicode domains and they usually work in
most modern browsers already and
keywords yes there I'm sure their
keyboards with emoji buttons already
online Hema and Sigma ok so there's
already domains with that there was a
one question over there I think yes just
a second for the microphone
this
I don't know I don't know of any
explicit currency emoji but there are a
lot of currencies symbols like euro
dollar yen and many others already in
the Unicode standard if you want a
crypto currency in there you can propose
that to the Unicode consortium please
look up if they have any objections or
reasons why they would incorporate that
or not I can quite imagine that they
will are rather unlikely to include
crypto currency currency symbols into
the Unicode standard telecom we have an
addition to that I did not know that
it's great I learned a lot when giving
these talks thank you very much can we
take one more so one last question
anyone
nope I'll take further questions over a
beer thank you very much for your time
you