hello next topic is secure design
principles by Nikola Lubitsch
hey guys well I'm gonna start this talk
with a short story about Susan now a few
years ago Susan was the chief security
officer at a large corporation you might
have heard of called Equifax she's
retired now but the reason for her
retirement has nothing to do with age
Susan retired because of the absolute
disaster that was the Equifax data
breach now as you may know this attack
happened about two years ago it was a
multi-phased attack where the attackers
managed to retrieve about 140 million
records personal data related to
Americans so almost half the population
of the states this attack succeeded
because Susan and her team failed to
apply some simple secure design
principles
so at the start of this talk we'll go
examine the broader scope of secure
design principles and see how they
address software security how they fit
into this secure software engineering
after that we'll look at five sets of
secure design principles which are
applicable to almost anything that you
can make today from various software to
protocols to building design and then
finally and hopefully the most important
question by the end of this talk how can
you start practicing this these design
principles in your everyday software
development so let's start we want to
have secure software and as software
engineers now and thankfully security
engineers require this is not something
that's easy to do we need to address
security throughout the software
development lifecycle we need to specify
the security requirements we need to
examine the threat model hood who wants
to attack us which hazards do they want
to harm and how do we protect them then
we start designing we need to construct
a secured by design solution so this is
the first point where these secure
design principles enter our story when
you're performing design activities you
always want to keep these design
principles in mind so that you can
create a secure by design solution then
we move on to code where we want to
perform some static code analysis some
security code reviews to make sure that
there are no code level owner abilities
that there are no flaws in your
implementation
arguably the most important part of our
secure software engineering is the
verification and validation so we need
to see if there are any vulnerabilities
left in our solution we need to test to
perform penetration testing security
testing to see if the secure design
principles were followed if the if there
are no secure coding mistakes and then
basically if these guys don't find your
vulnerabilities you know who will once
we have a potentially shippable
increment it's time for release so maybe
we'll deploy perform some secure
delivery and deployment activities and
of course all of this needs to evolve we
need to manage the work that we do we
need to follow the threat landscape to
see which news and tools come up and to
integrate them into our security
development lifecycle so now let's focus
on the secure design principles who are
the people working in software
development that should be aware of this
well as I mentioned of course if you're
a designer of software and systems you
need to address security during your
design you need to plan for security
plan the security controls the security
work so that it gets done but it doesn't
stop there when talking about
implementation we really can apply these
secure design principles at the code
level as well so when talking about
design we have this macro level the
architecture of the system of the
software but we also have the micro
level the code design and this is where
we can apply these principles to write
better code and of course the security
code reviews will review the code that
we write and make sure that it follows
the design that we specified
our testers are affected as well because
we need to verify that these principles
were followed they will examine our
attack surface they will see if our
access control is correct and this is
something that we should plan in the
design so let's look at the principles
we will examine today
we'll start with defense-in-depth and
the idea here is to apply multiple
security controls to our solution so
that we can remain secure even if that
control fails let's look at an example
so we have some file integrator service
application it's communicating with some
external file storage maybe this is our
system maybe it's a business partner it
doesn't really matter all that matters
is that we're receiving important data
from this external file storage based on
which we can perform some business
operations and then we store it
somewhere locally the idea is that we
have an attacker that wants to modify
this data compromise its integrity so
that it can harden they can harm our
system they will change the data it will
become corrupted and then our system
will crash or maybe it will continue
working but with false data it's it
doesn't really matter and we want to
protect this data a possible attack can
be on the communication channel itself
so we introduce a security control we
introduce secure File Transfer Protocol
job done right well not if we're talking
about defense-in-depth
we need to ask the question what if it
breaks what if this secure File Transfer
Protocol doesn't work doesn't provide us
with the security that we need well
another related question might be why
would it break why can't we trust this
control well security controls field for
a number of reasons we can have a bug in
the implementation of the SFTP you
create software you make bugs all the
time well why don't why wouldn't these
guys make the same mistakes as you
technology can be vulnerable we've seen
it a large number of times even in
well-known security controls that we are
supposed to trust then we might miss
configure this software maybe the SFTP
is secure the implementation is okay but
we don't properly configure it our IT
personnel forgets to set some
certificates or maybe set the
appropriate configuration so we have a
vulnerability and finally the security
control can be improperly used we might
think that we're secure but we don't
really understand the security control
and then we're applying it to no great
effect
so defense-in-depth tells you to ask
this question what if it breaks is there
anything else that provides security for
me in this case we might introduce file
signatures so digital signatures to
guarantee the integrity of our data as
an additional security control now if
the SFTP fails we still have the digital
signature as a fallback if it fails
hopefully the SFTP won't and if both
fail well that's just very bad luck
so another example we have a similar
situation where our application is
communicating with an external service
and we have an attacker that wants to
spoof our business partner to pretend
that it is this service so that he can
supply some data for us once again maybe
he wants to compromise our system in
some way the question is how do we
authenticate this business partner and
an easy solution is to have some
endpoint addresses that we are services
targeting and to make sure that they are
targeting our business partner but of
course this isn't enough because the
addresses can be spoofed the attacker
might perform some DNS poisoning or
something along those lines and the
requests and communication can be
redirected to his malicious service so
we introduce cryptography once again we
have some certificates for
authentication and now we have some we
have some security that this business
partner is the right one but of course
this doesn't really solve our attack
surface what if the attacker is inside
our business partner system and then he
can channel the attacks through these
legitimate communication channels so
validation is an obvious solution here
we want to validate everything that's
coming from our business partner and to
make sure that no rubbish gets
introduced into our system what happens
if the validators fail what happens if
our application crashes we might decide
to introduce a service dedicated for
this validation so that it crashes if
there is some advanced attack vector
coming here and similarly to the
internal business app in the previous
case we
we'll introduce all of these security
controls to have this multi-layered
defense in depth all of this is at the
software level so far right but what
about the network what about the
hardware the operating system well we
should consider these controls as well
to have really a multi-layered
multifaceted defense in depth where an
attacker that manages to break a single
control
ideally won't have any other advantage
he won't gain even anything by
compromising our SFTP for example but
let's at least try to reduce the
advantage and advantage that he does get
from this successful exploit moving on
attack surface analysis now this is more
of an activity than a pract than a
principle but it is still somewhat
related to software design the idea is
to always keep in mind where an attack
can come from and then to limit these
avenues as much as possible of course we
want to have the system perform the
business functions that it's supposed to
but nothing else here let's look at an
example where we have some user
communicating with an application with
which is in turn communicating with some
data center our set of SQL databases no
SQL databases files whatever and we have
some files with which the application is
communicating and an attacker that wants
to compromise our data center he wants
to destroy our data modify it in some
way or simply read it to sell it on the
dark web
the question for attack surface analysis
is where does the attack come from and
we call this attack surface mapping well
in this case the attack can come from
anywhere this is the first assumption
that we should make start from either
everything and then focus but what
should we focus on well trust boundaries
can help us here we can determine where
it is likely that an attack can come
from by examining who has access to
particular resources in our system if we
have a browser application then pretty
much if it's publicly available pretty
much everyone from the internet can
target these endpoints here what about
the communication between the file
system and the application on the same
machine well it's not really easily
accessible right so we can see what is
inside our scope and what is implausible
and reduce some of these concerning
areas to focus only on the important
parts for this attack surface analysis
so we would want to protect the
communication and end points facing the
Internet we're concerned with files here
because insiders might compromise them
and so on
once we've mapped the attack surface we
can okay before let's just summarize
this part where can an attack come from
the interaction points are an obvious
attack surface all your data stores data
flows especially those between multiple
machines what should we focus on data
arriving from less secure zones
especially those zones that have a near
infinite amount of attackers such as the
internet and what is out of scope well
of course we have a scope defined bar by
our team
we will try to secure the components
made by our team but we should really
write down the assumptions that we make
maybe we say that we're not concerned
with protecting the OS okay but write it
down because when another team member
comes with more experience he might tell
you why this is a mistake and that you
should be concerned with the OS
even though you're a web developer now
after we mapped the attack surface we
can start reducing it the first question
is how can we limit the access to this
attack surface so when talking about
access control the most important
question is who can access this who can
access these files who can access these
endpoints who can access the data center
which applications which users these are
the questions that you need to answer
once we've limited the amount of
attackers that can access our resources
the question is how can we limit their
opportunity and what do I mean by this
well in this case we have some temporary
files right how long are they available
is this something that we will delete in
a minute in a day in a week an attacker
might not take over our system by
compromising these temporary files but
he might learn something interesting he
might read some errors he might steal
some data if we don't really need to
have these temporary files available for
a month
why not delete them after a day or even
sooner
for the application we can ask the
question how long how frequently are
functions used do we need to have all
functions available during the night if
this is an internal app we can maybe
shut down the system but more
importantly are all the functions that
are available in the software actually
used is there some set of functions that
nobody uses or that are very small
percent of our users use maybe we should
remove those because they open an attack
surface and we don't really get much
benefit from them and of course this is
related to deprecated code as well do
you have some dead code that nobody is
using nobody is mint maintaining it
might present an attack surface that you
completely forgot about in general this
is good advice for software development
not just for security but also for
security for the data center we can ask
the question how much data does the
application use how frequently does it
contact it to retrieve data as we'll see
with Susan it can be quite important to
limit the amount of data that's
available from the database to minimize
it to only the necessary amount of
queries commands demanded by the
business
once we've limited who can access the
endpoints who can access the files once
we've limited how long they are
available when they are available the
question is how can we limit the attack
vectors that can arrive through these
controlled channels and this is
basically input validation when talking
about the application layer so the
questions that we should be asking is
how does the application how does the
data center handle malformed inputs so
this is a tack surface reduction for
limiting the attackers access we will
examine the next set of secure design
principles related to sound access
control for the attacker opportunity we
should consider the time frame when data
and functions should be available the
frequency how much availability should
we have once again some measurements to
see what is the expected amount of
queries and so on and really should we
even have that data and functions
available to begin with for attack
vector limitation input validation
something that you should really perform
for all data coming to your application
in general we can always limit the type
of data the length possibly the
character sets or values which are
arriving but we might also perform some
specialized validation for specific data
sets data types so we're talking about
SQL injection some prepared statements
XML injection exists X as the validation
and so on
so let's look at one more example for
attack surface analysis to wrap this up
and we will examine at a low level of
design this time where we are looking at
a single application a spring
application a dotnet application that
doesn't really matter we have some HTTP
endpoints which are communicating with a
data access layer
you must bring repository for example we
have an attacker that wants to
compromise the data and now we're
examining a single part of the attack
surface namely the HTTP endpoints how do
we perform attack surface analysis here
for one we look at all the endpoints
what are all the functions that are
available to this user and then for each
endpoint
we examine all the inputs all the places
where the user or rather the attacker
can send an attack vector
so we examine a single HTTP requests and
here we have an obvious input in the
query parameters but a somewhat less
obvious input are the headers especially
when you have custom headers these are
headers which your application is
processing at some point and then the
attacker can send attack vectors here as
was the case in Susan's system
so we would go on to map the attack
surface by examining all of these
endpoints for post requests put requests
we would obviously also look at the
request body and this would be the
mapping of our attack surface the
reduction access control input
validation and so on crucially
understand where the attack can come
from and then limit these avenues as
much as possible
sound access control is next as I
already mentioned earlier and this is
essentially a set of three security
design principles that we will look at
the idea is to restrict access to all
objects across the system at all levels
at all times as much as possible support
the business and nothing else but also
minimize the power a single individual
has so let's look at this
the first principle we're looking at is
complete mediation and this is basically
check everything always for the example
from a few slides back we should be
asking the questions
who is this user that's communicating
with our application do we check all the
requests that it sends that he or she
sends and who is who has access to the
files are all requests checked is all
access tracked for the data center
likewise who can access this data center
is it only the user app is it some
administrator is it everyone but also
who can access the particular databases
here the tables do we have some control
for this we should and this is least
privileged basically assign allow access
only afford the business and nothing
else
so if we have three sets of users here
maybe we'll distribute a set of
functions to the first set another set
to the second and the third set to the
third for the data center maybe we'll
will have multiple applications
interacting with the databases are we
controlling which application can
which data this is a least privileged
minimize the amount of access
finally for separation of duties we want
to limit the amount of power a single
individual has and to have them be
accountable for all their actions going
back to the defense and debt example we
can ask the question who has access to
these data stores now if a single person
can configure all of these endpoints and
certificates that person can also point
our system towards a malicious service
are the changes to these data stores
given their criticality logged can we at
least make the guy pay for ruining our
system and a related question who has
access to the log files is it the same
guy well obviously he can hide his
tracks then
so essentially sound excess control is
an extension of the attack surface
reduction to limit access to only what
is required by the business and nothing
else secure mechanism design is our next
topic and here we will also examine a
set of three secure design principles
the idea here is to conceptualize a
simple design in general we want to have
simplicity in our software but for
security controls this is especially
important complicated design will make
finding vulnerabilities more difficult
so we want to simplify this to make sure
that we understand how our security
controls work to avoid their
malfunctioning also we want to avoid
shared States as much as possible if we
have a state that is shared between
multiple users or multiple programs then
an attacker can corrupt this shared
state and trigger the attack on these
other users or programs and finally to
have a secure design we need to fail
securely failure will happen and we need
to be prepared for it so let's look at
the design principles that make up this
sets
the first one is economy of mechanisms
and as I said it's related to simplicity
to elaborate on this let's go back to
the application example now the question
here is where do we perform input
validation we said that there's data
arriving at our HTTP endpoints it might
be in the headers it might be in the
query parameters it might be in the
request body at what point do we
validate this data to make sure that the
attacks do not trigger one option is at
the source as soon as possible when the
data is arriving at a rent point let's
validate it as much as possible the next
option is at the sink right before the
attack triggers this is the place there
where we want to discard all the attack
vectors the third option is somewhere
along the way between the source and the
sink so where do we validate well the
answer is both at the source and the
sink we form we perform source security
checks for two reasons one of them is
that this helps protect all the things
the attacker might be supplying an
attack vector which will harm our logger
or maybe some XML parser in the business
logic if we remove these attack factors
at the start
these attacks won't go to the database
they won't go to the parser to the
logger we can remove them as soon as
possible
another benefit is that we're moving
rubbish quickly we don't have this
malicious malformed data traveling
through our system being processed in
some way we're discarding it at the
so we're doing these checks at the
source why do we need to perform some
checks at the sink well two reasons once
again the first is that here we can
prevent specific attacks if we're
talking about SQL injection and we can't
really whitelist the sensitive
characters that can perform this attack
well we can create prepared statements
at the sink if we have some XML parsing
we can perform excess D validation at
the sink at the parser but also what if
we have multiple sources what if there
are sources that are out of our control
by validating at the sink we can defend
even against these poorly validated
sources so let's go back to the design
principle make simple designs that
enforce security consistently what we
should definitely avoid is to have some
custom validation somewhere in between
rather focus always on the source and
the sink so that people can know this is
where we expect to see security controls
and we do really need the source and the
sink so that we can have this
consistency so that we can validate all
the data and not just have some part of
it be validated
the next design principle that falls
into this category is least common
mechanism and the idea here is to
minimize the amount of shared States
that exist in our software let's look at
an example with a web application where
we have some global variables which our
application is loading into the browser
if an attacker can compromise these
variables we he might be able to play
some cross-site scripting attack he
might be able to do this through the
front end application or maybe as a
malicious administrator that has access
to the configuration files he inserts
this attack vector we should definitely
minimize the amount of global variables
and ideally control access and perform
the necessary validation to all the
shared State that must exist looking at
another example say we have an
application running on a machine it has
access to the file system and we have
another application here which has a
vulnerability the attacker might be able
to exploit this application to
compromised the file system or maybe to
so he could delete the files that are
required by our secure application he
might clog up the memory take up all the
threads the processor and crash the
whole machine so to solve this we
invented virtualization right we
invented containers to separate these
applications and if the vulnerable
application is exploited well at least
our other application will suffer
finally secure failure so our software
will crash it's inevitable all software
crashes what happens when our software
crashes is a security concern
how will we fail what happens if our a
single function crashes or a service
does this mean the end of our complete
solution well let's look at an example
where we have a user with some
application and we have some
authentication logic where the user is
accessing the application he first must
login and the proper access control
checks might be it must be performed and
we also have some auditing logic so
everything the user does needs to be
logged so we can have non-repudiation
a user makes a request and the
authentication logic fails does the
operation continue does the user perform
the action that he wanted the business
logic is fine but this authentication
logic does not work obviously we don't
want this to happen we want to block the
operation and we call this fail closed
if this fails everything should stop
what about the auditing logic what
happens if we can't log the action maybe
the file system is full our log files
need to be rotated something along those
lines do we stop the operation well it
depends we might fail openly we might
say okay these are some less critical
applications we don't expect serious
security issues if these actions aren't
logged so maybe we will say ok continue
on with your operation but if this is a
sensitive action if we're talking about
some banking transactions obviously we
would want to have everything working
properly
the question here is very similar to
defense-in-depth what happens if the
component a service a function fails
should our process stop will our system
even require a recover these are the
questions that we need to address and to
know how our system behaves when it does
crash so for secure mechanism design
simplicity minimize shared States and
fail securely the final secure design
principle I want to talk about today and
this will be a short one is related to
secure security controls now we have all
of these security controls they are
performing some encryption and
authentication some validation but are
we sure that they are working correctly
are we sure that they are improved
implemented properly this principle says
that you should thoroughly investigate
all the security controls that you are
using to make sure that you are aware
how to use them how you can configure
them perhaps to be insecure and how they
can fail you let's go back to the first
example of this talk the file signing
now we have this digital signature
mechanism but the question is how do we
implement it in our code do we implement
our own algorithm probably not we can
fail it's every step along the way do we
take a proven algorithm something that
people claim is secure take the design
and then implement our code for it well
slightly better not not really great not
terrible but still it we can introduce
code level vulnerabilities here right so
we choose
existing implementation we find a
provider of this function and then
integrate it into our solution and use
the API but it's not really that simple
who can we trust
who are the trustworthy providers is
this some github project with two stars
some student made for his bachelor well
obviously this is not a good choice but
if it is something offered by our
operating system maybe it is a good
choice or a renowned provider of
security controls we select a provider
and then we should ask the question what
are the configuration options for this
control is the function secure by
default I don't have to provide any
parameters and it will work maybe
probably if it's a good provider but
don't count on it you need to be aware
of the configuration options to realize
what can go wrong what can be miss
configured because if we have a Miss
configured security control we might not
have a security control at all and
finally are there any known
vulnerabilities or issues with this
implementation something that really
should be applied to all of your
third-party dependencies be it
tools database is the operating system
or the plethora of libraries that you're
using check to see if there are any
known vulnerabilities on the CV and the
nvd examine if there are any problems
that you should be aware of that can be
exploited to sum up when introducing
security into your codes don't make the
Google query and then copy and paste the
first link from stack overflow
there was actually a study where the
guys examined the amount of vulnerable
code that's posted on Stack Overflow and
how frequently it is found in Android
applications it turns out quite a lot
about 30% of applications that have some
security code had venerable security
code because they pasted it from Stack
Overflow and the irony is that in the
comments people stated this is
vulnerable code don't use it but the
developers didn't care don't be that guy
so for secure security controls always
investigate perform your due diligence
you're introducing this security control
make sure it is introduced correctly now
let's wrap these five sets of design
principles up through Susan's story
let's examine what happened at Equifax
two years ago so in this story we have
some guys that want to get rich this is
your standard attacker he is examining
the internet for services that have
vulnerabilities they at this point there
was a publicly known vulnerability for
Apache struts a framework for building
web applications not unlike spring and
equifax of course use this version of
Apache struts so the attackers were
examining the internet and lo and behold
they found this vulnerability at a
corporation that's serving hundreds of
millions of people
the vulnerability in question in the
Apache struts framework is the lack of
input validation for HTTP headers and
this is where the attackers were were
able to deploy the attack that took over
the machine it took over the machine
because the web application was running
under administrative privileges so they
managed to perform remote code execution
here
the attackers started examining the
system from this point and quickly
discovered the database containing
administrative passwords these passwords
were not encrypted they were not hashed
nothing was protecting them not even
basic access control they took these
passwords and then they started
accessing all the other systems quickly
they retrieved millions of sets of data
related to personal information about
140 million slightly over that people
got their data stolen of course there
was no network segmentation here there
were no query limits on the database so
attackers could perform tens of
thousands of queries with no penalty
with no alarm
there was actually a security control in
place that could have seen all of this
but it was broken there was a network
monitoring tool that could have looked
raised an alarm but it wasn't working it
was that the certificate expired 10
years ago and nobody changed it yeah
so basically Equifax sucks at security
all of this is basic hygiene all of this
is one of these design principles so for
the HTTP headers this is slightly
cheating but it is an insecure security
control you're depending on this
framework it does provide a number of
security options out of the box
you really should be updating it but how
could I back with hacks known well the
Department of Defense sent an email
before way before the attack telling
them hey maybe you have Apache struts in
your infrastructure you should probably
check it and they said now it'll be fine
they didn't check it and then the data
got stolen for the web application
having full privilege over the machine
obviously we don't have sound access
control design for the administrative
passwords no access control and really
no defense-in-depth where's the
cryptography for the passwords Network
segmentation obviously some form of
access control query limits attack
surface reduction limiting the
opportunity that the attacker had and
broke network monitoring well insecure
failure at best but broken security
control
at the core okay so these were the five
sets of security and security design
principles that can apply to all
software really and there's only one
question left to answer how can I
introduce this into my organization into
my team obviously this one our talk
won't cut it right at best I gave you a
map of where to look so you need to read
a lot first of all you can start with
this nist publication in its appendix f
it covers a broad spectrum of secure
design principles a lot more than i
covered here today not all can be
applied to all systems but you really
should check them out to see which are
applicable for your context now these
design principles really like any
software engineering principles it's not
something you can read and then I know
it you need to search for examples you
need to examine them research them you
need to reread the definitions
experiment it takes a while to learn
after that you can examine these two
books they are concerned with an
activity of design review that checks to
see if your design is actually secure we
call this security design analysis so
and shortstack and Shawn field can
really help you develop this attacker
mindset that's required for security
design analysis
finally when you've digested all of this
it's worth examining the complete
security development lifecycle to see
how your design principles can interact
with the rest of development you can you
can access the freely available
Microsoft ebook regarding their as deal
but core software security is slightly
less known but still a valuable catalog
of information now after you've digested
all of this after you've done your
preparation you can start thinking about
introducing this to your organization by
performing a proof-of-concept on the
software you're developing and here you
have two options you can go solo and try
to work overtime maybe grab some hours
from work to start introducing this
security into design the design of your
software the obvious benefit of this is
that you're only working with your time
right you don't need to get other people
involved you don't need to ask for money
basically
but the flaw is that you're really
overfitting yourself for one only you
are becoming the expert here and for two
you might not well more minds are better
than one obviously the second option is
to get team buy-in where you will get
some resources from the team from your
product owner and start introducing this
probably more slowly but also probably
more efficiently and then hopefully you
have some good results and you can move
into the continuous improvement phase
where you'll focus on increasing the
efficiency and quality of your security
design analysis and maybe after some
time go into marketing
to show how secure your design is
so it's not an easy journey and
hopefully I've given you this map that
can help you with these design
principles but if you need more help so
as a supplemental or maybe alternative
approach feel free to contact me I have
a small team of people working with me
on this so maybe we can set some
collaboration up now I can take your
questions
or did I just kill you
well well okay guys if you need a
refresher I'll be here all day so red
shirt guy there's four of us in this
room hopefully you'll find me the only
one with the beard though so feel free
to approach me ask anything you like
regarding the secure design or the
security development lifecycle thank you
for your attention
you