okay we're gonna start with our next
talk now in which Philip is gonna talk
about sack comp your next layer of
defense enjoy one who is already
actively using SATCOM okay that's not
that merit but it's good because this is
an introduction so don't worry so what
we generally do is I want to give a bit
of an overview of what second us and is
how it's used in our product so I come
from elastic the company behind the
elastic search and beat those are the
two ones where I will look at what we do
with sec comp in there and then at the
end quickly how you might capture
violations of sec come to figure out
what bad stuff has happened so let's see
where we can take this oftentimes this
is our approach to security where we
accept that everything is fine and this
works for some time until something
happens and that something could be lots
of stuff it could be your instances
start mining bitcoins or somebody steals
you data or whatever bad stuff could
happen with your stuff and then you
figure out that nothing is fine and
everything is on fire and everything is
terrible and we kind of want to avoid
that bottom half where we say what what
the hell is even our problem and there
are lots of solutions for security
issues and the one thing I want to point
out this there are no silver bullets and
that's why I called it in the defense in
in depth or in layers or whatever is
because there is not one solution you
want to deploy but you want to I have
multiple layers of protection and also
nobody can sell you a tool that will
make everything secure that's yeah nice
for sales and nice to present to you but
it's not working like that so you want
to have multiple layers and seccomp is
one of these potential layers that you
can add to your applications so
basically the idea of second is that it
can block specific system calls in your
application so basically your
application can say like hey I know that
I don't need these system calls so I
don't want to allow them for myself or
put it another way you instrument the
kernel to abort certain calls in your
application
or to kill the process entirely so for
example even if you had a bad
vulnerability in your code and somebody
can do a remote code execution they
might not be able to fork off another
process or call some other binary or
bind the shell or whatever because you
just don't allow it in a second profile
so basically you're filtering out what
system calls are possible from your
application because your application
should know what it needs and then you
can filter out stuff that you don't need
so for example if you know you will
never need to fork another process and
you disallow that even if somebody hacks
your code and you have a remote code
execution vulnerability in there
somebody will not be able to start a
Bitcoin miner a separate process because
you can just not work off that process
that's the general idea what you
probably want to have in your code at
some point it's pretty much an
application sandbox you can limit what
you're doing in your application that's
the overall idea generally this is not a
new feature so it was added in 2005 in
general like it's bit different than
what we have today so the first version
that was in there was and you have proc
the process ID and then a file seccomp
and if you said one in that file you
would enter a strict mode and then your
application would basically be limited
to readwrite exit and secret turn
because that's what a lot of
applications just needed you don't need
to execute another binary you don't need
to fork a process that is kind of like
the first step you know we our
application is fine with those steps so
we are just limiting down to those then
in 2012 basically the foundation was
added to control system can cause more
finely granular so you can actually
register which sis calls are supposed to
be allowed and which ones are supposed
to be forbidden and this was further
improved or especially the ease of
configuration in 2014 when there is now
a system call name seccomp
and with that you can actually register
which system calls are supposed to be
allowed so this is what you're most
likely using today unless you have a
very old kernel somewhere this is what
you get
and just to quickly make sure where we
are so we have syscalls
and it's the one with the s to show you
all the sis codes and if you scroll into
that you will see that these are all the
system calls that you could do
there are a lot over time I'll just
quickly jump to SEC comp and it shows
you okay this system call has been added
in kernel 3.17 as I've had in my slides
and then you could actually look into
the system called and then you can see
what you can actually do here so you can
have that strict mode that is kind of
like that initial mode that we had and
then you can actually set a specific
filter or sometimes also called the
profile where you're actually defined in
the PPF Berkeley packet filter format
what is allowed and what is not allowed
from your application so this is the
system called you're using to actually
register what is allowed and what is not
allowed and you could whitelist or
blacklist depending on how you want to
approach stuff so let's break out of
here again is anybody using that like
any big applications probably quite a
few of the applications that you're
using on a daily basis are using second
profiles already so this is not a
computer completely but this is one so
for example you have google chrome using
it and also flash running in google
chrome I would have its own seccomp
profile to try to filter out bad stuff
but you have it in other browsers
OpenSSH Tucker systemd and quite a few
others so all of these are using
succumbed to kind of limit what you can
actually do how do you register a second
filter then so like we've seen in a man
page already it's written as a Berkeley
packet filter which is I guess nice
which it for computers but not so nice
for humans to create and read or at
least not for me but it is what it is is
anybody using vpf anywhere already
for example if you use TCP dump and
there you could filter with the BPF
format what you actually want to cover
capture or not capture so PPF is widely
used you will run into it every now and
then I'm sitting on the friend of the
syntax but it is widely available and
you will run you to it
and then once you have registered a
filter every single system called that
your application does is running through
that second filter that's it Sam slow no
it's not because this is registered in
the kernel and this will never have to
go to user land but it can only stay in
kernel and so this is a very fast filter
but at first it sounds very expensive
that you say oh we have an additional
filter we need to call for every single
system call but since it's in the kernel
it is fast and probably this is not what
is making your application slow so I
wouldn't worry about that part so much
and I think the results have three
possible outcomes the first one is it's
allowed like we didn't run into any
denial rule that might block that the
process or thread can be killed like you
say hey you run into some you're trying
to do something where I know you should
never do that so just to be safe I'm
terminating the entire process so we're
just cutting you off or the third option
is just to return an error for that
specific system call like the
application still keeps running and
we'll be around but you filter out that
specific filter system call and then log
the error so you can decide what should
be the behavior kill the process just
block the system called or everything is
allowed and keep doing what you want
that is what you have India so like I
said I work for elastic we have our
entire stack how do you seen this one l
or heard of that elastic search logs
such Cubana and because the first
letters make up this nice little L
that's what we always use for that we
have added another component over time
which is called beats which is like a
lightweight agent the shipper written in
go which is basically like tailing log
files for example
the problem is there is no BNL that's
why we try to get rid of that and the
first thing we tried is this the bank or
the LTP which could look something like
this you can see it's a B it's an elk
the combination but doesn't really scale
so we had to do we didn't want to redo
the entire branding and then if we had
add another component we want to redo
that again so we just called it elastic
stack now but if you say elk we still
know what you mean and the entire stack
looks something like this and the two
components where we want to look into
what's a comp is actually doing is
elasticsearch which is kind of are all
this component and where you store your
data and beat that is the one the agent
that runs probably on all your posts or
is a sidecar on your containers or is a
demon set in kubernetes to collect data
that also uses that come to filter out
what is running because well since you
run rolled it out and lots of
applications or lots of nodes you want
to secure that so beach has components
like file be to forward
log files and metric be to collect
metrics and audit beat will quickly look
into that at the end to collect auditing
files this is also how we will be able
to figure out what second violations we
have run into so what do we have here so
in elastic search we are using the or
let me start over elastic search is a
Java process how do we get to the sec
comp profiles or how do we interact with
those low level system callers Java has
something called Java native access GA
and that is how you can interact with
system libraries and do stuff like
seccomp and that is what we were
actively calling there and we have it's
a bit small but probably you can see
that we have a stack class bootstrap
Java and this is pretty much when you
start up the process where we register
that second profile and allow or
disallow law calls as needed here this
is what the initial lives natives the
calls we have here it does a lot of
things one thing I always like to point
out even though it's not SEC comp
specific it's this one here
this is a check that we always run if
you want to run the server processes
root we'll just system.exit
the
we think that is a really bad practice
and sometimes people really want to run
elasticsearch s route which we don't
understand but the only way to make this
work like run elasticsearch as route
would be to fork the code and comment
out this check and there is no other way
around elasticsearch s route just just
saying because this is something that
people run into every night then and
then we have this call here where we are
trying to register the call and we'll
reach out then configure set compass we
need it what we're actually doing here
in the initialization we are calling the
different implementations for the
different operating systems because only
in Linux it's called seccomp but other
operating systems have similar systems
they have different names they behave
slightly differently but we do try to
use them as well I will just focus on
second but you have similar things on
some on BSD even on Windows you have
something to kind of like filter down
what system calls are allowed from your
process and we will just initialize the
one that is the right one for your
operating system
it's just I've added those to you so you
can actually trace through the code and
see how we call stuff and we will throw
an exception if we cannot register the
system call yeah so yeah similar
features just different names and
different operating systems you can find
details in the source code even though
I'll brush over them for today this is
the one and this is the BPF
configuration now that we register in
elasticsearch how when you started up
umm yeah for me it's still a bit of an
arcane syntax but luckily we have these
comments on the side which might be very
hard to read but I'll publish the slides
afterwards you can read them there what
is kind of like the important part is
here what we disallow is fork and
execute of the process elasticsearch so
even if we have some bad stuff in there
which we used to have in the past every
now and then especially around scripting
and people could work another process
out of elasticsearch this is not
possible anymore because we just
filtered it out so nobody can start a
Bitcoin miner by forking out some other
process or bind a shell
of this year because of the system
called is gone it's just quite a bit of
configuration to actually make sure we
have said that and at the end we're
actually checking where we able to
register the SATCOM
filter and if yes we'll just continue
and everything works as expected in case
and if errors happen we will actually
fail the process I I think even though I
would need to validate that so this was
elasticsearch beats is written in gold
there we have a slightly different
approach
so for beats we have actually written
our own library the got comp BPF it's
basically a nicer wrapper so that you
can use the ml to point figure set comp
if you like a mule or not that's a
different discussion but that game is
pretty simple and also you just call it
from your go code so that's pretty
simple to configure what this looks like
or actually this is not what we are
actually using this is just an example
here because what this does is it allows
everything by default but it this allows
these calls here so for example a
connect to the outside world would be
disallowed which doesn't make any sense
for beads because Beach is there to
collect data and then forward it being a
data shipper you will need to connect to
other systems so this is not what beats
uses that's why editor contact is not
used by beats just to be explicit
because this would not allow us to
forward any data this is just an example
but this would be something if you know
like you have some binary running that
never needs to reach out to the network
this is how you could configure order or
filter out the system calls to actually
not connect to anything or receive
messages or whatever so if you have
something that doesn't need those
doesn't need to bind to an interface
doesn't need to listen
you could disallow that and then all the
network traffic or access has been
blocked what we actually have in beats
is it has a white or a loud list it is
going on pretty long and it's much
longer these are all the ones that we
whitelist and allow so it is more
overhead to maintain this because
elasticsearch had a different approach
there we just blocked the forking in
execution part
we actually wipe lists all the calls
that you need and this is a general rule
here in Lippitt which is basically the
base library specific beats might add
specific permissions on top of that so
you can basically just merge more things
into this array that allows that but
this is kind of the baseline that we
maintain that all the beats have these
and then you could add some on top of
those and only those are allowed
everything else is forbidden that is
kind of the approach that we have taken
with Beats here so let's try something
so for example let's run that cat let's
bind to port 1025 if you have a computer
open or a phone with a telnet client you
can do the same because this is an
online instance you can just call it so
this is the domain Sarah WTF because wTF
is obviously the right thing for any
demo and we connect to port 1025 I have
actually opened that so this is binding
to any interface on port 1025 I can just
connect to that and then I can just say
hello Philip and on the other hand hello
Philip is coming out if anybody wants to
try it out feel free to send me a
message and I will receive that so I
will let that run for a moment if you
want to chat with it or actually we can
kill that and instrument that a bit
better so what I'm doing here is I'm
using s phrase to actually get a bit
more insight into the process here I'm
just interested in the binding of the
process so when I run this you can see
this is the call that is being run here
we have pint call to that port to that
address and then it is actually running
and we'll be using that later on to
debug it if we actually kill or disallow
something from the process so what we
have here is we think this one we've
seen this one I'm using the library
called fire jail anybody heard of a used
fire jail so fire jail is
that allows you to set up namespaces and
second sent boxes and I'm just using
that to with one command line argument
actually secure my MC our net cat call
and to actually disallow the binding on
the network interface which looks just
like this so you can see we will call
fire jail with the no profile option and
then we set the second drop rule that if
it binds it should not allow that one
and then we just call the process netcat
on port 1025 so notice this is not the
one I want
this is the one I want what will happen
if I run this any guesses yes it will
exit very quickly and it will tell us
well second protect enabled and then it
will tell you well it didn't allow that
one to actually see what is going on in
there we'll fall back to s trace again
so here I'm using fire jail with the
same thing but here I'm adding s trace
again on the call so when you run that
you will get a lot of output of
everything that the system calls that
are being done internally here the
relevant part is this one here you see
you try to do the bind and then you have
the called B order process being killed
and we that will actually be locked as
well so this is how you can very simply
kind of like simulate setting a second
profile and then a process being killed
and actually monitoring it mid s trace
to see that this is not allowed this
kind of the hello world example of
second and s trace and this is as far as
we will push this for today so it's not
very wanted to go yet now most like
so we have seen that one and now you
don't want just to block everything you
want to collect what has happened in
your system as well so you want to
actually see that somebody has run into
a sec comp violation and you want to get
to that so for that you could use for
example oddity anybody using oddity no
it's a Linux auditing daemon basically
you can define some rules of what should
be collected in terms of security events
it could be stuff like you were binding
to some interface you were accessing a
file where X is executing a binary it
has its own interesting syntax to
configure stuff but in a Linux world
it's pretty widely used to actually see
what is happening and you could by the
way look at what that looks like is if
you say sudo or search this is stuff
that Oddity would spit out for example
here we have been I don't know we've
been calling proc title and then we have
collected a message and then it has some
prop title that we have collected or you
could see here we have been running var
run and sed socket here we have been
running something on the pass so this is
just all auditing information that the
kernel can collect as well
what part of seccomp this is all it D
but this is also very useful to actually
figure out what that stuff has been
running on your system the main problem
here is to centralize these locks as a
bit of a pain in the ass because every
single line looks different than the
other one
and to actually extract the meaningful
information you would need to write the
regular expression here who likes
writing regular expressions
that's the Stockholm Syndrome right
where you get so used to actually doing
some stuff that it's supposed to be the
right way yeah I'm a bit lazy and as a
company we try to avoid some stuff that
we don't like and so for that we have
another page called audit beat that is
using SEC comp but all it beat can
actually get the oddity information
that's the entire idea and we have
another base library behind that and
what that is doing is it's the go-live
audit library and it's basically using
the audit D data to not write that out
to a file but just get in a structured
format from the application right away
and then we can skip the regular
expression part but we can collect that
which then looks something like this
so if you've never seen it this is
Cubana this is where we put stuff
together and we have recently added a
jump right to this part we have added
something we call a seam this is
basically the visualization of what we
have collected with audit beat so you
can see here audit beat has collected
from my host 940,000 security events for
example we have seen logins that's
probably fail ssh attempts and stuff
like that i know what packets are
installed with processes are running
what users I have system log files you
could add other stuff like seek and bro
seeker bro as three catalogs you could
add stuff from your network devices all
of that can flow together here and then
you could just look at the outputs here
so you can see what has succeeded in
what has failed for example and you can
sue see which users have been running
here what I'm interested in I just
searched for SEC comp because I know
there was a second violation and then
down here you can see second pass for
example being called by the main page
because yeah it wasn't a call for the
main page but what I'm more interested
in is this one here and you could just
extend a time line here drop in that
call and then you see these were in the
last fifteen minutes because this is
filtered down to just the last also it
not last 24 hours
this is when we ran that we could open
one of these here I switch over to the
Jason
because this is the actual event that we
have collected the relevant part is here
you see from the audit D module we have
collected something here and you can see
we have a set comp action that was the
one that was triggered and you can see
which user was doing that that is my
user that has been running this and
somewhere in there it would say that
netcat was trying to do this and here
you have the actual event that has been
collected by Oddity and then you can say
okay I see here a violation has happened
we need to actually look into that user
or that binary or whatever has been
happening so you can combine all of that
here so since we're running short on
time time to wrap up security is
generally made up of lots of bricks so
it's part of how you program your
application but it cannot be part of
stuff that you do on the operating
system including second or oddity for
example second is generally vitally
available and used so do use it because
it's another nice layer of protection
that might save your ass at some point
any questions if you want secrets by the
way on the table in the corner there I
have a couple of stickers to just grab
them I think we have like three minutes
or so left so questions
this is not New Year's what about the
users I'm using fire protection
I mean 5 yes five gel comes with the the
profiles and for various applications
and you could use them but what do you
mean that the ruleset per application or
I mean it I'm not I'm not sure I'm
following the question fully but you
have on the github repository you you
have the code and then you have the
rules that people provided and you can
figure out what what is available and if
that works if those are the perfect
rules I'm not sure and it will also
depend on the application and part of
the problem is it might work today but
if they have an update and then do some
new system calls you your application
might just fail but that's just
something you need to fix or depending
on if you wipe the blacklist because if
you just
blakeley's it might be fine if you need
whitelisting it might be more tricky but
that depends on the rules yeah i'm so
for example in elasticsearch what i've
shown you what we are doing here is
blacklisting whereas in beach we are
using whitelisting so you could use
either approach depending on how you
register the filter and how to approach
that then cool yeah wait for the
microphone please
I retired in the duration
yes I mean so why we could use so that
the syntax kind of like the the right
syntax that is see like was let me find
the elasticsearch example this one would
be kind of like the the syntax that you
would use in general but we have
basically done is we wrote the library
for go that will take the other
configuration and just create the right
BPF syntax out of that and so you could
do that for any other programming
language or jason or whatever you want
to write that in but you would need to
write it so what we have done then is we
have used this is for example our
library that this is for dog and then
game to actually just provide yeah it it
tells you how to actually use it and how
to generate the right second profile out
of game through go for the second vpf
syntax but this is custom stuff that we
had to be sure i guess we have time for
one final question
otherwise spank me afterwards for more
that could be very much a trolling
question and I'm careful not to answer
this year so to say I would not say that
Linux is the most secure operating
system because then the
yeah if you if you want to have a heated
discussion with the FreeBSD folks for
example and you could say that and I I'm
very careful to avoid that here because
I I might end up beaten up in a dark
alley afterwards
I so I would be very careful not to say
better because it is really just
different it's different approaches and
different things you can do or cannot do
and this will lead to very heated
discussions if you if you try to say
that so I'm I would be very defensive
and careful here and they say like this
is what Linux does and this is how it
works and it probably adds layer of
protection for you and other operating
systems have something similar which
will behave which is called differently
and behaves differently but to be honest
also I have never looked into the BSD or
Windows implementation so I would avoid
any any qualification of what is better
or worse others have that as well and I
am trying to not have a flame war here
okay good
if you have any questions afterwards I
just find me thanks a lot
you