the sweet of features so it's well known
but it's not really well adopted in the
Enterprise so we'll kind of take a look
at how it works and how attackers kind
of have to change based on these
mitigations
so about me my name is Connor I'm one of
those dumb developers you heard about
earlier I'm at crowdstrike I'm on
Twitter and I have a Blog and I'm pretty
much interested in anything uh C
assembly development related
so today we'll kind of talk about what
Windows exploitation looks like current
in its current state we'll take a look
at the internals of the mitigations
which we're going to speak about then
we'll see how that kind of affects
exploitation
so when it comes to exploitation today
attackers have a few different options
when it comes to taking advantage of
what we would call memory corruption
vulnerabilities
um and the way that this usually uh
occurs is an attacker will try to
execute some sort of unsigned code or
Shell Code as you're all familiar with
the reason for this being is most C2
Frameworks for instance they have a
shell code blob they run because they
call into Windows apis which are a suite
of exported functions on Windows that
allow you to open network connections
Etc so when you do that in pure Shell
Code it easily allows you to call those
functions set up arguments Etc and it's
the path of least resistance
so um most exploit chains today though
they take two separate um exploits and
the reason for this being is popular
initial access targets like web browsers
they're sandboxed so an attacker
exploits a web browser for instance
um the code execution they have is only
in context of a very low privileged
um sandbox essentially you can't open up
network connections do any of the things
we want to do
drop files Etc so what they'll try to do
is they'll try to privilege escalate
from there
um and the and the main method of that
is Through the Windows kernel because
obviously it's accessible to anyone that
uses the OS
so the way that this works is that it's
a three-step approach so attackers on
Modern operating systems there's really
no read write execute memory by default
so they'll find a writable portion of
memory where they can write their shell
code to they'll use some sort of first
stage payload to mark that Shell Code as
executable because remember that memory
is only writable it's not executable and
then they'll do something called control
flow hijacking where they force the
target to execute that memory which
obviously it's now executable and so
it's going to run your shell code
and in the windows kernel here's kind of
how this looks a high level diagram so
basically we got the memory address
ffff780 sign extended and it contains
some Shell Code in the red and we can
see the acronym pte
um below which stands for page table
entry that describes this memory region
so what this is saying the K stands for
kernel it's a kernel mode memory address
W stands for writable and v stands for
valid so we've taken care of the first
step which is writing some shell codes
somewhere that's writable but it's not
executable
then an attacker will use some sort of
second stage payload which we talked
about and they will find the page table
entry that corresponds to the memory so
the page table entry describes that page
it says hey this is readable writable
Etc they locate that metadata and they
corrupt it and so now when the memory
manager or excuse me when the CPU goes
to execute this instruction it looks at
uh the metadata and it says oh this is
executable that means there's code that
needs to be executed there so we've gone
from a writable page to executable page
and then on the right hand side we can
see that we overwrote a function pointer
so as the name infers function pointer
points to a function so we override it
with the memory address of our Shell
Code so what will happen now when this
function pointer goes to be executed
it's going to execute this memory
address which is a malicious address
that contains Shell Code which is now
executable
so that's kind of that three-step
approach we talked about this is
actually mitigated so that was a kernel
mode example but in user mode where
typical users operate that's actually
mitigated with a mitigation called
arbitrary code guard and what that does
is it basically says it's Windows
implementation of write to X or execute
which means memory can either be
writable or executable but never both so
in our example what we did was we
corrupted the page table entry to make
memory uh memory that was writable
executable well that violates the tenet
of arbitrary code guard that memory
can't be both of those things at any one
time
um but that's a user mode mitigation
arbitrary code guard and the reason why
that's a user mode mitigation is because
the mitigation itself is implemented in
the kernel so we have a user mode kernel
mode security boundary so if we
implement the mitigation in kernel mode
well attackers in user mode they can't
corrupt the Integrity of that mitigation
because it's protected by the kernel
right
but in our example that we showed it was
a kernel mode exploit right
so
if you try to implement a mitigation in
the kernel but your mitigation Works off
of the fact you're trying to block
attackers that already have access to
the kernel that's basically a mid the
kernel trying to defend against itself
right if I'm an attacker and I access
internal you put a mitigation there well
I'll just disable the mitigation and
then go on my Merry way so we need to
address this problem of how do we
address this if the kernel is the
highest security boundary essentially on
the OS
and that's exactly what we'll talk about
here we'll talk about hyper-v we'll talk
about VBS which is virtualization-based
security and then hvci is a little later
we'll get to that
um VBS or virtualization-based security
it's as I mentioned a suite of features
uh enforce and provided by hyper-v
um this Suite of features as I mentioned
if you're familiar with it you're
probably familiar with credential guard
for instance which is one of the
security mitigations offered Under the
Umbrella of VBS
um and what VBS does is it works off of
hyper-v which is Microsoft's hypervisor
so since hyper-v is responsible for
enforcing VBS it's worthwhile
investigating the design
and hyper-v works off of the notion of
partitions so the root partition is
What's called the host OS so what
happens is with hyper-v when your
machine Boots the root partition fills
the entire physical address space that's
your host operating system right there
shouldn't be any VMS running at that
point so as VMS
what are known as child partitions and
those child partitions are basically
just a set of resources that host a
virtual machine
and as I mentioned the root partition
takes up the whole address space of the
computer and then anytime we create a
virtual machine we allocate from that
root partition
here is an example a diagram of this
taken from the msrc blog
as we can see we have the root partition
and the child partition they both run on
top of hyper-v um the child partition
doesn't run inside of the root partition
as I mentioned the root partition gets
allocated from as child partitions are
there
so basically we can just think of this
as root partition that's your host OS
right that's what we use on an everyday
basis child partition our instances of
virtual machines essentially and they
run on top of the hypervisor which is
hyper-v
um a child partition as I mentioned is
allocated from the root partition right
so that means it has its own address
space
um and it has its own address space
because we want to isolate it from other
child partitions and the root partition
right like if you've ever ran malware
before you want to run it in a VM
generally speaking barring any
vulnerabilities in the hypervisor
because it's isolated right
um but how does that isolation actually
work there's a technology on Modern CPUs
called slat second layer address
translation and Intel's implementation
of slat is known as extended page tables
and what slat does is it allows the CPU
to intercept VM memory access
essentially and the reason for this is
is because VMS just act on memory as
we'll see in the diagram in the next
slide as if they're the only OS running
right you don't know about other VMS at
a high conceptual level
so something needs to compensate for
that because what if we have multiple
VMS running for instance
so if we look at this example on the
right hand side outline in the red we'll
call that our child partition which is a
VM running right it runs inside of the
in the computer essentially
um and then we have the root partition
there which is total address space and
the child partition is allocated from
there
the issue though right so if we look on
the right hand side you can see like any
of those memory addresses let's choose
Xerox 1000 for instance on the right
hand side
well on the host OS that's actually
located at 0x4000 right so the VM Maps
you know 0x 1000 as oh I'm just going to
access 0x1000 well Xerox 1000 on the
host OS is unmapped right up there and
that's where the vm's running so that's
where the memory technically lives so
what slat does basically it says hey I
see this VM going to access 0x1000
that's actually located at 0x 4000 so
let me perform translation so that the
VM knows hey even though it thinks it's
accessing 0x1000 that memory is actually
somewhere else on the host
and the way this is done is by managing
an additional set of page tables
um so paid tables basically contain all
the necessary information to perform
memory translation so what happens now
is every VM is associated with an
extended page table
um
and the CPU basically knows that and it
knows to associate each set of page
tables with a given VM so let's say vm1
goes to access ZRX 1000 the CPU knows
hey I need to access the page tables
from vm1 so that I know I can translate
0x1000 into the actual memory on the
host OS
and the way this is done is VMS emit
something called gpas or guests physical
addresses so the VMS just act on memory
as if they're the only OS running and
then the CPU behind the scenes
intercepts that and translates that into
actual uh memory on the computer
so as you can see in this example
um the VM in the bottom left it accesses
a memory address which gets translated
in context of that VM then that gets
emitted and the CPU intercepts that and
says hey I see you're going to access
Xerox 1000 let me look at the virtual
machine control structure or vmcs which
contains your vm's page tables and see
where that memory actually lives on the
host OS
so this is actually the technology that
allows VMS to remain isolated because
the CPU handles all of the translation
VMS can only access the partition
they've been allocated
and what VBS does it basically abuses
these principles for security purposes
so now we can isolate sensitive parts of
memory basically how VMS are isolated
but instead of using virtual machines
VBS implements something known as
virtual trust levels or vtls
foreign
so as we can see here vtl 0 is what we
refer to as normal mode
so you boot up your machine it's got VBS
running you don't really know it it's
not transparent to the end user and
they're operating in normal world so you
have your typical user and kernel mode
over there but now we have a vtl1 which
is known as secure mode which contains
the secure kernel that can basically
protect all of the secrets
um
of the OS itself
um so we can think of this as when you
run your machine with Windows uh excuse
me with a VBS enabled you're kind of
running in a VM of sorts so we don't
have virtual hard disks or networking or
anything like that
um vtls are just an isolated segment of
memory just like a VM is
so as I mentioned that's what a vtl is
so we can isolate one vtl from another
just like we can isolate VMS from one
another and this allows hypervisor
protected code Integrity or hvci which
is the mitigation we're going to talk
about to work actually
so hvci is another mitigation just like
credential guard that falls under VBS
and this is the answer to the question
earlier of how do we stop Shell Code in
the kernel because we know we have
arbitrary code guard in user mode but
that mitigation is implemented in the
kernel so if an attacker in user mode
wants to try to disable arbitrary code
guard well you already need access to
the kernel but if the kernel is a high
security boundary how do we stop kernel
mode code execution if we assume an
attacker already has access there
so what happens is vtl0 and vtl1 are
placed in the root partition so there's
no child partitions anymore we place
them in the root partition so they
technically have access to the same
physical address space
and since they have access to the same
physical address space we don't really
need to use the extended page tables for
translation anymore so hvci abuses them
for a different purpose and that's to
create an additional set of page tables
with an immutable set of permissions
so what that means is vtl1 which is
secure world when the system boots
vtl1 can ask the hypervisor hey I want
to configure the extended page tables
with these permissions
and the hypervisor manages those
um so now what happens is if a kernel
mode exploit in vtl 0 tries the page
which we talked about earlier that
metadata which describes a given memory
page well we have a source of Truth now
that's managed by the hypervisor and the
hypervisor is a higher security boundary
than the kernel so therefore you can't
create Dynamic executable memory here's
kind of what that looks like
um so in this example we have a memory
address and we have a pte which we saw
earlier so this describes this memory
page as writable and readable then we
have an Associated extended page table
entry which again is managed by the
hypervisor
so if we do the same thing as last time
we corrupt the pte which are stored in
the kernel
and we make it executable well the
hypervisor says no way actually this is
still readable and writable because it's
those extended page tables are actually
the source of Truth and they're managed
by the hypervisor and the kernel can't
directly access the hypervisor
and the way this works is we use the
exact same Concepts as we did with the
virtual machine so with a VM when it
goes to access some memory what can the
CPU do it can intercept that or gate
that access that's exactly what we do
here anytime vtl0 which is the normal
world or untrusted World anytime we
access memory we can VTO or excuse me
the hypervisor can gate that memory
access just like a VM we can intercept
that and we can say hey we see you're
trying to execute this memory but
actually our version of memory which is
immutable from the kernel it says it's
not executable and therefore we're not
going to let you execute this memory
anyway so we can dilly dally in the
kernel all we want corrupting all the
page table entries to say this memory is
executable but the hypervisor has a
source of Truth and um it's immutable
so to summarize this vtl1 sets up the
proper permissions of memory so what
vtl1 is responsible for here is setting
up just like arbitrary code guard right
to xor execute no memory is ever both
writable and executable which is a
prerequisite for Shell Code
all of those extended page table entries
that contain the ground truth are
protected by the hypervisor so even an
attacker in kernel mode can't
arbitrarily access the hypervisor
um to corrupt that metadata essentially
so now that we know this information
let's see how this affects exploitation
so we've talked about using hvci for
enforcing executable permissions correct
so thus far we've said hey with hvci
enabled we can't just make our own
executable memory to start executing
Shell Code
but another interesting thing about hvci
is we can use those same principles to
protect other sensitive parts of memory
such as the kernel control flowguard
bitmap
so a white kernel control flowguard is
is it's the kernel mode implementation
of CFG or control flowguard which is a
mitigation that's been in Windows since
Windows 8.1 it was an optional update
then
um and what CFG is it's mitigation that
checks all indirect function calls to
ensure function pointer hasn't been
overwritten
and the way this is done is a bitmap is
created of all of the known valid
functions that are used in indirect
function calls in a given application so
you develop your application you may
call into five different functions at
compile time a bitmap is created with
that information and anytime an indirect
function call happens we check that
bitmap to say hey is this a valid call
Target is this a legitimate function we
know about if it's not we crash a
process
and that may sound a bit confusing but
if we go back to our original example
what allowed our Shell Code to execute
we had to overwrite a function pointer
right and when that function pointer was
executed in the future it redirected
execution into our malicious Shell Code
well now that that's called an indirect
function call when that happens and
that's now checked by kernel control
flowguard and that will crash the
process essentially at that point
because we've done a malicious action
um so kcfg runs into the same issue as
our as
um trying to implement arbitrary code
guard in the kernel right
normal control flow guard is protected
by the kernel the bitmap but when you
try to implement a mitigation in the
kernel as we talked about earlier and
you assume an attacker has access to the
kernel well that's again the kernel
defending against itself we can't do
that right because an attacker could
just disable the mitigation before they
deploy their attack in the kernel for
instance
so we've got to do something about that
we do the exact same thing as hvci
except we do it on read-only permissions
at this point so what hvci does is it
protects the kcfg bitmap and it says hey
this bitmap is read only because if an
attacker can make it writable they can
mark all of memory as valid call targets
and call into whatever memory they want
right the point of kcfg is to prevent
function pointers from being overwritten
so we do the same thing here in this
example it's a debugger in the bottom
right where it says pte that's the page
table entry that corresponds to the
kernel control flowguard bitmap and I've
marked it explicitly as K kernel which
it already is and W as writable right
but then I use the EP command to try to
override it with some junk data and look
at the error I get memory access error
that is hvci saying hey the extended
page table that maps to the bitmap is
read only even though in the kernel
you've said it's writable the hypervisor
views it as read only so we block the
right operation essentially and that's
how we protect kernel control flowguard
in the kernel
so with hvci enabled in totality here's
where we stand
can write our Shell Code all day long to
Kernel mode memory that's already
writable
but we can't make it executable
and even if we could make it executable
anytime we try to override a function
pointer to go to execute that Shell Code
kernel control flowguard will prevent it
so this puts us in an interesting
predicament
so what do we do about this
so as I mentioned earlier what is Shell
Code used for Shell Code as I mentioned
like a C2 framework well it's a blob of
Shell Code that calls into various
Windows apis right so you may have a
function a Windows API called open
process maybe you're familiar with that
that's to obtain a handle to an object
basically that's the that's what um C2
Frameworks will do they'll call into
these apis in ways they weren't intended
to to open up network connections read
files or write files read memory from
other processes like lsas for instance
um so we know that's what we want to do
with shell code but we can't actually
execute shell codes so what if we could
do something that was hvci compliant but
accomplishes the same thing of calling
into windows apis
well the main issue that's facing us is
how do we gain execution
um
kernel control flowguard is going to
prevent us from overriding a function
pointer for instance but that's not the
only type of control flow transfer
that's available what about returns for
instances right an assembly when a call
instruction happens what happens at that
point a return address is pushed onto
the stack and that's just if you in C
for instance if you have a function body
what does it normally end with a return
it returns a value to the function which
called it an assembly what happens is a
return address is pushed onto the stack
and when the function is done executing
it uses that address to know where we
need to return execution back to well as
I mentioned it's used to return
execution somewhere so it's also used in
a control flow transfer one of the known
limitations of CFG in general is return
or backwards edge control flow transfers
kernel control flowguard only
investigates forward Edge or calls or
jumps it doesn't investigate returns
so what if we could override a return
address on the stack right if you're
familiar with your typical 32-bit no
aslr depth buffer overflow that most
people do as their first exploit
um that's what you do you don't people
use the term like oh I overwrote EIP for
instance you didn't overwrite EIP you
smashed the stack and you found a return
address on the stack you overwrote that
return address and eventually that
return address was loaded into the
instruction pointer so we kind of need
to go back to the basics if that makes
sense but we can't assume we have a
stack overflow
and we need to leak the stack of a
kernel mode thread luckily enough
Windows blessed us with this gift a
function exported by ntdll called NT
query system information that will
gladly give us kernel mode addresses
from user mode from a medium Integrity
process so medium Integrity process
that's basically any application you
open up on Windows
so what we can do here is we can create
a thread
in user mode and we could put that
thread in a suspended State then we
could call NT query system information
which is accessible from user mode and
that would give us the K thread object
associated with that thread and a
k-thread object as it infers by the
first letter in the name k kernel it's
the kernel mode representation of a
thread thread is an object that's
managed in the kernel
so basically we can leak the threat we
can leak a k-thread object from the
kernel of any thread we create in user
mode basically by Design
and each user mode thread has a user
mode stack and a kernel mode one now you
may be thinking Connor this doesn't make
sense you created the thread and user
mode but you're telling me you've leaked
a kernel mode thread well that's because
every thread on Windows has both a user
mode stack and a kernel mode stack
regardless if you create it in user mode
or kernel mode
so what we can do is we can basically
use native functionality in Windows to
leak a k-thread object associated with a
thread we control and if we look in K
thread there are two members of that
object called stack limit and stack base
as it infers that's the stack and what's
on the stack return addresses
so since we know we can leak the K
thread object associated with the thread
we control
which return address do we want to
Target
so we see a bunch of these return
addresses on the stack this is what a
call stack looks like for a newly
created suspended thread and we're going
to choose Ki APC interrupt as our Target
address we're going to overwrite this is
all going to make sense in a little bit
um and the reason why we're going to
choose this one is because a suspended
thread on Windows is actually just a
thread that has what's called an APC or
an asynchronous procedure call cued to
it and that APC tells the thread don't
do anything and what an APC is it's
basically a code root it's basically
code just like a thread a thread
executes code but instead of executing
code in a thread that code is executed
in context of a given thread
so what happens is with an APC a sort of
software interrupt gets issued that
calls an APC which tells the thread hey
don't do anything which sounds like a
suspended thread that's not doing
anything
and the way you resume this thread or
the way the thread can start executing
again is it's it's um basically waiting
on an object and that is the suspend
count
so until the suspend count of a k thread
is zero your thread is going to be
suspended so when we call uh suspend
thread or when we create a suspended
thread suspend count is set to one
and we decrement that by calling resume
thread so if you think about it without
knowing any of this lower level
knowledge quote unquote if you created
the suspended thread and you call resume
thread that should theoretically resume
your thread right what that's actually
doing is it's incrementing and
decrementing suspend count
and the reason why this is even
important at all is because we know that
when we create a suspended thread we
know an APC should always be queued and
therefore that return address should
always be on the stack
Now using a kernel mode vulnerability we
have the stack right we can locate
return addresses we can corrupt those
then when the return address is executed
it will call into our fake return
address basically
so if we look at this in this example in
the top screenshot of our exploit we've
leaked the stack which we've done no
exploitation up at this point this is
perfectly legitimate Windows exported
functionality that I encourage you to
try out on your own so we've leaked the
stack but then we use our kernel mode
vulnerability which again now we're
getting to the vulnerability part where
we corrupt that return address with 4141
4141 and look what happens we get an
access violation even with kernel
control flowguard implemented because
what happens when that return address
gets executed it's now trying to execute
4141 4141 so basically we've we've proof
of concept that we can control the stack
we can control execution at this point
so with the control of this we can
basically do a code reuse attack
um if you're familiar with the term
return oriented programming or raw
that's probably the most
um mainstream of them
um we can't execute Shell Code directly
but what a Shell Code dude it calls into
windows apis
we can do this in peer return addresses
that's what a return oriented
programming infers
and that's basically mimicking our Shell
Code so we can't just set up a Shell
Code blob anymore but we can kind of do
the same thing shellcode intends to do
so what is Rob
um just a high level ROP is basically
flooding the the stack with a bunch of
fake return addresses essentially and
each fake return address does some sort
of interesting code sequence and it ends
in a return
and the reason for this being is because
what a rat actually does a return
instruction it takes whatever is located
on the stack pointer and it will load
that into the instruction pointer for
execution so by Nature every time what's
called a Rob Gadget which is a series of
instructions it's executed when the
return happens what does it do it looks
at the stack picks up what's ever there
and executes it well if we flooded the
stack with fake return address every
time we execute a rap Gadget it's going
to go pick up the next one and the next
one and the next one
and here's an example of this so we
pretend that we control this stack which
we do in our exploit and what do we do
we flood it with fake return addresses
and what we do is we set up a function
call by par by setting all of the
functions in the proper registers so
each architecture has a calling
convention right on Windows 64-bit
systems by default it's the fast call
calling convention and what that means
at the assembly level whenever you call
into a function if you actually looked
at the disassembly each one of your
arguments that you passed is loaded into
various registers namely rcx first for
the first argument RDX R8 R9 so that's
what we do here we load up our arguments
and then we return into the function so
basically this is a way to call the
function virtual protect in peer return
addresses
and the reason why we do that again is
because that's a code reuse Technique we
are reusing code that's already
executable we can't just Supply our own
we have to find code because again
applications are made up of code so we
know we can basically do the Shell Code
via Rob so what is this useful for
so let's do an example right we have a
kernel exploit let's try to do something
interesting like terminate the msmpng
process which is the Windows Defender
anti-malware service process
so if you've ever heard of the term PPL
before protected process light this is
basically a type of process that is
special in a way so in this case this
msmp engine it's what it's an
anti-malware process so AV vendors are
afforded the ability to make their
process a PPL and in this case it is an
anti-malware PPL and what that means is
it prevents other processes even
administrators from tampering with it
right so it's a special kind of process
that only the kernel could do something
with as we see in this example even with
a command prompt running as an
administrator when we try to kill the
process what does it say access denied
because it's afforded special protection
so we know we have a kernel exploit even
with hvci enabled we know we can call
into Windows API so let's see if we
can't do anything interesting
so as I mentioned earlier a handle I'll
give a just a brief overview it's not in
the slides a handle is a an intermediary
way to interact with an object right so
a process is actually a object managed
by the kernel so we can't just access
that directly right but we can open
What's called a handle to it which
basically is a proxy almost like an API
of sorts that allows us to request a
given access or action be done so we
could open up a handle to lsas which is
what attackers do and they might call a
mini dump right dump which is a Windows
API function that dumps the process
memory you need a handle to do that so
in order to terminate a process we need
a handle
but we know it's a PPL so even as an
admin we can't terminate it right so we
need some sort of Kernel exploit to do
this which we already have
um so we we need more than just admin
access essentially
we need to actually get our handle from
to this process from the kernel right
even an administrator cannot just
arbitrarily open a handle we need to do
it from the kernel well we have an
exploit primitive to start calling
functions in the kernel so good for us
we can call into the function ZW open
process which is a kernel only API call
that as it infers opens a process handle
so using Rob uh basically here's an
example once we control the stack using
all the aforementioned steps we talked
about we can flood the stack with fake
return addresses and in this case we
populate arguments in registers that
eventually call into ZW open process and
this is what it would look like we
leaked the stack we corrupt the all the
return addresses and we're able to call
into ZW open process so that alone would
give us a handle to the defender
anti-malware process even though it's a
PPL
but there's a bit of an issue and that's
because we're in the kernel now so what
happens anytime there's any kind of
fault or issue in the kernel you get a
bsod a blue screen of death right so
we've just totally smashed and just
mashed the stack with garbage
essentially that we control and there
are legitimate return addresses that
need to be returned into critical
functions right so if we just let
bygones be bygones there we're going to
just
um cause a Visa a blue screen of death
essentially
so we need some way to avoid that
so what we actually want to do is we
want to find a way to actually terminate
the thread that that X our exploits
running in because as we talked about
earlier we've created a dummy thread to
do all this exploitation work and right
we don't care about it necessarily but
we needed to gracefully terminate we
can't just let the kernel
um you know handle a fault because it
may be devastating
so basically we just append our first
rock chain with a second drop chain that
invokes terminate thread
so we have a handle to our dummy thread
we just pass that handle in to terminate
thread and after we open the handle
defending process terminate thread lets
the kernel handle all of the termination
of our thread so we don't need to worry
about cleanup because the kernel is
going to handle it for us
so basically after our exploit work is
done we call ZW terminate thread and
that's going to terminate the dummy
thread gracefully and we're not going to
get a blue screen of death
so here is
um the the last set of issues that we're
facing here and these are more just
about the creativity of exploitation not
really hvci
so we want to pass the defender process
handle to the function terminate process
right because we want to terminate the
process
although we have a handle to the process
there is an issue that we're facing it's
actually two issues
the first being handles are stored in a
per process handle table
so what that means is every time a
handle is open that's managed by a table
in your process so our exploit process
let's say it's called exploit.exe right
well that's got a handle table of all of
the handles that are opened stemming
from exploit.exe
um yeah so let's talk about that a
little bit so they're in a handle table
so we're gonna have to resolve that in a
second
um being able to locate that handle but
the main issue is that anytime a handle
is open to most anti-malware
um processes something happens and
um
let's sorry I'm losing myself here
um let's talk about this as I just
mentioned so anytime in a um
anti-malware
um process you can register since you're
a special type of process these um
kernel mode callbacks you may have heard
of these before and basically what a
kernel mode callback is it's a function
you register in the kernel that anytime
a given action happens any function that
was registered is notified so for
instance you can register a callback
function for process creation so let's
say Defender registers a kernel callback
for process creation anytime a process
is created on the whole OS that Defender
uh process
callback is called so that's how your
anti-malware
utilities know a process was created
right
while there is also a callback you can
register for object creation so anytime
you open up a handle
um any uh security product that
registered a callback will get notified
that you've created a handle and what
Defender does is anytime you try to open
up a handle to Defender that callback
will strip the access rights from it so
you can never open up a handle to
Defender with the needed permissions to
terminate it from user mode
and the second issue is that even if we
were able to open up a kernel handle to
this process anytime you open up a so
let me explain this uh we opened a user
mode handle so even though we called a
kernel mode function as I said
um it's in our per process handle table
so exploit.exe is responsible for
opening up that handle right to the
defender process well that means that
handle will be stored in exploit.exe's
handle table
um but we want to open up a kernel
handle to it because anytime you do a
user mode uh handle to the defender
process you're going to get your access
rights stripped but the issue is if you
open up a true kernel handle which we'll
talk about in the next slide a true
kernel handle that will get stored in
the system processes handle table so now
we run into an issue where even if we
get the necessary handle it's stored in
another process as handle table so when
we call terminate process it will try to
look up in our handle table all of the
handles and it won't find it because
it's located in another process
so the first issue is we need a true
candle we need a true kernel handle so
the way we do this is when we call ZW
open process we got to supply a
structure here called object attributes
and there are a few uh there are a few
options you can set here in attributes
one of them being OB kernel handle as
the name infers this is going to make
this handle what a kernel handle so
basically now when we call into this
function we Supply this and the the
handle will be opened up as a kernel
handle which means Defender won't strip
the access rights
and this is how this is done so
basically we can just set 0x 200 which
is the notation of object kernel handle
the actual value
so great now we have a kernel handle so
we know we can terminate the process now
but the issue is when we call terminate
process to actually kill it where is
that handle located in the system
processes handle table which we cannot
just arbitrarily access
so we need to think a bit outside the
box here so what if we could actually
Force our process to think it needs to
locate all of its Handles in the system
process table
there's actually a way to do this you
need a kernel mode vulnerability but
basically we know we can leak k-thread
objects right of all threads there is a
member known as a previous mode in what
previous mode is is it's a way to denote
um your execution came from when a
system routine reaches the kernel right
so if you're familiar with system calls
on Linux right like you load a system
call number and you invoke Cisco that's
actually true on Windows but it's
abstracted from you so what happens is
for instance when you call virtual alloc
to allocate some memory that's actually
just a wrapper which calls another
wrapper which eventually goes down to
the ntdll layer which invokes NT
allocate virtual memory which does the
same thing loads a syscall number and
does syscall and what syscall does is it
transfers execution into the kernel to
allocate some resources for us like
memory
so when that system call happens
previous mode is always one when it
comes from user mode so the kernel knows
hey this is untrusted input from user
mode let me do some Security checks but
when previous mode is zero this means
that the system call originated from the
kernel itself
so what if we used our current
vulnerability to make the kernel think
the handle it needs to resolve is from
the system process handle table
well if we look at the actual system
call that's responsible for terminating
a process which in this example at the
top it may be hard to see in the
outlined red box is NT terminate process
which again terminate process is a
wrapper which eventually invokes this
system called routine and one of the
first things it does is it looks at the
thread that's responsible for invoking
this routine and it captures previous
mode and it passes that off to another
function
and that function is called OBP
reference object by handle with tag
mouthful
um so what this function actually does
is it looks and it says hey is this a
kernel handle and the way a kernel
handle is denoted is its sign extended
with ffff8
and after that check is done it looks at
previous mode and it says is previous
mode zero well if it's one that means it
comes from user mode right and we should
not trust it and we don't want to look
up the handle table in the kernel
because it's originating from some
process in user mode but if it's zero we
infer oh this this execution is coming
from the kernel itself and where is the
Kernel's handle table located at the
system process
so if we corrupt previous mode to zero
and then we invoke terminate process
this kind of tricks the kernel into
looking up handles from the kernel
handle table
so we can actually do this in our
exploit um so in this example it may be
hard to read we open up a handle to the
thread that's performing all of this in
our exploit which is the current thread
so we open up a handle to our own thread
we leak the K thread object associated
with that thread again perfectly valid
Windows exported functionality you can
do not a vulnerability
and we leak the K thread object which is
a kernel mode address we then can um
corrupt the previous mode member of K
thread to zero so now what happens
anytime this thread makes a system call
the kernel thinks oh this is originating
from the kernel
so now what we basically can do is we
can use Rob to call ZW open process and
obtain a kernel handle then we can clean
up our execution which we talked about
with terminate thread and then we can
use our vulnerability to corrupt
previous mode and set it to zero and
then using that same thread called
terminate process again this would have
been a lot easier to just have a shell
code blob in the kernel mark it as
executable and run it but that's kind of
the point of this talk is we can't do
that anymore we have to get very
convoluted with these sort of things
so I won't press play yet but on the
right hand side this is um process
hacker and that you can't see really but
it's msmpng and that's showing our
process is running the defender process
let's see if this plays
so now we run our exploit and if we keep
a look on the right hand side
give it a second
no I was not brave enough for a live
demo
oh did I oh it's not it's it paused
halfway through my video
can't even get the pre-recorded demo
right
and if we look on the right hand side
now
um in about there it goes uh the
defender process is terminated so that
would have been a lot easier to do in
Shell Code but again we can't do that
anymore
so last part
um we've kind of said oh hpci is really
cool right but we it doesn't really
matter because we can get more
convoluted and take care of it
um that's actually not the case let's uh
we'll talk about how we augment hvci
so what did our exploitation rely on WE
flooded the stack with a bunch of fake
return addresses correct
well with the Advent of Intel CET which
is a hardware mitigation that's actually
no longer possible
so what CET is it's uh control flow
enforcement technology and it's a
hardware mitigation that protects the
Integrity of the stack
so earlier we talked about when a call
happens at the assembly level what will
happen a return
so in this case we're calling the
function Foo and its return address is
pushed onto the stack but now we have
something called a shadow stack which is
Hardware protected that software
technically can access for checking
purposes but not anything that could be
corruptable because if you're in user
mode the checks are done in the kernel
so you need access to the kernel and
same thing here if you're the checks are
done and if you have CET running in the
kernel it's protected by hvci so that's
kind of why I'm bringing this up here so
in this case we have a stack we push
them onto the stock the return addresses
so now we kind of do what we did with
Rob right we corrupt the return address
but we actually have the shadow stack
which is an immutable copy of the stack
and then anytime a return happens into
this corrupt into the uh stack we check
that which with the shadow stack to
insert a little overwritten
so if you override a return address you
crash
um so that's the end of Rob with um CET
and what did our whole thing rely on WE
flooded the return address with Rob or
excuse me we flooded the return address
the stack with return addresses and we
can't do that with CET anymore
so with the way this goes with
mitigations is your mitigations are only
as res they're only as good as their
resiliency
and I know that sounds kind of redundant
but hvci does what it's intended to do
you cannot execute unsigned code anymore
but it's not resilient until you
implement something like CET coupled
with it that totally prevents even other
things like code reuse
um so the conclusion here is these
mitigations are great but the the they
complement each other
um so just depending on one
um won't it'll help you with out of the
box exploits but the more determined
attacker not so much
um but what's interesting too is Windows
only uses the shadow stack portion of
CET so CET actually is twofold it checks
return addresses with the shadow stack
but there's also something called
indirect Branch tracking or IBT and that
is checking jumps and calls well Windows
already has CFG and they have a better
version of CFG called extended flowguard
or xfg so Windows actually only uses the
shadow stack portion of CET it doesn't
use all of it so to keep a technique
like this alive basically you would need
to find a bypass in CFG or xfg because
control flow enforcement technology is a
hardware mitigation right you can't
access it in user mode and the shadow
stack excuse me or in the kernel
um so believe it or not these are all
free mitigations not well technically
not free because um
you know you need supported Hardware to
do it and that's my last little 30
second tangent I'll give it actually
wasn't the TPM that was responsible
these mitigations are enabled by default
on Windows 11. TPMS have been around for
a very long time actually there's
another Hardware mitigation called mbeck
it stands for mode based execution
control
and windows has a software
implementation of mbec for CPUs that
don't support it well that software
implementation is much slower than the
hardware mitigation mbac but in order
for hvci to also be resilient you need
mbac which is outside the scope of this
talk and Microsoft didn't want their OS
to be slow obviously you don't want to
use the software implementation if you
don't have to you want to use the
hardware and that's where the CPU
requirement really comes in but it was I
don't know why it went under the guise
of TPM because those have actually been
around for a really long time
so these are all available for free you
can enable them on supported hardware
and yeah that's the end of my talk so if
you have any questions I'm happy to take
them now or later
yes
at the same time Kenny
development debugging okay so um believe
it or not
um most of us are probably familiar with
like if you've ever done basic buffer
overflow's immunity debugger or some
debugger like that Windows has their own
fully supported debugger called wind
debug
when dbgs some people that's not you
know you'll get a lot of flack for
saying it that way but that's how it's
spelled and it's a fully supported
debugger by Microsoft and it's can do
kernel debugging so all of these other
debuggers can't really do kernel
debugging and it's all supported by
Microsoft so what's cool is
um you can parse
memory as objects that are supported by
Microsoft for instance so they publish
what they're public symbols which
contain all of the um like notations for
all the function names object names Etc
and then I also like to use a
disassembler um Ida I'm sure you've
probably heard of it before and I kind
of augment them together so I'll use I
for like static analysis for instance
what is what is this kind of doing at a
high level but Ida can only get you so
far because there's a dynamic component
to it what is the code actually doing
while it's running so I'll kind of
couple those
um together and another one is strings
utility
um so parsing a binary where's the mem
copy happening at things like that so
and there was another one yeah
okay
foreign
yeah so um that has to do with
um just the um like we saw for instance
with a suspended thread right the APC is
handed at the kernel level so each um
thread for instances like that where
that's done the kernel interrupt and
it's got to be in context of a given
thread that's why there'll be an
Associated kernel mode stack with the
user mode um thread itself so no matter
what you're doing there's always a
portion of the stack kernel mode memory
reserve the stack for any given thread
foreign
it depends on where the execution is
um so execution depending on if it's in
the kernel or in user mode
um but it's not like a one-for-one copy
right so the the user mode data isn't
located on the Kernel mode stack for
instance
yeah um good question so um Windows
doesn't fully support it but there is a
mitigation as well it's called
supervisor mode access prevention and
what that does is it also prevents
accessing
um data in certain instances
um in user mode and um it's just not
good practice really
um the the best practice really is like
in a system call for instance you safely
copy the parameters down into the kernel
and then um deal with it that way a lot
of drivers they'll just arbitrarily copy
stuff into the kernel and do things like
that you don't want to do it that's why
we have that previous mode for instance
because it says hey I need I know I need
to run these checks now in the kernel to
handle this untrusted input essentially
it's a tough
design flaw regardless right handling
user mode data in the kernel or vice
versa I'm easy to also don't want to
leak kernel mode addresses you know if
you access things in the user mode
portion if you do a bad copy or
something you may leak a kernel mode
address up there as well so that's that
yeah yeah
um so these this was actually this
demonstration was in a third party
driver which
um we actually blogged about on
crowdstrike about like detecting all the
typical Market fodder type stuff but
these types of things I think the
Malaysian government actually was hit in
2021 I think with the win32k bug which
obviously people are probably familiar
with 32k not very um
um great because of this wonderful gift
Microsoft gives us of user mode
callbacks where the kernel will go
directly into user mode and call things
of because it needs to be passed back
down
um so in in Native drivers we do see
this
um but it it's more targeted attack type
thing right so if I can compromise a
domain with domain admin I'm not going
to do something like this right but if I
need something quick and that's well put
together like nation state level in
terms of I have a browser exploit that's
paired with a Sandbox Escape that's
paired with a kernel exploit all
packaged in JavaScript user just views
the browser I've instantly got kernel
mode access to their machine that's
really targeted operations because you
have things like patch level right
um at every patch level these offsets
that you use will change where the code
is actually located so making the
exploits
you know 40 of it sixty percent of it
I'd say is making it portable
um so making sure it works in every
single um instance so it definitely is
for it's further and few between these
sort of things but they definitely do
happen and obviously
um fishing is bad but I don't think
there's anything worse than like a
remote code execution vulnerability no
user interaction kernel mode access for
instance so it's definitely something to
pay attention to but it's not as
prevalent I would say
cool well thank you
thank you
eighty percent of that was way over my
head but