uh hey everyone my name's lena i'm based
in sydney australia and i work in
incident response at secureworks prior
to working at secureworks i was also
doing incident response and threat
hunting at accenture
in my spare time i do like to publish a
lot of research and i do so on twitter
and also on my blog and my primary
interests lie in apt attacks mobile and
also cloud security
so today we're going to cover a few
things however my overall goal of the
presentation is to
i guess really demonstrate the impact
that chinese political goals have on the
style of attacks that are carried out by
chinese apt groups and throughout the
course of the last few years the
relationship between china and australia
has
you know soured and that has resulted in
an incredible uptick in the amount of
chinese alleged chinese apt cases that
we've seen and worked on at secureworks
so specifically throughout this
presentation i'm going to touch on four
attacks that i worked on
and show you how these goals or this
these attacks were linked to the overall
goals of the chinese communist party and
at the very end i'm going to talk a
little bit a little bit about china's
recruitment policies and thought
curriculums
so full disclaimer i am going to be
saying allegedly a lot because threat
intelligence is rarely ever 100 accurate
but on top of this this presentation is
not a reflection of my personal
political views nor is it a reflection
of secureworks political views
so with that let's get into it
in 2012 right after xi jinping became
the general secretary of the chinese
communist party he announced something
called the chinese dream and in chinese
it's referred to as
means
which roughly translates to the great
rejuvenation
or revitalization of china
and this particular dream had two goals
the first one is for china to become a
well-off society or moderately wealthy
by 2021 which i do believe they have
achieved and the second is for china to
become a fully developed nation by 2049.
now from 2012 until today
these two pillars have been the
underlying crux of the xi jinping
administration
and on top of this you know all goals
kind of dwindle without some kind of
success measurement and in this instance
it is china
apologies it is china becoming a world
leading economy
and so as a part of this
china set up something called one belt
one road and basically this strategy is
to generate some kind of economic trade
dominance
and
the tldr for this is china is basically
financing leasing a set of ports and
hubs all across central asia and through
europe
and the purpose of these ports and hubs
is to facilitate trade and also maritime
access
and you know the initiative has taken an
immense amount of funding from the
chinese government
and the goals of this is to strengthen
financial cooperation with each of these
countries strengthening the trade
relations with these countries and also
to make lumen be the main trading
investment currency and i say maybe as
in the chinese currency itself
now getting one belt and one road to be
successful
it's not as simple as just you know
purchasing and leasing a set of ports
and hubs
there's also a series of strategies that
kind of underpin the push for this one
strategic movement
and one of this is a set of acquisitions
of course there are a lot of
acquisitions so i've had to just pick
and choose cherry pick and this one was
one that i found particularly
interesting
and this acquisition was cydic telecom
purchasing links telecommunications and
the reason why this is interesting is
because it gives china access to the
underlying telecommunications
infrastructure and services of 130
countries that coincidentally sit in
this belt and road region
and
i say that acquisitions are interesting
because of something called the chinese
national intelligence law
this is a law that states that all
chinese businesses
subsidiaries even located outside of
china and also all chinese citizens are
required by law to support assist and
cooperate with matters of national
intelligence and by that it means you
know all these people need to use all
the means tactics and channels that are
available to them in order to carry out
this work
we had an example in recent times of
what you know failure or quote-unquote
failure may have looked like
and this happened during the log 4j
vulnerability which i'm sure a lot of
you would be familiar with uh one of the
security researchers at alibaba cloud
found this vulnerability however they
did not
first disclose it to the chinese
government and that has resulted in a
series of punishing actions you know
financially punishing actions such as
chinese regulators suspending
partnerships with alibaba and several
contracts
now before i jump into the case study i
kind of want to touch on the diminishing
relationship between china and australia
because this directly links to these
four cyber attacks that i'm going to
cover
so i'm going to give a high level
timeline of this now so in 2012
australia you know we were setting up
our
national broadband network and we banned
huawei from putting in bids
in 2018 we actually banned huawei
completely from constructing any of our
critical infrastructure
that includes 5g
on top of banning it we proceeded to
urge the uk also not to take in bids
from huawei for 5g
in that same year we actually passed a
foreign interference law that made all
industrial espionage illegal
in 2020 china actually published a
dossier of 14 disputes or 14 grievances
with australia so these are things that
china's upset with australia about and
in that list it included things like the
banning of huawei and the blocking of
several chinese investments in australia
so from 2020 until 2021 more things
happened in 2020 australia pushed an
inquisition into the coronavirus
outbreak you can imagine that wasn't
received very well in 2021 australia
blocked china from investing in any of
our critical sectors like infrastructure
tech and you know energy
in 2021 australian government then made
a series of very public criticisms of
what china was doing in xinjiang with
the weak muslims in taiwan and also in
hong kong
now the nature of the china-australian
relationship is very interesting
because historically china has relied
very heavily on australia as we export
iron ore to china
and we also export gas oil and you know
coal so this is the mining and the
energy sector
following the tensions that happen in
china released a five-year plan to end
their dependency on australia for iron
ore completely
this will have severe economic
repercussions for australia because
china is actually 36.5 of all of our
gross export shares
it will hurt the australian economy
and china's strategy to do so includes
importing iron ore from brazil and also
building an iron ore mine in the west
african mountain regions that spans 110
kilometers
now
bronze mohawk is a threat group that
secure actively tracks and this group
you may have seen referred to by other
vendors such as apt40 or maybe leviathan
and the reason i'm pulling this out is
because this particular threat group we
have actually seen been incredibly
active during the 2021 uh
year
in 2020 the australian government
actually released a very interesting
paper
and it was called the copy paste report
and this report was went on for 62 pages
and it said that a nation state was
targeting australian organizations
it did not state what country this
nation state is but i will leave the
inference up to you
it covered like a set of ttps that this
nation state was using including
breaching companies through
telerik sharepoint mobile iron the use
of ldifde tool abuse of legacy microsoft
365 and the use of dll search order
hijacking to install cobalt strike
coincidentally we've seen every single
one of these in cases that we've worked
from 2020 to 2021
and i'll go into this in a little bit
in 2021 right after the chinese
government released that they had
developed a plan to end their dependency
on australia's mining sector for iron
ore
one of our clients in the mining sector
experienced an alleged bronze mohawk
attack
the attack started with web scanning
which is you know very typical for a
large organization
this web scanning wasn't too aggressive
it actually blended in with the usual
web traffic but one thing that did stand
out was the use of nuclei and i say
nuclei is interesting because this then
became a recurring theme throughout
every single one of the bronze mohawk
engagements we worked on
they used nuclei to perform external
scanning and through that they found
that this client you know was running a
contractor portal which is very normal
for infrastructure-based clients
so then they found this portal and they
enumerated it and discovered it had a
series of sql injection vulnerabilities
naturally the attackers exploited that
and proceeded to use this you know sql
injection to start to attempt to
download security and system event logs
this is very interesting because
gathering the security and system event
logs would allow this threat actor to
you know enumerate the types of logins
that happen services that run and also
schedule tasks that run a lot of
interesting information
through sql the attackers then proceeded
to install a jsp webshell which i've got
you know a screenshot of the actual
webshell and this allowed the attackers
remote code execution onto the server
which they then proceeded to run a
series of commands using ldifde which i
said was mentioned in the australian
copy paste report
this is a microsoft owned tool that
allows enumeration of forests and
domains
i've also got a series of other commands
that they ran that i've got in the super
timeline
you know just usual credential
enumeration and then in pink i've
highlighted the command that they ran to
perform credential dumping now we kept
recurringly see
these alleged bronze mohawk attacks use
this method for credential dumping and
we did not see evidence of mimikats
being utilized
the end goal of the attack was for file
access and file enumeration and it was
very clear that this was the end goal
because the attackers started to
enumerate several documents pertaining
to mining and other
you know documents like that and it was
interesting because the attackers also
logged into three specific mailboxes and
they did this through leveraging legacy
authentication in microsoft 365 which
once again was referenced in the
australian copy paste report
on top of this the attackers also had an
awareness of several employees within
the business
like very in detail knowledge of these
people's existence and our hypothesis is
it's probably gleaned from linkedin but
of course that's difficult to prove and
at the very end of the investigation we
had collected around
30 different ips that the threat actors
used
literally right after this case finished
we got another case it kind of even
overlapped
this case was the energy sector big
surprise and this particular client had
received a high confidence alert from a
trusted third party and i do say trusted
because it was a trusted third party
that alleged bronze mohawk ips were
interacting with their environment
so we were called in to perform incident
response on this instance
and
the second we kind of jumped in we had
you know found a series of other ips but
these ips were all geo-located in
australia
but more interestingly they were
instances of compromised microtech
routers that the attackers were using to
proxy the attack in
once again similar ttp started to emerge
apologies including the use of nuclei
python and other open source tools
and it was really interesting because
after using nuclei the threat actors
once again zoned in on a contractor
portal which they then found a
vulnerability for that they then you
know exploited
that allowed them access to that server
and they proceeded to log in using
decommissioned third-party credentials
they created malicious user credentials
and then they proceeded to enumerate
documents hundreds of documents
pertaining to this client and they even
attempted to try and exploit sharepoint
which was interesting because they made
a series of remote procedural calls to
do so
and
interestingly enough one of the ips that
we witnessed in this particular incident
we had already seen prior that year on
one of another another one of our
clients that we worked on that
experienced an alleged bronze mohawk
attack
during the investigation
the clients also seemed like they had
some kind of a playbook that they were
trying to run
and what i mean by that is they were
looking for instances of mobile iron
running they were looking for instances
of telerik running now if you remember
when i was talking about the copy paste
report the australian government
actually outlined a series of
technologies that the client was uh not
the client the threat actors were
targeting and prior to them actually
breaching this organization we saw a lot
of instances of them you know looking
for telerik and looking for mobile iron
now what's interesting with this case
with the mining sector and also with the
energy sector firstly i would say is the
fact that you know there was a big shift
in sophistication
from what was done for initial
reconnaissance through to you know uh
initial exploitation it was less
sophisticated and then when they
actually landed on the server the types
of enumeration and defensive asian
techniques they used became more
sophisticated and it's actually been
hypothesized by several security
researchers that perhaps china has a
tier one that operates across various
apt groups and then hands over to you
know another tier and i say this because
there was a stark contrast in technical
skill
xi jinping's dream of china is one where
china's military power is
you know second to none and what that
means is the ability to deter the us
specifically if conflict is required
and currently
the people's liberation army has the
largest naval force in the world they
also have hypersonic missiles which
travel five times faster than the speed
of sound and they are the second largest
military spender in the world right
after the us
china also has an air force with
advanced equipment allegedly stolen from
us designs
now back in 2017 a defense contractor in
australia that was focused on aerospace
engineering experienced an incident and
this incident resulted in the
exfiltration of 30 gigabytes of
sensitive data that was under restricted
access
the data included information pertaining
to the
f-35 stealth fighter
which was actually recently featured on
the news i think a few days ago and this
was all stolen through the china chopper
webshell which is a notorious webshell
that chinese apt groups have used
throughout the years and i think like
notorious because it actually even
emerged in 2021 with the exchange breach
and you know then the attack is then
subsequently installing china chopper
and here you can see the uncanny
resemblance between the chinese tendul
j-20 aircraft and the american f-35 and
actually a few weeks ago this article
was released that china was potentially
you know gonna release a stealth
helicopter that resembles the u.s black
hawk but you know this is conjecture at
this point in time you know it's alleged
no actual images have surfaced but it'll
be interesting to keep an eye out on
that
as a part of you know china having a
very strong naval base they're very
focused on naval technology
and in 2018 there was a chinese
businessman that was allegedly tasked by
the chinese northwestern polytechnical
university to export u.s hydrophones to
chinese state-owned businesses and
hydrophones are devices that allow
underwater sound monitoring so you can
understand why this would be important
to the naval base
he was found guilty of supplying up to
60 hydrophones worth 100k
but he was you know allegedly
it was alleged that he stole over 8
million
and so as a part of this i guess thirst
for technology that brings me to the
third initiative that xi jinping has set
and this this initiative is called made
in china 2025.
the goal is for china to move from being
a world producer of cheaper low-tech
items to becoming a more technologically
intensive manufacturer
and so the goals of this initiative
include china ramping up their right
research and development spend
especially on tech
reducing tax rates on all the domestic
tech companies
approving mergers and acquisitions with
foreign tech companies and focusing on
areas like cyber security robotics
fintech you know biotechnology quantum
computing
the goal is for china to become a
technological powerhouse and by that
china sees the importance of
self-sufficiency
and what i mean by self-sufficiency is
not needing to rely on the supply chain
from other countries they want to be
able to control the supply chain all
domestically
and that kind of brings me to my next
point so china is actually outpacing the
rest of the world in 5g
because of you know huawei and also
electrical vehicle adoption
both rely on the use of semiconductors
and semiconductors are
i mean has been referred to as the crown
jewels of tech because it's a critical
enabler for new technologies for example
quantum computing uh you know fintech
space etc and what's interesting is
leadership in the semiconductor industry
would actually allow will help china
geopolitically because currently taiwan
and the us dominate the supply chain for
semiconductors and semiconductors i'll
just note are also critical in military
has military advantages because it's
used in national security systems
as a part of this china has actually
accepted all domestic semiconductor
companies from tax for 10 years and
china has also you know raised billions
of dollars in their national
semiconductor fund
the reason why they're focusing on
semiconductor links back to made in
china 2025 where they want to be
technologically self-sufficient and if
the supply chain is stopped or disrupted
by taiwan or you know us that greatly
hamstrings china's ability to evolve in
the tech space
in 2021 i worked a case where this
client was a big tech company they were
one of the
i guess world pioneers of this
technology in their respective sector
and during this time a lot of
interesting things happened the dwell
time that we witnessed was around four
months
on top of this the threat actors started
to use dll search order hijacking to
install cobalt strike in enterprise
application directories
the thread actors also performed
credential dumping through manually
dumping out elsas which
you know i've already referenced twice
in the previous two cases
the threat actors were focused on
exfiltration and that seemed to be the
goal
they were iterating through file servers
and share drives globally through this
company looking for documents pertaining
to research and development innovation
patents technology you know you get the
gist of this the style that the files
that they were looking for and once the
client
realized that the threat actors were in
their environment
you know most clients tend to kind of
react very quickly and start to shut
down servers etc but that alerted the
threat actors and resulted in a series
of punishing activities like the threat
actors started to lock people out of
their accounts by changing credentials
and the threat actors also started to
enable hundreds of disabled user
accounts
now as per the copy paste report we did
see dll search order hijacking used to
install cobalt strike uh is my screen
loading
or is it just me that it's looking kind
of glitched
no it's glitchy
okay so
let me go back is that better
yeah it looks better now
okay perfect so as per the copy paste
report we saw dll search order hijacking
used to install cobalt strike i've
redacted this a bit so
uh i'm just gonna verbally talk you
through it basically what happened was
the attackers used remote wmi to execute
cobalt strike and they installed it in
you know application directories that
were specific to the organization and
then on top of this they started to
execute the dll through msfield.exe and
proceeded to run the dll in memory so
now once cobalt strike is running in
memory the thread actors then removed
the dll
and that obviously was a form of defense
evasion and this technique was
referenced in the australian copy paste
report
in the same year i actually worked
another case where one of our nursing
home clients were also experiencing an
alleged bronze mohawk attack
now this client actually received an
alert from a trusted third party and
once we jumped in to do the ir we had
found around five ips pertaining to
alleged bronze mohawk and what happened
was the attackers
were using nuclei to perform enumeration
of the external perimeter
then the attackers realized you know
once they started like going through
telerik mobile iron this client was
unfortunately running mobile iron so
they zoned in on the mobile ion server
exploited the vulnerability and used
that to install jsp web shells and i've
got a screenshot of the webshell there
and they installed several jsp web
shells by injecting it to the start of
legitimate web pages
they then proceeded to enumerate
credentials
they iterated through the web logs
looking for lines in the logs that
showed the attack ip they proceeded to
delete those logs and then installed
tsunamibot
now at this point if you think that this
is strange i'm with you it does seem
strange but we'll talk about that in a
second so i've got a screenshot here of
the command they used to run the jsp web
shell and the command that they used to
remotely install tsunami bot from a
remote server
and so i say this is interesting because
back to the energy case where the client
was running you know uh had ips
attacking them from compromised
microtech routers we hypothesized that
this attack was likely for the purpose
of infrastructure building
now in order for china to become a world
economic leader it needs to rely on the
youth and that is where this comes in
as of
china is bringing something into the
school curriculum from primary through
to university called xi jinping thought
and this is a thought curriculum that
teaches the youth
it's strange using the word youth that
makes me feel old but it's to teach the
youth the importance of nationalistic
pride and to also instill in them this
sense of national responsibility and a
call to arms for these kids to innovate
coincidentally this aligns with china's
goals of becoming you know a
technological superpower
and so you can see that the role of
education is critical in the achievement
of the chinese dream because in 2021
georgetown cset division actually
published a brilliant report and this
report highlighted the like the link
between state-funded chinese
universities six of them and how they
were linked to six apt groups the first
one on the list ain't n university you
can see there it's linked to apt40
aka bronze mohawk
i've also got screenshots of various
professors from these universities in
particular professor gujen from hainan
university was said that he would post a
lot of job listings on student boards
and host hacking competitions and
specifically look for students to quote
solve problems and these problems were
also always referring to some kind of
hacking problem or a technical issue but
he would offer prize money of up to 74
000 usd which is an incredible amount of
money to just be throwing around at
problems
but as a part of china's science of
strategy
china's science of military strategy
universities are actually
a key vessel in how china maintains
their cyber security influence the
university's role is to
foster foster you know cyber talent
develop new tactics and methods that can
then be leveraged in the future in cyber
attacks and this kind of shortens the
length of time needed to turn academic
research into operational cyber
capabilities
now you'll also see in this list that
all six of these universities partake in
creating courses cyber security courses
that align with ai and machine learning
china is heavily investing in ai and
machine learning pertaining to the
research in cyberspace
now in terms of takeaways for my
presentation the first one i want to
highlight is the impact that
presidential terms and checks and
balances has
what i mean by that is in western
politics like australia and us in
australia the prime minister only has a
term for four years
china is in a very unique position where
xi jinping isn't held back by that and
that enables him to think about the
strategies for china 20 to 30 years in
the future
hence why made in china oh sorry hence
why the chinese dream
was created in 2012 and has spanned the
entire length of his term up to date
the second point is that
china moves very fast and has an
incredible agility in politics and that
has led to a rapid you know rapid growth
in their technological sector
and a part of that is the lack of checks
and balances so xi jinping's able to
instill policies
and in western politics that wouldn't be
the case because there's opposing
parties that would question those
policies and debate them
as a part of this that links into my
second point
because of this rapid technological
growth china's cyber capability is only
elementary compared to what it can be
and i say this because you know china is
heavily investing in these areas as
you've seen it's a part of their overall
geopolitical strategy
the third point is that threat
intelligence especially when it comes to
nation-state threat groups is very
linked to the geopolitical goals from
that country and also the geopolitical
relationships between each country
and i hope that through this
presentation you're able to see some of
the linkages that i was you know subtly
trying to push
between what was happening in the
decline of the australian and chinese
relationship to some of the cyber
attacks that i've referenced
the last point i want to raise is the
importance of being more proactive
versus reactive
you know in the past a lot of you know
incident response people kind of respond
or only talk about what's happening
after an attack happens
given that we know that china has a
specific policy that links universities
to these cyber security groups and has a
specific program for them to generate
research in machine learning and the
applications of that in cyber security
i think it would be very wise for you
know us to pay attention to some of the
research being funded and pushed out
because it'll only be a matter of time
before the research makes the jump from
theory into practice
and with that thank you guys so much for
listening i really appreciate your time
and you can always stay in touch with me
on twitter