i am so excited to introduce samara
um i told her while we were getting
ready for her talk and kind of
discussing the topic that i i really
wish i had seen this talk four years ago
when i was setting up my own program
and i think it really connects nicely to
some of the the themes that we talked
about already um
you know the the talk previously about
connecting into m a and integrating with
sort of a non-traditional group so i
think samara is going to expand on that
and i'm really excited to hear what you
have to say so thanks amara
yeah thanks kristin appreciate the intro
so
first cti presentation here so be nice
to me okay guys i'm just here to have
some fun share some content okay um i am
manager of thread operation so i am
responsible for vulnerability management
and threat intelligence right and that's
just it's a beautiful marriage between
the two um i work at cardinal health so
i like to call it the silent giant it's
a fortune 14 company okay like every
time i talk about cardinal health and
how huge it is people are like huh who
is that so
we are we are healthcare's most trusted
partner is what we like to say so we are
global you know well over 100 you know
100k
assets and plenty of attack vectors
across pharmaceuticals medical devices
supply chains
so let's get into
it oh
okay a little bit about me so
i'll zoom through this but what i like
to tell people is that if you don't
appreciate my talk we can at least talk
about something else right we have
something in common so i'll start with
the top left i like to binge anything
and everything so
lately it's been netflix but mostly it's
like hulu things like that right i
played basketball in college for a
couple years but i ended up
finishing online so if anybody went to
those schools hit me up let's talk about
it i love meeting uh
alumni so i'm a huge kobe bryant fan i
play basketball in college right so
january 2020 was tough for me
on the bottom these are my puppers here
they're the cutest i also have three
kids but i don't like putting their
faces everywhere so and a wife but you
know she would kill me if i put her face
because it would be huge right in the
center of the slide i am also originally
from texas i live in ohio now so any
other ohioans out there hit me up let's
talk about it i always put the texas
flag on here though because when you're
very young the brainwashing to be proud
so here i am a product of that
so get into it
threat intelligence now to the top left
here is my sort of definition i give
people outside of our org right so
consumption of generation of information
an organization uses to understand the
threats targeting the organization you
disseminate that information and inspire
action to drive protection and defense i
know what you guys are thinking
especially seasoned folks out there
intelligence is not information i agree
with you but i hate to break it to you
the people outside of our org they see
it as information it is our job to show
them that it's intel intelligence
so this could be a refresher for some
people girs versus pir so i'm going to
zoom through a lot of this but
general intelligence requirements girs
are sort of general threats that we care
about
um across our industry
priority intelligence requirements sort
of hones in on your company and what is
important to you threats that might be
targeting your organization
so we'll talk more about that in a bit
the cti life cycle
so when i give examples here you'll be
able to identify sort of you know what
area of the life cycle you know i'm kind
of
referencing but very quickly direction
is
what are we what are we doing what are
we talking about who are we talking
about what what gir's or pirs are we
focusing on collection going around to
the right
is what are we collecting
how are we collecting it maybe it's deep
dark web maybe it's an oh sitting feed
maybe it's a commercial feed
processing how are we collecting it and
what are we doing with it are we using a
sim are we leveraging a tip are we you
know integrating with our store platform
analysis this is where we figure out why
what what do we what are we doing with
it right does it even have context
related to our organization um
aspects of minor attack things of that
nature are going to land in analysis
dissemination what are we how are we
delivering it what product are we using
is it a presentation is it's
um uh brief you know there's all kinds
of ways you can disseminate the
information and feedback um arguably one
of the more important aspects of the cci
lifecycle
we had to talk about that garrett he
talked about feedback it's incredibly
important if you don't know
what your customers want to hear about
right and you don't give that to them
they're not going to read your stuff i
actually have a pretty funny story about
that a company i used to work for you
know back in the day i'm not gonna name
names we we ran a test to see if anybody
was um reading our briefs so for the
month of december we didn't send any it
was like a weekly thing right so very
forced until
it wasn't my idea i promise
we stopped delivering those those um
briefs for an entire month and nobody
said anything until january 15th like
mid-january it was very telling
so that was a that was a huge learning
experience for me
next up so the intel partnerships i'm
gonna mention i'm gonna i'm gonna
lightly touch on some of the traditional
partnerships which i believe these are
my opinion based on talking to other
intelligence organizations is security
operations incident response security
leadership i delineated security
leadership specifically because i'm
talking about
directors vps svps your cso
um red team
vulnerability management and fraud
prevention
this shouldn't surprise anybody but if
some of these traditional partnerships
aren't
you know partners you generally
partner with then let me know let's talk
about it
now less traditional partners uh
partners that my team partners with we
put a little bit more you know
emphasis on these and some of the more
traditional ones are threat modeling
executive leadership okay so that's like
depending on where your ciso is it's
unfortunately it's a lot a lot of the
times above this user
uh governance risk and compliance with
an emphasis on third party risk uh
business information security officers
which is besos
um devsecops slash absec
again kind of depends on how your
organization is structured and then
security architecture and engineering
so
really quick before we go into the
partnerships let's talk again another
refresher for a lot of people out there
uh but i
i encourage you all to look up the types
of intelligence if you don't know them
already so tactical when i talk about
tactical intelligence i'm talking about
ttps i'm talking about infrastructure
right and now i'm going to use that icon
there
operational we're talking about specific
attacks
or campaigns
targeting an organization that can
include intent
motivation
you know capability things of that
nature
strategic got the little chess piece
there uh that's gonna be more
sort of broad and threat landscape based
maybe
i don't like to say it's to go to less
technical partners but that is sort of
how it's
described for a lot of people
so running through the traditional
partnerships really quick
so i hope not to offend anybody but i'm
a squash security operations with
incident response a lot of companies do
that they're on the same team maybe it's
a rotational maybe there's more senior
people doing instant response but the
key word with these partners is context
right so when we talk about tactical
intelligence
tactics techniques procedures
um infrastructure we need to add
context to that otherwise it's just
information kind of like before
we can definitely make the these teams
lives easier by minimizing okay
i forgot to mention i'm gonna say a lot
of buzzwords in here and i'd love for
somebody to keep count i think it would
be kind of hilarious because it's
something i'm working on um so when we
talk about
um
minimizing alert fatigue okay security
operations incident response threat
intelligence can do that so arguably and
if you disagree with me please let me
know i think
a lot of threat intelligence going to
these teams can be automated right i
think we can do that i think we can make
it happen i personally really like the
intelligence we get from these teams so
i do like a nice mutual relationship
between a threat intelligence team and
their partner
four security leadership i have a lot of
strong opinions i have a lot of strong
opinions in general so i don't i'm not
going to say that the rest of it you're
just going to hear a lot of them so
security leadership i talked about this
being directors vps svps
you know csos
if you do not have
some sort of direct
contact with your cso okay
if you are a manager of an intelligence
team or a director of intelligence team
and you are not letting your
intelligence team
interact with the cso you are doing the
entire organization a disservice okay
threat intelligence
should be
assisting a cso without any thing lost
in translation to make actionable
uh decisions i'm sorry informed
decisions okay
we can also make our csos lives easier
so i call this little this red star on
the side our red star remember
something y'all can take away
some good advice from kristin
appreciate it
so next continuing on with the uh
traditional partnerships
red team we got tactical intelligence
right there ttps infrastructure that
relationship there is it's just organic
right we we report on something we tell
them hey this is kind of hot and cool
something sexy and they're like yeah
let's do it your red team is always down
right always down
vulnerability management
i will try to be brief
on this because
this is sort of my bread and butter so
what threat operations is made of
my threat intelligence team um partners
directly with our vulnerability
management team
to not only make their lives easier but
to create a risk-focused environment
i i talked about cardinal health having
over 100k assets right well over that um
that can get kind of tough when when
vulnerabilities are released and you
know there's these zero days but then
you know you've got attackers that are
exploiting you know cpus from five years
ago so to stay on top of that we have a
custom
risk framework that we use
okay um this is all true it's super cool
too we use different aspects of threat
intelligence right collecting data on
the sophistication of the attack um
it is our vulnerability on the perimeter
how many assets
is it uh you know impacting um what are
the other ones
i'm missing them somebody out there so
there's somebody on my team out there
that can include them but essentially we
have a custom risk score
that is tied to a custom patching cycle
and i'll i'll be
talking about that a little further
throughout the environment throughout
the um
presentation as well fraud prevention
there's a ton of people out there who
are much smarter than i am on fraud
prevention so i'm talking as simple as
like social media monitoring brand
monitoring there's a lot that
intelligence can do in terms of
collecting that data to help our fraud
teams so
our red star remember create a
risk-focused environment i believe i
strongly believe that a threat
intelligence team is collecting all of
this context so we can better understand
what our
technical cybersecurity threat risk
whatever you want to call it truly is
threat modeling so we've transitioned to
what i believe to be the less
traditional uh through intelligence
partners
so
some teams have like dedicated threat
modeling teams it's super cool and a
little uncommon
other teams like app security
red teams you know threat intelligence
and response they have their own sort of
threat modeling within their function
and that's totally cool too but threat
intelligence should have direct
involvement
okay in threat modeling so we can from a
tactical perspective develop attack
chains based on exposure right so what
does that even mean from my perspective
that means vulnerability we know
everything about our internal soft and
squishy right we have our threat
intelligence team who knows everything
about what's going on external to our
environment when we put those two things
together leveraging something like mitre
attack
we can sort of build these attack chains
and identify where we have some gaps so
that brings me to the strategic aspect
we can track technological and process
gaps notice i talk about process gaps
maybe it's because i'm in healthcare but
there are many process and visibility
gaps that should be tracked
to identify some additional risk right
so our red star remember for this one is
see the adversary be the adversary it's
like a like a mantra right
if we know what the adversary is doing
we can be that adversary and we can
identify certain weaknesses throughout
our environment
so executive leadership this is
something i'm very proud of
not everyone has the luxury
but having that direct line to the ciso
having the csos report having a cso that
believes in threat intelligence these
these things can happen you can have a
relationship with your you know
executive leadership i
we have regular sort of um
we have agenda items within their oc
meetings it's awesome okay
so what we've done from a tactical
perspective is something called ocean
projects okay this is
relatively simple it's just hardest to
get it started right so what we did
is we talked with our ceo cio cto chief
legal officer you know chief human
resource officer chief diversity officer
whoever and we dug up as much as we
could off the internet on them we tried
to be as creepy as possible so it was a
lot of fun naturally you know we went to
you know their houses and took pictures
you know identified some things like hey
your your fence is open in the back
should probably do something about that
but in all seriousness it was
interesting it was interesting to
put all of that stuff into a
presentation and show them hey this is
what we know about you we got all of
this information for free
and on the deep the deep and dark web as
they know it you know you can get even
more damaging information for
pennies okay
so
their their reactions were actually much
better than expected um they they took
it
some did something with it others you
know kept posting their vacations and
stuff but what you know what can you do
so that leads me to internal targeted
phishing right now let me there's a
disclaimer here not everything on these
slides some of them are just smart being
you know a visionary of sorts but others
are you know actually on our roadmap
these are one of the things that are on
our roadmap working with security
operations
to do internal targeted phishing we have
all of like a lot of the data on them
that would make them click
on a phishing email for our cio we
actually found out what car he drives
the number
we
we crafted our own phishing email based
on like
him having a recall in his car or
something we actually found a true
recall um but you know kind of drafted
this website that was obviously not
where you can look at your recall and
he's like
i would totally click on this
right he was super honest about it and i
love it but
there's
there's benefit in that right getting
their eyes open to something like that
so it's part of strategy metrics on
attack chains
tech trends excuse me um dashboards on
compliance risk exposure we talked about
threat modeling if we can identify some
of those risks put it in a nice pretty
dashboard with all these cool colors you
know they love it eat that stuff up so
our red star remember is make your
executives
feel cyber smart now if there's
executives out there please
don't be offended but your executives
need to feel it right that doesn't
necessarily mean that they are but they
should feel they should feel more
confident before you about identifying
fishes right being able to um
sort of
prevent or not prevent but identify um
and ignore social engineering things of
that nature
governance risk and compliance i think
people sleep they sleep on this area
quite a bit i think it's super cool so i
talked about
vulnerability management having a custom
sort of risk model and i talked about um
having that custom patching cycle so
the only way well i'm not gonna say the
only way but the best way in some cases
is to get that in some sort of policy
right so arthur intelligence team
influenced policy creation we prioritize
an update and our patch management
policy
to say hey if your threat intelligence
team
says
this is bad
related to vulnerability management
and it's affecting your asset
you need to comply with this patching
cycle i was like left that's a win you
know it's nice to have that sort of fall
back on when people are whining and i
don't want to punch it well you you need
to because of x right it's nice to have
that so
new definitions of compliance we bumped
up that patching cycle based on
that trending vulnerability as well as
tracking the risk we talked about from a
threat modeling perspective and we'll
continue to talk more about this um so
our red star remember for this one
honesty is the best policy i know that's
not super original but it's true right
going on to third party risk i did
include customer risk here um again
maybe it's because i'm in healthcare but
this is an area that is often overlooked
right having an assessment for a vendor
isn't enough you need more okay so from
a tactical perspective threat
intelligence the information that we
collect you know leveraging things like
mitre attack and some other risk
frameworks we can be consulted we can we
can consult on creating and updating
third party assessments now it's enough
that's nothing
there's no phenomenon you know included
in that but on a quarterly basis
based on what we're seeing the threat
landscape right this is a great inn
right with your third party risk team
hey you know let us
it's no biggie there's no
you know action on their part outside of
sending you the assessment so you can go
through it and provide recommendations
that's generally what we do in general
we can't change their assessment there's
no harm in that which could lead to
these next ones here so from an
operational perspective assessing
exposure of third parties under contract
there are
tools out there that can help you see
the uh if there's some soft and squishy
on the outside of these third parties
and you could see how long
how long it takes them to fix it right
sometimes it's a good sign
sometimes in healthcare specifically i
don't talk about healthcare but that's
what i'm working in i worked at another
company as well healthcare it's an
interesting beast but
if there is a vendor
who is offering
a product they are the only vendor that
offers said product doesn't matter how
soft and squishy they are okay
they help your company is probably going
to invest in it but right it might it
might frustrate you whatever that's
business roll with the punches it's
still important to understand the risk
associated with partnering with that
that vendor
lastly from a strategic perspective
monitoring and the analysis of
third-party compromises
now it's very important to have some
sort of centralized
database where you have all of your
third-party you know
companies or people you do business with
or customers whatever so that you could
say oh okay let me look at this i see
these you know compromises happening
through whatever source
maybe some keyword alerts um sometimes
you have to
prioritize them you know based on b2b
connections or whatever right um and
track them that way unfortunately
sometimes it's all up in somebody's head
that's why the partnership is important
right for them to
unload that information so that we can
help them in some form or fashion
our red star remember is stranger danger
we should all be familiar with this as
children i still am it's very important
but before you do business with somebody
they're a stranger and you should treat
them that way
next
besos so i'll start with the red star
remember this is a movie quote so make
sure you uh you know comment if you know
it did we just become best friends
okay it's true besos
and threat intelligence can't they can
be best friends okay it's your channel
to the business you can get so much more
done if the business knows that you're
around
or is you know they know that you exist
i should say so
from a tactical perspective we have a
regional bissell so thanks billy
cardinal health they kind of jumped on
the biso train early and we have a
be so for every region of the world that
we work in we also have a b-scale for
the uh business units right so we have
one for corp medical
and pharma
regional user education is the first one
so we worked with a particular
in charge of the apac region um he was
awesome he loves threat intelligence
eats it all up and he reached out to us
and said can you help me identify
what's going on in this area of the
world they're like yeah give me 72 hours
and we have this product we delivered
the product now what were my
expectations out of that what were his
expectations he was expecting to get a
product
check
i was expecting him to read the product
and do what he thought was best for it
okay we should not get prideful as
intelligence analysts and say
do use my product i put this together
you should use everything in it no he
made it his own he created his own
document his own how to on how to
identify social engineering
in a phishing email how to report it to
use native language throughout it okay
these this is value that we're talking
about he leveraged the intelligence
information
to make it his own make it digestible
for the audience right that's a team
effort and it was awesome
at the business unit from an operational
perspective bec
right i want to say it was it was before
like everyone was talking about
ransomware for and when i mean everyone
i mean like the websites right that that
our students look at and stuff um
bec was super big and we worked with our
corp
business or biso to talk to our finance
department and be like
this is what it looks like
we're going to test you on it so pay
attention okay obviously there is more
involved with that but that partnership
right
business unit visos are huge champions
for change right because kind of have to
be they understand the intricacies of
the business and how that can impact the
organization as a whole
and from a strategic perspective
intelligence is being shared
bidirectionally i talked about having
that mutually beneficial relationship
the be so the intelligence team it
should be a marriage they should be in
love and going on vacations together and
you know uh getting their vows enrolled
every five years or so it should be
so much shared back and forth because
you can give them what you know about
emerging threats they can give you some
like heads up on what the business is
working on right because we seem to be
surprised by that often
next
devsecops i also include apsec because
sometimes they you know they run in the
same circles right this one
red star remember buzzwords coming shift
left
secure from the start
if there's other ones include them in
the hallway let's uh let's talk business
or buzzwords
so tactical perspective i'm going to
zoom through this one too because i am
not an expert but we do have a great
partnership um with our apsec team
and we talk about
introducing the threat models from our
perspective into the early stages of
testing there's also a mutual
relationship here because
you know we have a lot of
applications that are big old money
makers things that we've prioritized
ourselves um and
we can use the information from their
threat models in our own the ones i
talked about early on right so
it's important
even if so there are some okay let me
how am i going to say this there are
some teams that don't think they need
you
right so it's important
to sort of
you know not force your way in there i'm
saying force your way in there and and
show them how they need you right
develop that brief even if they don't
ask for it we're going to talk about
getting buy-in as well and i can
reference abstech dev setups um
prioritize at vulnerability so
you know vulnerability management we
obviously you know there was a huge you
know boner really that came out we're
still dealing with no big deal but you
know
from even from a container perspective
it's all very different right and i i
love it it's a it's a good challenge to
have but you know there's not really i
mean you could fix containers and all
that but generally it's a burn and
redeploy so are there processes that you
can implement with that team to say
you don't redeploy until you fixed and
stop it right these are the things you
know you unfortunately you're strong
army but they'll start to understand you
know the importance of it
lastly security architecture i'll try
not to spend how much i got 10 minutes
left or so
so we talked about minor attack
if you have a solid relationship with
your security architecture team you
should be talking to them on at least a
weekly basis if not daily in terms of
tracking control coverage
across tactics and techniques now minor
tag has already done a great job helping
us out with that okay but it's important
that these controls are configured
properly and that they are tested right
so it's it's all this happy you know
this party between uh security
architecture engineering threat
intelligence your red team or purple
team to test these things and actually
validate that they're working
defense and depth analysis so
well it's essentially the control
mapping with some added things right so
when i talk about defensive depth
i am also talking about
issues with or coverage related to
mitigation
those process gaps that i referred to
earlier but also gaps in visibility yeah
like i know we talk about you don't know
what you don't know but
seriously let's think about this okay
because there are things that we don't
have visibility into that are creating
incr like huge gaps okay
okay i'm not i'm getting excited now but
you understand what i'm saying defense
and depth analysis with control mapping
we should have a good idea of our risk
exposure we shouldn't be tracking this
in some sort of risk register with
digestible remediation plans that teams
can actually conquer right
leveraging our threat modeling team it's
all it's all a happy family okay talk a
lot about marriage and family that's my
thing so lastly from a strategic
perspective
consult on control acquisition so in a
perfect state right this is optimal we
know we know our control gaps we know
you know um where we have issues with
process we know where we lack visibility
at that point we should be able to say
is there a control out there
that we can acquire that will help us
with this
ideally right or maybe you make one
you know so our red star remember is
what does coverage mean to your
organization for us it means technical
controls mitigating controls
process
gaps visibility gaps
it's important to know what coverage
means to your organization
getting by and i had to throw memes in i
try not to meme you guys to death but
this is one of my favorite okay so
getting buy-in like i said before having
a supportive ciso can make getting
buy-in much easier obviously
so first one we got here a road show
explain who you are everyone does threat
intelligence differently so it's
important that you meet with your
potential stakeholders and you talk
through
what they can expect right
what does threat intelligence mean to
samara what does it mean to cardinal
health what does it mean to our
organization as a whole
for the first i want to say six months
of my job building the threat
intelligence team it was a road show it
was going out and talking to people
making yourself known
we talked about grrs and pirs
for each partnership
you should have pirs you should know
what is important to them so you can
reference them when you're going to
deliver a brief make sure you check in
that box okay
once more than check in the box you got
me though define goals and timelines so
i'm talking about having this ready
before you talk to them okay and i'm not
i'm also not saying that i had all of
this down right but there were some
repercussions that i learned in the
process of that road show to say hey you
know i probably should have said this is
what we plan to do and this is the
expected timeline so they don't come
knocking three months later like hey
but i've been waiting for this and
you're like oh well priorities have
changed nobody wants to hear that
they're not a priority
define stakeholder action it's very
important that you manage expectations
in terms of what you need from them
and then value proposition so
based on our goals based on stakeholder
action
why should they do any of it
we're all busy okay
tell tell them what value will come of
your
brief product whatever you're delivering
and what they should be getting from it
right sometimes it's obvious other times
they're like yo my day is full already i
don't need you adding to my workload so
the value proposition is probably most
important here outside of the goals and
timelines
lastly well this isn't the last slide
but lastly preventing a toxic
relationship i don't know if you guys
know
these people in the bottom right um it's
a very well known show on netflix but
they arguably have the most toxic
relationship that there is okay
how to prevent a toxic relationship
detailed scope so this is not only based
on the gir's pirs it's also based on
those goals and timelines so you could
say you know for the next 12 months
these are our goals for the next 90 days
this is a scope of our engagement right
and you deliver on that okay and then
you can extend it from there
continuous updating road map okay so
it's important well for me what i did
was had a certain are certain partners
sort of listed and then over over time i
showed which one would be like a
priority
in general right going across sort of
the calendar year or fiscal year
whichever you guys work with but it's
important to update this
continuously okay
and uh show okay we are ahead here we're
a little behind here
but you know i think we can make up time
here like it's important to keep those
lines of communication open right you
can
you can adjust based on the feedback
that you're getting adjust based on the
speed in which you're working um adjust
based on
you know ad hoc work that's coming in
this fourth one y'all okay
i really need you to listen and hear me
get the right people in front of the
customer
okay so
there are so many people that can work
in intelligence super crazy smart people
okay
not all of them should be interfacing
with
a particular customer okay
it's very important that we sort of
pay attention to the psychology and
different personality traits certain
people and maybe we don't put you know
two tauruses in the room together
whatever
feedback feedback feedback i've
mentioned this already
i'll mention it again a million times
make sure those lines of communication
are open and you're receiving feedback
this is the last slide so i'm coming up
on time i realize that in closing no
intelligence program is created equal
everyone does it differently
you decide what value you want to bring
to what partner and just do it and do it
well
partnership value is dependent on the
type of organization so like i said
we put a little bit more emphasis on
some of those strategic relationships as
opposed to the tech more technical sort
of indicator based relationships because
that is our gateway to the business
and providing value
throw these in your 135 your one year
three year five-year goals i'm not
saying go out there and do this now i'm
saying let's start thinking about it
let's put it on our strategic roadmap
last last last slide there's my twitter
handle
that's my name on linkedin seriously
outside of the hallway we let's talk i
am super open i love this topic and i
want to help so feel free to reach out