i am um super excited to introduce becca
not just because we're friends but
because she's an amazing speaker is this
going to be your is this your fourth
time becca i it's third or fourth time
right i don't even remember yeah
the pandemic makes it hard to think
about uh to think about uh things but uh
you know rebecca's done some really fun
stuff with the summit the last time we
are in person she was a driving force
between uh for jeopardy and she was
trebekah
alex trebeka brown which was pretty
entertaining um also one something
actually quote could be monthly and
people on my team probably
know that i have said this but there was
i think it may have been your first talk
for cti summit probably four or five
years ago and you talked about open
source and you said open source was like
puppies like yeah somebody gives you a
puppy it's free but that doesn't mean
there's not a lot of work associated
with with it and that that works for
open source intelligence that works for
open source threat intelligence tools so
that's just one of many you know ear
worms that when your name comes up that
just pops into my head so we're
absolutely thrilled to have you back
again um i'm i'm excited about your talk
uh you're gonna talk about
many different things but one thing that
was kind of standing out in my mind is
you have a slide on cognitive
functions in here and that's always a
big thing for me especially
in the midst of the pandemic especially
if you just look back just over 13
months if you go solar winds to log 4j
just everything has happened to our
community in that time it's been really
tough so becca please take it away super
excited
thank you so much
um yes frias and puppies is one of my
favorite uh i think axioms that i got to
bring in and it was my first cti summit
presentation
and let me make sure i can click through
here
awesome so i am so happy uh to be here
today and thank you so much for the
introduction
i've said it before and i'll probably
say it many more times
this is one of my favorite events of the
year
it's where i have met many of the people
i call my dearest friends including rick
i believe we met at the 2014 cti summit
katie as well we met at 2018 2016 i met
scott roberts and it's one of the places
where we started working on our book
intelligence driven incident response
um and it's also where i come to
remember that no longer no matter how
long i've been in this field
and it's 20 years this year which seems
like a really long time
i always have more to learn
so this morning i want to talk a little
bit about some of the core elements of
threat intelligence work
throughout the summit you're going to
hear a lot of case studies presentations
even some workshops that talk about how
much variety there is in the cti field
you could be supporting a sock response
to a ransomware event
or analyzing a nation's past 15-year
history of network operations prior to
kinetic warfare without ever leaving the
field of cti
but what's amazing in this work and one
of the things that i have spent
the past few years kind of really
digging into are what are the elements
that underlie
all of these types of operations
and that kind of bring us together and
make us one field and help us learn and
grow from each other
and what i've come down to
is that we're all tied together all
these different varieties within our
field are tied together by the stories
we tell the systems we build
and how well we know ourselves and how
well we know our teams
hopefully you'll see some of your own
cti journey and some of the things i
cover this morning
or maybe you'll see something you want
to implement or something you can tie
into the amazing talks that we have
lined up for you throughout the summit
so the data we use in cti is often
pretty technical um and it isn't always
accessible or understandable by all the
people who need to understand it and
with the way that we use technology
everyone really does need to understand
it everyone um has potential risks or
threats that they're exposed to just by
how much our lives are online especially
so during the past two years
so cyber threat intelligence provides an
opportunity to take these technical
details and build a picture of the
threat
regardless of the name or the face or
the logo
every intrusion attempt every
spearfishing email has a story to tell
and one of the first stories that cyber
threat intelligence told was the
cuckoo's egg by cliff stoll
and if you joined us early and you got
to hear some of rick's fun trivia around
the cti summit um cliff actually
keynoted the 2017 cti summit which is
where we got this quote
in addition uh the book the cuckoo's egg
and you know i'm realizing we do have a
lot of new folks so for quick synopsis
if you haven't read it
first of all absolutely please read this
book um if you're new to this field it
can be life changing but the summary is
there were hackers breaking into
government and military networks in the
1980s
and this activity was identified by a
systems administrator who picked up on a
billing error in the system um you know
you had to pay for the time that you
were using the computer systems and
somebody wasn't paying
so of course uh that began uh cliff down
a journey which he calls to track a
wiley hacker
where he ended up connecting printers to
the phone lines sleeping on a basement
writing down tons and tons of
information in a notebook until he could
build a story and build a picture of
what was going on on this network
but that was only the beginning of his
story because once he found out what was
going on he actually had to convince
people that it was important and that
they needed to do something about it
and that is where this quote came from i
thought all i had to do was show people
the data and they would understand but
it doesn't work you have to tell a story
the cuckoo's egg also has a special
meaning to me personally
i started my career in cyber threat
intelligence as a marine
i had done about eight years as a
traditional um intelligence analyst
focusing on national security and
counterintelligence um and when you're
in the military and if i have any active
duty or any veterans and here you
understand this you don't always have a
choice with what your next duty
assignment is or your next job is even
if you think you're really good at the
thing you're doing now that doesn't
always matter as much as one might hope
and so i was given an assignment to our
new
cyber unit as an intelligence analyst um
and they tried to assure me that
you know i was gonna be fine it was
gonna be great it was the same things i
was doing intelligence analysis um just
with computers uh but i was really not
excited because it i didn't think that
it would capture my interest and it
wouldn't let me um allowed you know
solve the complex puzzles uh that i
loved in the work i was doing
but luckily uh we have a i don't know if
people know this marines are voracious
readers so we had a book assigned to us
each month
and at the beginning of my my new unit's
tenure
we were assigned to read a cuckoo's egg
and that completely changed my viewpoint
on not just the job but what i could
bring to the table
i understood not just that there were
absolutely puzzles that we could put
together
and new puzzles that not everybody knew
what they look like and how to shape
them but that i could also bring my
communication skills and my storytelling
ability to help people understand what
was going on
um so again i uh master gunnery sergeant
givens um dr gibbons now i believe it
was our senior enlisted at the time and
he was the one who told us to read the
book so if you're ever listening to this
thank you
that set me on a trajectory that brought
me here uh keynoting on the same virtual
stage that clistol once stood on
as analysts we have this sort of
superpower of looking at things like log
files and intuitively seeing uh the path
our adversaries took and what they are
after
but what's important to note is that
this superpower is unique to us
it is not intuitive to everyone else so
our job isn't just to show someone the
log files uh our job is to bring our
insight and connect it to others via
story
so story is so important to cti um i
think so cliff thinks so master gunnery
sergeant givens thinks so um and so it's
important to know how we can leverage
this in the critical work that we do
i'm also a big fan of brene brown and i
love her podcast dare to lead she starts
each interview with um she has some
really really great key influential
folks on there but she always starts off
by asking them to tell their story
and this isn't just an exercise in
vanity letting someone talk about
themselves
usually they start way back in childhood
and that is usually not a flattering
place to begin one story
but the reason this story is so
important because it gives the listeners
context into their lives and how they
approach the world
and it sets the stage to receive the
information that they're going to be
passing on via this podcast
story serves as a connective tissue
between people
it connects the person telling the story
with the audience it connects what
happened in the past with what's
happening now
and it connects what's happening now to
what we think may happen in the future
since the one telling the story is
typically the one talking especially if
it's a written format you're kind of
just conveying information to people
establishing that connective tissue is
really really important
there's a quote i love
and it is there are two ways
to share information you can push it out
or you can pull people in with story
for what we do and especially with as
high stakes and as complicated as some
of the things we're trying to pass on
are
we will be far more effective if we can
set
that stage and make that connection so
people listen if we can convey why does
this matter to the person who's reading
it
um
then we can actually get them to pay
attention and to draw their own insights
another thing that i love about story is
connective tissue is that when we
collaborate in our field
sometimes it can be something like
a reading a report or giving a brief um
but often it turns into a conversation
and that's why i love things like our
slack channels that we have for this
summit
is it turns just one person telling
their story from their perspective
into more of that game um that you know
you might have played it as a kid but uh
each person goes around and one person
starts with a sentence and someone adds
on and someone adds on and you end up
telling this story that is completely
different than maybe the person who
started it thought it was going to be
but by adding everyone's perspectives
and allowing them to tie in and see how
it relates to their piece you can
actually come out
with a far more better more cohesive
story than if you tried to do it alone
however
with great power comes great
responsibility
uh truth is critical to the work that we
do
and it's also really really hard to land
on
often when we are
sharing insights or or displaying
something in a story format to someone
it's not just based on facts we're not
just showing someone the log files
um we're sharing our insights and our
judgment and this should really be based
on our best judgment
when we have people's attention it's
easy to try and
learn what is going to make them tick
and what can we say how can we phrase
something in a way that is going to get
them to act and when we do that it is
really important that that information
be truthful and accurate
um there's no place in our field for
intentionally misrepresenting or
misinterpreting facts to push an agenda
no matter how honorable that agenda is
if we put information out into the world
that isn't accurate and that we know
isn't accurate
and people start leveraging that and
pulling it into their own story and
pulling it into their own insights we
don't know what side effects that might
invoke and so
it is really important to have integrity
in the stories that we tell we're not
fiction writers
at least not in this job i actually know
a lot of really great cti analysts who
write some good science fiction
but they keep those works separate
now that doesn't mean that we're always
going to get everything right all the
way um all the time
right away
um
there is
a lot of the work that we do is based
off of incomplete information and
there's uncertainty and on top of that
we're often working against an adversary
who is intentionally trying to make sure
we don't have the full picture
so we do have to do
share and analyze to the best of our
ability
but we should always be on the lookout
for new information being introduced
that might change that narrative or
might change how we recommend someone
acts and when we get that new
information or when we uncover a mistake
um
that we find you know maybe we
misanalyzed or misinterpreted a piece of
data previously it's really important to
correct that mistake again we're
building a body of knowledge we are
putting things out for other people to
use in ways that we may not anticipate
and having accurate information out
there
is very important
and it's also a sign of courage in the
field
if you say something wrong
honestly make a mistake and you go back
out and say you know what
we have new information this is actually
the case or this is actually what we
recommend
that shouldn't be viewed as a mistake
that should be viewed as learning
and there is no cti field without
learning
so not only do we as individuals
need to feel comfortable with our
analytic capabilities to come out and
say when we have changed our our
assessment um but as leaders we need to
encourage that and the people who are
working for us
and as spectators
even on twitter
it's important to know that people
correcting information or updating an
assessment
is
probably one of the bravest and most
useful parts of our field
so we don't get to good accurate stories
by accident
um
excuse me i forgot i had a slide in here
so the last aspect of stories
is that they drive action uh so unlike
like i mentioned some of the folks out
there who uh write fiction novels um
or other types of of work this isn't
meant to be light reading for someone at
the end of a hard day
we're conveying information that someone
needs to act on
this can be through direct
recommendations if we think we have a
good idea of what needs to be done in
response to the adversary that we're
talking about we can provide those
directly but it can also be through uh
changing people's perspectives helping
them understand more about the nature of
um an activity or an adversary that they
might not have known before
changing perspectives is especially
important when we're dealing with fields
where we're not experts in ourselves
and we might not know the best course of
action but we can provide information to
people who do
one example of this is a work that i've
done in the past on the wastewater
system
i have
some experience with water and
wastewater
i talk about my mom a lot she is a
wonderful human being she has a phd in
wastewater
um and so she will frequently come to me
and ask me like cyber security questions
or i read about this attack or what
should i do
and i can tell her about the attack but
i can't tell her what that necessarily
means to her you know bio-organic system
that's growing bugs that eat
parasites out of water again i'm not
entirely sure what she does but it's
wonderful
so i need to be able to provide
information that she can use to say okay
i understand what this means for me
maybe i didn't think this was important
before but now it is
and we can only do that when we are
humble enough to know that we are not
experts in everything
but we can also use story to build
knowledge
and again this is why it is so important
that that knowledge is accurate and that
we update it when situations change
because i might put a report out on an
adversary activity that i see that maybe
no one else is seeing right now but by
having that accessible and searchable
and accurate and up to date hopefully
with a date on it as to when i put that
information out there
maybe when rick or katie come across
that information
they can take what i've learned build it
into theirs and continue to grow
the canon in our field
so regardless of whether there is a
specific actionable
item that you want to tell someone to do
it's important to remember that the
stories we write we don't write them for
ourselves we write them for other people
and we want it to be in a way that they
can use it
so how do we get to the point where we
are writing
or telling or sharing
stories that are helping people make the
right decision about things
it isn't by accident
it comes from the second core element of
cyber threat intelligence which is
systems
um and i'm not talking here about
computer systems or a system that we
built to automate to do something
although maybe that ends up being um the
solution but the systems here i'm
talking about can also be known as
processes uh it's a set of principles or
procedures according to which something
is done
it can be an organized framework or a
method
i am a systems thinker i view things in
connections
understanding how one action might
impact other actions um i love systems
analysis if you've taken forensics 578
and seen the systems analysis slides
those were ones i insisted on sticking
in there just because it's so important
to me personally um but it makes sense
to me that i also love systems in
general
so we have some great framework and
methods in cti already things like the
diamond model uh cyber kill chain uh the
attack framework but how and when we use
these tools or what truly makes up our
systems
uh james clear has an amazing book
called atomic habits where he touches on
the key components of systems
which i think is sometimes in direct
contradiction to the way we like to do
things primarily in incident response
and in cyber threat intelligence
he talks about the importance of
building these systems
in a way that we can
work on them in an
iterative manner um that we can day by
day by day go through this process then
become better and smarter and more
efficient at them um and because of that
it really is the consistency of the
systems and not the intensity that
matters
james even goes on to say that our
systems are the most important factor
and whether a person is successful in
achieving their goals
one example of this is the olympics so
everyone who is participating in an
event at the olympics has the goal of
winning the olympics but not everybody
can actually win the goal or can win the
win the gold medal just having the goal
doesn't necessarily mean that you're
going to be successful
what actually makes people successful
what makes them win
are the systems they build their
practice uh their training regime
um the habits that they've been
developing over years their coaching
systems
the best process is for self-reflection
and improvement
all of those done consistently
will provide far more success than
somebody who just sets the goal and says
i'm going to win the olympics
so for us in cti this adds an extra
layer of complexity
because first we have adversaries who
are working against us they have goals
that are typically the exact opposite of
our goals
and in addition we rarely have static
goals and sometimes the goals we set are
not even completely achievable goals
we can't win the internet
we can't prevent all attacks from
happening 100 of the time
so instead of being goal-driven we
should strive to be systems driven
so how do you build a good system
well that depends um as we know that is
the standard answer and you're going to
hear it so many times throughout this
summit and i'm actually pretty impressed
that i made it like 15 minutes without
saying it
um but
best systems for the task will be based
on a lot of different factors
but luckily there is a system for
building systems
the first part is framing the problem
and then you use that to leverage
systems thinking and designs thinking
into developing requirements something i
know rick is very excited about um
but how so what exactly is systems
thinking and design thinking and how do
they connect the problem with the
solutions we eventually end up
implementing
systems thinking means we think of the
interconnected parts that are critical
to addressing the problem and to meeting
our requirements
if the problem is that your organization
can't keep up with all of the media
reporting on threats that exist and you
don't know what you might need to
respond to
your system thinking will start
enumerating all of the very components
required and addressing that problem
you'll need news feeds you need a threat
model you need people to review those
feeds and the models
those people need the time and space
free from other fires to do the analysis
to update the threats to update your
models you need a mechanism to
disseminate the report to those who need
it you need to figure out who actually
needs to receive this information
design thinking is another area that's
incredibly useful to building systems
because designers focus on addressing
problems by building solutions and they
really get the design right the first
time
instead
they work on rapid prototypes that show
whether a specific design meets their
needs
if it doesn't they address the prototype
or they just go back to the drawing
board to the beginning
when we start to design a system to meet
a need we have to be careful not to get
stuck on the first idea we had
um
there was a tweet recently um from
christian another good friend of ours in
cti which was a blank spreadsheet that
said
threat intelligence categorization
framework
and a lot of times this is what happens
when we start our system thinking that
we know the answer already without going
through this process
and i felt a little called out because i
went back through my google drive and i
saw how many documents i've started that
had like grand titles like
ground truth and threat intelligence or
system for categorizing systems and then
just nothing in there
when we go in thinking we already know
the solution and we know what we need to
do and we skip going through this
process of framing the problem and using
systems and design thinking to build a
system that is going to address all of
our needs in a way that allows us to be
consistent
we're going to be stuck with just a
grand title and no data
so there's another aspect to just
building the system um that's going to
depend or
that is going to help us build the right
system
this is
the connection framework
which means habitat
and the reason is named that is because
a habitat campaign contains a lot of
different
types of actions that we need to respond
to a lot of different systems of
different natures that all interact with
each other
it is a truly complex environment
and
the the problems and the issues are
varying complexity but at the end of the
day they're all things we need to
address
it's been described as a sense-making
device rather than a categorization
model
because you can't always put things into
one particular bucket
but
it can allow you to understand to assess
the the problem that you're dealing with
to identify what type of system you
might need to build
um it's based off the concept of ordered
systems so you have uh ordered systems
disordered systems which are complex
systems and chaotic systems and ordered
systems are split into simple and
complicated
so simple systems or obvious systems
as sometimes people like to use
are problems that are well understood
and the solutions are evident there is a
very clear cause and effect model
when you have this type of situation you
can implement a well-known system
this is a place where a lot of our
industry best practices thrive
you can use something like the diamond
model consistently to address certain
types of problems or the kill chain is
another example when you know that an
intrusion has a series of steps you can
use a system to map them out
now the reason i prefer this to be
called an obvious framework rather than
a simple framework
um is when we view something as simple
it's it's actually easier to think that
we can cut corners or skip it entirely
and have the same outcome
what is important here with simple
systems is that even if they are not
complex they still require that
consistency that james clear talked
about
so an example of this is uh i mentioned
scott roberts he and i are
doing a second edition of intelligence
driven incident response and i'm very
excited about that we've been working on
it for a few months now and we have our
outline we know what sections we want to
add we know what things we want to
update what new models we want to bring
in
it is a well-known
um
a well-known system
and we can implement kind of the best
practices
um but telling myself that it's a simple
process does not make it any easier to
sit down every single day and actually
do the writing and do the work that is
going to make this an effective system
[Music]
so
when you're dealing with a situation
that you think is a simple situation
you need to build out not just the
system but build in the time
to build those habits and build that
consistency
and that's doubly true of systems that
you might think are simple
the next situation are complicated
situations
so again this is still an ordered system
there is cause and effect we generally
understand it
however this is the area where you start
getting into
not a clear best practice
but several good practices that would
probably all work in the situation and
so this is when you need to start
pulling in expertise
people can help identify and implement
which system is going to be best
subject matter experts are critical for
these complicated systems
another thing that's also really
important to remember with complicated
systems if you're a manager is that you
need to defer to the people who are the
experts in whatever the situation is
rather than trying to dictate what you
think is the best model
because in these situations your
perspectives might be different
and you might be dismissing someone
else's really really good idea and
asking them to implement it in a way
that makes sense to you rather than in a
way that
makes sense to them and it is equally
sufficient
so the difference between simple and
complicated systems is really best
practices first kicking the best out of
good practices
so complex systems i think this is the
area where a lot of us in cti thrive
most will find ourselves often facing
truly complex situations
so we may need to spend a great deal of
time framing the problem
uh prototyping through using that design
thinking to say okay is this working is
this not working
and with complex systems sometimes when
things aren't working the problem is not
actually with the system you're trying
to implement the problem might actually
be that you framed it incorrectly and
you have to go back to that problem
framing stage and restart to make sure
that you do understand all the facets
and all the aspects of this issue
so you can build a system
that is going to address it
this is the space where
a lot of our fields really really tough
problems exist
a lot of people find this to be the most
rewarding environment
but it can take a lot of time and it can
be quite mentally exhausting to spend
too much time only focusing on complex
problems
so the goal is not to spend all of your
time here as exciting as it can be to
dive into some of these really complex
problems and systems
so speaking of places we do not want to
spend a lot of time
uh chaotic systems when you're in a
chaotic space things have gotten out of
hand and you need to respond immediately
in many cases
and you don't always have time to go
through and gather all of the
information that you need to really
properly frame a problem and and iterate
through different types of systems the
way you would with a complex system
often when you enter the chaotic space
intentionally it is for innovation
but most often we enter it by accident
because of a crisis
chaotic chaotic situations highlight
gaps in our systems
um again if you're in there for
innovation you're highlighting a gap in
an error in opportunity you have to make
things better
but if it's a chaotic crisis
you missed something some
system some process somewhere that led
to this chaotic state so it's important
to get through this
but afterwards we need to make sure we
follow up and come up with a response
and really do a good after action to say
how did we get here
what could we have done better
did the way we address it actually
address it or do we need to go back and
continue to build a better system to fix
it for the future
so a lot of these spaces they don't stay
static
as we better understand and define
complex problems
and build systems that support them we
can actually start to move them
towards better understanding we can can
identify that cause and effect we can
know the impact an action will have on
one aspect of the system
and start to build good practices and
best practices around that
it's also important to note that chaotic
problems especially when they emerge as
a crisis
often have best practice solutions that
we just overlooked and didn't implement
previously
uh there is one more aspect to this
framework um and that is this space of
disorder here
disorder doesn't speak to the nature of
the situation itself but it speaks to a
miscategorization or a lack of
understanding of the true nature of a
system
this is also a problem we run into a lot
and we often err towards thinking
something is overly simple when it
really is complex
i think this every time somebody looks
at
uh a company that experienced a breach
or had an intrusion or is dealing with
some issue and says well this would this
would have been solved with best
practices
without understanding the full nature of
a complex problem when you over simplify
things you can also run the risk of
shifting yourself over into the chaotic
space
so
one of the big issues
with cti
and we're going to dive into this next
is that
the more problems that arise the more
especially complex or chaotic problems
that arise and this is an area where a
lot of us think we thrive
the more mentally taxing it is
and the more taxing something is
the more our analytic skills actually
decrease and we shift more towards uh
assumptions
and lean back at experience we give into
our biases we give in to the noise and
we can shift into that disordered state
where we're not accurately identifying
the true nature of an issue and of
course when you don't understand the
true nature you can't use any of these
systems
accurately
so the last thing we're going to talk
about today is our self
all intelligence analysis
requires humans
we have a lot of tools we've built a lot
of systems we've built to help augment
that but at the end of the day we truly
require human discernment to make
judgments about the situation pulling in
lots of different facts
but at the same time we're being
bombarded by other stimuli subliminal
information
and internal forces we know nothing
about
robert sapolsky wrote a really great
book called behave it's like 900 pages
of history and anthropology and
neurobiology so if you ever can't sleep
i definitely recommend it
but it really did shine a light on to
how much our minds and our thinking are
influenced not just by external forces
by internal forces as well
so
this is
this yellow part of the brain is the
anterior cingulate cortex it's not
completely understood no part of our
brain is completely understood
but we do know that it plays in a very
important role in cognition
including decision-making empathy
and parts of functional memory
especially where patterns come into play
now i'm not a neurobiologist
but i did read that 900 page book by
robert sapolsky and i also just finished
up a um
a series of courses on neuro leadership
which helped me understand how you can
leverage principles of neurobiology to
be a better leader
and i cannot read about types of brain
function without trying to apply it to
cti analysts who are some of the most
fascinating thinkers that i know
and one of the very interesting
hypotheses i have
that no one has so far let me test out
because no one will give me access to a
functional mri machine
is trying to understand the difference
or the association between people who
are really really brilliant at pattern
analysis at picking up anomalies and
understanding small deviations and
baselines like cliffstall
picking up that eight cents billing
error
and
people who
have a really hard time
dropping things
or saying this is good enough i can let
this go
a lot of times the same super powers we
have that allow us to pick up on a
pattern and dig into it and identify
something is wrong can actually work
against us when it comes time for us to
say
i'm carrying too much cognitive load i'm
not thinking clearly i'm going to let
this problem rest and come back to it
tomorrow
and i think that that is one of the most
important skills that we need to learn
as cti analysts is where our own
limitations are
and where our skills actually start to
work against us
i love thinking about cognitive skills
it's almost like playing cards
if you're a leader and you're building a
team um you know katie talked about
encouraging diversity how we need so
much diversity in this network
is because the more diverse your
organization the more diverse the
cognitive skills you're bringing to the
table are and you really do want to have
people who
have strengths in all of these different
areas
sustained attention
inhibitory control
processing speed
cognitive flexibility is very important
especially when we talked about
storytelling and introducing new
information and being able to
quickly see
how that new information can build into
what you already know and being
comfortable adapting cognitive
flexibility is i think one of the skills
that we need to foster more
to allow us to really continue to grow
and to be okay with the fact that we're
always learning
selective attention is also important
because it allows us to dive into things
when they're important
but like i mentioned before about
sometimes our
tendency as analysts can never let
things drop if you can move your
attention to something else you can
actually free up space in your brain to
think more clearly about the problems at
a future time
working memory uh category formation i
think we have a lot of folks with
strengths in category formation
every time we come up with a new
framework or model i can really see
those people with strengths and category
formation just shining
and then pattern recognition which is
one of my strengths and again i
definitely admit i am one of those
people who cannot let things go
especially when i know that it doesn't
fit my expected pattern
so a lot of people will have
strengths on this list a lot of people
will have areas where they need to
improve or that they can grow things
but what we also know about cognition is
that across the board all of these
skills get degraded when we're not able
to give ourselves that proper care rest
and support that we need
sleep deprivation uh and sleep
interruption even waking up frequently
um both impact cognitive performance
um so for example sleep deprivation uh
impacts
your working memory uh it impacts your
cognitive flexibility in particular and
i think maybe that's one of those one of
the reasons that we do struggle and we
get stuck and mired down in some of the
biases when we've been working
late nights on an intrusion or patching
because of a vulnerability is truly
because those skills that we need are
degraded
stress also matters
it activates the amygdala which controls
your body's fight or flight
or freeze functions actually and it can
hijack your cognitive functions
and so this can severely impact things
like pattern recognition and again
cognitive flexibility because your mind
is looking for the threats that your
body is telling you are out there
you're actually much more likely to
attribute anomalies inaccurately to
malicious activity when you're under
stress because your body everything
physiologically is telling you that
there is a threat there and you're more
likely to see that even if that's not
the true nature of the issue
cognitive load as well or how many
complicated or complex mental tasks
you're juggling
impacts focus working memory and impulse
control
and again it's a double-edged sword
because the more successful we are at
our jobs the more consistent our systems
the more connecting our stories
the more impact it has on our cognitive
load we're asked to do more we unearth
more connections more things that we
need to identify and categorize
uh so the first time i read
the cuckoo zing and again if you've read
the book and sorry for spoilers if you
haven't read the book
um i skipped over he has all these
little sections and tidbits where he
talks about his interest in astronomy
and cooking
um and a lot of like hippie activities
and i'm a hippie-leaning person myself
and they were a little bit much even for
me and i glazed over them
as tangential or not relevant to what i
really wanted to know about which was
this amazing like whodunit hacker
mystery
but when i reread the book now i
actually zero in
on those sections
and on those details i overlooked and
thought didn't matter
they may actually have been part of what
enabled cliff to make those connections
he did and to tell his story the way
that he did
he knew how to balance his stress and
his cognitive load he knew even when
he's sleeping on a basement floor so he
can see when a printer comes up that
there has to be a counterbalance and he
has to do something to regain that state
and keep his cognitive performance
optimized
so
it's easy to say this rest sleep you
know take care of yourself
but if you can actually view this as
part of your job requirement and
managers and leaders if you can view
this as a requirement for the folks
who are working with you
that if you want their cognitive
performance to be best you want them to
get answers sooner collaborate better
and be thinking more clearly you need to
build in time for their brains to get
back
to homeostasis don't keep them sleep
deprived don't keep them under stress
don't constantly toss the same complex
problems on the same person just because
they're good at it because
without that balance
it actually impacts our analytic
capabilities and we won't be able to
move forward as a field
so if you're anything like me the past
few years have been a bit draining
the cognitive load i carry has been
overwhelming at some times
my systems are sporadic at best
sometimes i have neither consistency nor
intensity um and the stories can get a
bit redundant as we feel like we're
dealing with the same problems over and
over
but once again um that's why this is one
of my favorite events of the year it
recharges me even though it is
almost 7 am now here on the west coast
um and i should be practicing what i
preach about sleep deprivation and sleep
interruption
but coming here and being around all
these people all the creative thinkers
and seeing what they're learning and how
they're trying to approach not just cti
in general but cti during a you know
chaotic two years where we've had a
pandemic and and just all sorts of crazy
things going on
it reminds me that things are hard but
in cti we can do hard things
we're not set on a fixed path we're
creating our own future by coming
together and sharing our stories seeing
how others have built practices that
support their work and more than
anything else looking out for one
another