hi everyone my name is Alan Monde and
today I'm just going to go through a
quick presentation on how to get started
on car hacking and it's actually a great
segue to a TTS presentation because some
of the things that he talked about like
radio hacking with Bluetooth can will
come in really handy and if you have any
questions yeah definitely interrupt and
ask your questions I'll try to keep
track of what's going on on the chat so
here are the things that we're going to
talk about how to get started so what
are some of the areas that you can look
into to attack a car the vehicle
networking basics that are required to
have a car so some of the very basic
things that you need to know about the
vehicles internal network a very very
short demo showing what that looks like
and then how to build your own testing
book for very very cheap objectives talk
is to create awareness obviously and to
for more important audience so a little
bit of background I'm originally from
Argentina and I worked at Bosch for a
number of years on the Pontiac Solstice
doing engine calibration and a lot of
work internally on how the vehicle
communicates with between the different
modules I then started a small equipment
sharing company called Muni rent I then
launched in 2016 car loop which is a car
hacking tool and you'll see it pop up
here and now I recently started at
voyage doing hardware integration and
controls for a self-driving taxi service
so
and below are all sort of my interests
so if anyone is interested any of that
stuff definitely hit me up on Twitter my
Twitter is on there as well
oh yeah since i have a captive audience
right now I want to just download some
information that I had about the Pontiac
Solstice that I can't just give this
information to anyone so since you're
here I'll just tell you the way to
identify whether a Pontiac Solstice
which is this car is a turbo versus a
regular naturally aspirated car is with
this so you can see that that the grill
actually has minor difference anyway
says kind of a slight step for the talk
but what are some of the different
attack surfaces on cars when you when
you come across a car see when there's
when you when you come across a car
there are some some things that you
might notice as you start hacking with
cars and there's there's a number of
attack surfaces so the person that a lot
of people sort of disregard is the tire
pressure monitoring system sensor in
every car nowadays you have to have a
sensor that connects to the car and it's
located in each one of the four tires
and that sensor measures pressure the
way that communicates to the body
control module is via a radio signal so
it's a low frequency radio signal that
sends the data back to the module so you
can actually in turn intercept that
signal and that would be one attack
surface another attack surface is a
Bluetooth Wi-Fi so essentially there's
nowadays there's a lot of parts that
have onboard Wi-Fi so they have a 3G
modem or a 4G modem and in Wi-Fi
hot spot in the car and a lot of times
that hot spot is open completely
unsecured so you can actually if you're
driving next to someone on the highway
you can actually tailgate them and log
into that network and that networks
actually connected through the main
inputs infotainment system system which
is those screens in the center of the
car so the third one is the obd2 port
which is typically underneath the
steering wheel sometimes it's to the
left of the steering sometimes it's to
the right and this is the main entry
point access this is already inside the
car and then the fourth one is the
infotainment system itself and USB
there's there's a number of ways you can
actually get root access to the
important system and after this talk
again I can point you in the direction
of where these resources are so how to
get started the first thing that I would
recommend anyone if you haven't already
is to pick up this book called the car
hacker's handbook is written by Craig
Smith and its first published in 2016
there there aren't a lot of there's a
lot of literature out there surprisingly
about car hacking and this is I think
one of the most comprehensive ones
it's actually free to download so if you
go to this link you can download a zip
file and a PDF of the entire book so one
of the nice things about this book is it
really does cover a lot of the nitty
gritty of hardware hacking so for
example when you when you actually get
an engine or transmission control module
or any module in the car you can
actually open it up and it goes in
pretty deep detail on how to
download firmware and do a lot of things
that addy do was talking about in the
last presentation there's an entire
chapter dedicated to socket can and can
you tilt and since I'll show some of
this it'll be very very good if you like
this to kind of follow up and read that
chapter because it's it's very very good
and also talk about how to reverse
engineer and see any to you which is
really interesting
so we'll in order to get started in car
hacking the easiest way is to have
access to the of DLC it's data link
connector but more colloquially known as
the obd2 port the obd2 port is called
like that because of regulation from the
California Air Resources Board to have a
standard way to read diagnostic false
hopes that would affect the environment
so any fuel related and then it became
this sort of standard for reading vocals
in an engine the interesting thing is
since 2008 a lot of these since those
2008 obd2 was mandated to be on can the
can protocol and i'll talk about that in
a little bit and this is very important
because the rest of the car is also on
the same can network so what was
exciting about being able to access the
obd2 port is that once you can read data
from the obd2 port you can write data
very easily and control the car it's
completely unencrypted so you mean a can
Hardware tool this comes in many many
shapes you can find one that goes from
the obd2 port to rs-232 connector really
what you're looking for is a
microcontroller that has
a can controller on it and a can
transceiver and some of these tools are
pretty pretty affordable but it does
require you to buy another cable to go
from the obd2 port to the tool from the
tools through your computer if you don't
have rs-232 it's kind of a pain so and
you also need a Linux machine I guess
before I keep going at my background it
is not in security actually my
background is on automotive so
definitely ask any questions with that
in mind and take whatever you can from
from this and apply it to to do it any
type of penetration testing on on cars
you can also there are other options
like this is why we came up with with
car loop which is basically a cable-less
device so you just connect it straight
to the obd2 board and you can either use
a micro USB or Wi-Fi to be and it
supports the same socket can and it's
completely open source as well a lot of
times I get asked the question but what
about these $10 obd2 dongles on Amazon
why can't I use those to hack my car
actually you could they're just in my
case it just takes a lot of work to use
the tools because there they have an
integrated circuit all the elm327 it
actually takes the raw can messages and
then converts them into physical values
or to actual values from the engine so
inside this elm327 there's this data
dictionary that whenever they sees a can
message it actually sends out an actual
signal so you're not really getting the
raw and messages and you're just looking
at the obd2 mandated messages rather
than being able to see the entire
range of canvases that are available so
that's why the obd2
dongles on Amazon are just not a good
tool to write either so you can only
read you can't really send canned
messages back into the vehicle um from
what I've seen the most comprehensive
list of hardware devices car hacking
tools both software and hardware that
are open-source are on this awesome
vehicle security list on this link and
if you go there you'll see in the readme
is just an amazing a plethora of
information and then some friendly
forums that I like to hang out at open
garages org it's great they always have
really really sort of no judgment zone
comments and same with community Doc REO
and recently there's been a new one
called
comma black doctor it's basically comma
dot ai which is a self-driving car
company that has open source a bunch of
stuff but and they also have bounties
too if you can basically create a port
to do a self-driving car so it's a
really interesting interesting place to
to ask questions about car hacking in
general as well okay so in order to to
command a vehicle or to to figure out
what are some of the easy ways to modify
a vehicle you need to have some idea of
networking basics of the vehicle
networking races um every vehicle that's
rolling on at least in the US and a lot
of Europe Asian and South America
there's internally there's a network
called the canvas and it connects all
the modules through this two wires
basically two physical wires that
connect
the dashboard to the engine to the body
control module the airbag control module
the transmission infotainment system
everything is connected on on on a
canvas can it stands for controller area
network it's two wires can hi and
cantaloupe there's typically more than
one canvas on vehicle for example on on
test left they have the Tesla Model S
has six different canvases for different
parts of the vehicle so why focus on can
it's mandated since 2008 and so a lot of
manufacturers use it so if you have to
work on one product all protocols can is
the protocol moving forward that's going
to be the most open and right now it's
not encrypted at all so if you connect
any device to a car you start seeing
data so this is what it looks like on an
oscilloscope and when you convert this
to actual data this is what you're
seeing so basically met the signals go
from high to low so from two point five
is the resting voltage and then whenever
there's a packet that's being sent the
information is transmitted by modulating
this signal so I'll explain the the most
important part of a can message is the
ID and the data so the ID is basically
what that can message what kind of
information that camera such as
containing and the data is the payload
basically this is what it looks like on
your laptop when you're running a can
you tilt which is one of those utilities
for from socket cam so I'll give you a
very short demo of what that looks like
so the first thing you want to do is you
want to install can you tilt and is that
you do it on you boom tube in the case
of introducing a car loop you can
provision a car loop with can you tilt
and flash over the air on your car and
you can actually go to this this address
because on this URL you will actually go
through what is what are some of the
things you have to do to get this data
through socket cam and then you just
type in can never see can zero and then
you start seeing a bunch of data I'll
show you what that looks like
so this is just a chip but if we stop
that this is what the data coming from
can looks like so this is the ID and the
rest are so there's definite this
there's basically eight bytes of data
and each byte pair contains different
types of information this is coming from
the ADF module of a Ford Fusion and so
there's there's only a few messages but
if you do this on an entire car it'll be
three thousand messages just scrolling
through so the way you identify what
this is is you look at the ID and then
you see what kind of what changes for
example of you if you unlock the doors
which one of these digits or which one
of these by players are changing and
that's how you can actually decode what
each ID is there's no documentation out
there and manufacturers don't really
want you seeing what this is but it's
fairly straightforward once you have
this in front of you and you start
clicking different buttons on the car
you actually see this changing and the
the colors change as well this tool with
can't sniffer which is open source and
native for
so if you don't feel like hacking on
your own car you can actually build a
test bench and for less than a hundred
bucks you can actually have a running
can bus with for example an engine
control module a power supply and any of
the can Hardware can devices that I
mentioned the bus if you add more
modules you get more interesting data
this is for example a test bench for a
Ford Fusion so there's a dashboard the
sink 3 module which is really
interesting to hack on the controls for
AC the radio and the you see the fuse
box there we actually have some internal
relays and all that is sending canned
messages so if you disconnect one you
can actually see what are the canned
messages that are coming from that
module so it's a really really
interesting exercise I'm going to check
if there are any questions so far yeah
and we can we can go a little long here
if we need to okay yeah so no worries
okay so that that was they'd actually
yeah now I know I but there's some good
questions in here so we had someone just
ask if you can can you get this from
your local junkyard those those parts
that you were just talking about yeah as
a matter of fact Kardash part.com which
is what I was showing earlier let me go
back to that yeah so car - part comm is
actually even better than your junkyard
because if all the junkyards across the
US all on this website so people that
have jumped here just post cars that
they have and it automatically populates
the parts that will have them as far so
you actually go there you order it and
it arrives typically everyone ships USPS
priority
and that way you don't have to go do it
yourself
awesome let's see we had someone ask how
do you access proprietary key IDs yeah
so kids which are parameter IDs or obd2
those are harder to to decode because
those are use of response that a query
and response structure those are
specific to obd2 so they don't just
stream the data doesn't just string
actually have to send a specific pin to
get it back and the way I think most
people do that is is by using a scan
tool you can you can buy a scan tool for
that specific brand and use a lie
splitter what that looks like
why splitter I mean this is I'm not
trying to the easiest way to show what a
why splitter looks like yeah so
basically you connect on one side of a
device that reads data and then on the
other side you can access scan tool so
you can actually send a request like
what is the I don't know what the RPM
and then you'll get it back and you'll
see what is the request sent and how to
capture the message back as well does
that make sense I think so um C&C can
you please explain about the replay
attacks on car key fobs using hack RF I
have types of devices yeah I either have
it I was eight I haven't played a lot
with that so I really can't comment but
I have no idea what's the difference
between kind of the tool set that you
described in a couple the first earlier
slides and the stuff that's like on
illmatic the Charlie Miller kind of
tools he dropped when he did the cheap
research and the hacking manuals there
yeah so there there's a lot more sort of
setup with the tool that they use and
that's actually a paper that I forgot to
include but it's it's a really really
good read because it goes through some
of a lot of the process of decoding each
of the can messages and it actually has
some IDs already on there that you can
look at if you have the same brand of
card each each manufacturer has their
own specific set of ID's that they use
to describe different things in the car
so Ford uses one type of ID ID let's say
it's called a DBT file so sort of a data
dictionary but in terms of the tools
there they're all very very basic and
they're all the same it's really just a
in terms of hardware it's just a
microcontroller with a can bus on it and
that can transceiver and as long as you
have that very simple sort of tool chain
you can you can start hacking cool also
just wanted a shameless plug out there
so bugcrowd is running the car hat or
the car hacker CTF this year at the car
hacking village at DEFCON the CTF grand
prize is actually 2017 truck so if you
guys are if you guys are coming to
DEFCON come compete in the CTF and you
can have a chance to drive away with a
new vehicle yeah with the URL for that
is what car hacking village get so ya
know you can google it cracking village
CTF or something like that but when we
make sure yeah well yeah we I'm also a
part of that shameless plug I'm really
proud of the CTF site that we built with
C T FD the design is awesome
yeah it's at car Hackney village calm
that's all the information for the con
car hacking village in its entirety bug
crowd will have a table there and will
be handing out tons of stickers and Alan
are you going to be in Vegas in a couple
weeks or are you we have again I'm
trying to make it work
I think it's I've been there last year
and it it's super fun and there's a lot
of people that are very very
knowledgeable so you go to the car
hacking village just always learn
something new it's really really
valuable
awfully with the link actually there's a
question about the link
let me grab it oh it's at the car
hacking handbook yeah cool well this was
super helpful I'm going to we'll try to
get you back again sometime to do some
more chats people really really enjoyed
this talk cool thank you very much for
having me