so I assume everybody can hear me -
sense responding back to me if you can't
I've got
chat open here so I'll keep an eye on
that and I guess
full disclosure before I start I am
insanely nervous I considered this a
chat among my peers and then I noticed
all the people that are on here are
people that I look up to so bear with me
if I've got the jitters obviously I'm
going to be talking about hidden in
plain sight disclosing information via
your IP is a couple different things
that going to cover there before I get
started I just wanted to give a big
thanks to Sam and had extra storms and
so Jason before I was putting this
together
Jason had reached out to me and thought
it might be good for a good opportunity
to make a presentation and I didn't
really think I had a topic to to work
through but in the chat
wake him up with something or rather he
he kind of encouraged me to do it so so
thank you for that
there's also been a ton of information
that he shared with me in my interview
with him if you haven't seen that I
would encourage that as well when he sat
down and chatted with said Shana with me
for hacking pro tips as well so in terms
of who I am
Pete Gorski at yours pretty much
everywhere I'm now part of the
application security team over at
Shopify and that's largely because of
bug bounties really firmware for bug
bounties I wouldn't be there so Casey
was talking about that earlier I'm
definitely one of those stories and I'd
be happy to chat with anybody about that
if they're curious how that came to be
I've also written a book web hacking 101
which hopefully in the new year will be
real-world web hacking via no starch in
print I don't know when it'll be
released but pre-sales are up now and
I'm obviously also a bug binding
participant so in terms of what I'm
going to cover with you guys or girls
what we're going to talk about so I'm
going to kind of lay that out so we got
some groundwork I'm going to talk about
why we care about disclosing information
but I'm going to take a bit of a
different truck than others have and I'm
going to kind of go through why it
happens I feel it's important to
understand kind of the mistakes that
developers can make because once you can
get into that mindset you can open the
door to some some great vulnerabilities
that I think people without
developer experience might miss so my
goal hopefully wanted to take ways is to
give you insight into that and give you
a framework to to continue on and I
talked about how you find these types of
vulnerabilities so that's hand in hand
kind of going off of why it happens and
then I'll share some examples from
bounties that I've had I've chosen three
but I probably could have listed upwards
of ten or fifteen or so and of course my
slide is going to go so in terms of what
we're talking about I'm talking about
API is that are disclosing personally
identifying information or application
sensitive information right so this is
something that can be leveraged by an
attacker to attack the application
itself or its users what I'm not talking
about is headers that just say you know
you're using nginx version 2.1 or
whatever the versions are PHP version
this of that we're going to talk about
ap is which render information on the
page as well as ap is themselves that
are used by mobile applications but
really it's the API set of rendering
this type of information on page that I
find to be overlooked quite often and
it's I assume it's because you'll see it
in this massive HTML page so there will
be a ton of HTML and then down at the
bottom you might see this JSON encoded
blurb that's all the data that's being
used on the page and the tip-off for
that is when you're seeing frameworks
like react or angular or whatnot and you
can see some of the calls that are
having API information there in terms of
why we care I mean really these are and
the reason why I debated presenting this
was because it almost seems so easy to
find these and I know at least I hear
that a lot kind of when I was learning
this is easy that's easy but it's really
just opening your eyes to looking at
HTML source looking at api's and then
one of the things when I had an
interview with with Franz was him
talking about looking at the information
that's being disclosed by something and
then figuring out how that could be
sensitive to a company that was a huge
takeaway for me because I started
changing my perspective on applications
that I was hacking on looking for
information of if they disclose this do
they actually care that they disclose
that
so that's why I consider this to be easy
the impacts really range like you can
have something that's you know you might
be disclosing something that the company
doesn't really care too much about but
you can also be disclosing some critical
information and I'll show you that in
one of the examples we talked about
where I found on page and the HTML
source users IP addresses birthdays hash
passwords the salt for their hash
password a whole bunch of information
and you'll see it as one of the examples
and really it was because I looked at
the HTML source for the page and there
was a pattern in this application and it
seemed like they had a lot of technical
debt where this was a design pattern
that they had used and I'll try to
explain why I think it happened and then
lastly sometimes these information
disclosure x' can be chained together
and so I recently had one that I've
reported earlier earlier this week a
couple days ago where as exactly that in
a 5-time I'll talk about that because
it's not part of the examples but these
are the types of messaging that I tend
to look for so here you'll see you know
your I just won't be shared with anyone
that's a red flag for me because if I
can find the address that's obviously
going to be a problem for the
application this is one from the
examples because my D is 26 characters
long you'll never guess that well if you
leak it I don't have to guess it you
know we want to show your postal code
regular users can only see other users
and we use this data for analysis will
never share it again it all kind of
stands out in terms of why this happens
I really think it boils down to two
things I was going to put a third but I
didn't want to be an ass for lack of a
better term it's really automation of
repetitive tasks and I'll show you that
and then code abstraction the third one
I was going to say was laziness or
stupidity but I mean I think when you're
moving quickly some of these sites are
building things out pretty quick you
know they're competitive they want to
have product and market right away so
when you're looking at automating
repetitive tasks and kind of abstracting
the code it's easy to make mistakes and
incur that technical debt and that's
where we come in to kind of help out the
company to to fix that
so I'm using a rails example here and
I'm talking about the automation side of
things so when you're working with rails
and you're developing an application
you're going to end up going through
this this design pattern at the
beginning because rails is what's
referred to as a Model View controller
architecture so MVC so the idea being
that all three of these layers are
separate so you'll send a request to a
website and the controller will receive
that request right it'll be you know
come in through the application and
you'll know they're the route or the URL
that you looking for it'll go to the
controller and that controller is
responsible for taking the parameters
and then touching the database and
getting the information so that's the
model layer right the model interacts
with your database and then gives the
information back to the controller now
the controller is going to pass that
information into the view that's going
to render it for you and that's where
you see it right so whenever you're
developing these applications you have
to go through that create a route and
then you got to create a controller and
then you got to create your view you got
to create your model and it gets super
repetitive so rails is awesome for
automating repetitive tasks and one of
the things that they do is they provide
this command line command line command
that allows you to automatically do all
of that so you can tell that rails
I've got rails G scaffolding which is
just in a command which is actually
generate so it's real generous scaffold
and then the user is actually the one
I'm generating so I'm going to generate
this this concept of a user on the site
so I'm going to have a user's table I'm
going to have a user controller and then
for each user I'm going to collect their
birthday their phone their gender their
sending their name and so rail stones
all that wraps it all up and if you're
not entirely familiar with rails what it
will end up creating for you is this
controller which we just talked about
and you'll see here that in it it's
telling you it's going to give you get
slash users as a URL but it's also going
to respond to get users dot JSON so
really it's going to give you an API so
when you're developing this if you're
not conscious about that you'll have
that and then you'll go into your view
and so this is what the generated HTML
looks like and I hope you can see my
mouse because I'm moving it all around I
guess kind of
seriously but here if the user is going
to view this users information or a
subsequent music I don't want them to
see that you know the sin and the gender
let's say we're going to keep that
private so where I've got gender and
I've got sin I'm now going to go ahead
thanks for confirming yet I'm going to
remove those so they're not in the view
anymore so when you actually go to this
page slash user one you're not going to
see that information and so that's
awesome
however because you've gone ahead and
you've created this API endpoint
automatically sugar scaffold if you ping
users JSON it's going to render those
two pieces of information and so if you
were not consciously as a developer
developing your API you might not
realize you have to edit the second file
to remove that information so this is
what was actually generated when you run
the scaffold and so we had that view
that actually shows the information but
then there's this JSON file and so just
what happen I was using J builder for
the example and that's why this is this
is rendered here and so you'll see JSON
extract right and you're telling it the
exact parameters that you want to render
when you're going to the JSON endpoint
so if you don't update that file and
remove gender and sin your HTML file is
going to be fine but when you ping dot
JSON it's not going to be fine you're
going to disclose that so from a
development perspective that kind of
explains the beginning we're talking
about automation but in terms of the
code abstraction if you're developing
and you're building your application and
today you have five parameters you're
going to render tomorrow of ten next day
you have 15 they're continually being
added to for this model based on the
type of information or your you're
changing functionality it's going to get
super annoying to have to keep going
back through this process all the time
and so are you going to do it all by
hand the answer is of course no you're
not because you're a developer and you
want to save your time so rather than
have JSON extract and all the parameters
where you're going to list out you know
you're 15 20 or whatever you're just
going to use the handy method merge and
you're going to say give me all the
attributes that's on the user so rather
than have everything you now have this
nice short
chambo piece of code they both provide
you the exact same thing right you see
everything that's there so that's
awesome
if you kind of know what's going on and
you want to render everything you don't
have a problem but tomorrow if you
decide to to add a sensitive parameter
to it let's say a secret password you're
fine using the first because you haven't
actually consciously added that right
this code hasn't changed once you go
ahead and you add this column user's
password and then you update your HTML
you're still fine you saved yourself
because you haven't updated your JSON
however if you've gone ahead and use
JSON merge when your model was
originally benign it had no sensitive
information and then two years down the
length down the line you add a sensitive
parameter JSON merge is going to bite
you in the ass because you're going to
add this parameter for password you're
going to update your view you're going
to forget that you've used JSON merge
and now when you ping that URL you're
going to see the new parameter that's
down there despite the fact that you
didn't update that field or rather that
file so those are the reasons why this
happens the last one you'll see here
where I've automated the task out of
stupidity is a personal anecdote from my
own so when I was a developer I was
working with a mobile team and I had no
concept of security at the time and so
the mobile team kept coming back to me
and saying hey we need some more
information provided of the API and so I
said you know what I'm just going to
give you the full object because you're
getting annoying I don't want to keep
updating my code and you're developing a
mobile application who's ever going to
see the traffic as a mobile application
so that's another reason why stupidity
comes in right we all know we can proxy
a mobile app there's all the information
because I've returned a full object out
of every field so that takes us to how
do we find it really this is this has
been covered off by pretty much everyone
was talked right Jason Haddix talked
about it right away when you identify
software used right going back to how to
shop web once or web one-lap eliezer is
my go-to I love it I will always look
for rails angular and react
rails and angular particularly because I
understand the rails development pattern
so it's real easy to start finding
things and think through the logic that
people are using because I've played
with it before right so I encourage you
as a hacker one of the things I think
that's super fundamental and helpful is
to go out and think of something that
you want to build take a weekend and
build it in rails or build in Django or
try to actually develop that and then
you'll see the struggles that developers
go through or even just pick up a book
and understand their thought process
design patterns and where things can go
wrong you'll find a lot of documentation
around that in terms of like security
considerations for different frameworks
tools all kinds of stuff the other
reason why I look for angular and I'm
not going to touch upon it but is
angular injections are so common so
start throwing around those well those
are the moustache curls or whatever they
referred to as with seven times seven
and look for 49 I do that and so many
applications are vulnerable to that the
reason why I list react there is because
an angular the reason why they're
included here is because they will use
that API design pattern right like
they'll use the API and then they'll use
the information out of what's being
returned in JSON to render on site so
you might not see it on site but that
information is going to be there if a
developer screws up so with react I've
seen that's where people will kind of
render in the page just because of the
way that it's designed and developed
whereas angular that's where you'll see
actual API calls if you're monitoring
your traffic the real sites that's kind
of what I was talking about in terms of
the design pattern you'll always have
this kind of slash model slash ID in a
URL so that's kind of a giveaway when
you're looking with rails it's not you
know 100% but you might see slash users
slash one or you know slash user slash
bookmarks slash one type thing and then
it gives you an idea that you're you're
working with rails also watch the bird
proxy history right like it's super easy
to start looking through the HTML that's
there and watch for those JSON encoded
blobs that are there it's crazy
the sites that I've come on to join
private programs that have had hackers
there for a couple months and nobody's
looked at this because there's so much
HTML that's returned it's returned at
the bottom I can only assume that's why
so that's been been successful for me
and the cool thing about that too is
it's a design pattern right so if you're
seeing in a one URL chances are it's
going to be at others so you've got to
go through everywhere and what
differentiates that between a site that
you know site wide as a CSRF problem is
that these are unique endpoints right
like there is no single fix for that the
application owners have to go through
everything and find out where they've
done this to fix it so they're unique
bounties for you there's really never at
a site argue with me about that because
if they're separate issues right like
you can't go and fix that right away
arguably and you know knowing my luck
tomorrow someone will say that they can
in terms of the verb history again watch
for the API calls you'll see in the
examples where API calls in a returning
full object as opposed to you know just
the fields that they need and developers
won't realize that you can see that
potentially or rather than their cue 18
because they're not necessarily looking
at the API calls they may just be
looking and using the website itself so
they don't realize the informations
there how it can be chained together
lastly mobile apps provides you great
insight into into api's which people
think like myself when I was naive and I
developer don't think people are going
to see and so as a result you can see
all the information that's there and you
know that'll be usually there will be a
lot of I doors their information
disclosures and other fun bugs to play
with so in a nutshell you're going to
want to look for that private user
information Brunner account information
admin info but something that can
actually be used to attack the
application and then demonstrate what
the issue is so in terms of my examples
first and foremost here this was one
that kind of it frustrated me when I got
this response but at the same time it
was a huge learning opportunity and
something that I took away so I found an
endpoint
where you could go to you know / I think
with / customer none guessable user ID
and then whatever you went to after that
whatever endpoint existed you had access
to despite the fact you didn't have
permissions to it and so because I had
that I reported that the vulnerability
yes you had this you just user ID but at
the same point everything after that was
disclosed and then it had permission to
see it so they closed it on me and that
said no this isn't a vulnerability
because you'll never be able to guess
that customer ID so I told them I'll be
back
sure enough spent day two days and it
just turned out if you had access to the
order for a user you have access to
customer info they ended up giving you
this customer ID and so that was the
unique user ID that I was looking for
and so it just happened to be that there
were angular application they were
returning this in the API but they
weren't actually using the information
so when you saw in burkas tree there's
your 26 character UUID pop that into the
URL go to billing info and then all
sudden I have all kinds of crazy
information about the customer that I'm
not supposed to have sure enough we
agree is with vulnerability here's your
four figure payout which probably could
have been avoided if they violated the
first one and give me a three figure pan
so that's a key takeaway for me is that
you got to dig a little bit deeper and
you'll get paid a little bit more in
terms of the private address info here
this this target identified that you
know you're in a you're going to suggest
a contract to another user but that user
will never see your address until they
actually accept the contract so again
red flag for me your address will never
be shared with until some point so can I
find the address before I hit the until
sure enough again sorry for the crazy
amount of red here but I wanted to use
this to demonstrate this is all HTML
like this is all the HTML blurb that's
there so it's all encoded text but if
you actually look at it and I yeah
here's the actual size of the HTML like
this is math
so you had to scroll way down inside of
this blurb that had a whole bunch of
crap in it but then you can actually see
here's the actual address and this
happens on the create end point not the
accepted end point so they're disclosing
the information well before they're
supposed to be let them know and yep
they agree and there's another four
figure payout a last example here and
this was the best one that I've ever
found again same idea and the reason why
unfortunately I can't show you the HTML
is because I didn't record it because I
was sitting there in a scratching head
and I couldn't understand how I found
this I just grabbed all the information
decoded it and provided it to the
company but you'll see here birth date
was something they said they would never
ever share I could find out when a
user's account was created and their
email confirmation code I wasn't sure
what I could actually do with that but
it was listed their Facebook identifiers
their internal IP phone ID password hash
and how they received their payments I
don't know what the refund token was but
sounds kind of interesting their roles
on the site and so they actually have
administrators and employees that have
profiles so I assumed that there would
have been something juicy there for us
to at least target and then the salt for
the password so that would help me
trying to decrypt kind of what they're
doing
again this was a high figure high
forefinger payout and you'll see here
that they said they resolved it quickly
just because of the severity of it and
this was awesome this was a this was a
great payday right before Christmas so
that's it I save some time because I was
hoping there might be some questions to
kind of go of or go over and obviously
I've got my shameless plug here for web
hacking 101 and then obviously check out
Shopify com slash careers because the
place to work is honestly amazing I can
have realized it before I join them and
yes I absolutely love ketchup chips I
feel like everyone this presentation
would love ketchup chips as well if they
tasted them and especially bagels
dude great presentation thanks so much
man
no worries I'm glad to have you have had
the opportunity thanks very much
let's see where we had no schedule right
now it is 123 p.m. Pacific Standard Time
a couple minutes for questions literally
two minutes anybody have any questions
let me look in the thing now it looks
like we're good Pete thanks so much for
for coming on alright awesome I have to
figure out how to give you back control
over everything okay yeah thank you so
much Peter it's uh you've got a lot of
fans right now in the in the chat all
right well thanks everyone and yeah I'll
hand over control soon as I figure out
what I'm doing here Sam thanks again no
worries thank you