hi everyone welcome to our session on a
deep dive into mac OS MDM my name is
Jesse Endel I'm max phenology I work at
a company called fleet Smith we're an
Apple device management product and I'm
a staff engineer draw box a little bit
of background on why we did this
research so you know it's what it's what
our product does so we have kind of a
vested interest there
it handles you know OS updates app
updates security policy enforcement and
compliance for Apple devices we have a
really high security bar for for our
products so we want to make sure it's
secured by design and we put a lot of
work into making sure that's true our
goal with this talk partially was to
increase the security of MDM and dep and
also kind of raise the bar for all MDM
vendors and i just wanted to work with
Jesse again so quick agenda will be
covering some basics some terminology
some concepts moving into an overview
followed by the deep dive section which
max will walk us through also disclosing
the vulnerability that we found and
explaining how that works then we'll
actually be exploiting that so we have a
laptop here in the box if all goes well
our demo will work with no issues and
finally we'll we'll go through the fix
and some conclusions and takeaways
so let's jump in what is MDM it can be a
confusing term because it can refer to
an entire kind of product category when
we say MDM we mean Apple's specific
flavor of MDM which is a protocol as
well as a few other things that we'll
touch on
to set system configuration in a
centralized way through an MDM server
and that MDM server is built by a third
party it's not something that's run by
Apple so that could be fleet Smith that
could be another product like air watch
so if you've heard of kind of mobile
device management products that's we're
referring to here and an MDM server can
send MDM commands to a device that
includes things like a remote wipe
command in case the device is lost or
stolen as well as a command to install a
configuration profile which could
contain something like password
complexity requirements for your
enterprise or perhaps you know Wi-Fi
network settings to join the WP hu
network and include the you know network
password for example all right
DEP this stands for device enrollment
program this is a complementary
technology to MDM and it allows you to
have devices automatically enroll with
an MDM server immediately upon first
boot the first time they connect to the
network this is most useful obviously
when the device is brand new because it
can help you achieve the holy grail of
IT workflows which is a zero touch
deployment workflow meaning the IT team
never has to touch it the laptop ships
directly from Apple to the employee
they're the ones to unbox it connect to
Wi-Fi and boom it sets itself up
automatically through your MDM product
obviously this could also be useful for
provisioning workflows if you have an
advice that's being used by an employee
they leave and you want to wipe it and
redeploy it it could also be useful in
that scenario as well skip the stands
for a simple certificate enrollment
protocol and this is a way for a device
to send a certificate signing request
this is a request for a certificate to a
skipper
generally this is going to be
implemented as part of the MDM product
the client will
you know send its request the server
will evaluate whether or not it should
grant the certificate and if the answer
is yes the client the device will
receive a TLS client certificate that's
used to authenticate later on to the MDM
server configuration profiles I touched
on this briefly already this is Apple's
standardized format for enforcing system
configuration such as password
complexity requirements Wi-Fi settings
disk encryption you name it it's a file
format that can contain multiple
payloads so you can have one file that
contains the settings for all three of
those things and it's based on the P
list or property list format which is
Apple specific flavor of XML the
payloads within the configuration
profile can also optionally be signed
and encrypted to validate origin ensure
integrity and protect their contents so
a quick overview of the entities at play
here there's really five key players
there's Apple themselves running some of
the server infrastructure and of course
the manufacturer of the devices next up
you've got resellers this would include
large resellers like CDW it would also
in the world of DEP include Apple Retail
third you've got the MDM vendor fourth
you have the customer there's the
company that's actually you know trying
to manage their devices for their
enterprise and fifth you of course have
the device itself ok protocols the MDM
protocol is really a combination of two
protocols the first is Apple push
notification service APNs you may have
heard this in relation to other
technologies such as iMessage if you've
you know sent I messages on your iPhone
that's actually built partially on top
of APNs next up it's also a restful api
so there's sort of two pieces to this
here and that's the part that the MDM
server implements and that's a restful
api communication occurs between the
device and the mt MDM server and the
device receives commands in plist
encoded dictionaries this is all over
HTTP HTTPS and optionally MDM servers
can be pinned but it's not a requirement
authentication works differently for
each of these so as I mentioned earlier
that
client certificate issued by escape is
used for authenticating to the MDM
server for the push notifications that's
actually done via a push notification
token we won't get be going in depth on
ApS today because there's already been a
lot of research on that whole area so
that's why we won't be diving into that
today
all right DEP there's actually three
separate API is related to DEP one for
resellers one for MDM vendors and one
for the device itself to prove its
device identity which is undocumented
the nice thing about all these is
they're more modern api's they use JSON
no P lists and today we're only going to
be focusing on that middle one there the
MDM to Apple communication between the
MDM vendor product and the DEP cloud
service API ok the cloud service API
what is this thing used for it's another
restful api there's two main use cases
one is to sync device records so when a
reseller or Apple themselves adds a new
device into their internal DEP database
somewhere then those device records need
to be synced over pulled into the MDM
product somehow that is done over this
DEP cloud service API and then the other
thing that happens is the MDM vendor
pushes back what's called a DEP profile
which contains a few different things
and that DEP profile is delivered to the
vise later on the first time it boots up
so that DEP profile which is a JSON
payload contains three things the MDM
server URL any additional certificates
that need to be trusted for the sake of
pinning as well as any setup setup
assistant configuration you want to do
so that setup system you see on the Mac
first boots up you can customize which
screens are shown there and this
authentication is handled with OAuth
between the MDM server and Apple so step
is another restful api it was created at
a time when TLS and HTTPS weren't that
widespread and so it relies on CMS or
pkcs number seven signed data to ensure
message integrity it supports the
concept of a challenge password
for authentication unfortunately in the
RFC that's really just defined as like a
string we think that field should be
used a little bit more carefully and so
what we do is we actually stick an H Mac
in there that server generated so that
we can correlate that with a specific
enrollment request from a specific user
all right establishment of trusts
between all these things it's pretty
complex and we're not going to go into
it in detail here but we do cover this
very extensively in great detail in the
white paper so definitely check that out
and it's just important to call out that
there's a lot of cross hunting that goes
on a lot of uploading and downloading of
certs in order to get to the point where
the MDM vendor now has the right to send
MDM push notifications down to the
device as well as sink those device
records to the DEP servers with Apple
and push those DEP profiles back alright
some differences here
the authentication for the for MDM is
via API APNs whereas for DEP it's a toe
off token so different auth stories here
all right putting it all together so
there's sort of if you look at the
entire lifecycle the entire bootstrap
process for DEP and MDM this is what it
looks like from start to finish this is
kind of hard to get an understanding of
so we made a visual for this as you can
see the first step is the reseller or
Apple creating that device record the
next thing that happens is the customer
the enterprise actually goes into
something called Apple business manager
which is a web portal and assigns that
device to a specific MDM server from
there the MDM server is able to sync
those device records over as I mentioned
earlier as well as push those DEP
profiles back up back to Apple next the
device actually checks in via DEP -
Apple receives this profile then we've
got the sort of bootstrapping of the
initial MDM config which max will walk
through in greater detail and finally
the device can start receiving MDM
commands like that remote wipe command
install
configuration profile etc alright thanks
Jesse
so today's deep dive will focus on the
for later stages of the process now for
more info on stages one through three I
do recommend you check out the white
paper so as we've seen the later steps
involve the device itself in these steps
Mac OS interacts directly with apple and
the MDM vendor servers we're gonna use a
scenario here to sort of walk through
the deep dive
so imagine a user is getting a new a
brand new MacBook and isn't unboxed it
that MacBook has been previously
configured by the employer to set itself
up automatically via depth and MDM so
dep and MDM enrollment on the Mac
involves many different agents daemons
it's a bit of a confusing maelstrom of
dynamic linking and IPC however a there
is very conveniently a single framework
that abstract away all that complexity
for us that is the private configuration
profiles framework this gives you a set
of functions that map really well to the
steps that we're going to go over today
so if you ever seen this screen then
you've seen what it's called the setup
assistant or internally nicknamed Mac
buddy this is the the app this is
actually a cocoa application this is the
first thing you see when you turn on the
device so that is its icon complete with
bowtie the Mac OS setup assistant is one
of the users of this framework and
that's how it enables Depp in MDM
enrollments so to simplify our view
today we're going to take the point of
view of the max of assistant we're going
to use that framework as a lens to look
at each step so let's recap so we have
four steps to go over the first one is
the DP check-in now the purpose of this
step is to verify whether the device is
DP enabled and if so we we have to sort
of take special action so in this step
internally this is called retrieving the
activation record now Jessie detailed
what a depth profile is that is roughly
the internal name for a depth profile it
contains almost all the same information
this is implemented by a demon
underlying the configuration profiles
framework and a bit of a quick note
this is a pretty common mac OS pattern
in order to guarantee privilege and
process separation Apple will typically
farm out work to do
daemons under the hood that have
specific entitlements allowing them to
do the work and so the configuration
profiles framework itself doesn't really
do anything here it just signals an
underlying daemon to do some extra work
now this step will begin as soon as the
device is connected to an so the second
it has a network reachable or internet
reachable IP it will it will begin to
attempt checking in this is driven by
the private CP fetch activation record
function and as I said it's implemented
by a demon called cloud configuration D
now this is a launch daemon which is Mac
OS bling go for it runs as route and and
can and can be kept constantly running
and it is signaled through Mac OS
specific IPC called X PC which if you've
if you've done any kind of iOS
development or Mac development before
you are either directly or indirectly
aware of so let's go back to our fancy
architecture diagram so we have setup
assistant which is now linked the
framework and it is ready to call the
function to retrieve the activation
record so at this point it sends a
message to cloud configuration D over X
PC to say well you should actually
implement the the fetching process and
now we'll go over exactly what happens
during that process so at this point
before we can make the request to Apple
to request to to actually retrieve our
our depth profile we need to establish a
rather peculiar type of encryption which
is internally called absinthe there's
the object in cloud configuration V that
runs this is internally called MC Tesla
configuration fetcher which is partly so
pretty well named
so this manages a five step process the
first step is to plainly retrieve a
certificate from Apple's servers now one
quick note on this absinthe is a rather
complex topic and we're not going to go
into much detail but we'll go over the
sort of basic steps here so first it
retrieves a certificate next it uses
that certificate to initialize the
internal state of absinthe this is
called this is through
function called NEC in it this
interestingly also uses various device
specific pieces of data things like the
serial number which we retrieves vio kit
but also MAC address and others
now with that data once the
initialization is complete it posts the
essentially that raw data back to Apple
via the session endpoint we're not
exactly sure what this does but it
appears that an extra handshake is
necessary to ensure the device is who it
says it is and finally with the result
of that it find it calls NEC key
establishment which completes the
initialization for the encryption now
what we believe is that absence job is
to provide a way to encode on a per
device basis and so to relatively
securely identify a device for Apple and
finally now that the encryption is ready
we're ready to make the request the last
step is to make a post including a JSON
payload to the mac profile endpoint what
this will do is take the example JSON
payload below it will encrypt it using
absinthe base64 it sign it and send it
over over HTTP so let's go back to
architecture diagram again now as you
can see cloud configuration D is
interacting with apple of this step and
it's using both TLS with the standard
root certificates installed on the
device along with the extra layer of
absinthe encryption and at this point it
basically says I am this device I am the
serial number what is my activation
record what is my profile should I be
enabling them now in response the server
provides a JSON dictionary that is
essentially a slightly differently
formatted version of the DP profile and
this includes what Jesse mentioned
things like customizing the setup
assistant but most importantly this
includes two fields that will unlock the
next step the first one is the URL of
the MDM vendors activation profile
endpoint will go into exactly what that
means but that's the main thing that
will enable the next step to occur but
most importantly it also returns the def
profiles anchor certs property meaning
for that URL that is referring to an MDM
vendor endpoint you can also provide dr
encoded certificates
to pin that next request and so so far
we're able to validate server trust and
we'll be able to continue to do so so
going back to the overall process we now
know that we mate we are a DP device or
not now what's next this step is called
profile retrieval in this step we'll be
retrieving the configuration profile
from the MDM vendor directly so we're
done talking to Apple for now so you've
ever seen this screen this is actually
the screen that indicates that your
depth profile has enrolled you into DEP
once the activation record is downloaded
this will appear it is possible to allow
users to skip this in case they don't
want enrollment but it's also possible
to make it mandatory so in this case you
can see that there's no skip button so
in this step we need to retrieve the
activation profile now what is an
activation profile that is the internal
name for ADP delivered configuration
profile so Jessie detailed config
profiles earlier those are a rather
versatile P list-based files that
contain multiple payloads that can be
installed on a device now for MDM
purposes this is a little bit more
restricted but and we'll go we'll go
into that in a sec this step will begin
immediately as soon as the user clicks
next it's driven by another function in
configuration profiles dot framework
called CP get activation profile
unsurprisingly however this one is not
implemented by cloud configuration D
this time it's implemented by a somewhat
older component of the OS called manage
client app so in fact this is actually
part of the older mcx infrastructure
that predates much of this today's
modern MDM what's also interesting is it
doesn't use X PC this time it uses MIG
which is a much older IPC mechanism on
Mac OS this is also a launch daemon
running as root though it can delegate
to per user tasks in some scenarios
however in this case there is no user on
the device yet and so almost all of the
work happening in the demons will be
happening as root the implementation
here in case you're you want to go
smoothing is is the following so what
exactly happens to in this step so we
send a request in the URL that was
provided earlier that URL is pointing to
an MDM vendor server somewhere and its
job is to return a configuration profile
and again if the anchor certificates
were provided the implementation will
actually pin using those certs and we
validated that that is the case now a
request is a very simple property list
containing up to seven keys providing
device identification so while the
device is identified with Apple already
and now has to prove who it is to the
MDM vendor and in this case it will
provide a serial number but also a UDID
OS version product name that kind of
information
now the that request payload is
interesting lis CMS signs and D are
encoded it is signed using the device's
identity certificate that's part of
Apple push service interestingly it also
includes supplementary certificates in
order for we believe to validate them
but that certificate chain includes an X
and E now expired Apple iPhone device CA
it is unclear why that is still the case
it is likely a very good story so let's
go back to the architecture and at this
point manage client is ready to talk to
MDM and it's as well this is who I am
and what is my configuration profile
which the MDM vendor can now provide in
response now in this case TLS is used
and the anchor certs will be used to pin
so we consider this step as being secure
all right so we're on to step 6
we have the configuration profile we
know we're in VP what do we do next well
config profiles now have to be installed
now as a quick reminder a configuration
profile can be installed in many ways on
Mac you can get it automatically through
DP you can actually download it and
double clicking on your desktop which is
how some small startups IT departments
might operate you can also retrieve it
you can also receive one through MDM
itself which lends to that leads to some
fun recursiveness later but now that we
have a profile we have to install it now
once it's approved the profile is stored
on the system the location is not super
relevant but what is interesting is that
it is system integrity protected what
that means in case you're unfamiliar sip
is a mechanism entry
in Mac OS Sierra I believe which allows
the protection of system folders and so
no one including root processes can
write to those folders so technically
the profile is secure now this step will
begin automatically as soon as the
profiles retrieved if your instead of
assistant now again this also maps to a
function in configuration profiles dot
framework which again is aptly named CP
install activation profile interestingly
this is implemented by yet another demon
called MDM clients which again is
relatively a recent so this one's using
XP see now it can run either as launch
daemon so meaning as root or as launch
or as a launch agent meaning as a user
depending on the context in our context
so in in our scenario it will be running
as root so a quick refresher on
configuration profiles they are these
large XML documents they can contain
multiple payloads and the installation
of a profile essentially amounts to
looping over the payloads and installing
each one one at a time now the framework
to do so has a plug-in based
architecture each payload type is
associated with a plug-in and so for
example the certificate payloads so if
you are using the configuration profile
to deliver a certificate will be
implemented or will be installed by a
certificate X PC service now X PC
services are the modern way to achieve
privilege separation on Mac OS
interestingly plugins can either be in
the main framework or in the older
manager client application and so that
can make things relatively confusing
when you're looking for traces so
typically an activation profile so a DP
delivered config profile will include if
provided by an MDM vendor three payloads
now the top one is expected comm apple
MDM and this contains these settings
necessary to enroll the device in mobile
device management with the MDM vendor
but you can also include other payloads
such as Skype to securely provide a
client certificate to the device or p.m.
in the case where you would want to
install a trusted CA certificate to the
system
keychain so if you've ever read Apple's
public documentation on the MDM protocol
in installation of an MDM payload
actually it is actually equivalent to
what Apple calls the MDM check-in
protocol now the what that essentially
does is sets up the device for receiving
commands from an MDM vendor the payload
in an MDM pail or the the MDM payload in
the configuration profile will typically
include three important properties first
there's going to be the check-in URL
that will be used in the immediate and
as well as a command polling URL which
will be used later on that also includes
the APNs topic that you can use to tell
the device via push notification to pull
the command polling URL so to install
the MDM payload in the immediate a
request is only sent to the check-in URL
this is again implemented in MDM client
what's important to remember here is MDM
payloads can actually depend on other
payloads so you might be asking yourself
now how do I pin I've just introduced
two new URLs that are MDM vendors
there's their third-party URLs that are
not Apple signed so how do I actually
pin those well the answer is is
fascinating the MDM payload is allowed
to depend on other payloads in the
configuration profile so for example the
both the check-in and server URLs have
matching properties allowing you to
refer to another payload by its unique
identifier and that essentially says the
certificate in that payload included you
should pin using basically the other
important thing that the payload has to
include is an identity certificate each
device has to have a certificate that
uniquely identifies it this is mandatory
this is another property in the MDM
payload and it's meant to refer to
another certificate typically skep will
be used though it's I don't believe
that's the only way to achieve this it
is probably the best way to achieve this
I guess one last thing on this it
I guess what's important here is that
you're essentially pinning BIID you're
not pinging by using a dr encoded list
of anchors which is a little bit easier
to do so going back to our architecture
diagram the setup assistant requests
through configuration profiles that the
profile be installed and so MDM client
receives that fun fact here it actually
loops back to itself because of the
recursive nature of profiles but we're
not including that in the diagram
because that blew my mind
and it was not enjoyable so the request
that's made here goes to the check in
URL on the MDM vendors servers but again
it is TLS but it is pins with a
certificate if you provided that ID and
so you have a way of making this secure
and so now we get to the last step at
this stage the MDM server is ready to
send a provision devices commands so
after the check-in is complete that
means that the push notification topic
is ready and the device is ready to
receive notifications once a
notification is received MDM client
again that same process will be handling
the push and will in response pull the
MDM server using the server URL property
of the payload that was passed in now
this of course makes use of the other
properties in the payload as well and so
you are going to be able to pin that
request using the matching pinning
certificate you IDs a property and then
and then the identity certificate
property I mentioned earlier will be
used here as the TLS client certificate
whence once the poling request is is
made so a little bit more visually the
process is now asynchronous so we start
bottom left with the MDM vendor who
decides to issue a command to a device
it uses APNs to send the push to the
device MDM client receives it responds
to it but not directly through the push
service by definition it does that by
contacting the command endpoint on the
MDM vendors servers and again you can
see that it is using TLS
and you are able to to pin using these
certificate IDs and so so far so good
and now we get to the fun part MDM
supports a very wide range of commands
and one of the most popular commands is
install application this is pretty
self-explanatory allows remote silent
installation of applications on the
device what's interesting here is that's
implemented not in the MDM
infrastructure on the device but it's
implemented in using the App Store's
api's so the command request contains
the URL to a manifest the manifest this
job is basically to describe the app
package it says this is the apps
identity this is the certificates
potentially and this is where you can
retrieve it the manifest is going to be
encoded as a property list as many Apple
payloads are but importantly it includes
the URL of the package to retrieve and
install now on Mac OS that has to point
to a signed distribution package which
will be a dot pkg now the way this is
implemented and we're going to go really
deep here MDM client will use the
commerce core framework this is part of
commerce kit which is the private API is
built around the App Store on Mac OS for
other oh s services this framework
contains various services each are
backed by specific launch agent or
daemon depending on the context again
store asset these job is to download and
process manifests and if they're valid
it will leveraged or download D to
download and install them now what
happens when MDM wants to install a
manifest is it uses a private function
called CK MDM process manifest at URL so
let's look exactly at how this works MDM
client while executing the install
application command will link against
commerce core doubt framework it which
will itself use X PC to trigger the
asset daemon to process the manifest and
validate that it is correct once or
after I skip this up there it will
actually first download the manifest
from the MDM vendors endpoint and then
process it for validity now it's
interesting here is there is no pinnate
and we'll get to it we'll get through
exactly what that means and again once
the once the manifest is validated it
will download the package itself and
install it what's interesting is the MDM
in the store
they're two very separate components of
the OS it's safe to say they have
different threat models the MDM client
here is not evaluating the trust of the
manifest URL and neither is the store in
fact store foundation which contains the
core classes that power commerce core do
not evaluate Trust at all this allows a
man the middle attack so as an example
in this case a state actor or someone
with considerable resources could target
a specific organization by men men in
the milling commands from the MDM vendor
now this is not limited to the DEP
scenario we've looked at this could
actually happen during later commands if
the MDM can be established they they
can't man in the middle of the commands
but they can man in the middle of the
stretching of a manifest that's right
sorry you can Manimal not commands but
the actual install application commands
and with that we'll go to our demo and
while we get set up I'll go over the
details of this we're going to simulate
a malicious isp or state actor by using
Mac OS as internet sharing as finicky as
it is we're gonna be proxying all the
traffic from the from a brand new device
using them a little proxy we're going to
simulate a compromised CA by using a
valid sir that we created from fleet
Smith CA and we're going to intercept
the request for the manifest as the
device first boots and and rather than
provide the fluid Smith fleet Smith's
agents we're going to be serving a
malicious manifest that will download a
mysterious other application and install
its package now it's important to to say
here is that developer ID certificate
requirements still apply and so packages
still have to be signed and so there is
the extra step that an attacker would
have to take of actually signing their
their malicious application though this
is still relatively easy to do it is
important to note though that Apple is
making great strides here with things
like notarized developer ID certificates
they are adding quite a bit of of checks
to make sure that malicious software is
is harder to create but this is still
strictly possible and the last thing
I'll add there is the developer
certificate that's used to sign that
distribution distribution package does
not have to be a
any type of cert that's associated with
a business entity it can be a personal
Apple Developer certificate and so for
the sake of this demo that's exactly
what we've done here all right when was
that so the device is first booting
let's see if what's the graphics adapter
gets ready I think you'll be able to see
what's gonna yeah it's worth calling up
that uh the only way that this is
possible is by really stimulating that
nation state level attack by both being
able to man in the middle the internet
traffic from the device so maybe having
the ability to see internet traffic at
the ISP level as well as having the
ability to get a certificate issued
improperly from a commercial CA both of
these things have happened sometimes in
the same country sometimes in countries
that are not friendly to you know
journalists for example so it is a
real-world kind of situation here that
we're simulating but it's worth calling
out that the only reason we can do it is
because the device at this point in the
bootstrapping process already trusts the
fleet Smith CA because it's delivered in
that initial configuration profile so
this can't be done without a lot of
resources basically
all right so let's make sure we have
some network connectivity before
proceeding here since that is pretty
important so for some reason this one's
not working well but oh that's test with
this one which we just freshly wiped so
it should work just fine demo gods are
networking yep okay this one has network
this was really here so now let's go
ahead and proceed there we go there's
the remote management screen so this
means that the device has received its
DEP profile that JSON payload so this
points it will retrieve at this point
will retrieve the configuration profile
and install it and we are actively a
man-in-the-middle egg which you cannot
see unfortunately all right all right
let's proceed
so at this point we can tell that the
looks like it worked yeah it looks like
the the payload was installed the agent
was downloaded or what it believes as
the agent was downloaded and this is
usually the part where a progress bar
would be nice but yeah it usually takes
around 30 seconds at this point yeah and
there we go and the agent has been
replaced with the calculator so and so
it is supposed to be fleet Smith's agent
software is now so our package our
malicious application in this case
created a launch D on watch agent or a
system-level launch agent that cannot be
stopped that runs the calculator
constantly and so I don't believe you
can close this I don't if we fix that
but I think we were moving back oh maybe
we folks there yeah it was it was pretty
annoying for in testing yeah so we
install this to the system-wide launch
agents folder which means any user that
logs in will have the calculator started
it's important to note though that even
though we launched this in a user
context at the time that our malicious
package is installed we do have the
ability to execute any command as root
and so this demonstrates that the device
is actually fully rooted at first boot
all right let's go back to the slides
well the good news is that there is a
mitigation already in existence for this
problem a new command was introduced
recently called install enterprise
application this includes new properties
that allow you to control the trust of
of that URL for the manifest and so this
is available in Mac OS 10 thirteen point
six that's also ten fourteen what's also
important to note here is that there's a
there's a time delay for new hardware to
support the fix as we've just
demonstrated what's also important here
is that this requires the MDM vendor to
do its part the new command has to be
adopted before the mitigation is fully
ready now how does this actually work
there is now an extra property manifest
URL pinning certs this is a again a list
of D are encoded an anchor trust that
will be used when evaluating the trust
of the manifest URL this can ensure you
can also ensure that revocation checks
are performed which is quite nice under
the hood what happens well the ck MDM
process manifest at URL function which
used to only take a URL as a parameter
and another thing that was more of a
flag now actually takes in a dictionary
that dictionary contains private keys
that map to the properties in the new
command and also most importantly store
foundations core objects now have the
ability to evaluate trust which was
relief to see they actually if you're
curious this actually uses an external
connections standard elegant methods for
authentication challenges so let's move
on to some takeaways here number number
one this is a really complex system on
Mac OS with a lot of moving parts some
will have different threat models and
what that means as vulnerabilities or
bugs can appear at the intersections or
at the borders between those guessing
yeah so in addition to these takeaways
here we through our research came up
with a bunch of recommendations for
Apple here on kind of how to improve the
whole security story for MDM and DEP and
so here's that list of recommendations
the first is that we'd really love to
see the entire security model for DEP
and MDM documented
if anyone's read the incredible iOS
security guide white paper that they
published that's really what kind of the
along the same lines of what we're
thinking here so we know they have the
ability to produce something of a really
high caliber and and we'd love to see
the same thing including a description
of what the role of that I've Apple
iPhone device CA is the next is that
we'd really like them to be more
aggressive in a technical enforcement in
the OS that requires pinning for all of
these things right now all this is
really optional and up to the MDM vendor
which given how early in the in the
process it is and and kind of really
scary implications if if an attacker was
to really package up this exploit and
use it at scale we really think that it
would be a great a great improvement if
this was required the next is that we
really think any configuration profile
that contains sensitive data so that
could be like a TLS private key for
example or it could be the Wi-Fi payload
that includes the plaintext password for
your corporate Wi-Fi network right I'm
any payload that includes sensitive data
like that we think the OS should enforce
that it's both signed and encrypted this
is also optional but it's it's really
not very heavily utilized in in the wild
by by various products fleet psmith does
do both of these things but we'd really
like to see this required as well and
you might be thinking well isn't this
already TLS protected and the answer is
yes but if you look at the past few
years you've had heartbleed you've had
poodle you've had Apple's own go to fail
bug and so given the history of TLS
phones we really think that this is a
great defense-in-depth measure to
require that these sensitive payloads
are are protected and in fact Apple's
own documentation says on page 19 of the
config configuration profile reference
they give this guidance that because the
password string is stored in the clear
and the profile it's recommended that it
be encrypted for the device and you can
get really powerful here and encrypt
these payloads on a per device basis
because this
server can safely escrow the public key
which is part of the certificate right
even even though it doesn't have the
private key I can use that public key to
encrypt these payloads and so that's
that's something that should be
relatively straightforward for for
people to implement the last one is that
we'd really like to see that DEP cloud
service API contain just a bit more
information it already contains
information on like the model the OS
family so it'll tell you if the device
has Mac OS or iOS for example but we'd
like to see two additional fields in
that API one with the OS version and one
with the OS build number and the reason
we want that is so that we can surface
that information in product so that if
there is a Vaughn on a version of Mac OS
that's shipped from the factory at least
you have the information at your
corporation from you know your IT team
your security team had at least has the
information to know maybe we shouldn't
rely on you know on that OS version if
we're shipping it to you know a country
that's might be doing some of these
things that we've talked about right all
right and then for MDM vendors we we
wanted to share what we think of as sort
of like a security checklist to make
sure that you're doing all the right
things and we tried to make it kind of
really concise and targeted on just the
highest impact things so painting at
every step of the process super
important the anchor certs
in the DEP profile so that the first
time the device calls in to the MDM
server that's pinned that's step 4 step
five which is pinning the actual MDM
URLs for ongoing polling for new
commands both for the check-in URL and
the commands URL and then finally in
step seven pinning using the new install
enterprise application command so right
now that is also optional install
application is not deprecated it's still
available Apple has given strong
guidance at WWDC when they announced the
install enterprise application command
that they'd love to see vendors move to
this but they didn't give a hard time
line and it is still optional as well
and then finally this is the one
I think is the most subtle a lot of
vendors sort of supplement the
functionality of MDM with an agent
binary that they've written themselves
we do the same it's really important
that the vendor is pinning inside their
own binary as well so we we do the same
thing we pin our root CI within our
binary to make sure those communications
also can't be man-in-the-middle and
finally I skip it is really the best
option for getting these device identity
certificates generated and the reason
scape is far superior to alternatives is
because the private key is generated on
the device and never leaves the device
the server never sees it whereas the
only other alternative is the server
actually generating all those client
private keys and distributing them down
to the client and I think at least one
vendor does this currently all right
next is the configuration profiles we
already touched on this we really think
that they should all be signed and
encrypted especially if they contain
sensitive data and finally this is more
about the cloud production environment
or even on crime as well but any
sensitive data that's being input into
the product like that Wi-Fi password
right a private key all of that should
really be encrypted at rest in the
database within the MDM product as well
all right
disclosure timeline we first disclosed
this to Apple on April 28th it was
acknowledged April 2nd the new command
was announced in that session at WWDC
titled what's new in managing Apple
devices on June 7th but Apple of course
did not share the sort of background
history there that's obviously what we
were sharing today although they did
strongly urge vendors to move to the new
command as soon as possible the MDM
protocol reference documentation was
updated to include the installed
enterprise application command on July
5th and the actual ability to use that
command with devices was introduced with
Mac OS 10 13 6 which was released on
July 9th
so this concludes our presentation but
we have a few acknowledgments we want to
make before before we're done yeah
person first and foremost we really want
to thank my co-founder Stevie her Xu who
did a really incredible job on all of
the early research for this talk like a
straight week of you know eight to ten
hours a day the next set of people we
really want to thank is Victor papeon
Mike and Jesse who have contributed just
a lot to the Mac kind of security
community as well as last but not least
of course they've been really great
actually throughout the whole process
and obviously you know even though we
found this vulnerability here both max
and I just have a ton of respect for
their security engineering team and what
they're doing to improve the platform
security for both iOS and Mac OS and we
just want to say keep up the good work
all right and with that we are done I
think we may have time for one question
but thank you so much for coming
[Applause]