nothing better than having some IT
problems to start with but that
shouldn't hold us back from anything
here welcome what's happening right now
in data science for cybersecurity is a
little concerning and in some cases even
dangerous we're giving our attackers the
over hand in some cases which it's not
really what we want to do we're gonna
explore the next 50 minutes the topic of
artificial intelligence machine learning
a little bit and talk about why
algorithms can be dangerous we're going
to explore a number of topics during the
talk first of all we're going to look at
why we don't have artificial
intelligence yet algorithms are getting
smarter but experts are more important
than the algorithms stop throwing
algorithms on the wall they're not
spaghetti we know I don't have to just
throw something I want to see what
sticks and see if we can't find
anomalies I can take any algorithm find
something interesting in your data set
but understanding what we're finding and
what the whitespace is around that is
very important understand your data
I say it again understand your data and
your algorithms before you do anything
with it
invest in people who know security hire
good experts if you can find them and
all of you probably qualify for that
build systems that absorb expert
knowledge don't just run an algorithm
they randomly post something up but
figure out how to put expert knowledge
into these systems think out of the box
history is often it was really bad for
innovation in a lot of cases I love to
delay on this thing my name is Rafael
Marti I've spent the last 20 years in
cybersecurity looking at data and how we
can apply interesting algorithms to the
data to find insights I started back in
a day at IBM Research where we need a
lot of anomaly detection research on
firewall data and intrusion detection
data I then moved on to arcsight where I
started the solution and content teams
where we continued some of that work on
how do you make that data actionable I'm
going over to Splunk continue to work
and sort of help Splunk setting foot in
the security market how can we solve
security use cases I started a couple
big data companies where we applied data
science and big data to the security
problems and currently I'm running
corporate strategy at force point where
we're focusing on understanding the
behavior of identities of users of
devices to see what's anomalous and we
are trying to understand how the data
moves around in your network to also
find when something is going bad we're
doing this across our portfolio of
products on firewalls DLP Caspi and
insider threat and so on we call this
whole thing the human point system I'm
gonna look at three areas in this talk
first we're gonna look at a brief
definition of what machine learning and
artificial intelligence really is we're
gonna look at the dangers of algorithms
and why just applying some of these
algorithms can actually be very
dangerous and then we're gonna step
through an example together so starting
with some brief definitions I don't want
to bore you if these things these are
not academic definitions but I want to
have some kind of a working definition
for this stuff let me talk about machine
learning there we go mmm-hmm machine
learning is sort of a way an algorithmic
way to describe data if you want there's
two subcategories that you might have
heard of they're supervised and then
there's unsupervised machine learning in
the supervised case we're basically
giving a system a lot of training data
data where we already know the outcome
of what it is if it's good or bad or if
we classify it in a certain way and the
system learns the characteristics of
those data sets in the unsupervised case
we are kind of giving the system some
kind of optimization to soul think of
clustering for example where we're
trying to extract the inherent okay
we're seeing we're trying to extract the
inherent structure of the data to see
how the data is is sort of made
and I have a couple examples in a second
where we're gonna visualize some of
these and get a little bit of feeling
for this what you've probably have heard
of us is deep learning
everybody talks about deep learning as
the solution to all of our problems
right it's gonna help us with all kinds
of different things and it's also the
promises that it should solve a whole
lot of security problems for us well it
actually has helped us in a lot of areas
of security to advance incredibly I will
show you some examples of that but in
the end deep learning is nothing else
than a little more sophisticated machine
learning algorithm it's not that much
newer than what we had before it has a
couple of very interesting advantages
one it eliminates that of the feature
engineering step what that means is when
you're taking the data and you put it in
the outdoor into the algorithm you have
to sort of extract certain
characteristics from the data that you
feed into the algorithm and that step
can be eliminated in certain cases one
big problem though with myth machine
learning is that it has an explain
ability problem what that means is I
can't look into that black box I
basically put data in this box learn
something and output something I can't
look into there to explain what it just
learned and a lot of cases that's very
concerning to me right do I really trust
a black box to make the right decision
on all kinds of different areas then we
have data mining data mining is
basically a way to explore data data
visualization is often put into the data
mining environment and we're gonna show
you a couple of visualizations and then
we have the great topic of artificial
intelligence we do not have artificial
general intelligence yet like what we
would think of as an intelligent system
that just learned something and comes up
with new knowledge we don't have it in
any field we have smart algorithms I was
trying to define at some point how would
how did we find that for cyber security
to have real artificial intelligent
intelligence and when I came up as I
said you know what if it's a program
that doesn't simply classify or compute
model parameters sort of taking out the
machine learning cases but it actually
comes up with novel knowledge something
I haven't known yet before that a
security expert finds interesting
you need to apply somehow it can't just
be any novel knowledge it's like oh da
yeah okay it needs to be sort of
security relevant and we really don't
have anything like that yet
whatever the vendors are claiming in
their marketing they probably refer to
an to analytics as artificial
intelligence right colloquially people
use artificial intelligence to mean
analytics and that's also I'm gonna
probably in my talk say artificial
intelligence a couple of times but what
I really mean is is analytics where are
we today with artificial intelligence in
general we've all heard and seen a bunch
of smart algorithms that saw certain
problems right it it got really really
good at certain games we have now
computers that are way better than
people at playing chess right deep blue
being the example there then we had
alphago from that from google that beat
the NGO world master world champion go
with an incredibly complex game it was
very complicated to build that system we
have in drug discovery there's a lot of
artificial intelligence or advanced
analytics being used and then obviously
you all have used some kind of speech
recognition be that Siri or something
where artificial intelligence or this
kind of analytics really has made a
difference now if we looked in security
where we had or where we are using
machine learning I was trying to
inventory a little bit where are we
using supervised and unsupervised
machine learning today and where it's
actually working and I didn't find that
many examples actually there's
definitely when we talk about malware
classification of binary classification
into malware and good where there's
immense advances we have made in
cybersecurity and in that whole field
there was a talk earlier today by Josh
Sachs from Sophos who was talking about
deep learning and he is explaining sort
of how we really made incredible leaps
in detecting malware better today with
deep learning than we were able to do
that ever before in spam identification
we have made great advances and then
there's a very interesting project ml
sec from alex pinto where they looked at
firewall data to understand where there
are bad areas in the internet bad IP
spaces and the unsupervised side there's
all kinds of interesting examples
there's the NS analytics
obviously on threat intelligence when
trying to duplicate things when you're
trying to prioritize how your see feeds
and things like that there's some very
interesting work that we want to get
into a little bit in the end on sort of
the tier one analyst automation so that
the whole triage in your sock for
example there's some very interesting
stuff going on there all right so that's
a little bit of ml and a I in a very
short terms let's look at why it is
actually kind of dangerous to apply some
of these algorithms so this is if you're
looking out there in in the news in the
literature you find a lot of examples
where artificial intelligence has failed
or has produced some not so good
examples or good outcomes this is stuff
that you find in the internet when you
google this you can read those yourself
one example was pretty interesting the
Department of Defense had a project
where they were trying to take images
and understand that there was a tank in
the image or whether it was just a field
and the tanks were often sort of
camouflage it was not that easy to find
them so they took a whole bunch it took
like a hundred images to train this
system and to understand where there's a
tank either or not and then they applied
it in the field and the system did
horrible because what happened is they
noticed that all the images they fed the
system that had a tank in it were taken
in cloudy environments it was kind of a
dark picture and all the images where
there was no tank and it was just an
open field we're taking in sunshine to
the picture was much brighter
so the algorithm basically just learned
the brightness after of the image to
classify there's a tank in there or not
and that was obviously quite a fun
failure so this is sort of the money
slide why is it dangerous to just apply
algorithms two years data and try to
find attackers or bad things in there
there's a number of things to start with
it's the data itself the algorithms
often make assumptions about the data we
need to have clean data first who in
here has looked at NetFlow data ever in
their lives
whoa I'm sorry for you guys there's a
bunch of stuff in there that it will
find that's kind of tricky to clean up
often the source and the destination are
gonna be turned around in your records
you have to clean that up I'll show you
a visualization in a second where that
wasn't done a lot of people don't even
know that and they just do some analysis
and you get all kinds of wrong results
doing that often the algorithms they
assume a certain type of data normally
distributed data for example categorical
data versus numerical data we have to be
aware of that to understand how to apply
the algorithm to the data often the
algorithms don't deal well with outliers
so often we have to eliminate them first
because they really gonna skew our data
machine learning assumes enough
especially supervised assumes enough
training data that we can actually train
the system well enough right let's in
statistics you learn that what's the
what's the sample size you have to take
to make it relevant right often we need
context to data just an IP address often
doesn't tell me much I want to know the
host name at a roll of the machine
things like that we have to augment our
data and then there's me more technical
right in the the algorithms they often
are pretty much all the time require
that all the data is normalized in the
same way so if you scale something you
have to scale all the inputs because
otherwise one is going to dominate so
that's on the data side there's all
kinds of bias in the data it's also what
data sets are you choosing to train your
system do you have a historic data set
well where did you get it from does it
really have all the artifacts in there
that you're trying to train the system
on how do you know it's way too easy
today to run a machine learning
algorithm on your data you can go online
download tensorflow or torch or
something around it on your data and you
get an output in this look here's all
your anomalies but do you know what the
algorithm did do you know that their
parameters in that you might have to
tweak that if you don't change them you
might get completely wrong results and
there's too many people doing that and
I'll show you an example of how that
looks in the end and then algorithms
don't know anything about your domain
they don't know about security they
don't know that the layer 4 protocols
are all slightly behaving differently
and you probably want to train each
individual protocol on its own because
very different characteristics how do
you define meaningful distance functions
when you're doing clustering I'm talking
about in a second again I'll show an
example and then part of the things that
drives me absolutely nuts is when people
are using port numbers as integers
they're saying well 80 is one away from
81 - away from 80 - so they're very
close together and then 443 is really
far away right encrypted HTTP and then
8080 B's job visit often proxying is
even further away they were all almost
right next to each other right they're
closer together than 80 and 81 so you
have to take that into account it's not
a numerical value anymore if you can
just plug into an algorithm and that
gives you some really strange results if
you're looking at the data and the
biases in your data there's a bunch of
other things I have an interesting
example here where if you go to Google
Translate and translate this very simple
sentence here in the into Hungarian and
then back from Hungarian - into English
there is a biasing here
it starts with he is a nurse she's a
doctor if you translate it back you get
exactly the other gender back right she
is a nurse and he's a doctor so there's
all kinds of bias in our in our
algorithms in our systems that we don't
even know about right if you just
translated that and we didn't know where
it actually was translated from we
wouldn't know what's going on
again it matters a lot on how what the
data set is that you're using the train
these systems where do you take it from
you have enough historic data you have
everything covered you need to know are
the collection errors in there how do
you know right there might be missing
data right maybe you have a Mis
configuration somewhere but one host
doesn't generate certain event IEDs and
you're still learning on that data set
and suddenly this machine is really
skewing your results what's the context
you operated this whole thing in right
and if you take me from one customer
environment to another what are the
differences there are they homogeneous
are they the same do I have to take that
into account how do I take that into
account
another example FTP right it's generally
not considered or is generally
considered insecure and often you would
say you should use I have to pee anymore
that's old and
not encrypted and that's a policy
violation it's bad in certain
environments it's absolutely needed we
still have mainframes where everyday be
downloading FTP to get data and
transactions onto other systems and
there's just no other way to do it right
now right it's not an anomaly there it's
actually normal to use that and then
finally how do you know whether you can
trust some of your data inputs intrusion
detection systems right how do you know
the convey the confidence you can have
in a certain event that's generated how
do you know it's not a false positive
there's a very interesting example that
I show I used to teach a class here at
black in the last few years on data
analytics and data visualization I would
show this visualization between two
nodes it had sort of two events
generated between two machines one was a
UDP bomb and the other one was some i ke
some-some alert that came up and I was
asking the students what's going on here
and they're like oh there's like a DDoS
attack over UDP happening right this UDP
bomb thing and then there's the I ke key
exchange going on and I like well I can
read to write like that's just like
seeing what's what's written there but
really what's happening it's just a VPN
login there's an i ke exchange there's a
lot of UDP traffic happening the IDS has
a certain threshold set that if it sees
a certain amount of UDP it calls it a
UDP bomb so you have to interpret these
things in the right way you can't just
read them off and believe in it and
that's we either domain knowledge I try
to put together a couple of facts or a
couple of sort of guidelines and when
you should not be using machine learning
for your data if you look at a very
simple sort of data flow right you have
beta on the top left you put that into
this machine learning black box and then
out comes some kind of detections and
some classifications I'm output from
these a lot from this algorithm often
you also add expert knowledge into the
into the machine learning algorithm
right you want to teach the system what
features to extract exactly or how to
interpret certain things now don't use
machine learning if you don't have
enough quality labeled data right if you
don't have enough test data
don't use machine learning or supervised
machine learning make sure your data is
clean it's normalized in the right way
look at your time stamps do you have
time zones in there make sure your
account for that right when you're
collecting from different parts of the
world these things happen at the
different times even though they say the
same thing you have ten different time
zones make sure that you have enough
understanding of the data to engineer
meaningful features if you're using deep
learning to classify files into malware
and good wear or benign wear whatever
you call those if you just take the byte
stream like you took an image to do
image classification of deep learning if
you just take the byte stream that thing
is physical or learn individual byte
features but a file there is a reason
why two bytes are next to each other or
three bytes or four you have to take
engrams in there and feed into the
algorithm right you can't just blindly
take individual bytes so you have to
know that that that actually matters
maybe you want to engineer other
features and say oh there's a data
segment and there's a code segment and
there's all these other things in there
that you can use as very high signal
features for your argument that's very
neither domain knowledge and then make
sure that your data is not prone to
adversarial input so that someone
couldn't cheat or inject false data or
or misleading data somehow into your
algorithm in the middle side make sure
that you have well-trained domain
experts send them to the classes here
send them to other classes make sure
that they're you're exchanging knowledge
with your peers if you're in the
financial industry I don't think you're
gonna get a huge competitive advantage
by having a little more knowledge on the
security side than any other financial
service talk to each other and there's
all these FSI stacks like the financial
services information sharing group
there's for all kinds of different areas
for the for retail for automotive
there's these interest groups
participate there talk to each other
help each other out we're one community
right we help each other out doing these
kinds of things and then make sure that
you have someone data scientists that
understand security so you need to find
these unicorns out there that understand
both domains security and data science
it's incredibly hard to find those and
those who tried to hire these people
it's not easy but we need people that
understand both or at least put teams
together that had both sort of domains
together but you have two statisticians
data scientists really know the data or
the algorithms and then statistics and
then you have the domain experts that
can help putting the expert knowledge in
there if you want to really make sure
that you can verify your output and you
can interpret what the system learned
machine learning it might not be the
right thing because we have this black
box if you're doing deep learning in the
end what you end up with is a bunch of
nodes and weights on those nodes
what's the knowledge that this thing
learned I don't know there's just some
numbers in there right I can't extract
the knowledge of what it actually
learned I can't extract the rule there's
a lot of research going on right now and
people trying to figure out how do we
solve that problem but I'll show you a
different approach then sort of
circumvent said to start with so here's
a very quick example I didn't I stole
this from a paper that I found where
machine learning is pretty prone to
adversarial input right on the left hand
side what you see is it's the regular
image of this Panda the algorithm looked
at it and said with about a 60%
confidence this is a panda speed okay
right but at least we identify the Panda
then these researchers were adding some
random noise the image on the right
contains that noise the human eye we
can't see that at least I can it's still
it's still a panda but now the algorithm
is absolutely sure this is a Gibbon all
right there's no doubt it's like ninety
nine point three percent confidence so
these are the problems that we're
dealing if imagine is a stop sign and an
autonomous car it's trying to read that
stop car it's a stop sign
okay give you a little bit of an
overview of what's machine learning
artificial intelligence the dangers of
the algorithms let's go through an
example and kind of drive some of these
points home
the tasks I'm gonna give you are we
going to solve together is we got to
look at network communications we're
gonna take some net flows right for
those we've done that before we're going
to find this familiar territory here and
what we want to do is very simple we're
gonna try to find anomalies or attacks
in here okay how do we do that well deep
learning everybody says this thing is
solving all of our problems why don't we
try that supervised machine learning
well deep learning has a few very
interesting promises it does the auto
featuring extraction thing right we
don't have to do crazy feature
engineering it promises us it has a
pretty high accuracy for detection in
general so that's all great things okay
do we have all the right requirements
math do we have a lot of data we do
right we can collect a lot on that like
net flow I can send you tons of net flow
if you want some but here are some
caveats a single record in a net flow is
just a session between two machines that
doesn't necessarily tell me enough
whether this is good or bad all right
someone connecting to a website that
could be good or bad so I don't have
enough context in a single record well
what we could do is we probably could do
some pre-processing where we put certain
sessions together and extract some
interesting features possibly right we
can still work around that we probably
don't have enough information in these
flows we just have IP addresses we don't
know what these machines are and without
that context it's pretty hard to save it
or something is anomalous if I know that
this server is a DNS server and it
serves up websites it's probably not
very smart I often don't co-locate my
DNS and HTTP over web servers right so
if I know that I can make a lot of
better statements we could import some
contacts right we could add some
information from our asset management
systems and then augment that kind of
information can still do that now the
big problem is we don't have labeled
data we don't have a training set where
we know for these records they're good
these records it's bad people have tried
all kinds of things there's all kinds of
synthetic data sets out there that
people have been trying to build for for
years and years and years every single
dataset at some point some researcher
came along and said oh you know what you
can do all kinds of crazy learning on
this data and come up with very
complicated rules and things like that
but guess what if you look at the TTL if
it's below 20 it's an attack if it's
above 20 it's it's normal so they found
one artifact in the data that's giving
it away so building the perfect data set
is almost impossible and how do you
build a data set that's sort of generic
enough to cover all the different
scenarios that you want to have it run
in in production in the end okay so I
guess steep learning is not the answer
for everything
well maybe unsupervised learning is
going to be helpful basically what we
want to do is we want to exploit sort of
the inherent structure in the data to
find anomalies into tax right so
something like on the right hand side
where I take this data and it creates
these wickedly lines and I see oh this
is normal and this is abnormal how would
we do that
well here's this little process that
we're gonna walk through quickly we got
to clean the data we've got an engineer
to distance functions we've got to
figure out the right algorithm there's
multiple clustering algorithms out there
we gotta apply the right parameters to
the algorithm I'll show you what happens
if you don't and then you have to
interpret the data so let's get into
that this here is a visualization it's
called a parallel coordinate where you
see every vertical line in here is one
field in your data so this the first
part there is a source IP address then
the second is the time then you have the
source port source port starts from 0 on
top going down to 65535 then you have
your destination port and one event the
one flow is one line going from left to
right all right so it starts with some
IP some port or at certain time port
port so you have one line is one record
here's a bunch of records visualized now
this is from a challenge the the vast
community the visual analytics community
puts out a challenge every year and for
a number of years they put out Network
flows and asked researchers or everybody
to come up or to describe the data set I
dealing visually
so these researchers go off build all
kinds of visualization tools and
detectors and things like that to
understand what's going on in the data
this was one of the visualizations that
I don't want to bash this paper but and
pretty much every single submission that
I reviewed had this problem they didn't
clean the data well how can we tell well
maybe this is a little bit of a telling
Stein if we're here we go that
destination port the source port there
of 80 is probably the destination port
if you actually follow the lines you
will see that the destination port for
this guy is all kinds of high port
numbers on the bottom there so it's
probably exactly one of those cases
where the source and destinations are
turned around so we have to clean the
data up if we look at the the next part
in here there's a port 70,000 okay I
guess you get it and then if you look at
all these source ports they really are
these destination ports here if I were
do analyze this data set I would find
all kinds of anomalies and say oh my god
that's traffic to these high port
numbers is probably some malware active
here we got to look at this well again
this is probably exactly the the
counterpart of that port 80 there and we
have to turn that stuff around now the
challenge is I tried to actually clean
this data set up at some point and I did
a whole blog post about it it's really
hard to figure out when you have to turn
something around if you just have the
raw network flows because you don't see
which side sent the syn packet and which
sent a syn ACK and and so on it's a
really hard problem but we have to try
to account for that if we don't we find
all kinds of anomalies in this data set
and believe me these researchers found
all kinds of stuff
among them attacks on port 0 which is
ICMP traffic right but these guys didn't
know they didn't have the domain
knowledge all right assume you have
clean data we're gonna now engineer
distance functions we have to define if
I have two records how far away from
each other do we want to plot them on
the graph are they going to be really
far from each other I don't need close
to each other so
they basically find that the similarity
between the different records well you
need to have domain-specific similarity
functions you have to take into account
this is a URL for example it's not just
a random string there's structure in
there if you have a hostname there's
different parts to it right if you have
port numbers again they are not just
integers treat them as categorical data
beam them together similar things need
to go together and then user names are
probably just categorical don't don't
treat them as strings but per se on the
right hand side I try to it's a very
simple maybe a little convoluted example
here but it hopefully shows that if
you're clustering is traffic and on the
x-axis you have the port number and the
y-axis you have the number of bytes
transmitted well just because that is
port 443 up there it doesn't mean it's
an outlier just because it's the top
right there I couldn't use the distance
doesn't make any sense in here right I
can use this graph for making other
statements that I see a lot more traffic
being transmitted on HTTP then on the
other protocols but I can't really say
anything about clusters per se so then
the next challenge once we have good
distance functions and you should do
some research on that it's actually not
that easy but quite interesting we have
to figure out what clustering algorithm
I use there's a number of them out there
this is not all of this just a few on
the right hand side you see a little bit
of a visualization on different
clustering algorithms are the color in
here and some of them are doing much
better
to actually match the structure of the
data versus others that you see there's
a sort of disagreement between the
structure itself and the coloring
probably pretty apparent but when you're
choosing the algorithms you have to
figure out what's the dimensionality of
your data often a pretty high
dimensional data a lot of columns in my
data and a lot of algorithms don't deal
well with that so I have to do something
like PCA is a like basically reducing
the number of columns but I'm losing
information that way so is that still
gonna work then the shape of your data
matters as well because certain
algorithms they get a little upset when
you're giving them certain shapes of
data they might find them at a local
minimum where they're gonna get stuck
and things like that so you have to take
that into account often you have to know
how the algorithm intrinsically really
works t-sne appear is a very interesting
algorithm that's basically a
multi-dimensional
Jochen from high dimensional spaces into
a two-dimensional space
super-interesting creates incredible
results these are actually t-sne
visualizations here but you have to know
the intrinsic workings of this thing to
really get the right results and then
often it's also do these algorithms
converge to something and what's the
speed of running this stuff I don't have
all year to run an algorithm my huge
data set to come up with a result
sometimes I want to do this in almost
real time to classify or cluster things
so that's uh that's where you see that
you probably want to have a data
scientist on staff so here I want to
show you what happens if you don't
understand your algorithm what you see
here is is the same data set that I put
into this t-sne algorithm and the first
on the left-hand side is I just
downloaded the library ran the data on
it and visualize the output and what you
see here these are just machines on the
network the individual dots if you look
at this and I would ask you do you see
any specific clusters in here or like
just the data separate in certain ways
you could say maybe right there's a
bottom part there it's maybe something
that's a different and you could come up
with maybe some clusters in here but
it's not really clear but then you go
energy discover oh there's these two
parameters in this in this algorithm
there's an epsilon and the perplexity
you like let's see what happens if I
change it so I changed the epsilon to 19
right let's crank it up and run the
algorithm again and poof I have three
clusters in here it's pretty nice
separation right I have three different
types of machines it seems and I my god
that's great maybe we can tune the other
parameter to maybe we see even better
results so you start tuning these things
and turning these knobs and on the right
hand side completely random so if we
actually put some ground truths on top
of this I'm not sure if you can see the
colors here if you advance it yeah so
here this is the ground truth right I'm
overlaying what I already know about
these machines there's two data there's
two classes in here of data there's the
blues and the orange ones in the middle
one we thought we had three clusters but
really the data set itself only has two
so you see what happens if you don't
understand what the algorithm does and
if
you don't understand how the two nice
parameters here's another example that
just probably drives the point home
quite a bit if we highlight sort of the
the outlier there on the bottom right
where you can see we think that that
bottom right little node is actually
part of the of the cluster on the right
hand side there right and that can get
really dangerous when you're starting to
make decisions based on this you don't
know you don't know those colors up
front that's what you're trying to
discover I'm giving it as as a as a sort
of showing what's going on here all
right now we can assume you had clean
data we had the right algorithm we had
the right parameter set but then you get
an output and you have to interpret this
stuff well what are these clusters this
is a web server an email server a DNS
server I don't know I have to somehow be
I need to be able to introspect this
stuff and look into it how do you do
that are these Fosters good or bad I
don't know what's anomalous in here
maybe I can do something over time to
find anomalies and how do you find
compromise machines in here I did it's
not that easy okay so that was the the
an supervise case now I want to take you
through a last example where instead of
using sort of traditional what
supervisor unsupervised learning that
everybody's talking about I want to
bring back a very old concept of belief
networks people have used them two
decades ago kind of dismissed them
they're like it's too complicated and
it's not really gonna cover everything
this and that but I think there's
actually some really really interesting
stuff we can do with them and I see some
startups that are starting to use these
belief networks very very very in very
interesting ways and they get really
good results what we're going to play
with here is ability Bayesian belief
Network what that means is on the right
hand side you see the hood a textbook
example assume you have a lawn and I
want to know the question I want to ask
in the end is well what's the
probability that it's raining given that
my lawn is wet and what I can observe is
whether the lawn is wet I could go and
test it I
an observer that the sprinkler is
running and I can observe whether it's
raining or not right and what I do is I
basically come up with this look graph
this is a dependency graph and say okay
I can go out and look at historic data
what's the likelihood that it's raining
and I can say well 20% of the time it
rains in this area I can then look at
the likelihood that the sprinkler is on
and the sprinkler it's kind of dependent
no matter it's raining right I'm not
gonna run the sprinkler when it's
raining so that's a very low probability
but when it's not raining I actually
turn the sprinkler on so I capture these
probabilities as well and then I can go
and measure when the lawn is wet and
based on whether the sprinkler is on and
whether and whether it's raining so I
built these sort of joint probability
tables and by doing that I come up with
these different probabilities in this
network and then what I can use it I can
use Bayes theorem just too much math to
go through here but it's this formula on
the bottom there for those who are
interested where I can then compute the
probability that given that it's raining
that my lawn is actually wet and what
we're going to do is we're going to
apply this to network security now all
right well let's go through this example
here what we want to do I want to detect
what a device on my network is
compromised and to do that I'm gonna
define behaviors that I can observe that
are reducing my uncertainty of whether
my device is compromised
so things I can observe some facts I can
observe I listed a bunch of them this is
a toy example don't try this at home
maybe expand on this and come out with a
good model for it but so I can observe
all kinds of things right I can see if I
have encrypted port 23 traffic why would
that be weird
well encrypt the DNS telnet that's often
an interesting sign right talent is
generally plaintext so that might be a
sign that the machine is compromised
it's not always the case right some
people run encrypted stuff over 23 and
it's totally fine there's all kinds of
other factors I can look at then what we
do one of the problems is that if we now
went ahead and Bill
this crazy belief network and started
doing all these probabilities across all
these different facts even explode very
quickly it's an exponential problem I
have to compute all kinds of stuff and
it's not gonna help us much so the trick
here is we're gonna introduce grouping
nodes these nodes are basically other
probabilistic nodes other observations
but they group together these different
themes here a little bit let's look at
the bottom left one that the host is
tunneling data well I can define all
kinds of observable factors to define to
determine whether something is tunneling
data in this case I just looked at very
simple thing in protocol mismatch or
maybe app that encrypted traffic on port
23 they could be indicators for
tunneling traffic there's all kinds of
other stuff right you can look at DNS
things and ICP stuff baba keeping it
simpler does this model you can extend
out much more just to give give you an
idea of how this works so you group
these things and then what you do is you
introduce the dependencies between these
things the white arrows and the green
arrows here the obvious ones right like
obviously the device is compromised it's
gonna depend on whether I see a normal
it's Network behavior tunneling data I
have a hit on my threat intelligence
feeds and so on and then the individual
observations can lead into these other
grouping nodes but then I can also have
dependencies between the different
observations right some of these are not
independent if I see that machine shows
up with a new operating system that
could actually be because the machine
was just updated to a new operating
system right so these two things kind of
have something to do with each other
so once you have this whole graph built
while you do then is you go and you talk
to experts I've taken a little extra
excerpt from the bottom left of the
graph I'm just focusing on this for the
example here I have these three nodes
right I can ask an expert what's the
probability that I have a protocol
mismatch on the network and they give me
is it so it's very low it's like 0.01
percent and I asked them for all these
no to get these expert knowledge then I
continue and I can do conditional
probabilities I can say well you know
because these things are related I could
say what's the probability that I have
tunneling going on all right if I have
Dean encrypted traffic what's the
probability I have tunneling going on
and there's some in this formula I see
some of the terms I already discovered I
already asked my expert and there's new
ones I can add more knowledge to and
then I can go and do the joint
probabilities over this stuff and I get
even more information and you see what
we're doing is we're asking experts
pretty interesting questions that they
can answer in general they don't answer
we're not answering them with historic
data and so then when we when we're
looking at it's a device compromised
what we take into the joint conditional
probabilities over all of this stuff and
you're golden so I hope what does that
mean now so we built this network with
the probabilities right by a net from an
expert and then we observe what's going
on out there so we might see that we
have a new OS showing up the machine
didn't get updated in its open port 53
and I have a probability that this
machine is having an anomalous traffic
of 0.3 so 30 percent secure sure that
it's enormous traffic by these new
inputs that Jack's it up to 0.5 right
the network updates itself and then
going down to 0.1 and then if you
continue the computation be oh god we
get this to 70 percent compromise now so
these are network updates itself with
these formulas basically now to make
this even more solid what we're doing we
can now ask the experts all kinds of
questions across this whole network that
we have and these questions actually
make sense to it what's the probability
that device is compromised and I have a
highly suspicious network behavior and
nothing on the threat intelligence field
as an expert you can answer that you
could say we know that's kind of weird
it's puppy doesn't show that 30 percent
of the time it doesn't help now you do
this with 100 experts a thousand
questions and you got a pretty solid
Network that explains what's going on
now the benefit of this stuff is it's
pretty it's an iterative process you
have to keep doing this right we can
actually verify what this thing learned
I can read out the probabilities and see
exactly what this thing learned I can
extract the knowledge from it and you
can I guess answer all kinds of
questions I can for example answer
what's the most determining factor for
understanding whether device is
compromised or not which of the
different inputs do I have to look at
and do I have to date
for that if I don't have the data I
might invest in getting that data
there's some disadvantages and it's kind
of hard to do sometimes I also want to
big shout out to my friend Chris that
responds after to help me building this
whole example and then like entertaining
all of my questions so thank you Chris
alright so in summary what did we just
look at start with use cases not
algorithms the algorithms are secondary
once you have the Hughes case defined
you will find out whether algorithms to
use often it's simple statistics I just
talked an all-kill a colleague of mine
and we just talked about oh my god
everybody using machine learning for
finding anomalies it's it's so simple to
just write some rules and use simple
statistics do some counts some distinct
counts and stuff ml is barely barely
ever the solution as I just say
statistics often works use ensemble of
algorithms so multiple algorithms at the
same time that they augment each other
and sort of cancel out each other's
problems
teach the algorithms to ask for input if
the algorithm if you know it's acting on
a decision boundary but it's not sure
but I'm making the decision whether it's
left or right ask an expert for input
make sure this thing keeps up with
change and so on and so on I mean that
as I said earlier arguments are getting
smarter but experts are more important
you all will still have a job tomorrow
understand your data and your algorithms
and your data science process and
history is not a predictor its knowledge
--is be careful these belief networks
don't use historic data to train them
because as we talked earlier data is
bias I want to train these systems with
expert knowledge not with historical
data and with that I think we're right
on time thank you very much appreciate
it
[Applause]
you