today we are going to be speaking about
wrangling with a ghost which is
essentially a inside story about how
spectral meltdown was mitigated within
Microsoft yesterday there was a panel
about the industry cooperation and
mitigating specter meltdown which was
really interesting also today there is a
talk in the last slot about meltdown if
you're interested in technical details
on meltdown that is probably the better
talk to go to because we're going to
talk mostly about mitigation we're going
to skip relatively quickly over the
attacks that also makes our talk kind of
orthogonal to the two other spectrum of
down talks that have been yet on the
past so spectrum meltdown one two ponies
yesterday so we kind of think that it's
a relevant talk so without further ado
my name is Anna's I am a security
researcher and I should mention here
that I did this research while I was
employed by gee data and bounced
analytics and while under contract with
Microsoft the presentation here does not
reflect the views of my previous nor my
current employer and I'm Christopher so
I'm a security engineer and the nsrc in
the UK office
alright so Spector and meltdown these
issues gained a huge amount of interest
from the research community when they
were first disclosed earlier this year
because they represent a fundamentally
new class of Hardware vulnerability
which is an extremely rare occurrence
and the scope of the impact is just
massive potentially leaking information
across nearly every security boundary
that we rely on so when we were first
made aware of these issues in June last
year we kicked off our Incident Response
process and this is the typical process
that Microsoft follows whenever we're
made aware of a security vulnerability
either being actively exploited in the
wild or just a high threat risk that
requires mobilizing a large number of
people within Microsoft in particular
perspective we realized we were dealing
with a fundamentally new class of
vulnerability and
we decided to bring in an expert anders
so once again why do why does Microsoft
care about these issues because they
were relevant to nearly every security
boundary we rely on so if an attacker
has some kind of code execution even
within a scripting environment such as
JavaScript
they might potentially be able to leak
information across a security boundary
so this affects potentially hyper-v
Windows kernel and the browser so before
one can actually start mitigating a new
class of vulnerabilities one has to
think about what are these
vulnerabilities especially when it's a
new class and what we did was we made a
made a taxonomy and a framework to
reason about not only the attacks but
also how the mitigation could look like
and this is going to be the topic of
this section of the talk but before we
can get that far we need to talk a
little bit about how modern CPUs
actually work just for context so
usually we think of programs as recipes
that execute one instruction after the
other sequentially and in fact this is
how programmers usually try to write
their programs turns out that if the CPU
interpreted the program in that same way
it would be rather slow so modern CPUs
especially the high the high performance
general CPUs do many things at the same
time and this takes a couple of
different in a couple of different ways
the first way is pipelining pipelining
means that when it takes an instruction
in it works on this instruction doing
bits and parts of it through multiple
stages but simply lot essentially like
an assembly line the second thing is
monitor views are superscalar that means
nothing more that it they are capable of
working out and march on more
instructions num1
at the same time and we'll take a look
about how that works in a second
then we have out of order execution so
out of order execution means that the
instructions are no longer treated like
a recipe they are actually executed when
the dependencies resolved and when
resources are available so this makes it
possible to execute things out of order
and this again is a speed-up to my
session
finally we're going to talk about
speculative execution as well and
speculative execution is essentially
when the pipeline is working on data
that is predicted instead of actually
calculated we'll also be talking a lot
about that so here you see a very small
assembler program that consists of two
more instructions and an instruction the
first and the third instruction here
don't have any dependencies which means
that if we want to start to run this
program on a CPU these both instructions
are ready to start running at any time
whereas the middle instruction depends
on the result from the first which means
that this is not ready it has to wait
for the first instruction so when we
actually start executing this program on
I wanting to CPU will have that the
first and the third instruction will
start executing this is both superscalar
because we were executing two
instructions at once and it is also out
of order because the third instruction
shouldn't execute and rip recipe order
until the second instruction action was
done the advantage of doing it this way
is that since we're executing two extra
instruction at once this program will
take the time of one more than one ad
whereas if we were executing in a
program order recipe order it would be
the time of two miles in one ad which is
for cost a lot more so about speculation
when we went into this we made a very
general spec definition of what
speculation is more general than you
normally find in textbooks so our
definition of speculative execution was
that it's speculative whenever the
pipeline is working with data that may
turn out to be wrong that is predicted
in some kind of way
so why does CPU predict data well
typically it's because real data arrives
late they're calculated later in the
process and that it can be predicted
very well so if you get this situation
instead of waiting for the data you can
predict it if you predict it correctly
you win if you predict it wrongly you
unroll so speculative execution consists
of many kind of things you can speculate
on say conditional conditional live jig
you can speculate on the instruction
pointer where that has to go you can
speculate on the values of registers you
can defer error handling things like
this so when this prediction is actually
unrolled all the results that are that
comes from working with the mispredicted
data are just dropped just completely
removed from the CPU and this includes
registers memory operations things like
that and when these things are then
dropped execution will pick up where the
prediction was made because now we have
the right data however there is this
tiny snack here not everything is rolled
back and an example of what's not rolled
back when speculative execution is
unrolled is the caches so speculative
execution can actually load a cache and
will not unload it afterwards so we need
to talk a bit about memory uses and
caches so it turns out that main memory
that is DRAM modules reading data from
those are really really slow compared to
how fast a modern CPU actually is and
one should also notice here that memory
access patents are not random this they
can in terms of rejected in some way and
the way that this works is that usually
CPUs tend to use the same memory again
and again and there's a solution for CPU
designers to this to make this faster
and this is to make a very small cache
inside of the CPU not in MIT just part
of main memory but inside the CPU and
keep the most recent memory access in
there
serve memory requests from this cache if
possible and this of course makes it a
lot faster so this also entails the site
channel so that an attacker can time how
fast a memory accesses and if it's fast
well it was recently used and this of
course means that he is able to tell
something about memory access pattern
made by whoever executed before him
which again means he's able to tell
something about that and we're gonna see
this a lot going through this
presentation so the fundamental idea
about spectral meltdown is that when the
CPU unroll speculative execution
it doesn't unroll everything the cache
is the example here and that through
this side channel we were capable of
recovering information that was used
during the speculate execution and the
results here can then be recovered
through the side channel and in some
cases these results contain private data
and we have leakage of private data
between security domains so moving on to
spectral variant one so spectral Rayyan
one works with prediction of conditional
branches so the thing about a
conditional branch is that you don't
know where it goes until it's been
executed however we want the pipeline to
be full to have it full of instructions
to work on from the out of order
execution engine for this reason the CPU
predicts the conditional branches
because it can do that right up the top
at the pipeline and keep on filling the
rest of the pipeline so we have this
delay here that I was talking about
before this actually works quite well
modern CPUs are capable of predicting
conditional branches above 99% of the
times correctly however we said before
that conditional branches are predicted
on past history of the CPU and this is a
problem because if it's an attacker is
running on the CPU he actually
determined
past behavior and he determines how
these things will predict be predicted
and this allows the attacker to
determine the prediction and if we look
at the code but below the blue thing
we'll see what essentially will be a
conditional branch and we have an
untrusted index in here so if the
prediction is wrong or no matter what
the predictor
no matter what the value of the
untrusted index with the wrong
prediction the the code below the if
statement can execute speculatively so
this means that the second line of the
code is capable of accessing in in a
buffer indexed on our untrusted index
and this untrusted index can take any
value meaning that we essentially have
arbitrary load of memory into the CPU
this is enough in and of itself not a
big problem the problem comes with a
search statement and the search
statement is essentially loading into
the cache some address depending on the
value that we read from arbitrary memory
so we take the cache in a way that
discloses what the value of the memory
the arbitrary memory that we read in the
previous statement in other words we're
capable of reading arbitrary memory
using the side channel timing attack we
described on under the caches so if
you're wondering what that 40 in that
statement is it's because caches don't
really work on bytes they works on
blocks of 64 bytes and 40 hexes 64 bytes
and to be able to distinguish between
all different values you need to
multiply by that the consequence of
having this code somewhere in your
computer is that if an attacker can
execute this code can find execute or
generate and execute this code he'll be
able to read memory at the privileged
count the privilege level where they
found this code so if this is a kernel
or the hypervisor or
in clave doesn't matter he's capable of
reading the memory with a high privilege
this is a clear violation of basic
security principles so moving on to
respect to variant two this time around
if not conditional branches is indirect
branches and in our back branches is not
predicted whether they are taken or not
taken because they're always taken
they are predicted where they are going
to go so like before indirect branches
can be trained but there is a special
thing about indirect branches that it's
not just a single bit that has to be
predicted it's an entire address and for
this reason the CPU keeps a table where
any indirect branch past behavior is
stored this is called the branch target
buffer of btp and because you can't have
a table for every possible indirect jump
it actually is indexed with just a
subset of the bit of the address of the
indirect jump this means that if an
address if an attacker knows which bit
this is and this can be reverse
engineered and has been reversed
engineered he can just allocate a piece
of memory put an indirect branch in a
location that collides with this and
then he could start training his
indirect branch to go wherever he likes
meaning that an attacker is capable of
picking code in the security domain
where he found the indirect branch
essentially anywhere so I try to
illustrate this here with the read 5,000
rx equals that it should go to 5,000 put
speculatively it can go anywhere and an
attacker can make it go to 4141 if he
likes the assembler code in the lower
part of the slide this is same as the C
code and the previous slide it just
reads memory and persists into the cache
so this makes the attack a lot worse
from from a defender perspective because
now we don't need to have a long blog
consistent code we can actually just
have a in Eric branch and and the rest
of the code that an attacker needs
somewhere which is of course much more
flexible again the consequences of this
is an attacker is capable of reading
they shouldn't be able to memory to read
that is in the security domain where he
finds these two things which leads us on
to the third variant the third variant
is also known as meltdown and it is
fundamentally different from spectra in
that perspective you need to find to
create this code you could bring it with
you an attacker can write all the code
that is needed for this attack so this
is the first major difference
the second major difference is that this
is not about branches so what happens
here is that when a user tries to access
kernel memory the colonel says no you're
not allowed to do this it's both an
exception and stop program execution
which is great because then you can't
read kernel memory except what happens
in some CPUs is that when you try to
read kernel memory the CPU speculates oh
he's just reading from memory I should
give it to him and at some point a
little later it will discover oh there
should be an exception and this gives an
attacker a window to do the exact same
trick as before persist the memory into
the cache and side-channel it out
afterwards and this leads to the
situation where an unprivileged user is
capable of reading arbitrary kernel mode
memory and that again is a clear
violation of standard operating system
security so now that we have seen the
three variant that we were presented
with in June last year we go on to
building economy about that the first
question we need to raise this why do we
want to create a taxonomy the thing is
when you design medications especially
mitigations which relies who comes with
a new class of vulnerabilities you want
to be systematic about it you don't want
to mitigate the three examples that we
were sent from Google project zero you
want to mitigate every possible
variation of these and to do this you
need a taxonomy to reason about how this
thing actually works when does it break
down when doesn't it break down so we
went on to
work on a taxonomy and what we noticed
was that there are four steps that are
required for an attacker to run a
speculative execution attack the first
thing that an attacker needs to do he
needs to get wrong data into the
pipeline and we call that call the
process gaining speculation and we call
the primitive the code that actually
does this that for specter of you will
need to find from milp and he'll need to
write we call this a speculation
primitive and this essentially gets
wrong data into the pipeline the second
thing that an attacker needs to make
sure is that once he is in speculation
the CPU will try to rectify this as soon
as possible
and he wants to delay that so that he
can run the code that persists persist
the secret data into the cache of some
work somewhere else to make sure that he
can read it out later so there's a race
condition here and he needs to make sure
he can win that and we talked about a
window for speculative execution and
hence we're talking about Windows
gadgets and the third step he needs to
do is he actually needs to write the
secret in to a side channel where he can
read it later we call this this
disclosure tachat and finally he needs
to get the information back from the
cache or wherever he stored it in
whatever side channel he used and we
call this the disclosure primitive this
is where he gets the data back so he's
able to work with it and disclose it or
do whatever evil he wants to do with it
oh sorry so it should be fairly obvious
that if any of these steps breaks there
is no speculative attack and when you
think of it like this this is very
important information for somebody who
wants to mitigate this stuff I'm taking
a closer look at some of these things so
gaining speculation the speculation
primitive essentially we have three
versions or we have three versions of it
we have misprediction on conditional
branches we have misprediction on
indirect branches both of which could be
trained the in
break branches a bit more sophisticated
there allows an attacker more
possibilities and finally we have the
meltdown version where we have an
interrupt that is delivered after it
should be and allows execution to be
continued with data that a that
shouldn't be present in the pipeline so
the second is window gadgets maintaining
speculation so the thing here is that
once we an attacker executes the
speculation gadget he is on a race
condition against the CPU finding out
that it was working on predicted data
mispredicted data and to win this race
condition he needs to have some code
that gives him time and he also needs to
make sure that the code he actually
wants to execute can execute out of
order so there are some limits about how
the code that generates the windows has
to look and window gadgets can occur
naturally that is kind of the entire
point why the CPU is able to do out of
order execution but in some
circumstances there are some ways that
an attacker can actually engineer having
good window gadgets and the actual
window size is very difficult to reason
about because it derived from a lot of
things the first is the actual hardware
on which was running the second is how
the dependencies that the code looks
like and the third is what other
congestion are happening on the CPU at
the time that is running so it's kind of
difficult but you can in big terms
reason about what kind of windows you're
looking at the third will catch it that
we need is the disclosure gadget and the
disclosure gadget is centrally just
writing into a side channel and the
example here is the cache that we have
before and it needs to run within the
speculative window and the fourth and
final is of course getting the data back
from
wherever we started before using some
kind of primitive we call it the
disclosure primitive and we can
generalize a bit more about that but
let's go into specific instead so taking
each of the four components with
examples we've had it before conditional
branches indirect branches and deferred
into interrupts the techniques that we
knew on June and when we go on to window
gadgets we have a couple of special
cases the first case here is when we
have dependencies on a load loading
something from memory so this is the
case where the attacker is actually
capable of engineering the gadget so if
you make sure that the value here in P
is not in the cache it will load much
much slower than if it were and this
actually increases his window size if
there's a dependency on this value and
in this fashion he can create a lot of
window for himself so something like
this is likely to occur naturally in
code and he can then engineer situation
where his window gets big enough you can
take this to an extreme so if you have a
chain on dependent load from cache
memory you can create very large windows
up to the theoretical limit that is
determined by the hardware that however
is not very likely to be present in much
naturally occurring code and the final
thing is a bit more worrying in natural
occurring code this is because if you
have integer operations on the same
variable that too can cause a window to
be created and that is something that is
likely to occur in a natural occurring
code meaning that it's likely to find
gadgets window gadgets in natural
occurring codes just by having somebody
do something on whatever into job even
floating point so of course there can be
more window gadgets than the ones I
listed here in fact there could be an
infinite number of them but we haven't
done Tia about how they could look like
the next step is the disclosure gadget
we talked about two levels of in
directions a lot so far because getting
arbitrary memory persisting an arbitrary
memory into the cache this is the second
one and in the box here but it's easy to
realize that if say you have some secret
value X that is used in speculative
execution and you do a load on that
you'll load the cache for that as well
and this means you have another
disclosure catered with just one level
of indirection and you can do three
levels of indirection as well that will
leave leaked memory too and you can
probably do a lot of other things that
will write something into some side
channel and this is important to notice
when you want to do mitigations because
it becomes more than just the case that
we had before and in this the examples
that we got from project zero and
finally we have the disclosure primitive
here we're just listing disclosure
primitive that relates to to the cache
because that is what we have been doing
this in this talk so we have the classic
flash and we load the fashion we load
that is essentially what I've described
so far requires that the attacker and
the victim code actually shares some
memory that is not a strict requirement
there are other attacks on the cache
called evict and time and there is prime
and probe which don't have this
requirement which can lead data without
actually sharing memory with the
attacker between attacker and victim if
you want to know more about these two
attacks I did a talk at hack in the Box
in 2016 that covered these kind of
attacks in much more detail so once we
have a taxonomy in place we need to look
at where are these scenarios relevant so
the first thing that we did was we came
up with some categories of disclosure
and the first category is what happened
inside a virtualized system this is
relevant for things like Asscher for
hyper-v and this is like disclosure
between two guests or disclosure of
memory between the hypervisors itself
and an a process you we have another
category about what happens in a in an
operating system
and here we're talking about disclosure
from Colonel between processes and we've
had a final category about enclaves and
enclaves are sensitive because they're
supposed to be secured about against
anybody in any scenario and then we had
listed all the scenarios that we could
find I'm not going to read them and
realize that spectrum version 1 and
version 2 actually is relevant for
everything here whereas the meltdown
appears to be only irrelevant between
four operating systems and only between
the kernel and the user and that leaves
the systemic systematization part of
this talk thank you so now we can begin
to reason about the kind of mitigations
we can put in place for these types of
attacks so we defined three mitigation
tactics the first of which is preventing
speculation techniques and specifically
what we mean by this is we want to
prevent unsafe speculation where the
speculation primitive could lead to a
disclosure capture the second tactic we
have is removing sensitive content from
memory so the idea here is to eliminate
entire attack scenarios or simply limit
the severity of what speculative what a
speculative read could actually disclose
and the final tactic we had was removing
observation channels so the idea here is
to make it as difficult as possible or
even impossible for an attacker to
observe changes to the cache state for
example and infer secrets from that but
the key point here is there's no silver
bullet that each of the attack scenarios
will require a different combination of
mitigations both hardware and software
okay so starting with removing
speculation techniques once more the
goal here is to prevent unsafe
speculation which could lead to a
disclosure capture first thing we can do
is have some kind of serialization of
the instruction pipeline so on x86 we
have the L offense instruction which has
the neat property of acting as a
speculation barrier so if we think back
to
this variant one code pattern we can use
the elephants after performing the
balance check and this will create the
guarantee that speculation won't be able
to continue on from past this point
where untrusted index is greater than or
equal to length second thing we can do
is have some kind of implicit
sterilization so thinking back to
variant one again we can use a
conditional move instruction to set
untrusted index to a zero register if it
is greater than or equal to length and
this will force the miss speculated path
to execute the subsequent two array
operations with untrusted and index
being zero which won't disclose a
sensitive secret and to do this we have
Q Spector command line flag in visual
C++ which will automatically detect
potentially vulnerable code patterns and
insert appropriate sterilization
similarly for Microsoft edge we have
mitigations in the chat for a JavaScript
engine which prevent an attacker from
being able to create these kind of
vulnerable code patterns to disclose
memory the next thing we can do is have
some kind of workload isolation so as we
heard earlier indirect branches are
predicted based on past behavior which
is stored in the branch target buffer
these kind of prediction states are
generally either shared per core or
hyper thread in the case of simultaneous
multithreading is enabled so what we can
do is we can assign a certain core to
guest VM for example and leave the
others for the host and what this will
do is it will prevent a malicious guest
from being able to collide the branch
prediction state and trigger unsafe
speculation from an indirect branch of
the host and to do this hyper V supports
min route and CPU groups which can be
used to schedule the behavior of the
guest the next thing we can do is make
use of the indirect branch control
features which are provided by micro
code updates by Intel and AMD
so we have three new options we have
IBRS which kind of acts as a way of
creating two different privileged
domains so we set IVRS to zero for the
lower privileged state and then on
transition into the higher privileged
states such as on kernel entry we can
set IBRS to one and this will create the
guarantee that the higher privileged
state will not be influenced by
prediction changes made by the less
privileged context the next thing we
have is IB PB which essentially allows
the operating system to flush this
prediction state so this might be used
when switching context switching
processes or switching guest virtual
machines for the hypervisor scenario the
final thing we have is s dibp so as we
saw when in the case where simultaneous
multithreading has enabled two
co-located threads on a single core
might share some prediction state so if
we have higher privilege contexts
running and a lower privilege context
running on the same core the lower
privileged context might be able to
collide the branch prediction state so
setting s GI be p21 just prevents this
attack scenario and all versions of
Windows client that are supported make
use of these features the next thing we
can do to prevent speculation techniques
is used non speculated or safely
speculated indirect jumps so on Intel
CPUs the far jump and far ret
instructions which are indirect jumps
that also change the code segment will
not be speculated so we can replace
indirect branches with these
instructions and this will guarantee
that miss speculation will never occur
from an indirect branch
similarly for AMD CPUs we can use the
elephants instruction and will guarantee
also that Miss speculation will never
occur from an indirect branch there was
also this proposal by Google for Rhett
Pauline and this essentially can be used
to control speculation after an indirect
branch so speculation could go to an
infinite loop say where as architectural
II the jump will resolve as normal
Windows kernel and hyper-v are using a
combination of these to best optimize
performance so moving on to the second
tactic removing sensitive content from
memory once more the goal here is to
limit the sensitivity of memory that
speculation could read and disclose the
first thing we can do is have hypervisor
address space segregation so as the
hypervisor runs we can map guest
physical memory on demand as its
required as opposed to historically
where the hypervisor would have all
guest physical memory Maps at all times
and so what this means is that if a
malicious vm performs a hyper call and
tries to induce unsafe speculation it
will only ever have access to its own
guest physical memory and so will not be
able to disclose guest physical memory
from other virtual machines running on
the host the next thing we have this is
specific to variant 3 the kernel user
information disclosure scenario is KB a
shadow so previously in user mode
execution the kernel page table entries
would be mapped but just marked as
inaccessible with KB a shadow we
guarantee the user mode execution only
however has access to its own page
tables we add the kernel page tables
back in when we transition to the kernel
as as needed all supported versions of
Windows client enable this by default
and final tactic removing observation
channels once more the goal here is to
make it difficult for an attacker or
even impossible to observe changes to
the cache state and infer secrets from
that the first thing we have is mapping
guest physical memory as uncatchable so
if we have some system physical memory
we can map it as write back cache for
the guest so it will be no performance
packed for the guests itself but for the
hypervisor we can map it as uncatchable
and what this will do is it will create
the guarantee that if the hypervisor
performs a speculative load on this
guest physical memory it will obey the
uncatchable property and so won't be
able to make any cash cash changes that
will be observable to the guests through
a flash memory load primitive so this
acts as a generic mitigation for yes to
host a flash memory load the other thing
we can do similarly to prevent guest to
guest flash and reload disclosure
primitive is simply ensure that we never
share any physical memory between two
guests so we ensure they always have
their own copy of everything and this
ensures that changes made to the cache
and one guest cannot be observed by
another through the flush and reload
primitive which requires shared cache
lines finally we can decrease the time
of precision in the browser so there's
this API performance start now which is
accessible to JavaScript which
previously could be used to time a
single indirect a single load and then
determine whether that address was in
the cache or not now what we do is we
decrease the precision of this timer and
we also add random jitter to prevent
clock edging techniques which makes it
much more difficult for an attacker to
perform a speculative attack in the
browser so for closing remarks I just
want to reiterate the point that there's
a large number of attack scenarios and
for each of them we require a different
combination of hardware and software
mitigations to prevent the problem as
best as possible thinking back to the
variants themselves variant 1 well
they're all Hardware vulnerabilities
variant 1 is going to require software
changes so that might be using the Hugh
specter command line flag to insert
appropriate serialization variant 2 is
mitigated by the operating system by
making use of the indirect branch
controls for example and finally variant
is completely mitigated with KVA shadow
so once more userland execution never
has kernel page table entries mapped
since then we've received also some new
variants which I just like to go over
briefly the first of which is
speculative store bypass which worked by
creating mispredictions between data
dependencies of store and load
instructions the mitigation for this is
the same as variant one just adding
serialization to the pipeline for
vulnerable code patterns alternatively
there is a feature of the CPU which can
be used to disable this memory
disambiguation optimisation but that is
disabled by default as no vulnerable
code patents have efan have been found
affecting Microsoft code the second of
which is the lazy floating-point state
restore so 32-bit versions of Windows
prior to 10 would make this optimization
where when context switching between
processes instead of always just copying
the floating-point registers they would
simply mark them as inaccessible and
then restore them on first use through
triggering an exception the problem with
this was speculative execution could
reach stale floating point register
values from prior process as the
exception could be deferred similar to
variant 3 the mitigation for this is
simply to disable this optimization
which is done and the latest version of
all windows 10 the bounce bounce check
by PI store this was where a conditional
branch would mispredict leading to an
outer bounds right speculatively and if
this speculative outer bounds right
corrupted an indirect branch target this
could lead to speculation that an
arbitrary attacker controlled address if
that was then called similar to how
variant two works so that's powerful
because it could lead to disclosure
primitive the mitigation for this is
once again identifying vulnerable code
patterns and inserting appropriate
serialization
then moving on to finally in that
Spectre which was the first attack
demonstrated over the network the
mitigation for this is once more just
detecting vulnerable Co patterns and
inserting serialization but we we expect
this to be a continuing subject of
research and so we've launched our
speculative execution side-channel
bounty the max payout for this is 250 K
USD for new variants we also have more
information about the variants
themselves and developer guidelines on
tech nap globe so I just like to finish
by saying thank you to everyone who is
involved in this research and the
mitigations it's been a tremendous
undertaking I would like to join in that
thanks and I would also like to thank
Microsoft for allowing to me to be a
part of that process and for allowing me
to be here today and of course to all of
you guys who came to to watch this talk
thank you very much
[Music]