all right thank you so yeah for the next
47 minutes I'll be talking about
just-in-time compilers for JavaScript
mainly how they work and what kind of
box you can find there
we'll start with let me turn this on
yeah we'll start with a short overview
how the JavaScript engine look like yes
these are kind of the main components
you'll need to make a JavaScript engine
first we have the parser that basically
takes your JavaScript code as textual
representation and converted to byte
code usually that custom byte code for
the engine so that kind of a bytecode
compiler if you watch next
we have an interpreter and or a JIT
compiler which basically consumes this
bytecode and some are executed right so
the interpreter interpreter can just
execute the code directly the JIT
compiler first converted to machine code
then runs your machine code so while
this code runs it interacts with what I
call the runtime which essentially
defined various data structures like
values objects and so on and it provides
a bunch of building functions objects
etc and finally we have the garbage
collector so JavaScript is garbage
collected language meaning the
programmer doesn't need to take care of
free memory so the garbage collector
does that so with that here's what we'll
talk about today we'll start with some
introduction or some background on the
runtime how it works mainly we'll talk
about JavaScript values and objects then
we'll talk about gee compiler internodes
how they work how they convert
JavaScript to machine code then we'll
talk about a text surface what kind of
parts you can find there and how to
exploit them a bit and finally we'll
talk about one specific bug in WebKit
which I use for counter on this year all
right start with the runtime and
actually start with JavaScript values so
javascript is what is called the
dynamically typed language that means
that for example variables or properties
they can essentially change type so if
you look at these concepts here you'll
see
this variable a its first a number 10
it's a string at an object that's all
fine for the engine that means that it
has to store type information together
with this value information and then the
challenge here is to do this efficiently
and usually the solution ends up being
some clever hex that managed to store
both type and value information in eight
bytes there's two of those favored hex
basically one is called non boxing and
there's this pointer tagging for this
talk we'll talk about pointer tagging
just because it's a bit simpler actually
we will use the schema from v8 chromium
engine so in v8 JavaScript is basically
and an 8 byte number or 8 byte value
assuming 64-bit architecture
now if the least significant bit if that
is cleared if that is 0 then this thing
is a number or a small integer they call
it so that's what you see on the left
here you see that these significant bit
is 0 and then the halo 2 32 bit payload
is stored in the upper 32 bits so this
value if you see that in an engine in v8
represents the number hex 42 on the
other hand if the least significant bit
of that is set then you have a pointer
and that's pointing to some object and
then at that location there will be more
type information so you can see here on
the right side that where you have some
one bit set so it's pointing to some
kind of object all right so speaking of
objects that's the next data structure
we'll look at so the question here is
how to represent objects efficiently for
us an object is basically just kind of a
collection of key value pairs
key is being strings and various being
JavaScript values so if you wanted to
store that maybe the first thing it
could come up with this just make a hash
map that map's strings to values yeah
that's quite simple but it's not what
happens so in reality and of the major
engines right now what they do is
essentially they separate property name
information from value information and
then they have this
object that I'll just call shape for
this talk this shape object essentially
swords the property names so let's look
at that again this is the object we want
to represent so X&Y properties and
instead of you know having this object
store with hash map mapping strings to
values instead we have the object which
points to its shape so that's a separate
object now this shape essentially Maps
property names to integers and these
integers they are being used as indices
and to basically a dynamically
dynamically size array of pages
associated with every object okay so
let's say you wanted to look up the
property X on this object what you would
do is first go to the shape then you
could see that property X
distorted slot 0 then you go back to the
object go to the slots array and then
you find the value 41 so that's how it
works
so you're probably wondering why why are
they doing that what the benefit here
let me show you an example
so again we have the same object X&Y
properties now if we create another
object that similar in the sense that it
also has X&Y properties now suddenly
those two object they are able to share
the same shape so there's no redundancy
essentially right so that's the main
benefit here that these shapes they can
be shared so this they can use to
conserve memory basically yeah and they
are shared between similar objects
essentially so the next question is well
what happens if you change one of those
objects so for example here if you add a
third property to the first object now
those two objects they can't really
share the same set shares this shape
anymore because the second object
doesn't have this property so in this
case well we have to separate those
shapes again
now there's two one has three property
if the other has two the one important
property here is that shapes are
essentially immutable that's following
from the from the fact that they are
shared yeah so then next thing if we
were to add this third property also to
the second
then again they can share the shape
there's some clever mechanisms that make
this work efficiently but this is
essentially how it works what what
happens so yeah if you look at any
optimator for engines right now and see
if how they implement objects what you
would find is essentially that all of
them have reference to this shape object
and that's called differently in all
engines so in Firefox it's actually -
it's called shape and the group object
in v8
it's called map in WebKit it's called
structure and an edge it's called type
but they all do the same thing they are
shared and immutable that's the two
important properties and they fully
describe the object they tell you which
properties it has where they are stored
what prototype it has etc then you have
these property slots and usually you
have a few property slots stored in line
so a fixed number of in line property
slots and then you have an out of line
yeah appointed to an out of line
property slots area that's dynamically
sized where our properties are stored
that don't fit in the inline slots so
then the other thing you have is usually
a buffer for element storage that's just
due to the fact that in JavaScript you
can kind of use every object as an area
so they also have this having a storage
essentially and then you might have
additional type specific fields so for
example if you have a regular expression
object or a typed array object you would
have more data fields in these objects
but these are the main ones the first
vote for all right so the next thing
we'll talk about is my TD JIT compilers
how they work for JavaScript so we do
kind of a 10 to 15 minutes tutorial on
how to compile JavaScript but first
let's start with some motivation why do
we want charge it compilers we all
already have those interpreters which
can just run our code so what's the
benefit of just-in-time compilers well
it's probably quite obvious its code
speed if you have this optimizing JIT
compiler it's probably running much
faster than interpreting your code
however there's some drawbacks also so
one is that the the startup time of an
interpreter is probably much lower so it
can just start executing the code
immediately after the bytecode compiler
finishes vs JIT compiler it has to do
this expensive optimization etc so it
takes a lot longer to to start executing
code kind of the same with memory the
the interpreters probably using left
memory then the JIT compiler as such
what what all the major engines engines
do right now is a half essentially a
multi tier architecture where they start
running code in the interpreter then
they monitor how many times the function
has been called and at some point they
determine okay this function has been
called a lot of times it's probably
worth optimizing that then they put that
through their JIT compiler produces
optimized code and once that's done they
switch to the machine code so this is
how it works all right so let's talk
about how to compile JavaScript here's
the small function javascript functions
just adding two arguments together yeah
how would you compare this to machine
code this seems hard right it mainly
seems hard because we have no idea about
types of the parameters so a and B they
could be numbers but they could also be
strings they could be objects whatever
we don't really know and this makes
makes it hard to produce machine code
here so the the plus operating in
JavaScript it's quite complex if you
look at the specification this is the
pseudocode for adding something in
javascript right and all these blue
functions are essentially subroutine so
it's really complicated and you wouldn't
want to omit this as machine code all
the time so that's okay another example
here's another function that just
fetches a property from from an object
again this seems hard to make machine
code for this same reason we don't know
the type of oh and in particularly we
don't know its shape so we have no idea
where this property's been stored could
be anywhere
so what it means is essentially that the
main major challenge here of JIT
compiling these languages the
using type information right so that
will be this song so let's just assume
that for some reason we we had type
information so maybe we had kind of a
JavaScript dialect that the strictly
typed and it tells us that a NPR Smiths
are these small integers in the 8th can
we produce machine code now turns out we
can it's that's quite easy actually
we know the in-memory representation of
Smith's it's just tag pointers again we
can just add them together in this
representation right so there's machine
instruction you can use to add registers
so that's quite easy there's one catch
because in JavaScript there's no integer
overflow essentially so the engine here
has to do what is called a bailout if
this addition overflows what it has to
do is essentially go back to the
interpreter so that the bailout it bails
out to the interpreter and that
interpreter what it would do in this
case is convert the arguments to double
it and then do double addition right but
this bailout mechanism is quite
important we will see it a few more
times right so obviously what we don't
have strictly typed language so we don't
have type information what we have is or
what we can have is type information
from previous executions so remember I
said that right now when you run
JavaScript in an engine it first runs it
in the interpreter and only after some
time it goes to the JIT compiler so by
the time we want to compile we do have
type information from previous run so we
can just keep track of all the types we
see for every variable so how does this
help us well what we can do is speculate
then in the future we will see the same
types and this is really the main main
trick here and this is where the name
speculative JIT comes from so its look
at an example again here's our add
function and let's say we we keep track
of it while it runs in the interpreter
and this is what we see it's always
being called with smiths as arguments
okay so at this point when we compile we
speculate Ted also in the future we will
see sneeze as arguments for this
function so how does this help us right
so now we have we
we have type speculations for all
variables what can we do now the trick
is to use so-called speculation guards
and these are just kind of small pieces
of machine code they ensure that our
speculation still holds at runtime so
there they are they come in different
flavors here's two of them on the right
side you see a semi guard so that just
makes sure that some variables is me as
we expected so it's checking this least
significant bit here and if not it plays
out again bailout mechanism on the left
side you see a shape guard which makes
sure that some object has the expected
shape what it does is just fetch the
shape pointer from the object compared
to constant and this works because
shapes are shared and immutable so
that's why they are yeah how this works
so it's not good an example again here's
the other function the function that
fetches a property let's say we
speculated all will always be an object
of a specific shape and then this is
what we could generate as machine code
so first we have to make sure that
always notice me so we need to have the
inverse me guard that makes sure it's an
object again checking the least
significant bit then we have shape card
that makes sure we have the expected
shape and then at that point if both of
these cards run through we have type
information we know the shape of this
object and we can just directly load
this property from the object so in this
case maybe property B is stored in an
inline slot so we can just dereference
the pointer basically yeah what that
means is that essentially this
speculation guard they give us type
information back so that's the main
trick for dealing with missing type
information so let's look at kind of a
typical JIT compiler pipeline this is
what you would see a few yeah where'd
you go through the code basically so
always right now it always starts from
byte code plus value profiles that's not
necessarily like that so we ate used to
see the the abstract syntax tree in its
JIT compiler but right now our engines
say they start from the byte code then
they convert this byte code to their own
custom intermediate language which they
do we can
while the bytecode isn't really there
for optimizing so they converted to a
different form that's better suited for
optimizing the code later on then they
do this typing or specializing where
they apply those right where they look
at those value profiles to the type
speculations insert type cards and then
they end up with this graph or usually
graph based intermediate language plus
runtime guards and at this point we
basically have type information
afterward it kind of looks like a
classic compiler for like C++ or Java
maybe so they run a bunch of optimizers
to produce better faster code they end
up with this optimized intermediate
language then they have to lower that to
machine code so that's called lowering
selecting machine instructions
allocating registers and so on and then
we end up with machine code so let's sum
this up what we've seen is that major
challenge of JIT compilers is missing
type information solution is to first
observe runtime behavior keep track of
types then speculate that we will see
the same types in the future gaagh these
speculations with these runtime cards
and then basically optimize and emit
machine code if you want to take a look
at this there's a really cool tool from
eh developers it's called turbo lighter
what it does is basically render their
intermediate graph based language in a
nice web base UI so that's what I did
here I just kind of compiled this
function foo in v8 took a look at this
graph and what you see here is
essentially data flow graph so parameter
one that's oh it flows into a check heap
object no that's making sure that it's
me if it is then it plays out next it
flows into this check maps node so
that's making sure it's having the
expected shapes or remember shape is
called map in v8 and after these two
checks it knows the exact type of the
parameter so it can just load this field
from upset 24 in this case right so yeah
now we have kind of a basic idea of how
these compilers work so let's talk about
a tank surface
so here I made this is my list of kind
of bug categories that I want to talk
about in this talk the list is sorted
from basically classic bugs that don't
really have anything to do with JIT
compilers to very specific box that you
can only find there right so the first
one is memory corruption in the compiler
that's kind of obvious because these
compilers are written in C or C++
actually so they can have all these
standard box right overflows you dr.
trees etc so it's really not specific to
JIT compilers at all and we actually
won't talk about them any further the
next two categories here are bugs in the
lowering phase where it converts to
machine code so we'll talk about that a
bit if there's time at the end I can
show some example a box of mine for for
these two categories if not then you can
find them on the slides afterwards so
then the biggest part at the biggest
categories that I want to talk about
it's incorrect optimizations so we'll
spend a lot of time there and then at
the end I'll talk about everything that
I didn't talk about because not enough
time just very briefly yeah you can also
divide this like this so basically the
memory corruption box they would create
a compile time right because the
compiler itself has a memory corruption
bug versus all the others they only
crash at run time while they they
produce for the conditions at runtime
right so they're a bit more interesting
I think so let's start with the first
one that's the slow path handlers so if
you look at basically this lower ring
code where they convert from their own
intermediate language to machine code it
usually looks like like this where they
just have one function for every
operation or every instruction in the
intermediate language and this function
is responsible for turning that
operation into machine code so here's
one one example yeah
what it might look like usually then
there's a few different cases so there's
one case or a few cases where they know
the type information and the type
information is so that they can
specialize essentially so it's kind of
the Fastpass so let's
he wanted to compile an addition
operation and you knew that your your
incoming arguments are always Smith so
in that case you can just submit machine
code as we saw it but then there's the
other case where maybe all you know that
the argument could be an object or could
be a string or whatever and in that case
you don't really want to omit this whole
pseudocode that we looked at right that
was kind of a big list so what you would
do is just kind of emit a call to a
runtime function to a C++ function that
then implements this big plus operation
here right so the takeaway here is
essentially that this function that's
being called this low pass operation XYZ
in this code here that's just kind of a
built-in function like all the other
buildings in this engine that's a
function that's implementing in C++ it
takes JavaScript they use does something
return to JavaScript value so you can
just audit it like all those kind of
classic JavaScript engine bugs right so
then let's look at the other paths here
let's say we can specialize because we
know that the arguments are maybe quite
favorable they are only always integers
maybe so in this case this is this is
somewhat what you would see in these
these engines in the code what they do
is usually kind of allocate a register
maybe for the results then emits a
machine code to perform the operation in
this case like an integer multiplication
yeah
jump if overflow in this case is also
required and then they set the result
right so yeah it's really just a code
generator that emits machine code so
yeah what could it what could go wrong
with this what what could happen
essentially this isn't too different
from the previous one right so the
previous example though it was C++ code
that's doing something now this is C++
code that produces machine code that
then does something right so you could
essentially have all the same box in
this and in code like this one thing
that happened a few times is missing
integer overflow checks right so this is
always a problem you can do the same
bugs with this kind of code there's some
other stuff so for example you
see here it has to do register a
location that might be tricky so they're
in some box with register allocation
here that you wouldn't have in the C++
code but really it's it's yeah kind of
to the same kind of JavaScript engine
box that you will find elsewhere so
let's now talk about optimization so
this is the biggest chapter that I want
to talk about incorrect optimizations so
what is an optimization first it's
basically a transformation of code that
is not required for correctness but
improved speed right so here's a simple
example we have this function here
circumference computes circumference of
a circle and in this case a compiler
could notice that this expression 2
times pi is actually constant so it
could just pre compute that at compile
time and yeah insert that constant here
and save a multiplication at runtime so
that's called constant folding it's very
basic optimization and there's a bunch
of others should look at those compilers
a huge list of optimizations they do
some of them are quite complex quite
dangerous of that goes wrong that
usually results in pretty nice bugs and
you will talk about two of those so the
first one is parts check elimination
right it sounds pretty dangerous already
so that's yeah it is
turns out the other three diamonds the
elimination that we'll talk about later
so let's talk about bounds checking
first here's some code what what it does
is just a function that you give an
index it fetches 13x from an area from a
global array if you compile that in
bieed and you again look at this code
graph here this is what you would see
again the data flow graphs or has this
parameter one the index it flows into
this check bounced node and this makes
sure that I is between zero and 4095
if it's not again bailout dimittis then
okay that's inbound so we can just index
into this array so that's our good and
we need to check here because I could be
yeah arbitrarily large so let's say I
added another statement here in this
case what I'm doing is just ending the
index was hex ffff and in this case the
boss check isn't really required right
because
the output of this and operation must be
between zero and hex FFF so this is the
goal of elimination essentially figure
out what our checks are redundant or
aren't required the idea is to perform
what is called range analysis so
essentially track all the possible value
ranges of integers in the in the
intermediate code and then if it can
prove that an index will always be in
bound so it knows the range of the index
it knows the range of the array length
so if the biggest index is always left
in the least area length and it can
eliminate the powers check so we can
kind of see that here again the Scout
craft for the speed of code so what you
see is that parameter one it floats into
this bitwise N and the compiler at this
point it figured out that the output of
this speed wise and must always be
between zero and 4095 so later when it
lowers this code to machine code it
realizes that the check bounced no
that's actually not required because the
input is already in that range so we'll
just eliminate the bounce check at that
point basically all right so what could
go wrong with this well quite a few
things basically every time you have
kind of a discrepancy between the value
range is computed by the compiler and
the actual value range that's a buck for
this pulse check elimination
so why would that happen there's a few
reasons one is due to integer related
problems so integers are hard yeah we
kind of all know this or there's sinus
issues there's overflow problems and
this range analysis is here has track
integers has to really do a lot of on
integers so it might run into any of
these standard integer related problems
the other source of Parts is essentially
incorrect emulation of this compiler
intermediate language so remember the
previous slide where I had this bitwise
and the compiler essentially had to
emulate this bitwise and to figure out
that the result would always be between
0 and 4095
no bid wise and it's simple that's quite
easy to emulate but there's a few others
it might be a bit more tricky and that's
a really cool bug I like from a good
friend of mine Stefan found NVH and
that's what we look at now so there's
this function called string dot last
index off you can call on a string what
it does is to give it a search failure
and it tells you the last index where is
this search value occurs in the string
so you might be searching for character
or whatever
now the v8 engine it put what it try to
do is essentially inline this this call
to this function and it would try to
predict the the output value of that
call so lastly next off what it can
return is essentially negative 1 in case
this search value isn't found or it
gives you an index so what they saw they
said well the the return value of this
call it must be an integer between
negative 1 and the maximum length of the
string minus 1 right because it's an
index so it's left and must be less than
the links or so they thought because if
you look at the documentation there's
this one sentence that said that an
empty string search value will match at
any index between 0 and the length of
the string so you can see that here in
this code snippet there's the string of
thanks for if I search for the last
index of the string empty string it
actually gives me 4 right what it means
is that this range of this type or code
here that determined try to determine
the output range is off by one so
actually this call can also return
string not max links so how can you
exploit this this is essentially the
pseudocode that you would need so you
start with this string of maximum
lengths in this function that's being
compiled then you do last in makes off
with an empty string at that point the
compiler syncs the output will be
between negative 1 and the maximum
length minus 1 but it can actually be
between negative 1 and maximum lengths
so then you add one just to get rid of
the negative 1 so again the compiler
sings is between 0 and max lines it can
actually be between 0 and makes things
plus 1 then you use it for an index into
an array
of this max Ling's plus one science at
that point the compiler sings well
okay the index is always in balance I
can just eliminate the bounce check
reality we get out of bounds access and
if you play around with it you can
basically get arbitrary out-of-bounds
access so if you interested I encourage
you to just read the report by Stefan it
contains a full RC exploit for this
packet there's a few more example where
this have happened so there's some
Firefox box from a few years ago there's
true blog post by GDI about similar bugs
and then project also found some of
those alright so let's talk about the
other optimization this is redundancy
elimination first question is well what
is redundancy in this case so let's say
we have this function that's fetching
two properties adding them together if
she compiled it's just like in with the
schema we've seen you might end up with
code like this where it first does the
swee guard and the shaped are then fetch
it's the first property and then it
again does its me guard shape guard
fetches the second property well in this
case obviously the second set of guards
is redundant right there's no way the
shape can change or the think enter into
an integer in between so in this case
what we want is this code right the
second set of cards removed so how would
you do this essentially the idea is to
determine duplicate cards on the same
control flow pass and then just keep the
first one sounds quite simple it's
actually tricky because you also need to
keep track of side effects so what is a
side effect well essentially calling
arbitrary JavaScript is a side effect so
let's look at this function here this is
essentially the previous one just now
I'm doing a function calling between
calling some JavaScript let's say we did
our redundancy elimination and this is
what we came up with first set of cards
then the call to this argument function
here and then no more guards and
directly the property fetch is this
correct well here's one case where it's
not let's say our callback what it does
is delete the property B in this case
it's the same
has changed right as a result of a side
effect so so this axis here
it cannot be safe we remove this
property be this this can't be good
so in this case we have to keep the
shape guard essentially the second so
that's what you have to do if if you
realize there's a side that's a
potential side effect here you have to
keep the following shape guards right so
this requires the engine to essentially
be able to precisely model our side
effects of all the operations in it
intermediate language and this is hard
so javascript
is full of these callbacks they're
everywhere they've been a big source of
parts or for for the last years
essentially and they continue to be yeah
it stores the parts in this case here so
it's not about exploitation how could
you exploit a bug like this for that we
need to talk a bit about arrays in
JavaScript so let's just do this very
quickly here so areas are kind of
commonly used data structures so the
engine tries to optimize for them let's
say we have an area that only stores
doubles like in this case here in that
case the engine would realize okay this
is only storing doubles so it would try
to store these dis values as actual
doubles and not as JavaScript pages
which are a bit more expensive because
they use more memory so if you look at
the backing storage of this area in a
debugger maybe you would see that it
just stores through our doubles and this
information is also stored in the shape
so here for this array the shape tells
us that it's storing unboxed doubles so
that brings up the question well what
happens if we store something that's not
a double in such an area and well what
happens so first before that we all only
have these unboxed tablets in our
banking storage now we put an object
there so now the engine has to go ahead
and basically convert all these tablets
to JavaScript values and then insert
this this object here so if you look at
maybe the the last elementary in this
area you would see it's pointing
somewhere and that somewhere if you look
there you will find this tablet value
again so yeah you can already tell why
the engine tries to optimize because
JavaScript values
and if it's torrid em as JavaScript
values it will take three times as much
memory as if it's towards an unboxed but
okay so how can we use this to exploit
these redundancy problems so this is
kind of the pseudocode for such a bug
where you have an unexpected call back
somewhere in between your your dude code
that you're compiling and then
essentially the exploit looks like this
so you first optimize your function to
work on areas with unbox doubles so in
this case is this for loop here to
always calling it with an unlockable
array then you call it again and this
time in this call they could transition
the area to now store objects and then
if the function with this callback
returns the JIT code essentially it's
the things that the array is storing
unbox doubles but it's now storing
pointers so in this case what it would
do is basically fetch this this pointer
treated that treated as a double and
give it back to you so you would get
this weird-looking double which is
essentially the address of this object
in memory so that's an info leak so we
get a type confusion that's basically
what we achieve here this part we've
seen it a few times
again VD is written a blog post about it
project here also found some box and
then there's this my CD from WebKit
which I used for pendulum and that's
what we'll talk about no right so this
was a JavaScript code the WebKit engine
they also using a graph based in treated
language they also do this precise
modeling of side effects because they
want to be redundancy elimination in
their case there's this class called
abstract interpreter which is
responsible for doing just that it's
tracking all kinds of read Riots to
stack heap and so on and it's making
sure yeah it's tracking essentially side
of things right if you look at this
abstract interpreter it's essentially a
huge switch case statement that for
every operation in the intermediate
language knows what side effects it's
have it has in case it has side effects
like a call instruction it's calling
this clobber world function which
basically says that while this has side
effects
throw away all type information and keep
following shape darts
right so if we look for some other code
here there's one operation that's called
create this what it does is basically
during construction it allocates the
objects that's being constructed and if
you look at this code in the abstract
interpreter here you can tell it it
doesn't call a clobber world so it's
assuming that this operation is in fact
side effect for you right well it turns
out it's not and that's exactly the bug
I exploited so create this it can
actually call JavaScript the reason is
very JavaScript specific essentially
when you construct an object the engine
has to fetch the property from the
constructor and fetching a property in
JavaScript that's something that you can
intercept for example with the
properties of proxies just kind of a
tool that you have in JavaScript to
intercept all these standard operations
on objects so here's kind of my pseudo
code you have to this function C which
is the constructor then I put a proxy
around it that intercepts property loads
and then I'm calling it as a constructor
now it's creating this this object that
it's constructing and at that point it's
running arbitrary JavaScript because I'm
intercepting property loads so that's
really the unexpected callback in our
example so let's look at what happens
now this is the function we want to
optimize the first thing it does is this
graph building phase yeah this is how it
would look like in the their
intermediate language first to create
this operation then shape card or it's
actually called structure check in
JavaScript core because yes shapes are
called structures then it's loading the
element and storing it on the object
next thing it does something called
check hoisting which is an optimization
where it tries to move these structure
checks as far up as it can so it's
actually duplicating the structures
check and putting it at first thing in
the function and then it's doing
redundancy elimination and at this point
it's removing the second structure check
because it's assuming that creates is a
side-effect free so what we end up with
is this operation which can have side
effects it can call JavaScript and then
there's an
unguarded access to this area
essentially and this is exactly the
condition we can exploit so for this we
can just view it the same trick that I
showed previously with the array
confusion stuff and confuse doubles and
JavaScript menus from there we get these
two primitives address often fake object
that I already used two years ago for
for another exploit basically you can
read up later you interested here and
from there it's really easy or just to
be really easy it's basically take a
type array as you get arbitrary right
that way and then you can just run shell
code basically yeah so this is kind of
the proof of concept for this book it's
a bit more complicated so I'm not gonna
go through all of this code right now if
you ran this on the vulnerable version
it would crashes for one for one for one
for one because there's this weird
double value that you have at the bottom
here if you're interested I will push my
commented exploit to get up so you can
take a look and we'll do a demo right so
what you will now see that basically my
full count your own chain so it has the
web PRC which gets this code executes in
the renderer and that's according this
part but only this one so this one is
quite powerful it allows us to bypass
our mitigations and then there's two
more boxes one one logic Park in Mac OS
that gets me out of the sandbox and then
there's another logic park that I used
to escalate from user to root and then
root to Karl because that's kind of a
additional security boundary and Mac OS
I guess right so let's see this in
action so there's the calculator popping
up mandatory calculator and here we can
see this is K X Ted so it's showing the
list of loaded kernel modules and this
is my own kernel module that I loaded
into the counter without a developer
certificate so it's not not signed in
anyway right so this is the full chain
gives us goes from browsing to web page
to kernel code execution kind of yeah
just a few seconds and it's super
reliable because it's basically just
logic box the whole way
all right so that brings us to the end
obviously we haven't covered everything
so there's a lot more to these compilers
there's this planar mechanism which I
only touched on it's quite complex
actually to just at some point in the
function go back to the interpreter and
continue executing code there so there
is some potential for box there there's
some other mechanisms like on stack
replacement where basically the engine
can also switch to the JIT code while
running the function so let's say you
have a function that has a while loop
that's running very long at some point
the JIT compiler could compile this the
whole fashion and then just switch to
the JIT code from one loop iteration to
the next so they're faulted quite a
complex mechanism there's register
allocation which we haven't talked about
at all
also in nine caches inline caches is
essentially kind of a something in
between the interpreter and the
speculative and optimizing it but I have
some references on the next slide if you
have two or next slides where you can
read up if you're interested and of
course all of these are quite complex
there's potential for box there so enjoy
finding them I guess cool that brings us
to the end so here's my summary what
have you seen essentially we saw the
type speculation and runtime guards make
up for missing type information due to
dynamic typing we've seen a lot of
complex mechanisms lots of optimizations
potential for bugs right very complex
code bases we've also seen very powerful
bugs so it's it's not uncommon that one
bug is really enough to bypass all
mitigations in in a super reliable
manner and super quickly and the whole
thing is also again kind of this
performance versus security trade-off
right now the engines they all go for
performance right they want to do these
very complex optimization to produce as
fast code as possible which results in
complex code
potentially for security bugs right so
nothing really new and as I said there's
some further reference is just a list of
kind of interesting articles the site
will be published so you can take a look
now and with that Thanks
thanks for listening
[Applause]
[Music]