hi good morning black I'm J little I'm a
principal security engineer at relevance
and I've been working in the computer
security field for about 10 years I
originally got into it by playing CTFs
on teams like white Hatter's 40 thieves
hate irony Marauders and I used to run a
CTF called ghost in the shell code and
in the past year or so I've been working
on the theorem smart contracts it's been
pretty exciting because it's like a
whole new technology stack at trilha
bits we're a security research and
development firm we're headed quarters
in New York but half of our employees
are remote we work in a few different
areas for research we make foundational
tools like binary lifters that are
usually based on white papers and we
release as much as possible we release
as much as possible on github an open
source for engineering then we custom
security software like OS query
extensions and we also perform security
assessments from everything from user
space libraries to kernel drivers to
block train chain contracts so for what
I'll be going over today I'll give a
quick overview of aetherium it's virtual
machine called EVM in the front of the
most popular front-end language solidity
then I'll go over a few classes of
vulnerabilities that can exist and I'll
show some tools that can help you find
them then I'll talk about the
unfortunate pains of running your own
aetherium software and then we'll
finally talk about how to analyze
transactions traces and look at
contracts that have been destroyed so
for what prompted this earlier this year
I was working on a project with my
friend Ryan storts and we were talking
about how to analyze an secure value
from aetherium contracts one of my parts
for this was to get a copy of all the
contracts
it's the blockchain everything should be
there but I noticed that when I tried to
get some of them it just returned an
empty value represented by this zero X
and this led me to a whole lot of
questions and that's this presentation
so let's get into some of the details
but first who here has bought aetherium
before
oh wow it's a lot and who has sent a
transaction to a contract no stola and
who has made your own contract and has
anybody had their contract hacked no
hands okay well one guys with fifty
fifty so maybe he doesn't know so let's
get into the basics of aetherium
aetherium is a distributed blockchain
system
it's like killer feature is called smart
ranch smart contracts these are little
programs that execute on every node in
the network this leads to it being
called the world computer it's currently
the second most valuable cryptocurrency
according to a snapshot on Quay mark cap
and over the past few years a lot of
banks and have shown interest in it the
main that launched just over three years
ago
so everything's relatively new a little
bit about the implementation its
formally described in this yellow paper
written by Gavin wood it's literally
yellow but there's a much more
approachable version called the beige
paper that has a lot less Sigma's and
other math symbols don't worry I'll be
reading this to you verbatim or anything
as some better examples so let's talk
about transactions that can happen
between accounts so accounts are think
of them like a bank account they're
uniquely identifiable 160 bit numbers
I'm just gonna use emojis instead
because the numbers not show up very
well on PowerPoint and the rest is also
like a postal code or a routing number
you can send a transaction to any
account you'd like an account could send
money called ether to another account
and there are special accounts called
contracts that have code that runs
whenever a transaction has sent to that
these transactions are grouped together
into a grouping called a block and
that's what's actually saved on the
network so for a little bit about the
etherium virtual machine that the
contracts run it's a big-endian stack
machine it's got about 185 op codes
currently there's more added
incrementally over over the course of
time the native bit width is
256 bits and most of the address spaces
are also that same with one interesting
part is that about a quarter of the
possible opcode address space that's one
byte is used up by very similar
instruction so there's a unique outcome
for push one byte on to the stack and
push five bytes on the stack and so on
each of these instructions have a gas
cost to prevent infinite loops on the
world computer and things like added
subtracts how much lower gas costs in
storing into the permanent ledger a good
reference for more about EVM is ether V
Mao or this EVM opcodes repository I
made on github so for a little bit about
what these address spaces look like
there's about five of them maybe six
depending on how you view a few things
but the important part is that most of
them start at address zero so your code
is mapped in at zero that is what where
execution starts on every transaction
storage is for your contract is start
said zero as well but most people don't
make their contracts in solidity or
sorry any VM that you write them in
solidity instead because it's a lot
easier to use solidity is kind of like
JavaScript with maybe a little dash of
Python thrown in it's meant to be
expressive and pretty easy to read
solidity compiles down to EVM very
directly it's a very new compiler it's
only a couple years old the
optimizations can literally only get
better and this language has evolved
more than it has been designed and
making incremental changes that break
backwards compatibility every few months
so here's an example contract this code
can essentially be deployed directly
into the etherium network - go for it -
go over it kind of quickly there's two
state fields of state variables owner
and jar jar's a mapping mapping is
basically an associative dictionary
these state variables persist across
transactions when the contract is
created the constructor is executed in
this case it saves the Creator into the
owner field and then there are a couple
functions bake and eat these are
callable by anyone on the network anyone
who has an accountant aetherium can call
in to these functions and finally
there's a closed function that does a
validity check and what's the owner or
tree value from the contract so in this
example like the owner has been the
cookie shop that's been baking cookies
and getting money every time it bakes a
cookie because a person has to send in
0.1 ether to make some cookies and when
they're done they want to get that money
back and a common way to do this is with
the self-destruct function and opcode so
let's look at what happens when a
contracts created manual creation of
contracts happens when an account sends
a little bit of money to cover the gas
costs for creating the contract and the
contract creation code to address zero
so what happens is just what you'd
expect it creates a new contract
represented by this robot the owner is
set to who created it and a jar is
basically empty everything is
initialized to zero so for the corollary
operation closed what happens like I say
before the close function gets its
prototype gets hashed the first four
bytes are used as a mixer and that
transaction gets sent from the owner to
the contract
it runs self-destruct and so the robot
sends money back to the owner and then
the contract goes away after this
transaction there can be no further
trade transactions to this contract but
let's not focus on that too much let's
talk up more about cookies here's a few
examples of what some transactions look
like anyone can call bake
so here we have two calls of an
astronaut calling bake and one weight
lifter collide bake and at the bottom
there's a representation of what that
looks like
so the astronaut has a few cookies and
and so does the weight lifter but let's
talk a little bit about eat he takes an
argument this argument is the type of
youant that is short for um 256 and
these arguments are big endian so this
is what the transaction would look like
and as we see if the weightlifter calls
like eat 5 to the contract it will the
contract will just subtract the count
and the state will be agreed on by
everyone does this look suspect to
anybody there's a little bug in this
simple contract as it turns out there's
an integer overflow I'm the only
subtraction and the whole thing so what
happens if the detective sleuth emoji
contract calls eat one on the contract
well contest or just initialize to 0 so
0 minus 1 is ffffff a lot of us and then
here's an example where somebody would
have a whole lot of cookies or they
wouldn't expect so that's just one
example of something that can go wrong
in solidity integer under flows but I'd
like to describe a few more for a
language designed in this decade there
are a lot of issues that lead to
confusion by developers can me john
expects the states and some of those can
lead both to developer confusion in to
vulnerabilities so letís working on
correcting their tooling and the
language specification but it still has
a lot of work to do i can just go on for
hours about all this but just to
highlight a few type inference and re
links are things that are going away in
the next version of solidity because
they're just removing that feature and
like to talk about one more
uninitialized variables this is a
contract i found on the reddit eath
subreddit and this was used as a
backdoor the basically there's a few
state variables and this
contract the important one here is
secret seed and it turns out that when
you declare a variable but don't
initialize it it just gets initialized
to zero piece of course it would and so
what happens on this line if this is
seed components s it actually creates a
noose
a pointer to zero and when these
assignments happen it overwrites the ste
variables so this bottom line overwrites
the secret seed and this was used to
backdoor a lottery system for more
examples we have a repository on github
called not-so-smart contracts they have
concise examples and triggers for many
kinds of vulnerabilities so now giving
you a little taste of what can go wrong
in the contract but I'd like to show
some tools that can help discover issues
and understand them better I think the
best tool out there for analyzing binary
contracts is ether splay so our binary
ninja I'll get it displayed is really
really good control flow recovery and a
lot of works been put into it and it
displays it in a nice graph view like
this it also has a dictionary of over
30,000 function signatures like I've
showed before so I can show you useful
information like the name of functions
and the parameter types if you'd rather
use Ida Pro than binary ninja I've
ported some of the you display features
to an Ida Pro processor module it's
still very much a work in progress but
if you if you want to look more like if
you used to Ida you can definitely use
that instead a useful website is ether
p.m. tada oh I mention this before for a
top code reference but one day they
released a decompiler on their website
so if you don't mind sending your code
to the website it'll give you a
decompiler output it's not perfect but
it's definitely way better than keeping
track of a state machine in your head or
on a sheet of paper for another tool
there's a myth roll made by consensus
it's basically a Swiss Army knife
can analyze solidity can analyze
binaries you can query the live
blockchain for some information it can
perform searches for certain byte
sequences on the boxing or code
sequences and it also has a graph view
representation for some like hot off the
press kind of news rattle is a tool made
by my friend Ryan it lifts EVM to an IR
that IR has a single static assignment
form and it can do a lot of
optimizations to simplifications it can
actually go between basic blocks and
summarize code this is something that
Susilo T compiler itself doesn't really
even do yet it can also analyze all the
references to a certain memory address
source it's a storage address and
recover some variable information this
is the example output it's like a dot
file and for one more tool it's
Manticore our Python symbolic execution
framework
it supports x86 and arm but about a year
ago we added IBM support so it
symbolically executes contract
blockchain states it's got a bunch of
cool features can emulate multiple
transactions multiple contracts it'll
automatically explore all the paths in
your contract and it will also emit an
output directory full of concrete test
cases for it so that's just a preview of
all the many of the tools that are
available there's more every month so
now for a bit of the ugly part running
your own aetherium software this is very
much hindsight advice before you run
your own node you definitely want to
check your storage requirements this is
on the FAQ for parity and Kev but the
best resource I found is on Stack
Exchange basically if you want to run a
full node you will need over 1.1
terabytes so I'll say personally I
filled up a 500 gig SSD first and then a
terabyte one huh and then I bought a 2
terabyte
another thing that's not really talked
about all that much is disk throughput
matters you're basically maxing out your
AI ops for days and days of day so for
example with singing parody I actually
double the total disk rights to my SSD
just syncing the blockchain so there's
two options for running aetherium
software they call a client I'll just
call it a note because our client would
be me so the official implementation is
called gif I guess the GSP as it's
written go and it uses leveldb as its
back-end for key value store parody the
alternative implementation is written in
rust and uses rocks DB the public note
percentages here just from the show down
scan from a few weeks ago so there's a
few different types of clients not
everybody needs one terabyte of space or
more to do to use the etherium network
so both death and parody have
implemented some of the public client it
can't really verify all the previous
transactions - just trust they're true
and you can actually use this one on the
hard drive accordance with the docs I
haven't tested that most people who are
curious about transactions that want to
run a fast client after about five or
six days it'll be fully synced and you
can query it if you want to film a full
client type that can query any
transaction arbitrarily you'll need at
least about 200 gigs of space and you'll
need over 1.5 terabytes
if you want to get traces for every
transaction so four options for running
these running a full note is not the
default so I've highlighted some of the
options basically use sync mode equals
full GC Modi's are equals archive that
says dome from purge your old state the
bottom two options are for performance
tuning and it let's just adjust much
less often with the bottom one and the
traces are exposed in the debug RPC API
kind of equivalent options for parody
pruning equals arc
tracing equals on there's many more
performance tuning options and parody
I found a github issue for this txq
sighs somebody was setting it to max int
but then it would just panic the rest
clients so I wouldn't really recommend
anybody turn that on and they also have
some JSON server query query
optimizations so if you want to be able
to core your core you're faster so I
have some suggestions just when you're
running the software be very patient if
something messes up just our MRF it
don't get sentimental II attached to
your 600 gigabyte chain data folder or
you can redownload it and know that it's
right definitely recommend using Linux
and the fastest SSD you can find it will
seriously max out also just for anybody
who's running their own client don't
also browse the web from the machine
running your JSON RPC because of DNS
rebinding it can be a bad time
so we run software and we just wait a
few days and we can analyze contracts
right and we can finally start to answer
some of these questions so who created
this contract how do we how do we tell
this well the answer is tracing and here
is how to call the tracing API parity
has a slightly different implementation
than guess they have different options
but here's what an output trace looks
like and we can actually answer a whole
bunch of these questions we can know
what the this is a the example of the
trace for the last transaction sent to
the contract we can see who it's from
that it this is the actual self-destruct
part because it's saying it's from the
contract to a different destination and
it has a value that's how much ether was
sent so if we printed by this a little
bit there's more information to actually
answering the wind' question we know the
block number we know who created the
contract and this is a quick summary of
all the transactions
the creator of the contract added a
little bit of either to it this new
account sent some unknown Tran command
and then it's into command that we know
called kill and then the self-destruct
record and it's sense the point to about
point to ether to this new new account
so what is this attack was this an
attack maybe it definitely motivated me
to get through scanning the whole
blockchain and seeing what else is out
there but it's a little more tricky than
just getting a trace it turns out that
on the blockchain it's a distributed
ledger not a database you can't just
query like say select star from
transactions to an address you have to
iterate over every block and we're doing
something that atheneum isn't really
meant to do because we're going back and
looking at transactions from two years
ago most people wouldn't care but
definitely kind of curious so we have to
go through a lot of blocks so what's in
a block as I said before blocks out
transactions transactions have all sorts
of metadata who it's from who it's to if
there's input if there's gas if code was
created and there's also a seat field
that can can tell you most of this and
for how we get blocks programmatically
there's a client API there's two popular
ones that are in the etherium github web
3j s and web 3dep I both have gone
through breaking API changes within the
last few months I believe web three
touches has switched over to promises it
can hopefully do some more synchronous
calls in web 3 pi in version 4.0 they
switched iPhone 3 and totally deprecated
their Python 2 library so I was forced
to upgrade everything to Python 3 and
for a little bit about how you talk
connect these clients to the etherium
node you can use IPC if you're on the
same machine
you can use WebSockets if you're curious
about streaming events like filters and
you can use RPC for everything else
so here's finally some actual code this
is how you just iterate over every block
we pass a flag to say full transactions
equals true this just prefetches all the
transaction data that we're gonna eat it
anyway for each transaction we get the
receipt if there is a contract address
field in the receipt we know that a new
contract was created then we go and
check the code if the code is empty then
it's likely that it might have been self
destructed there's a few other
conditions that I'll talk about later
the other thing we can check for is this
status field being equal to one this is
only in available after block or million
three hundred and seventy thousand for
the post byzantine fork i believe and
this is a much better filter versus an
error in creation but running this
client software isn't always so easy a
lot of times you might not get synced
fully for example if you see Jeff saying
imported new State entries or updated
chain data
don't try to query it you won't get
valid results back and a lot of some
times you won't actually get caught up
to the current block sometimes parity is
not any better if you are running parity
and you're looking in the in your
console and you see this yellow number
to the left that means you can't query
past that block number and get any valid
results back also I found out in the
current version if you turn on a lot of
archiving options it'll crash eventually
but don't worry I reported that and
they're working on a fix so with these
clients not able to always get us what
we need we need a solution and there's
only one hope and it's either scammed IO
it's really a great resource at website
you can just they've done the database
query for you basically so for any
contract you want you can get a list of
transactions in a few seconds just by
using their website they also have some
features our contract authors can upload
their source code and verify that it's
what they say it is so we'll take a
hybrid approach we'll run our local
software to do that code that I showed
earlier just to get a list of all the
contracts and then forgetting the traces
I'll use ether scan they have an API
actually it'll list both internal and
external transactions the way it does
say to limit to five queries per second
so if you have tens of thousands of
contracts you're curious about like I do
it'll take a few hours but it will
finish eventually so finally some
results type out so I queried from block
0 to 6 million that was from a few weeks
ago and found out that there have been
about total of 2 million contracts
created in the etherium network on main
that and of those about 55,000 are empty
is your X so I was like wow I had no
idea what to expect I just looked at my
I just didn't LS and WC - no so how many
there were and I got curious like what
if I md5 them how many of these are
actually unique and it turns out about
half of them are duplicates in some way
and the other thing to note is that
about 32,000 of them or empty and had a
balance of zero this so there were some
that are empty that had a balance and I
was kind of weird because if they were
destroyed by a self-destruct they
wouldn't have any balance because it
transfers all the balance to the
argument so I started looking at what
are these 0x contracts and it turns out
the first one is kind of an interesting
case we're almost at the three year
anniversary of this this was the first
attempt at creating a contract and I say
attempts because they didn't pass in
enough gas to create it
I believe when it hit this s store RS or
uses 20,000 gas and they just didn't
send enough but if you
use the clients to query this it just
returns empty later that day there was a
contract that contract was co-created
there was empty but it doesn't have any
code in it they just sent an empty
transaction about a input value the kind
of disappointing part of this is you'll
see in value the the person who did this
sent fourteen ether to this so now this
contract that has no code permanently
forever has about seven thousand dollars
a V theory imminent but later later that
day there was a contract that was
created successfully but just to kind of
show that there's noise and transactions
and that everything is immutable
a couple months ago somebody decided to
send 420 in way as value to this
contract that doesn't do anything with
it and then later that day somebody also
sent at 69 way so I was curious about
more of these duplicates so I just did
like unique def see saw what was the
most common one and this was kind of
interesting in the contracts here
basically just infinite loops it kind of
jumps back into itself in a few spots
and it calls code copy which takes the
code you see here and copies it into
memory it turns out that some people on
Stack Exchange say that this is a
network dos because it just to keep
reading code and several accounts since
this about ten thousand times to go
along with that second example from
before there have been about another
10,000 accounts created that have a
total of about 2.5 million dollars but
they have a new code behind them so
there's no way to get it back for one
more example of duplicates this one was
kind of funny it was just really big
there are 6,000 adults and
these contract this contract code so it
doesn't actually make it the contract
doesn't actually do anything it because
in all this the stop opcode but that
6000 number is kind of interesting I
noticed that in this VIP basically the
RFC s4 aetherium
and 170 the maximum size is hex 6000 so
maybe whoever was trying to fill up the
blockchain and I had a heck forces
decimal conversion problem and there's
one more interesting example of and here
we've actually have a real self
destructs there's a few thousand of
these where they just push address and
call self-destruct that's the total
purpose of this contract and in the
transaction trace they all send zero one
or two way basically nothing like even
like an ADD opcode cost three-way so I
went on ether scan and looked at what
this look like and we just see this huge
list of self-destructs there I think
about 500 in this transaction and it's
actually it's like what's going on this
is really weird
I haven't seen anybody really talk about
it and it turns out that this is the net
effect of that transaction well it
actually happened was there were a whole
bunch of contracts created each one was
set to send a message to another one
it would then self-destruct and just
kind of spam out on the network this
only happened a few times but it
definitely filtered out a whole lot of
transactions just because it was just a
whole lot of noise or about three or
four thousand of these in total so after
all that filtering down to about two
thousand contracts I think this was a
previous slide was like 1988 we round up
so we filtered it out a lot of spam some
dust attempts a lot of noise and let's
get into some specific criteria for
finding these cases of self-destructs
so I'll just kind of give a high-level
overview with more emojis
to explain what we're looking for so if
somebody creates a contract that's
totally normal so some things we may be
interested in is when the self-destruct
when somebody when the owner sends a
self-destruct to the robot at the robot
contracts and then that ends up sending
money to a different address it wasn't
the original creator that can be a red
flag another red flag would be as if
somebody who wasn't the original creator
causes the self-destruct transaction so
let's do some more filtering in and see
what meets these conditions so again
from the trace we know the destination
of these self-destruct transfer and when
we filter who was not the original
creator there's only 630 contracts and a
kind of depressing fact about 10 of
those is they self-destructed and since
their money to address 0 so it kind of
burned it forever the most unfortunate
of these is somebody sent 50 ether
that's several thousand dollars in this
transaction and in the ether scan trace
the owner called a kill command that
took an argument called - and just was
all zeros so I don't know if they did
this intentionally but it is kind of
unfortunate to see somebody lose what's
like $20,000 in today's value another
one of these transactions that I got
kind of excited about was the largest
self-destruct in history where it sent
10,000 'if but I think this is after
looking at the transaction traces I
think it's ok I can't be completely sure
because I don't know who all the
accounts are but in this contract it
implemented a parody multi-sig Walla it
was likely vulnerable to this and it
wallet attack basically there were some
initialize variables in the in the
constructor so done by a function later
but anybody can call that function and
initially influence the state of it so
the first transaction to this contract
was calling an it wallet and but I
followed it later and nobody transferred
in 10,000 aetherium to it
that 10,000 ethereal transfer happened
as the self-destruct happened in the
same transaction so I think this was
actually a system set up as part of a
token presale and they just happen to
get lucky and nobody redirected their
transfer for one example of the this
parody anit wallet attack at the bottom
of this slide these are the actual
attacks that are probably the largest
ever on the etherion network this one
person got over a hundred and twenty
thousand ether in a couple of minutes
doing the attack but it wasn't this one
so it's kind of bummed about that so
let's do some more filtering and we have
these hundred and then we'll have from
630 down to about 160 transactions where
the originator of the self-destructs
wasn't the original creator and then
just looking at these there's only 25
that have sent more than point 1 e and
16 that sent ye so there actually hasn't
been a lot of these like mass hacks
using self-destructs but because there's
so few I kind of like look through every
one and I'll show you some of the
results
so this was one of the largest transfers
on the self-destructs where 308th was
sent to a different address from from a
transaction that was not the original
creator but going through the trace we
find out that this was actually
intentional this first argument from was
the original creator and they just Tramp
the contract was coded to allow somebody
else to be the owner so this is actually
a totally okay thing to do and they were
just using the etherion features this
will be a little bit of a trend as well
see so this one kind of stood out to me
in my list because it has a really
interesting address address it's like
dice EE and it turns out that if you
look at the Creator they've created
several contracts including some that
have source code available and it's just
a gambling game and this is yet another
example of where the transaction came
from somebody else but it's was actually
totally intentional and this one sent 65
ether that's a lot
so there's turns out there's even more
gambling on the blockchain here's
another one that turns out to be
intentional
it's called ether Wow the Google
Translate says it's the most popular
blockchain guessing digital game in
China I'm not so sure because there's
only been a few ether ever transferred
into any of these things and in a
different version of this the creator's
created several contracts and if you
trace through them one of them has
source code available and there's this
really dramatic comment above their
owner kill function to be very careful
emergency only for contract upgrading so
again this is yet another example with
these large transfers but it doesn't
look like it's an attack it's just the
design of the contract
so I finally have one that's a real
example of a likely attack basically
there's this contract that ended up
calling this mortal function and it was
the exact conditions we want it was
somebody who is not the original creator
of the contract the destination wasn't
the original creator either and I can't
be sure exactly what happened because we
don't know the intent behind everything
but it what it looks like is somebody
copied some code from this immortal
contract which its intended
functionality is to initialize the owner
and if you're the owner you can kill the
contract but I think somebody probably
renamed the contracts if they're for
exposing this mortal function to anybody
because somebody totally called this
function and became the owner and got a
couple ether
so we learned from all of this there's
not a lot of like epic attacks on the
blockchain a few of them do happen but
it's really difficult to go in and tell
what happened a few years ago to
actually analyze this I couldn't even do
it on my own computer I needed to use
ether scan to help fill in a lot of the
blanks so if you're in theory developer
here I'd strongly recommend you
understand and fix all of your warnings
maybe use the or echidna testing
framework to help make better tests just
few early rigorous if you'd like some
help
performing the assessment under your
contracts definitely get in touch with
us we're very thorough if you're a
security researcher become a blockchain
Explorer it's kind of fun you fill up
your whole hard drive and you can like
do some sequel queries later but grubart
have patience and if you're into
symbolic execution check out Manticore
and thank you for your attention
[Applause]