welcome and congratulations for making
it all the way almost all the way to the
end of blackhat and for joining here and
listening into our talk let me assure
you you won't regret it because after
this talk you may look a little bit
different at some of the devices you
have like your phone your laptop your
tablets your watches now let me first
ask you a question and I want to see
some hands who does have a device that
has a webcam yeah I guess majority of
people what can we do I think most most
laptops most phones have webcams so who
has actually sat in front of a computer
and was wondering am I being watched
am I being recorded yeah quite a couple
of hands and so what we're going to show
you today is that this scenario is not
really unrealistic but it not must not
necessarily there is a human on the
other side watching you instead it could
be malware that is sitting on your
computer already for a while I may be
watching you stealthily so I'm leading
the cognitive cyber security
intelligence team at IBM Research and
I'm being joined here with two of my
colleagues didn't kirat I'm Chi Yong
Chang at IBM research we have a long
tradition of analyzing new technologies
new threats that were being posed by
these new technologies how do these
technologies emerge and what do they
mean for the cyber threat landscape when
we look back at what happened the world
last UK decades every shift of
technology has impacted cyber security
quite a bit in the PC era viruses worms
came up and they stayed till today later
on in the web era we had cross-site
scripting cross-site request forgery
that was affecting many websites now
more recently we have seen a big push
with AI a
becoming very powerful but also becoming
highly accessible to people in fact you
know you can download lots of AI
libraries that can do many great things
today open source available and we can
call this a democratization of AI
everybody pretty much having access to
AI and indeed we've seen many amazing
things that come out of AI people using
a and create great tools however AI can
be used for different purposes good
purposes but also you know less less
good purposes and in fact bad guys cyber
criminals out there are studying up on
AI and use it for their advantage and
weaponize it so we've seen very recently
a number of examples of AI is being used
to create new forms of attacks making
them stronger harder more evasive for
example we've seen how researchers have
shown that you can create emails with AI
that evades existing spam filters or how
they are mining social networks to find
very targeted people that that the the
spam campaigns should go after or last
year blackhat we've seen Hiram Anderson
talk about how he's using genetic
algorithms and reinforcement learning to
create ways of how the malware can
mutate existing malware and then bypass
antivirus filters or even you know AI
making attacks very creative changing
things that the human attackers wouldn't
have anticipated we've seen some
examples also last year where there has
been intrusion sequel injections where
the AI hasn't even understood what
sequel is we call these types of attacks
ai aided attacks now what we're going to
show you today and talk about today is a
different form that we call a I embedded
attacks so different to what we've seen
where you use
to kind of craft different types of
malware or run some type of of campaigns
with the AI here the AI is really deeply
embedded in a piece of malware almost
you know think of like bringing the
brain of the cyber criminal into the
malware itself and take decisions so
what we're going to show you is really
how attackers can take AI readily
available for them and create new forms
of attacks in particular we're looking
at something that is becoming extremely
invasive and extremely stealthy so the
AI is really being used to create a way
to hide the presence of the malware and
to evade from detection so in this
context let me briefly talk about the
evolution of evasive malware and this is
really you know I kept in my house case
we know this very well in the security
domain we have attack attackers or
malware creators that wrote some piece
of malware and they realized antivirus
systems are picking up on it they have
signatures to find our malware obviously
they went on they then did some
obfuscation we've seen you know how they
mutated payload polymorphic and
metamorphic malware came out which then
led to the security industry to look at
program analysis trying to deallocate
what's going on and then understand
there is some bad things in that payload
attackers went on adding encryption
packers to to basically hide the
malicious payload security industry on
the other side enhance then okay let's
take a dynamic enemy analysis malware
sandboxes run these things to see what's
going on Marva Riders came back we're
gonna check for malware sandboxes are
there any processes are there BMS where
we were executed then we're not gonna
execute
and so on and so forth you know we had
anti anti-malware monte anti sandboxing
technologies then by the security
industry all the way to you know
attackers really creating very crap
and attacks at malware that only execute
under very specific conditions and you
know then only show their malicious
intent now what's the next step because
when we look at this we realize in all
cases we have some clues for the Malheur
analyst in this malware if you look at
this manually line by line you see a
couple of interesting things there's
always a key it may be physically
present in the malware or it may be
received via command control Network and
then there are these checks so you can
still very well see that if you're
really analyzing the malware that there
is some malicious things going on there
is some intent but what if there is no
key what if there is only a key maker
embedded and that key maker can decide
when to generate a key and under what
conditions a key can be generated
so we developed a proof-of-concept and
we call it deep blocker we develop this
to demonstrate how easily today
attackers can take AI and can create
such key makers at a very hard if not
impossible to reverse engineer so I'm
going to hand it over to my colleague
young to take you through a demo of how
deep blocker can work in practice all
right thank you Mark so some of you who
came to the room already and we get we
are busy on the stage and might be
curious what are these guys doing with
the camera wrapped up as you can expect
we are going to show a quick demo and
the demo is about to demonstrate what
the cybercriminals maybe can do with the
AI
and what kind of the targeted and
evasive your tech may be achieve so
specifically for this demo and we are
going to show the HUD how the tip
blocker can be widely distributed while
remaining Stacy so from the last year
you may remember there was ccleaner
incident it was quite sad story so
secret now is one of the popular windows
duty
the program that is supposed to clean up
your windows registries and file which
is not necessary but unfortunately the
problem was that the secret of their
superior development as pipelines could
compromise such that their resume
download server started hosting the
ccleaner with malicious code embedded
and the problem was that the malicious
version of synchrony had been downloaded
by more than 2 millions of users which
is quite significant number support a
demonstration purpose we design program
called the talk which is about video
conferencing application for the
demonstration purpose the crease maybe
we can switch in to the camera to input
to camera yeah is it too dark is it ok
maybe too dark as you can see there is
wrapped up and as a user I'm gonna go
ahead and download to start using the
program video conferencing application
called talk ok there is application
download I'm gonna download the program
saved to my computer ok
I should have my program at the tunnel
hood ok now we have the program of
course whenever there is new updates
comes in people go to download the new
binary and always they renew the contain
start using the final program and this
happened many many times so I'm gonna
start using this program and I'm gonna
run it so program is running as you see
this is program code talk and which is
video compress application nothing
suspicious happen everything looks
normal so at this moment what may not be
obvious is that actually the malicious
code inside is program and it is
specifically tailored for the one
specific person so put this demo so I'm
gonna invite one person from the
audience for the demo and who is our
speaker is own Bob and Bob can you
please come onto the stage so Bob Allah
Allah please
so as a normal user okay you probably
start using we're trying to using the
program and okay maybe you'll get yeah
Oh what happened so you just see maybe I
hope to Jim in a little bit so you see
the famous want to cry dancing where it
just pop up so what just happen is there
the video the webcam of this camera just
to see the Buffs face and he released
the malicious payload which was water
cry in this case so what happened was
that we specifically trained this
program to recognize specific target for
demo the bout was parent here and used
Bob's face as a specific target and this
program is actively looking for a
specific person and until you can put
specific person to release the program
Chris can you switch into the slide tag
thank you so as you can demonstrate the
cyber criminals can embed any kind of
the malicious software into any kind of
benign program using a technique so what
it makes extremely dangerous is that as
you can see it may in fact millions of
people but it may reveal the malicious
intent or near a specific target so it
becomes really Stacy it may be evading
or the different s end boxing or static
analysis cut technique so it makes
extremely hard to understand and decode
and interact the program then a teaspoon
or probably you have in mind okay how
this can be done and from now on I'm
going back to tell you to Kosar what's
really happening inside of the tip taco
AI factory alright I hope you enjoyed
the demo so so far we can see that we're
using AI or the attacker it is in the AI
to detect or recognize the target but
the story is not only that the story is
that it's also concealing what it's
targeting
and I'm gonna focus on that part the
scaling part of the target so if we look
into you know very from the higher level
what is a targeted attack right it's
simply a very simplistic you know if if
condition where it asks this question
which is is this you know system is a
target and if the answer is no the
program is gonna end and if the app
targeted yes is going to execute its
attack so we can see that you know for
example in Stuxnet if you look into the
code you will see that it's actually
checking for the presence of certain
application in this case step 7
application and if it sees that
application then only it's gonna execute
its attack so for any targeted attack to
be very very stealthy there are two
components that it really wants to hide
the first one is the target specifics
about the target like what it's
targeting and the second is the actual
attack was the real goal of the attack
and we see this logic that no matter
where this attack is running it must ask
this question before it you know steps
further that is it a target and we can
see that and the problem is if there is
a model analyst looking into this
malware it will see that it's ax in the
question and then they can simply pass
that question that is basically past
that if condition and directly jump into
the actual malware code and run in a
sandbox and see what exactly it's trying
to do but we realized that at this very
simplistic form of if then if this then
that kind of construct can be actually
transformed into a very convoluted and
very complicated a logic of decision
logic using deep neural network so what
I mean by that is the attacker is using
deep neural network to decide whether to
attack or not and then the problem for
the defender is that looking at this AI
model it's going to be very very
difficult
to figure out what it's targeting and
when is there what is the right target
and that figure out the actual malicious
code so why is that the case to
understand a little bit more into that
let's quickly look into what exactly
neural network is so it's basically from
the very high level is basically we have
three layers the input layer you know
hidden layer and output layer input
layer probably is getting some sort of
sequence of pixels that represents a cat
for example the hidden layer is doing
its you know magic and producing some
probabilistic score that whether it's a
cat or dog or something else and inside
the hidden layer there are multiple
layers of computational nodes that are
using the input and transferring the
value to the output there are also some
linear and nonlinear layers that's
making this Network more complex and is
able to capture and learn a lot of
complex concept of the input this is
this form of neural network is actually
quite old dating back to 60s but the
recent iteration of the neural network
which we call the deep convolutional
neural network is actually introducing
this new type of neuron called the
convolutional neuron that is able to
learn about new filters and understand
high-level concepts of the input such as
you know painting style of van gaal or
something like that and that's great
that's really great and we have seen
great results with this new form of
neural networks but that what is
interesting about these deep neural
networks is that they are very very
complex and deep to analyze understand
what's happening for example this is a
Alex Nate which was one of the very
first deep neural network that was able
to produce really good result it is
Italy it has eight layers and already
six hundred thousand-plus neurons and 60
million plus parameters see if somebody
wants to know what's happening inside
it's going to be very difficult and in
fact
the whole community have been trying to
understand and interpret what's
happening inside how they're encoding
the knowledge and how the different
neural network AI models are encoding
different aspects of the input
parameters it's difficult
well the attacker can actually use that
fact that it's very difficult to
understand and analyze these logics and
use that to conceal the information of
the target they encode their logic of
target detection inside the deep neural
network that's exactly what the deep
Locker is doing here
and since we are using deep neural
network it can actually consume
different types of variety of target
attributes for example in this
particular demo we saw that it was
looking at the video and trying to
capture the face but it doesn't have to
stop there it can't look for audio can
try to recognize some voice recognition
it can look for a software environment
so that in this case of Stuxnet it can
look for more you know advanced a user
behavior and attack certain types of
user maybe a manager or developer or
something like that it can look for a
geolocation to pinpoint its target it
can even look for sensors and what I
mean by the sensor is that for example
we all have you know cameras in our
phones and these sensors during is a
manufacturing process there are
non-linearity in these their pixels all
the pixels are not the same they have
you know different sensitivity to light
and you can actually turns out extract
those very specific you know a
distribution of this non-linearity in
your sensor from your maybe you know
pictures that you post in your social
media and then use that in code that
into DN a model and detect that a
specific you know phone and only target
that of course using all these sensors
and availabilities geolocation and all
that you can even derive a very
high-level physical environment clue
using all the sensors and whatever the
attributes you can access so how would
somebody would if
if they want to implement it how they go
about it so attacker usually in the case
of face recognition
there are a DNN that are trained to
recognize face and generate some kind of
a feature vector of the face that the
facial feature vector in some high
dimensional space and if you want to
detect the target a naive way would be
to implement some kind of a template
matching and what that is is basically
you have a target template that's the
feature vector of the target and when
you grab the input and generate a new
feature vector and you compare with the
template basically computing some kind
of a distance and if the threshold is
lower than what you expect you detect
that it's a target
however the template matching requires a
template to match and that's a problem
because so you have to include this
reference face inside your malware right
the attacker has to include this
template and that means you are giving
away some information about the target
it's not concealing the information
about the target so we realize that
instead of training the DNN to spit out
this you know feature vector for the
facial feature vector you can actually
train the DNN to generate a unique key a
deterministic key that is only generated
when it sees the target so with this the
attacker will be able to completely
conceal what's the target is because
it's all inside the DNN model which is
very difficult to decipher and using
this key it can also encrypt the actual
payload which is the real bad thing and
hide it completely independent so from
to overview that so basically if
targeted have the target generation the
first there are two stages first you do
the concealment that is you generate the
the malware for that the attacker has to
first figure out you know what are the
attributes he or she wants to use to
target the attack and then it he has to
select some secret
key and then train the DNN model so that
it generates the key when it says that
those particular attributes and using
that key it can encrypt the actual
payload and generate a concealed payload
and in in the unlocking phase the DNN
will look for these attributes and if
and only if it sees these attributes it
recovers the key and converts the
concealed payload into the real payload
and executes it only at the target so if
you see that the attacker only has to
transmit or two things from from this
process
that's the DNN model and the conceal
target so the only two things so there
is no key to devote and uncover from
from the distribution of the malware and
it will be very very difficult for any
analyst meno and analysts to find out
the key because it's hidden in in the AI
model of the target either you need to
know the target which is already a
secret and until you don't know the
target you don't have the key and if you
know don't have the key you don't know
what's the the payload is so let's look
at a little bit into the key generation
for the case of face detection so
usually there is the DNN model that
generates some kind of feature vector
that I as I mentioned before and then
one naive way of converting this to key
would be to do some sort of quick bucket
ization right if it's you know two zero
to one and creating a beeps for your key
if it's zero point nine it converts to
one if zero point zero or one it
converts to zero and so far and so forth
but turns out if you use this kind of
pocket Isis and the key is very unstable
that is even for the same person's face
the the feature vectors are there are
enough randomness that one or two bits
is going to be flipped and then your key
is not going to be the same and you not
be able to properly attack generate the
attack and this is because these you
know high dimensional feature vectors
are close in the higher dimensional
space but the individual dimensions may
have you know some variation there so we
realize that instead of
using the bucket digestion it can also
be replaced by another
DNN model so basically what you do is
you select some random key and train the
key generation model what we call the
key generation model to spit out that
specific key whenever it sees these
parameters or the special feature
vectors and this key generation model is
a type of multi-class classification
model where the outputs nodes represent
a bit or class and you train such that
you know for example if we select a key
that is 0 1 1 0 1 and all the our ground
proof for the input target would be
class 2 and class 3 and class 5 and if
one belong to class 1 and class 4 so
that would be our ground truth and we
trained that P generation model says
that it whenever it sees the target the
first stage of the DNN produces the
corresponding feature vectors and that
will be mapped into the very specific
deterministic key that we use to encrypt
the payload so we did some analysis with
this approach of key generation model so
we use publicly available data data set
that is the labels faces in public and
what we're seeing here is the
performance of this key generation model
so we have the precision and recall
precision measures how precise the model
is and then the recoil represents how
complete it is for example if the
generation model generates ten valid
keys and turns out those ten valid keys
are generated from real targets so that
we have 100% precision but if there are
20 input target pictures but only ten
was able to generate the real key then
we have only 20% 50% recall so if you
look at the graph we see that it's very
very precise precision is a 100% when
you have enough in a training so what
that means is
whenever it generates a key it is the
target but every call is not hundred
percent but that means maybe some some
images may not convert in the real key
but that's probably not going to be a
problem for an attacker because the
whole goal of the targeted attack is you
know sacrifice they want they sacrifice
the target space but try to be very
stealthy and keep their code away from
the defender so finally with this
approach of AI powered a concealment
what the attacker is able to do is have
three layers of concealment or further
attack the first one is that the target
class consonant and what I mean by that
is when looking at the theme of the
modal key generation model you won't be
able to tell what it is targeting what
class of target it is is it targeting a
individual is it targeting an
organization or maybe is it looking for
something very obscure object that is
only available in the target environment
next layer of concealment is the target
instance consumed and that is if even if
we you know Jase that maybe it's a face
that it's looking for it doesn't tell us
what you know tip in the individuals
face it's looking for what's exactly the
key that is looking for it what's the
actual target so it doesn't we don't
know who is looking for and finally
using the key so it can crips the actual
payload which is the final goal of the
attack and it's completely conceals the
malicious intent of the attack so we see
that you know using this AI power
targeted attacks can create very very
sophisticated and very precise targeted
attacks and that journey is going to
discuss some countermeasures you know a
possible countermeasures for this
imminent threat of high powered attacks
okay so as you can see and the dealer
explained the team record
a very new challenging problem to a
security community and this is actually
the wake-up call to discuss and to think
about what kind of possible
countermeasures
we can develop to protect against this
kind of AI powder attack in order to
develop a new solution
let's first break down this problem into
a small piece so at a very high level so
timenado actually has a two main
component first obviously is about
consider the payload execution which is
about actually the malicious code and
the second component is about how we
conceal the payload and actually intend
using AI and then let's discuss about is
there any kind of the method or cut
possible countermeasure
put to address each of the component so
in terms of prevention so it is highly
desirable to have every code running on
your system is sign poor valid code code
attestation and at the same time if the
program it's not necessary it doesn't
have to have the access to all the
sensors for example if we do new if the
program doesn't suppose help though
listen the audio or video it should not
have the access of microphone and the
camera and in terms of the monitoring
and the detection now we really need a
resilient and powerful the host based
monitoring system so we have developed a
lot of new tapas monitoring but to
detect this kind of sophisticated and
very targeted attack we need to catch
the moment the when the program changed
their behavior for our demo basically
trigger the ransomware so we need to
detect that is the change of moment of
the behavior by monitoring at the host
level and similarly now we also need to
monitoring the how the AI use for
example the outcome about your AI model
for in our case face detection comes out
of generating about all the vector
values and we need to monitor in this
vector values for the mobile application
they said now this day they have
sophisticated model to take face and
maybe changing your appearance making
decorated they also use the AI but in
this case we're generating key and there
is complete difference and we need to
monitoring AR use to detect
is kind of suspicious activities and
obviously if the kiss is small we can
try to brute pros which is obvious way
but it may not work all the time and we
so similarly put the AI so is the
dealing spraying there is a lot of parts
of an attribute or take you may come up
with from the port target attribute but
curious ting may help about what kind of
class or the attribute a looking for so
we can maybe get a kind of initial sense
but of course it may not be perfect and
there is a whole rub research and
development around the cyber deception
and the cyber deception the core is
about how to poison the adversary ie
motor so that they can make a wrong
decision so cyber deception could be one
way to address and a pair of the
execution and the steer the AI to make a
different choice so that we can pull the
way the attackers in the raster II so of
course we can try to reverse-engineer a
road to understand what is the actual
intent of a call and they similarly put
AI part concealment we can reverse
engineer the area model here what we
refer is AI lockpicking
because we develop airlocks missing so
basically a lock-picking is answer the
question about the cuban air motor what
can you learn from it so in other words
they are locking technique is to divide
inside how the internal operation and
behavior of a motor and we don't
understand we need to understand this
internal behavior to better protect
against AI powered attack and of course
from the AI community there has been a
lot of effort to understand and to
visualize and interpret how air motor
works so these are the few example from
the recent the recent literature and
exempt of partial or corrosion to
systematically occur some of the part of
the image to understand which part of
picture is significant affect about
classification result in the mirror you
can see the monitoring the how the
neural excitation work for each of the
radio and the generating heat map again
this is also decoder similar to
understand what picks
in perfect but picture of the input
image is a nearly significant support
the classification wizard and also there
is another part about the debugging so
similarly what we debug our program
- debugging the AI model is any error is
ending kind of the disagreement
different among the different model to
understand how the error motor works
internally so for example using the
frosting techniques which is one of the
recent paper so these all this effort
could help understand how the AI motor
works internally and which can help us
our clue about how we protect our how we
prepare better to prepare the better
solutions against the AI powdered egg
you know to wrap up so I'm gonna hand
over to the mark yeah so we would like
you to take home a few important
messages from what we've shown you today
the very first one is really that with
AI becoming democratized and being
widely available there are new types of
attacks coming our way
we call them a high powered attacks and
there I mean in him an imminent threat
to many of our security systems and
organizations the number of things that
really are going to change in terms of
the characteristics of attacks when AI
is involved we see things become really
highly invasive there is a lot of ways
of making a new level of scale and speed
in the attacks where reasoning and
decision-making can be deeply embedded
into these attacks and there is a known
whole new form of adaptability and
autonomy that these attacks have attacks
becoming really creative and being able
to be extremely surgical and precise
when they're executed now what we've
shown you today is what we call deep
blocker this is really just a proof of
concept to demonstrate how we can use AI
and everybody can use AI to craft new
variants mutations of what of attacks
and threats that we're already knowing
but this time very concealed very shady
very hidden and very precise in
at their execution but deep Locker is
really only scratching the surface we
haven't explored everything in our
research there are many things that can
be done
I mentioned reasoning that can be
embedded into the malware to decide when
to do what let me give you just one
example as really summarizing very much
I would say where this space is heading
take the DARPA Grand Challenge from 2004
where we had self-driving cars competing
in the Mojave Desert to finish a track
only a few cars actually have completed
in the first time but they got better
and better and look where we are today
2018 we have self-driving cars most of
them do a pretty good job some of them
have some issues still but we have
self-driving cars that can do their job
now 2016 we had two DARPA cyber Grand
Challenge where BOTS have been fighting
each other in capture flag competition
to win and you can basically extrapolate
of what we have seen in these
competitions and where the future can be
so I think this is what we have to
realize as security community as a
security industry that the landscape is
yet again to change with AI in coming up
so to the last message and this is
really the point I think our defenses
that we have today will become very much
obsolete think of now we're trying to
learn what the rules are trying to
circumvent these rules because they
these rules can be mined one way or
another and can be executed so we need
to come up with new defenses and we need
to study this form of malware our new
forms of malware similar to what we've
done with deep blocker think about what
can attackers - with AI to find the
weaknesses find the attack points how
can we attack them cyber receptions
young men before I mentioned it before
could be one thing can we how can we
poison and we misdirect the attacks at
the malware into believing or during the
right thing but in reality they're just
being pulled out of the real environment
and
taken down so with this I'd like to end
I'd like to thank you for your
attendance and we're open for for any
questions you may have
I'm sorry Kenny
this Desai's you want to take that all
right I guess we were told not to
release too much detail into exactly you
know what you have what we have
you know tested but maybe we can you
know talk in person yes please it's a
great presentation so when you're
talking about object orientated
streaming media or streaming data as it
applies to current and existing systems
that are already in place a lot of this
would make sense for the sake of data
being distributed in an if you know on a
platform and where content and subject
matter that nobody seems to figure out
what the hell is going on when it comes
to AI which still leaves the human
capital factor being able to determine
to decipher what exactly it is that
they're visualizing you guys have any
thoughts on that area where it applies
to what you're saying in conjunction
with humans applying this very theory
and concept and how it can work together
hand-in-hand so let me answer it this
way so so the proof of concept
implementation that we've shown with the
video conferencing application is really
just one anythings of how you can do
this since any video conferencing
application out there is from time to
time
obviously legitimately using the camera
the deep locker malware or concealment
can also tap into that camera stream
very stealthily and correctly without
the user realizing that this application
is using video and from that point it
can start sample pictures and see who is
in front of the computer who is there
can we unlock our malware and if it does
so yes it can do it so if other they say
millions of other people who have also
using are also using this very same
benign video application benign looking
video application it will never unlock
and everybody else is thinking this is
this is a good piece of software it's
doing its job and and and they will
never realize that there is something
hidden in there that is only unlocked
for one or two or a handful of specific
targets it may have thank you mm-hmm yes
so that to run the neural network on the
target each time a face passes a front
camera what are the computational cost
on the target to run something that big
and is it noticeable to the user so
that's a great question so there is some
computational cost to that so but the
problem you know the attacker may be
very very stealthy that is you know it
can only check for maybe you know 30
seconds or maybe every minute or
something like that to reduce the cost
of computation and the other thing is
like there are you know if you look at
it snapchat or something like that they
are always using this face detection and
all these things inside there inside
their app and you can simply embed the
you know deep Locker type of attack into
this kind of model and it's doing the
key generation at the same time is doing
other things so I think we have you know
systems that is capable of you simply
handling this kind of competition so you
can run an or network on their laptop
and not see immense spikes in CPU when
their model executes on a face so when
it's detecting definitely not it's not a
lot of it's it's basically if you look
into the DNN is simply your flow so it's
not training it's actually you know
putting in emails and flowing through
the the network and it's not a lot of
computation 2007 Thanks
you guys say is the blocker can target
any attribute
like not only like our picture audio
superior environment or activities but
as I know
GNN or Cumberland Cumberland generally
talk these specific ranks of feature
include pictures but like audio or in
activities so I meant a minute length of
pictures so is there any way to create
to transform this dynamic length of
feature to GNN info pictures so I'm not
quite sure I completely on the studio
question so are you asking that
other than image features it can also
look for other types of feature like
Network I heard network okay is that is
that what what you're asking yes yeah I
think I think the possibilities endless
right so I we have it we had a chart you
know there are different types of
attribute that you can use to train the
DNN to detect the target and one of them
could be your you know network a
structure you can scan your network and
if you find it it's very specific
network structure then you generate the
key that's definitely possible okay
thank you thank you for your
presentation my question is how do you
reduce your rate of false positive or
false negative because we know that
malware sometimes is difficult to
predict or defense but you're AI Mesa is
very magic so I would like to about a
false positive or negative rate how do
you reduce that so let's let me repeat
the questions here you just so that I
understood correctly so you're asking
the false positive detection of the
target or false positive detection of
the malware my way of Malwa
I guess we are not talking about
detecting malware I guess I mean the
deep blocker is more like
adversary can do to create a malware so
your question is I don't know I mean I
can answer both questions if there are
two questions yeah but I think one one
thing I wanted to say is if you really
think about false positives of the
d-block or AI to figure out if it's on
the right target or not then this way of
what we have seen when we when we built
and implemented some of the deep lock
deep blocker algorithms is that we are
building this in a very very specific
way so a very high specificity almost
pretty much zero false positive re wrong
identification because the AI model is
so specific that it's only triggering on
the real subject and you can tune this
parameter in in the model this is this
is making a lot of sense in fact when
we're an attacker because we don't want
to this malware trigger in the wrong
situation but maybe you know as an
attacker we have time we can wait for
some time until we're really sure that
we're seeing that attacker in front of
us and only then reveal and release the
malicious intent now going to your
second question that you know in terms
of how false positives could could
reveal itself on antivirus system or or
maybe detection on of deep blocker we
realize this is gonna be extremely
difficult because most applications in
the future we foresee have some form of
AI included so they're using an AI model
and and they're feeding something from a
sensor or multiple sensors into an AI
model and this is where attackers can
try to find their way in and can for
example take an existing a I'm out model
and retrain it basically you can do some
form of shallow additional learning to
to the model itself and an ad deep
Locker
detector on top of it so this is also
what was called like transfer learning
and and and and it's very it's gonna be
extremely hard for the
detectors to detect things similar
things but to be honest I think we
haven't really explored this part in in
our research because we really wanted to
understand just how AI can be used and
we were not into making this absolutely
perfect but more trying to demonstrate
what's the art of the possible can be
okay thank you Thanks hi in this
scenario a face detection model or some
sort of sensor based target detection
model is based on supervised learning
man alike let me just repeat you said
supervised learning yeah so if these
motor are based upon supervised arriving
method so I think it's a need to correct
target data before in fiction so as a
ready way to correct target data or try
and also train motor before a cryptic
target data inside the target machine
yes yes and absolutely I think it's a
supervised learning process and it lends
itself very well to such a the
supervised learning process because we
could we can take Bob here we can go to
his LinkedIn website you can maybe have
access to his Facebook or Susan
Instagram account and we can just
harvest a bunch of pictures and we can
do a supervised learning and optimize
that AI model to really trigger only on
Bob and you've seen it we have the L the
faces in the world basically that you
can use as the our data set to say okay
don't trigger on any other face but
really only just on on Bob's face you
can you can harvest faces millions of
faces of course from the weapons I make
this a very very well model supervised
learning and I just wanted to add one
more thing so there are two two stages
right the first one is actually
capturing the class which is the face so
we you can use you know different it
doesn't have to be always Bob's face so
we you have two stages first stage you
learn how to understand the face and
then the second stage you understand
which face so you can
have always good you know data for the
first phase and then you only need few
data for the second phase okay I got
this thank you hello we're good work how
question about P generation part from my
point of view a key generation it seems
when we my ping from the input to the
key and from the key you can is not easy
to reverse understand the input which
embody our targeting way so this
property is quite similar to the Hashi
function exactly yes yeah so any
comments about say if I possible are
using ha c function to replace key
generation part was Paul that accounts
yeah that that's a great so actually
that's how we started that our thought
process was basically you can actually
have the key for example in case we
Stuxnet instead of you know putting the
entire value it could actually has what
it's looking for and then you will never
know but this kind of hashing only
worked for a very deterministic target
right if your attribute is very very
deterministic but what we are talking
here is very in a high-level concept
light in a face and when you detect
those things as I mentioned earlier the
key would be not stable there will be
some bit flips and it's not gonna work
exactly the way because like what we do
you have right so you generate maybe you
know some feature vector for your face
facial feature but if you have that it's
never going to be the same hash so I
hope that makes sense okay so the from
your pond where Sims it's a a I paste is
taller and sound noisy right exactly all
robust for the cats
okay thank you thank you right thank you
very much sorry just a quick fall off
with the guy who asked about the CPU
load earlier so I might have missed this
earlier but at the point
Bob's face was recognized that means his
images to the camera were being somehow
exfiltrated by the network into the enn
of the AAI
part of the network right and that is
when it all that was the key was
matching weights or key were generated
and then the key was matching on the
other terminals all right so there is no
network activity in there so everything
is in the application itself the the
neural network is this construct that is
deeply embedded in the application
itself and and the face the picture the
pixels are basically sent to that local
network components it's in that it does
an API call and then you get back a
result of what the neural network thinks
it is or what already yeah the output
okay so how sorry of quick koala so
howhow is it
obviously that means some kind of
computation to like you know to match to
match that right so is it not gonna
generate some kind of CPU spike heat and
all that you're not not in our
experience I think neural networks these
days are very powerful also their
implementation is very powerful and you
have a lot of new nets or AI already
running perhaps in applications so it's
very hard to distinguish them from the
chittim of use of of AI I'm as mentioned
before we can piggyback also just on
regular AI models and embed some of the
malicious output in legitimate models
that's definitely I'm realistic to think
about thank you so much thanks thanks
thanks
[Music]
[Applause]