okay good afternoon everyone thank you
for coming to our talk don't at me
hunting Twitter bots at scale my name is
Jorden I do research and development at
duel security on the duo labs team and
I'm a Lobby day Andy Shea and I'm a data
scientist and duo labs so Twitter and
other social networks allow people to
connect to share ideas and to build
communities info second general largely
shares information via Twitter now one
of the things that makes social networks
great is the ability to have authentic
honest conversations automated Twitter
accounts or Twitter bots change this
conversation they change it both in good
and bad ways but regardless that
conversation is changed so today we're
going to see how we can go from zero to
finding Twitter bots very quickly and at
a large scale so Twitter bots come in a
variety of forms these are the ones that
many people are familiar with that are
spam generating BOTS they share the same
links over and over in the hopes of
having some victims click on the link
and fall victim to the scam other bots
don't necessarily generate content but
their goal is to try to amplify the
popularity of either existing content or
account this could be done by liking or
retweeting tweets or by following
accounts at a large scale so these don't
necessarily generate spam but they do
introduce a level of dishonesty and it's
important to note that not all bots are
malicious
we have bots to provide us with breaking
news geological information or like the
screenshot on the right shows a stark
reminder that this is truly the future
and we're living it together so this
research project didn't focus on whether
a bot was malicious or benign instead we
wanted to ask ourselves can we find a
large data set and identify automation
within it so we're excited for the
possibility of future research where we
can take that next step
asking ourselves what makes a bot
malicious now while some butts aren't
malicious some are the screenshot behind
me shows a bot spoofing TechCrunch in an
effort to try to spread what we call a
cryptocurrency giveaway scam the
talk about in detail later militia spots
aim to change the conversations that
we're having introducing dishonesty
spreading malicious content and
injecting themselves in the conversation
to try to influence our discussions now
whenever comes to hunting down bots it's
important to give credit where credit's
due
there's an entire community of bot
hunters already out there doing
incredible work on finding bots and
showing those results and we've
highlighted some people here today so
I'd encourage you if you're looking for
people to follow on Twitter give these
people a shout because they're doing
really really great great work our goal
today is to take that to the next step
and to open up this research into a
wider audience you all we're excited to
be able to share our tools techniques
and methodologies showing how we can go
from absolutely zero to gathering a data
set and finding entire not only Twitter
bots but botnets from those bots and
sharing that back with the community
we're firm believers that InfoSec is
full of incredibly talented researchers
who love taking on a hard problem by
researching twitter bots we're not only
helping keep social networks healthy
it's simply a technically interesting
problem to dig into so we encourage
everyone to take the research that we're
producing today build on it improve on
it and really help take it to the next
step so whenever it comes to what we're
going to talk about today it's really
divided into two or three parts the
first is that we want to gather a data
set this includes finding accounts and
then after we find accounts we want to
enrich that data set with content this
could be tweets that accounts or
publishing or the social networks for
those accounts then we want to take a
practical data science approach to build
a classifier to try to identify BOTS
within this large data set as accurately
as possible and finally we're going to
show how we can take a small number of
bots and help tell the bigger story
using very straightforward techniques to
try to map out connections and show how
BOTS can be organized into entire
botnets so let's go and get started now
whenever it comes to analyzing a data
set it really hinges on the data that
you can gather
and so whenever it came to gathering our
data set we had two goals in mind the
first is that we wanted to play by the
rules of Twitter's API Twitter publishes
an API and and we want our research to
be reproducible both by academic and
security researchers alike this means
that we used a single API key to gather
all of our data this also means that
we're subject to the API rate limits in
place from Twitter this kind of leads us
to our second goal which is we still
want to gather as large of a data set as
possible but since we're subjecting
ourselves to the rate limits in place we
have to be as efficient as possible we
need to be clever with with how we're
using our requests trying to get the
most bang for our buck in order to get
both a large data set very very quickly
now this is what the data gathering
process looked like we talked about this
just a minute earlier but the first step
is finding accounts and what I mean by
accounts are the screen name the user ID
and metadata about the account these are
things like numbers of how many tweets
you've published how many people are in
your social network after we've gathered
accounts we can start enriching this
data set gathering the tweets and where
possible gathering the social network
information so let's start by finding
accounts the first way we found accounts
was using the users lookup API endpoint
this endpoint allows us to send up to
100 user IDs and then for every ID
that's valid Twitter will return to us
the full user object now what's
important to note about this endpoint is
they're just incredibly quick it allows
us to make nine hundred requests every
15 minutes and we talked about a full
user object but what does this look like
this is what a Twitter profile looks
like through the winds of this API
endpoint as you can see it's pretty much
all the metadata about an account or the
only thing that's missing is the actual
tweet content or the actual information
about who's following you and who you're
following but this information alone can
be incredibly useful in identifying
weird behavior identifying BOTS that
have anomalous characteristics and we
talked about this endpoint being very
fast so we can send 100 user IDs every
request
we can make nine hundred requests every
15 minutes well we did the math and that
results in us being able to make eight
point six million lookups per day this
is a significant data set but it also
poses a challenge to us how can we
generate account IDs that are valid in
order to be able to take advantage of
the speed that this endpoint offers
let's talk a little bit about how
Twitter account IDs are created Twitter
started creating account IDs is 32-bit
unsigned sequential integers but simply
this means that we can start a zero and
work our way up creating a hundred IDs
at a time sending them sending them up
and seeing what comes back now we didn't
want to cover the entire 32-bit space
because we just didn't have that much
time so instead we opted to get a random
5% sampling so for every 100 possible
user IDs we could submit we picked five
random ones and submitted those instead
now it's important to note that this ID
space isn't maxed out not every user has
an ID or not every user has the next ID
in the chain the density varies for
multiple reasons maybe some accounts
have been deleted some accounts have
been suspended so you're not always
going to have a one-to-one mapping so
the screenshot on the right shows what
this density looks like this may mean
that for every 100 accounts we send up
maybe we get 80 back maybe we get 40
back it really just depends on on where
you are in that gathering process now
some papers have covered this before
some papers have shown the 32-bit
unsigned sequential integers but what
they don't talk about is that it
actually goes a little bit further now
to put in perspective where we are data
gathering wise just that first technique
alone over the course of a month let us
gather 66 million accounts we notice
that this account ID space moves into
that 33 bit space past the original 32
bit max integer so we actually observed
accounts all the way up to about the 5
billion range and these accounts were
created all the way up through 2016 this
gave us another 3 million accounts to
add to our data set but then things
changed Twitter started generating IDs
with the system they called snowflake
snowflake operates as a cluster of
workers that all have the same job to
generate unique IDs as quickly as
possible now it's important to note that
this format for IDs began to be used for
all of Twitter's objects so the same ID
format is used for accounts tweets
direct messages likes you name it
this along with other reasons that we'll
talk about in just a moment makes it
hard for us to enumerate Twitter IDs the
same way that we did earlier but first
let's see what a snowflake ID looks like
snowflake IDs are 63 bit IDs with an
example being shown at the top we've
broken out this ID into a binary format
so that we can talk about how the pieces
are organized the ID starts with a 41
bit timestamp this timestamp is based on
a custom starting time a custom epoch of
November 4th 2010 after the timestamp
you have a 10 bit worker number or a
worker ID this is a unique identifier
for the worker who generated this ID now
we want workers to be able to generate
mini IDs per second or per millisecond
so they've also added a 12 bit sequence
number at the end this is a rolling
sequence number that resets every
millisecond so now we would have to
guess all of these values in order to
come up with a unique ID that's valid
this is difficult we would have to guess
a timestamp a valid worker number and
then the valid sequence number for that
particular timestamp this is difficult
trust us we've tried you'll find in the
paper some approaches it didn't pan out
didn't go the way that we thought they
would so even if we did generate a valid
ID we don't know if that's a valid ID
for an account for a tweet or for a
direct message it's hard to get that
same level of data gathering so we have
to take a different approach instead we
can let tweets and by extension users
come to us by hooking in a Twitter
streaming API we get a stream of tweets
that are a random sample of public stat
statuses these tweet objects have the
user object who happen to author that
tweet so this lets us stream end users
over time now what's cool about the
streaming API is it allows you to also
do some targeted data gathering you can
put in keywords locations hashtags
topics and more in order to refine what
results are being returned to you so if
you're looking for a specific type of
Twitter bot or a specific type of
content you can do this through the
streaming API now one thing we want to
notice that this does introduce a bias
into our data set when making when doing
analysis over a data set typically you
want to take the same analysis and
extrapolate it out saying we can say
this is part of the bigger picture but
you have to be careful and realizing
what biases you're putting into your
data before you can make those
assumptions in this case the bias that
we're putting in is that we're
introducing users who have tweeted
recently this doesn't necessarily change
things in the short-term but is
something that we have to keep in mind
when doing the analysis later on so we
have a data set at this point of a whole
bunch of accounts now let's start
enriching the data let's start gathering
the content to fetch the tweets we use
these statuses user timeline API
endpoint this endpoint is slower than
gathering users in fact it only allows
us to make 144 thousand requests
compared to eight point six million for
getting users so we have to be a little
bit more careful with how we use it we
have to be a little bit more efficient
this means that we have to put some
rules on what types of accounts we want
to get our tweets for the first rule
that we put in place is that we want to
gather only the latest 200 tweets for an
account we felt that this was enough
tweets to try to indicate some type of
bot like behavior then we only fetch
tweets for accounts that claim to have
more than ten tweets to begin with you
know the if they don't have enough
activity to go off of really it's it's a
wasted request at that point and then we
filtered on accounts that had English as
their declared language part of our
analysis is manual analysis
English is the language that Allah bidet
and I are most familiar with and so it
allows that part of the analysis to be
as accurate as possible and finally many
of the tweets that we gathered were
replies they were responding to a
previous tweet Twitter doesn't give us
these by default so we have to go fetch
them we went out and gathered the
original
sweets because that relationship between
the reply and the original content has
some very interesting characteristics
that can try to indicate some bot
behavior so after gathering tweets we
can start talking about mapping out
social networks the screenshot on the
right shows how we were able to take one
bot account which was a fake follower
and we were able to do a one-degree
crawl getting every account that bot was
following and then likewise every
account following those accounts this
let us create a mapping showing
thousands of BOTS all with the same
characteristics all following the same
legitimate accounts now so this is an
incredibly powerful tool and we'll talk
a little bit more about it later but
what's important right now is that this
is very very slow the API endpoints that
we can use to gather this data only
allow about 1,400 requests per day this
means that it's simply unfeasible to do
this across our entire large data set
but instead as we'll see a little bit
later in the presentation doing targeted
social networking analysis can be
extremely powerful and taking a small
number of bots and finding entire
botnets from them so this is what our
overall data gathering system looked
like we're not going to cover every box
and every arrow in the flow chart but
really there's the two parts to the
system there's gathering accounts in
gathering tweets and we talked about
speed this is what this looks like in
summary gathering accounts by far was
the quickest operation we could submit
up to eight point six million lookups
per day and that's not counting the
accounts that we get from the streaming
API gathering tweets was much slower at
a hundred and forty four thousand
requests per day with gathering the
social network at the end being so slow
that it's infeasible to do this at scale
this is our final data set these are the
final numbers that we have to start
analysis over the course of a month we
are able to gather 88 million accounts
enriched 3.1 million of those accounts
with the tweets that they authored this
gives us a final data set of 576 million
tweets so at this point we have a
significant data set and we can start
analysis I'm going to pass it over to a
Labadee to talk about how we can take a
practical data science approach
to identify BOTS within the data set
thanks Jordan so before we can go about
trying to classify these different types
of accounts we need to try to understand
what do BOTS look like and so we're
going to talk about that through the
data that we were able to gather so like
Jordan mentioned we have three types of
data we have the account attributes
again those were the accounts that you
have those number of favorites number of
tweets how many times your account has
been listed and how many tweets an
account is authored do you have the
actual tweet contents so this is what's
actually in the body of a tweet are
there URLs is there media do they
mention someone things of that nature
and then last you have the tweet
behavior
looking at the way someone tweets can
say a lot are they treating throughout
the entire day
you know what is the distance between
the reply of the user ID that they're
actually replying to and things of that
sort so the first step we try to do was
trying to develop some heuristics we
didn't want to do anything sophisticated
at first because it may not be that
necessary and so we tried to examine
these particular attributes by
themselves trying to find outliers after
looking at the distributions so looking
at the account attributes so we looked
at a few things the first thing was the
entropy of a username if you're trying
to create accounts and maths maybe
you're going to generate a random user
and so as you can see on this slide
there's a username that seems pretty
random there's a great mixture of
numbers and letters um this was
associated with a body count we also
looked at how many numbers are at the
beginning at the end of a screen name
again if maybe you have this set number
of screen names that you use and maybe
just want to increment for every byte
account that you create and it'll ask to
really fall on two different ends of the
spectrum we're looking at the ratios or
followers to following if someone's only
following accounts like a fake follower
maybe that ratio will be probably really
low but maybe they're trying to
masquerade or appear to be a legitimate
account maybe that ratio would be a lot
higher so the same thing could be said
about the number of tweets in the number
of likes there are accounts that are
kind of sleepless and that they author a
lot of tweets are spamming and also are
liking a lot of accounts and then there
are some that have no activity at all
really but we have the tweet content
again like I mentioned earlier this is
number of hashtags or the percentage of
tweets that include media or URLs the
thing about this particular set of
attributes is it presented a couple of
problems like we mentioned earlier there
were accounts that discrete allowed
links that may be a little bit malicious
or try to get people on a particular
insecure site but then there are a lot
of legitimate accounts that are tweeting
links to their content or their articles
like legitimate news organizations so
that's none of the problems of actually
looking at these dimensions by
themselves and not taking a more
holistic view then we have the tweet
behavior the first thing that we looked
at was the number of unique sources so
the source is an attribute that's
returned into the tweet object this
contains information about where the
tweet was authored was it Twitter for
iOS or Twitter for Android or some other
type of application you would expect
that most users would probably have
maybe one to two unique sources but for
those people who are maybe authoring
tweets from maybe five sources or
particularly unique sources that we've
never seen anyone else author tweets
from that may be pretty suspicious or
weird then we have like the time to
reply and to retweet a particular tweet
and this was really important to gather
those replies because they again that
wasn't included in the original tweet
object it's really hard for a human
being to look at a tweet come up with a
reply and then actually to reply in
about 5 to 10 seconds maybe that is a
sign of automation and the same thing
could be said about retweeting a tweet
and a very quick time span we also
looked at the number of unique users
someone was retweeting it would be
pretty weird if they were only maybe
retweeting their own tweets or someone
else's tweets because we expect that
most people are retweeting a lot of
different accounts with a lot of
different material then we also looked
at the distance between geolocation
enabled tweets we were thinking that we
would find some people or some accounts
that are tweeting from locations and
really rapid manners where they maybe
have to travel at light speed to get
from location location the one problem
with this particular dimension is that
it's pretty sparse and that not a lot of
people have the geolocation neighborhood
for all of their tweets and lastly we
looked at distribution to tweet times
they're like how many hours out of a day
was a user actually tweeting and so you
can see in the graph on this particular
slide we say you see a genuine account
and an account that was a bot that
identified itself as such that just
tweeted song lyrics you can see that
there's a pretty steady or uniform
distribution on the number of tweets
author every hour by the song or the
song lyric bot again those accounts are
sleepless in nature but the genuine
account you see there's some spikes in
like a trough that's like six or seven
hours be hypothesizes maybe this is just
the user actually sleeping and actually
not authoring tweets but again we would
suspect there'd be some differences
between our people or accounts that are
utilizing automation and those accounts
that aren't the big thing is that min
each BOTS tried to be or appear to be
human and we really broke those down to
three different types of box
there's the spam box that we talked
about earlier those that are just
putting a lot of content on - Twitter's
platform there are spamming this text or
media or links then we have the fake
followers these accounts are really
trying to amplify the popularity of a
particular account by increasing the
ratio of followers to following that
gives a lot of air legitimacy to an
account and then there's a council to be
classified as amplification box that try
to increase the popularity of a
particular tweet by liking or retweeting
said tweet so now that we've kind of
talked about some of the different
attributes that are associated with BOTS
and the different types of what we want
to do is actually look at all those
dimensions together try to weight them
appropriately and trying to find and
identify BOTS and this is really why we
wanted to use machine learning to try to
do this at scale so I understand that we
have limited time up here and I can't
explain the entire data science process
or what it means to be at maybe a
machine learning engineer but I think
it's important to kind of level set to
bring everyone to the same level and
kind of introduce some of the process
and some of the terms that are going to
have and later in this presentation
so the first step usually in any data
science project is to gather acquire the
data Jordan let that part and I consider
that the pretty difficult part of the
entire process do you want to build
features so like we talked about earlier
the identifying characteristics of those
bots are going to be translated into our
features that were going to feed into
our algorithm then we also want to split
the data
it's important that your data that you
have in your splitting that you're going
to train your model on actually has
labels so can you have some type of
certainty that that count is actually a
body count and we'll talk about our data
set in a couple slides then you want to
evaluate different algorithms there are
many algorithms that can help you
classify or do binary classification and
we chose a few and then you want to test
your model and an unseen data you want
to see how well your model is going to
generalize to data that your model
hasn't been trained on so now that we
have the process is going to introduce a
few terms that I think will be helpful
as well
so I've mentioned already do have models
and algorithms so the algorithms are
really the math is so dissociated we're
trying to classify accounts those models
are those trained algorithms that have
been trained with some type of training
data we have three particular algorithms
that gonna explain a little bit further
the main thing I want you to remember is
that these algorithms output a
probability that an account is a bot so
it may be 51% or maybe 75% that's the
main thing that you want to take away
these particular algorithms decision
trees at first use it like a if
statement logic so if this than that and
they use that maybe branch in different
ways to try to classify accounts random
forest builds on that by using a lot of
decision trees that number is
configurable and they branch in
different ways to try to take advantage
of those economies of scale and then we
have another algorithm called a Debus it
learns from weak classifiers slight
decision trees and then builds another
model to learn from the mistakes that it
was making to try to have a higher
accuracy the main important thing is
that to try to evaluate or to understand
how your model is performing we have
usually two particular metrics that are
important binary classification we have
precision which is trying to understand
of all the accounts that you label it in
our case as bot accounts how many of
them were actually bought accounts and
then we have recall was of all the bots
in your data set how many did you
predict and last we have
cross-validation which we want to talk
about a little bit further in a
step-by-step process but it's it's a
process of trying to evaluate how your
model performs by splitting the data in
different ways to see what are the
metrics like precision or
call now for the data scientists or the
engineers in the audience I know I
probably grossly oversimplify this
entire process but this one to give
everyone a brief overview so this is a
data set so the data set that we
actually train our models on consisted
of partly some data that was gathered by
some USC researchers and a paper that
was released back in 2016
again these are the label what accounts
accounts that were labeled as genuine
they reached out to users and actually
interacted with those accounts and then
accounts that related with a social
spambots or just box in general but as
we said earlier we identified some bots
that were associated with a
cryptocurrency giveaway scale so we were
able to bolster our data set by adding
those accounts to so now I'm going to
talk about how we end up doing some
classification by looking at just to get
account features and also including that
tweet data that enriched dataset we're
going to talk through how you go about
finding the best model and also about
how to go about identifying the most
relevant or features that give you the
most signal so in order to find the best
model using again like you start with
maybe a lot of models or algorithms and
again those algorithms have different
parameters that you can change but again
we didn't do any of that we just started
with five algorithms three that I
mentioned earlier I have to do that
again you split the data so again you
want to see how if you shuffle the data
does your model perform differently and
what are the attributes of those
particular accounts that did perform
well and then again we use those metrics
that we talked about earlier and that
helps us evaluate or choose the best
particular model to then predict on
these unknown data sets so this is
accuracy again we've missed and
presented recall but accuracy is
something that we most of us understand
pretty well as you can see the three
particular algorithms that I talked
about earlier performing very well above
95% really in most cases 98% the model
that performed the best was the random
forest model that I mentioned earlier as
well as you can see was still pretty
close to a Debus but on the other
metrics that we tried to evaluate these
algorithms we're in the forest was far
above the best so these are some of the
other metrics that we had again
associated with precision and recall for
this random forest model we saw that
Ramona had 99 percent precision and 97
percent recall so it was doing
really really well but we want to
underscore that classification is really
hard I'm going to talk a little bit more
about that especially in the concept of
doing this analysis on this Twitter
dataset what we want to stress is there
are a lot of unknowns we don't know the
true percentage of body counts they're
actually on Twitter's platform and that
makes some of the analysis really hard
especially something associated with
calibration so I'm going to take some
time to explain that the calibration
like I told you each model outputs the
probabilities that account is actually a
by so if I say that an account has a 75%
probability of being a bot we would hope
that 75% of accounts associated with
that probability would actually be BOTS
and 25% wouldn't be now calibration is
not always important during
classification but it does go into
actually if you wanted to make a
decision or action on whether you want
to block or maybe restricting account
that would be pretty important the next
thing I want to talk about is we we in
our data set only have two types of body
counts there are many other types of
automation on tauros platform that we
didn't have so it would be particularly
hard to generalize our results because
we might be missing BOTS that are in our
data set and then last we don't we don't
have the optimal thresholds so our
models when trained use 0.5 as the
barrier of whether account is a bot or
not so again if a account has a 51
percent probability of being a bot we
labeled as a body count if it was 49
percent we were labeled as a genuine
account now it's hard to understand if
that is the optimal threshold and where
to make prediction and this would
definitely skew our results if that
percentage is not actually the percent
or proportion or makeup in our unknown
data set so I want you to kind of keep
in mind some of these cap of these
problems associated with classification
trying to understand how difficult it
can be what we actually try to do our
best to try to resemble what we've
believed to be or what people have
reported on being the true percentage of
body counts in there
those same USC researchers talked about
maybe if the percentage being between 10
and 15 maybe at those are at the lower
ends but we wanted to try to mimic those
data that particular proportion and put
that into our data set and see how our
classifier actually performed so as you
can see those
are pretty bit lower than a 99%
precision that we had earlier we have
92% precision when only 10% of accounts
are actually body counts and that rises
to 94 when we're estimating that 15% of
accounts are actually BOTS in our data
set now people are probably wondering
know what is the number associated with
the accounts that we that we actually
gather learn 88 million accounts just
utilizing the account attributes so our
classifier using again that point five
or the fifty percent probability
threshold found that 30 percent of
accounts were more likely to box than
not but only one person had that over 90
percent probability a lot of the
accounts had a probability that was in
the middle that between point four and
point six so it's possible that those
accounts some that were classified as
Union accounts could have been actual
bot accounts and those that are actually
labeled its bot accounts could have been
junior accounts so that's just one thing
to keep in mind and here's like the
makeup are some of the CAC the
attributes that we looked at and what
was the makeup of those accounts that
were more likely to be bonds and ones
that weren't so when really just
examining the ratio of followers to
friends those accounts that were at
least likely BOTS had a higher ratio and
just to drive this home all of the
accounts that were verified in our
particular unknown data set this
unlabeled wear that we're all in the non
BOTS or genuine accounts so this is why
this particular number would be skewed
and be higher when it came to screen
name entry we didn't really see any
differences especially 90 statistically
significant differences between those
accounts in that top 20% in the bottom
20% however when we looked at those
accounts in we looked at the numbers at
the beginning in the end of the screen
name we did see some pretty unique
differences between those accounts that
were labeled as BOTS and not but also we
saw that our classifier was actually
saying that accounts that were more
active that were tweeting or liking
tweets more often were more likely to be
genuine but we want to stress this that
your model is only good as your data so
we talked about how our particular data
set doesn't include all types of box and
so you want to drive home the the
problem associated we're trying to
classify other types of automation that
you may have never seen before
so our mono only headed to 80 percent
accuracy when trained with those social
spam bots but trying to predict those
cryptocurrency giveaway accounts and
advice and when you flip that our model
Bailey was only barely better than the
coin flip
when I trying when trained with the
cryptocurrency giveaway BOTS and trying
to train are trying to predict on these
social spam bots again when you're these
bot accounts have differences or their
accounts are not the same your accuracy
is going to decrease but the great thing
is we don't just have to look at the
account attributes we can add the tweak
content the behavior data and we're hope
we hope that that would actually
increase the amount of precision
accuracy and things of that sort
so in total we had about 22 features
after we iterated and the ability to
actually build those features with the
data that we have now it's important to
note that thousands of features could
probably be created and cording to
Twitter data but these are the 22 that
we had the one thing that's important
though again as all these features
aren't created equal I talked about the
sparsity and the data being a problem
but another thing is when you have fewer
features you have less data to store
your model has less complexity and its
users faster to train and that's
important we were trying to do these
things at scale so in order to try to
find those features that were the most
important or that via the most signal we
use recursive feature elimination so
there are many ways that you can go
about eliminating features but this was
the approach that we took and so
utilizing this approach we found that
these were like the five most important
features of those 22 isn't it kind of
default profile so those are those egg
accounts that you know don't have they
don't have a picture they don't have the
default bio also we looked at the
average number of users that were
mentioned in the tweet so are they
replying their tweets do they have a
tweets that they know just mention other
users then also we looked at the average
number or average distinct hours tweeted
in a day so again we talked about those
restless accounts we of course
hypothesize and our model actually saw
this out that it tried to find users
that had those high numbers we also
looked at a favorite rate and also the
distance between the users a particular
users ID and the idea that they were
replying to so we found that our model
is actually better with this particular
data as we hypothesize and here are some
of the results on that unknown data set
back large corpus that was enriched with
those with those tweets
on that model that was more accurate
only found that 21 percent of accounts
were more likely be BOTS than not and
only 0.8 percent had above that 90
percent and so we want to kind of drill
down and make sure everyone understands
like this model was better it had better
accuracy and so that's why that number
was lower and so again to kind of
compare those particular attributes that
it found pretty orth on that was pretty
successful help identifying bots or not
we looked at those accounts that that
the highest percentages they most like
if they had more default profiles and
those in the top the bottom 20% they
also mentioned users less those bot
accounts also treated more often they
actually were favoriting less tweet
there are more less active on the
platform but also even though those
numbers are very large they're pretty
similar really and the so that we didn't
really find any big differences between
the average reply ID distance but we
wanted again say the classification is
hard even if you have the context and
the tweets but more data can help so
again when trying to identify bots of a
different type we saw that our models
improved again we going from 80% to
really 83 percent when we our model was
trained with the social spam bots and
predicting on this cryptocurrency
giveaway box and then a Model X
increasing 53 percent to 62 percent
where our model was trained with the
cryptocurrency giveaway BOTS and they're
predicting on the social spam bots now
we want to talk about some of the
limitations or some challenges are
associated with our approach and the
data that we had it's important that we
kind of provide this contest context and
perspective account change over time so
we only were able to pull the last 200
tweets so if an account was exhibiting
characters of automation and the tweets
before that's 200 maybe we will miss
identify a particular account also we
don't have that network or those
connection data that during talked about
being pretty slow to gather that
wouldn't really be able to tell us a
more holistic view of how that count is
interacting with other users and the
platform in general and lastly we don't
have the insight into the cost of a
false positive that is a lot as a very
big deal especially we're doing to any
type
prediction because that would probably
change your threshold and also with
changed again the metrics associated
with precision and recall again if false
positive is particularly costly in terms
of the user experience or support costs
again you might want to move that
threshold but you're pretty sure that it
counts actually a lot before you take
any action but what we wanted you to
take away is that straightforward
techniques do help find box we didn't
invent a new machine learning technique
or really changing the parameters
associated with the defaults for these
particular algorithms but we were able
to identify BOTS with a high accuracy
precision to recall so now that we've
identified some of these bots that are
accounts that have a high probability of
being BOTS can we find some connections
can we find a larger botnet and doors
gonna talk about a little bit about that
awesome Thank You ulema day so we've
gathered the data we've taken a very
practical data science approach to
identify BOTS within that data set now
we can talk about the final chapter in
the story which is how do these BOTS
that we identify connect with one
another how are they organized how are
they structured and how do they work
together to share a common goal during
the course of our research we identified
accounts that looks like this many of
you may have seen an account like this
some of you may have been spoofed by an
account that looks like this these bots
were spreading what we call a crypto
currency giveaway scam the premise of
the scam is very simple they'll take a
legitimate account starting with
legitimate cryptocurrency accounts like
Bitcoin the wait for Bitcoin to tweet
and then they'll interject themselves
into the conversation saying as part of
this great news we're excited to share a
new giveaway with our viewers and then
they'll say if you give us so much
cryptocurrency we're going to give you
back even more now I understand it seems
foolproof but they do in fact take the
money and run now what makes these BOTS
so effective is that they spoof the
legitimate account they copy the profile
picture they copy the name and they try
to make it seem as if they're legitimate
we wanted to ask ourselves how can we
see the links between these BOTS how are
they structured how are they operating
so we turn to their social networks
connections one of the first things that
we noticed with
that many of the bots all followed the
same seemingly legitimate accounts we
didn't see any clear ties to why these
accounts were being followed by all
these bonds we didn't see a clear tie
associating them with the scam at all
but what we did know is that all of
these accounts had a whole bunch of bots
following them so we can start mapping
this out we can say let's start with a
small number of bots figure out who
they're following for every account
they're following let's find more bots
and just start working our way through
for every new bot we find we expand our
network running this recursive crawl
gave us two clusters that we wanted to
point out today the first cluster is
that hub and spoke structure that we
talked about just a little while ago in
this structure you have all those
legitimate accounts that are highly
connected nose towards the bottom left
those very dark nodes around them you
have all of the bots there following
them so that was one structure that we
found the next cluster that we found
took a different approach it was more of
a mesh like structure so instead of bots
following legitimate accounts instead
they opted to follow each other now this
is visually compelling but it also helps
us tell a story we're able to show how
the structure of this button that
evolves over time changing the way that
they're organized let's take it a step
further to add legitimacy to the tweets
the bot owner created separate bots that
had one job and that was to like the
tweets associated with a scam this is
called amplification this is trying to
give an artificial inflation to the
popularity of a tweet so that if I'm a
victim and I'm scrolling through Twitter
I'll come across one of these scam
related tweets I'll see that it's been
liked or retweeted multiple times and
maybe I'm less inclined to be suspicious
these are what those accounts look like
this is a traditional amplification bot
in this case you'll notice that the bot
was created in June of 2018 I think that
we found it probably around June of 2018
and it had one job and it likes tweets
every one of those likes was a tweet
associated with the scam so we can start
crawling these as well
we have statuses of bots that we found
already
let's figure out who likes those tweets
for every one of those accounts that
like those tweets let's map out let's
find every tweet that they've liked and
let's find new BOTS from those
connections mapping out all of these
relationships helps us tell the whole
final story on the left hand side you
have that original hub-and-spoke
structure that we talked about and then
on the right hand side you have that
more mesh like structure of bonds but
the glue that's keeping everything
together
are those amplification bonds those
green relationships are the likes where
someone is liking a tweet from that
particular bot this helps us figure out
that this botnet has a very hierarchical
approach it's more sophisticated than
what you would see with a traditional
botnet usually everybody does the same
job they all spread the same spam in the
same way and it's very flat but in this
case we saw a hierarchical organization
here that in fact changed and evolved
over time one of the first ways that the
boss changed was through the content
they would add remove whitespace they
would change letters in the tweets say
taking the letter in and replacing it
with the letter in from a different
Unicode character set visually it's
going to look the same but if I'm trying
to do some string matching that's simply
not going to work they also changed who
they're targeting who their target
audience was we talked about
cryptocurrency accounts but we've also
seen many instances where they change
techniques and started spoofing
legitimate news organizations including
wire CNN and TechCrunch and this helps
show what you see from a victim's
perspective you see a legitimate tweet
at the top followed by the scam right
below it towards the end of our research
after the paper was completed then we
were still monitoring the botnet we
found something interesting
we found close to 10 verified accounts
being taken over and used during the
scam now the the screenshot on the right
shows what this looks like you see an
account the spoofing coinbase and while
we've blurred out part of the screen
name because it is an innocent account
you can see just from the first couple
letters that that screen name is not
Queen based but since it's a verified
account it adds an air of legitimacy to
the scam where if they're replying an
interject
themselves into a conversation it's
gonna be more difficult for me as a
potential victim to be able to tell the
scam apart from a legitimate
conversation to really illustrate this
point this is what it looks like in a
conversation you have legitimate Elon
Musk account at the top replying to an a
user on Twitter immediately below it you
have a verified account that's been
taken over uses a ulong's profile
picture changes his name and spreads the
spam now in this case as a potential
victim I really only have a couple
things to go off of I mean the verified
check mark is there but the screen name
is different so maybe I could catch that
and the s in musk has been changed to a
different character set that's a Unicode
equivalent it's kind of hard to tell
from back there right imagine if you're
just scrolling through Twitter trying to
have conversations trying to see what
people are doing you would see that this
seems legitimate it's easy to fall
victim to it and finally at the very
bottom you still see the same
amplification that we talked about
earlier with the likes and the retweets
now after we finished the research and
we published the results just yesterday
a couple days ago we had some people
commenting about it and helping kind of
get the word out which was always
exciting from a researchers perspective
in this case someone was sharing the
research and then they actually had a
bot that was spoofing their account
spreading the same scam
respond to that tweet trying to yet
again spread the scam so a little bit of
irony at the end of the project so we've
shown how straightforward techniques can
really allow us to follow a thread
unraveling an entire botnet these are
this is an application of targeted
social networking mapping it's nothing
more than that that allows us to take a
small number of bots and tell a bigger
story now we believe in honest and
transparent research that's the core of
what we do so at this point we shared
everything with Twitter giving them our
findings or methodology and gave them
access to our data set we had a very
healthy conversation with Twitter we
enjoyed being able to share our work
with them and we're excited about the
different things that they have coming
out that they've published in in blogs
just here in recent months they shared
with us the statement Twitter is aware
of this form of manipulation in this Pro
actively implementing a number of
detections to prevent these types of
accounts from engaging with others in a
deceptive manner spam and certain forms
of automation are against Twitter's
rules in many cases spammy content is
hidden on Twitter on the basis of
automated detection when spammy content
is hidden on Twitter from areas like
searched and conversations that may not
affect its availability via the API this
means certain types of spam may be
visible via Twitter's API even if it's
not visible on Twitter itself less than
5% of Twitter accounts are spam related
now we're excited to continue this
conversation exploring not only new
areas of this research but also
exploring what is that relationship
between what's exposed via the API and
what's exposed via the UI but we also
want to give back to you to the
community and this is why as part of
this project we're open sourcing the
code that we wrote to do this research
this includes the data gathering system
the code you that we use to build a
features an example showing how those
features can be used to create a model
to identify twitter bots we're also
sharing our paper this paper includes
the full methodology of how we did this
research project and all the findings
associated with it and in summary large
Twitter datasets can be gathered very
quickly and very efficiently if you're
efficient with how you use the API
requests that you're given then you
could take this data set you can apply a
very practical data science approach to
accurately find BOTS within this data
set then you can take these BOTS and you
can start unraveling entire botnets
figuring out how they're organized how
they're structured and how they work
together and it's easy to stand on stage
and say this is the conclusion of the
research there's nothing else to explore
we're taking the complete opposite
approach we're excited to be able to
open this up to the community lowering
that barrier to entry to start hunting
down twitter bots by working together as
a community we're excited to see how
people build improve and find new ways
to identify bots at a large scale by
working together we can create healthy
social networks that allow us to share
ideas connect with one another and
build really healthy communities thank
you
[Applause]