all right Aloha and welcome to my talk
on making and breaking mac firewalls my
name is Patrick I work at digital
security where we are creating
cybersecurity tools for the Mac
Enterprise I'm also the creator of the
Mac security website objective-c so
today we're gonna talk about creating or
making a firewall for Mac OS we're then
gonna shift gears we're gonna put on our
hack your hats and talk about then
breaking or bypassing such products so
about a year ago I decided hey I want to
write a firewall for Mac OS so this
section of the talk will describe that
process in creating a free Mac firewall
product called Lulu
so there's many reasons you might want
to create or install a firewall some of
the obvious ones are obviously to help
protect your privacy firewalls are also
good at sorting a cyber attacks so many
firewalls are able to generically detect
malware that perhaps has gotten onto
your system and now is trying to beacon
out perhaps to talk to a command and
control server so what our firewall will
do is monitor all network traffic and
allow trusted traffic while detecting
and blocking malicious or unauthorized
traffic now since we need to monitor all
network connections we are going to have
to write a kernel extension luckily in
Mac OS Apple provides something called
Network kernel extensions or NK ease and
they provide a way to modify or extend
the network infrastructure one type of
nke
is called a socket filter filter which
as its name obviously implies can filter
network traffic at the socket level
which for creating a firewall sounds
perfect so in order to filter network
traffic and connections we first have to
register a socket filter so you
accomplish this by first filling out a
socket filter structure and this
structure has various callbacks which
once registered will be invoked by the
operating system anytime a socket action
occurs this thing gives our fire
while the ability to monitor examine and
filter these socket actions now once
this socket filter structure has been
populated you invoke the socket filter
register function and this will as its
name implies register or install the
socket filter now besides that populated
structure structure we just discussed
this filter also takes the socket domain
type and the protocol so this means if
you want to filter multiple socket types
for example ipv4 ipv6 etc etc you have
to invoke this function multiple times
all right so now let's talk about these
callbacks which as I mentioned once your
socket filter is installed the operating
system will automatically invoked when
socket actions occur allowing your
firewall to examine and either allow or
block these events so first up we have
the attach callback as the slide
mentioned this is called anytime a
socket is created and it's called with
the actual socket and also a cookie
parameter which can hold any socket
specific data so here we allocate a
chunk of memory and then we store an
action based on the pit of the process
if it's a process we're going to allow
we set it to allow if it's a process we
want to block we set the action to block
and if it's a new process or something
that we don't recognize we set the
action to ask next up is the connect out
callback and this will be called by the
operating system anytime a socket
attempts to initiate an outgoing
connection it takes that same cookie
parameter which we've set to either
allow block or ask the socket and then
the remote address that the socket is
trying to connect to so we can examine
the endpoint now if we've previously set
the action to allow we just return okay
from this function this tells the
operating system we're cool with this
and it should be allowed if we want to
block this we just return an error from
this callback and this will tell the
operating system to block or deny the
connection now if the cookie has been
set to ask this means we we're not sure
what to do you know should we allow the
process should we block it we're just
not sure so we have to have some extra
so if we don't know what we should do
we're gonna have to ask some other
firewall components so the first thing
we do is still in the kernel we set the
thread to sleep basically pausing the
operation we then ask our user mode
firewall component daemon for assistance
and we pass the information that we have
from the kernel to user mode via shared
queue for example the pit and the socket
that's trying to initiate the outgoing
connection so the daemon now gets this
request from the kernel and what it does
is that map's a pit to a path and then
first checks if this path exists in the
rules database if it's not found meaning
it's a brand new application or a piece
of malware that's never been on the
system before what it then does is it
sends another message to another
firewall component that's running in the
user's UI session which will now
actually display the firewall alert to
the user so the user now has has to
basically answer the question should
they allow this connection and what we
do is we wait until they interact with
this alert once they've clicked either
allow or block this response is first
sent back to the daemon the daemon then
updates the rule database and then
propagates this response back into the
kernel via and i/o kit interface the
kernel extension wakes up the thread
that it had previously put asleep and
then applies the action that the user
specified either allowing or blocking
the connection so basically that at
least from a conceptual point of view is
all the pieces we need to build a
comprehensive kernel level firewall for
Mac OS so we put this all together we
have Lulu so mention Lulu is a free
firewall for Mac OS the entire source
code for this product is available on
Lion and as of today you can download
and install version 1.0 all right now
black hat is predominantly at least in
my opinion at a hacker conference so now
let's turn our attention to breaking or
bypassing these firewalls so imagine you
are an attacker or perhaps a piece of
malware that's made it to a host so
you've infected a system unfortunately
there is a firewall installed so what
your goal is pretty simple
it's to connect out to either a command
and control server for tasking or
perhaps to exfiltrate some data without
being blocked by whatever firewall is
installed on that system so in this part
of the talk we're first going to look at
some malware firewall aware malware
we're then going to talk about some
exploitable security flaws in firewall
products and then end with talking about
some of firewall bypasses so it's
actually very important for malware to
detect if there is a firewall on the box
because if they don't as we can see on
the slide this might be their undoing
the firewall might detect when the
malware which was previously undetected
connects out and that's alert the user
that there's something suspicious on
their box now I've yet to see any public
Mac malware that is proactively trying
to bat bypass firewall products but
there are some Mac malware specimens
that are firewall aware what I mean by
this is they actively look to see if any
firewall product is installed on the
system and if there is they will not
persistently infect that box so one
example is devil robber here is a
snippet of code from one of its scripts
install scripts and we can see what it's
doing is it's checking for the presence
of Little Snitch which is a popular
third-party firewall if it finds that
extension instead of infecting the
system persistently it just executes a
benign app version of the application it
infected and then exits so the author of
this malware basically said hey I don't
want to be detected so if there's a
firewall I'm just gonna bail all right
so now on to some real issues firewalls
are obviously rather complex pieces of
software they run with elevated
privileges in route or in the kernel and
unfortunately they're often not as
well-written as the operating system nor
as audited so they make great targets
for looking for local privilege
escalation vulnerabilities so a while
back I found a kernel bug in the Little
Snitch firewall driver basically it took
a 64-bit value from user mode and passed
this value to an allocation routine and
then a copy routine now the issue was
the
Haitian routine expected a 32-bit value
so it truncated the 64-bit value the
copy however used the full 64-bit value
meaning we could cause a controllable
mismatch between the allocation and the
copy routine
giving us an exploitable heap overflow
in the kernel another issue I found also
in Little Snitch when I was working on
these slides affects its installer or
updater component basically it would not
validate that the new firewall
components it was installing had not
been tampered so what a local
unprivileged attacker could do is modify
these components and then the privileged
firewall installer would naively use
these infected or modified components
and execute them as root basically
giving again a local and privilege
attacker root privileges all right so
now let's talk about bypassing these
products first we'll look at ways to
bypass various products so some specific
product specific bypasses and then we'll
talk about some more powerful
capabilities that can bypass all third
party firewalls again the goal is to
access the network without being blocked
by and installed firewall now I do want
to make one point and that is any
security tool that is proactively or
specifically targeted will be by
passable so in my opinion these aren't
necessarily security flaws like these
shouldn't be assigned CDs I think that's
kind of lame however they are very
important for attackers or malware which
might otherwise be detected or blocked
so first up we have radio silence radio
silence is a popular firewall for Mac OS
and by default it actually allows any
new process so it basically takes a more
blacklisting approach expecting the user
to blacklist a process now if you look
at the disassembly for it's blacklisting
logic in the kernel we can see it's
checking the name of a process and if
the process named is Launch D it cannot
be blacklisted more blocked so to test
this we create some malware and we name
it launch D doesn't matter where it is
just as long as its name is Launch D we
manually create a rule to blacklist the
malware and then we execute the malware
and low
hold even though there's a rule to
blacklist that it is allowed because it
matches on the name in the kernel so
this is kind of lame but you know it's a
full bypass another popular
Mac Firewall product is called hands-off
and it turns out we can fairly easily
bypass it via synthetic or
programmatically generated clicks so say
for example we want to execute curl curl
is used a lot by malware to download
other components maybe a second stage
implant etc etc so if we execute this
the firewall will detect that curl is
generating an outgoing connection which
is good but what an attacker or piece of
malware can then do is send a synthetic
mouse click to that alert to
programmatically click the allow button
this will allow the connection and
dismiss the alert and there's also ways
to do this invisibly so that the user
doesn't see the alert pop-up and the
mouse generate the click now odd to Lulu
as Lulu is open-source turns out it's
really not that hard to find a bypass by
default Lulu trusts Apple signed
binaries although it has a grey list of
Apple signed binaries that perhaps could
be utilized by malware to perform
malicious Network actions for example
curl and net cat so the question is can
we find a Apple sign system binary that
can allow us to do nefarious Network
actions but that is not on the grey list
the answer is of course yes turns out
you can actually use the Whois utility
to exfiltrate data this was news to me
since Whois is signed by Apple proper as
we can see on the slide when we use
Whois to exfiltrate data the firewall
Lulu will see the connection because
it's monitoring all connections globally
but since it's signed by Apple and not
on the grey list it is allowed finally
we have Little Snitch which is probably
the most popular or well-known Mac
security product and it turns out it has
an undeletable system rule to allow any
process to talk to icloud.com
this means any process even malware will
be able to talk to Apple's servers so to
test this we can create a rule to block
curl and then we can execute curl and
specify a URL that exists on iCloud and
turns out even if we have this rule
curl because of the end point has been
basically whitelisted it is allowed by
Little Snitch
so while back i reverse-engineered the
iCloud protocol and set up a command
control server on iDrive which is also
an iCloud domain of course just for
testing purposes so once we understand
the protocol we can write a script that
will export rate files for example
something called top-secret txt to
iCloud to the iDrive command control
server we have set up again little
snitch will see this connection but
because of the endpoint is allowed it
will allow the exfiltration to occur all
right so those were product specific
bypasses there kind of neat but they're
also kind of lame why well the attacker
will first have to enumerate what exact
product firewall product is installed
and then use one of these product
specific exploits so that's kind of a
pain in the butt now much much better
would would be to have a generic bypass
which would in type ass any installed
firewall basically saying I'm agnostic
to whatever firewall that's installed
I'm just gonna generically bypass this
and these are possible because firewalls
must allow some traffic on the network
for example system protocols system
binaries and also the user is probably
going to fully allow things like
browsers giving them indiscriminate
network access so to generically bypass
a system with a firewall we going to do
two things first we're going to
passively sniff and determine what
traffic the firewall is allowing out and
then we're going to abuse either these
protocols or these applications to
perform nefarious Network actions so
first to determine what processes or
protocols are allowed we can use the LSO
F utility which is built-in system
utility on Mac OS you can execute it
without any special privileges and it
will show you what network traffic is
allowed so this is a dump for my box we
can see things like chrome the browser
you know chat applications like slack
signal bunch of Adobe crap basically a
lot of stuff now some firewalls will
have endpoints specific rules meaning
that they might say ok Adobe is only
allowed to talk to the Adobe servers but
as I mentioned something like a browsers
go
to be able to talk to any remote web
server on port 80 or 443 of course also
a lot of these applications now talk to
the cloud for example AWS so even if
there's a rule to say I only want slack
to talk to the AWS infrastructure we can
probably also create a CNC on AWS okay
so now we know what traffic and what
processes are allowed or allowed to pass
through the firewall
so the first generic bypass were
actually going to indirectly exploit the
trust of a process via a trusted
protocol so on Mac DNS on Mac OS DNS
requests are handled by the system mdns
responder so if a random application or
a piece of malware wants to resolve a
domain this is sent locally to the
system daemon then the system daemon is
the one that actually generates the
network requests so the firewall is
gonna see this DNS request but it's
going to be coming from a trusted system
daemon which is generating all DNS
requests for the entire system so the
firewall basically has no choice but to
allow it so what we can do is we can
basically build a DNS based CNC
mechanism which has been discussed
before and again since the firewall is
going to trust DNS requests from the
trusted Apple system daemon this will
allow us to have a full command and
control mechanism which can generically
bypass all third party firewalls next up
let's abuse browsers the simple fact is
if you have a browser installed even if
you also have a firewall installed
you're going to give the browser
generally indiscriminate access because
I mean think about it it browses to
hundreds of websites every day there's
no way you're just gonna sit and
whitelist all of them and of course this
is something that we can passively
determine via l sof we can for example
watch for a few hours even a few days
and build a profile of what traffic the
browser allows and then basically say
okay it looks like chrome is allowed to
talk to any network endpoint so the
first way we can abuse a browser to do
some malicious network activity based on
our behalf is via Apple script so on the
slide there's a few little Apple script
commands we're basically asking Safari
to invisibly browse to a remote attacker
controlled command-and-control server
again the firewall will see this request
but will allow it because it's coming
from the context of the users browser an
even better way to generically bypass
all firewalls is to abuse the browser's
command-line interfaces all the major
browsers now support synthetic browsing
via the command line really doesn't get
easier than this so again the firewall
will see these connections but will
allow them as it really just appears
like it's the users default browser
browsing to some endpoint which is what
browsers do yet another way to abuse any
application or trusted binary is to
inject a dynamic library into it once
the library or your code is in the
process context of this trusted process
from the firewalls point of view
whatever trust that application has will
be also given to that dynamic library so
for example if you have a chat
application or a browser that's allowed
to talk to any network endpoint you can
inject a dye Lib into that process the
firewall will also give that library
full access because it's checks or
insight is really only at the process
level now there's many ways to inject
dye lives into third-party applications
on Mac OS fortunately due to time
constraints we can't go through these
but I've listed them on the slide now
the final way to bypass firewalls invert
involves getting a malicious code
running in the kernel in short if an
attacker can get code running in ring
zero it's really game over from the
firewalls point of view first most
firewalls actually generically allow any
traffic that originates from the kernel
anyways so you can just generate an
outgoing network request the firewall
will see it but again since it's coming
from the context of the kernel it will
be allowed you can also do something
like generically unhook or uninstall the
socket filter firewall driver or
extension this will transparently
disable the firewall and then the
attackers code or any component in user
mode can generate outgoing connections
and since the firewall has been
effectively neutered this connection
will be allowed now a valid question is
how do we get code running in the kernel
recent versions of Mac OS require kernel
tensions to be signed so one way it's
just to bring a third-party driver that
has a vulnerability along with you to
the target you then load that driver it
will be allowed because it's validly
signed and then you can exploit the
vulnerability so for example we could
bring the Little Snitch Colonel
extension load it and then exploit it
eventually Apple does blacklist some of
these extensions but not for a very long
time and this is obviously only if they
know about the vulnerability this is
interesting because the slingshot apt
group did exactly this on Windows 2
VIPRE bypass Microsoft's kernel code
signing enforcement now I talked about
this attack at Def Con 2016 and since
then Apple has sought to mitigate this
by introducing a security mechanism
called user approved kernel extension
loading basically apple says ok even if
you have a third-party driver that's
validly signed if you try to load it
even if it's a legitimate driver we are
going to block it and prompt the user
turns out it was trivial to bypass this
via a synthetic click and although Apple
patches patch that unfortunately as is
the case with many Apple security
mechanisms it's still completely trivial
to bypass so since the introduction of
the security feature it's been
completely broken so I'm gonna give a
talk at DEFCON on this if you are more
interested in that all right so let's
wrap this up so today we talked about
making firewalls basically using a
socket filter it's really not too
complicated if you're interested more
some of the details or the source code
check out lulu again it's fully open
source lots of comments you can build it
compile it poke around and hopefully it
gives you a good idea exactly how you
would go about building such a firewall
we then talk about breaking firewalls
turns out yes they have security
vulnerabilities and unfortunately they
are pretty easy to generically bypass
now this doesn't mean all is lost but it
certainly makes a good case for
defense-in-depth
in my opinion you should have some other
security tools perhaps that are
detecting dial-up injections or perhaps
detecting if a browser is executed from
the command line more behavioral based
activities that might indicate a
precursor to an attack now a firewall I
don't think should be monitoring all
these other behavioral detections but
perhaps some other third party utility
can
also finally I'm stoked to announce that
I'm going to be organizing max security
conference called objective by the sea
it's gonna be this November in Maui we
got a great lineup of speakers and if
you're a supporter of objective-c which
you can be for $1 the conference is
actually completely free I can talk a
lot about how awesome speakers are
they're very awesome but you know come
on it's in Hawaii in November so if
you're interested check out objective by
the sea calm this is the resort it's
going to be held and again that's me a
lot of great talks about iOS and Mac
security alright that's a wrap
really want to say thank you for
attending also want to thank the
partners and Friends of objective-c
digital security and Malwarebytes and we
have about two minutes for questions and
also be around after the talk if there's
some more questions you'd like to
discuss
yeah great question so is in the Mojave
bet betas that are coming out how has
Apple basically implemented any security
features that may impact this and that's
a great question because they've
actually limited what certain
applications can do so for example you
can now no longer use Apple Script to
talk to another application so you can't
for example drive Safari via Apple
script unfortunately you can still do
things like various die live attacks or
execute Safari from the command line so
there's still multiple waves but they
are kind of blocking some of these
attack vectors some of the precursors to
the attacks so you know I think I would
definitely install it when it comes out
because it it does increase the bar in
terms of security so that's a good thing
any other questions I'm guessing this
applies to the built-in firewall as well
Oh excellent question so the built-in
firewall is is great but the problem is
it only monitors incoming connections so
any activity for example any malware
that gets on your system that tries to
connect out to a command control server
or exfiltrate data the built-in firewall
is not even looking at this traffic and
the majority of attacks affecting both
the enterprise and end-user and Mac
users that is going to be kind of that
behavior that the malware is going to
come in maybe via an email the users
going to be tricked into downloading and
running something so the first network
traffic that's actually going to be
generated is this outgoing traffic so
it's good to turn on the built-in
firewall but it really doesn't buy you
that much in my opinion and I think
Apple did this because they don't want
to annoy the average Mac user with
pop-ups when for example the browser
they installed tries to connect to the
internet because you know that would be
confusing to at least a handful of Mac
users and Apple usually airs on the side
of usability versus security awesome all
right we are out of time I will be here
for a few more questions again
Mahalo so much for attending my talk and
I hope to see you all in Hawaii this
November