hello thank you very much I'm actually
going to be doing this talk with my
friend bunny my daughter asked me to
bring bunny with me so can everyone just
say hi bunny thank you very much
so I'm Shawn Metcalfe this is from
workstation the domain admin why secure
administration isn't secure and how to
fix it so I'm Shawn I'm the founder of
Trimark a company that helps
organizations better secure their
Microsoft environment including the
Microsoft cloud I'm a Microsoft
Certified Master Mac to directory
there's about a hundred in the world
most of whom work for Microsoft
I do not I've spoken before at blackhat
I'm very excited to be here so thank you
very much for being here with me I'm a
security consultant and researcher and I
own and operate 80 security org which
hopefully many people have heard of are
used to help secure your environment so
there's a number of things I'm going to
talk about during this presentation I'm
going to talk about where we've come
from as far as administration what it
looked like as we've advanced what we've
done over the years and the weaknesses
that are still inherent in those
processes as well as the things that are
currently considered secure
administration and why they aren't and
then I'm going to close up with how to
better secure your environment and how
to better perform secure administration
so many organizations have upgraded
their security we've added better
visibility through security tooling
event logging auditing ADR tools we have
blinky boxes we've flowed all these
security events hopefully many of them
into our sim tool we're watching those
we're getting alerts we've done all of
these other things to lockdown secure
workstations to have better control of a
better visibility in our environment but
rarely have we actually done much to
secure or improve the way that a quick
turi is administered we need to do
better based on what I've seen so let's
start from the beginning
in the beginning we had a workstation
and we had a happy user on their
workstation and this user had problems
so we added desktop support and desktop
support met a bunch of other
administrators with remote access or
local admin access on that system and
after desktop support we realized what
we need to patch the system there's
vulnerabilities we need to fix so we
added actually patching and agents
associated with Paget
and then ultimately we realized this was
too much to handle with all these
different systems we need to integrate
it better so we set up a mission control
types configuration and with our mission
control we had better central management
and control of our environment but the
result of all of this is that we have a
workstation that has 30 accounts in the
local administrators group
which could be a mix of ad accounts and
local accounts we've got about 50
accounts with local admin rights through
this management system we've got 20
accounts with control of the computer
through security agents or tooling and
we end up with about a hundred accounts
that have admin rights how these numbers
might be off for a lot of organizations
but I'm sure there's some people here
that are trying to hide their head right
now because that's a very similar
scenario because ultimately it comes
down to who has control of the
workstation who are the administrators
who can control manage modify that
system and what if the administrator of
Active Directory actually uses that
system so let's take a step back and go
through the evolution of administration
we went from using something like VNC to
RDP we were using run ads in order to
run our MMC and a lot of other acronyms
but in the beginning there were admins
everywhere we had administrators we had
domain admins oftentimes user accounts
were actually domain admins in some
situations every local administrator had
the same name and password across the
organization and some environments
actually had as many domain admins as
users which is the ostriches here I
can't tell if they're users or admins
but there's a lot of them so that's bad
right and this resulted in a situation
where we have an environment that's
target-rich
the attacker gets into the environment
and they can just kind of pick and
choose what they want to use because
there's credentials everywhere because
of the way we've been managing our
systems the way that we still manage our
systems most of the time we're using a
user workstation standard regular user
workstation we log on with the user
account and then we perform under
administration through RDP or some other
method so when we talk about the way
where we were the old-school admin
methods like I said logging on to the
workstation as an admin we probably
don't do that anymore hopefully because
credentials were an else ass for that we
don't really use run as any more on our
workstations because again credentials
end up in else ass but we do often RDP
to the main controllers or admin servers
and manage them but that means the
credentials are in alsace on that system
so if we're connecting to an admin
server and that admin server isn't well
protected then an attacker could use
something like mini cats to extract
those credentials and reuse them like
this so where we are now we have newer
better secure admin methods right we
said no more to run as we said no more
to local MMC's activities and
administration when we use RDP we are
going to use an LA Network level
authentication which prompts us for our
credentials before we connect to that
system and sometimes we're gonna use MFA
in fact I've noticed more and more
customers and organizations are using
MFA which is great others are starting
to use password vaults enterprise
password volts like psychotic secret
server or cyber-ark so let's talk about
how we could exploit the typical
administrator so here we have a regular
workstation and just a regular username
Sean is logged on to it so he needs to
do some work so he's gonna run MS cts
see it pops up that RDP window and he's
gonna type in his credentials and do
what he normally does as an
administrator but behind the scenes
there's a file that just gets dropped
into the C Drive it's very interesting
file this temp file
what is this temp file so the attacker
behind the scenes completely in stealth
has performed a WMI implant method to
drop us a task a w my task on this
system that whenever M STS C dot exe is
executed a special PowerShell script is
going to be run that I've decided to
call a CCM health check sounds good to
me
alright but what does SCCM health check
actually do and did microsoft write this
so we go forward and look and see well
that doesn't look like a CCM health
check that looks like something very
different so when we are trying to
figure out what's going on and we're
digging through this we're gonna see
that this is the gets keystrokes
powersploit function and what keystrokes
does is a PowerShell script or function
is actually going to capture this
keystrokes while it's running to us to a
text file and that happens to be that
temp file that dropped to the C Drive
now can go anywhere on the system it
wants but it's going to capture every
single key press that happens on that
system and it can be quite extensive as
it captures this information the WMI
task could also have that text cop file
you copy it off to another location or
uploaded to a website and using
PowerShell I can go through and quickly
extract the information from this text
file and pull it together and when I do
this I can very easily identify assuming
that someone typed it in at this moment
what the server name is what the user
name is the admin and the actual
password so now I have the credentials
and guess what happens if this is the
domain admin account yeah I can use
something called DC sync so this is very
dangerous and even if I add MFA to this
situation
I don't need to use MFA when I'm running
DC sync because it's just an LDAP call
to the DC so let's talk a little bit
more about this what if we add MFA we
can MFA the RDP so the way you RDP weave
its MFA and we got everything covered
right well we have our RDP connection we
get our duo prompt I'm not picking on
duo but apparently they were in the news
recently so I figured I'd use them and
so when we click on this push we get a
pop up on our mobile device and we have
two options we approve or deny and
looking at it we decide yes this was me
I'm going to approve that but what would
happen if I got two of these
back-to-back what if I click approve on
the first one what do I do the second
one well the obvious answer is I deny it
right but how do I know which one is
mine and which one isn't or is this a
hiccup and the same thing can happen
with a DFS or on my mobile device itself
if I just look at the lock screen and it
pops up I'm gonna go yeah prove I just
did that
but what if another one pops up is that
me or did a hiccup or was there a
problem with the operating system on the
mobile device or the app what's it what
if there's a third one will the user
report this we'll use a report something
that's odd that's happening with MFA
what if the attacker can initiate
initiate or initialize MFA request at
around the same time the admins using it
everyone's very busy when we get prompts
like this we our tendency is to click on
it just tap tap tap oh do the second one
pop up I don't really know that's okay
it'll be fine so what if there's a way
that an attacker could actually subvert
the MFA system so here's a scenario that
I'm gonna put together we have this
fictional company called acne and acne
has a self-service portal where users
can go in and manage their own
attributes these are some standard
attributes like work phone number work
address
mobile number etc so pretty standard a
lot of organizations have this
configured attributes may vary so let's
say that our admin Luke Skywalker has a
user account and an admin account
because he's a smart guy and so he has
his mobile number set up in here on his
user account well if the attacker can
leverage the self-service portal they
can change it to 8 6 75 309 because
that's what any attacker is gonna use as
a phone
easy to remember and once he has that or
this attacker has access and the ability
to change that mobile number things get
pretty interesting because in duo by
default or at least in the
configurations I've seen as well as
other MFA configurations there's a
backup to the standard put app push
which is yes SMS or text so oftentimes
it pulls this information from the
Active Directory user account for the
phone number it should use for that text
message so if the attacker has the
credentials of that admin account and
they want to leverage MFA one thing that
they can do as an option is modify that
phone number that mobile phone number
and have a text message sent to their
phone and the actual user who owns that
account and it counts doesn't see
anything there's no message that goes to
them at all now there's similar
situations with with other MFA systems
and so just a summary of this if the
attacker can modify that phone number
that mobile number for that user account
which is used by the MFA and that backup
SMS text messaging system isn't disabled
there's a backdoor a way to use that
account and if these are admin
credentials then it could potentially be
game over and no one it's possible that
no one will notice now another
interesting thing about duo again I
promise I'm not picking on do they're
just very popular and like I said
there's a lot of activity about duo
recently but there was an article
recently a blog post about duo and fail
open versus fail closed so by default
duo fails open and duo uses a request
via the DNS lookup and then a connection
to its API a record under deal with
security comm so if an attacker is able
to actually block that connection what
happens is MFA doesn't work at all so
you can change this setting obviously
and there's another setting that's
interesting here and that is the ability
to
remove MFA requirement for local
accounts and so this way you can do
whatever you want as a local account but
everyone that connects in with an ad
account will be required to MFA so
there's some recommendations around MFA
first of all don't rely on it to protect
your admin accounts don't don't let it
be the only thing that is protecting
your admin accounts use hardware tokens
or the app disable SMS if possible
research failed closed for critical
servers remember that once an attacker
has 80 admin credentials it's game over
they don't necessarily need to go
through the MFA system and definitely
walk through the potential bypass
methods and implement mitigations and
detections
because it's entirely possible that
someone could social engineer their way
into switching a phone number some other
method through the help desk or some
other way or a different MFA app on
their - on their device people lose
phones all the time people have to get a
new phone configured sometimes they end
up changing numbers so does em if they
have value absolutely please please MFA
all the things just understand that it's
not a silver bullet and that there are
things that that can be used to bypass
it depending on the specific
configuration password boss so I see
password vault being deployed more and
more as Enterprise password vaults and
as a way to provide more secure
administration typically like I said
cyber-ark a psychotic secret server and
they often have what they call a
reconciliation account which is very
often a domain admin that has the
ability to bring these accounts back
into control so if you have an account
that's stored in that password vault
managed by that password vault what ends
up happening is that reconciliation
account will check to see if the
password is what it has for that account
in its vault and if it's different it
will reach out and automatically change
that account password this means that
very often the password vault itself has
a very highly privileged account in
Active Directory and it maintains ad
admin accounts in addition to that a lot
of the time and there might also be
additional components like assessing
session manager which I'll talk about in
a minute but here
one of the options for an enterprise
password vault that we see pretty
commonly check out the credential so we
have our workstation on the left or
password vault in the middle and our
admin server on the right that's that
star and so what we do is we connect to
the password vault and we via HTTP it's
just a website and then we check out
that credential copy that password in
our clipboard on our local workstation
and then we paste it into our RDP login
window and connect to our admin server
it's fairly common it happens a lot so
what can be done about this what can I
do as an attacker yeah and this is a
regular workstation so one of the things
I can do is I can set up my sec and
health check but this side up time I'm
going to use something another function
from powersploit called get x screenshot
or actually meta myself get clipboard
contents so I'm going to copy out of the
clipboard the contents that are there
and there's gonna be another text file
that shows up on the computer and as you
can see here every time I copy something
into the clipboard that PowerShell
function is just copying it from the
clipboard directly to a text file
constantly and over and over again and
through this method the attacker ends up
getting that password that's in the
password vault
now obviously the password well it's not
going to be creating passwords like this
but this is blackhat it would be fun and
then I could take that I can look at it
I can leverage that account password but
how do I know what the account name is
well that's where that get time
screenshot function comes in that I was
mentioning a little earlier because then
what I can do is have screenshots of
what shows up and then correlate that
with what's in the clipboard and I can
use a WMI implant to this
so there's malware out there right now
that is monitoring the webpage that
people go to by via the title it looks
for financial website names it looks for
certain types of title keywords you do
something very similar I can look for
cyber-ark or psychotic or something like
that and when that happens through my
WMI implant I can kick off these power
so components or something that I custom
write with in c-sharp to do the same
thing and capture this data so we want
to be very careful what systems we're
connecting to a password vault from ok
well there's a different way to do this
all right the RDP proxy approach which
is where we have the password vault
sitting in the middle we have our
workstation we're connecting to the
password wall via HTTPS we then connect
from the password vault to the admin
server via RDP and the password involved
is providing that proxy that RDP proxy
and the password vault has the
credentials the admin themselves don't
have the credentials don't know what the
credentials are password vault is doing
that entirely so it's a complete
password and a lot of the password
Volt's now have the ability to do
session recording as well although I've
never actually heard of someone having a
good plan for like going back and
watching sessions or randomly looking at
them but it's there but a couple
questions with this approach first of
all what account is used to log on to
that workstation it's very often a user
and then what account is used to log on
to this password vault that then has
access to this highly privileged admin
account it's often also a user and as
mfa used to protect that authentication
and what about the administration who's
administering the server this password
vault server that contains all of these
very critical credentials and what about
the network communications are we
limiting access to this password vault
most of the time there's no limitations
on the network to connect to the
password vault and a lot of the times
people are just accessing the password
vault using their standard web browser
which has all of the other things that
are usually in a web browser so what are
the extensions what are the settings how
is that web browser configured what if I
compromised the web browser how could
might be an interesting way that I
compromised the pastor vault connection
from that because it's all web at that
point one thing to think about is should
we be using a separate browser when
we're connecting to a password vault
well maybe the other thing I see too
often is a situation where there's a
password vault admins group in Active
Directory and when I enumerate the
membership
that every member or most members are
regular users anyone see a problem with
this I certainly do
these are the admins for the vault the
other problem I've discovered is thanks
to my friend show Dan they were able to
tell me that there's cyber-ark password
vaults on the internet which could be
okay
probably not it all depends on what sort
of data and credentials are there being
stored in them and I happen to find one
that's a little bit older which is very
concerning we'll talk about in a bit so
when we talk about the password vault we
need to look at the potential weaknesses
in the way that it's configured so
authentication to the web servers
typically a user account MFA or not
maybe these are often administered like
any other server so server admins has
full admin rights on them and the
sessions that are created by the admins
to connect to the password vault are not
always limited to one they should be
limited and a vulnerability and the
password vault can compromise the
directory entirely so just a few months
ago in April with the CVD at the top 20
18 9 8 4 3 there was a serialized dotnet
object vulnerability and the way that
cyber-ark was handling the API on the
password web server so just for those
who have cyber-ark if you haven't
patched it since April I highly
recommend you like message someone and
do that today because what this did was
it enabled the ability to run arbitrary
code on that vault and the proof of
concept is simply just running ping but
you can see that there's a very
interesting escalation process that
could be done here because the password
vault web server is the one that proxies
our brokers that request from the user
and identifies which password vaults
they have access to which credentials
that user has access to we can modify
that if we can change that we can do a
lot of really interesting things
what about the admin force so there's
been a lot of talk in recent years about
the red forest or the admin forest or
the ESA e et cetera et cetera et cetera
so the whole concept is that we're going
to take our production eighty forest
we're going to take all of our 80 admins
and we're going to move them into this
other 80 forest we're going to
completely lock down this other 80
forest we're going to make sure that
only our 80 admins are over in this
forest and they're well protected we're
going to have network configuration
where nothing else can connect to it
except the authorized systems we're
going to ensure that it's encrypted the
network communication is encrypted were
gonna have a one-way trust so that way
production ad environment trusts this
admin forest we're gonna have a group in
this admin forest that is a member of
the administrators group and active
directory and the production ad and only
these admin forced accounts are members
of that of that group and we're going to
make sure that that those accounts in
that group that are in this admin force
don't have any admin rights of the admin
force and aren't even in that group all
the time so the only way to administer
this ad environment according to this is
through this admin forest account which
oftentimes is using PGI and separate
management completely separate it so I
have a slide here which talks about what
I just said you can look at the slides
later but beyond 80 security out org
after the talk but there's some pros and
cons with admin force the pros are that
we are effectively isolating our ad
admin credentials into a separate force
where they're very difficult to get to
and when deployed properly it can be
effective in limiting access to these ad
privileged accounts sounds really good
where do I sign up well there's some
challenges with this first one is it's
expensive to deploy an admin force is
effectively increasing your management
overhead and cost because you are
duplicating your infrastructure you're
setting up new DCs technically they're
all supposed to be physical by the way
they're supposed to be managed by a
separate system any security tooling and
management
are supposed to be duplicated in that
environment and anyone that logs into
that admin force environment is supposed
to use a PKI card which has a separate
PGI from your standard PCI configuration
but ultimately it doesn't fix your
production 80 issues if you have
security issues misconfigurations if you
delegation that you set ten years ago
and everyone's forgotten about it and so
there's like four accounts in your
environment that have like the two steps
from da but no one knows about it this
isn't going to solve that in most
organizations we also have workstation
admins and server admins guess what
attackers don't need domain admin rights
they don't need act directory admin
rights all they want is access to data
access to system so if they can
compromise a workstation admin or a
server admin or both they can get that
the other thing is what about your
production ad privileged serves counts
so technically as part of this whole
admin force we're supposed to take those
privileged service accounts and remove
them just take them out of domain admins
take them out of administrators just
make them regular users delegate the
rights out most of the customers I
talked to can't just do that and so
these service accounts that are highly
privileged ended up sticking around and
so it's part of the admin force
implementation you're supposed to assume
breach that's our mantra assume breach
right we need to check the environment
to ensure it's configured correctly
there aren't any of these obvious miss
configurations but what if it's
compromised
what is this admin force actually going
to by us especially when we have to
assume that there's an active attacker
on the network well not much because all
we're doing is shifting the admin
accounts that are known in to our admin
forest and any of the sneaky persistent
methods that happen to be in the
environment maybe someone is pretending
to be a domain controller in the
environment that Vincent and and
Benjamin are going to talk about
tomorrow in the DC shadow talk
that's not admin force isn't going to
help us from that so what should be done
first these are questions and concerns
when you're going to spend a lot of
money on an admin force because
ultimately it's been billed a lot of the
times as the solution
- your act directory security problems
and attackers can figure out if you have
an admin force it's pretty easy we just
look at the trust membership and we
might see something that looks like this
and we're definitely going to see
another forest group that's in our
admins group for our Active Directory
forest so it's gonna be pretty obvious
when we have that how effective is the
admin forest
well the deployment often ignores the
production ad environment issues
organization is usually very quick to
deploy an admin force and get it stood
up and get these ad admins moved over
and these other things don't get fixed
they stick around and of course their
service accounts that are still there
there's agents on our domain controllers
that still have privileged access and
who has administrative rights of those
who has control of those agents they're
not in the admin forest and backup is
still a big issue so I worked with a red
team to help them compromise an
environment and AD force that had an
admin forest we didn't touch any of the
ad admin accounts we didn't have to so
there's definitely some benefits for the
large organizations that have multiple
active directory forest because if you
have several ad forests then you've got
to have a way to configure and manage
all of them so an enforce might make
sense in that scenario but there's
another issue that I've seen in a lot of
organizations and that is the whole
concept of cross force administration we
have our forced a because I'm very
creative at naming things we have a
force B because I'm incredibly creative
at naming things
so for stay is our production force B is
our DMZ environment our dev tests are
external
it doesn't really matter it's another
force that's not as highly trusted as
our production are at force tape
environment we're gonna have a one-way
trust so in Microsoft parlance and arrow
pointing from B to a means that a is
going to a resource or a accounts yeah I
got confused
hey accounts can access B resources so
that means our happy domain admin and
forest a can also be an admin and forest
B and so this happens a lot where we
have a domain admin forced a that
manages and administers force B and so
they connect into RDP and go ahead and
do what they need to do here's the
problem
force B is not as trusted is forced a
it's in the DMZ step test it might have
a hundred domain admins that are all the
developers it could be an application
force that has some internet
connectivity is not in the DMZ
so what do you think happens when that
force gets compromised well then our
happy admin gets compromised and
ultimately force a gets compromised
right a little bit of cliffhanger there
so simply from this trust and the fact
that we're using a forest a or
production domain admin to administer
this other forest with which makes sense
logically and a lot of Microsoft
documentation points this as the way to
do it is problematic because when we
connect using RDP from force data for SB
we often are leaving credentials behind
fact by default we are so I have a slide
here that has kind of a summary of what
I talked about but at the bottom is the
mitigation so we want to make sure that
we manage this other forest this forest
be with a forest be admin account not a
forest a account or you if you really
are set on using a forest a account or a
production account make sure you just
create a user account or user accounts
that have no privileges enforce day that
then are the admins for this other
forest and then protect them at a good
level all right so I've talked a lot
about the problems and the issues let's
talk about building the best defenses by
the way this is one of my favorite
castles in the world this is mount san
michele and which i'm pronouncing
horribly wrong I'm sure in France and so
for a Lord of the Rings fans this is
actually excuse me the the castle that
was the inspiration of the castle and
Lord of the Rings
80 defensive pillars we're going to talk
about what we need to do in order to
secure Active Directory so we need to
protect our credentials our ad admin
we need to isolate them and protect them
at the highest level we need to harden
our admin methods we want to make sure
that we're not using administrative
methods that could be compromised we
need to reduce and limit our service
account rights and as part of this pull
out any accounts that don't need to be
in domain admins or administrators and
then there's also effective monitoring
we need to make sure that our domain
controllers are properly monitoring the
correct events so that way when
something does happen we can see those
unfortunately that's out of scope for
this talk I don't have enough time but I
have bonus content at the end of the
slides you can look at later so the key
to this is focusing on protection these
at protecting these admin credentials
especially our ad 80 admin credentials
we need to have a separate ad admin
account from our user accounts most
organizations are doing this now
although the ones that have transitioned
recently often forget about some of
those user accounts we'll leave them in
AD admin groups making sure that these
ad admin accounts are different from
other admin accounts they're not
administering Exchange or SharePoint or
sequel and use distinct naming I like ad
a 480 admins sa 4 server admins and WAFF
workstation atoms that use whatever
works for you I went into a customer
site and they had all these different
accounts actually it's been a few
customers like this all these different
accounts different names different
setups had no idea what kind of naming
standard there was and so I went in and
talked to them about this after I'd gone
through and done some assessing of their
environment I said what's the deal with
all these accounts I can't tell like
this first initial middle initial last
name first initial middle initial last
initial and then like Superman a couple
other things I don't know what this is
like I don't like who our who's supposed
to be your ad admins you know huh you
don't know yeah you don't know either
and they said yes but the attacker won't
know which of these is the human account
I said yeah that's great but I have this
report here that has a list of all of
the admins that I've enumerated in your
environment from all of the standard
groups and the permissions in your
environment so I know who the admins are
the attackers know who the admins are
the problem is that we cannot
programmatically identify monitor and
maintain a configuration without a
standard naming convention for
administration I see that there's five
accounts and domain admins how do I know
that all of those belong who would I
have to talk to I'm going to talk to
like six other people to figure out
which of these five accounts should be
there right but if I can
programmatically configure the
environment to monitor an alert on
changes when it doesn't see an ad a and
domain admins or something like that
I've elevated my environment to the next
level
it could proactively manage maintain
this and of course we need to make sure
there are 80 admin accounts are only
logging into 80 admin workstations and
80 admin servers and domain controllers
but the biggest question is why admin
workstations hopefully some of these
slides have helped you and will give you
some some evidence and some ammunition
you need to influence others to get
admin workstations deployed because the
issue is the battle is shifted from the
parameter on to these workstations which
we know but we're still running
administration from them and the
management these regular workstations is
an escalation path there's lots of talks
about exploiting SCCM to then own the
environment or deploy malware right
Altiris SCCM there's a bunch of
different systems that are used to do
this and then the credentials that are
found on these systems are used to
escalate and move around the environment
and they can be in alsace they could be
typed into a RDP window or into a web
form but this builds on the whole
concept of having a separate account
separate admin account from your user
account which we've been talking about
for years right everyone knows we've
been since the beginning we've been
hearing this
we also have to remember that any agent
that can install or run code is a
potential compromise method of that
system so we need to expand out our
vision from just who has local admin
rights to what are the agents that are
running on these systems and who has
ability to influence them so when we're
talking about our 8e administration
systems we need to isolate and protect
these privileged credentials we need to
provide secure environment for the
admins to do what they need to do
ultimately we need to disrupt the common
attack playbook this means that we want
the attacker to have to go from chapter
1 page 1 a chapter 10 chapter 20 and by
making it more difficult for the
attackers we have better insight and
visibility because we want them to hit
those tripwires we absolutely want the
attackers to hit something we want to
set up a pathway that they go down
jessyca pain calls this building the
attackers playground as a defender we
have the ability to configure the
environment to be our home court
advantage we set up the trip wires we
form and identify which way we want them
to go and we look at that and we go all
right here's how we do administration so
what are the trip wires we need to
implement what are the events we need to
be looking at in this pathway how do we
ensure and know that only valid and
authorized people and personnel are
using those pathways so we need to
ensure the consistent is configured
correctly we need to make sure only
these specific admins can log on
separate administration of the system of
this admin system separate management
patching auto patching in many Senate
situations make sure it's firewalled off
the standard network we want to restrict
access to the management protocols like
RDP WMI etc and enforce NLA so that way
someone has to off before they connect
to that RTP server there's a great hack
or modification that I call a movie
movie hacking on Windows is just simply
replacing one file with cmd.exe so that
way when you hit a key over and over
again on that logon screen it pops up a
command box running a system on that
right I'm sure everyone's seen this call
a movie hacking because you just hit
shift 5 times in the
spatula now you can do whatever you want
with that system with nla you block the
attackers ability to have implant at
that and then to reuse it if they got on
that system previously so this is
probably one of my favorite slides in
the whole deck raise your hand if you've
seen this before keep your hand up if
you have been able to implement this
fully okay I think I saw one person to
two people
kudos so you see me after I have
something for you for everyone else this
is what I want you to focus on because
with the Microsoft tiered model tier 0
means domain admins domain controllers
and all of the supporting systems are in
that tier and can't get into another
tier and tier one is going to be your
server admins your servers the
management system for servers tier two
is going to be your workstations
workstation admins workstation admin
system and the management system this
means that you have to have if you have
a CCM you've got a deploy an SCCM
instance in tier 2 1 and tier 1 and 1
and tier 0 and you have to have admin
accounts in each one separately and none
of them can talk to each other so now
that many of you have your eyes glazed
over and are thinking there's no way
that I can do that this is where I want
to come back to let's focus on tier 0
let's focus on protecting the most
important assets in our Active Directory
environment our 80 admins or domain
controllers because the issue is with
the Microsoft tiered model is it's
difficult to implement it's costly to
implement it requires duplicate
infrastructure and admin accounts to do
it correctly it's very hard to do it
correctly there's like three people in
this room of let's call it 1500 that
have had it implemented it's rarely
fully implemented there's lots of
organizations that have gotten it close
so I want everyone to focus on tier 0
making sure that those are protected so
what is tier 0 domain admins privilege
80 admin accounts and systems or 80
admins or serfs council privilege 80
rights are 80 admin workstations and
servers are ad FS in Federation servers
if an attacker is able to get admin
rights to an a
best server they can extract the
certificate that's used to sign the
tokens and forge their own Federation
tokens for two years or more depending
on how long that certificates good for
anywhere on the network so you
definitely want to protect your a DFS
servers Azure ad Connect servers a lot
of organizations have gone off 365 and
Azure ad and are using Azure ad connect
to synchronize their user accounts on
their 8 on Prem ad into Azure ad so they
can use office 365 and a lot of times
they're synchronizing that password hash
data in Azure ad so the users can
directly log on Azure ad so you want to
be aware that if you have as you 8080
connects servers configured they really
should be in this tier especially if
they're synchronized map password hash
data because about every 2 minutes as
your ad Connect is going to ask the
domain controllers in each of the
domains that contain users that are
synchronized say send me the password
hashes for these users this means that
as rated you can ad Connect is like a
junior DC because those credentials are
passing through in memory on that system
on a regular basis and then of course
PKI password vault and the tier 0 our
management system should be in tier 0 as
well so we want to convince our admins
this is the tough part admins are two
that are typically mobile use a laptop
will require a second laptop that's
tough it's a tough sell they're less
than excited when they're told they have
to use a separate system for
administration ego 80 admin here's your
regular workstation here's your new
admin system you can't use both you
can't use this to do that and the other
way around and then the biggest
challenge with this is the people that
are most impacted are 80 admins are
often the ones that have to make this
change they have to implement it so
guess what happens I'm gonna do what
okay so I've got party one two three
four guess what it's gonna be right here
I think I have time next year
how's July next year work for you
but this is a good opportunity to
refresh hardware there's several options
for small lightweight systems for these
80 admin systems I like the Microsoft
Surface Microsoft doesn't pay me to say
that but it works well and now there's
cheaper ones out but it's important to
explain the reasons the how's the whys
why it's important to separate these
systems out because without that
information it will be the bottom of the
priority list and will never happen
because these isolating these
credentials are the most critical
now convincing management is just as
important if not more so got to tell
them why we've got to explain why this
is important why it's required yes these
systems and process will slow the
resolution of issues managers hate this
executives hate this because yes it
might take another day or two to resolve
an issue that you want done in hours but
it will also slow down and stop
attackers from having that access in
that capability and the cost of this
extra hardware and the delays that it
would take naturally to do things that
used to be done a lot more quickly far
cheaper than an IR far cheaper than
having Mandy and fireEye CrowdStrike
come in and kick out the attackers far
cheaper than the reputation hid far
cheaper than the downtime far cheaper
than people working 100 hours a week and
20% of your staff getting burnt out and
leaving it's usually the best ones to
you by the way start slow and build up
with gradual changes we need to partner
and make this a collaborative effort we
need to start slow and say here's what
we want to do and here's why let's talk
about how we can do this smartly how
that we can do this together
so it's a workable admin system ideally
would be separate physical devices but
that's not always feasible but since our
goal is to isolate our credentials let's
talk about using an admin workstation
leverages virtualization so that we can
have a good blend of security and
operational capability so there's a lot
on this slide we're going to start with
a host OS which is our admin environment
virtualize or user environment into a VM
and we're going to use that user
environment for all of our user activity
that host OS is effectively going to be
our admin system that we just use as a
jumping point to our admin system or a
DC this is the account that logs onto
this host OS is what I call a transition
account it doesn't have any rights it
can't do anything it just logs on to
that system and then once on that system
we can log on to in our DB server and
have been serviced so let's see what
this looks like so we are admin
workstation with our user VM we log in
as a regular user onto that VM we use a
transition account to log onto that
workstation and then we use that our 80
admin account via RDP to our admin
server so this way we can isolate those
credentials we can protect them and
since it's our admin workstation it's
not going to have all the standard
capability of management controls and
hundred people that have admin rights
okay Sean but we have a password wall
how does that fit in yeah you just plug
it in right here
same thing Laguz user use a transition
account the transition account is what
also asks that password vault but now we
know the admin workstation is protecting
those credentials were using to connect
into it using MFA hopefully and then
they pass with Vulcan proxy it through
I'm not advocating password volts by the
way we can have conversations offline
about the benefits etc so urban
workstations definitely start with our
act directory admins look at virtual
infrastructure cloud admins don't forget
about PGI mainframe so Chad's putting on
a great talk tomorrow afternoon about
mainframe hacking from a regular
workstation a lot of times mainframes
are administered that way
just like everything else is so with
this new standard this new configuration
we want to make sure that our ad admins
only ever log on to the main controllers
or 80 admin workstation or 88 admin
server we want to make sure that 80
admin counts are separate from other
administration we want to prevent them
from logging on other systems we want to
get all service counts out of 80 admin
groups as a general rule I know that
can't happen right away
but our new standard is no service
counts in 80 admin groups not domain
admins not administrators and then of
course we want to make sure our local
admin passwords actually get changed
so we need to reduce and limit our
service count rights then the vendor
requirements also push us in this
direction they say domain admins we say
ok let's push back what rights are
actually required to often their domain
admins administrators backup operator
server operators these are highly
privileged ad admin groups rarely do
they actually require it so I did a lot
of work and effort in my free time I
read through a lot of different
documentation from vendors piled through
this over hours and hours and I put
together a list of the most common
things that vendors asked for and I a
pattern emerged we're in Vegas so we're
gonna do a little Vegas magic let's see
if the pattern emerges for you - yes
domain admins solves everything right
oftentimes it's a vulnerability scanning
tool backup VPN even sequel ends up in
domain admins we don't need them there
we can pull those out they need less
rights and what they say they require
vulnerability scanning is a little
little trickier oftentimes the
vulnerability scanning tool is gonna use
an author authorized or authenticated
scan using a demain admin account but if
that hiccups and leaves behind that
credential of that serves count on a
workstation the environments don't
forget about the vulnerabilities if you
have unconstrained delegation a
vulnerability scanning account scans
that system guess what the Kerberos TGT
the authentication ticket is left behind
an attacker compromised that system it's
game over we need to get better we need
to get these accounts out backup unless
it's Active Directory backup doesn't
need to be in domain admins and even
then it just needs to be in backup
operators VPN and sequel shouldn't be
there
the issue with the pianos often the VPN
a service account wants to be able to
reset the user's password users trying
to VPN their password is inspired they
need to log on okay well let's delegate
those rights for that service account
let's not give it da & Seek why'd I have
nothing to say about sequel I don't know
why secret would ever be in domain
admins usually that goes way far back a
little note on sequel by the way
a little bit of homework for you when
you get back to your organization your
your act directive environment take a
look at your administrator account your
default administrator account for your
domains you read 500 count and check to
see if there's a service principal name
associated with a case pen okay if it
has a span it's a service count it is
being used as a service count your
environment that is bad please remove
that immediately because that is not
good at all
so in conclusion traditionally the
administration must evolve with the
threats to effectively protect 80 most
organizations have done something but we
still need to get better party 1 remove
all the accounts that don't belong there
and remove the service accounts that are
in 80 admin groups priority to protect
and isolate your at 80 admin credentials
that's been my time thank you very much
for yours if you like my talk please
submit evaluation also there's a QA that
I'll be in in this
[Applause]