according to the 2016 national survey on
drug use and health fourteen point six
million adults ages 18 and older which
is five point nine percent of that age
group had alcohol use disorder that's
one in seventeen I am one of those
people hi my name is Jamie and I'm an
alcoholic
as of July sixth I have six years of
sobriety and 17 years in information
security compliance and trust and safety
even after all that time I'm more afraid
of disclosing that I'm a recovering
alcoholic than disclosing any product
vulnerability security incident or that
I'm a queer woman insecurity due to the
possible impact on my career
despite this fear I'm here today to
share some facts dispel some myths and
provide some guidance on how we can be
inclusive in supportive of those living
a clean and sober life so what's alcohol
use disorder alkyl his alcoholism also
known as alcohol use disorder is a
chronic relapsing brain disease
characterized by an impaired ability to
stop or control alcohol use despite
adverse social occupational or health
consequences it can range from mild to
severe and recovery is possible
regardless of severity both alcohol use
disorder and substance use disorder are
considered brain diseases because
alcohol and drugs actually change in the
brain they change its structure and how
it works and according to the National
Institute on Drug Abuse addiction
alcohol use disorder and substance use
disorder are a lot like other diseases
such as heart disease or diabetes
both disrupt the normal healthy function
of the underlying organ and have serious
harmful consequences and are preventable
and treatable but if left untreated it
can last a lifetime
so in dispelling our myths today here's
our first myth that we're going to
debunk there's a single cause for AUD
there isn't one single cause for alcohol
use disorder
many risk factors come into play when it
comes to the development of alcohol use
disorder some we can't control like our
biological ones those would include our
genetics our development in utero
medical conditions and some we may be
able to address such as our home and our
work environment and our family and our
peer relationships another common myth
is it's all about self control as much
as we'd like to believe that with enough
self control we can defy our brains and
refrain from drinking our work
environments oftentimes work against us
either due to being on call or extended
problem solving or context switching or
many of the other things that we do all
the hats that we wear then we experience
mental fatigue we push ourselves to run
on empty more than we should experiments
have found that a tired brain will shift
activity from the prefrontal cortex
responsible for rational thinking so the
amygdala and the orbital frontal cortex
associated with emotional input
impulsive response and then we lose our
grasp on self-control additionally
there's a relationship between stress
and addiction extended periods of high
stress also contribute to an increased
likelihood of relapse more stress or
afraid our body produces a stress
hormone cortisol as part of our
fight-or-flight reaction in true
fight-or-flight situations cortisol
triggers the body to utilize glucose
differently and suppress non-essential
functions in order to efficiently react
to the situation among other things when
the situation passes the level of
cortisol drops however repeated acute
stress and prolonged chronic stress
continuously trigger the fight-or-flight
reaction this leads to cortisol levels
remaining high and has an adverse effect
on almost every system in the body
according to the findings from Raja
Sinha at the Yale interdisciplinary
stress Center
abstinent recovering cocaine alcohol
opiate and nicotine dependent
individuals with high cortisol ACTH
ratios show both higher compulsive
motivation for drug craving along with
poor stress regulatory responses as
measured by higher cortisol levels which
results in an enhanced sub Sept ability
to subsequent addiction relapse so that
means a stress brain a fatigue brain
plus all of these work factors leads to
this is fine I used to think of myself
like Marion Ravenwood from Raiders of
the Lost Ark she was fiercely
independent even in the face of
adversity and used her drinking prowess
as a way to further herself I did too I
built rapport trust and respect while
drinking I was including conversations
and in projects I would not have been it
in if it wasn't for that glass at hand
unfortunately the movies aren't real
life I may have been a functional
alcoholic in the workplace but not in
other facets of my life once I found out
that I was pregnant with my son I knew
that I had to make a change change
wasn't easy
I found that I struggled with most of
the work and peer related contributing
factors these contributing factors are
not the same for everyone some people
struggle with their biological risk
factors some folks struggle with their
home or their family environments or
peer relationships the ones that were
most impactful to me wasn't where my
work environment and my peer
relationships for example in my
workplace throughout the course of my
career especially working in antabuse
idea dealt with emotionally charged
content and that can be things from
abuse reports that came in to our abuse
desk to reporting things to the national
cyber tipline one of the other
challenges I had was attending
conferences and the prevalence of
alcohol there but also the
pressure to fit in and be included I
didn't want to feel like an outsider I
didn't want to be excluded unfortunately
in many of our security related roles in
our antabuse roles we are dealing with
prolonged high stress
remember the cortisol I talked about
before not having that opportunity to
let those levels come back down
additionally in security operation roles
many times people especially in
leadership are in high-risk on-call
situations they want to support their
teen as much as possible and so out of
being a servant manager they put
themselves in a position where they are
always on call for them which is a very
honorable thing but they have to
remember that you've got to put your own
oxygen mask on first before you can
assist others kegs in the office now for
some people and including myself this
isn't as much of a trigger at this point
in my recovery as it is for others but
that prevalence of alcohol in the office
can make it challenging it doesn't mean
that it's that sole factor that will
cause somebody to drink but it's
something that they think about and
think oh there's that keg there nobody
will know if I have a drink the only
person keeping them accountable is
themselves and every time they have that
conversation with themselves it takes a
toll regarding peer relationships the
hallway track or also known as
networking at the bar there's that
pressure of you're not really being
effective at a conference unless you're
making those connections and building
that trust and building that rapport
there is nothing wrong with the hallway
track however recognizing that the
hallway track is challenging for folks
because of other pressures in their
lives needs to be recognized dinners and
happy hours in other cultures dinners
and happy hours are are things that
require and or not require but there's
expected that there's alcohol involved
and there's again there's nothing wrong
with it but it is an added pressure of
how am I gonna make it through this
dinner how am I going to save face in
front of this customer I don't want to
be seen as vulnerable I don't want to be
seen as weak I don't want that to
translate as my product or my service or
my company is vulnerable or weak
another challenge are people who don't
understand people who aren't familiar
with alcohol use disorder or alcoholism
or their experience with alcohol is a
healthy one and that's also ok it's just
challenging and then there's those
people that push boundaries people that
enable drinking people who say hey why
don't you have this drink I know you
said no but it's ok nothing's gonna
nothing's gonna happen if you just have
one drink how about that drink
when I first seriously tried getting
sober I went about a year without
drinking and then at an industry
conference in 2012 I tried to socialize
as I used to with everyone in the bar in
the evening I ended up closing the bar
six drinks later escorting overly
intoxicated people back to their rooms
and we drank the whole bar out of dark
beer which is kind of unheard of for
Germany but we did another year went by
and I was almost a year sober again
returning to that same conference and
while socializing I was told you deserve
a drink I was able to extract myself
from that conversation and I proceeded
to have a panic attack alone in my room
I knew my sobriety was in jeopardy if I
stayed in that bar to network but I was
also afraid of the toll it would take on
my career by not being in the room where
it happens but it's not just conference
or industry culture that makes it
challenging for those dealing with
alcohol use disorder I had a manager at
a former employer who regularly held
team events at the bar I asked him if I
could have dinners with the team or
alternative and set in locations in
addition to at the bar because I was a
recovering alcoholic what he said to me
has stuck with me for the remainder of
my career and was one of the major
factors for me leaving that organization
he said you aren't an alcoholic I've
seen alcoholics you aren't a drunk we
don't tell somebody with diabetes come
on eat the cupcake your blood sugar
doesn't matter or to somebody with
cancer you don't look like you have
cancer why are you going to chemo
why should we treat anyone who has
alcohol or substance use disorder any
differently for the record I'm not
against alcohol
I loved alcohol alcohol was my friend
alcohol was my companion alcohol was my
liquid courage I'm not proposing a
temperance movement what I'm proposing
is that let's turn risk factors into
protective factors that we as a
community work together to make this
happen how do we leverage support and
inclusion as tools for the 1 in 17
dealing with this today we can make a
difference on an organization level at a
pier in management level and at an
individual level so we go back to those
contributing factors for myself if we
think about how could anybody else who
works in security operations or antabuse
who are experiencing these same
contributing factors how do we change
things culturally within the ecosystem
within our organizations as peers as
managers where when they see these
things we've got ways to protect them
we've got ways to support them as an
organization employee wellness programs
are extremely helpful but ensuring that
the employee wellness program extends
more than just let's make sure that
they've got healthy foods or let's make
sure that they can get gym memberships
or let's make sure that they are taking
vacation but also ensuring that our
employee wellness programs and our
benefit packages include real functional
mental wellness if you're holding a
conference as an organization or an
event where you've reserved multiple
conference rooms during your happy hour
or during one of the parties set aside
one of those unused conference rooms
with a posted Friends of Bill W meeting
time black hat does this Def Con does
this others do this for those familiar
with Alcoholics Anonymous they will meet
there during that time
and hold an impromptu meeting to provide
support for those in recovery if you're
sponsoring a happy hour or party event
in addition to the bar have to creative
signature drinks we did this recently
with with the cypher party we had the
Sazerac
which was the alcoholic drink and the
zero tres which was a non alcoholic
drink this gives people the option to
try something different than a plain
soda in a tall glass with a black straw
and they won't feel like you're sticking
out another thing that we did is at an
event we offer both beer and smoothies
but there was no secondary citizen
experience it was hey these smoothies
also had the same labels as the beers
had and it really didn't matter you
don't have to come up and say hey I'm an
alcoholic can I have the non-alcoholic
drink no you can just be like I feel
like a smoothie today and it doesn't
matter whether you're an alcoholic
whether you're choosing not to drink for
religious reasons whether you're
choosing not to drinks because you just
don't drink it's not something that you
like the taste of as a manager or a peer
if someone confides their recovery with
you please listen and do not minimize
their concern check your biases and
educate yourself if you're uncomfortable
with them disclosing their recovery to
you take pause and ask yourself why am i
reacting this way I've noticed over the
years that conversations came to a
screeching halt when somebody asked me
why I wasn't drinking and I told them I
was in recovery I found it was more
effective to say jokingly I was a
professional but I've retired I used to
be okay with saying this because it
worked to stave off any follow-up
questions it ended things on a high note
I was funny but now I'm not okay with it
in order to reduce the stigma of alcohol
use disorder we need to accept it for
what it is and move on instead of
minimizing it other things that managers
and peers can do they can attend the
mental health first aid training mental
health first first aid training is
available nationally it helps you assist
somebody
experiencing a mental health or
substance use related crisis you learn
risk factors and warning signs for
mental health and addiction concerns
strategies for how to help someone in
both a crisis and non crisis situations
and where to turn for help you learn how
to assess for risk of suicide or harm
you learn how listen non-judgmentally
you give reassurance and information you
encourage appropriate professional help
and you encourage self-help or other
support structures for that individual
also if you know somebody who's in
recovery you can help by deflecting and
redirecting invasive questions from
others about why that person doesn't
drink if they're your coworker they're
your peer and you're at a party together
this is an opportunity for you to
intercede on their behalf as long as
they're comfortable doing so another
thing you can do you can check in with
your team to ensure that they're not
under prolonged or continuous high
stress periods if someone has been under
continued stress please encourage
vacation time or work with them to
reduce their stress load be inclusive
hold team events at locations where the
primary activity is not drinking
remember the purpose of this event is to
focus on the team or the new hire it's
not the purpose of the event is not to
drink it's just one of the things that's
there just like we don't go to the
burger bar for the sole purpose of
eating hamburgers when we're going as a
group okay maybe I - but the last myth
the longer one's been sober the easier
it gets this sixth year has been my most
challenging year sobriety I almost
picked up this year in the middle of an
extremely stressful time literally still
to this day some days it's one day at a
time but nobody knows that I'm
struggling nobody sees it
it's what I'm dealing with on the inside
that's what alcohol use disorder is it's
a medical condition on the inside that
doesn't always show on the outside
as an individual if you are struggling
with alcohol use or substance abuse
disorder it knowledge concerns including
your own about your alcohol use decide
to change if you want a different
relationship with alcohol you can make
that happen you may need support you may
need structure but it is possible ask
for help if you're in a bar or even a
hotel or Airport bar and you're at the
risk of picking up a drink or you're
afraid you're gonna drink too much ask
the bartender to page for a friend of
bill you can even check with a concierge
at major hotels to see if any Friends of
Bill have checked in and see if they
want to get together you can attend an
alcohol anomic but Alcoholics Anonymous
meeting or another addiction recovery
group meeting you can use your
employer's Employee Assistance Program
their EAP you can call the substance
abuse and mental health services
administration national helpline this
service provides referrals to local
treatment facilities support groups and
community-based organizations
what's most important is finding the
assistance and the framing that helps
you commit to the change you want to
make whether it's reduction moderation
or abstaining from alcohol and drugs
also let's talk about it here at
blackhat we have two open friends of
bill W meetings on Wednesday and
Thursday from 3 to 4 p.m. in Coral Sea
North Hall level lower level where we'll
talk about and support each other in
recovery and those that are looking
pursuing recovery as an option for them
and remember you're not alone 1 in 17
right September is national recovery
month and their events across the United
States to increase awareness and
understanding around substance use
disorder and mental disorders and to
celebrate the people who recover I
appreciate the opportunity to educate
you all on some of the facts and some of
them
surround alcohol use disorder and if
there's any questions please head to the
mics
[Applause]
if anybody would like to speak with me
privately after the session I will be
heading over to the rap room if there's
something that you'd like to talk about
that you would rather not talk about in
front of the group or ask as a question
again well she's coming up I just want
to really thank you for doing this talk
five years ago I had a major relapse at
Def Con I was really lucky to have a
friend who kind of helped look after me
and at that time I didn't know that
there were meetings here or that there
were you know other people coming to
these conferences who weren't partying
and getting wasted every night and it's
really important that we support each
other and I think also like like you
said try to break down the stigma about
talking about this stuff because I think
more people are dealing with it then you
know then we think and and it's because
of some of the fears and and I don't
know the stuff that you talked about it
was really great I'm really glad that
you did this Thanks thank you that one's
mine
Jamie hey thank you so much for this
talk my father was an alcoholic my
grandfather is an alcoholic and
sometimes I wonder if I'm more mindful
of myself taking days where I make sure
I'm not drinking or weeks where I'm not
make sure I'm not drinking because I'm
afraid of that but I've been at many
social events where I've decided I'm
gonna go and not have a drink I wanted
to know what's your favorite
non-alcoholic drink to order when you're
at a bar with coworkers so my favorite
non-alcoholic drink I do try to ask the
bartender hey can you just make a
mocktail for me and sometimes I get back
with this really weird gross version of
like every juice they have at the bar
that's not good my default is just a
ginger ale with lime
it tastes you know good to me but that's
that's my preference if I'm in a
situation where I know that there's some
question about whether or not you know
some people look at me suspiciously like
hey you're not drinking here I'll get it
poured and that like really tall glass
with a black straw which is really clear
like she's not drinking what I'll do is
I'll go to the bartender in advance or
to the waitress in advance I will say I
will tip you $20 if you give me tonic
water and lime in the lowball glass that
you do for a vodka tonic with a vodka
tonic straw keep bringing them and
pretend they're vodka tonics and they're
just tonic water and lime I will
continue to tip you all through the
night if that happens and it works
really well and it doesn't create an
awkward social moment that's great thank
you have one more question but I'll I'll
follow up and say I really love the bars
that when I order non-alcoholic drinks
they give them to me for free because
they're supporting designated drivers
and my other question is that where does
Bill W come from so bill W comes from
Alcoholics Anonymous he was the founder
of Alcoholics Anonymous and so that is
the basis of hearing that Friends of
Bill it's the sort of a code phrase of
saying like oh hey I'm in recovery or
I'm doing 12-step
a is not for everyone I and recognizing
that everybody's program is their own
program Alcoholics Anonymous and 12-step
programs are effective for those where
it works for them within their their
personal belief system but yeah friends
a bill that's related to Bill W from
Alcoholics Anonymous and I think that we
are out of time so thank you very much
for attending and have a great rest of
your conference