okay thanks Alan for the introduction so
today my topic is king lab iOS jailbreak
internals the userland agreed only
memory can be dangerous so as many of
you noticed that king lab demonstrated
iOS 10 points 3.2 and 11 beta to
jailbreak at more SEC 2017 but the
details of the vulnerability has never
been revealed yet so today I would like
to take this opportunity to show the
details of all geo-print chance which
the park is the involved so first about
myself I'm the security researcher and
also the team leader at Hope Tencent
King secret lab and there previously my
research covers on the browser
vulnerability research exploitation
major Leon's Safari Chrome II and the
internet is prologue and now my focus
moved to the Apple vulnerability
research mainly for the same sandbox by
posse and also cannot privilege
escalation so today our agenda is like
we will firstly talk about the memory
protection implemented by our modern OS
this is not very interesting topic
because it is there for many years
next we discuss about the iOS DMA
features including the previous research
as well as the implementation of the iOS
m io m mu protection and the next
because King lab did a lot of reversing
work on iOS GPU notification mechanism
part since it is not open source part of
iOS kernel and there with enough
knowledge explained we will finally talk
about the pack which includes two of
them the first one is in the DMA mapping
feature vulnerability and another is
auto pound right in the apple
fix tech after the vulnerability has
been explained we will talk about the
exploitation we saw demo and then we
were concluded this talk so the first
part is operating system memory
protection overview so modern OS
actually implements the memory
protection at the hardware level to
mitigate the non attack attacks they are
introduced in different levels for
example the translation blog entry
properties at the MMU level so in this
part we will they introduced an external
executable bit and also the pxn to
prevent excusing the user land from the
kernel side and also the AP which
indicates access protection like the
read only or write only or execute only
memory and there besides that there are
also some of the medications like the
kppa mcc which is also relating to the
memory protection but they are
implemented in maybe deeper under lower
level which is not our scope of the talk
so among those memory protection
mechanisms use a land read only mapping
is a very old-school approach to protect
the user land the memory it is very
easily implemented but very effective
there are three major scenario of using
such read-only user land memory mappings
the first one is for example the
executable memory in iOS is only
read-only to prevent the attackers from
over writing the code at a very early
stage of exploitation and along with
some other medications like the code
signing enforcement this has made the
iOS very strong in security and the
second scenario is the sharing memory
the first is the second one is between
process for example two processes share
one physical copy of the memory
in a second in the sort of scenario it
is a sharing memory between the kernel
under the process memories sharing at
user land make the inter process or user
to kernel communication more efficient
this is because you do not need to use
traditional message sender mechanism
like the to call some disk or to call
some trap to send the buffer from the
user to the kernel and there in that way
the server process or the kernel who
owns that memory can trust the map can
trust it because he is the only one who
can modify it well the client side all
the client process can only have the
read-only process which it is not
possible to change the memory then the
owner process of the all the kernel can
eliminate the specific secret
considerations such as the boundary
check or the time of check or time of
youth issues so it's implementation at
the MMU level is quite easy it has in
the tbe entry it introduced access
protection bit where you can find the
specification document on the right side
our not looking to it very detailing
under when there is a way found to make
the mapping rightful then the whole
touched boundary of memory will be
broken but you need to make sure that
the memory is remapped into rightful
without marking them copy-on-write
otherwise another copy of the physical
memory will be introduced and we are not
able to mutate the original physical
copy of another mapping still under once
that is done then it can lead to
privilege escalation so in the process
to process memory sharings in there
you can lead to it can lead to sandbox
bypass Wow for the purple processed you
kernel memory sharing scenario when you
are able to modify a read-only mapping
it is very possible for you to get a
kernel code of X fusion
I always actually has its nature to
prevent such right polar mappings at its
kernel code you can see that once memory
is mapped to children you through the
process using read-only actually it has
that mapping has a property called max
protection and that max protection is
set no no higher than rightful so that
when you try to remap it as a read and
write the kernel will reject you
immediately but there is an exception
when you you specify a copy on write
protection properties it will the
remapping will be allowed but another
copy of the physical memory will be used
so you are still not able to modify that
original memory and of course there is
some historical issues for example the
first one reproducer enjoyed gr the
memory making it write book and cause
some issues and the second one is for on
Windows platform however you will be
noticed that on iOS platform there is no
such known issues so we have to research
on our the next part will cover the iOS
DMA features because the more stronger
under stronger and more abundant
features provided by modern peripheral
devices attached the to the mode mobile
device DMA technology is introduced to
enable the ability for faster data
transfer under interesting Lee the DMA
transfer we are not involved in a cpu so
that the access permission bits
and the virtual addresses will be simply
ignored and the next question is as the
DMA transfer use the physical address
and know if that is the case the no
memory protection is involved anymore
but definitely it is not the case
why because modern phones are first
reason is that modern friends are 64-bit
while many of their peripheral devices
remains 32-bit in that case address
translation is quite needed to trans
translate from 64-bit memory to 32-bit
memory and there another reason is that
we have to enforce the memory protection
for the DMA transfer also because if it
is not there it is not safe right the
because of this the M iommu is
introduced that you perform this job io
m mu if under 30 666 bit iOS device the
concept at that which refers to device
address resolution table is actually
introduced and responsible to perform
such address translation and there are
two kind of DMA one for host to device
DMA and another for device to host the
DMA for host to to device DMA actually
the system physical memory is mapped
into IO space visible by the device and
the device to host DMA it's actually
mapped the device memory back to the OS
virtual memory so that it can be
identified by the operating system and
in the middle 2017
Karl from Google Protege rope leverages
the EMA features on iOS to achieve the
firmware to host an attack under he
compromised the I Wi-Fi stack first and
then try to mutate some right podium a
mapping in the device memory and it is
also share the choose our OS kernel
memory under the OS iOS thinks that
there the DMA on the device is possible
so it's a limited necessary boundary
check and finally with the Wi-Fi stack
compromised it is very easy to to modify
that memory and finally lead to your
kernel code exclusion however such
attack has some limitations what a
pervious limited limitation is that such
attack can only be performed in a short
distance that scenario because you have
to compromise the Wi-Fi stack first
under that requires the attacker and the
big team in the same Wi-Fi environment
is it possible for us to make it long
distance for example we have a browser
exploit we can try to launch it remotely
by the browser exploit and together with
a kernel privilege escalation back and
of course by utilizing the DMA related
parks under that look like a very crazy
idea because the DMA features like are
kind of very low level implementation
which is mostly performed at the kernel
level or the device level it is not
exposed to chooser you landed directly
for sure and there is it is still
possible to think of it because there
might be some incorrect user land DMA on
the iOS for example it on the iOS system
it has some JPEG engine it is
responsible to to accelerator the
encoding and the decoding process and
also in another scenario there is I all
surface transform and actually it is
done by the hardware
it's called a scalar device and we were
looking to the iOS home feature a little
bit under with actually King labs
dependence on come to investigate their
iOS
I also face transform feature and before
we study it I'd like to briefly
introduce the iOS surface and the iosef
is accelerator framework some so on the
apple what the aisle surface represents
a user land buffer which is shared with
the kernel and the user land
applications can create a user IO
surface by providing a existing user
land buffer address and its length
so the code on the right side shows the
creation process so it first gets the
properties of that user land memory and
then Creator IO
memory descriptor with specific property
as options so here if option k io
direction out instead it indicates that
the user land mapping is read-only under
once the read-only mapping is a
read/write then option k io perishing
out as well as ki out eruption in where
people step and the second framework is
the IO surface accelerator and it's a
kind of noodle and a framework for and
it is only existing in iOS platform and
there are two important interfaces one
is I also this accelerator create and
another is I also this accelerator
transfer service
the first one is responsible for
creating I will kill the plant
connection representing our i/o surface
accelerator client could object under
the second interface well takes to our
old service tap handles one for the saw
Silas office and the other for the
destination and the build a transform
and there is one typical scenario of you
using this remote which is the screen
snapshot where you have your destination
I also service as receiving buffer under
the system mem tensor I also face the
photo frame buffer and you make this
transfer and you can get to a screenshot
of it of your current - screen and here
is the low level implementation of the
i/o surface patch accelerator so on the
top side you can see there is a object
called IO surface accelerator plant so
under the next component is the Apple mq
scanner CSC which is a upper level
driver and it talks to the hole which
stands for Hardware of a structuring
abstract level and the latter handles
the device independent dependent stuff
and the provided that device independent
interface to the driver under this
device for object also creates five
important objects which stand for some
important registers for that device and
that object Paul also maps a device
memory from the device IO space into the
kernel virtual space we are DMA
represents that the device key registers
so here is the overall flow for the
transform the first is the kernel where
validates the parameter from the unified
user land and then it obtains the source
and the destination IO surface address
and then it mapped the iOS our surface
buffer where DMA under then it obtains a
mapped address and set some buffer the
device buffer and then it has thoughts
scalar device and after the scalar
device is started then the kernel wait
for the interrupt
from the device to wait for its
completeness and after it is complete
everything is finished so we are mostly
interested on the DMA mapping part and
we are not interested in other part so
this is actually bound by the function
set map prepared a memory descriptor and
the years at function code you can see
that a kernel object called IO DMA
account created created with a very
special IO mapper and actually that
mapper is the instance of ioad part
mapper which is independent between
devices to make sure that device and the
device are separated in separated
reading i all space addresses so that
one can not interfere another and the
using a very basic I Oh s utility called
IO rec you can find this instance the
map instance for the dart scaler
under then the IO
surface memory descriptive descriptor
will be pointed to the i/o DMX Mountain
and the next step is to obtain mapped
i/o surface address in the i/o space
this is done by the calling the function
generate IO VM segments after you call
this function you obtain that address
and you can note notice that this race
tree indicates the result address which
is being 32-bit and after you create the
source and the destination iOS iOS
office address in IO space it's time to
set the scalar device register the key
register is for South Texas destination
config consume this object is used that
you specify those addresses under once
do you decide those addresses you just
changes or you specify it so we are
giving some real value understating to
some specific offset in that mapped
virtual memory and after that this is
done and the final thing is to start to
the scalar this is very easy you just
need to stare to one which indicates the
power of option at the offsets of 1 to 8
and there after you make that value to 1
the scalar device starts it's working it
starts its work immediately and the
final thing is for Colonel to wait for
that device to finish working and the
issue interrupter event to indicate that
this has been done okay so the next part
I will cover for the iommu memory
protection so similar as the system mme
you page table the iowa mm you also need
to have the page table specification
however unlike the cv cpu MMU the page
table document for iommu is not there so
you have to reverse the iOS part code to
find out as a specification and we did
it also and the coincidently call from
project zero google project zero also he
did a similar work and here I just put a
picture or written by him on the right
side you can see that it has very
similar specification as CPU MMU however
in his blog he didn't mention that
whether as iommu supports the memory
protection or not so here is a piece of
his block he said it is unknown whether
it is it came facility the user
read-only mappings however actually by
reversing the coding iOS 11 we can get
to the answer so I will be a map memory
function is
entry point for mapping the memory in IO
space among which map options parameter
here has included the memories
protection bit seeing of virtual space
so here the last repeat seeing that map
options is translated to a Direction
value of visible by the iommu so here
for read-only mappings it has the
direction value to and the right only
mapping has the value 1 and the read and
the write mapping has the value 3 we
only needed to remember this and these
of arrival finally reach the lower level
implementation part under a function for
the state translation is finally reached
under from the code logic here we can
clearly see that actually the 8 and the
nice bit in the TT entry ap related bits
so finally we got the access protection
specification in ki te for iommu on iOS
so here the red part is AP bits and the
arrow that will stand for read and write
there one read only and one zero right
on deck next we talk about the GPU
notification mechanism under our iPhone
7 device we found that Apple graphics
provides with 128 channels for
concurrent processing those channels are
have three categories CL channel GL
Channel and the GI Channel and the
kernel wraps join instructions from
userland and put them into those
channels and then kernel just wait for
the GPU to finish processing because of
that a well designed the notification
mechanism is very necessary because
it'll need to support for such high high
need for concurrent processing here is a
Bree brief architecture of the
notification the GPU task actually earns
us temporary representing our temple
status of each channel so this memory is
actually a representation of the uint32
agree of 100 under 28 elements each
showing the last complete instructions
step of that channel and this stamp
array memory is actually mapped not only
to the kernel but also to the userland
and of course the EULA land mapping is
read-only and the kernel also maintains
a rake or the stamp address array and
this array is very simply constructed by
the coder below under it
it contains address array of 128
elements and each element represents the
virtual address of that mapped stamp
stators kernel address under the stamp
value of each channel is incremental
upon each of the instruction processing
completeness which means once the
processing is completed then the GPU we
are update that stamp value add it by 1
and the in the kernel side there is also
a object called IO axial event which
represents the expected extent value
being specific channel of one or one
group of joying
instructions so one axial event IO axial
event contains eight sub events and one
sub event is eight bytes in sites where
it's lower for pipes represents the
channel index and the higher 4 bytes
represents the expected
and temple you of that joy instruction
so to test whether a jury instruction
has been completed or not you just need
to compare the extent expected temper
value with the value in that temporary
so here is a code it's check whether
expect a stamp is higher than the
current last completed in stamp value if
it is higher then it continues the
waiting process in the loop in either
loop but if it is smaller or equal it
means that joinings instruction has
already been finished last but not the
least to improve the performance the I
some of the io axial event object are
also mapped into the userland which is
highly related to our part this is to
make sure that the user land
applications can understand the status
of the current current instruction and a
la current event without asking the
curve of soldier the userland
a PP can also test whether the event had
has been completed or not okay now with
almost all the concepts we are explained
let's discuss about the real
vulnerabilities so the first of all
ability is quite simple and they're
obvious is 10 and the early beta of iOS
11 actually the map options of the
virtual memory is simply ignored by the
thought mapper so from the code below
you can see that in the third code I OBM
a lock there is an option called map
options which indicates accept
protection bits of the virtual memory
and this parameter is never used later
in that function and in the lower level
implementation when the
translation Asia is caught you can fund
that to the 8 spite and a bit and the
night bit of the tte apples set to zero
which indicates from our previous
research their own vero means the read
and write it means for any kind of user
land mappings or colonel at inland
mappings once it is translated and
mapped into the i/o space it is always
read on the right and the second is out
of point of bright vulnerability so
before I talk about it I will explain
the concept of the i/o axial resource
object actually I lack sale resource
object is very similar in functionality
as the aisle surface object except that
I will axial resource which presents a
share the New Zealand buffer which would
be mapped into the GPU tasks and like
the iOS our service object we can also
create the IO IO axial resource object
by specifying an existing noodle and
buffer wings are Uhland applications
under during the initialization process
share the mapping will be created this
shared mapping is called IO axial and
shared IO under this object contains io
axial event array with 4 elements with
the resource ID under its type
information under this object the whole
object is mapped into post noodle and
Andrew kernel and of course the noodle
and mapping is read-only and this
address will also be returned to the
user land application so the user will
know the trace of it and the user user
application can also delete the created
io axial results by calling the method 1
in IO axial share do you LaPlante
under after that the test event function
well being reached under this function
actually simply checks which if each i/o
axial event objecting IO axial and
shared ro is completed or not the coda
logic is quite simple so first it check
whether the events expect
stamp is lower than the current temp
maintained during a object called em in
line array and if yes then it means the
event has been completed yeah and if not
then the code tried to fetch the latest
stamp of value from the device memory
which is referred to by other array M
stamp address every and the after the
latest value has been obtained
it's a builder comparison again in to do
the comparison again and the check if it
is smaller or bigger under decide
whether this this event has been
completed or not it looks so very good
at first glance however together with
DMA mapping back that it is possible
that we can we can modify the channel
index here and because this this object
is created by kernel and is not possible
to be mutated by the user land
applications kernel fully cut it under
it's a talented form enough boundary
check
so once the index is mutated to a very
big value then of course we will have
out of bound read to read out the array
of the MCM array address
and readouts that value and then write
user em in line array which is OB right
[Music]
okay so after the box has been explained
let's look into the exploitation so
exploitability of those two parts
depends on whether we can control the
content for both m in an array and the M
temp address array we need to control
the content of both of them it looks
like a very hard task this is because
that both arrays are created in very
early stage of the iOS booting process
and it looks impossible that we can put
very controlled contents right after
them and also the second reason is that
the size of the element of each array is
quite different
the larger the index we specify the
longer span that is the address of the
reference array element we have so
that's not a very good news and the to
exploit this Park the memory layout
thing is a key factor before doing that
we need to understand the some facts the
first effect is that kernel heap memory
starts at a relatively low address and a
heap can glow ocurro
line ly with more and more memory
allocated under the start address of the
heap differs we see in tens of megabytes
upon each put this is to chooser early
by random value under also the address
of em in line array and the MS temp
address array are closed with each other
and because of that we can use a
relatively large channel index along
with some technologies like kernel hips
break we might able to increase the
possibility to
make sure that upon the value of post
array and our control so we definitely
need a heap spray technologies and
luckily this is not a problem because it
is we're all published under you can
fund a lot of public articles about it
and iPhone 7 under our test we can spray
around the 300 and the 15 megabytes
kernel memory we seeing the container
sandbox applications and after those two
arrays are created there are around 50
megabytes extra kernel memory allocated
[Music]
so what conclusion we can get at this
stage the first that because the em in
line array element size is 24 bytes
under M temp address array element size
is 8 bytes so if we can make sure that
the index value multiplied by 24 is
smaller than 400 megabytes under index
value multiplied by 8 is larger than 15
megabytes then with we get the range of
index using this this range and if the
index is in this range we will have
higher probabilities and higher
possibilities that post also upon the
value of post array are following into
our spread data and the next issue is
you have arbitrary memory read and write
according to the nature of the park the
arbitrary memory read is not a problem
because M stamp address array element
size is 8 bytes with arbitrary index
value you can reach every D Ward's
within each page however the higher 4
bytes of code cannot be read
but it is not necessary because we in
usually to make it code execution you
only needed to modify an address lower
bytes below four bytes instead of the
high of robots
however the arbitrary memory right is
more tricky because there because
because the M in line array element size
is 24 bytes only one of its D order can
be written so it introduced a very
interesting issue can we all be right to
an arbitrary offset in l0 X 4000 page
with all B array element size only 24
part before we solve this issue we need
to understand the some facts the facts
the first effects is a good news thanks
to the mechanism of the iOS excellent
you zoom a locator the base address of M
England array is always at offset zero X
F 0 or 0 X 2 0 F 0 because it is filled
in some bigger object which is 1 4000
new in Tucson the page is two thousand
the insights they don't excuse on the
insights and the similarly and stamp
addressed array is allocated with 0 X
200 insights falling into the catalog
dot 500 thousand and this address offset
we seeing the arrow X 4 thousand page
can all be the values can all can be all
values divided by PI 0 X 200 so this is
a good news under similarly we need to
fund a fund a way to write up III page
offset by all B right on em in line
array and this problem can be solved
actually part by a mathematic theory
called the congruence sir
so because 0 XC 0 0 0 is divided by PI 0
X 4,000 so o int X values where are the
remainder values divided by 0 X 800 are
the same so we can always open right to
choose the same offset in the M in line
array and the width in the factor here
which gets a conclusion that's given the
int X equal to 0 except to 7f 6 + and
multiple PI 0 X 800 so if that condition
is meet we we can always override the
chooser first 8 bytes in a spray the
page under the next problem is to reach
the arbitrary offset within the page we
sing with M be the offset of the page we
just ensure that index equals to this
under we can reach to arbitrary offset
within the page so we resolved this
problem so here you don't need to
understand all the stories of the
concurrence a lot of theory but you only
need to remember the results that our
conclusion
so when index equals to this under it's
missing the range of this then we can we
are able to to overwrite arbitrary
offset in a page and at last we choose
the value 0 X 9 6 1 8 5 which means it
can reach the opposite 5 6 8 of 1 4000
page by writing this M in line are a lot
of punt and now let's do the first
attempt of exploitation first we try to
explore spray around the three hundred
and fifty megabytes
under the logic is here the test event
function will reach the all B values
here here under then it's a try to try
to try to put a guest address on to it
under refer to the value of it in slot B
we call it have the value written read
what value to read under the value that
is red will be finally written to the
slot see at the offset 0 X 5 6 8 which
is M in line array in my array are
written under by first attempt of the
exploit we then receive the OMS
intricacy which message ate up refute
the address written field has been
changed by checking the new value in
that address we can obtain two very
important piece of information the first
information is which our message is
allocated in slots in another state on
the message important information is
which Oh error message is in slot peeled
because we can specify each of our
messages via our field very unique and
asked after we cut those information we
can perform the second exploit to bypass
a SAR we do it by filling a slot p with
h x GL context object and that object is
in Kellogg dot 8 1 9 2 so it's very good
you can feel free the slot P and a
feeling at the same address and then we
change the GA value to this which Allah
is all reaching a value minus 0 X so T
because the pace address of slot P is a
read
of the first eight bytes of the object
is vtable
address of HX GL context object so we
exploit the part again and finally we
got the lower four bytes of the HX GL
context of the table and after that so
we obtain there we bypass the ksar and
the finally we we needed a code
execution so to get the code execution
we need to free the slot see under
feeling with the object where it's upset
0x five six eight represents some
important object and we found the HX GL
context is a best choice also because
it's upset five six eight represents HX
accelerator object by calling that user
clients method of zero we can reach the
function context to finish and the
contest finish will give reference that
objects five six eight as pure as a HX
accelerate object and the use it to call
its virtual functions so pi exploits
that part again we are able to modify
the lower four bytes of that HX
accelerate object and modify the to any
arbitrary value and there we can consume
the content of that new address so that
we get PC consume
so finally I talked about the overall
exploit overflow so first we create I or
axial resource and then we call to the
i/o axial event read-only buffer we
treat the first part to modify the M
channel index to a bigger value and then
we clear prepare as a memory layout
trigger pakka to to obtain the index of
the slot B and the slots root C and then
we prepare the memory layout under two
to four ksar par-5 has taken about a two
and obtain the vtable of HX GL context
so that we bypassed ksar and finally we
prepare the memory Lake out again for
pay code execution to take a bug to
again and the overrides the ihx
accelerator pointer in Ajax GL context
and after that we can perform a rock
under gets the task of all p IE 0 and
then we perform post exploitation huge
jailbreak so after that we got such task
or PID 0 but it's only first step of the
jailbreak
we still need to break the amfi to
remember the route ifs to read and write
and the to perform the KPG and AMCC
bypass a statue and those are very well
documented outside publicly and it's not
a scope of our talk under we will assure
a demo of the attack yeah so because of
the time limitation i will skip some
parts and the first we we choose working
ten point three point three because I
only have this version which can exploit
at this part actually the park also
exists in some early version of iOS 11
beta but I don't have the device so we
click our application we bypass the
sandbox actually there is no sim parks
because we exploit the kernel directory
but are we involved
cubox so one I think maybe sometimes it
can also the DMA feature party can also
bypass the sandbox also but here we
don't use it we just use data to change
the index channel index
yeah after we bypass the PP k PP then it
do a risk bring and finally we found
that the the Cydia is installed on this
machine with European yeah but it's a
little bit broken but I think with
triple actions you can make it work yeah
and the finally you
under the corrected version of it and
there finally I talk about the
conclusion so with the first release of
iOS 11 Apple actually fix the first Park
which is a DMA mapping back under it is
actually fixed by adding the
implementation of the read-only mapping
at its path code under however there are
other Oh be right back
remains unfixed up till now and this is
a very good example of how secret can be
broken by a very bad implementation but
with very good hardware design and it
makes possible of very complex exploit
change to achieve that your break within
the Wilderland applications at this
stage it is still safe to say that
because with the first part fixed the
trust boundary of the user land
read-only mapping is back so you don't
need to to fix the part too but it
brings a problem to us should we
actually trust the kernel user userland
read-only mappings and of course
currently there is no definite answer
because I don't have another way to
break that trust boundary but at least
in this talk we demonstrated that the
user land read-only mapping can be
dangerous
it is possible that in the future
another part is introduced and a break
this trust boundary boundary again and
we make the whole exploit chain walk
again it's very likely and we never know
at this moment thanks for listening and
if you have any