so without further ado join me in
welcoming IJ we've audio
not for me for the video we have the
world of the Internet of Things internet
of Internet of Things what is the
Internet of Things is kinkabe unlike the
Internet of Things will transform the
way we do business
healthy people everywhere lives
healthier safer
[Music]
Chrysler has ordered a recall of over a
million trucks and cars after hackers
were able to take control of a jeep over
the Internet like so many thousands of
jeeps around the world it can be
remotely hacked over the internet
through a cellular connection to its
entertainment system they would allow
someone to take over its theory its
transmission and even its brakes
shocking new revelations from former
Vice President Dick Cheney admitting
that he feared his heart problems the
cost of his life but not in the way you
think just how easy it can be for
hackers to take over the stoplights on
your commute a major security
vulnerability affecting several white
label security cameras which allows us
to get the password to the camera no
matter how complex it is people cannot
use computers from far away systems to
attack your Internet of Things devices
the locks on your doors your HVAC and
air conditioning system can do all sorts
of really scary things in this new world
[Music]
so the video reflects and as will come
as a surprise to precisely no one in
this room IOT is going through a very
rapid era of change and like it or not
and realized it or not one of the
biggest changes that's right around the
corner is that there's about to be an
explosion in litigation and enforcement
activity when it comes to IOT hacks and
vulnerabilities my name is IJ Polanski
and I am NOT a cybersecurity expert
which means that it's a little bit odd
for me to find myself here at blackhat
and in fact when I found out that black
had accepted my proposal to talk I was
stunned
pleasantly which was very quickly
replaced by severe anxiety that nobody
would actually be interested in what I
have to say but looking out over a
pretty full room now I've got a new
concern which is that I don't totally
screw this thing up but luckily for me
and hopefully luckily for you I have
some relevant and even unique experience
with respect to IOT litigation so I'm a
trial lawyer and you probably already
knew that because I'm the guy black hat
with the suit
I focus on complex commercial litigation
some consumer class actions as well I
mostly represent defendants but a
particular relevance to this audience
I'm the lead lawyer in the federal
class-action lawsuit that followed from
the g-pack Court the Charlie Miller and
Chris valasek did and presented here at
blackhat in 2015 and 2016 and for those
of you who didn't know just a few weeks
ago the federal courts certified a class
of about two hundred and twenty thousand
of those vehicles which means that we
can proceed in one case for all of the
owners and all of the people who leased
all of those two hundred and twenty
thousand cars and trucks and talk about
that a little bit as we go along before
Negro I go any further I should probably
explain this sort of weird comic book II
thing I couldn't resist given the
audience and the fact that we're in
Vegas that's actually me from an article
in Wired magazine that they decided to
do as a comic book about when I played
the world's best AI poker computer in an
exhibition down the street at the World
Series of Poker about ten years ago so
after the talk if anybody wants a poker
game we'll all head over to Bellagio
alright so what do I want to accomplish
here today I actually have some pretty
ambitious goals I want to change the way
the people in the IOT space seem to be
thinking and ultimately what I want to
get to is to provide some fairly
concrete suggestions about what you and
your organization's can do to minimize
the risk that comes from the litigation
that we're discussing what it's going to
take a few steps to get there and the
place to start is by observing a
distinction between data breach matters
cases lawsuits and IOT vulnerability
hack lawsuits and the difference is
important for a couple of reasons but
first of all let's describe it data
breach disputes are relatively
straightforward you're all probably
familiar with them it's when a computer
network gets exploited and data gets
stolen IOT hacks and IOT vulnerability
based disputes and litigation litigation
are different first of all a pretty
different set of rules
the rules that apply to data breach do
not generalize to cases about IOT and
relatedly there have been a fair number
of lawsuits about data breach they've
worked their way up through the courts
and there's some precedent there's a
track record there and the saying just
isn't true when it comes to IOT
litigation there's very very little
probably that case that's gone the
furthest and the biggest case is my
team's g-pack case and that's got some
important implications with respect to
uncertainty risk and questions about how
long-standing rules are going to apply
so ultimately what I want to do is I
want to convince the people in the
audience here today that they've been
radically under estimating the risk and
the cost associated with what I believe
is an inevitable wave of IOT based
litigation that's right around the
corner conditions have changed and are
changing we're reaching an inflection
point where what's what plaintiffs
lawyers and the plaintiffs bar have been
talking about for years is about to
happen and that is all of the conditions
are going to be right for a wave of
these lawsuits where do we start I think
the place to start is actually with the
discussion policy and the reason is
we're talking about claims we're gonna
define what claims are in a little while
the rules of the road when it comes to
these lawsuits that have been around for
200 years the rules aren't any different
there are gonna be some legislative
rules some new statutes and some new
regulations and those are important
parts of regulating any type of conduct
when it comes to enforcement litigation
or just private civil litigation the
rules are the same the question is how
are they going to be applied and the
rules are strong and they're flexible
and they've been applied to new
technology over and over again for
decades but IOT is a little bit
different for at least a couple of
reasons first of all the technology is
extremely complex but also the
relationships of the parties involved
are a little bit different than most of
the relationships
in lawsuits up until now the
relationship between the user and the
supply side is a little bit different
and the relationship of all of the
different entities in the supply side
ecosystem there are so many of them and
what they do is so interconnected and
interrelated raises some really
challenging complexities when it comes
to IOT litigation and what that means is
that it's hard to predict how this
litigation is going to play out it's
hard to understand what you should be
doing if you're someone in the IOT space
to try to protect yourself when I end up
in a situation like that if there's
ambiguity or uncertainty I like to go
back to first principles because if you
understand what the rules are designed
to do and what they're supposed to
accomplish that's going to help you to
understand and predict how they're going
to be applied and I actually think a
really good place to start that
discussion is with the question that
Jeff Watts posed in introducing the
keynote speech at last year's blackhat
and he asked what would make defense
greater than offense that probably means
different things to different people but
as a trial lawyer who focuses on IOT I'm
going to tell you what it means to me
what it means to me is it's really hard
to measure defense if it's hard to
measure defense that's not limited to
cyber security it's true in sports it's
true in all kinds of different contexts
but if it's hard to measure something
you're not going to be able to put up an
accurate value on it and especially when
it comes to IOT right now when
everybody's trying to get the latest and
greatest gadget out to market as quickly
as possible so that they can get that
first mover advantage and cyber security
presents costs both in terms of dollars
and in terms of time if you're not
accurately valuing defense chances are
you're under investing in it and if
you're under investing in it then almost
by definition your products or if you're
contributing to an IOT product your
contribution is not going to reach the
right level or type of cyber security
now everybody in the room probably just
realized that what I just said
a whole bunch of issues packed into it
what is the right level of cybersecurity
for an IOT product and that's an
amazingly complicated question but
whatever the answer is if your product
has a hack or there's an important
vulnerability that's exposed and you get
drawn into litigation or the media
focuses on it they're gonna be asking
what did you do why did this happen
where did things go wrong and you're
gonna want to make really sure that
you're on the right side of the line
when the person who needs to answer the
question which is likely to be a judge
or a jury who doesn't know very much
about cybersecurity but when the
question is put to them and they have to
answer the question what is the right
level of cybersecurity for this
particular product and did this
organization need it you want to make
sure that you're on the right side of
that line with the margin for error
because if you're not not only are you
going to get dragged into the litigation
but you can be held liable
so there's massive cost and
significantly more risk than in most
other situations now as it happens this
is actually exactly the rule that the
legal system and lawsuits is supposed to
play in society there are different laws
and rules that are designed to regulate
conduct you've got statutes
you've got regulations and you also have
the court system and right now for IOT
cybersecurity I think that statutes and
regulations are an important piece of
the puzzle but it's going to be really
hard I'm from Washington DC I've been
there ever since I graduated from law
school and it's not going to come as a
surprise to anybody here the city is
completely dysfunctional so relying on
them to come up with the right statute
in a highly technologically complex area
where things are evolving so quickly is
probably not the best idea there are
regulatory agencies that are focusing on
it as well but they kind of face the
same issues and there are issues of
regulatory capture and so what you wind
up with is probably elevated importance
for the legal system
and when there are lawsuits there are a
couple of primary considerations that
drive a couple primary principles that
drive the underlying purpose of those
lawsuits in the civil context so take as
an example I do something wrong and it
injures you okay you bring a lawsuit
against me and if you can show that I
was at fault and that fault caused your
injury then the lawsuit the luck the
legal system wants me to pay for your
injuries
so two components to that one is
compensation you want to make sure that
somebody who's innocent and was injured
through no fault of their own doesn't
have to bear those costs themselves but
the flipside of it in determining
accountability it provides deterrence
this economists might call the sending
the right signal or incentive or making
sure that the right actors are
internalizing their costs so that they
are acting responsibly and this is
particularly true when it comes to
product liability the courts will try to
identify the actor or the actors who are
best situated to make sure that their
products are safe and if the products
turn out not to be safe then the rules
in place are likely to impose liability
almost regardless of fault depending on
the particular claim and depending on
what happened so all of this again gives
us some insight into how IOT hacking and
vulnerability litigation is likely to
play out now before I go on before I go
any further I want to take a step back
talk about IOT products in general there
are lots of them the estimates vary a
lot but you're up over twenty billion by
2020 these things are everywhere and
they're multiplying like rabbits I want
to talk about some of my favorite most
ridiculous IOT products in in third
place the bronze medalists the smart IOT
water bottle this one glows when it
wants you to drink
so I imagine that this is solving some
innate human problem that we don't know
what to do if we're thirsty but luckily
we're all going to get saved by the
glowy water bottle
silver medalist the IOT showerhead so
this one lets you turn on the water and
set the temperature before you get into
the shower now I've never had too much
trouble just reaching in and turning a
little handle what I can tell you with
certainty that if I had one of these
things in my house as soon as I got into
the shower my twelve year old in my
fourteen year old would hack into my
account and change my 90 degree shower
into a 40 degree shower and the gold
medallist easily is the internet
connected I condom this is real and they
market it as something that tracks
statistics and performance of the user
and uploads it to the cloud so that he
can compare his statistics to other
people around the world I'm not sure
whether this is more disturbingly
narcissistic or pathetically insecure
but I think most people can probably
live without this although I do see some
intrigue faces in the audience right now
so maybe I'm wrong alright so why does
that matter everybody likes fancy
gadgets right well it matters because
these things can cause harm and to a
certain extent I really do believe
people are under estimating it and IO
tight IOT products have certain
characteristics that if anything make
them more vulnerable than computer
systems they all have processors they
all have communication capacities and as
I pointed out earlier for various
reasons many of them tend to have
limited cyber security cyber security
may be an afterthought add to that that
a lot of these products have different
versions of code
they're often proprietary it makes
detection of cyberattacks more difficult
and patching more difficult and then you
have some per tick
Killer user issues not only patch lag
but consumers in society are just
starting to learn how to interact with
IOT at all let alone how to interact
with it in a way that's safe from a
cybersecurity perspective and what that
means is there are a lot of different
ways that these products can cause harm
so we've got data breach I said I wasn't
going to focus on that and I'm not going
to but obviously we don't forget about
it what you've got ransomware
you've got consumer products like the
ones that I just looked at that are
begging to be strung together into
botnets for DDoS attacks you got privacy
related issues like the webcam hack for
a few years ago that I'll mention again
in a few minutes and then you've got the
big one potential potential for cyber
physical impacts and this is really
important for a couple of reasons at
least one is that if there's a physical
impact either a personal injury or an
injury to property there is going to be
a lawsuit it's virtually guaranteed
because there is a victim that can be
trotted out in front of the jury
relatedly the legal rules when there is
a physical injury to person or property
are much more favorable to plaintiffs
and with the capability of IOT for
having cyber physical impacts on a hack
when this happens if you can get
attribution there is absolutely going to
be a lawsuit in virtually every instance
and we can think of some examples
already of cyber physical impacts from
IOT hacks you've got the Dick Cheney
example that was mentioned in the video
you've got Stuxnet and there are some
other interesting examples I was at a
presentation yesterday about industrial
IOT and then you have the one that's
near and dear to my heart
the g-pack case where obviously they
managed to hack a Jeep in a way that
they could control the brakes the
steering and even the ignition okay
that's great you're probably sitting
there saying this is no different than
it's been for years and we all know that
plaintiffs lawyers are not exactly shy
about bringing lawsuits if there's any
possibility of success so if there
hasn't been a wave of
lawsuits already why does Polanski think
there's going to be a wave of lawsuits
going forward and I'm gonna answer their
question and the answer surrounds how
plaintiffs lawyers think and what they
take into account when they're making a
decision about whether to take on a case
so as the cartoon reflects you've got
your standard ambulance-chasing
plaintiffs lawyers that's certainly true
but you also have some pretty good
plaintiffs lawyers they're smart they're
creative and above all else they tend to
be really good business people and their
business is investing in lawsuits
because plaintiffs lawyers often get
paid through a contingency fee which
means they only get paid if they win and
so obviously there are some factors that
they're going to take into account when
they're evaluating whether or not to
take on a case some of those are obvious
they're gonna want to know what the
likelihood of success is they're gonna
want to know how much they're gonna win
if they do succeed but there are all of
these factors that somewhat relate to
the things have already been talking
about that have made conditions not
right for IOT private civil lawsuits in
most circumstances first there haven't
been that many IOT hacks that are good
candidates for lawsuits to have a
lawsuit you need to have harm and you
need to have attribution so there's
certainly been a lot of IOT hacks there
have been some big ones but not
necessarily ones that are good
candidates for lawsuits relatedly nobody
understands this stuff plaintiffs
lawyers don't judges don't juries don't
and if a plaintiff's lawyer doesn't
understand the technology and doesn't
quite know how the legal rules are going
to apply they don't have a playbook that
increases the risk associated with
taking on that case and they're going to
decline it more often than not and
related to that there are a few
precedents like I said there really
aren't any in this field but all of
these things are right on the verge of
changing I think people tend to agree
that the cybersecurity by and large and
IOT
products is not where it needs to be
there are going to be more hacks there
are going to be widespread hacks they're
going to be hacks with cyber-physical
impacts and those are absolutely going
to lead to lawsuits and as there are
more lawsuits plaintiffs lawyers will
become more knowledgeable and more
comfortable with this field and as that
happens there will be more precedents
and you'll end up with a snowball effect
that takes off very very quickly and
this isn't just speculation on my part
obviously that's like the fact that I'm
primarily a defense attorney I'm playing
some role in this with the g-pack case
but I can tell you for a fact that this
is what the plaintiffs bar the group of
plaintiffs lawyers in this country have
been talking about for years they've
been salivating over this it's going to
be a feeding frenzy and they're right on
the cusp of this all being triggered
there's one related set of issues I want
to talk about i term this
interconnectedness may not be the type
of interconnectedness you're thinking of
but the idea here is that the ecosystem
on the supply side is so complex and
interconnected that it creates a new
type of risk for all of the defendants
so let me give you an example imagine
the cars driving along it hops a curb
and it hits a pedestrian the pedestrians
hurt he brings a lawsuit
who's he sue Sue's the driver Sue's the
car manufacturer may be the steering
failed of the brakes failed so he sues
the manufacturer of that component it's
not straightforward but it's not
terribly complicated now imagine that
that's a self-driving vehicle or even
just a connected vehicle and there's a
cybersecurity component something went
wrong with the cybersecurity that helped
to cause this accident same thing
happens cars driving long jumps curb
hits a pedestrian who does the
pedestrian soon now he sues the driver
who sues the manufacturer he sues the
component manufacturer he sues the
people who designed the cybersecurity he
sues the people who did the code he sued
the people who have the sensors and the
radar and the video cameras he Sue's the
component manufacturers and all of the
people who can
to that they sue everybody in sight this
isn't unique to IOT but because of the
interconnectedness it's much greater
concern because what happens next
let's assume you're working for a
company that gets drawn into this
litigation what do you do well first
thing you do is you explain to the judge
or the jury no no you don't understand
we did everything right we are not to
blame here that's the obvious first step
but don't forget you're in a courtroom
and just to the side of you is the
plaintiffs table and there's the
plaintiff in a wheelchair in a full-body
cast the judge and the jury are going to
want to understand what went wrong why
is this person been injured this
shouldn't have happened they want an
explanation so the natural inclination
is to say not only did we do everything
right that they're the ones who did
something wrong or these guys over here
they didn't take the proper level of
care that's fine but you know what these
guys and those guys are running exactly
the same calculus that you are and
they're going to start pointing their
finger right back at you so plaintiff's
lawyer can sit back and let the
defendants do his work for him as they
point their fingers at each other and
explain what everybody did long this is
another huge risk that's going to be
associated with this wave of IOT
liability and litigation who should care
everybody
anybody who contributes anything to an
IOT product it gets hacked or whether
it's a significant vulnerability
revealed is going to be right in the
sights of plaintiffs lawyers even if you
didn't do anything wrong
you can get sued and even if you didn't
get anything wrong because the judges
the juries the court system and the
lawyers aren't familiar enough with this
area you could be held liable if there's
any question about whether you took the
right level of care now there has been
some enforcement activity in some civil
lawsuits on the enforcement side you've
got a case from the FTC this is the
TRENDnet web cam hack from 2012
you probably remember this about 700
webcams were hacked and video and some
audio was uploaded to the Internet
the FTC investigated and entered a
consent decree which is basically a
settlement agreement in 2013 and the
terms are relatively straightforward
some training firmware updates testing
that sort of thing nothing to ownerís
this is really the FTC just dipping its
toe in the water and since then there
hasn't been a lot they've had some
workshops and some hearings and that
sort of thing certainly the FTC and the
CPSC the Consumer Product Safety
Commission are focused somewhat on this
area there hasn't been a lot of
enforcement activity since this what I'm
going to explain to you how regulators
think just like how plaintiffs lawyers
think I live in Washington DC I have for
20 years and you may think that a
regulatory agency is a monolithic
unitary entity that has you know if a
mission statement and everyone follows
it but it's not just like any
organization it's made up of individuals
those individuals may have their own
ideas about what should be done and some
of those individuals may be very
ambitious they may want to get promoted
they may want to run for public office
and get elected and what's the best way
to do that is to make a name for
yourself how do you do that well one way
is to find the cases that hurt the most
people or involve the most egregious
conduct they're going to go after those
but another way to do it is to find the
cases that are in the headlines and say
that you're the champion of this issue
and what issue is going to be in the
headline more than IOT I mean the video
shows that people love this stuff it's
like Star Trek has come to life but if
anything goes wrong the microscope that
you're going to be put under is going to
be intense and disproportionately there
is going to be enforcement activity now
obviously there are some limitations
through statute on the scope of
authority for regulatory agencies or
state attorneys general but make no
mistake they're looking for
an excuse to start in this area and then
we have private litigation we've got the
g-pack case so most of you are probably
familiar with this
in 2015 Charlie Miller and Chris valasek
did some amazing work showing how they
could remotely hack a Jeep Grand
Cherokee and what they did is they use
the jeeps infotainment system as the
attack surface they penetrated it and
were able to send or inject spoofed
messages to the vehicles can
communication networks and it allowed
them to control critical operational and
safety function of the jeeps as they're
being driven now you may know well first
of all this got a lot of attention here
as Lester Holt on the NBC Evening News
talking about it as Charlie Miller drove
Chris valasek into a ditch remotely you
may know that this was reported in Wired
magazine in July 2015 and you may know
that two days after that Chrysler issued
a recall you may think that that's where
things ended for me and my team that's
where things began in August of 2015 we
filed a federal class-action lawsuit
against Chrysler and against Harman
International who is the manufacturer of
the infotainment system that was used as
the attack surface and we alleged a
number of claims based on our
allegations that there were critical
cyber security defects shared by all of
these vehicles that render them unsafe
as I mentioned we just got class
certification last month and the
petition for review the appeal of that
decision was denied by the circuit court
yesterday so we're continuing three
years later and the litigation has been
ugly and it's been contentious and it's
been expensive there have been hundreds
of thousands of pages of documents
produced in Discovery there have been
all kinds of depositions taken and we're
still not even to the trial though use
of the expenses
litigation even before you get to
liability now there's one other
important thing that I should point out
I've mostly been talking about hacks but
you may mention or have noticed that I'm
also talking about IOT vulnerabilities
in this case no car was hacked in a way
that caused a physical injury to person
or property the theory of damages is
essentially a benefit of the bargain
theory and all that means is consumers
thought they were buying a safe car and
what they got was a car that was riddled
with cybersecurity defects that left
these cars and trucks unsafe that's our
theory and the measure of damages is the
difference between the value of the safe
car they thought they were buying and
the unsafe car that they actually got to
ask yourself how much is that that's
going to be something that has to be
determined at trial but multiply that
number by 220,000 vehicles and that's
our lawsuit right now let's talk about
the costs it's not just litigation we're
going to get back to that again in a
second you got reputational harm like I
said if anything goes wrong it's going
to be splashed across the headlines
that's probably not good leave your cost
of remediation you've got software
updates firmware updates and when it
comes to a physical product there may
even be manufacturing disruptions those
are all costs
you've got litigation alright so we
talked about that everybody knows
lawyers are expensive that's why
everybody hates us one of many reasons
but it's more than that these are really
complicated cases technologically and
otherwise you're gonna need experts
hacking experts damages experts possibly
other types of experts they cost a lot
of money it's going to be a burden and a
distraction on key employees this goes
unnoticed so often but if something goes
wrong if there's a hack if there's a
vulnerability if the evening news shows
up in your corporate headquarters lobby
and starts asking questions you're going
to want to know what happened you're
going to talk to your engineers you're
going to talk to your business people
and I'll tell you what that's
nothing compared to what the plaintiffs
lawyers are going to want in Discovery
which is a formalized process for
exchanging information relevant to the
dispute they're going to want every
document in sight they're gonna want
emails they're gonna want memos they're
gonna want an ala C's and spreadsheets
they're gonna want to depose to take
depositions of your key employees your
employees are going to be focused on the
litigation instead of I'm doing their
jobs and I can't tell you the number of
times I've sat across the table from an
employee before a deposition or putting
some of them up on the stand at a trial
these are people who love their job they
love their company and it kills them to
think that they may have done something
or that they might say something that's
going to harm the health of their
organization
it causes incredible anxiety this is the
sort of thing that keeps people up at
night that's a real cost and then we've
got uncertainty in risk this is a real
cost - like I said before you're going
to have judges and juries who don't know
much about cybersecurity making
decisions that affect not only the
health but potentially the viability of
your organization they're the ones who
are going to decide what the right level
of cybersecurity is for your IOT product
and they're going to decide whether you
hit that level and there are real costs
associated with that
for example oftentimes corporations keep
reserves so that if something goes bad
with litigation they've got money to pay
it and if it's hard to predict what the
outcome is going to be and it's hard to
predict what the magnitude of any
judgement is going to be you're gonna
need to have larger reserves and that's
money that can't be put back into the
business reinvesting and growing it okay
law school in ten minutes I'm not doing
this to punish you I'm doing this
because you need to understand the rules
and the standards that are going to be
applied if you get drawn into litigation
and you need to understand them now
because the decisions that you make
today and the decisions that you have
been making are going to affect the
come of any dispute that arises and so
what you have to do is understand the
risks and understand the costs so that
when you're making decisions about what
the right level of cybersecurity to
design into your product is you're
making it on an informed basis plus it's
actually only nine minutes I timed it
and it's not going to be Socratic method
like in law school so I don't wanna hear
any complaints all right start with
damages bottom line any type of harm can
be recoverable physical injury emotional
distress property damage overpayment
like in the g-pack case all of its on
the table depending on the particular
claim and the particular harm claims all
right what's a claim claim is just a
theory of recovery these are the main
ones in an IOT litigation you've
probably heard of most of them every
claim has a set of requirements they're
called elements in order for a plaintiff
to recover she has to prove every one of
the elements of her claim so we're gonna
go through them quickly before we do
that though one important point to note
all of these claims are state law claims
not federal and what that means is that
there's no uniform law the principles
are the same or close to the same in all
states but the particular rules and
requirements may vary from state to
state so be aware of that negligence
everybody kind of has a sense of what
negligence is somebody doesn't exercise
reasonable care so there's that term
again that's the legal standard judge
I'm the plaintiff they didn't exercise
reasonable care the judge says I don't
know what that means
give me experts give me testimony he's
going to decide what reasonable care is
strict product liability design defect
so here's the Ford Pinto many of you are
too young to remember this even I am by
a little bit it had a gas tank that was
placed right at the back right behind
the rear bumper there was a nail or
something that per true
and so the slightest tap on the back
bumper and the whole damn thing exploded
that's a design defect it should not
have been designed that way design
defects can cover anything it can cover
hardware it can cover software in
certain situations it can be things like
inadequate segmentation or failure to
use proper cybersecurity devices
failure to properly design the way that
passwords are handled all of this can be
the subject of a strict product
liability claim now there has to be
physical injury to personal property and
there has to be a defect and here we're
back to that standard of care idea again
it's different from negligence and when
I said at the beginning that if there's
physical injury the rules are really
favorable to plaintiffs this is what I'm
talking about to determine whether
there's a defect most states have one of
two standards or maybe even both the
product is dangerous beyond a consumers
expectations or if it's unreasonably
dangerous again we've got experts in
this room I bet we could get ten people
drawn at random in this room and there
is no way that they would agree what
unreasonably dangerous is for a
particular IOT device and what we're
going to do is we're going to ask a jury
that knows nothing about cybersecurity
to make that decision quickly a few
others breach of warranty everybody
knows what a warranty is there are
implied warranties that you may not know
about for consumer products this is one
of our claims in the jeep hack case
where we allege that there is always an
implied warranty of merchantability
which means that there's an assumption
that products are safe and usable for
their ordinary purposes and since we
don't think that the cars are safe we're
bringing a claim for breach of the
implied warranty of merchantability you
can have claims for fraud or fraudulent
omission don't say things that aren't
true fraudulent omission is when you
know something that's material to
another party and they're relying on you
for that information but you would hold
it so if you know or suspect that
there's a cyber security issue with your
IOT product and you're not telling
anybody about it
there could be a claim for fraud
into mission this is a big one state
consumer protection statutes plaintiffs
love these as the name suggests they are
designed to protect consumers and they
do a pretty good job of it for two basic
reasons one the range of actionable
conduct is very broad it's anything
that's unfair or deceptive varies from
state to state but that's the rule and
then it's left to courts to decide what
counts so it can be something fraudulent
but it can be something short of that as
well in addition the range of things
that can be recovered is much broader
it's any actual harm but there can also
be statutory penalties and there can be
attorneys fees and so attorneys love
this because they'll bring a case find a
technical violation hope to get some
statutory penalties and then they get
paid for their work so again even if
there's not a lot of harm these statutes
are often used by plaintiffs lawyers and
even state attorneys generals offices to
bring claims okay big question you're
probably thinking about hey I do what
everybody else in the industry does or I
even exceed that standard am I not in a
safe place and the answer is that's good
if you don't meet the industry standard
that's bad but it's not going to get you
all the way home because ultimately the
standards are going to ask whether we're
the legal standards are going to require
you to determine whether the
technological standards are set at a
reasonable level of safety so you can't
rely on this entirely okay what should
companies do well do what you're doing
but do it on the basis of complete
information hopefully I've helped you to
understand why there is going to be a
lot more litigation and what all of the
costs and risks associated with that
litigation are so that when you're
making your decisions in designing
cybersecurity at all stages you can
either be informed immediately or at
least you know what questions to ask
lawyers be paranoid I don't mean design
all cybersecurity that you possibly can
but think through all of the different
ways your product could harm someone and
then allocate risk you can do that in
both directions on the supply chain okay
so if you're dealing with another
business maybe a supplier you can have
contractual provisions that dictate
who's responsible if something goes
wrong it also works in the other
direction so even if you're a retailer
you can allocate some of the risk of
harm to consumers through warnings and
instructions it may not get you all the
way there but if you've got a big
honking warning that says consumer don't
do this really dumb thing and then they
do that really dumb thing and get hurt
you're gonna have a pretty good defense
design review pretty straightforward
hazard analysis risk assessment look for
potentially applicable standards follow
them test obviously but make sure that
everything is memorialized you want a
process a robust process for addressing
cyber security issues and you want to
show what you've done and you want to
memorialize it contemporaneously with
you taking the action ultimately a judge
a jury or the media and the public is
going to want to know that you acted
responsibly and this is the way to do it
word control programs okay so for claims
like fraud or warranty or consumer
protection a lot of that has to do with
the words that surround the product be
careful about the particular words the
substance of the words use instructions
and manuals look at your advertisements
very carefully and ultimately again
common sense don't say dumb things don't
over represent don't promise use
insurance this is tricky cybersecurity
insurance is a big growth area for
insurers but they don't understand
IOT litigation any better than anybody
else and so what they do is they load up
these policies with all of these
exclusions
that make them love questionable worth
so if you have a policy take a look at
it and see what the exclusions are if
you don't have a policy consider whether
you can negotiate one that might provide
you with some protection finally what
happens if something goes wrong all
right you probably expected me to say
this at some point hire a lawyer not
just any lawyer hire lawyer who actually
knows what they're doing in this area
it's complicated
not only is it complicated but you need
to have somebody who can communicate
these issues effectively to judges and
juries investigate talk to your
engineers talk to your businesspeople
identify the scope consider how to
notify consumers and act and respond
responsibly so takeaways I think it's
inevitable and it's going to happen very
very soon there is going to be a big
wave of IOT hack and vulnerability
litigation and enforcement activity and
if you're not prepared if you're not
taking steps now and you don't know how
to handle it this could be an
existential threat consider the scope of
the g-pack case as I described it that's
the tip of the iceberg exercise sound
cybersecurity principles but consider
all of the information and if you don't
have it get it involve lawyers a little
bit more in the process nobody likes to
deal with us but sometimes it's
necessary and make sure that you have a
clear process maybe you need a division
or a person who's specifically
responsible for cybersecurity make sure
you've got all the right pieces make
sure it's comprehensive it's written
it's followed and it's memorialized
thank you very much
happy to take any questions and if you
want there are the sort of big glossy
business cards at the back so you can
grab one on your way up I have a
question
um I'm curious what you think about
developers engineers working on IRC
security things and if you see our eyes
in those court cases as well the
question is whether there's going to be
cases against individual engineers or
software developers working for
companies the answer is no you're
probably just fine people don't even if
they could and I'm not sure that they
could people don't go after the
individual workers they go up to the
company that has the deep pockets hi
great talk thank you I have not seen any
software component IOT otherwise that
does not have basically known
vulnerabilities so is it possible to
actually does that the status quo is
things have bugs so can you can you just
go after that or do you need the harm or
something else so that's that's a really
good question the question is all
software has bugs so does that
necessarily mean that it's actionable
and the answer is it should nobody knows
for sure because it hasn't played out
but if your best argument is that this
has bugs and it's not unhackable it's
not gonna be a persuasive winning
argument so what a plaintiff's lawyer is
going to want to try to do is show that
there is an exceptional irresponsibility
in this particular case and that can
play out in a number of ways when it
comes to software but it's not going to
be just you know a relatively safe and
responsible set of code you suggested
that in the event of an event we go find
a good lawyer how would you suggest that
we evaluate that well so there are lots
of good lawyers out there but I think
that this field really is different let
me give you an example after we got
class certification in the Jeep case a
pretty reputable law firm came out with
you know a note a memo to clients saying
this is really important and they said
this is a really important data breach
case it's not a breach case totally
different set of rules
so obviously you shouldn't hire that
firm for IOT and frankly you probably
shouldn't hire that firm for data breach
either
it's tough I mean you really you want to
find somebody who understands the
technology it's not necessarily an
engineer though it's somebody who can
communicate about it and ideally
somebody who has some experience there
aren't a lot of lawyers like that but
that's what you're going to be looking
for so I have a question we just
recently released some security research
about inexpensive device IOT cameras and
the company that makes them is based in
the east so different country so if it's
only a $50 camera in the first place
what's the chance that like a US citizen
could sue that company to recover ten
dollars or something well ok so there's
a whole lot of questions wrapped up
another question is what if it's a
foreign corporation and it's a
relatively inexpensive consumer device
and the answer is if they're doing
business here and the harm is caused
here then they've submitted themselves
to the jurisdiction of the courts you're
not going to bring a lawsuit for ten
dollars but that's exactly what the
class-action mechanism is for is to
aggregate a whole bunch of claims of
people who have been harmed in the same
way I mean maybe it's time for one last
question
IOT isn't new it's just a new kind of a
buzzword so my company has a lot of
legacy systems that we've been doing
essentially IOT for 20 years how do you
handle legacy systems in these ways that
you know there's either need to replace
them or update them I mean the way to
think about this is to say what if
something goes wrong what what are
people gonna ask what are they gonna
want to know and are they gonna accept
as an excuse well we did this 20 years
ago and we didn't change it the answer
is no they're gonna want to see that
you're looking and you're evaluating and
you're updating in a responsible way
so if they continue to use that product
sorry it's all if they continue to use
that product is that then the and you've
issued a statement is that then the
consumers problem and not your problem
so the question now is what if you issue
a warning to consumers and the answer is
you want to willing to be as clear and
as prominent as possible it's certainly
going to help whether it gets you all
the way home is going to depend on the
specific facts so thanks everybody