good morning everyone thank you very
much for the introduction I'm glad so
many turned up after yesterday's parties
it's very early I've noticed myself so
I'm going to talk about a comparative
forensic analysis of the VIN vote voting
machine and I brought you one copy of
this thing which was given to me by
unnamed source maybe two years ago and I
kind of became slightly you know I had
like five minutes of fame because I
hacked this machine last year at Def Con
and I also would like to do some
advertisement because we have a voting
village again at Def Con this year so we
want to play around and hack those
machines
you're more than invited ok so let's get
started but the first thing I'd like to
say is actually I would like to kind of
take a little bit of a helicopter view
on Elections and the declaration for
Human Rights an article 21.3 actually
states that a genuine and credible
election is a human right it says
literally the will of the people shall
be on the basis of authority of
government ok that's good this bill
shall be expressed in periodic and
genuine elections but shall be by
Universal and equal suffrage and shall
be held by secret or equivalent voting
procedures the part was the equivalent
voting procedures was added because in
Switzerland they actually some people
who still vote by raising the hand on a
marketplace that cannot be called really
secret so that's called equivalent free
voting procedure ok so let's just kind
of think about what role does technology
in all of this play when you add
technology to the voting process you
clearly you know increase its attack
surface right and there are two big
problems business the one problem is
what we always do it black hat and DEF
CON that is cyber security and trying to
hack in right so you when when you have
a vulnerability in your system people
might actually use it to exploit it and
and try to hack it change votes on the
machines that's a real threat but the
other threat
is equally important and equally
dangerous and this is the threat of an
alleged cyber attack where people
claimed that there was a cyber attack
when they actually wasn't one and so
what I have done in my talk or in this
presentation what I will be doing is
actually look at this machine and we're
going to kind of hack it a little bit
and we did a little bit of forensics on
it and then I tell you what we found
about it but the main conclusion
actually of this talk will be that you
know if somebody claims this machine was
hacked you actually do not have a good
mechanism to say like hold on that's not
true
it wasn't hacked so let's look at the
United States and the use of technology
in the United States for the 2018
midterm elections which is just around
the corner you see that many states
actually use some form of technology and
I think the most well-known technology
these are optical scan machines where
you kind of fill out your ballot this
little oval and you put it into a
machine that scans it and interprets it
or or there are d-r-e machines just like
this one and just to kind of make me be
100% clear this one is decommissioned I
have never committed any felony although
there's a little sticker on the back it
says it's a class five felony to tamper
with this machine
okay so let's look at the pinball voting
machine a little bit more closely the
pinball voting machine for those who
can't see it is it's just a normal
boring machine okay they're going to pen
maybe the camera we want to take
pictures of it
you know people come after after the
presentation it has a little ballot
printer here but this printer is not
used for every voter to print out what
the voter print mode it it is actually
only used two times in an election at
the very beginning where printout comes
out and all of the tallies are zero
hopefully and at the end of polling day
when when the printout should say what
the result was of all of the machine yet
the boats collected on this machine so
let's go back to the to the slides so a
few facts about this voting machine the
voting machine was used for a city in
Virginia it's exactly this model and
4,000 like it it's about four so I
wasn't pulling polling places a 4,000
units I think very used but this is just
a guesstimate it could have been much
much more and for my forensic study I I
had access to this machine but you know
there's very little to go on and if you
look for irregularities on the election
machines you know it's like looking for
a needle in a haystack except that you
don't know exactly what the needle looks
like and you only have like partial
access to the haystack so I asked some
of my my friends because the sauce bag
got this machine from the source
actually gave away other machines so I
asked those people hey can I please get
access to your machine or maybe can you
give me an image a forensic image of my
of the harddrive so that I can
forensically analyze them and these
machines actually have two discs in them
there's a small disc listen these are
SSD disks keep in mind that this machine
was built in 2003 2004 2002
plus - not sure exactly when yeah okay
so um and it has a large disc that runs
the operating system and here on the on
the right on the left of the slide on my
right you can see a capture of the
original thing which it says it says
Microsoft Windows XP embedded version
2002 and unfortunately they did not
install any security updates on these
machines
that means the machines are vulnerable
to all kinds of attacks that were
convertibility that were collected since
2003 okay so that's not very good the
other thing is a lot of open ports on
that system and it turns out that you
know if you want to kind of use this alt
buffer overflow for our RCP know then
you know you can just try it out and I
have done it and I have of course
prepared it and I locked this machine
around the entire world to come here to
actually just hack it
and so another promises machine as it
has wireless turned on all the time and
having wireless turned on is very good
because if you are a polling worker and
you have to configure more than one
machine you just configure one master
machine and you kind of prints return
and of you know of the information goes
and it configures all of the machine but
you have to kind of make sure that it's
usable and in order to kind of make sure
it's usable to connect these machines to
the wireless network as well every
machine has its own wireless node you
have to type in a password and this
password is ABCDE and it's not a very
secure password I and I guess password
crackers and it's it's uses only PAP WEP
secure authentication so it's not very
good right so I have just kind of made a
very tiny script for where I start empty
Metasploit framework will load all of
the information you know setting picking
the right volubility and just kind of
hack the system I'm just a little luck
it says now it should say now Windows XP
no way that's the first time ever
really this was not intended I wanted to
do is click okay okay so I see this
machine
I don't okay so this is the IP address
of the voting machine I don't know why
it doesn't work okay I'm sorry I have to
take this offline because I just don't
have enough time to kind of debug it now
that we have to probably restart the
machine really embarrassing I wanted to
to kind of really say like how my
goodness is that it yeah that would have
been it okay so in Virginia in 2015
people became a bit cold feet as this
machine so keep in mind it was in use
from 2004 2004 2014 so this machine was
used for one presidential election for
Bush and two times Obama and they kind
of commissioned some report from the
Virginia Information Technology Agency
and they kind of said like it's a piece
of crap I'm sorry
so let's decommission it and so it's
decommissioned so when I hacked it last
year at Def Con I said like make cut
it's really easy to kind of show an
exploit but did it really have any
effects did other people do it and so
this actually what this talk is about
and I wanted to kind of know we did
someone interfere with the operations of
this machine so the first thing you do
is you kind of try to boot up Callie and
try to see like what can you get it's
more difficult than it actually appeared
so at the end it was much easier to kind
of just rip out the drives and Mike make
forensic images and that's exactly what
I've done so I've collected the forensic
images of all of these eight machines
and I used autopsy it's you know basic
forensic tool to to kind of study what I
find now some people might say like your
autopsy is like this is just you know
the general you can do it all but anyway
so if you can't I mean you know I'm not
sure
exactly what kind of needle in the
haystack I'm looking for so this is
actually a very very good tool to show
you that there is some irregularities
but we don't actually know exactly what
they where they come from and what the
explanations is and by the way the
irregularities I'm showing you here that
I haven't identified I have no idea you
know where they come from and I didn't
go any deeper so I think you know one
should really go the next level if you
really want to know if that was
something bad or if it's just something
that happened accidentally so these
machines were decommissioned 2014/15 so
we don't actually have any memory access
we can't study and forensically do the
memory there's just nothing there and
since it's Windows XP at that time there
are no logs of people actually
connecting wirelessly to the machine
which is very difficult if you want to
know if somebody Vilas the connects to
the machine so that you see the haystack
is it a big holes in it and also you
know we looked at the security event
logs and all of these things so they're
many log files that were actually there
like the event logs but security was
always empty so have no idea was it
because you know the vendor just kind of
miss you know configured it so that
nothing is written who knows okay so I
have all of these eight images and I've
imported them into our Topsy and that's
a little bit like what it looks like
what you have like and thanks to Josh
Nora me and all of the people who kind
of gave me that their discs and you see
like you have you have a normal window
okay so the you know menu do forensic
analysis you really have to kind of be
clear about the objectives otherwise you
just don't know exactly where you're
walking on what you're trying to find
when the overall objective is clearly
that somebody interfere with the
operations of the machines but what I
also wanted to know is you know that's
number one did what somebody exploited
all of these vulnerabilities did
somebody actually do something bad and
install some rootkits malware on it you
know we've seen in the Netherlands a few
years ago that Rob conkright did showed
how to use a voting machine base for
playing chess Alex Halderman from
University of Michigan showed how to
play
pack men together with Ed Felten from
Princeton and you know they're a couple
of questions you can ask so let's just
kind of go into it and see what I found
so the first impression okay so that it
is in autopsy there's a little folder
and says like are there strange strange
documents yes okay so you can't really
see it in the back of the room but the
blue highlighted line here is a Chinese
name which says MPEG 3 Ln K and you
wonder what doesn't what does a an
impact 3 file have to do on a voting
machine and I was actually curious what
this sounds like
so I hope that the sound works now it's
not under speakers unfortunately maybe
the audio guys can take the signal from
the HDMI okay so there's a Chinese song
that was actually ripped this this
machine okay so when you actually go and
you kind of look further you actually
see there are traces of ripping software
there's actually a on four of my
machines not all of them they were
actually yes they are software installed
to broadcast MPEG 3s and you know man I
just looked at my machine first and I
said like hey that's weird
did somebody really use the voting
machine to rip MEP MPEG threes in 2004
that's really bizarre and then broadcast
it to the Internet that's even more
weird but once you do the comparative
analysis you actually see then somebody
must have done this before they actually
kind of finish the image which they then
copied on the drives that then put into
the voting machines but still it's kind
of strange that there are MPEG three
files like this on the on the voting
machine then I went a bit more seriously
and I looked at the concrete days of
Elections okay so here's the
presidential election where Obama was
elected November 6 2012 and that's a
little bit what you see when you kind of
go into the timeline
and you see there's lots of events
happening so these are basically all of
the events that happened during election
day on all of my eight machines and keep
in mind against only eight machines
there are another three
thousand nine hundred ninety two
machines out there which I haven't
looked at so again you know we it's it's
the needle in the haystack
and you see that there was a lot of
events for some reason these machines
were configured to on to run on Pacific
time although they were used in Virginia
which kind of is a bit difficult because
you have to offset the times by three
hours but here at zero zero that's
actually you know where all of the the
machines were initialized
you know you see that some crude files
were created to start the election so
that looked quite normal
okay so then here's this this thing is
it basically records all of the devices
that were plugged into the machine you
know
USB devices because there's a little USB
thing where it actually collects the
votes and then we have yeah we have you
know lots of activities here doing the
day I think there was another machine
started but when you go through all of
the files all looks pretty reasonable
okay so they all kind of just work in
their own directory which is like the
the voting directory and they taste like
not double writing you know it all looks
pretty reasonable well then I went to
the 2013 election which was a
gubernatorial election in Virginia okay
so here you can see you can't really see
it but there something happened here
between 444 and 445 let me never about
sixty on one of my machines so seven
machines of my eight machines were used
for this election and on one of the
machine sixty files changed in the
Windows System directory okay so what
does that mean you know I don't really
know because you know it might be
completely harmless the system try to
update something they were all flagged
as modified and also the if the strange
thing is also the win vote itself was
flecked as modified but you know I've
checked actually the files themselves
they are actually all identical so I do
not know where this modification comes
from but during the election day so it
was a card for clock so that's like NDE
in the evening so that happens after the
poll has opened and before the cold Paul
closed somebody inserted some more USB
things into the
into the slots of the of the voting
machine okay so you know that is that's
that's really bizarre so and I only saw
it on one of the machines so I have no
idea so the vulnerability is so I can
only point out you know when you do this
forensic analysis you can only point out
there's some strange stuff but a good
interpretation of it is of course
something that has to follow and here's
a list of all of the different elections
that I went through so there is for
example you know most of those elections
actually look good except the one in
2013 in 2005 also something really funny
happened because there's actually an old
modem in these machines and for some
reason so five of my machines were used
in the gubernatorial election in two
thousand five and three of these min
vote machines actually on election day
try to dial out on the modem line I
don't know maybe it was to kind of
update their security patches one
machine unfortunately typed the wrong
number and didn't connect and the other
two were successful okay what does it
mean I've no idea it's just kind of a
strange observation so coming back to my
original point that when you have
technology in the voting process you set
yourself up for cyber attacks but you
also set yourself up for alleged cyber
attacks so a forensic analysis of those
drives cannot really tell us if hacking
has taken place or it has not and that's
just at least not for those machines
because of the logs but yeah that's just
this it's really really difficult so the
question is how do we get out of this
and so the way how we get out of this is
I think we we have to kind of remember
that our elections need to produce some
kind of evidence and the only evidence
that I had for the win vote in these
prior elections are those drives in
those those machines so if the Machine
doesn't actually print out any paper we
really have the only evidence we have
and there's just not very good evidence
okay so the let's just kind of switch
state for one moment and go from
Virginia
Colorado so in Colorado we have for the
2016 election you know Hillary Clinton
got about one point three three eight
million votes and Donald J Trump got one
point two million votes you know there
was a clear difference but between those
two apart hundred thirty thousand votes
okay so you know if these machines were
not used in that election these machines
were decommission 2014 they were not
used at all in the 2016 election but
let's think about evidence right so if a
machine like this were actually to be
used then you know we don't actually
have any way to kind of check you know
for is that a margin okay or not but
since about 2012 we have very very good
techniques of actually tackling this so
my question really is like what is
better evidence the paper ballots are
those drives of those who involve
milling machines so I hope I've
convinced you that the bright one is not
so that if the voting machine drives is
not good evidence so the paper evidence
is much much better so what you really
can do is you can do a post-election
audit on those kind of paper ballots and
those kind of post-election audits are
really really it's a it's a really good
mean in order to generate trust and
confidence in the election result
because when you draw and look at the
evidence in a statistical way no not the
drives they're not good enough but the
paper you actually kind of can gain
confidence in that the election result
was correct and there is a technique
which was pioneered by Philip Starck
professor Berkley and his colleague
liniment and they've developed the
technique which is called risk limiting
audits and that basically requires that
you have a secure paper trail and once
you have a secure paper trail is much
better than to have an insecure SSD
trail and so what you actually do is you
draw a random sample of a certain size
you kind of check if the sample is okay
if this sample is okay you're good if
not just the system or the the process
starts auto correcting at the end if
there's a lot of evidence of you
something is wrong there's a mismatch
between the paper trail and the audience
then the the paper trail and the
evidence then you have to do a recount
but the method will actually prompt you
to do this so it's a very good method so
the question is how many ballots they
actually have to draw and I think this
is where I opening for me
that it's actually not very many so on
the on the left you see the tool that
Phillip Stark actually produced that
computes the size of the sample that you
would have to kind of draw and I have
just put in the the candidates for the
for the election in in Colorado and the
number of pellets nationwide that you
have to kind of draw in order to kind of
gain confidence in the correctness of
the election result it's 142 so to state
wise you have to draw 142 ballots and
once you do that then you can be 95%
sure that the election result is correct
if you only use dia machines that do not
produce any paper evidence then you
don't have this option and so the really
really important point I want to make is
that it is really really important if
you want to kind of convince people that
this is a genuine election that you
actually do those kind of post-election
audits and I have put in a map of all of
the states in the United States that
actually kind of you know worry about
auditing a little bit and you see the
state of Colorado is actually the only
one that actually has implemented that
technique and that's why it's black and
the rest of the states are lacking
slightly behind okay and I would also
like to say coming back to my original
point there are still four or five
states in the United States for the
midterm election that use machines not
like those even vote machines that
connect and have a wireless access point
now there are machines that don't
produce any paper evidence and those
those states are Louisiana Georgia South
Carolina Delaware and New Jersey and
that is really yeah you know I I hope
that business talk I've convinced
you guys that actually paper is a good
way to do it I'm a computer scientists
so let me just say my conclusion and I
have only one conclusion and that is use
paper and do your audits that's the most
important part thank you you have
questions yes yes tape the paper the
paper
okay the paper needs to be verified by
the vote it needs to be Botev verified
and so there's right now in West
Virginia I'm not sure if you have read
this but West Virginia is trying to kind
of pilot a system for mobile phone
voting and they claim that also produces
paper but people wherever they are type
something on their phone and it'll print
something out that is not the paper that
you want you want exactly what you said
you want to have it voter verified it
needs to kind of reflect the intent of
the voter and that order has to kind of
agree to this so hard we have okay so we
go to the rep room if you interested and
have more questions thank you