we are very glad to be here at blackhat
to present my own so I am far with this
flow and he is a cabbie mujin we walk up
the CI in front she's casaya our energy
atomic it was energy alternative you
know it's nuclear stuff and we'll
present you a museum which has he said
remark of reverse engineering the
project is born in around 2006 and 2007
and it has been made the publicly
available in 2011 it's written in pitten
and it has its particular is that it has
it own intermediate representation you
have some website here in which you can
find more information about it so why
are we are here we are here to to show
you nezam from OC's it is used daily in
a malware analysis and packing and
static analysis and so on we have some
rules in order to to do to try to do
clean code in the Amazon here if you are
a novice in ISM you can use for example
some resources for example in the code
you have dog swings there is no real
full documentation in Jaime azzam sadly
that you have a lot of examples in which
you have some illustration of each video
of mesm which is very interesting to
read and there is a blog post I wasn't
as well we want today show a list of
features of mass because it's a bit
boring so we will try to enlight only
some very interesting features and we
will illustrate them with real code
examples today so first the basic stuff
in yes you have is music as his own
estimate is a similar engine and here's
he can manipulate x86 arm meats extra
architects use it can support al for
portable executable or roll and nutiva
as bipod we have we can had some custom
architectures maybe we are a mad guy
here who did that
and he will present it I think this
afternoon okay so to start with if you
want to everything start for the bite so
we have to disassemble the bite to do
this we can do this simple code so we
have a come to know we have to insert
this engine and we have to decimal a
function which give an assembly control
flow graph and we can dump it if you use
if you read this code you have written
in fact multi architectures code you
know which can involve a function so but
the real interesting you you have this
code in in in some resources here but
the real interesting since inea's is its
internal and intermediate presentation
and language this language is can be
extracted from a native assembly
language so we have a translator between
this language and this an tomato
intermediate to expedition here owns you
have this Co feature you can do some
manipulation on it we will see those
meditation in a couple of sites and
after you can use this intimate
representation in order to do some
static analysis and so on which will be
demonstrated in a couple of sites as
well to get this language you can write
this these lines which is a native
language and which will translate it
into this intermediate language okay
this language is based on abstracts and
6:3 and is defined by about nine words
and you have a simple very simple words
for example integers and have variables
and more complete cat in the world
for example operators bytes manipulation
and so on you have also an assignment
which is here represented by X
expression affectation in infants
affectation is f is for application and
it stands for assignment but in English
X us is with where the tool to use
okay so that word there are some roots
about this language the first rules is
that each expression it has a fixed size
and embed inside here and another rule
is that you can only have memory
Department or variable on the assignment
so as less values even surface another
interesting thing is that the expression
operator can takes anything any any name
of operation and me as we can rock with
unknown names of operators and it can
under law so it can do some propagation
algorithm extra unknown operators
another trick is that an interesting
point is that assignment are done in
parallel I will show this later so for
example if you want to translate navi-x
elites in x86 you have this kind of
stuff so you have an effect on
assignment between the ID
EBX and IDE 8 and you can print a human
readable version of it like this so you
have simply EI wall-e B's if you want to
read another example is a purse 8 for
example so you have here two equations
that are done in parallel so the update
of the stack pointer here and as a
storage of the eh in the top of the
stack and in fact this ESP here has
nothing to do with this ESP here in fact
this one is is the source of the
dimension and our very complete more
complicated stuff
for example the comparison between two
register in fact when we translate this
we will give some a bunch of flags for
example the zero flag high flags and
they are assigned from a very
complicated expression we which is in
fact the real a question of the carry
flag or the riddle equation of a flight
so to illustrate this we can start with
this native x86 language so we have
function some comparison between
arguments and return value when we
translate this code in
intimate language is a bit more
complicated here you can see that we we
can recognize his here - EVP here we
have the mo ESP in EVP and we have a
bunch of equation of old eflags which is
here and which is really complicated so
we have the jump comparison with the
jump less or every one which has its own
equation here so the fixation of X and
the resolution so the first thing we can
do here is to use for example passes
under here to generate a modified here
with some codes and education for
example the most common one is a dead
code elimination if you are on x86 you
know that in the IB you don't you don't
need the flags at the end of the
function so the computation of the carry
flag here is not used anymore so in is
in experiments in the east notes use
anymore here and so you can see that
this equation is not need here so we can
remove it so if we pass this this abyss
equation here we will have this code
which is a bit more simple in now but we
can do a better in fact the new feature
in Jasmine is to explain and represent
all the intermediate flags with high
level flags for example instead of
having very big equations in the
internet language we have only the
simple operator which does the same
thing which is very simple here and as
well the jump less well will be
represented by a new a new operator here
and which will take all the only parts
of the flags that are used to compute
the conditional jump so if we here is
the new intermediate position using this
new animated language here with sorry
with this new and
and the next step will be to it's again
a bit complicated so we have to do more
than this so we will try to do in asthma
propagation and to do this we have to
use a static single assignment it's a
new feature in us which has been added
by a contribution by team play Cisco and
Nico Schmidt's in fact it's very common
as well in population to use this
transformation in order to simplify your
code cut so it has a very interesting
property here each each pneumonia each
register can be assigned only ons so you
have material version of the same eraser
for example you have EA each all in X 1
X 2 X Terra and here is a new code so
you you can see that the ESP dot 0 equal
X around and and yeah it has the
multiple version of it here so know that
we are in SSA version we can do for
example constant propagation but we will
do more than this in us it's a cold
expression propagation because we will
try to do more than efficient constant
propagation to do this we have to we
have some rules with for example we
cannot propagate call operators because
a call represents a sub call the
function you cannot mess with readwrite
memory for example memory boring and has
but has we are in SSA we can do for
example register propagation and so on
so here is the actual code and when we
do this we will we will do a first step
of propagation so only a single set and
it needs this code so here we have the
house we have a source the eggs a 0 and
this value it comes from here so here as
we don't have any memory right between
this vacation is this weed we can
obviously replace this value by its
source so it will give this code so this
is the first step and the algorithm
trying to find a fixed point so after
this it will try to take those equation
put them here in the listicle
computation so
the operator here will be obviously very
very very long and we have some
high-level reduction for example here we
have a reduction that say that this
powder with those sub arguments can
reduce has this simple comparison okay
so we have the final code which is a
given like this and we from the x86 we
can recover that we have a simple
comparison which is the first argument
which is that's signed and for our igual
who as a second argument the last step
is to remove heels of he which has been
which has a bit of using the
transformation
so using this it Emily just as well so
here is the final version of the code
and we have the antimatter position of
the initial 86 code and there's a very
interesting point is know that if you
have the same code but in arm if you use
this algorithm here is a result for arm
so you have the same result so except
that on the arguments has change in arm
you have arguments as pass through
register so here you have register 0 and
1 which are compared and for example if
you are on alma 64 this is the same
reagent here from the native a phone
call ok so now if you use it in in a
real code if you have this kind of code
which is written in arms up in am some
it's a risk
so risk architecture so it's very
doubled we can reduce this to this so
now for reducer it's a bit more simpler
to understand the code now another one
for example if you reverse some anthem
and you have this function we can use
the same algorithm here and if you try
first to get the intermediate
presentation he gives this very
complicated code here and you can so use
those algorithm in order to redo this
and this gives the final result here so
and for those who are familiar with
reversing low-level arm you can see that
it's a simple function which will try to
change the direction part of the the
process of the CP and it's a bit more
simple to read this than the actual
native code I think okay
notice that this code is not the
compilation
it's only a modification of the
intermediate language and is only get
back enter a language but we will see
that we have some tricky things to and
generate back native language we can and
you can use this internal language in
order to do for example type propagation
value analysis or loop detection and so
on for example in the next slide we will
show how we can use this entire language
in order to do cut the sophistication so
here we will try to analyze the just VM
machine before going deeply in the
native assembly we will show you the
first feature which is symbolic
execution we will use in the attack of
this game summary execution is weak like
concrete execution as the difference is
when you are doing complete execution on
a CPU register can only integers has
value and memory a memory has only
registers integers and in summary
execution of register can have can be
represent a number or another variable
so if you have this native code if you
try to do a assembly execution here is
the result of the first line you have
ecigs which is a result and it's only
this it's 6 plus 4 if you do the second
line you have this week's eagle-eye
weeks plus 1 and if you do the
comparison between CL and one here is
the flag that will that are given by the
summary execution and you can see here
that the zero flag and depend only on
the ecig value and
equation no we have a jump if zero and
here we have the register IRD st and his
value is a new expression which depends
only on ethics and some integers so we
symbolic execution we get the fact that
we have this equation and we can deduce
dependencies of the next basic block but
we have a problem here
incomplete description obviously is zero
flag will be an integer and will be
resolved and here it's not special so we
cannot we don't know we have to do if we
meet we if we will go in be or 10 so
here this is a classic program in
summary execution and there are many
solution known here and we will only and
it's up to you to choose the good
solution for you for your use case and
for example you can do a state speed for
example you can run on the left side of
the branch and on on the right side of
the branch and and so on we will show
you this risk Emmy in next slides there
is another problem with memory accesses
for example when you try to affect
memory usage using symbolic pointer it's
a bit weird so India's with the program
is solved using dictionary with when you
have a symbolic memory base like this we
will spit this in the symmetric part and
the compiled pot and in NASM only memory
based on the same sampling base our can
and can interfere together so this is a
bit different from the real world but it
solves some some some problems ok so
back to the C&O in the in order to to
win some time so Otto does then did use
uses use the automation protection in
fact for those who doesn't know this
protection when you are completing a
code in native language it's easy for
resort to analyze this language it goes
it's 86 language is a bit like is the
mother tongue so it's easy and here it's
a very easy to compile the code to a new
CPU completely operated for for this
occasion and totally exists and and this
bytecode cannot be executed on directing
the city so you have to embed an an
emulator of this new CPU in your binary
and in fact when you run the malware it
run an emulator which run on by code
which presents the original color so how
do we how do we attack this protection
the first one is to do manual reversion
the reversing so we had to find the
fetcher here and so we have to find the
mnemonic one and to see how the the VM
its root 2 and so on
I want to have this you can use
somebody's equation to have the Rho
expression of the mnemonic so using this
result you can infer what is the VM so
to you where are the register where's
the van program punto and so on and all
you have done that you can use no miasma
to automate the recovery of the rest of
mnemonics so for example if you have the
first emulation of the first mnemonic we
have this and you have read as the
memory at easy 6 is a good memory
program to enter and you have the first
visual here of the execution of the
first mnemonic you can see that here
when you have this equation you can
reduce this as a program koonta the
other machine promoter so this one it
words to the original memory program
this machine prompt on top is 1 so this
can be reduced has this equation so
answer the question can be reduced as
this one is the better machine program
Kunta so you can rewrite it like this so
we will write those reduction rules and
in the azzam owns and after this we will
try to
Emma stimulates the rest of the nominees
and we will apply this reduction and
Yasim will give automatically this kind
of a question so it will vacuum the
original code of the of the mnemonic for
example if you have such a question here
you have such tree and the reduction we
lose this here other elections so this
is obviously the relations that I
explained earlier you have a seat which
is reduced as VM sweet this this memory
the first plant gives the NPC this one
gives a register and we don't know which
is it for which we reduced a for example
as an tiger and the look up at PC please
an integral will give an Integra because
obviously it's a immediate value of an
opcode and you have if you have an
operation between two integers obviously
it will give an integral so to this for
this we have first this history we will
apply the reduction so the first one is
to replace ecigs
by the vm pc streets here so we have
here all the integrals we will be
reduced to in here so now we have a new
structure which is known which has a
reaction rules and this wind this one
will give back rag it's this one you
will give back MPC here and so we have
VC plus int and the atomic memory so
it's obviously an integral and here we
have Antigua x1 take off so it leaves
and tiger and we have we stopped here
because we doesn't we don't have anymore
any reduction remaining so at the end of
the operation we know that the the
mnemonic is only an addition between a
register and an integer and here is a
result on some mnemonic of the veto
machine so here we have the result which
is a XOR between memory ported by the
register and an integral and we have a
the same M&E it was a very semi monique
except the the memory size as change
so here is obvious to see this
yeah and now the interesting thing is
that we can disassemble the bytecode and
re-inject the generic equation and s
transient design then using the Zener TV
code so we can get back the intermediate
position of the the them back on so when
we do some of this we will recover we do
a demo of C of this so here we rewrite
only the fetcher of the Vienna we
emulate also mnemonics and we integrate
some unix reject it in the in the memory
bytecode and here is the result we have
the animated language of the world
function which was emulated in the CM
and you can see first that it's a bit
complicated because as you can see for
example we have a register which is the
constant here and we have the constant
which is added with another constant so
obviously we can merge them in order to
generate the constants it will mean me
something here you can see that we can
use the previous algorithm with SSI
propagation and so on and if we did this
we have the we obtain the next result
and here we have the the original code
of the disaster without of his
obfuscation and but it's in animated
language so it's a bit way out we are to
to understand but in NASM we have a pass
which can take the n-terminal language
and translate it into a Librium language
and so we can obtain this and the best
part is that we can use this LLVM
language in order to compile it to
native x86 language and so we can obtain
this and we can obtain a binary we can
inject in the original binary of the
stem and when we we run it we can have
we recover the original covenant common
controller you are so all this work
is correct because the code has been
compiled and executed unreal unreal code
the interesting thing is that no our
does the version is very very very
quicker than the original one because
everything on the VM as disappear and it
has been translated into a native
language okay another interesting part
in Yasim is to analyze malware for
example in a question group you have a
naturist in step the battery itself is
not cyclone but every string used the
inventory in cycle and each time the
winery wants to use a string it has to
this fr it's in memory use it and to
wipe it after after this so forward as
you are if you want to do a static
analyzer in order to recover the strings
you have to manually take the function
take the progress and take the back the
the pointer to the site for swing is the
length of such a swing and to do some
stuff after one and we will show you how
to do this automatically so we will use
an algo in which is called the depends
you up I won't explain here because it's
a bit long it's a bit between so use
death chain and person sees chain which
can explode in with a big loop and in
this case our Halloween our algorithm is
a is okay if you want some details you
can see a slides here so the demo
session is is we have imagine we have
the a person group binary we have a
recovered the deciphering a swinging a
function and so we will show you a usage
of the function and if it is 64 it's
okay so here the register write is used
to store the length of the ciphered
function as a success thing and it it
stores the pointer of the sizeof
function when you reverse this it's
obviously that Alex is the pointer is
here and the length but
is a bit other too tricky to recover
here the eight depends on 12 and 23 and
if you click here you can see that all
12 is in saliste here with FF so what we
are doing with on either the following
the Euro step and so on can be done with
the dependency graph so here we run the
plug-in in in in HIDA we say on the call
we want to backtrack for example r8 and
minas will give you automatically the
lines which contains the instructions
that will give the result in r8 so we
will and has we have as well as symbolic
execution engine we can do this on the
on this intrusion and here musn't say
that the value is only and there is one
value and one possibility which gives a
ID equals to 22 and if we are for
example is an else it will track in in
both punches excellent so now we have
that we can automate to recover for each
prospect or some other function also
arguments and after this we will try to
do the result is that we have all the
values of those arguments
so when testing since know is that we
will use emulation mode engine of Mia's
in order to emulate a zoom deciphering
function and to get back the result so
to do this here is a simple example in
order to emulate a function so we had a
memory page here with the bytecode with
native code and we introduced the stack
and we run the code and for a special
example here we will do this but
additionally we will initially the
register using the recovered argument
and the length of the swing and the
pointer and when we do this we we and
after we will get the memory back to me
Azzam and we would women do this we have
the following result
here Kamiya isn't running as the script
on the on the wall bed and here you can
see that you have the detection of the
arguments the recovery and the emulation
and for every swing you have the output
deciphered string and moreover the sweep
will get back the residue either and if
you go back to either if you look at
each reference of the decree function
you have maybe it's a bit too little but
you have all the residual so for each
for each call so here we use in this
ring that's all for the automated
language and and he was Camino on the
emulation pot okay so I'm regarding the
equation group yells you also have some
cryptography inside and the idea is to
reverse the code on just one dll
discovered attractive to graphene and
then try to identify this crypto in all
the dll including on different active
architectures so how do we do that sorry
already a state-of-the-art source
offering samples are static approaches
like left in either but we'll use a
dynamic one why you will use that
because for instance air is a mem copy
which is a naive implementation it's
quite easy to recognize it but you can
have the same mem copy but obfuscated
for instance if it has been written by a
inter by an intern or you can have a
Victory's vectorized version with a sse
extra so what we will do is actually
consider the function as a black box we
will choose the input that's to say the
arguments and the initial state of the
memory run the function in a minimalist
environment let's adjust the stack just
to stack and and binary mapped and we
will if it reach the end I will will
check the output the output value and
the output memory in final memory
if it's much our expected one you can
say okay it's it's maybe the function
that we are considering so for instance
if you just if I have a black box I
refer to you to use the signature for
multiplication we have a five by ten I
run it it crash so obviously is not an
interpretation then I try to use
esterline with the yellow strings as
originally in memory
it runs students but written zero so
it's not a Shannon and and then I try
eight well with a one two three four as
a string in input which went to the N it
returns one two three four other longer
so I can say ok it sees the expected
output for height well signature so it
may be a twerk so regarding the
implementation we have to be resilient
to crashes because you can seg fault of
course if the function expect pointer
and you give in five it will crash so as
we are using the emulation in myosin
it's in lated so there is no will crush
the infinitely if you need to have Herzl
to be taking icons you just use timeout
the idea is to have a disk signature
description which is as simple as
possible and are agnostic if possible
and coding and which doesn't consider
the Kalinka mention so it can be a
several code to be sure that this is a
function and it is a problem which is
obviously embarassingly parallel so we
can use this so all these things has
been implemented in a tiny tools name as
Sevilla H based on onion which also open
source and one thing that I don't talk
about today but using the symbolic
emulation of mass M we can also learn
automatically new functions signatures
but this is for another day so getting
back to our equation drug a crypto we'll
just consider the beginning part reverse
we have reversed it so we want to to
discover its so we just create a simple
test test
then we prepare the the test we provide
the initial in memory insert memory so
it just dedicated to bignum then we said
the arguments we run the function and at
the end we check the final state of its
match if he is matching what what we
expect we can say okay it's the copy so
it's just one test so this is the one
slide a test which is discovering big
Numa cookie
so as a demo I will try to really run
this code on unto binaries and to DLL
one in HT HT 6 and 1 in 32 64 32 sorry
so we already implement some of test for
the beginning cryptography and then if I
run it sorry if I when it's under the
first binary everyone in parallels and
it will discover some of the the
signature that we just implements so the
multiplication the by now
the big name to string the comparison
extra extra and I can rent the same I
can run the same test on a binary which
is in 32-bit and it also found some of
the Bates termination is not not so slow
because you are using some just-in-time
compilation but just a implementation I
think so we if you have seen the
emulation as a tiny emulation with just
the code and the stack but we can do
more so for instance if you are
analyzing a shellcode which come from
angular exploit Keeton this is the
landing page you get to the 3G exploit
then you get the shellcode you you want
to analyzed it so you disassembly it's
you realize it's encoded and we can say
okay we just emulate it to to let Amanda
code himself and get back the
information so how if we just use what
she's done so far that is to say only
the code and a stack we run the
shellcode and Mia's will crash that is
normal it's kind of a try and I approach
because actually because the emulation
is minimalist it will put your finger
just on exotic things when when the
shellcode is trying to do something that
is not quite usual but actually is as
been the decode himself so we can get
back the memory and inspect wires are a
problem why is there a crash and
inspecting it will found this code so
this is a this is a common usage of
Windows internal structures to to obtain
imports to to resolve imports based on
our Windows internals ok so I will do to
continue the emulation we use the so
called sandbox in unison which actually
add in addition to the stack and the
shellcode I some GLS in the memory will
load it then some information on the
loader on windows installing structures
and @uv PB extra extra and so on
actually the memory in a museum being a
bytes precise we can split the for
instance is GB in just 4 bytes that we
know then skip as a sparse structures
actually so this way if the manual is
trying to reach an address that we don't
know because this is an exotic behavior
like getting the number of CPUs we it
will crush but it will put on finger
just on the code that is trying to do
something nice so using this will run
the code and actually investment we will
when we it will load the DLL and trot
structures it will treat fake address
for each of the API and if the code is
trying to troll one of these API it will
break on it and say ok this code is
trying to
to code this code is trying to call Co
initialize X so what we can do here we
can go back to Python and write
functions that so for instance if we
want to stab a star line we have a
naming convention then we can get back
the argument from the sandbox knowing
the idea and Davi we can get back the
Bison strings and we can compute the
asturian in a full Python and at the end
sets the returns value and lets the
emulation continue they can also have
some interaction with the VM like a
custom alligator or we can write
minimalist implementation like for this
function you are don't notify cache you
can say okay it always works it does not
actually contact internet but Toro is
the work and the final binary is name so
as a demo okay so now if we run the
decoder differently when it with just
the code in the stack we have T's crush
doing yeah okay we have to scratch
because we are not managing we are not
simulating the segment in the minion we
are not manage and we are not simulating
windows internal structures and so on so
now we can say is a an option to achieve
it to enable it and we go further and at
this time at the end of the famous ok
it's right when to call echo initialize
X so we can add a stub and if we do this
for some of the function for like C 505
function actually and if we run back the
binary
and if you just look at the results what
we can see here is that actually the
Chad has called URL then notify cache so
we get the URL of the CNC then we can
see that he has denoted at food that it
exists as is our name and we can see
after is doing shell execute and ionic
process next what we can also do is we
use the same script to analyze sheltered
from the same campaign by just reusing
it and if it works obviously
so we capitalize a bit or our previous
analysis and get the new parts so so far
we've seen emulation from very
minimalist uneasy code and maybe a stack
then we had signalman link window
structures then windows API simulation
which means we can go further recently
very recently we had the fully userland
emulation that is to say the code the
full userland run and just the channel
is simulate onion leaves for now so for
instance we treat linux environment
which is which will simulate the file
system the network except everything is
simulated sibility so we have to get
back the loader inside the sandbox we
have to map it indicated pre party
environment say what are the arguments
what are the environment what does the
deoxy draw vectors extra and as we have
done for the function studying before we
can stab the cisco so we can simulate
them so for instance if i want to write
a generic Cisco white what I can do is
to just pass the arguments knowing the
the calling convention gets the memory
back from the VM
and credits and a call right under fake
file descriptors then and I associate it
to the correct system number and and
it's done so has
there is a full run of file on the RS so
everything is simulated air you can see
that is trying to get the magic because
this is the variant binary file he is
trying to get its magic we infuse some
some of them then you read the file
apply is force and it output okay I
detected that it's alpha 64-bit to show
you that I'm not cheating
I can also run it for for instance LS
not notice not not fire just Alice on
arm so I can't use my own Cisco and
trainings we are simulating in get dance
extra and we get the right agenda which
is outputting the output of LS
so now we've seen the IR use we also
have seen some of the emulation part and
we can try to mix them together I will
do this we'll use one of the common
technique which is called Dyne dynamic
symbolic execution it's nothing new but
the principle is a very simple actually
you have a symbolic execution alongside
the concrete one and the concrete
execution say where we have to go so for
instance if I have these minimized code
snippet the concreting section is
entering the if if I just want as Ferris
said before a summary execution you will
get stuck on the if statement not
knowing if you have to enter or not T
statement in a dynamic symbolic
execution we will have a look at what
the concrete exaction is doing taking
the branch so we also take the branch
but as we are taking the ranch we can
add a constraint on the current path
saying that X has to be odd and
accumulate some of the some of this
constraint
along the execution
well had some usage of teaser teaser
method so Funston so for instance we can
say when you take the if you can say
okay is it possible to find a solution
which Wichita does not answer the
Restatement but as for instance and if
so can you create using a server can you
create an input that you that we will
reach T's T statement so it's used
basically to expand coverage and it's
very useful in phasing like user in a
vulnerability research and like in the
cyber Grand Challenge accuracy ago so
using it for instance what you've done
before we can create 10 bytes 10 bytes a
file named target run fully run the
phylla
binary on it brick on the reader Cisco
which is reading target bytes turn
target bites into symbolic one and then
we will run until the next Cisco but
each time there is a branch which acts
on a symbolic in bite it will try to
create a new solution for T's fats is
right for you try to create a new
solution which take the this new path
and this way you can expand the code
branch pass coverage if so so has the
demo if I rented van what I just said so
for now this is just the one that we
done that we've done before we get to
the Cisco read now it's go to the
symbolic ignition and try to to maximize
the deckle coverage so I found an input
which outer ASCII text then and I'd put
out which outer data then an output
which outer international I don't know
what a text I Tasha extra extra so it's
quite useful for facing another usage of
the GAC is to restraint the output the
input
excuse me based on what you want in the
output
so just to be more concrete I'll get
back to the shell cut and you even
notice that it's packed to be
alphanumeric so what we want to do is to
have a shell code which looks like
similar to this one but use our own CNC
so for instance using your bracket
common see what we will do is use the
DAC attach the jitter and and say that
the input shell cut it would be symbolic
so the the decoding routines will run on
symbolic byte and at the end we'll have
the equation of the output of the memory
output giving the input shell cut so as
an example and so what we will do
actually we just fixed the final you us
to be a say that we also want the that
the initial shell code has to be
alphanumeric and a special forgiving its
constraint to to find a new shaker so if
I run this demo I take just a few
minutes but we don't have time so here
is the output in the shell code that it
just treat created it's alphanumeric and
if we use the previous script that you
just use to analyze our angular campaign
we get back our own our own new Isles
like a black at that comma so if you are
using T shell code it will actually try
to reach a payload from from TV and look
like another Co coming from the angular
campaign so to conclude you have just
some ID to to get to take away from this
presentation is that miasma has as a
framework there is no magic here
I just think I just embed some of the
common parts that we used every day so
for instance the emulation
capabilities from just a function or
just occurred snipers to a full binary
we also have the IR hues with some
weapons like symbolic execution can be
used for the obfuscation from a lot of
things or just analysis and it's a
framework that we then used unreal
reward samples and real-world tasks so
it's we continue to improve it and we
continue to add to to bug fix and to add
features in it so maybe it's framework
you want to add to your toolbox
we are completely open to suggestions to
contributions to feedbacks to beers a
lot of Rods to do regarding effects
analysis to enhance what we present
today
extra extra so thanks for your attention
I hope the French accents doesn't win
everything and if you have maybe just
one or two questions I'll take them
thank you
[Applause]