so a quick introduction to who we are my
name is Claire garlic I'm the CTO of
terbium labs Trivium labs is a premier
dark web data intelligence company and
we specialize and using intelligence
from the dark web to mitigate risk for
our clients
so I'm Colin Smith I'm with RBC so well
thank you Canada is kind of his largest
bank and one of the largest in the world
within RBC we have a cyber security
research group named Vanguard and our
focus is on looking at future threats
and innovations in the cybersecurity
realm when we as soon as we get started
today we're gonna talk a little bit
about what the principles and motivated
our work today the first principle is
that data is an asset data has value and
because data has value to people into
organisations it also makes it a
liability you have to protect your asset
and a lot of people in this room will
spend a lot of time trying to protect
that asset but something we know in
particular here at blackhat is that
defense while necessary important even
critical is not sufficient we take the
approach and assume that exposure a
proprietary data is inevitable data
breaches are going to happen no matter
how many defenses you put up no matter
how much ever you put into prevention
things are still going to get out and
perhaps the industry that knows this
more than any other industry is the
payment processing industry or credit
cards despite massive investment to
prevent and limit credit card fraud
fraud credit card fraud losses still
exceed 10 billion dollars each year and
to make a bad problem worse much of that
money is funneled directly into
organized crime and terrorism so this is
an extremely important problem not just
from a business perspective but for
society as a whole and yet combating
credit card fraud is still a largely
reactionary process we'll talk more
about what we mean by reactionary in a
moment but what we're going to present
today we are going to demonstrate that
we can do better that there is another
way to think about this problem where
we don't have to wait to react to
credit-card fraud we can actually
prevent it what does that approach look
like well it's an intelligence approach
and we call it data intelligence kind of
to contrast it with threat intelligence
and the idea is that your data is going
to get out there and in this case
payment cards data are going to be
breached people are going to try to
steal them just in the act of using them
but if you track where that data ends up
if you use traditional intelligence
methods to measure it and find it then
you can do something to mitigate the
damage that that breach caused us to
your organization so in the case of
payment fraud payment cards a place
where they often show up after they've
been breached is on the dark web and
they're sold up and they're they're sold
in mass on the dark web and by measuring
and quantifying and gathering this
intelligence from the dark web we can
shift from a very reactive approach to a
proactive approach and the best part
about this is that this data fits in
very perfectly with existing analytics
and current fraud prevention approaches
so instead of being a huge and different
approach with a high lift to implement
it fits directly into existing
state-of-the-art so what is the current
state of the art so it's easy right so
in traditional point of compromised
detection you have some known
compromised cards there's multiple ways
you can find this out you yourself get
enraged when you get charged 500 dollars
for an e-book on Bitcoin that you've
obviously never bought or something or
maybe the bank has machine learning
algorithm that tells you that this was a
budget in charge or a third party like
these are or MasterCard gets in touch
and says look we think this is a
fraudulent charge so we know that these
this is traditional we know that you
know these guys are the victims of some
kind of fraud they also had some
transaction history so we can figure out
their common points of purchase so these
are the all the stories that these
victims were shopping in and then excuse
me through cross correlation we can
figure out you know well which
is the actual point of compromise so
here we see the victims all attended
cross ss fit and their data was stolen
okay so that's the traditional way but
there's a problem with this method and
there's two ways that you basically find
it out right you either have your victim
of fraud where in that case then money
is lost by the merchant or by the bank
and credit card information is stolen
along with our slides okay but then you
get it back so it's only it's only a
brief flip or you could tease me go
online and buy those credit card numbers
yourself to figure out who is being
compromised but either way you're
feeding money into the criminal economy
we don't want to do that so we're taking
an approach where we don't want to feed
money in but in doing so we are dealing
with more uncertainty so now instead of
knowing who the victim is we have groups
of candidates for each potential victim
and even still even with this
uncertainty like that yeah even when
we're in the dark we're able to make
some inferences as to who actually where
they pointed compromise actually has
occurred so we get these kinds of groups
from these this dark web intelligence so
you know the guys who committed this
data breach they know what sort well
they know it was CrossFit or sorry cross
SS fit I'm not actually trying to get
myself sued here and they they will list
you know some some detail such as the
bin the bank identification number where
they're putting the card up for sale
so we take that information and we build
up our candidate groups and then we make
some inferences as to who the victim is
there's one more thing that we do
because because of this uncertainty
we're going to need a control group to
make sure that you know we're not
pointing the blame pointing the finger
at the wrong guy so this control group
then is there to kind of veg for all the
other stories that you know
they're quite popular but there are also
popular amongst the control groups so
forget about them they're fine okay
so this is just a classic big data
problem right you you have a lot of
victims they have a huge transaction
history and you're trying to correlate
all the histories together and so you
know it's a classic problem so we have
classic solutions we're using a very
traditional approach there is a paper
that came out a couple years ago called
brief trader which is just it's a
Bayesian likelihood estimation method so
you know we don't really need the slide
so I can just tell you about it just
imagine right you basically start up
with some prior on all of your merchants
you believe like some merchants are more
likely than others ok so maybe you just
spread the blame across everybody
initially then using whatever evidence
you have such as the transaction history
you start updating that blame until you
end up getting to some stabilized
posterior right it's just a little
greedy algorithm that just alternates
back and forth it's very simple to use
you can do it in some map MapReduce
framework so it's it's you know it's
tried and trusted problem here is that
we are now adding me in this uncertainty
but you know we can still use this this
tried and trusted method we're just
augmenting it and we just have to get
around this problem problem being that
when you add in this uncertainty that
now we are trying to find the right
combination of clients across you know
possibly trillions of combinations ok so
I mean this is really like finding a
needle in a haystack so what do you do
when you want to find a needle in the
haystack
well you burn it down just set that
thing on fire
so there's a lovely animation of it on
fire so just just imagine yourselves ok
right so there's just different
thresholds that you can do to get rid of
this data we can say that you know say
that it's basically a popularity contest
say that the merchant is very very niche
and only one group has attended this
this merchant so that group represents
one possible victim
none of the other victims so if only one
group has attended it clearly it's not
one of the merchants that you care about
okay or maybe it's too popular you know
like the the Amazons or whatever or
Netflix everybody has a Netflix account
and so therefore the control group lots
of people have cans there it's not the
point of compromise or maybe it's super
unpopular nobody goes there nobody buys
it super uncool not likely to be our
victim okay so let's have a look at a
case study this is actually using
transaction data and using darkweb intel
and we were able to find a fairly large
breach right so we used the Stark web
intelligence we had a point of
compromise that was spread across ten
different batches on these card shops we
didn't know that they were correlated at
firts we did not know the point of
compromise either it had infected a
large number of clients however we did
know that a lot of these clients were
Canadian and so therefore we figured
that the business was probably Canadian
as well okay so this figure here this is
our probability distribution for the
merchants and you know the likelihood
that they were the point of compromise
so on the x-axis we have the merchants
the merchants here really refers to the
merchants name the point-of-sale
terminal and the week of any
transactions so on the y-axis we then
have the likelihood so you can see that
our number one spike that has a
probability of a point zero four percent
which might seem small but that is 60
times larger than random chance and it's
twice as large as the second largest
group but you know we can't just call it
a day and say that this point of
compromise which is a restaurant chain
we'll call it Bob's you know we can't be
100% sure so we need to look at some
some secondary evidence so the secondary
evidence is well let's look at you know
a time profile of this risk so this is
the the risk for Bob's from July up
until September and you can see
in July there's zero risk pops is fine
but I would really recommend not going
to eat there in late August because
trust me it spikes up to about point
zero four C okay
there we go I think if I just keep
hitting this it yeah it wakes up okay so
yeah this is another this is a really
good indicator that this the victim it
or the point of compromise is Bob's
because we're seeing this repeated
spikes in this short time window so you
know the algorithm doesn't build in any
kind of temporal coherence so the fact
that we're seeing that is a very strong
indication that this is also our victim
another secondary piece of evidence we
can use is the transaction data so we've
got two figures here on the left is the
transaction data for Bob and on the
right is for our second most likely
candidate this is a you know popular
online digital store let's call it
apples on so on the Left we yeah we have
pubs and in both figures we have two
curbs we've got the transaction curve in
blue and we've got the group spread in
orange so the transaction curve is just
the number of transactions made by
candidates that week
the groups red is the number of groups
that have interacted with that merchant
so when the point of compromise occurs
you actually want these two curves to be
as close as possible because that means
that there's only one candidate in each
group that has shot there so while the
digital store is a lot more popular you
can see that the blue curve is usually
way larger than the orange so it's very
unlikely to be our point of compromise
yeah so this using this information we
were able to confirm that this was a
point of compromise we were also using
historical data so I was able to go back
talk to the fraud department they were
like yeah that was a point of compromise
and we really feel like this method
works with very very large messy data so
I'll pass it over declare for the
conclusions okay so the takeaways from
this message is that traditional fraud
detection is reactive and by that we
mean we wait for fraud to occur so that
we can identify specific or attempt to
attempted fraud to recur
so we can identify specific accounts and
then begin our mitigation techniques you
don't have to wait for that to happen
you can start the moment that the
criminal has tried to monetize or build
their business online using dark web
intelligence and this is a big win
because more than just preventing fraud
you are actually stifling the criminal
economy by stopping money from feeding
into that system that is propagating
this business and creating a systemic
risk the second takeaway from this is
that this is not a method to prevent a
point-of-sale breach this happened
starting with the assumption that some
amount of data loss is inevitable that
does not mean that defensive mecha where
you're trying to you know chip chips and
other measures are not important they're
very important at reducing fraud but
even with all of those measures some
information is still going to get out
there and you still have methods of
mitigating that damage after it occurs
and this is what we call the dark web
data intelligence approach and the other
really important message to take away is
that this is really a small shift in the
way that you think about traditional
common point-of-purchase analysis as
opposed to a dramatic new algorithm and
that's a win because it means that it is
easy to implement and widely accessible
for the entire industry and one of the
things about combating credit-card fraud
is it really is an industry-wide problem
that would benefit from a lot of
collaboration across the entire industry
and so one of the reasons we're
presenting this approach today is to
encourage you to come talk to us about
how you can make this you can make these
changes and implement this strategy in
your own organization and I think that's
it yeah I think we're ready to open yeah
for any questions so okay despite the oh
yeah so we'd like to say thank you to
our colleagues Danni Rogers CEO of
terbium Cory Fong is the head of
research Vanguard it's RBC and Daniel is
very figure who helped us out with the
fraud
details yeah so despite all the
interruptions we still manage to kind of
blaze through that so we'd love to get
any questions from you guys at all so
the question was how do you deal with
dark women tell when it's basically
multiple breaches all swimming together
and one happy family you don't make the
assumption that it's only one breach and
while it might have seemed like we did
in this case that we only had one breach
we are making that assumption so you
have to be careful with basically the
thresholds that you use and then the
algorithm doesn't discriminate either it
can it can predict multiple the pocs and
so you look at your your top whatever
candidates and you look at the behavior
of that data again the group spread and
the transaction curves like they should
still be intersecting more or less so
you can still make inferences when
there's multiple breaches that are mixed
in together so yeah and we have come
across that yeah
all right so we are if right now this is
a perfect concept but when it's fully
implemented it can be automated and to
end from the data collection to the
analysis and the data collection can be
fully automated and collected almost as
fast as the information can be found and
then the transaction side is just can be
run distribute Li and can converge
within 30 minutes
yeah so I mean in the traditional POC
detection it's still actually incredibly
fast like I really am impressed with how
fast and I'm honestly at the time I was
competing with Daniel to find a POC but
even still we can still get an edge in
them and within 30 minutes for one very
large breach where it would have taken
them a couple of days to be very sure
because you have to basically you form a
hypothesis by looking at victims and
then you wait to confirm that hypothesis
where in this case you know you don't
have to wait so we would have found it
within 30 minutes so we don't make
assumptions on when the play no
compromise occurred right we usually go
we look at history of like two to three
years within the lifespan of a credit
card
so yeah the question is like is there
like how do you think about the delay
between when the cards are actually
breached and when they might actually
appear for sale so this is a risk
mitigation um so one of the things that
you might not you in some cases that
breach is ongoing in which you might
actually be able to prevent further
breaching but you can also just get a
heads up on your mitigation attempts
which means if it's a large breach and
the
it's very fresh you might want to start
reissuing you might wanna start
notifying customers you might want to
feed this directly into your real-time
transaction algorithms like there's lots
of different ways you can act on this
data given given the fact that our point
of prevention comes at the moment that
they try to mass monetize this data as
opposed to keep it very close to their
tossing that's sorry oh yeah really
bright I given that this model is kind
of nascent I have you considered any
mitigations criminals might take such as
commingling data for multiple breaches
or withholding cardholder information in
certain quantities from breaches to make
this harder as it gets more popular yeah
so we have been very careful with
exactly how we presented this a to today
because we this method today because we
agree with that so sorry repeating the
question it was can't the criminals just
overcome this method um so that we think
of it on two levels one some of what we
are observing are there ways of
advertising to their customers and so
this is how they make money off their
business and so if we force them to
change their methods they're moving into
less and less effective methods and in
some ways when you think about an
intelligence approach that is part of
the goal
so we're a careful one about our sources
and methods and specific details so that
we can you know still perform this
methodology but also keeping in mind
that stifling the economy even if it
requires them to change their their
methods is still the goal of how you
approach
how could you generalize this proactive
method to other industry like
manufacturing so how when you say other
industries in like manufacturing you
mean fraud it occurs in manufacturing
hmm it's a good question I don't I don't
know exactly how the the the two methods
overlap and I very much just inert he
deals with transaction data but I mean
we're certainly looking at we're
interested in looking at other things
involving say cryptocurrencies but you
know we're know we're at a stage where
we can we can talk about that yet when
it comes to other industries and fraud
yeah it's a good question I don't I
don't know yet which is that Deena's
valuable defense is necessary and
important but not always going to be
sufficient and that data is going to
leak so if you take the approach of
measuring where the data is and who's
using it and how they're using it then
you can still think about using this
data intelligence approach to prevent
some sort of damage that might occur to
the businesses I don't think that Colin
point-of-purchase
specifically necessarily generalizes to
two other industries but the basis
behind the work I still think as a place
it's a good basis on yeah okay awesome
thanks