and now without further ado it is my
pleasure please welcome our speakers yes
okay so I'm Jeff Moss I'm going to try
to moderate this crowd which is never an
easy task so I'm well we're all
commissioners with the global Commission
for the stability of cyberspace or the
GCSE and it's a three-year endeavor to
try to think about and formulate some
norms Commission's like this have
happened in the past we like to think
that we're a little different we have a
research component that we try to
actually use research to inform some of
our norms we're about what year to
middle year to one and a half year too
so we're really starting to digest a lot
of the thinking and feedback we've
gotten we've already proposed some norms
you might have read the one about the
call to protect the core of the internet
and we're about to release another
couple of norms so that's not entirely
what we want to talk about here what I
want to talk about is sort of this
interface between policy and technology
and some of the problems we're facing
so my first kind of question to
everybody here is just kind of give us a
your thoughts about this commission
commissions in general why you're
participating and what you hope to get
out of what you hope to see the work
product of a large Commission how it
will help people in the room anybody
want to go Jim this is an outgrowth of
something that started in the UK about
seven years ago where a bunch of people
mainly British and American got together
and said you know we got to figure out
how to make the interstate politics work
we've got to figure out what the rules
of the road are this led to this thing
called The Hague process which has now
become like a gathering of the clans the
last one was in Delhi and it's like
everyone on their dog and so they keep
adding things like the Children's
Crusade for cyber security and so it's
but one of the spin-offs was when the
Dutch did it they said we need to make
these things more concrete so they've
created this
Global Center for cybersecurity
excellence they've created a thing to
push this thing called the town manual
which is on the law of war and that it
created this global Commission and the
idea is governments are going a little
slow maybe we can help them out yeah and
I put in in some context because you
know I used to be at the State
Department doing the cyber diplomacy
whatever the hell that means and I'll
release and the idea is that you know
yeah the Dutch started this commission
but the idea of the Commission was
really to help supplement what was
trying to go on among governments and
governments were looking at what how do
you make cyberspace more stable in the
long term so there's a lot of things
governments and other people do to try
to respond to threats for instance a lot
of technical things about hardening the
targets
there's offensive and defensive and all
kinds of ranges of other things but the
idea is in the long term how do you try
to make cyberspace more stable by coming
up with some voluntary rules of the road
as part of it that's enormous part part
of it is international law applies in
cyberspace part of it is
confidence-building measures you know
just transparency measures so how do you
come up with the framework that in the
long term means that states don't have
an incentive to keep things working well
for everyone for the technical community
for for governments for citizens and not
have an incentive to disrupt them how do
we get to that stage and so this
commission was set up because usually
that's a discussion among governments
alone I participated in those
discussions and Jim did as well when
they're among governments in the UN
system and others but there really
wasn't a multi stakeholders we call way
to look at these issues and that's what
the Commission's trying to do not
compete with governments but help inform
that conversation the Commission has
folks who are technical experts where
policy experts from all over the world
and the idea isn't my expectation hope
is we're going to be able to really
contribute to that debate and really
bring some of these communities together
particularly the technical community the
policy community and others so that we
can focus on these issues because with
all the focus on all the things that are
happening every day some of these
long-term issues and what the rules of
the road are and what expectations are
really are going to be important so
Chris and Jim talked about the obvious
not the obvious
how many of you have heard of the term
sustainable development yeah let's all
raise our hands okay let's just all
raise our hands how many of you have
heard the phrase strategic arms
reduction right ductile again please
thank you how many of you have heard of
conflict prevention and the duty to
protect all of those phrases grew out of
Commission's all of them they were short
term high level widely ranging Big Idea
enterprises that brought together the
best minds to think about the biggest
problems
needless to say maybe this doesn't fall
in that category but that is one of the
aspirations of the commission and the
stability of cyberspace is a big phrase
I mean what do we mean by stability what
do we mean about about cyberspace and
you know I'm I'm an operator all this
be3 bla bla bla is interesting but what
does it mean we do and the second thing
this Commission is really I think doing
in the course of its work is teaching
government's how to work effectively
with non-governmental actors now
multi-stakeholder model working with the
private sector or working with academics
clergy industry is common course for
mayors and for people at the state and
local level around the world provincial
level around the world it is not the
common course for national level
governments for most of them and it is
certainly not the common course when
governments get together internationally
so one of the contributions this
commission is making in a field that
demands it is helping governments learn
how to work productively with
non-governmental actors so one of the
things I always find interesting is that
if you have norms people always say well
people can violate the norm it's not a
quote unquote hard norm how do you
enforce the norm and a lot of times it's
just important to figure out who's out
of line right who's violating a norm
well if the same actor keeps violating
an arm over and over maybe you pay more
attention to that actor but if it's
every once in a while so it helps you
keep a scorecard of maybe who the people
are
that are acting in good faith versus
those that part and so there's a lot of
uses of norms that aren't there's not
one particular goal
Norman purposes and I bet a lot of us in
this room we already follow norms that
you probably don't even think about
their sort of internalized right you
think about acceptable use policies
they're sort of contractual but how many
people actually follow the letter of
their acceptable use policy right it's
kind of a guideline more than a contract
right peering agreements other things
that keep the internet working there
essentially norms and it's all kind of
negotiable but right don't we talk about
ISPs or transit providers if they
misbehave enough times we know they're
violating the norms and we avoid them or
we penalize them somehow
so what we're doing is essentially that
at more of a policy level and that's
something I find really fast me I want
to ask the panel about is this interface
between tech and policy because I came
from the tech side and I got more
involved in the policy side and there's
there's a class of cultures there right
the the different words you do things at
different speeds and I see a lot of tech
people want to get involved in policy
and they run in there and they shoot off
there ten ideas they get very little
accomplished they get burned out and
then they leave and I think that's
because they don't know how to
necessarily engage in the policy world
you know it moves some of these things
move it decades speed you know people
say why are you involved in the GCS less
yeah nothing's gonna happen it's like
well I deal day-to-day on small problems
and I'm doing stuff that will take years
maybe decades and so how do you
reconcile right that need to involve
tech people and so let's talk a little
bit about about the role that norms play
in our everyday lives given that this is
such a norm observing group but norms
really I think they play two powerful
roles one is they they condition our
performance in any given moment you know
there's a bandwidth of acceptable
behavior that we will perform and the
second thing that norms do is create
prospects for the rest of us it gives us
some love
of expectation of where you will fall
there are norms of expected behavior so
the Commission has come out originally
now now with two norms that it has
published one is Jeff mentioned on the
con protecting the core the public core
of the internet and the second norm it
may not surprise you is about non
interference with technical means in
elections and referenda and plebiscites
that happen around the world now you
might say you know seriously I mean you
know sort of you know put your wand away
you know but but if we don't if we don't
speak these norms if we don't narrate
what the expectation of performance is
we can't complain when people don't
comply and so the the normative exercise
that we're going through now is not so
much the articulation of of a brand new
and exciting and unimaginable
expectations around how we should treat
each other in this thing we call
cyberspace so and and the way that's
built so it's I agree with Jenny
completely surprisingly but they're
really expectations for you havior you
don't expect people to follow them right
away you have to get global acceptance
of these because we're cool a lot of
people say cyberspace is a rule free
zone or it's a wild wild west whatever
help term you want to use and it's not
true there are things that apply to it
already there are common practices or
common practices for states to but at
the same time we need to articulate what
are these where are these you know rules
of the road that people can then adhere
to them whatever expectations of other
states and then when states break those
of expectations when they do bad things
it's not just calling them out which
they've done we've been better at
calling them out but you know you can't
really name and shame some of these
countries just by calling them out so
you have to have consequences for that
but I want to go to the Jeff's point of
the the issues of trying to deal
bridge the gap between the policy
community the technical community and
there's lots of different divisions in
the space so even within the policy
community the economic people don't
really talk to the security people
really well so there's that division and
then there's this division between the
you know the technical community and the
policy community who don't speak the
same language and this was made clear to
me one of the norms
that Jane mentioned was this one don't
you know don't essentially futz with the
public core of the Internet don't don't
do something that would undermine it in
the large-scale and that seems
reasonable and then there was one that
came out of this UN process
don't States should not attack the certs
the t-shirts of another country because
they're seen in a sense as the ambulance
is there the response teams and they
should use them for good for defensive
purposes not bad so a couple of weeks
ago about a month ago I was keynoting
the first conference the form of
incident response and security teams
that was having its meeting in Malaysia
and I talked about these particularly
the one dealing with certs and there
were you know several hundred people in
the audience they'd never heard of this
before and this is the audience this is
really aimed at so if they're not
knowing about they're not taking that
work forward and actually going to
various vendors and say this is a good
idea we need to bring this forward
that's a real problem that's a real
disconnect and we really need a bridge
ICAP as much as possible so this all
started in 1998 when the Russians
proposed an international treaty in the
UN that would govern cyberspace and they
were particularly concerned with the
risk that this new technology would give
the u.s. a military advantage that it
would use and the treaty was premature
of course it received very little
support but a bunch of us started
thinking you know ultimately we're gonna
need some kind of convention some kind
of formal agreement among states but
people are not ready to do that and so
how do you build a pathway to get to
trust to get to agreement and that
pathway that a few of us identified and
has come up in these three rounds of UN
negotiations was norms which are
expectations about state behavior
confidence-building measures like I'm
gonna tell you what I'm doing so you
don't freak out and then capacity
building which is making other countries
able to defend themselves and that kind
of that was 2010 and that was the agenda
there's two problems that sort of touch
on what we're talking about here and
sort of explain the Commission the first
is we probably have all the norms we
already need right we there might be
some places we're missing but we don't
we don't need
anymore norms and so we've got a cottage
industry and universities of cranking
out you know on alternate Wednesday's
Wednesday's people agree not to attack
certs or something we've reached the end
of this path and in some ways instead of
building trust there's much more
distrust than there was in in 2010 it's
gonna be hard to get agreement second
part was this is a really complicated
problem and I fear a little of the
responsibility for this because I I
basically copied a lot of old Cold War
arms agreements like the conventional
forces in Europe agreement if you want
to raise your hand again the Helsinki
agreement these are models that we use
to deal with conflicting states and it's
not just a state problem that gets us
back to this issue of who else is
involved to us as a stake now I
completely reject the idea that
corporations have the same power as
states only the the people like people
who say that are people who've never had
to deal with a state when it's in a bad
mood right our opponents will kill but
they will also they're afraid they want
to come to a deal so the first problem
is how do we involve this broader
community and there really aren't good
models for that yeah the second problem
is this touches when it was arms control
was relatively easy arms control when I
used to dermis control like here's the
tank there's a tank I got a tank you got
a tank this this touches everything it
touches economics it touches politics
it touches society and so when states
see this they see high levels of
distrust no good models for how to deal
with that a big community of their
citizens who want to be involved and the
fact that it doesn't really fit the it
touches on so many things they become
cautious and that means they move slowly
well and and this is such an undeveloped
area that a lot of states at a really
high level you know the people who are
in the trenches get this but the people
at the high level the decision-makers
the presidents prime ministers others
they're beginning to understand these
issues but but it's still seen its
attack I'm just happy we're not
following mutually assured destruction
models we are we are people seem to go
to the models they like if we use I
don't know plows wits again or
an udder loop it's likely you know
people fall back on the constructs are
familiar with and so maybe in the early
days it was arms control yeah yeah okay
sorry sorry the only former soldier on
there I feel compelled to speak up okay
you're exactly right I mean the the
danger is we go to what we know right
and so there there is an awful lot of
knowledge and practice around security
norms and behavior between governments
it is not the right model in my view to
just simply take all of that and import
it into this area the other the other
model that we have that that I'm a sort
of unapologetic advocate for is thinking
more along the lines of public health
you know why can't we insist on basic
hygiene in cyberspace basic defenses
that we know prevent or rapidly mitigate
the problems that we know about and and
those exist that you know I'm a board on
the board of directors of the Center for
Internet security so is so it's Chris
and Jim had a had a key role to play in
creating the top critical controls you
know them as the top 20 you know Etsy
has its own and the Australians have
their own why can't we insist that
people in effect wash their hands before
they get online why is that such a
bridge too far back to Jim's point
because people don't think we can impose
expectations on industry or companies or
enterprises and that's just wrong well
we have we have two trends and they
unfortunately run into each other the
one trend is the resurgence of
nationalism and authoritarian regimes
who really don't want to play by the
rules the second trend is the Internet's
had a political effect and it's changed
the grounds for legitimacy so it used to
be when I was worked in the government I
had a joke with my wife said what they
don't know won't hurt them she says I
can't say that anymore but to get people
to support something now don't scream
you need a different approach it can't
be so much top-down it can't be multiple
layers it's got to be flatter there have
to be avenues for the citizens to
contribute directly a guy who's sort of
good at this and you may not like him
but he's an effective politician as
someone named Trump he's discovered how
to make that connection
and we're struggling with that I think
all democracies are struggling with
citizens now want to be more involved
how do we do that yeah although I'd say
this is not exactly a priority for him
this area but well we have a monthly
quota on Trump jokes and unfortunately
we've exceeded it already so I mean but
but you know I think the other issue is
I was going to the maturity model and I
agree with Janet or the hygiene issue
which is one part of this but there's
also what are states when you talk about
norms especially it is what it states
willing to constrain themselves what are
they willing to give up and decide
they're not doing so one that came out
was don't States should not attack the
critical infrastructure of another state
absent more time if it's more time there
are rules about proportion and
distinction ality and all these things
for the law of armed conflict
humanitarian law but but absent that you
know what estates constrain themselves
to do and this is such a new area and
there's so little comfort in this that
states are not really willing to
constrain themselves a lot however they
have made some strides and doing that
and then we see them actually exceeding
those agreements all the time and then
the question is how do you make sure
that you reinforce that those are real
important expectations and their
consequences for breaking and the other
more norm that's in there is one this
has been true for a long time you as a
government are responsible for actions
taken from your territory so if there's
a pirate base in San Francisco the US
government has the obligation to other
states to close down that pirate base
and in the West what you can call the
West in countries that have rule of law
you know they'll go after hackers but
there are many countries where they
either don't have the capability or they
don't have the desire or they're
actually sponsoring them in you know and
so it makes it a much more complex
environment to say here's a norm and
it's like that's really interesting come
back to me in the year so we've got I've
got two other questions I want to
explore we've got about half hour time
left one is then how would you suggest
to people that are more technical than
policy how do you suggest they get
involved or is it you know at what point
are there too many cooks in the kitchen
when I was at ICANN and people would ask
me this I I had limited options I mean
there
requests for comments all the time at
ietf you know I can and its people would
say well I don't want to put a comment
on a webform it's I agree with that but
on the other hand I can we tracked all
those comments and there was one person
that never showed up to any meeting
nobody knew who they were they commented
on every single proposal for like the
last decade I mean this person was
legendary and so when we read that
person's comments they like counted for
like ten of other people's comings
because they understood the process
they'd been involved for a long time
they'd considered multiple viewpoints
and so that was like getting almost a
white paper and that one person's
comments so they never had to spend a
nickel to travel to any meetings or
anything and so I think our venues are
avenues for participation are more be
are different in the technical community
but you could see what the NTIA comments
or through the who was at the Department
of Commerce and their comments on arms
control versus exploits what was the the
Wassenaar Wassenaar comment sorry record
number of comments more than they'd ever
had from the technical community so I
think you know we're desperate to
participate but we don't have maybe have
the ways to I mean what would you think
I go ahead just I I was the person who
negotiated the Boston our agreement and
there's a like so many of these things a
part of it that is in public where it
was successful and the rest of it some
days I wonder if it was such a good idea
so I think one of the things is we need
to do a better job this is one of the
reasons we're trying to have sessions
like this you know as part of it is
actually you know government's and also
process the Commission need to actually
take some of the the momentum and go in
engage with groups like this and try to
ask them it's not really reasonable to
ask for people just to come and write
all these comments because that's not
going to happen because a lot of you
know this is gonna burn out by my talk
at the first conference people don't
even know what happened the hell's
happening so how can they have a
conversation about this how can they
actually contribute this process if
we've been so bad about actually
engaging these communities on things
that are core to them and talking about
it so I think we do I think part of it
is us
so I think there's a pretty fundamental
challenge that's out there
for all of us right when I when I talk
about this and I explained cybersecurity
to non-technical executives of which I
am one as they look you know people say
it's real complex it's real simple there
are three problems we have not solved
problem number one how do we architect
systems we can trust from components we
can't problem number two how do we
safeguard the security of our eye and
the integrity of our information and
identity in an open Internet problem
number three what should the role of
government be now this is a problem
because when it comes to security
governments are used to being not only
the big players governments are used to
being the monopolists in cyberspace or
in security space and they are in
physical space and they are not in
cyberspace and so there is really still
a tug-of-war among all the competing
stakeholders on who should set the rules
and so what if a communities like this
is thinking about getting involved I
mean the government the way you know the
fastest pathway it's not very fast is to
come into government and learn how
government works and learn the problems
that governments are prioritizing and
and there's a shortage of skills that
exist in this room in government what
we're trying to do as part of the
Commission's work is expand and relax
government's mind a little bit that you
don't have to have all the expertise
existing within you know the federal
work force or in the military that
there's an enormous capability out there
that we have not even begun to tap into
systematically there's a generally
shared sense that there's a strong
disconnect between the policy community
and the technology community my own
sense is there's there's solutions to
some of our problems that are kind of
rippling below the surface but there's
no way for either side to discover them
and part of it is this disconnect the
problem gets more complex when you throw
and you start sorting in the the changes
that are coming on so we were talking
about don't scream AI beforehand and
okay so it's another program like who
cares but but the level of understanding
how do you get people to write rules
when they don't understand the
technology right that's it's better than
it used to be one of the things like do
is when I go to a control
my office I see whether the member as a
yellow legal pad on their desk that's
generally assigned they're still not
using the Internet and the number has
gone down but the level of how do you
how do you get people to make rules for
a community they don't understand or for
devices they know so that's an argument
for greater presence but when you think
about it from when we're at Homeland
Security we took on the challenge of how
do we increase the ranks of qualified
cyber security personnel working in DHS
across the board Jeff was involved and
and we figured out we had to do five
things well one we need to hire test and
train two standards I mean can people do
stuff or not it's one thing to talk
about a good game it's another thing to
be able to do it you know I fly a lot I
am NOT a pilot okay there's a difference
and you guys understand that number two
is how do we open up genuinely the
pipeline between academia industry and
government in a way that allows a more
free flow of talent across the board how
do we how do we revise all of our
procurement guidelines how do we
successfully manage this group of folks
once you're in government not a trivial
challenge and then how do we swarm on
problems when they're big ones because
they lie beyond the capacity of any
single agency to handle I mean these are
practical were real-world problems that
government agencies have to cope with in
thinking about bringing on board talent
well there is also this trend I mean
when I had the office in the State
Department we were the first one
anywhere in the world then there was
like 26 now countries that have them I
had a lot of policy people I also had
some really strong technical people were
there to help inform we don't as jane
said you not to be a pilot to fly in the
plane you don't have to be a pot you not
to be a technical expert to understand
some of the policy dimensions to this
and I think that's why this has always
been treated more as a boutique shiny
object issue by senior decision-makers
because they think oh cyber that's
really complex I don't get that but
having that those people there to draw
on that it is really important so I want
to move us into sort of our final topic
and then if we have time to do some
questions um which is consequence side
of this right so what what are your
options realistically if you do see
people violating norms maybe talk about
certain norms and the consequences and
then how that might or may not apply
into the cybermen so
I mean let me start on that because I
think it's important that as I said
before if there are no consequences
there'll costs for your actions at all
then that is essentially creating a norm
of inaction and saying that this is
acceptable conduct if you can for
instance manipulate country's elections
and there's no consequences no cost
they're meaningful and they have to be
relatively timely there's issues around
the attribution etc untimely they have
to be timely and they actually have to
change the decision-makers calculus so
they don't do it again and we've been
really terrible about that we're trying
to get better we've been better at
calling out countries great but you're
not gonna name and shame Russian you're
not gonna name in shame or North Korea
so you actually have to tailor this
there are issues around escalation
because this is a new area is it's gonna
escalate out of control
you're not just gonna use cyber tools
people think there's a cyber button you
press and you out and you know against
the end that's it's not true but you're
gonna use economic many people get
really wrapped up when United one right
when the United States said we reserve
our full set of tools to respond to a
cyber all of a sudden everybody says
you're gonna drop a bomb on me because I
sent you a ping and you're not gonna do
that you're not gonna send kinetic
weapons for most of these cyber types
because we're not the level of war I
mean we're below that they're still
serious whether it's theft of
information or things like not petia but
we've got to take action and we've got
the other thing I'd say it's collective
action it's important building alliances
with other countries and actually
talking again to the tactical community
to say are there other tools are there
other things we can be doing that are
beyond the toolset that we normally
think of diplomatic economic kinetic
cyber there is a there is a consensus
now in the intelligence community and in
the military that unless we impose
damaging consequences on the people who
are attacking us and as you guys
probably know and certainly Cyber
Command knows we are attacked every day
by one of the four dwarfs right and the
feeling is that sending them a nasty
note or naming them in public sort of
like worried before another sanctions I
mean how many there's no sanctions left
that we can impose on Russia right why
does it really have to go we disagree
because I'm in the camp that says we
need to shoot back and we need to think
about how to
use that in a way that doesn't risk
turning into a bigger conflict but at
the same time we don't it's a game of
chicken and right now the other guys are
winning because we chicken out so
there's a consensus I'd say up to the
three-star level that the US needs to
think about how to retaliate forcefully
I mean if it really didn't answer it let
me just say the Matt real quick it was
some temporary painful and reverse
irreversible nothing anything and that's
how over the counter you know yeah good
luck with that
I you know look let me give me the leash
it depends on your theory of the case
right if your theory of the case is the
only reason people conform to reasonable
norms is because there's a fear of
punishment then we should all go home I
mean there's a there's a lot more
motivating us in terms of compliant
behavior I think you know you do you
reach the limit case where you know
shooting back is the only option every
single Society on the planet has rules
for that but it's not just sort of fly
your own flag and you know shoot it will
and and even Stand Your Ground laws
which we've seen play out in the
physical world here you know people have
been beginning to use that language in
this domain and it just feels inept look
there have been consequences around the
world for politicians failing to
understand the very powerful social
norms that have emerged over the past 50
years the norms of inclusivity
transparency reciprocity and
accountability what what does that mean
inclusivity nothing about me without me
how many politicians now are facing the
consequences of failing to get that
right and not just in the United States
across the world
you know public's are angry and they're
angry because people are that it seems
like our institutions and our political
class or unresponsive to the changes
that have gone on largely brought about
by the internet and connectivity
knowledge information and community
that's emerging so ever I mean can we
imagine a moment in time where we need
norms more I can't well but I D counter
that I'd say the Obama administration
knew by April of 2016 what the Russians
were up to by August of 2016 they
developed a package
overt and covert responses and they
didn't pull the trigger and that's why
we're in the mess we're in today
I mean responses to norm yeah
I mean not necessarily government norms
what we're proposing aren't our
sanctioned by a particular government
what we're saying is here's some rules
of the road for everybody right right
but what what do we do if I in the
United States see I don't know some
other country violent or another company
right what are my options I guess I
could name in shame I could get on a
mailing list I could get online and say
hey look it's a fifth time that this
behavior has happened or why we seem to
be getting a lot of attacks from Iran
lately I mean really what what are our
options
short of picking up the phone and
calling that base of our buyers I think
a lot more thought and I think not a
slavish and Jim didn't suggest this
adherence the sort of military analogies
well you know they have that spectrum of
escalation this straight line I mean
Wars don't happen in straight line every
fistfight does not hold the potential
for a nuclear exchange I mean there are
important disruptions along the way and
there are other tools that can be
brought to bear when trouble happens
it's almost never a point problem it's
it's this toxic cocktail of things that
come together in a way that that have
opened up points of influence and so you
know should we put fight back yeah I
think I think we should do we know do we
have any common understanding do we have
any coherent understanding of the
conditions under which that's the right
response not yet
yeah I do think I agree that we have to
use all the tools in our tool set we
have to use them in the right way and
the most effective tools that we have
and so we haven't done that and I'd be
the first I mean I'm not the first but I
would also agree that we didn't do it
not from the Obama administration in
fact I mean I that's not that's
absolutely right and there are a lot of
reasons I think not newest laughs I'm
not doing it because there should have
been a lot more action and that sends a
message but then to your point Jeff I
mean if you're a private entity and
you're seeing this you know I think
there are some things you can do some of
the public attribution a lot of
companies are done I think that's
actually been helpful sort of the apt
one report like for instance when we ago
she ated be agreeing with the Chinese on
the theft of intellectual property I
think that you know when they when the
report came out on the Chinese that's
actually
if even though the Chinese were
convinced that it was asked to did it we
which we did that actually kind of
helped because it got it out in the
public domain and people were discussing
it and I think it helped push along and
you you guys probably know this but the
FBI really only looks at people
reactively I mean there has to have been
a crime or an imputation of crime or
something and then they can go and look
NSA has broader authorities but they're
focused on a very narrow target set
right and so there's a huge amount that
doesn't get picked up by the federal
government in frankly we wouldn't want
them to pick it up so the question is if
folks out there are seeing things and if
they have ideas on how to reverse it
yeah how do we create a pipeline for
they and that's the last thing I want to
say is that we're it's stuck with the
tools that we have and some of them we
haven't really used is not enough of we
don't understand we don't have the whole
capability but they're traditional tools
one area I think of work with you guys
is saying are there things that we
haven't thought of should we think about
black holing traffic from a country
freely I mean that has a lot of economic
consequences beyond impact including on
the country that's imposing it but are
there things that we can do that really
we haven't thought about the government
hasn't thought about that would help us
improve this tool set so we can hold
people accountable in a reversible way
that's like painful but reversible I
think the other thing to keep in mind is
that there are for too long government
has treated problems in cyberspace as a
matter for the intelligence community
and something that needs to be
compartmentalized and kept aside as if
really the only important and valuable
information we're in that community I
mean there are a couple of pathologies
in our approach to intelligence that we
really haven't yet overcome one of them
is you know the harder a piece of
information is to get the more important
it must be well you know we had a
pushcart dealer in Times Square warned
us about a guy who is trying to bomb New
York City you know another pathology is
the higher up the source of information
the more authoritative it must be
seriously do we still believe that I
mean show so we have a lot of we have we
need a lot more rigor in our thinking to
vote to develop responsible policies for
the kinds of things
Jim
talking about and this connects back to
our initial discussion which is norms or
rules of behavior people are going to
violate them until they decide there's a
penalty to doing that and then we have
to figure out how do we detect violation
how do we respond to it when I say we to
Chris this point to James point it's not
just Uncle Sam anymore it's got to be
something broad and it's also a
consortium of countries so you're
stronger if you could do it with others
right so the flaming ball of cyber death
is coming towards you you need to take
action you're gonna you know what every
country is gonna have to take action
obviously but if you have a chance to
build a coalition of other countries and
work together that's a stronger message
it's a less blur when you're absorbing
the fireball of death let's spend one
minute on that in the in our lifetime in
the lifetime of the people in this room
there have been four or five great
strategic moments where questions have
been put to us at the end of World War
two the question was how do we save
succeeding generations from the scourge
of war which twice in our lifetime
brought untold sorrow and misery to
mankind
nabela Archibald MacLeish it's the
preamble to the UN Charter and the
answer was NATO it was the UN it was a
number of institutions that brought
governments together collectively during
the Cold War that strategic question was
how do we save ourselves from nuclear
annihilation
the real fireball because the only thing
standing between us and the precipice is
our judgment and again here it was
institutions and regimes for controlling
the conversation or guiding the
conversation between governments with
these destructive weapons at the end of
the Cold War the question was my
goodness look how powerful the United
States is what will the United States do
with this power the answer became to
many around the world whatever we want
and the question now is how fragile is
the American commitment to democratic
values that's one of the questions and
how fragile our democratic values when
we're looking at a highly heterogeneous
world that's ever more connected
educated mobile and politically engaged
than at any time in history
so this normative exercise is not just a
walk in the park it's a deep thinking
and
an action agenda to decide what it is
we're going to do and who it is we're
going to be that's a hard one to follow
up but I'll give you a try there Chris
do you wanna do questions me yeah yeah
let's do some questions we've got it
right I wasn't trying to follow up no
we've got a wise man let's move on to
questions we've got a little bit about
10 minutes left so we'll try questions
if we don't get any questions we'll just
keep going up here we can talk forever
we haven't done our boris and natasha
and imitation yeah where are the
microphones there's one over here and
there's one over here okay so this
gentleman was first can you just say
your name and del Jones I'm just curious
if you think the reluctance to shoot
back in cyberspace might because you
don't want to tip your hand in
cyberspace I'm sorry it says like adding
reluctance to shoot back in cyberspace
might be because you don't want to tip
your hand on what your capabilities are
in cyberspace or where you might already
be there's there's some truth to that
and then there's a sort of a process to
go through and make those decisions and
the question that's come up is there's
now beliefs that we could take some
actions there's a decision do you do it
covertly and say it wasn't me I have no
idea do you do it privately and say
something bad happens and you go to them
say gee I'm really sorry that happened
but you know when you interfere in our
elections geez what can you say there's
a there's always a debate there but it
shouldn't be a debate that paralyzes you
into inaction it's an operational
question and I think you know yes you
may be using a tool and exposing a tool
by doing that but I but I also think you
have to couple it with for instance
messaging diplomatic message is saying
it's us that's doing this to you and
stop it or we're gonna do it to you
again but but also thinking I goes back
to the overstatement of what our
capabilities are and Rob Joyce who's
also I think here somewhere at the
conference or a Def Con or ha who used
to be used to be the White House had a
really interesting way of saying and
said you know people think we have some
capabilities we have the capability to
knock someone down but we know how to
make capable they put our knee on their
chest and keep them down and I think you
know if you're really going to change
behavior you have to think about how all
capabilities play out what the follow-up
is and what the messaging is which can't
just be the use of the capability it has
to be part of a larger strategy I had an
interesting conversation right after
Snowden because I know some of the
people who build tools for the
Department of Defense and I said done
Jesus must have been a real setback for
you guys I mean what Holland's are gonna
take to recover and they said I'll you
know maybe three months there's just
it's not that hard so there's a we might
overestimate the the damage of revealing
some it's more the political side of
saying the political side in the sense
of saying hey we're on your network and
the fact that the other guy tends to
improve his defenses
after you do something but these are all
things we ought to be able to calculate
sir hey I'm a threat intelligence
analyst in the private sector and I've
really enjoyed to talk about one of my
you know primary focuses is on China and
the way they've kind of used and abused
the private sector and non-state actors
so how do you handle on an international
policy level a you know effectively a
non-state actor and you know how it's
being abused by other nation-states and
you know groups like that just because
of you know the difficulty and
attribution and compliance and yeah I
mean I think I'll start and I think I
think to our dogs to yeah I mean I first
of all I think there is this sense of
attribution it's impossible and it's not
you know attribution mean you may not be
able to do it right away
but you look at more than the digital
footprints you look at a lot of other
things and of course countries try to
use proxies and cutouts as a way to hide
their identity but you can often see
beyond that too by looking at all again
all the information you have and you
know I think we've done that I think you
know Muller has done that also in this
indictment we've seen examples of that
and that's also where I think some of
the private sector report is helpful and
maybe talk just a little bit about the
people in technical community you know
the saying is like pcaps or it didn't
happen you know packet traces or we
don't believe you but so and that's a
big problem and a lot of times I tell
you it's is it Team Russia or team China
you just I will tell you that I've had
this debate with Russian diplomats where
they say we want a hundred percent proof
if it's not 100 percent proof then
that's not good enough and there is no
standard for attribution in cyberspace
it is a political issue when the state
says someone did it it's a political
decision now that doesn't mean they
don't have confidence that that actor is
the one who did it because it turns out
it wasn't that actor that really erodes
our credible in the future so they take
a lot of carrot before they actually do
that but it still is not a quantum
decision and I used to be a prosecutor
where the standard is more than
reasonable doubt that's not absolute
proof and one of the things is when I
was in Los Angeles if you had a juror
who was an out-of-work aerospace
engineer and there were a lot of them
they wanted mathematical proof of guilt
and and that's not the standard here so
I think you have to work around that and
really think about you know if it walks
like a dog and talks like a duck it's
likely a duck you know and what's really
interesting about this question I think
at a at a strategic level is governments
collectively all of them have an
interest in understanding what Jim said
earlier the rule of law well the rule of
law comes in various flavors right
there's contested order there's
alternative order and there's no water
all order is contested everybody is in
an environment where they're vying for
control of that particular order and
sometimes like that that contest emerges
into alternate order we're seeing that a
little bit in cyberspace should there be
sort of completely separate rules from
those we know in physical space and
whatever from whatever domain but we're
also seeing lawlessness I think we are
migrating irreversibly away from
lawlessness we may not like where we're
going but as any good pastor once said
to me if you don't know where you're
going any road will take you there so
just quickly on the attribution point
remember that there multiple means to
collect information and that includes
human agents listening to phone
conversations which it turns out we're
really good at along with all the cyber
stuff so when the US says something it's
based on multiple sources and on the
China question China's decision on how
it will interact with the rest of the
world is the great strategic problem of
our time and the Chinese now they have
their own internal problems but they're
in this thing
we're moving back to the center of the
stage the world stage China the world
should be China centric and for them
that means in the norms we're talking
about and for the laws we're talking
about
they don't always think they need to
follow them they think maybe they need
to rewrite them to favor China this is
gonna be a long struggle it won't be a
military struggle but it will be a
struggle I think there's a non-trivial
coda to what Jim just said the United
States is unique among great powers and
that it has always been willing to
accept the responsibility that goes with
its power and when you look at the other
power centers around the world whether
it's in Europe or China or elsewhere
around the world even regionally that's
not always manifest and so this when
we're talking about shooting back or
we're talking about creating norms or
we're talking about any of the behaviors
that guide or that lead the direction
that we might be headed in it's
important I think to remember that it's
if you're keeping score the film
references have been spider-man this
fifth dimension with that one with Chris
Willis and then dr. Swift element yeah
fifth element you know if anyone you
know my twitter feed I have a cyber a
movie poster a week I've now done I'm
not number forty this week so any
suggestions are welcome hey sir so do
you believe that cyber will remain more
of a force multiplier or do you think
there's a real possibility it will move
into the cyber is a force multiplier or
will or do you think there's a
possibility that responses from
governments will be more physical or the
response of governments I think I think
we are we're lost if we think the only
way to respond to cyber is by cyber but
at the same time we have to have this
capabilities it has to be part of the
toolset yeah they'll be physical
responses we've responded to some of the
physics and the cyber things with things
like sanctions and other physical
responses that's that's the way you do
you never go limit yourself to one
channel you know a little information in
the hands of the eager is a dangerous
thing and but when you think about what
can cyber do I mean I think at every
level it's a force multiplier when when
I you know I was in the Army we used to
think about that really so
within the context the story and
narrative about how to fight win the
nation's Wars what we're lacking really
is an overarching narrative about
cyberspace and the role that it plays in
our lives it's becoming utility we don't
like using that word but it is and we
have really not even begun to sort of
frame out the set of issues in anything
approaching a prioritized way about how
to equitably distribute the advantages
of that safeguarded in ways that we find
acceptable you know based on our culture
and our norms as societies and then
coexist peacefully I mean the challenge
is huge
yeah I'd also say it's a force
multiplier in the sense that yes it
gives you more capabilities it's also a
force multiplier in the way that it also
multiplies the vulnerabilities we have
in the reliance we have on it so the
trend in the military is to integrate
cyber into other operations and look at
it for what you guys would call mobile
radio connectivity the making it part of
how you fight wars the problem we have
is that there's a threshold roughly
defined on what constitutes a use of
force that would justify force and
response our military is doing good
planning on what to do if we get in a
shooting war and the Russians the
Chinese a couple of others are doing it
as well
most of the conflict we're going to see
is below that and so that's where it
gets difficult is what when it doesn't
involve an action that obviously
justifies force in response what do we
do back into James earlier point and dr.
Strangelove we do the arms control II
term is we have to populate all the
rungs of the escalation ladder we have
to know how to respond maybe it won't
involve kinetic force maybe it will but
most countries are gonna try and stay
below this threshold of open warfare
because it's just it's just too
dangerous for nuclear powers to get in a
big fight wait you have to communicate
that to okay I'm gonna go to our last
question over here on the right sir and
then I think you said there's a room if
you want to continue the conversation
we're gonna go out this door and still
do is certain south side South Seas H
we're gonna go to after this so last
question sir
hi my name's Niko penetration tester
from San Diego so considering the low
barrier to entry for the cyber worker
how teeth or what type of nation state
actors do you think have come to
prominence due to the low barrier of
entry and how much truth do you think
that statement has well the traditional
top players are obviously and the DNI I
said this every year from like time
immemorial China and Russia's the most
capable actors full spectrum actors
North Korea and Iran raising fast but
the problem is as you say there is a
little asymmetric nature to this where
countries and I don't know I've heard
lots of different estimates how many
countries are developing cyber offensive
capabilities dangerously without any
doctrine around them and the u.s. does
have some rules and doctrine around what
they do a lot of other countries are not
and they're they're developing in a
different way so it is a challenge
because if you have all these countries
developing capabilities and they can
actually cause real damage then the
problem is how do you control that how
do you deal with like proliferation of
these these actually these capabilities
that's really hard but part of it is
enormous discussion again if we can
create a generally accepted worldwide
norms that constrain behavior that's
helpful it's not the only whole answer
but that's part of it so every year
since 2011 or 2010 I've been asking the
heads of major Western intelligence
agencies do non-state actors have the
capability to launch damaging
cyberattack say of the equivalence of
Stuxnet or Aramco and every year the
answer has been no but within two or
three years so it's a kind of a rolling
they first said that twenty years ago
actually so right now only states have
the most damaging capabilities the
things to watch are the rate of change
are other states because so Iran has
improved markedly over the period when
we started watching them the rate of
change and then the diffusion so far it
hasn't diffused to non-state actors and
I'm not sure why is that the Russians
keep their guys on a leash is it that
Hezbollah doesn't have the capability
yet but so far it's mainly States and
the question is will that ever change
you know I think
whole but you know the way we think
about conflict and violence really is in
need of close examination we call
conflict and ethnic conflict as if that
tells us why people are killing each
other it doesn't give us any insight
whatsoever
the barriers to entry in terms of
conflict in the real world are
themselves also low the world is awash
in weapons and ammunition it doesn't
take a lot
it takes the intersection of deprivation
and discrimination and you have a
population willing to be led to a fight
now they're gonna riot but they're not
going to engage in a systematic campaign
of slaughter unless they are led and so
the conflict of the scale that we should
worry about is a phenomenon of
leadership and here more than ever we
need some so just a really quick besides
North Korea and Iran all right no you
are out of time thank you very much and
we're going to carry on in the South
Seas H thank you
[Applause]
[Music]