thank you for joining our talk after
lunch hope you have good food and good
time at blackhat my name is Alex we also
have here Mick and Jesse they are from
Eclipse iam doing firm and harder
security as a result of our daily work
we were releasing the research quite
often in this area for them in couple of
recent example so like where is the
system from runner abilities in Super
Micro pretty interesting us and from
updates we releasing the even made
attack without open in the case or use
beauty backup abilities also we release
it like how to apply Spector in our
ability to the system former and special
to the SMM runtime part of the system
for month but today here we want to
present some really new research from us
remote that I can system from man in
this research we will focus on what kind
of new capability system from I have and
what kind of new risk this capability
adds to the system from already stock we
will go over over the list of the remote
vectors as an industry problem with
example from the US research and our own
research done in this area there will go
details about the executive findings
which we have in the system from inner
mode vectors go or exploit having the
demo of the exploit and we will talk a
little bit about mitigations and the
detection capability switch which is we
can apply for this type of problem if
you think about technology stack there
is a bunch of good application running
in a user mode like browsers office and
other applications and then you have the
kernel mode or incurring 0 when you have
the operation system and drivers which
is managed for the resources to provide
the the boot there are the capabilities
to the application and they have a lot
of good security here we have like
internal teams which is validating these
products we have the bug bounty program
we have a bunch of exploit prevention
capabilities like SEFI on our other
capabilities which has recent years who
is
to this to this step 2 the user modern
kernel which is raising the bar for the
attacker for attacker to compromise the
system they Nitin when the remote code
execution then they excape from sandbox
and on local field escalation tie a
bunch of exploits so pretty pretty
complicated work to compromise the
system and pretty expensive so but there
is another part of the technology which
is hardware from server to desktop to to
a network gear ATM machine Adi system so
there is a bunch of card bra and
historically we think about Hardware in
monolithic trusted block but recent
recent decades last decades the
situation is change it harder become
much more complicated so this is the
lower end example of the server a
motherboard which has between 10 10 and
20 different component are called
controllers and these components
communicate which has over the buses
which was designed 20 years ago and that
these components may run a software
called the firmer domain to manage to
management capabilities of this device
of this controller this former can be
from different vendors the components
can be from different vendors it can be
really old and the code was may not be
updated long time this may be compile it
with all compilers which may have a
bunch of which may not have the exploit
prevention capabilities like in some of
the example could build stack executable
some of the example there is no as where
NDP and so and so on in many cases this
framer may not be updatable so if not
update the from and these devices so
this one are vulnerabilities there that
will live forever and there of course
many vulnerabilities and that components
because the code is not updating often
in some cases if it is updatable the
update may not be silent so you
basically can use legitimate interface
to update the firm on that devices and
attacker can do it without any any
problems
and another last point is that in many
of this Fromer there's no read interface
so you cannot make a monetary no you
cannot monitor this device at at the
runtime so that's showing us them
overall the problem about the formula
card for the modern system as a blind
spot as an area when the security
researchers should get more and more
attention and if we're talking about
what kind of hardened former vectors of
attack we have we can split it for two
categories one is which is require
physical access like yo meta tag which
was released in a couple weeks ago and
to demonstrate how what you can do with
five minutes of the access to the
enterprise laptop
so can basically in fact that was there
the stealth implant but there's not the
parts off to attacks and the software
part may may have different vectors
itself like me it might be software
attacks from the person system it may be
sort of attacks or a different
components and so on so forth those come
many examples for them for the reason
for the last years about all of the
software attacks for the system from a
traumatic from other companies as well
but there is also remote attacks and
usually we think about remote attacks
where the format is something which is
not really often because there is not
many network stack implementation there
is not many network interfaces there but
in reality it's not that in reality many
of the formal components has the network
stack here's couple example for example
in Intel meam team has some own
implementation of the network stack
which which has an example of the
vulnerability released in 2013 being
seen being sits itself it's that
component which is responsible for
management capabilities for the servers
which is basically run in entire us with
all the capabilities like OS including
Network step and there was a couple
Vernor ability found in HP and Dell
servers in the BMC and one of them will
be presented and this black hat
or in the recommended to take a look but
this also showing us that there is a
remote vector for the BMC to compromise
service and nowadays for the last couple
years for 2015 we start we start see
that system from also incorporating the
network stack like we have IP DCP HTTP
implementation in the ufi basis from in
the system from energy on a current
limit a reference implementation why we
need these capabilities we need these
capabilities because we want to put our
OS from HTTP for example and there is
another part of them of the remote
remote capabilities remote management
capabilities in the modern part platform
which is vendor specific so think about
this so there is a reference
implementation part which implements
some functionality and there is vendor
specific part which is also may employ
meant additional features and may have
them own tools for that man them own
service and in this talk we will focus
for this vector for the vector for
vector for the system from in a
management functionality of them of the
platform and specifically which is
vendor specific features implemented in
some of the vendors with this I will
switch to to make here to continue this
more details about this vectors Thank
You ax for that review I'm gonna go into
a little bit a further detail into the
overview that Alex went in and we're
gonna start with BMC BMC is is an
acronym stands for base board management
control in case you don't know it is
used in server boards for management
obviously in the picture in the slide
you can see is zoomed in photo from the
previous slide this is the the BMC
complex on the motherboard as you can
see it has its own CPU SRAM and flash
it's an independent computing system
the motherboard it does not require a
CPU or RAM or any other peripheral to to
work from the host the moment you plug
in a power cable it will boot up and it
is from that point on
susceptible for attacks the BMC's are
designed for out-of-band server
management some of the things you can do
with them are KVM which allows you to
VNC over the network to the host which I
need a server and configure bios or
install an operating system by showing
an ISO image to the host or flash the
BIOS remotely power on or off the
platform or even reset it they come in
different flavors of licensing some
though in a paper feature model some go
by tears for example dell idrac have the
basic Express and enterprise tier so you
pay more you get more features in Super
Micro we have paper feature we have an
example we have personal experience with
that when we accidentally brick to one
of our extant servers and we couldn't
physically flash it we didn't succeed
for some electrical reason and we had to
go purchase a license from Super Micro
to go through the BMC and flash a
recovery image that worked from an
attack surface perspective over the
network when you look at the BMC you see
the IP mi the the IP my protocol the VNC
port and the web interface it is very
very hard to scan BMC as it takes a long
time but if you look at a little bit
more detail sorry for the horrible slide
they there's more than network on a BMC
alright we have the land or the NIC
where the BMC shares a network port with
the host or has its own dedicated
network port and the serial connection
the IP MB and the ICMP bridges as well
as other connections going to the host
for example
the system interface between the BMC and
the hosts think about it as two
computers the BMC is one computer the
host is another computer and they
communicate between each other now if I
were an attacker and I would want to hop
from the host to the BMC I would use
this connection usually what happens is
in data centers and enterprises you'd
have the BMC on one network segment and
you have the hosts connected to a
different network server so you have a
management networking on non management
network as an attacker jumping from a
non management network to a management
network is ideal the short history of
IPMI 1998 the IPM I spake out the spec
comes out 2001 it bit it gets its land
editions in 2004 yeah it's a few more
editions with VLAN and firewall and then
we start seeing vulnerabilities if 2013
2014 the of the famous ones are HD more
than a farmer where they scan the
internet and found 300,000 bmc's and 53
thousand of them were vulnerable to
cyber zero authentication bypass and
most recently they vulnerabilities which
i think should win the pony Awards is
the HP ILO for authentication progress
with 29 or 27 days the Mema am team
unlike the previous zoom in picture I
cannot show you the CPU it has a
dedicated CPU it's in there
it says its own SRAM it also shares ram
with the host it steals a little bit and
it loads its code from the main platform
flash if BMC is management for servers
than a Mt AME is management for
enterprise clients think of it as an
equivalent platform in functionality but
not the same physically enterprises use
these to provision systems to allow IT
professionals to install OS s remotely
configure BIOS and hardware and firmware
attack surface from a web perspective if
you look at the open ports AMT has a web
interface we all know the famous
vulnerability from a year and a half ago
will allow you authenticate bypass and
the standard ones VNC in zero over land
and there's all so many features we're
not gonna go into it a little brief
history of that first encounter day we
first encountered AMT in 2006 2007 added
wireless support 2008 provisioning over
the network 2010 remote KVM and 2017 is
when we see the first major
vulnerability a brief recap of that
vulnerability in case you've never heard
of it it was a an authentication bypass
where you could send a an empty digest
to the AMT and he lets you authenticate
and login and there's a few more in 2018
we haven't had event but Intel released
of a month ago advisories explaining
they found few a few more
vulnerabilities that they dispatched
internally which is nice
who the stand tall for disclosing
publicly things they found internally
BIOS ok if you don't know what BIOS is
I'll go briefly over that it is
essentially the early code that
configures the hardware before loading
and transitioning execution to the
operating system what I mean is by
configuring Hardware is it is setting
registers configuring memory memory
protections sitting SMM locking down the
configurations with bits that you write
once to them and after you write once
they're set and you have to power cycle
the platform to change them it also sets
protections on its own flash so no one
other than itself can write and read
from it yeah right to it
read from it it can the code is main CPU
flash main flash around mainframe it's
part of the main up main platform
bass is the cute of trust that
everything that works afterwards relies
on so if you compromise BIOS you win
BIOS in the early days everyone had
their own version in 1998 Intel said
let's that's the other heads together
and do something about it they they
wrote efi 1.0 in 2002 it evolved into a
forum and more and more company started
to adapt it 2007 they added cryptography
network authentication more of that 2015
is interesting more functionality starts
to pop up Wi-Fi Bluetooth support HTTP
HTTP ads in 2016 with the with the
introduction open SSL and in 2016 we we
have a publicly disclosed vulnerability
in the core code which also is called
Tiano core where Topher Timson has
discovered there is a missing size check
in a DHCP packet the interesting fact
about that is there was a check it
wasn't an assert they fixed that let's
look at the the reference implementation
for the you fight 2.4 spec there's an
example you can see that there is a lot
of functionality here for if you want to
do up pixie boots over v4 v ipv4 ipv6 is
cozy as well you see there's TCP UDP IP
for ie6 and DHCP and so on and so forth
on top of that that's what the reference
code gives you as a is a vendors and as
an independent bios vendor or ibv HP in
2015 saw that reference code and decided
ok we need to add more so they based on
that implementation they added their own
implementation for HTTP boot so what you
see in blue is HP's addition in tinted
green is what the reference code offers
and the pink bottom is the harbor layer
this is a perfect example of what
vendors would do when when the reference
code does not fit their needs for the
market they're targeting another example
today for that is am i a dish am eyes
addition for the Bluetooth stack in BIOS
the reference core code does not have
support for it has some support for
Bluetooth nowadays but in 2017 am I
decided to implement their own Bluetooth
stack basically it's Bluetooth in BIOS I
don't know of any use case for this but
it allows you to connect to it before
the OS base we did actually find a Dixie
module module in a production laptop
that is Bluetooth as a memo so it is
used in the wild another great example
for adding to an existing functionality
is ami again where UEFI the reference
code offers a Wi-Fi stack but it's not
complete so they would have open network
connections and wpa2 connections but
they didn't apply EAP so ami came along
and implemented their parallel driver
for the Wi-Fi stack so you get these two
ecosystems one I have to run next to
each other and that's something that is
worth knowing and with that oh so not to
Jesse thanks Mickey so I'll take over a
little bit and this is an example of a
feature that has been added like HP had
their own version of HTTP boot and it
eventually was a similar functionality
pulled into the official UEFI
specification so the UEFI specification
and reference implementation now has
HTTP boot also this was basically done
to replace pixie which was the older
version of remote network boot this
actually allows you to configure a URL
and download a UEFI application that's
run as a boot loader or even like a
complete ISO image over HTTP or HTTPS it
will mount it basically has a ram disk
functionality where it will download the
ISO mount the Ram disk and look for the
UEFI boot loader in this I so that it
downloaded which is kind of cool it does
do signature verification before
executing this UEFI there's there's
basically a policy bits that specify if
a UF application that comes from this
location check signature if it's coming
from an internal thermoball um--
don't bother checking signature but
because it's from a remote source it
does check that signature verification
in order to maintain the secure boot
chain at this point so intelligent
provisioning is kind of an interesting
feature that we ran into this is a
feature in HP servers and it it
essentially is kind of an embedded
system in HP where BIOS can go and
transition into this alternate
environment that it can download
firmware updates can apply the firmware
updates it can actually download drivers
for your hardware from the internet and
inject those into your previously
installed operating system so it all
mount file systems that have already
been installed and inject new drivers
into the system which is it's kind of
cool but makes me a little nervous also
it also has some functionality where
it's kind of like this wizard version of
simple configuration and provisioning of
the operating system so you can
configure a bunch of different devices
use this provisioning capability and
it'll install windows or SUSE Linux or
different operating systems from a
configuration file instead of manually
going through the operating system
insulin
and steps so what one other thing that
we ran into is SMTP from UEFI so this is
a feature that from BIOS it will bring
up the network connection get a dhcp
address and connect to remote email
servers to send email for you in this
particular example it was designed to be
used for a diagnostic tool where you can
report an issue back to the to the bios
vendors a technical support team a
really interesting feature this
particular feature is that they have an
NTFS driver in this bios that this
feature can use that ntfs driver to
mount your hard drive partition you can
browse to any file in the file system
and attach it as an email as long as
it's left for three Meg's and send that
from BIOS before the operating system
ever loads which is it's kind of neat
this this feature and functionality is
there present in the operating in the in
the BIOS so if someone is able to
compromise BIOS all this framework is
there you could take advantage of and
potentially use it maliciously another
feature that we ran into it's pretty
interesting is HP has a remote
diagnostic download function where in
BIOS you can configure this
functionality that will when you reboot
it will bring up the network connection
before it even loads the operating
system go out to a remote server
download and executable from that remote
server in this case it does check the
signature before executing it like the
other like the HTTP boot it basically
does a similar signature verification
check and then executes this executable
that you downloaded off the internet you
can either specify downloading it
officially from HP's website or you can
have your own custom URL where you put
this
diagnostic tool or random signed efi
binary somewhere else on the Internet
and it'll download it from there and run
it there is the ability to take the
results that are take that are output
from this tool and upload it back to a
different website on the Internet you
can specify using a password if it's
behind is something that's like a FTP
server specially protected but that that
functionality is all there in the system
and it's interesting because this one
you can schedule it automatically so
every climate reach so it doesn't run at
run time after the operating system has
run up but every time you reboot it it
will check and see if if it has if
enough time since the last check has
happened so if you have it scheduled
every week and you reboot your system
after a week in half it'll run again
connect to the internet download this
and upload the results somewhere else so
it's kind of an interesting feature and
so another thing that we ran into is
historically BIOS has been kind of
difficult to update so a lot of people
don't update BIOS I got I know I have
been kind of laxed and gotten better at
updating BIOS I started working on this
kind of research but because it's been
such a difficult thing to do multiple
vendors have started adding
functionality so they can basically
check if there's a new BIOS update
available before even loading the
operating system so from BIOS it will
bring up the network connection make
requests out to remote servers on the
internet potentially download those
updates and apply them and there there
isn't a standard way to do this in UEFI
so the different vendors have just all
made their own implementation and
everybody's done it differently so there
might be some problems with that here's
an example of this is what as rocks
implementation looks like it's basically
goes out it connects to the internet and
shows you if there's an update allows
you to update that if a new update is
available
asus has a similar functionality it's
it's basically exactly the same
functionality it just looks different
and it's it's all built on top of those
core UEFI Network primitives like TCP
for Dixie the DHCP primitives but
because all the extra update
functionality is custom it's just
implemented differently HP has a similar
feature where you can basically do the
same thing you can configure your your
update source directly from bio so you
can have it point at hp.com
and this one is interesting because
it'll also you can you can schedule
dynamic it'll automatically download and
apply those updates if a new update is
available and this is kind of a
difference between like this is more of
like a enterprise feature or focused
feature where it's like it'll go do it
for you the other ones were like more
consumer focus where it's like in the
foot the feature is there but it you
can't have to go do it yourself
so we as part of our research we
basically discovered that both asus and
asrock we're doing this in securely and
they had basic buffer overflows in there
their update process so to show this off
we basically wrote a demo to exploit
this and and see what we can do and we
can show what it what that looks like
right now
so as the the tradition is to a Papa
shell when you are exploiting stuff we
figure or a pop calc we figured we might
as well do that so this is like the BIOS
what it looks like we're gonna go and
launch the internet flash function and
and see what it looks like
so this got triggered just by checking
if an update was available we didn't
have to go say okay go apply the update
and actually apply it basically apply
the update it's it's just just checking
is enough to it to trigger this so we
can also have like a bigger payload
that's a little bit more elaborate like
that was a pretty small payload it's not
that interesting but you basically have
complete you can run much bigger code in
your in your exploit so this one is
actually a popping shell instead so like
the this the the shell application isn't
included in this UEFI binary but we can
just include it in our payload and it
takes a little bit longer but you get a
complete interactive shell you can
basically run any arbitrary UEFI
application that you want at this point
you don't have to have any kind of
visual like you you don't have to show
anything on the screen we we did this
just so that you could actually see that
something's happening but you can have
it be completely silent and then inject
something and then continue booting up
if you want to so so once we reported
this as rock was like well oh they
basically provided firmware updates for
all effective systems that just disabled
the functionality and it was almost 300
different motherboard models that were
affected by this basically the last two
generations of Intel processors
basically from Haswell onward and then
AMD processors were also affected but
there's I think three different
generations of AMD using the m4 socket
has rocks response was they basically
said it's this is only happening before
the operating system boots so it doesn't
really matter this isn't a problem and
we went back and forth with them a
little bit and tried to explain no you
actually really should fix this
they didn't seem to understand why so
this actually hasn't been fixed so let's
take a look at what the exploit actually
looks like it's it's a little bit
different so well some things will look
very similar so the way this works is
here's the example of asrock where it
basically does a plain HTTP request out
to the Internet at asrock com2 this live
update a sv page it does include the
specific model of the motherboard that's
running so if you need to return a
different exploit for a particular
motherboard you can totally do that also
but it is plain HTTP and that's it's
possible the man in the middle of that
so let's take a look at what the
response looks like it's basically just
a xml document that has some urls region
information and then a list of what BIOS
updates are actually available and as
you can see like we made our description
like this is a malicious BIOS and if you
actually run this the description shows
up in the in the in the UI and gives you
the ability to go and update that BIOS
but we figured out that if you basically
just make some of these fields much
longer like if we put a bunch of A's in
the URL field when you're checking this
when you're checking for the update it
just hangs and you're wondering what
happened it's like I'm not sure what
happened here but we can take a look at
this and figure out what's happening and
I'll talk a little bit more about how
specifically to figure that out in a
second but first let's take a look at
the Asus one it's it's a very very
similar situation where it's it's also
making plain HTTP requests to a Seuss's
website and this the structure of the
request is slightly different where
instead of a an ASP page with the model
they have a specific path that they're
requesting for this specific motherboard
and here's the response from the server
saying here's your update that's
available for this motherboard in this
case it's not XML it's like XML but a
little bit different and it has similar
issue it's like if you put long strings
and in these fields you get the same
behavior where the update just hangs in
order to figure out what actually
happens
at that point and what actually happened
like in an operating system or
application like applet user mode
applications even kernel mode apps you
have gdb kernel debugging tools when
you're debugging BIOS you don't have
those capabilities yet so you need to
use some hardware debug interfaces
instead if you look at these three
xtp is the really old expensive one old
systems basically had a socket on the
motherboard that was marked sometimes
it's even on the silkscreen of
production system saying CPU XDP or PCH
XDP that you literally had to open the
case plug this into and then you had
this debug capability and you can see
what's going on they've moved to what's
called called a closed chassis adapter
which basically allows you to do debug
through a USB port and figure out what's
going on without opening the case and
there there's also so there's the
clothes chassis adapter and then there's
also just a native debug key USB 3 debug
capability which uses this cable on the
the right here which it's essentially
just a USB 3 a to a cable where the V
bus line has been removed they all like
the the two on the right are essentially
equivalent and you can use those on
systems from skylake and newer all three
of these were made for debugging the
hardware and there they're sold to OEMs
and bios manufacturers so that they can
figure out what's going on when they're
implementing BIOS and bringing up
platforms before they sell them to
customers the two on the left you in
order to get those you can buy those
if you're an external customer but you
need to sign sign up basically get an
account with intel sign an NDA the one
on the right if you have a new a new and
uh platform you can just buy that from
third-party vendors and go go use that
with a newer platform so it's also a lot
cheaper but basically those you can then
use with what's called Intel system
debugger it's part of the Intel system
studio package it essentially gives you
capabilities that are similar to gdb
where you can examine memory you can
look at register state you can look at
CPU structures like the GD T table you
can set breakpoints it's a little bit
cumbersome to use sometimes and also you
run into interesting things like when
since this is basically like JTAG so you
you might need to halt the system enable
your breakpoints your hardware
breakpoints and then go do your tests so
it's there's a little bit more work and
it's not quite as as simple as just
running gdb on a user mode out this
freshing so there's also what's called
the Intel the debug abstraction layer
which is essentially it's part of this
Intel system debugger and an adult
system studio there there's essentially
a framework that you can write Python
scripts in order to go do things and
script your analysis and debugging of
the system so once you get into what's
going on UEFI is a little bit of a
different environment just because
obviously your normal show kill won't
work because there is no operating
system yet like syscalls don't work none
of that framework has been loaded yet
but there are some things that help us
out a lot so first you're running is
ring 0 there there's none of these
protections are present so there's no
address randomization things are at
relatively predictable locations there's
an executable stack it's basically
easy at that point once you know what
your environment looks like there's
there's some other things is that you
don't have operating system like Windows
or Linux or whatever functions yet but
there is something called UEFI boot
services that those are present and you
can call you fi boot services functions
up until the point where exit boot
services is called and the operating
system boot loader is launched so all of
that is still present but you need to
know how UEFI works internally to
actually take advantage of that and how
to use these functions so a pretty key
point of how UEFI works is it's all
built on top of this concept of UEFI
protocols and protocol interfaces and
these are essentially human inter
component mechanisms for communication
it's essentially like an object-oriented
programming class where there's you can
have one piece of code published an
interface using that's identified by
this gooood which is a globally unique
identifier of course and you can you can
basically specify here's an interface
that provides these capabilities and I
want to publish that by a go ahead and
then some completely other different
piece of code says I want to go use that
piece of capability so tell me where
that that capability that protocol is
and then you can look up the protocol by
go ahead and call functions in it it's
it's essentially you look up this object
and then call functions in the object
and it has built-in function pointers
and then it's and private data exactly
like a class so some of the really
critical boot services functions that
are useful are locate protocol that's
the that's the mechanism by which you
can go find some other part of UEFI so
like all of the functionality that we
talked about before with the the network
stack that functionality to send email
the functionality to use the D ntfs
driver to look at your file system all
of that is is published all of those
interfaces
published by doing so your shellcode can
actually just do a locate protocol call
from boot services in order to go find
the gooood for NTFS and then call
functions and that and do some
interesting things some other really key
useful things for our purposes are load
image this is essentially the key
function that's used to load a UEFI
executable in the first place and you
can either specify a device path to a
particular firmware volume or source
that you want to load this if I execute
able from or you can give it a buffered
in memory and a size which is really
nice for what we want to do and start
image basically takes the handle that's
returned from load image and runs it as
an executable and launches yet launches
the executable so putting this all
together our payload layout ends up
looking a little bit like this where we
have a limited amount of size on that
field that we talked about that's
overflowed it turns out that if you have
too many bytes there you cause a pointer
to reference that crashes before you
even get to the return address so you
only have a limited amount of space on
in that overflow on the stack itself but
we found that the entire XML document
that was downloaded from the remote site
is also in memory it's basically sitting
on the heap and we just in our in our
exploit that actually goes on the stack
in the overflow we just have a little
egg hunter shell code to go search for
the heap search the heap to go find the
rest of the exploit and basically jump
there one thing that we ran into though
is that the XML document with the rest
of our exploit is sitting in the heap so
when when it was right before we we hit
the return instruction and returned to
our overflowed return address they
called a free function so our data is on
the heap but it's in no longer allocated
space so if we trigger
allocations it's gonna corrupt our our
buffer that we want to preserve and we
want to execute our malicious code out
of so it turns out that we basically
need to copy ourselves out of the heap
into a different location and then from
there we can call the the load image and
start image functions and basically
provide whatever arbitrary UEFI
applications we want after that we could
we could go use some functionality
that's built into the system we could
bring up network connections we could
use the NTFS driver but we could
basically do whatever we want at this
point
I imagined the NTFS driver a couple of
times and the interesting thing about
that one is that if you've looked at the
hacking team rip kit they actually as
part of the recs way they packaged up
the NTFS driver with their exploit so
that they could use that functionality
to rather than read a file out of the
operating system they would persistently
inject their agent into the operating
system using the NTFS driver and that
was an interesting at UEFI rootkit that
you that you can do essentially that
from this exploit except you don't even
need to bring the NTFS driver with you
because it's already on the system so
what can we do about this there is
there's been some talk in the UEFI forum
about hardening you if I like doing
hardening page in configuration actually
randomizing the stack making it a non
executable sack but none of that have
actually been implemented yet so we're
hoping that this will go in but it's
it's not even in the reference code and
even once it goes into the reference
code it'll take a while before it shows
up in real vendor biases that are being
shipped into production devices so
that's what so we if you are concerned
about detecting this we can we can
detect it with a fairly simple Yara rule
if you have an IDs that can feed your
network data through your aware it's
like we just need to look for our
an extra-long URL field and it's a
pretty simple rule so we can detect the
asrock buffer overflow live on the
network with this Asics one is basically
very similar it's just a different field
so if somebody has already modified your
bios a useful way to detect
modifications to the system after the
fact is you can use the the chipset tool
which is a really useful framework for
exploring hardware interfaces in the
system you can use it to check for known
miss configuration so like there's a
there's a lot of bits and locks and
hardware configuration that needs to be
set properly in order for a system to be
secure once it boots up and we found
many many issues where biases were not
setting everything that they needed to
set or they were setting one part and
not setting it in other places so I
totally recommend trying out chips like
it's also a good frame it's basically
there's a kernel driver to go get the
rep Hardware access then it's all
written in Python so it's really easy to
to build new tests and framework so you
can use it to explore the system you can
also use it to build build exploits and
proof of concept to try things out but
there's basically some built-in
functionality that's been added to chip
sack to be able to extract the spy image
from the running system and then check
it against the whitelist that you've
built previously so if you've if you
think you've been hacked or somebody has
implanted a system in your implanted
your bios made some modification
maliciously maybe somebody managed to
find a runtime vulnerability or there's
a vulnerability and how it sets up the
system so the spy right protection is
not correctly configured and somebody
the a is able to modify that and
they're able you can basically extract
the spy and then check it against the
whitelist you can also generate a
whitelist so like when you buy a new
system if you if you believe it hasn't
been tampered with yet hopefully you
didn't have a supply chain compromised
and along the way but if you think it's
in a known good state you can generate a
whitelist using this second command line
here which will basically parse all of
the firmware volumes generate hashes for
all of the images in the in the EFI
binary and then later maybe once you've
traveled to Vegas with a bunch of other
hackers maybe you think something
happened you can then go go back and
check your generator your you can check
your system against this but this
whitelist that you generated previously
so it's a really useful bit of
functionality so some basic concepts is
the system firmware is really big it's
complex it's highly privileged software
it runs before the operating system
loads also BIOS has about has had a
bunch of issues where it's like it's
been kind of a mess and it's it's
getting better like the update process
it still is a mess it's hard to update a
lot of people don't update BIOS but this
this remote attack surface it's it keeps
showing up in new places and new places
that didn't have a network remote attack
service now suddenly do and part of that
is just because of like trying to fix
the problem of doing system updates in
the first place people are adding new
exploit vectors and adding new
vulnerabilities to the system that
didn't exist in the first place
so I think we've reached our end of a
time so anybody have any questions do
you have a time for questions okay
[Applause]