thank you all for coming I know it is
bright and early on day two of blackhat
which is generally always a challenge so
by the attendance and the audience I'm
guessing that this is probably a hot
topic before I get started the last
three four or five days that this talk
has has kind of made around the social
security ecosystem has been a really
interesting experience for me I found
that the security posture of software
releases is a very sensitive topic that
you know nobody wants to talk about but
unfortunately it's reality you know I'm
gonna try not to break any news to you
but software's flawed every release of
software is flawed and anybody that
tells you that they're releasing
software that is perfect is absolutely
not telling the truth so let's get
started and a little bit about this talk
today and I'm not working here we'll try
this manually all right a little bit
about the team that helped put this talk
together because this is a lot of
information and anybody's put a black
hat talk together knows the amount of
work that goes into it
again I'm Christine Gadsby I have the
pleasure of being the director for the
product security Operations Group at
blackberry I am basically a big group of
defenders so anything that hits the
market as far as a blackberry product or
service goes we have a team of people
that is a centralized organization their
only job in blackberry is just to look
at products and market that offers and
affords us some really unique
opportunities and and one is to
obviously look at the health of software
releases Diane Gooden our Senior
Operations program manager who actually
is in charge of managing this program
right now did a lot of work here we have
our social media Cimarron our social
media specialist and then Tyler towns
who's the manager of the cert did a lot
in this talk too for those of you that
were at blackhat 2016 you may have seen
a talk that Jake Coons and I did on
open-source software security and this
talk is going to springboard a little
bit of off of that Blackberry released
what we call our open source software
maturity model which is really an
introduction on how
you as a company can start looking at
the use of open-source software you know
how do you create some process to
understand it in your organization and
this isn't just from licensing and
compliance perspective this is more on
how do you look at the footprint be
create and the attack surface that you
create by introducing open-source
software into your product verticals
that is actually available in our github
as well which is product security easy
to remember so you can pick up a copy of
that at your leisure
after this talk I want to start a little
bit with a story and I want to thank
Kimberly price who actually had a
conversation with me about this analogy
and it's actually fantastic this is Lucy
this is my dog she's a Woodill she's a
service dog I have a daughter who is
autistic and this is her service dog
that lives in her house every day but
the interesting thing about lucy is she
wasn't free she was actually pretty
expensive but her day to day care is
insane it's something that I was I
wasn't ready for when we got her but
much like open source you know she
requires maintenance you know and what
happens when you don't take care of the
maintenance is this so you know you have
to remember with a dog and anything you
know you got a feeder you got to take
care of her you got to make sure she
doesn't get in the garbage while you're
on a conference call because this is
literally what happened to me last week
I came out after a conference call in
fact I think I was on a conference call
with you guys and walked out to my
Moodle in the garbage so this is just a
really great picture of the fact that
you know using open source in your
products is the same thing really it is
it's a great analogy when you put an
open source library or a free library or
any kind of project into your products
it takes maintenance you can't you know
stick it in there and ship a product and
then think you're done actually it's not
it's much like taking care of a dog you
got to track it you have to understand
you know doesn't need patching you have
to understand is the is it even
supported in the industry those are some
pretty heavy thoughts to take on and at
blackberry what's interesting around
releasing software is we sort of look at
this very black-and-white because we
have the centralized source and we have
the availability to I look at software
releases as the left of the right side
of the screen
if you're watching your software
releases and you know the kind of
software that's shipping and you're
looking at it like you know a I have a
choice I can use this software release
to either a reduce the attack surface in
the attack footprint that I'm shipping
or B increase it or you know if the key
here and understanding this program is
if you're not asking yourself that
question at the time you're shipping
software you need to start asking that
question because that's exactly what
you're doing whether or not you're
actually looking at it or not that's
what you're doing so you're on the left
side of the screen a sort of figure you
you're answering those questions you're
understanding it you're looking at that
liability you know or the opposite on
the right is you're creating liability
and if you're not looking at it you
actually don't know you're creating
liability which is from the last week of
conversations that I've had with people
if you're sitting here thinking you're
in that boat trust me the majority of
people are actually in that boat so why
does blackberry care this is a question
that I get asked all the time blackberry
is in a really really unique space right
we have all these high assurance
customers we've pivoted to be a software
security vendor you know we have
companies within blackberry like qnx who
is deeply buried in the supply chain so
from end to end we have all of these
opportunities where if we aren't
tracking our software releases and we
aren't looking at them as a vehicle to
either reduce or increase attack surface
and if you're playing a drinking game
I'm probably going to say attack surface
a lot but if you're not you know then we
have to be we have to be and you know
why is that important well we've got
hundreds of products we managing market
you know we have hundreds of sources of
threat intelligence that we actually
monitor daily we have thousands of
vulnerabilities we investigate and then
you know many strain relationships if
you think that you will create some kind
of a program in your company where you
are looking at attack surface of
software releases for product teams and
that will not strain relationships think
again because product teams love to ship
software of course they do their job is
to create revenue and if you're going to
come in and point out their baby's ugly
I'd better have a plan for that because
that's a problem let's look a little bit
though of a picture of what a general
sdlc looks like bringing a product to
market right
I look at it kind of as two different
ways of getting a actual secure product
market there's the general you know top
of the slide here that I think what dev
teams think and this is how my product
teams work you know they're looking at
the requirements phase and the design
phase and they're looking at you know
doing the development and intestine and
the testing then you know obviously
they're shipping you know deploying to
market what's really cool when product
security and software security gets
involved at blackberry and I have a
counterpart in my organization Jonathan
I know he's here his whole role in the
company is to look at pre market
software so blackberry is again really
fortunate that we take this extremely
seriously it's you know our heritage and
and how we've gotten to where we are but
Jonathan follows this bottom you know
footprint himself so while the dev teams
are doing the top he's doing the bottom
he's doing threat modeling and design
review he's got secure architecture and
hardening requirements you know static
analysis and a facts for threat modeling
if you didn't catch Adam Shostak stalk
yesterday when the videos come out make
sure and catch that talk out of them is
just definitely a great resource when it
comes to threat modeling but this is
really how everything works in life to
bring you know a product to market
that's secure but the problem that we
have is what happens the day that's
available to the public you go to all
this efforts to bring up this product
and all of these design and requirements
changes and the product it goes to
market and then what I see in the
industry a lot of times is company is
you know like in it you know and they're
they're done that's not it at all again
going back to Lucy my puppy you know she
needs maintenance and so does your
software you have to think about it like
open hunting season the second that
first customer available build is out
there it's out there for everybody
including your attackers so you've got
to watch it because you know if you
think nobody's watching it that's just
not the case so what should you be doing
I think we understand the problem and I
think
again nobody wants to talk about it but
everybody's talking about it so this is
why we put this talk together we want to
help this problem and we want to go off
some of our years we have a program
called the software readiness review
it's about an 8 year old program at
blackberry
oh man has it gone through a lot of a
lot of iterations over the years but
what we're gonna do is we're gonna make
available in our github some of our
templates I'm going to cover so that you
can kind of start to at least have
conversations to look at what it would
like you know to build this program on
your own so but why do it what should we
be doing so mitigating risk on behalf of
your customers is really important
having a software review program is
absolutely the first step in taking
in-depth to start reducing that attack
surface for your customers if you are
shipping a product it doesn't matter
what it is
you are increasing attack surface for
the people that are using that product
we have multiple product versions in
market at the same time it doesn't
matter how many products you have it is
I mean I'm not gonna tell you any news
you don't know you could have three for
18 whatever products in market at the
same time if you fix something how do
you know where your fixes are do you
know that they're in 6 of 18 products
that are actually in market or do you
know if they're in all 18 that's a
question that you should be prepared to
answer that actually leads into
obviously a bigger goal for this program
which is just knowing your security
posture overall this is kind of a
double-edged sword because customers
don't like upgrading we struggle or at
least did for a couple of years talking
through customer demands for patching
blackberry is very vocal about all the
software patching it does it's it's a
huge priority we spend a lot of money on
it
but if you're an enterprise software
vendor it costs you money to take those
patches so on one side customers are
often saying hey patch this you know I'd
like I like a patch every two days well
that's great but then if we give them
updated builds every two days they have
to pay to implement it so then they're
complaining about
about how much it cost so you know it's
a double-edged sword do you want
software patches or do you want cheap
software make up your mind right it is a
tough one and it's a balance having a
software readiness review program allows
you to take a lot of customer feedback
to take a lot of product team knowledge
and put that into a big program where
you can start running data to understand
your cost effectiveness which again
revenue is king so we have to understand
that the last note here for this slide
is the biggest one that's why it's in
blue you have to actually ensure you
have a way to get your security fixes to
your customers it absolutely blows my
mind how many people I talk to you in
the industry and I know I'm not alone in
thinking this we're you know big
business is like oh well we fixed that
two months ago and I'm asking the
question to anybody okay well when did
you ship the fixes because this person
just found the vulnerability as a as a
customer so where's the disconnect
product team's goal is to develop fixes
it isn't necessarily their goal to track
those fixes to market in different
versions so if some product teams do and
some product seems don't but if there's
no security function within your company
tracking that as a standard then you're
gonna be all over the place and you're
really never gonna know your security
posture and market because you're not
gonna know if your product version six
point seven has you know eighteen out of
twenty eight critical patches or not how
I mean if you're gonna let the product
team tell you what they've done are they
keeping track if you think they're
keeping track that's okay but I would
double check and I love this quote and
Tyler on our team came up with this a
fix in the build that is better than two
in their repository and that is that is
certainly true all right so now what so
you know you have to do it how do you
get started great question so number one
first things first you want to go have a
software review program at your company
get support I think most companies in
here are probably doing a quarter of
this already or half of it or
three-quarters of it you're tracking
your software for things like
functionality right
you're taking two products you're
putting in a calendar functionality and
if it fails the build your tracking
stuff like that right so why not have a
security review why not add one more
criteria so start at the top and work
your way down you definitely need to go
to the highest product level whether
it's a senior leadership where it's your
CEO or whoever is going to be
accountable for that make sure you're
getting that buy-in from the top down I
have lots of great ideas as far as
support you can get to do that for your
senior leadership team realize that at
some point some of this is going to be
regulated at some point not today
but realize that well your senior
leadership team may not be paying
attention people in security are and
there are lots of projects going on
right now externally looking at do we
regulate Bill of material transparency
do we regulate understanding open source
software in products that should scare
the living daylights out of everybody
because if you're not ready for
something like that to happen and you
don't have a program like this built
your customers are going to drown you
and that is one of the key pieces of
data to take back to your leadership
team we'll throw some stuff in our
github in order to help with that but
just just know that there's lots of data
out there to support it so anyway get
support most important thing product
leaders need to be on board senior
leaders need to be on board step 2
define what a vulnerability is goodness
gracious this is one of the hottest
things I swear in every company I go to
talk to or people I talked with in our
organization you would be amazed at how
many different definitions there are of
what a vulnerability is on the right
hand side here is is just a simple
picture and this will be available in
our github too you can take this this is
really easy but what I see is something
really easy it never fails I you know
talk to somebody else and in the product
scope and they're scratching their heads
and so it takes some explanation but
basically when you're looking at
software releases you need to look at a
product as in
if it ships to gold candidates a year
the go global you have two opportunities
to go sweep up all that security debt
are you gonna take it or you're gonna
leave it that's one product
so obviously customer counting that's
high liability on that's high if you're
not going to look at that as it an
opportunity to you know increase or
reduce attack surface then you're gonna
let it go out the door and you're not
going to be able to do it again so take
that into account right
Devine the risk based on your customers
partners stakeholders and again that
goes back to the product release another
thing that absolutely must happen in
this once you have support and everybody
agrees that you want to start looking at
this is defining what critical means
this program we have is about eight
years old and I can remember six years
ago or so we couldn't agree what
critical was and because we didn't do
step one we didn't really have support
for the program we just kept changing it
to be more important and I know there's
people in this room that know exactly
what I'm talking about we did
showstopper curtain because it was
critical and we just couldn't get the
critical push through so we changed it
so shop showstopper super bad really bad
bug I don't even remember what all the
names were but because we weren't
getting executive support we just kept
trying to charge when you know we would
see things that weren't patched in order
to get people to pay attention so again
not good but decide what a critical
means decide what a critical means
between your product teams decide what
it means when your security groups
decide what it means and everybody
that's gonna have to look at that that
way there's no arguing right all right
ensure security development are able to
agree on prioritization of that so what
are you gonna prioritize when you do
your software review and you find stuff
it's not patched because you're gonna
you're just you're going to you're gonna
have debt you need to look at it so
decide what's gonna be more important
than something else with your product
teams so that they buy in and then
create standards so this is really
really important step three and we tried
to keep this you know generally easy to
follow again this will all be available
in our github but you know once you
that's support from leadership to use a
software readiness review program you
need to understand that you have to
track each release so this is another
thing you have to add a certain way you
know we use JIRA to track bugs so you
know going into that the third bullet
point it's a really good idea also to
establish you know tags that you can all
understand it's it's difficult to get
product names that are believe it or not
we you know I think every team or
company has a challenge with this but
you know every team within a company
calls a product name different so when
you create tags to tag vulnerabilities
make sure that all everybody knows what
you mean when you say product a even if
it's invaded it has six different names
assign a specific vulnerability name to
it so that when you look at releases you
all know what you're talking about again
that goes between you know the
communication define that risk threshold
I'm not gonna tell you what BlackBerry
does for this you need to make up your
own but everybody should be on the same
page with what the risk threshold is is
it no criticals you defined a critical
so you should all be on the same page
are you gonna be okay with a load of
moderates you have to define now and
then you need to outline an exception
process because at the end of the day
product teams need to ship products I
can tell you it's not worth worrying
about a hotfix it's going to one
customer and dying on a hill over
something that's gonna be you know GC
the next day you have to decide what
that looks like and you need to do it
for so what do we need we need templates
we also need spreadsheets and this guy
he's got some great spreadsheets for us
so here's the first one
available in our github I'm gonna go
over this quickly basically this is a
should we ship it calculator this
calculator assumes that there's a
vulnerability that you've investigated
already this is in addition to cbss
score this is not meant to look at cbss
for this template is awesome because
what it does is it speaks to your
business your business wants to fix
security vulnerabilities they do but
they need to make money
so you have to be able to be in the
middle of that relationship and allow
them to securely release software and if
you're going to establish this program
as a security control and make it
effective you're gonna have to get
together with your business and know how
to speak them speak to them again this
will be available in our github
basically it looks at revenue impacts
for a release looks at what's the ease
of discovery of the vulnerability and
you can see that at the top right there
the base cbss score is actually included
but it looks things like media and
publicity and impact the business and
then in research trends right this is
way more important if it's a 5.2 V cbss
score if it has to do a Spectre meltdown
because it's trending and your business
needs to know the dollar value and how
its assigned so this is a really really
helpful helpful help Bolton template all
right but still it's not that easy and
you need to remember when you're using
some of these templates that there's no
patch Tuesday for open source software
gosh that would be amazing if there was
but there's not right and then you have
things like multi-party disclosure
there's researcher involved this is
there another company involved these are
all things that you have to add onto
that template to help the business
understand what it is you're dealing
with you've got to do things like track
fix commitments so if your product team
tells you they're going to fix the
vulnerability in the next release did
they fix it or did they back out because
it broke functionality and you've still
got a fix you need to push through
you've got to standardize those
processes between all of the business
units but we're always going to have to
escalate because we're always going to
have to escalate so here's another
template we're going to share with you
in our github this is the template
technical escalation we use when we have
a software release where we need to
escalate liability and again we don't
gate software we actually just make sure
that if there's any potential liability
that it's escalated in our github will
also be these instructions with how
you're going to look at filling them out
and then some final things to remember
before we're done here today from 2017
just some stats from our group we we
have a average about 8 Boehner abilities
we investigate per product
instance in our company that's a lot we
looked at 515 security releases last
year that's a lot of security releases
to put this program through so just if
you want some some helpful numbers to
take back with you
discovery and public announcements of
vulnerabilities are unpredictable this
is important for every release every
time no matter what because you don't
know what you're gonna wake up to
tomorrow morning just the nature of the
cert and then focus on making progress
you know your business is trying to make
money you have to remember that the idea
here is to make progress with them to
teach them how to ships you know secure
software reduce attack surface footprint
and ultimately make money just make it
make it securely okay that is it for me
today here's some contact information
you can reach out to me I am C Gatsby of
blackberry comm or you can write to our
BB cert we have a career site where
obviously hiring there's our github
address that'll have all of this
information and also the open-source
maturity model if you want to pull that
down I know I've had a lot of companies
take that and reuse it you're welcome to
use it and then wear a BB cert incident
response team is if you'd like to find
them and I'll be available for questions
in the breakout room
[Applause]
[Music]