hello and welcome strap modeling in 2018
why do you want to listen to me talk
about this maybe some of the reason is
I've done a lot of things around threat
modeling I wrote a book that created a
game I shipped some software out of
Microsoft to help people do this and
people have been asking me since I wrote
that book what's new in threat modeling
since you did that and my answer was
sort of not much not much and then I
started looking at and I said well
there's some changes happening and so I
put this talk together as a way to give
you my perspective and share with you
what I'm seeing is changing in the
practice of threat modeling also about
me I helped create the CVA I'm on the
review board here I'm gonna mention a
lot of products as I go none of this is
intended as criticism it's just intended
to make things concrete and so with that
what people asked me what's changing in
modeling I asked what's changing in the
world and to me threat modeling is a way
of looking at the world and so the
changes in the world
we're reflected in the way that we
threat model and so we've seen really
interesting news stories just this year
there was a death caused by swatting
where someone spoofs a phone number
calls 9-1-1 and says there's a crisis
that this address we saw a self-driving
car impact and kill a pedestrian we've
seen the rollout of GDP our privacy
regulations which actually have a lot of
impact on threat modeling and the
economics of it we get to use phrases
like I got root on the vacuum cleaner
the fellow you see in the bottom middle
is a president Trump no the fellow on
the other side of that is Kim Jung Choi
who the FBI has publicly said was
responsible for the hacking of Sony
Pictures the stuff we do has different
consequence it's bleeding into the world
outside of just exploit
these things matter in different ways
they're used in different ways and then
just a fascinating little story the
Dutch spies broke in to IOT video
cameras in a Russian military facility
and read over the people's shoulders to
figure out what computers they were
hacking into cameras are better than we
expect and we'll talk about that so when
I think about 2018 in a nutshell it's
2018 we need some cat video and what you
see here is a sophisticated attacker
deploying tools against an IOT defensive
system and I'll mention all of the URLs
there's a lot of URLs there's a lot of
references they're all in the speaker
notes and I'll produce a PDF of that
that'll be available later today so you
can find the video you can find the
stuff that I'm talking about so when I
talk about threat modeling I think about
four questions I think about what are we
working on what can go wrong what are we
gonna do about it and did we do a good
job and I created this frame when I was
simplifying things back in 2006 2008 and
it still works well in 2018 and it's
working well enough that I'm actually
gonna use it as a frame for this talk
we're gonna talk about what are we
working on and we're gonna talk about
what can go wrong in the what are we
working on part of this I'm also going
to talk about how we're working on it
because first the fast-moving world of
cyber there are new things happening we
need to threat model them but also the
ways in which we're working are changing
agile has one we need to threat model
actually and I've been talking to a lot
of people about
what models are and why different models
work in different situations and I want
to share some of that with you
from there we'll talk about what can go
wrong we'll talk about stride we'll talk
about machine learning and we'll talk
about conflicts that happen at a higher
level of the stack with that let's talk
about the fast-moving world of cyber
it's really popular to say that
everything is changing so quickly the
world is changing new stuff is happening
every day I mean here it's easy to get
overwhelmed with the new vulnerabilities
the new exploits the new techniques all
the cool stuff that brings you to black
hash if we take a deep breath we slow
down a little bit we model we use models
to help us see the shape of the world to
help us organize the information that's
coming at us the rate of change looks
slower the Morris worm 30 years ago 30
years ago the Morris worm used stack
smashing stack smashing sort of a solved
problem if you're using a modern
platform we've got a SLR we've got depth
we've got all sorts of Defense's that
make it really really challenging to
write a buffer overflow the way we did
20 25 years ago
um the Morris worm used passwords guess
what we're still seeing passwords and
password leaks and password problems
every day but I think the world is
changing fast in one area and that's IOT
there are a lot more sensors and
actuators than there were five years ago
there's a lot more sensors than there
were 10 years ago and a lot of these
things run Linux like it's 1999 it's
awesome you get nob sleds to land your
exploit and again
well it's awesome if you're an attacker
if you're defending not so much but a
lot of these things they look like cars
they look like dog Oh door opening dogs
and the cost is all over the map you
have things like light bulbs you know $5
$10 for an internet-connected light bulb
and you have things like jet engines the
airplane you flew here in was probably
sending telemetry back to its
manufacturer in real time so that they
can schedule maintenance so the plane
has more useful hours you have fewer
delays which also means that your jet
engine might be running Linux like it's
1999 the impact of these things are also
all over the map if you're if your
internet-connected water sensor is down
for a week or a month it might not
matter you might not have a water leak
in that time it'll be okay you can fix
it if on the other hand you have a
problem with a medical device that's
implanted in someone's body well that's
much more impactful much much faster and
so we have these wide ranges of things
to consider as we crack model as we look
at what can go wrong we've got a broad
spectrum a much broader spectrum than we
did even a few years ago and we also
have new attackers and I'll talk about
those newer choppers and later in the
talk and and so all of this means that
the ways to threat model are evolving
and changing in response to the
pressures that they face and I want to
be really specific about the phrase the
ways to threat model are threat modeling
is a collection of techniques that we
bring to bear it's not one monolithic
thing it's different ways different
tools that you can use and so the
tooling that I ship the previous version
of the Microsoft SDL tool is an IDE it
does everything in one place
and in the last year we've seen some
really interesting new tools to domenica
a British company has a service and what
you do is you upload a diagram and they
give you a spreadsheet of threats it's
it's discrete tooling that does one
thing well huh that's a whole different
model and then there's a company and
continue Arius risk I'm on their
advisory boards disclaimer there but I'm
there because they're doing interesting
things about scaling threat models
across lots and lots of enterprise
applications there are much smaller
threat models they're much faster and
all of this is the ways that trap models
are evolving and our tooling and ability
to engage with those changes is evolving
I think it proaches I believe strides
still works well I'll talk about it more
I think the kill chain approaches are
really coming into their own as grant
model and tools and I'll talk about how
to do that but I want I want you to
think about threat modeling there's four
questions as building blocks what are we
working on we have a set of
interchangeable blocks we can use what
can go wrong we have a set of
interchangeable not quite
interchangeable but we have a set of
ways of answering that question that we
can use in the right circumstance and
when you think about it it helps you
adjust what you're doing in your threat
modeling activity choose changes you
don't need a whole brand new strat model
and approach because of IO Ching you
need to make some changes you don't need
to have a whole brand new threat model
and approach because your company is now
doing everything in an agile way you
need to adjust the building block so
you're using a little bitch and so
brings us to agile and frankly agile has
won and that's a fine thing and when I
think about trap model and people often
say but the way you talk about modeling
is waterfalling
okay yes it is a little waterfall II
because it's easier to conceptualize
when we model development as a waterfall
then when we think about these
interlocking agile cycles or fast C icd
cycles but the thing that I believe very
deeply is that the right modeling is no
more inherently waterfall II or agile
than Ruby you can use Ruby in a
waterfall process you can use Ruby in an
agile process same thing for scribe
modeling and so when you do this you in
the waterfall world versus the agile
world the skills the techniques the
tools that you use are super similar
they can be the same the scope is very
very different the deliverables are very
very different and so you can bring
these skills that you've acquired
however you learn to threat model and
when I think about agile when I think
about these four questions there's a
little bit there's a lot on this slide
and the reason there's a lot on this
slide is I wanted you to be able to take
it in at a glance so down down the left
column are the four questions system
model what are we working on that's what
can go wrong fixes what are we going to
do about it quality and test did we do a
good job and so when I think about
threat modeling something like Windows
or a big travel site or a big social
networking site there's a you can take
it all and say wow this is this big
complex thing and that's the waterfall
approach and you can say what are we
working on in this sprint in the agile
world you can just say what are we
working on in this sprint let's not
model that maybe it's complicated it's
something that crosses over a trust
boundary in some new way maybe it's
something very simple more
building a new recommendation engine and
so it's taking in the same data it's
it's emitting the same sorts of
recommendation structures that's a very
simple track model but will scope it
down to what we're working on and I'll
talk about security debt in a minute we
find threats the same sort of way we
find the threats using stride using kill
chain whatever the techniques are and
our fixes go from we're writing test
plans and mitigations she we might have
a security acceptance criteria for the
release we might have some controls that
go into the backlog don't you have to
fit into that particular release and so
doing making the shift is a shift of
scoping and a shift of deliverables and
a lot of people ask me but Adam I'm
starting out threat modeling I need a
big system diagram I need to understand
how everything comes together right well
it's hard to get there it's hard to
convince people in an agile world that
they should stop and create this big map
of everything I see you agree with me a
little bit there so what you can do is
just start with whatever the team is
working on do some very simple threat
modeling around that demonstrate some
value and over time the people will say
oh yeah and this component over here has
this problem good you notice that let's
will accumulate that knowledge we'll put
it in the backlog and over time the act
of creating an all up system diagram
might be the sort of refactoring or bid
complex work that gets its own sprint
but we actually have an advantage it's
an important advantage which is 2018
involved GDP are coming along
and gdpr says you need to know where
your data is going for European privacy
regulators Oh someone else did all the
work
to find out where all your data flows
are you should become their new best
friend because they've moved from being
a project office get ready for gdpr
to a program office that has to go and
bug the developers every quarter to say
what new data flows have you added oh
well maybe you and the GDP our folks can
team up and keep those diagrams that
they created up to date you can use them
for broader analysis of what can go
wrong and you can develop deeper threat
modeling so I want to I want shift
topics a little bit and evil Gayle
Perrin of the e FF tweeted something
this spring she said our models scary
mm-hmm and then I British academic I
know was talking to me and he said yeah
I've been doing SDL usability studies
and I was rolling this out and someone
said to me you know the thing your
questionnaire doesn't capture is this
modeling thing is just scary it's like
huh well that's interesting it keeps
this mean keeps coming along and the
first thing I want to say is we should
absolutely respect the concern I don't
want to say just deal with it
look I created a game to help people
threat model I think it should be easier
um but some things are a little
challenging and also people not all the
time
we use models you're coming to a
conference you didn't figure out the
path from your hotel room to this room
in advance you have a model I've got a
run there's a convention center I'll
walk between it you're abstracting away
important details that you had to know
about we're good at modeling many things
but in a world where we generate code
automatically it's scary to ask people
to do things that work
our thought it's scary to ask them to do
things we're figuring out what is right
and what is wrong is not obvious and so
yeah models are scary and I have a
little quiz for you we've got two models
of a car here there's a model of a lego
car who thinks the model of the lego car
is a better model they've got a few
hands who thinks the Hot Wheels model is
a better model get a few hands again
many of you are not committed many of
you might think that this is a trap of
some form I don't know what you'd think
I would put you in a trap of some form
but the answer is you're all right
the Lego model is more fun to build you
can reuse the parts in interesting ways
and it's lower fidelity right the Hot
Wheels model is more resilient when a
four-year-old steps on it or throws it
across the room it shows the curves of
the car more accurately and so models
are useful depending on what you want to
get out of them there is no best model
and statistician George box like to say
that all models are wrong and some
models are useful and I find myself
quoting him about once a day because
this this is just a really deep truth
all models the nature of a model is you
eliminate details so that you have
something that's easier to construct or
work with and therefore it is by
definition wrong we should judge models
on usefulness and one of the places that
models are useful and I'm borrowing here
from John ospa who is the CTO at Etsy
he's got a great blog where he talks
about the practice of engineering and he
talks about the difference between
dialogue and discussion
and a dialogue is when we have a back
and forth like a platonic dialogue we
together are searching out the truth
there's and we're learning from one
another and that exploration that what
if that prototyping precedes the act of
making a decision and a decision is
saying we're going to do this not that
and models play into this right a
whiteboard model is great for what if it
is great in dialogue and as engineering
project moves from brainstorming to
delivery to production it goes through
phases and in the beginning we have
dialogue where we have pictures on a
whiteboard we're talking on slack and
maybe even still email if you're
old-fashioned at some point someone says
hey we'll write a specification for this
and the diagram moves it goes from the
whiteboard into Visio or into
OmniGraffle or whatever it is you're
using and maybe if this is a spec a lot
of people are gonna read it gets put
into Photoshop so it gets really pretty
each of these involves energy each of
these involves work and if there's one
thing that I get from the actual people
I collaborate with it's that they love
eliminating work from their programs and
so we can ask ourselves which of this
work is important for which pieces of
the things that we're working on in
which projects and the answers can be
different that's okay the ways to threat
model are we can do more than one thing
and we can do the thing that's
appropriate for our project if all we
want is a dialogue about a bunch of
possibilities we go to the whiteboard we
have a conversation we discover that one
has more good properties than others we
take a note we take picture we're done
now
um the the other thing to say here is
it's pretty common for people that I
work with to say hey can you bring me a
diagram before we have a crack model
meeting and you know what you're
actually saying I don't want to have a
dialogue with you I want to sign off on
your work because by the time they're
ready to bring that diagram to you and
have it reviewed they're done making
decisions they want your acceptance of
their decisions not your engagement and
so that question perfectly innocent and
one I've asked a thousand times turns
out to have real implications for the
ways in which we collaborate with the
teams around us so we have talked about
the change in world agile and models and
from here I want to shift our attention
to the question of what can go wrong and
what can go wrong is at the heart of
threat modeling it's the hardest part in
many ways to find systemic structured
comprehensive ways to predict what will
break in a system before you've even
built it that's why we do this work
that's what makes it powerful and that's
also what makes it difficult because
predictions are heard especially about
the future and so I want to talk about
stride I want to talk about adversarial
machine learning I want to talk about
the use of kill chain and can you kill
my mic for one second I need to cough I
don't want to kill everyone's
sorry about that I'm hearing the volume
here and you you don't need the the what
can go wrong is not a deaf in you and so
I want to talk about operations and I
want to talk about conflict so stride if
you're not familiar with strident sense
moving tampering repudiation information
disclosure in Ohio service and elevation
of privilege it is a model of what can
go wrong it's a wit it seemed a monic it
is not a good taxonomy you'll hear it
referred to as a classification or
categorization if you use it that way
you're making work for yourself
you found the threat move to the next
problem but when you're looking across a
system it's a helpful mnemonic and
there's a lot of new things happening
that fit into the system well and so we
can think about them and also its 2018 I
get to use emoji in my slides so there's
a variant of stride called stride
lateral movement and everything you need
to know is in the emoji no no actually
I'll talk about it just just a little
bit and how I feel about it so the
essence stride scent stands for spoofing
and I want to talk about three areas of
spoofing which are new the first is
phone authentication there's markets for
selfies which i think is an interesting
development and i want to talk about
audio video spoofing so first nist has
deprecated the use of SMS for
authentication if you rely on text
messages for authentication doing
something that a national standards body
has said is no longer acceptable might
create problems for you when lawyers
show up I'm not a lawyer I don't want to
make a prediction but you should be
aware that NIST is saying stop doing
that so important attacks where I call
up and I say hey I'd like to move your
cell phone for
AT&T to t-mobile or vice-versa why do I
do this because all of your bitcoins are
stored in a way that's protected with
two-factor authentication and so
stealing your phone number allows me to
steal all of your cryptocurrency that's
the only cryptocurrency thing I'm gonna
say in this talk I apologize if you're
here for that and lastly I see your eyes
and scam Acree and scanner crea is a
term for a legitimate company mimicking
a scammer where they do something that
is indistinguishable from the behavior
of a scammer your bank calls you and
says hi this is your bank I need your
social security number and you say how
do I know you're not a scammer and they
say well look at your caller ID know the
right answer is let me call you back at
the number on the back of my card and
teach people that that's what they
should be doing because that's way safer
accepts the above about phone hoarding
attacks so markets for selfies and
facial recognition in general so in
April 2016 or so MasterCard announced
pay with a selfie woohoo cool and in
March of 2018 sixgill in Israeli cyber
intelligence company announced that they
were finding selfies in dark web falls
the collection of information that you
buy to break into someone's bank account
so the other thing up here is this hash
and if you look carefully at this hash
there's my laser there are little LEDs
here and these are infrared LEDs and
what they are doing is shining bright
light on the face of the person wearing
the hash so that it fools facial
recognition systems into authenticating
them as someone else the the attacks on
biometrics are getting really
interesting I I wish more people from
the biometrics world would
talk to the threat modeling world I
think that would be a useful thing so
there's also spoofing of audio there's a
whole field called voice cloning
so I'll set of companies up there that I
found poking around at this and so if
you have like when I call my bank it's
awesome now I don't have to give them my
password because they listen to my voice
and they run a biometric in the
background to determine if I'm a I don't
know how well that works against voice
cloning I hope they do and you can even
think about who saw the video of Google
duplex the the Google thing that was
making a phone call and making an
appointment with your haircut for a
haircut so some of you saw this really
interesting video and when I add voice
cloning into that so that now you get a
call from the CEO saying hey Alice I
need you to pay this vendor 50 thousand
bucks and it sounds just like the CEO
Wow BC is going to become really
interesting or you get a call from your
significant other and they're like hey
honey the Netflix isn't working what's
the password
and because passwords have always been
with us and always will be you use the
same password for Netflix in your bank
right and that's pretty nervous laughter
so when your sweetie calls you and says
I need the Netflix password you give it
to them because we're used to using
biometrics we're used to using these
human factors as ways to authenticate
people now there's also the spoofing of
video and this is this is really scary
stuff it's really disturbing stuff as
well and I recommend girding yourself if
you choose to search for it because a
lot of the ways in which it's used are
to put people into adult video they
didn't participate in and that's really
horrific for the people who are put into
those videos but you can create these
new videos using machine learning and I
was able to find a sick worksafe example
which I wanted to share with you here so
you can see how it we're entering an era
in which our enemies can make it look
like anyone is saying anything at any
point in time even if they would never
say those things so for instance they
could have me say things like no kill
monger was right or Ben Carson is in the
centum place or how about the simply
President Trump is a total and complete
you see I would never say these
things at least not in the public
address but someone else will someone
like Jordan Peele and notice the
gestures and movements are different
moving forward we need to be more
vigilant with what we trust from the
internet that's a time when we need to
rely on trusted news sources and they
sound basic but how we move forward the
age of information is gonna be the
difference between whether we survive or
whether we become some kind of up
fist over thank you
stay wolf bitches
[Music]
[Applause]
so in this particular instance they used
a voice actor rather than a voice
cloning service as they put this
together but you can see this becoming
commonplace the technology is available
to create these it's only going to get
faster and better and so when we start
to think you know I was opening a new
bank account for my business and that
part of the process was a short video
column which I displayed my idea it was
sort of cool I don't think they've seen
this video we're sorry
no more Jordan Peele or President Obama
so so tamp moving from spoofing to
tampering Roy D'Souza who's a colleague
who I used to work with is now with an
IOT company and he he was encountering
an issue where his colleagues would say
but our devices are in people's homes
they're not subject to attack and he
created the term Airbnb attacker as a
way to say these devices are in people's
homes that they rent out to other people
who they don't know who stay there for a
week at a time and so that's an
interesting way to get people to think
about tampering with devices in a new
way there's also this tap lock which is
a new chief fingerprint e IOT walk which
as it turns out has an exposed point
which you can put a screwdriver into and
unlock it attacks get better but it's
important to remember the traditional
ones I'm gonna skip repudiation for now
information disclosure first location
location location some of you may
remember in January there was a fitness
tracking company
and as it turns out it's fitness
tracking map its fitness tracking tools
we're being used by Special Forces all
over the world from Western militaries
and you could go to their website and
see maps of where these people were
running in places where there's
officially no military base or presence
and and so that was bad but that was
January and then earlier this month
another equipment company had the same
problem now as a fan of that model and I
believe very deeply that the best time
to fix a problem is before you ship the
product but the second best time to fix
a problem is when your competitor is on
the front page of the New York Times for
a problem that you two have and you can
go to your CEO and say there but for the
grace of God go away now they didn't do
these things and two days ago the
Department of Defense announced a ban on
the use of GPS enabled fitness monitors
in operational areas it's a very broad
ban and again the link is in there it
was surprising to me but the worst time
to fix the problem is after the DoD has
banned a large chunk of your customers
from using your devices the best time
just as a reminder is by threat modeling
and finding it before these problems
have occurred so location is fun but
there are lots of sensors and mobile
phones are driving the cost of sensors
down and the quality of sensors up in
amazing and unintuitive ways there was
an attack a couple years ago where the
accelerometers in Android reveal your
password to any app on your phone
because as you move just a little bit
the accelerometer
not sensitive unexpected cameras take
pictures that are way better than people
expect and so we see pictures of
documents that shouldn't be public
because people don't expect the camera
to blow up the picture to blow up that
way if the lens is far away you're safe
no you're not all of this needs to
exciting new information disclosure and
so tracking data flows from those
sensors to wherever the data is going
becomes more and more important
so denial of service denial of service
traditionally was about compute storage
and bandwidth it's now also about money
the $500 cloud security screw-up another
black hat speaker who I like very much
blogged about this and said someone
broke into my AWS account and used it
for cryptocurrency mining five hundred
dollars later Amazon had spent the money
that he had authorized and fortunately
Amazon gave him the money back but
that's not guaranteed money is now a
target for denial of service and so is
battery people want to be able to set up
a wireless security camera and so
there's competent these things are
insane two years on a pair of double-a
batteries for a Wi-Fi connected camera
that's doing JPEG encoding that's really
nice engineering really but there are
denial of service attacks that are
intended to degree in the battery which
is annoying when it's your security
camera and it's really really really
annoying when it's your pacemaker
so elevation of privilege last year or
so there have been a lot of isolation
breaks that make it easier to elevate
privilege for
one jillion to another from one part of
a system to another and we're gonna see
more of these but there's also if she's
in the IOT world there was a very again
disturbing article in The New York Times
about use of Internet connected devices
by former intimate partners who had been
kicked out and it's easy to say oh they
should just reconfigure the device I
want to tell you a personal story I was
using an email account I don't use very
much
I discovered that at BCC to another
email account this was on my Mac I used
to be a systems admin person I know how
to debug things I could not figure out
where that BCC was defined in 30 minutes
of trying these systems are complex
there's lots of places in which
configuration information is stored and
so we have to think about privileges in
new sorts of ways so in the interests of
time I'm actually gonna skip I'm gonna
say not a fan of lateral movement I
think it's an extension of spoofing but
if it's gonna help you go ahead and use
it I'm gonna talk very so the kill chain
as an alternative to stride I see lots
of people using various kill chain types
to help them think about operational
security in new ways I like it there's a
guy in the Netherlands created a unified
model meta model for the kill chain that
allows you to pick and choose between
variants and find ones that work for you
there's a there's a new field emerging
called adversarial machine learning and
this allows you to bend other people's
machine learning to your goals or just
to break it there's a lot of interesting
things happening here but fundamentally
I want you to remember that machine
learning is code it's complex code that
you don't understand
more code more bugs more complexity more
bubs less understanding more bugs do you
see where this leads there's a top
tomorrow if you want to see more on
adversarial machine learning and so I'm
skimming ahead because I want to talk
about conflict I want to talk about
moving above the thinking about just
exploits to thinking about conflict and
as an example of this this is an
interstitial that Yelp showed about the
redhead restaurant you may remember
there was a kerfuffle in the news they
kicked out the White House press
secretary and what Yelp did was they put
up this page that says hey we don't take
a stand on this but review reviews
should be about the restaurant not about
the news okay that's fine that's what
they did and I want you to notice that
there are several oh the other thing
they did is they said we will review all
of the new reviews and get rid of a lot
of them I want you to notice that there
are two important technical decisions
that they made the first is they put up
this page someone had to spec the code
someone had to write the code someone
had to write the text there they
internationalized it probably into a lot
of different locales they did
engineering work in response to the use
of their platform in this social
conflict the other decision they made is
to put these things into review rather
than just locking the review for some
number of days right lock it for
something between 10 and 15 days don't
tell people so they can't put a calendar
reminder most of them will have
forgotten before they come back to write
the main review or the glowing review
you can make technical choices about
what to do in these situations and so we
can think about applying the for
question frame what are we working on
some system that has user-generated
content
as social content what can go wrong all
sorts of conflict trolling death threats
that we've all seen these things what
are we gonna do about it our intuitive
fixes don't work as well as we'd like
and did we do a good job well we've got
another emoji here and so a bunch of
people have been doing really
interesting to work on extending threat
modeling choo conflict
Shareen Mitchell and John Pincus have
some attack trees I'll show you in a
second Amanda Lewandowski built a tool
called sculpt that's an explicit analog
to stride so that we can start thinking
about these as problems that we can
engineer around or we can engineer in
excuse me and so we've got an attack
tree this is bye bye John and Shireen
and if we want to harass a person we can
trigger them we can flood them we can
make them look bad this looks like the
same sort of thing we do with other
threats we can learn to work in this
space in this way what to do the obvious
fixes fail turns out that real name
policies make trolls more virulent oops
but there are successes next door is a
social network for is a social network
for neighborhoods they had a problem
with people using a lot of racially
profile language that seemed to be
racial profiling in their posts and they
said that's bad they didn't like it
there was a media cycle there was
another media cycle so what did they do
they did what agile teams do these
ginned up a bunch of things and they did
a B tests and then they evolved them and
they did some more a/b testing and when
they were done they found that they had
reduced racial profiling in their posts
by 75%
that's good is it great no we'd all like
to see them do better but they're using
the tools of software engineering to
address these problems so what do we do
the fixes are less obvious we really
need expertise in human behavior we need
sociologists we need anthropologists we
need people who frankly are better than
we as engineers that's a weird sentence
we as engineers are not very good at the
human side of things a lot of times we
need people who focus on that there are
smart people who have useful things to
contribute to this conversation along
with us and I believe that we need a
catalog of effective design patterns
so to summarize tried instances are
evolving there's new and interesting
variants adversarial machine learning is
fun and it's going to get way more fun
for the attackers and way less fun for
you and conflict is really looming over
us I really see the conflict end of this
being what I'm going to be talking about
a lot in the next couple of years so a
few key takeaways for the talk overall
first the fundamentals of threat
modeling remain important and effective
second the details of what we're working
on how we're working on them and the
threats all of these things are changing
lastly conflict again conflict modeling
is going to be big I'd like to say thank
you very much I also want to mention
since you are here there is an
increasingly active threat modeling
community on the OWASP slack Channel be
great if all of you could join us if
you're interested in this please please
do I am actually approximately out of
time and so rather than taking questions
here I'm just gonna say thank you
so much for your time and attention and
happy to take questions afterwards
[Applause]