before we get started if everybody could
please raise your hand either hand works
all right come on let's go all right so
anyone who didn't follow the seeding
instructions please lower your hand all
right all right still looking pretty
even I would say between people who know
web and people who know native so that
means as we go through this yeah put
your hands down please
we'll probably give a little bit of
remedial education on both sides of the
house just so people who only know web
aren't lost when we're talking about see
stuff people will only know see aren't
lost when they're talking about web
stuff so I apologize if any of this is
review for you all right so I'm Justin
this is Tyler we're here to talk about
web assembly so our talk today is not
about how to like break out of the
browser and web assembly or use web
assembly type bugs to end up exploiting
things in the browser that talk was
Natalie's talk and if you're interested
in that you should go see it three hours
ago it was a really great talk and maybe
you can catch the recording of it later
but we're only going to talk about the
application security side of that so if
you are a web developer who is trying to
implement some new web assembly things
into your existing web site what kinds
of security problems could you cause and
you need to worry about as an attacker
when you're looking at a web page that
includes web assembly what can we use
that for from an attack perspective so
that's what we're looking at in this
talk so in order to do that we have to
talk about how web assembly works and
some other kind of introductory tooling
stuff so you can understand later on
when we go into the different exploits
what's actually happening under the hood
so if you saw a Natalie's talk this
morning that part will be review but
then the other stuff should be pretty
fresh at the same time so in short what
wasum does is it allows you to take code
written something else we're gonna only
talk about C code here but you could do
anything compile it and then take that
binary and run it in your browser what
that gives you for one you didn't have
to rewrite that code in JavaScript and
two it's much faster than new
the same thing in JavaScript so you can
see here web assembly on the Left
getting 30 frames per second at face
recognition JavaScript on the right
getting 2 frames per second so much
faster there's a lot of different things
that it's being used for right now I'm
only going to highlight a couple of
these right now the archive.org has this
really cool thing where you can go play
old console games and old arcade games
on their web page they do this by they
didn't like a rewrite and assembler or
re-implement the games in JavaScript
instead they used web assembly to
compile an existing emulator that
already knew how to emulate those games
throw a little bit of wrapper code
around it probably more than a little
bit to handle the display and control
some such and then they can run all
these games that already had previous
emulators other thing here that's going
to be interesting to this audience is
there already been scene crypto miners
in the wild that have been using
webassembly because it's much faster so
you can mine more coins webassembly
isn't just about the web though there's
lots of really crazy things that are
kind of up and coming everything on this
is kind of very early stages or
experimental but it's important that you
know that there's a lot more that's
going to be happening soon so brow 6 is
essentially implementing all of classics
in web assembly so if you had a Linux
program you would be able to run it in
web assembly and have all the things
like files and stuff work in the browser
jeaious Linux takes that one step
further and actually emulates an entire
operating system in the browser so if
you want to run a copy of a recent Linux
or something like Windows 2000 you can
run it in your browser and it runs all
with wasm runtime j/s going in a
different direction is a microkernel so
the idea is instead of running a whole
OS somewhere you would just run this
thing and all it has in it is node and
wasm so then you know you can drop the
whole OS and just concentrate on running
stuff but that also means that it's all
running and ring zero right because it's
all its own curl nebula is very similar
except without the node so we're just
going to run wasm straight-up ring zero
as its own kernel
service is very interesting so instead
of trying to start a new OS they're
going to allow you to run web assembly
things that hook into your Linux kernel
so then you can directly access memory
and stuff in there that's very fast
sounds like a great idea mmm
crane lift is actually going in Reverse
so you can take a Wazz 'im program the
compiled binary and then turn around and
turn it into a real machine binary that
would run on like x86 or arm and lastly
in probably the most useful of all of
these is V wasm so aetherium is a
cryptocurrency that has its own language
and so the idea is that you can compile
things with this language and then they
run on the blockchain with all the stuff
it's pretty interesting except that
solidity is terrible and the EVM is
terrible so they're working on switching
it to running wasm instead so then you
can write your your smart contracts in
whatever language you want and then they
run in wasm on the blockchain cool stuff
so any of you who have been around
computing since about 2001 or so may
remember that we used to claim that like
there's these cool things called Java
applets and they're sandbox and they run
in the virtual machine and they run in
your browser you can write them one so
you can run them anywhere and you can
put them in other things besides
browsers like this is all the stuff that
a Java applet claimed to do 20 years ago
and now we're doing it again I really
wonder if there was an folks knew that
they were reimplemented stuff or if they
are surprised that this is actually
happening all right onto what web
assembly actually is it really probably
should have been called something else
like web bytecode or something there's a
virtual machine so don't think about
like VMware more like a JVM so a special
purpose machine that doesn't really
exist but we're gonna emulate that
machine and it has a very specific set
of instructions it's a very small set
and then there's a binary format that's
the instructions for this machine are in
and we have compilers that can compile
it can target that new virtual machine
so then you can have code that was
written in other things
and compile it to webassembly where it
will run way faster than javascript it's
already in pretty much every browser
that people use on a regular basis but
as we talked about earlier there's no
reason we can't take wisdom and put it
in other things as well let's talk a
little bit about the mechanics of wasm
so we have instructions they live in
their own spot these are the machine
code essentially for wasm and the
machine that runs wasm doesn't have any
registers so instead of registers we
have the stack you don't think of the C
stack that's totally separate and has to
happen later this is the stack within
web assembly and it replaces registers
so the idea is that every operation will
push or pop its values to from the stack
here's a very simple example so first
line it module means this is a program
and the next line line - we are
declaring a function called add we give
it two parameters x and y and we're
saying it's going to return a value all
those are 32-bit in the line three we
say get local X what that does is take
the value of X and push it onto the
stack get local Y push it onto the stack
and then I 32 ad is gonna pop two values
from the stack because add pop you know
add takes two operands and then push
back the the value of that addition onto
the stack and the last line here is
export what that means is that this add
function will now be available to
whatever it is that's embedding your
your wasm system so in most cases your
browser or JavaScript and web assembly
doesn't have access to your computer's
memory it has its own memory that gets
emulated this is called linear memory
it's just in its it's hosting could
implement this however it wants but from
web assemblies point of view it's an
array of bytes integers whatever you
want and it can put things in there and
take them out in random access that's
all I can do with it
there's no way that you can see the real
address that something's living in from
the webassembly side you just know about
the the values that are there in their
indexes in that array everything in
there is untight so the other piece of
the puzzle here there's a few things
that maybe will become clear if you're
well into the sea world for starters
since webassembly runs in its own space
so it's not like say x86 and arm where
your instructions are interleaved with
your data in the means in the machines
memory instead as a separate Bank of
memory for instructions and a separate
Bank of memory for memory of reading
data so there's no way that we can have
like a pointer that goes to an
instruction but we write C programs like
that all the time and so we need a way
to implement that in webassembly they
didn't made this thing called a function
table so all a function table is is you
can declare hey I'm gonna want an
indirect call to a function somewhere
and then that goes in the table the
table just has numerical indexes and
then later on you can say okay I want to
jump to function number decide to set
run time and then later it goes look set
up and does that let's take a look at
that in code and if you can't read this
in the back I'm gonna walk through it
not necessarily you don't need to really
understand this to get to the rest of
our talk but it is important so again we
have a module we're going to declare a
type of type function with a result so
what we've done here is we've said we're
going to have function pointers and they
are going to return and answer they're
not gonna have any other parameters then
we're going to make this table table to
any function says we're gonna make a
table that has size two and an element F
1 and F 2 on line four says we're going
to add two new entries to this table
they're called F 1 and F 2 on line 6
we're going to declare what F 1 actually
is and note that it has the same
signature that we talked about before it
turns an end that's all it does in this
case we're just returning a number same
with f2 here we're gonna actually call
something so this is a function we are
taking one parameter and returning one
thing and in here we're gonna say get
local I so get the value of the
parameter pushes on the stack and then
call indirect some type so now calling
direct is gonna pop the thing off the
stack that we just pushed which is the
value in the parameter and then it's
going to go look up in the function
table where which function is that and
then go and actually call it so just
another way to show that so when you use
calling direct it's gonna pull something
off the stack go look up the add the
value in the stack of the function table
the function table knows the address of
the actual thing that's going to call
and that's what makes the call so
everything we've talked about before
this has just been about wazzing we
haven't talked about the browser at all
so we need to talk a little bit about
what weighs amines while it's living in
the browser wasm can't talk to the dom
plasm can't read your memory it can't
write to the screen it can't do anything
on its own can't it's totally sandbox
off from all that stuff if you want wasm
to do anything other than spin your cpu
you have to declare some imports or some
exports you can the most obvious example
this is functions so we declared export
for the add function and then that meant
that javascript could call that add
function and it would run the wasm and
then return the value back to javascript
you can also import an export the memory
javascript is able to to look at the
linear memory and you can also share
that Leonard linear memory across
multiple running instances of wasm if
you want to and the tables can also be
shared across multiple instances of
Azzam if you want to this means that you
can do things like kind of a
multi-threading thing where you've got a
web worker running something and another
web worker running another thing they
can share memory if you need to they can
share libraries if you need to by by
sharing a function table so on in script
in is I guess a tool chain or an SDK
and it's point is to create waves and
binaries for you out of other things and
we're going to talk about C and C++ it's
built on LLVM and clang it includes all
your expected built in c libraries and
it also makes it really easy to
integrate your wasm that you've just
produced into a webpage by automatically
generating javascript and HTML for you
that will handle the glue code that
helps the the two pieces communicate
there's a whole bunch of other things in
this script and ads as well but the only
things that we're going to talk about
here are these two things called EMA SM
and in script and run script those are
both two different ways they're slightly
different but the idea is that you can
use those to run arbitrary JavaScript
from inside wasm that's going to be
really important later for some of the
tricks we're going to do if you want to
know more about in scripting Azzam since
Natalie's talk is over and you can't go
see that anymore you can go read the
spec you could also this PDF here is
does a really good job of like if you're
a reverser and you want to know like the
nuts and bolts of how the binary format
works it does a great job of running
through what a webassembly binary looks
like and how it all works
I wish I had that PDF before we started
doing this research so we're gonna talk
about old exploits and I have a lot of
choice vintage well-tested memes to go
along with these slides so we think that
a format string attack will work just
fine for the web people who don't know
see I have to cover what a formatting
attack is so there are a family of
functions in C that take a format
specifier where you can say okay I'm
gonna have some values of some variables
that go into the string and then the
values get filled in at runtime the way
that it works if the user can control
this format specifier then the user
could add in extra lookups for variables
that didn't actually exist and because C
loves to let you shoot yourself in the
foot it just starts popping new things
off the stack and putting them in the
string there's also a way to write
things to things because they added this
percent and that lets you write so
essentially what it means is if there's
a user that can
put in that can taint the value of the
format screen specifier then they can
arbitrarily read an arbitrarily right
for the most part go back one we don't
have a POC for this yet so you can tell
me to get out later but we think that
this will work integer overflows
overflows are present in a lot of
languages but for people who haven't
heard of them if you have an integer it
has a maximum value in any any
programming language so if you do an
operation that would cause the value
stored in that integer to be higher than
what the maximum value was supposed to
be then it rolls around to the back
again so if it's a signed type then you
you end up the negative numbers if it's
unsigned and you end up in a low value
this is important for one because you
might be if this was a value that was
like your bank account you can flip it
over or you know withdraw something that
you shouldn't been able to do things
like that but also it's a gateway
sometimes to buffer overflow exploits
because you can change the expected
value of how long an array was supposed
to be before it gets created things like
that so just in this deplane sea world
wasm isn't doing anything to defend you
against these so if you just have a
straight-up
c integer overflow it's still going to
work fine the interesting part here is
that now we're throwing in wasm and
javascript into the mix and they all
have their own integer types with their
own maximum values and everyone's
different so I'm not going to list off
all the different types and see there's
a ton while some have in 32 and 64 float
32 and vote 64 javascript has two the 53
minus one so what that means is if we're
sending a value from JavaScript to wasm
the Weizmann value was declared as a
32-bit value but the JavaScript that we
send is say two to the forty then what
we've just sent in already overflowed
before we even started the C and so then
you know there's going to be a problem
there we had a demo of this but it was
boring so we didn't put it in
you could also overflow in the other
direction so if the the wasum was too
big for what we returned back to Java
then you could have the same problem
once it gets back to the JavaScript but
for overflows so again for people who
are web people a buffer overflow happens
because C doesn't check the bounds of
memory when you have an array and so if
you tell it to write more things than
there is space in the array it just
keeps writing through into other things
in memory this still happens perfectly
fine in wisdom you're not writing in
kind of regular memory you're overriding
things in that linear memory so whatever
was in there we can continue to
overwrite the kind of simple case for
this is if there's a value of memory
that you wanted to change because it
means something important in the context
of the application so there's something
like a privilege level your account
balance or whatever if we can find a way
to overflow into those then we can
change those values which is useful the
other thing that these normally are used
for in C is to run arbitrary code now
running arbitrary code and lazarum is
much harder because we don't have these
function pointers and return pointers
and all these other things that we can
try to override and then put our code
furthermore we can only do this in
linear memory which is never executable
so we can't like write some executable
code and then jump to it so we need some
other things to do we'll talk about that
later if you try to go past the bounds
of linear memory like in to something
else that the browser would have it's
supposed to give an error
I think Natalie's talk talked about a
few cases where that wasn't actually the
case in a browser implementation but
from a generalized perspective it's
supposed to work fine with all that
being said there are still some
interesting things we can do with buffer
overflows that get us some interesting
kinds of code execution we'll talk about
that in a minute okay I have a pretty
simple demo here which is an end of the
most basic type of buffer overflow so
here on line 6 we're using this a.m.
underscore J s which we talked about
earlier and this is allowing us to
actually define JavaScript inside of our
native code so here you can see that
we're we're creating a function called
overflow alert and we're saying that
it's void it takes no parameters and
that it just creates an alert box that
says overflow and then here in our main
function we've got two buffers one is
ABC one is once
three and then here we've got a string
copy when we're putting way too many
bees into this bought one and then if
then we're going to check the value of
both zero so if both zero is ABC then
this string compare is going to return
zero and nothing is going to happen if
there is an overflow and it's not ABC
anymore
then the string a pair is going to
return some value and if it does then
we're gonna get this overflow alert box
so if we see the overflow alert box that
notifies us that there was an overflow
so I can go into my virtual machine and
our gonna use em script ins e/m run
which allows us to just sort of like
it's kind of for like testing code you
can it's a basic web server kind of a
thing and we can just run our boss zero
dot HTML file which we compiled with um
script in and see if we get our alert
box and we got it overflow
all right so there are way too many
different types of bugs and see for us
to cover all of them we'll just briefly
cover the rest of the existing sea bugs
and kind of give us give you our take on
whether we think they're gonna be useful
or not from an attackers perspective so
talk to race conditions that stuff
should all be just as before with the
caveat that threading is not very mature
in wasum yet same story with timing
inside channels we think that heat based
arbitrary writes will also work in the
context of linear memory we don't have a
PSC for that either things that won't
work are your classic buffer overflow
where you jump back to the code you put
in things like rock won't work because
we can't arbitrarily jump to places in
memory and as it's supposed to work you
shouldn't be getting any information
from the browser for example when you
declare your memory it's supposed to be
all zeroed out when it gets to Assam so
you can't expect to you know lead on
initialize memory and get something
interesting there onto the new exploits
and Tyler assures me that all the memes
we have here are really fresh and
everyone in the 15 to 25 demographic
will get it off to XSS so let's talk
about XSS for a minute since we gave the
all the web people that remedial see
stuff we have to do the other way to XSS
means that we're running arbitrary
JavaScript in the content in the context
of a webpage now if you're not that
familiar with web stuff you might think
oh big deal I made a pop-up or old big
deal I can steal a session token' those
things are things you can do but what
XSS really means you can do is you can
control everything that that user could
have done and a lot of things that maybe
they didn't even know they could do in
the context of that website where you
got XSS so if it's a bank and I get XSS
I could use all the functions to
transfer money out if it's a social
media account and I get XSS I could post
social media stuff on your behalf I
could change your password etc etc so
XSS is a real thing and in the
webassembly world that's actually even
more important because the javascript
has the ability to read the linear
memory that it's allocated
it has the ability to start and stop as
Amit has the ability to modify wasm code
I don't think you can modify it when
it's running but you could stop it and
then restart it with your new modified
version so you should never consider
that code that's running in wasum is
somehow protected from the browser if
someone has XSS they'll be able to do
anything they want to the one that's
running in addition to anything they
want to the rest of that site No let's
go back so now that we know what XSS is
let's come back to what it means to do
buffer overflow here so if there is an
array that is written to the Dom and we
have an overflow somewhere and we can
overflow the value that would have been
written to the Dom then we have xs/s
pretty much all there is to it we used
to be our first demo of this stopped
working like halfway through our
research and we were really worried but
it was because we were overflowing a
literal which normally is really hard to
do and they moved we're literals go in
an updated version of the script and I
think to go below us in the stack and so
we couldn't overflow it because we can
over only overflow up other interesting
thing here is that your typical way to
find XSS is to look for reflection so I
put in an input in some webpage and then
I look to see if that gets reflected
that same input that I put in comes out
somewhere else and then I can try to see
if I can manipulate that to run
JavaScript we can do XSS without any
reflection here because we're actually
putting in a value somewhere over here
using it to overflow something that
shouldn't have been over shouldn't have
been writable by the user and then
that's what actually causes the XSS okay
so I have another another example here
for how we can use this buffer overflow
the XSS concepts so for this for this
example we have this ba function which
the extern keyword is going to let us
call it from JavaScript and this
function is going to take two parameters
it's gonna take p1 and p2 both of which
are just character pointers your
character is and we've got two character
arrays both 1 and both 2 both of which
are 16 bytes long and then we've got to
unsafe string copies from p1 at the path
ptoo in the bath - and then here we're
using this EMAS em again where basically
we're just getting this element by ID
we're getting an element called SS X and
we're setting the innerhtml
to this pointer stringify function the
pointer stringify is going to take like
an index into linear memory and it's
basically going to turn that into a
string and it takes these two parameters
0 1 1 which are defined here which is
both 1 and the length of both 1 so
essentially what we're doing is we're
taking p1 copying it to both 1 and then
we're taking pop one and we're printing
that directly to the dom and here in my
example page yeah so here's what the the
code is gonna look like from the
JavaScript side of things and the reason
why this can be especially dangerous
this you are calling our Bob function
and here we've got a static string which
we're passing in as p1 and some
user-defined string as p2 and a
developer is thinking to themselves I'm
putting a static string in here it's
totally safe I don't have to do any kind
of encoding I don't have to do any kind
of sanitization I wrote that string I
know what it's going to be but because
there's an overflow in the code we can
take this string with user input so we
can see here when we smash our like
button we see our static string is
written to the Dom we can put in a
couple of days and nothing happens we
can put in the cup of Morris and we can
see that now we're actually starting to
write user input over to the Dom and now
we can go to the end of our thing and we
can try to make some kind of a XSS
payload see if I can do this right
without messing up
and we got Xbox all right so that's kind
of basic still cool but not that
technically interesting we know we can
overflow values the reason we went over
a bunch of details about how function
pointers work is because we can do some
interesting things there too so we know
that function pointers in Wazza mark
really pointers they're integers to this
table that does the lookup and we know
that when we use the calling direct
stuff to execute a function pointer the
that's going to pull it a variable get
the value go look up from the table what
to call and then call it now we've just
shown you that we can modify what's in a
variable view and overflow so you should
be able to guess what comes next in
scripting when it adds things that
you're using it puts them in the
function table so if you used in script
and run script in your program for some
benign purpose it's going to be in that
table so we can call it dynamically as
well it has a signature it returns
nothing and it takes that's supposed to
be Const car but keep in mind that this
is wasum and wasum only has four types
so really that's integer so and then
when it takes whatever string is pointed
to by that and executes it
so if we can find a way to pass whatever
we want to this function then we win we
get XSS again in order for this to work
there's a few things that have to hold
so it has to be used in script and run
script has to be already in the program
that we're wanting to to attack that
means it's in the function table there
has to be a function pointer somewhere
else in the program that has the same
signature as on script and run script so
returns nothing takes one in parameter
and we have to be able to somehow
overwrite that function pointer we're
gonna show you about for overflow any
other trick you've got
that can arbitrary arbitrarily rewrite
some value will work okay so here we
have another example of yeah it's a good
meme right we have another example for
our overflow this look okay yeah this
looks pretty good okay so the the
scenario here is we've got some kind of
a file processor which is going to take
a file and it's going to run some kind
of a processing algorithm on it so we
have this file processor struct and the
struct is going to have a character
array of 64 bytes and that's gonna
represent the file that we're uploading
it's got a file length and then it's got
a function pointer for the processing
algorithm because you know say there's a
couple of different processing
algorithms that we might want to try to
run and so this is going to let you
dynamically choose between which
processing algorithm you want here we
have our trigger function which is just
going to call the processing algorithm
and it's going to pass the file to it so
it's just gonna call that function
pointer and here we have our machine
learning blockchain processing algorithm
the next iteration is going to be IOT
it's a pretty cool start if you guys
should check it out yeah and so here in
our in our function that we're exporting
the overflow we're declaring a file
processor we're setting the algorithm to
our machine learning blockchain
algorithm and then here we're doing a
mem copy from the payload which is just
the parameter to this function into the
file and then as you can see we're mem
copying 88 bytes
whereas the file is only 64 bytes so
this is a pretty classic buffer overflow
and then here this is important we have
in script and run scripts which is in
this case it's just saying that oh
there's some kind of a log which is
saying congratulations you uploaded the
file correctly but this has to be in
here because this is putting it in the
function table and then finally we're
just going to call our trigger on the
function pointer so we have a payload
which we're going to this is the file
that we're going to upload so we're
going to have alert XSS and then we're
gonna be filling in some some spaces
just to fill out the rest of the 64
bytes and then here we're filling out
the rest of the struct we're filling out
four which is going to be the file
length
we're filling out this is the integer
five now as Justin may have mentioned
earlier the file the the indexes in the
function table are constants not just
across execution all right but across
compliation so I've compiled this on
three different machines and every time
the index of em script and run script is
index five so five is the index of M
script and run scripts and so hopefully
the our function pointer over right
instead of calling the machine learning
algorithm that we wanted it's going to
call it scooped and run script and it's
going to pass a load to it so here we
have another example where we can choose
our file and that one cross your fingers
for the demo gods and we got excess
blocks so more details about this
there's no reason we have to go for the
xs/s here we could instead have used
this to call some other function that
was important with values that we wanted
so if there was a function to change my
password or something like that we could
call that and then give it the values we
wanted to then do what we wanted it to
do we can do this to anything that is in
the function table and is you know has
the right signature that is something we
can overflow to so jonathan foot if
you're in here raise your hand
no okay so he made a blog post he works
for fastly that talks about some very
similar techniques he was doing instead
of using buffer overflows to make his
overrides he was doing it via like type
confusion or deserialization type bugs
but it's the same endpoint so he's using
those kinds of tricks to end up with a
function pointer that calls something he
wanted to call instead of what the
program was originally gonna call looked
like he was doing it about the same time
as we were so I know that all you see
people don't care about XSS even though
I tried to explain how important it is
so we had to give you some RC here right
so
if the server is running node and you do
the exact same thing we just showed you
then what is XSS mean and node it means
RCE
so we should be able to run whatever we
want on the server if we have the same
policy in place alright last example
it's the exact same file processing that
we have before only now this the the
payload is slightly different instead of
an XSS payload now requiring we're
requiring a child process and we're
going to be executing some application
of our choice and the rest of it is
identical so we're gonna go over to my
virtual machine here see you got this
one
this one and we're gonna just run our
node server go back over here hopefully
this is still the same IP address
nope let me try and come in together
there we go okay so here's a file upload
so we're gonna choose a file but now
we're we're not just running this
locally in the browser we're loading
this to node and nodes going to run it
upload a file and demo gods we're not
kind to us gonna try this one more time
if this is work I have a recording of it
working this one
yeah all right so now you guys have seen
some cool bugs let's talk about what we
can do about it so one thing we can
think about is are there things that in
script and could add to make everything
more safe so there are things that are
kind of out of their scope so for
example it's not doesn't really make
sense for them to look at things like NX
and stack Canaries and things like that
even though those are valid see
mitigations they don't really apply in
the Western world because the code and
the data are already not interleaved
some protections they could add
something like address space
randomization so when we put things in
the function table the order that they
are in there is determined at compile
time which is bad from its curve
perspective because it means that your
exploit will always work except when it
doesn't like but it should always work
so there is no reason they couldn't make
it so those values there was a much
larger set of values to choose from and
they are randomly determined at runtime
then you wouldn't be as easily able to
mess with function pointers in the way
that we're showing it would be nice to
also have some library hardening I don't
know that anyone uses percent and in
format strings anymore it looked like
the heap implementation that's being
used is kind of an older heap that
doesn't have a lot of keep mitigations
in place so there's some improvements
that could be made in inscripted things
that work really well
control flow integrity so if you're not
familiar with control flow integrity
there's a switch you can I think it's
clang or LLVM not sure where it happens
but you can turn it on in there at
compile time and what's going to happen
is it kind of generates a mapping of all
of the possible flow States between
different functions in the program so
these are all the things that could ever
happen and then if at runtime you are
off the map it just crashes so if you
turn that on our function pointer tricks
won't work anymore
[Music]
the other thing that's effective here
already is the way that wasm works to
not
allow us to jump into arbitrary things
it means that there's no way to do
something like Rob the best we can do is
call individual functions one at a time
so we spent a lot of time researching
this and then found that buried on the
security page of the web assembly design
specification in the third paragraph in
the fourth section like they talked
about oh and by the way we probably
didn't protect against this and this and
this and this of this almost everything
we just talked about in this talk the
web assembly people did talk about and
say yeah we probably didn't defend
against these it would be nice if they
made this much more obvious instead of a
buried paragraph that's so long and
wordy like a nice bulleted list of you
still need to fix all of these kinds of
C issues this is so I'd love to see them
fix that if you're an application
developer and you want to try to make
your code safe the first step if you
cannot use in script in run script you
will be much better off if you have to
use it you have to use it but just like
any language where you have something
that's like eval like you want to avoid
that if at all possible even if as we've
shown even if you don't have a user
tainted way to get into it if there's an
overflow we can still call it if you
don't use it in your code we can't call
it and so then it's not useful as
attackers the optimizer so sometimes
when we would do things they wouldn't
work and why did my demo stop working oh
we compiled it with the optimizer turned
on which changed the way everything
worked in in some cases it removes
functions or in lines number I don't
even know what's going on but there's a
lot of times when we turn the optimizer
on all the way some of our stuff doesn't
work anymore so turn on the optimizer
it's not on by default but use it when
you compile control flow integrity we
talked about how that works there's a
performance penalty when you turn that
on but depending on what you're doing
maybe you can handle that maybe you
can't but at the end of the day even if
you do all those things there's still
plenty of sea bugs that are going to
work just fine on your web assembly code
so you still have to fix those things as
an attacker if you find one of these and
you want to do something interesting
we'll look forward script and run script
cuz that's where you're gonna have the
most fun if you don't see that you can
use overflows you can use other things
that allow you to write arbitrarily to
over
right values and in the function
pointers cases you can overwrite
interesting things there if you get XSS
you can turn back around and modify what
the wagons gonna be and even if there's
no XSS because they didn't use encrypt
and run script for example then you
should still be able to modify things in
memory that are useful to you and then
if you're talking about node then all
these tricks turn into RCE we have a
whitepaper security chasman Azzam went
in my Brian Tyler Jeff and myself
blackhat site has kind of the version
0.9 we have a couple more things we want
to finish and when we do we'll put that
on the NCC website so I'm Justin this is
Tyler thank you for coming if you
enjoyed our talk please fill out the
survey if you didn't employ enjoy a talk
please don't fill out survey our speaker
liaison has told us that we don't have
to go to the Rapp room because it's
lunchtime so we can just take questions
here until we're done questions yes yeah
sure so if I wanted to debug an x86
program I'd use like all of your eider
or something but would I use for web
assembly there's actually really good
debugger support in browsers now so both
Chrome and Firefox if you go into
developer mode sorry repeat the question
you wanted to know how to debug this
stuff if you go into developer mode you
can actually see all of the web assembly
instructions in S format which is what
we were showing a mess and you can like
step through you can set breakpoints all
that stuff in chrome you can actually
see the values that are on the stack at
any given time it's pretty cool works
really well thank you yeah what would
you want people implementing other
programming languages on top of web
assembly to know or do you think of that
I could only hear half of that a little
louder sorry what would you want other
people implementing other programming
languages than C on top of web is holy
what would you want them to know or
include okay so
if your if your language is already
memory safe then we've like a lot of the
things that we talked about aren't
really going to apply you need to think
about all the existing known
vulnerabilities in the language that you
have in its kind of base form and then
for each one just think about how does
this apply to the architecture of web
assembly is there something about web
assembly that makes these
vulnerabilities not work anymore is
there something that makes them more
prevalent because of whatever is going
on I think things like the serialization
will probably still be an issue I don't
know if there's something as a language
developer you can do about that but
it'll be interesting to think about it's
not something I've thought about yet
Thanks Thanks yeah I I'm totally missed
during your demo when you're uploading
the file are you just reading the file
contents into that proper yeah we were
copying the file contents what they do
it into a string yeah after we're done
up here if you want to see the code we
can just show you thank you hi great
talk
maybe I missed it though a little louder
no maybe I missed it yeah but what
happens when you go pass the local
variables like what do you overwrite an
in your memory or can you can you even
do that so the locals can be overwritten
I think I can't remember how well it
depends on the compiler so each one is
gonna be a little bit different in how
they implement the various like data
structures and stuff and see but there
are other things like outside of your
local variables that could be potential
targets depending on the the compiler
yeah so like we mentioned we earlier we
were able to overwrite literals which
normally like in other languages usually
you can't do that because there's
somewhere else right but because of the
way they was laid out at that time it
was working because we could go find it
now it doesn't work so a good place for
you to start would be to look at that
PDF that we linked because that lays out
they have the entire file format as it
exists currently and like where the
different sections are and how they work
so that would be a good place to think
about that but at the end of the day a
lot of that stuff is only in the web
assembly instructions section and so you
can't get to it from linear memory
because lean
memory is the only thing we could
overflow so I wish I had a better answer
for you but the answer is one it depends
- it's probably gonna change and three
there could still be interesting things
like that we don't know yet right so
does that also mean that there's a point
in having some kind of stack Qunari
equivalent potentially as in you know
you would want to have boundaries
between your various linear memory
pieces or sections yeah maybe I don't
know how hard that would be for them to
do but yeah there's maybe you also have
to keep in mind that we're doing web
assemblies supposed to be really general
and so maybe something we do for that
works well and see but then it's gonna
make it harder for them to do things
about the languages so thanks all right
no other questions thanks sweet thanks
guys appreciate it
[Applause]
[Music]