all right thank you for coming to our
talk about the Windows notification
facility so just to get started like to
introduce my co-speaker Gabrielle so hey
everybody I'm Gabby reverse engineer at
Crocs lab in France and I'm focusing on
Windows internals and not specifically
Sakana
I'm also bidding bedont going to the
black Fuji against this organization ku
where we trying to show newcomers ladies
that's reversing some answers pretty
hard for me thanks Abby
you know it's very rare that it happens
that you do research and you end up
having a collision of someone and
instead of fighting over who's gonna
present and you know trying to get into
all sorts of pestering it's nice that
we're in a community where two people
who met at a conference doing similar
research got to combine their research
so I'm very lucky to have Gabrielle here
who helped out a lot with some of the
tough stuff you're gonna see in this top
for those of you don't know me my name
is Alex Enescu
currently VP of EDR strategy crash
strike and I'm a passion and Windows
internals researcher that have been has
been doing this for way too long now
publisher of the windows internal series
and you know often speak your various
conferences about low-level things in
Windows that no one knows about that are
interesting to misuse abuse or otherwise
play around with and hopefully you'll
see some examples of that in this w NF
talk so first of all we'll start by
talking a little about what double-unit
is why it exists why it was built how it
works some of the api's who use w NF and
then Gabrielle will go over some of the
data structures for those of you who are
doing forensics or kind of understand
how it works behind the scenes and will
also talk about some tools that we've
built together some wind back extensions
some Python scripts some C scripts that
will be releasing so that you can also
you know fuzz manipulate and play around
in W net area I don't think you some of
the interesting attack surfaces a WMS
provides like most you know kernel
functionality it's not inherently bad
it's just the way people use it and you
know what can happen when you misuse it
and kind of break the assumptions when
things are undocumented there's often a
lot less fuzzing and security testing
that goes on within the vendor because
they figured hey it's undocumented until
someone talks about it we're okay
I'll also talk about you know
interesting use cases of W&F that are
probably not intended things like using
it as a covert side channel as well as
using some of the notifications that
provides for you know rootkit like
implant like behavior without doing some
of the hard work someone in that space
normally has to do it is a kernel level
facility and so it allows you to get
very fine-grained information about the
system and you get to see some examples
that you often can't do in carl mode at
all or that's very very complex and
again piggybacking on the system we're
living off the land is something that's
very popular these days and insecurity
research and also talk about a few
examples on how WUF can be used to
manipulate a system state you know
instead of global variables more and
more state is now stored in W&F data and
again you can manipulate assist them in
interesting ways either as an
administrator or not and then we'll wrap
up with some some future research ideas
that would come up with so let's talk
about first of all what is w enough so
the Windows notification facility this
is a new kernel component that was added
in Windows 8 and it's essentially a pup
sub model publisher subscriber so you
have one side that's basically
publishing data publishing notifications
and you have one or more subscribers or
consumers on the other side that are
consuming that data now the way WF was
built is actually very nice because it
fixes some of the design limitations
that Windows had before and I'll give
you an example of you know something you
couldn't do before W enough now what's
really cool about is that it's
completely blind in many pups up models
the publisher has to come first
you can't subscribe for something that
hasn't been published yet and if your
publisher you're publishing something
before their subscribers and subscribers
might miss the data and so there's a lot
of synchronization in a lot of classical
pup sub models around who publishes
first who subscribes and so on and so
forth so forth with W&F it's kind of a
blind system is registration less and so
the publisher in a consumer or
subscriber don't really need to know
about each other's or cool loads first
before the other so kind of support is
out of order behavior on top of this it
has lots of cool features like
persistent data versus volatile data
it has a change stamp so you can see
someone's modify the data in between you
lives reading it
it supports when to secure the scripture
so it's kind of got all the features
you'd expect out of amateur Windows
kernel functionality and a good example
for why you need something like wnf is
on Windows the example when you write a
Windows driver that loads a boot and you
want to write to the disk
now the disk when Windows boots up is
usually mounted read-only this happens
in every major OS in the world and even
Linux and Mac OS booted discrete only
then at some point around a utility like
fsck or AutoCheck and windows this case
which makes sure the disk is safe for
writing 6 is any bad sectors and then
rebounds to drive as read right now that
point a driver knows that it's safe to
write to the disk now because AutoCheck
executed now to do this oughta check
signals an event that's named but who
creates that event because if AutoCheck
creates the event then any drivers which
load before auto check don't have an
event to wait on because the thing that
tells you auto check around doesn't
exist yet if the drivers are supposed to
create the event first then which driver
becomes the first one to wait on the
event becomes the one to create the
event again you end up with in these
weird
ordering problems which were fixed in
this particular case by having the
kernel very early boot being the one
that carries the auto check event that
way auto check always knows it can
signal it and drivers always know it's
it's already there someone took care of
it for them but this is for this one
specific use case right sure some of
your programmers you've had similar
issues where there's some event out
there at once I need to signal and other
sightings through to wait on how do you
wait on something before it exists right
W&F solves that because with W enough I
can subscribe to that event and block
even if it doesn't exist yet and when
the event actually gets created then
I'll actually wake up once it's get once
it gets published too so that's kind of
one of the top use cases is blind
registration less subscription model now
in the W&F world would you have aren't
events there W&F state names these are
basically 64-bit IDs they're just
numbers well there's a trick to it these
numbers actually encode a data structure
inside of the dodges
random numbers they actually are bits
that represent a version a lifetime of
scope a permanent flag and then a unique
sequence number the trick is you take a
W&F state name you take the 64-bit
number you XOR it with this magic key
here which you know who knows what it
really means I don't know if it's a
person's name and a skew or whatnot but
you XOR it with this key and then you
get this data structure out of it with
these different bits that are gonna mean
different things so they're not just
goods they actually have meaning
associated with them so the first
meaning is the lifetime W&F state names
have lifetime and there's three main
lifetimes that are used well-known names
vermin and names and persistent things
and then there's a fourth type of
lifetime which is a temporary name now
well-known names are actually in the
registry and they're published and
basically created when the Windows
installation media is created so these
are in a header file of Microsoft and
they basically get added in the registry
permanent names are names that can be
registered after the fact they're also
stored in the registry so once a
permanent name gets registered it
persists it's data may or may not
persist there's a flag that specifies
should the last data that was associated
with this state name be persistent or
not and then this is gets a little bit
confusing there are persistent names
which go on a registry key called
volatile notifications so persistent
names are persistent with regards to the
process that registered them but they're
not permanent across reboots so if I'm a
process and I register persistent name
and I exit the data and the name of that
wnf state name persists until I reboot
and then it's got a temporary name if I
create it and I exit it's got no
registry backing associated with it once
the process exits the temporary name is
gone so temporary names are bound to the
lifetime of the process persist the
names are bound to the lifetime of the
system permanent names are in the
registry forever and then well no names
are in the registry but you can't
register them they're kind of pre
registered well no names that the system
is going to use and this kind of follows
similar models objects where unless you
an administrator or you have the create
global name privilege you can't create
permanent or persistent names you can
only create temporary names unless
you're an admin or above and then
obviously you can do that the second
piece of its state name is its scope and
the scope determines basically the
initial security boundary and visibility
boundary around a WF state so W and F
state name can either be global
or it can be unique to a session or it
can be unique to a user or it can be
unique to a process so you can say only
this process and it's threads know about
these state names or only the user only
Alex's processes can touch the state
name or only whoever's logged in a
session one can touch a state name or
anything across the system can do this
so there's different scoping that you
can associate and lifetime in scope
obviously go hand and hand together for
example you couldn't create a permanent
name that has process scoped because
that wouldn't make sense once your
process is gone the process scope is
gone where were you why are you
persisting this name that no one will
ever be able to open again because no
one will ever be that process again so
there are some rules obviously some
scopes don't make sense for certain
lifetimes and vice-versa and then the
last piece is the sequence number
because since these names are just bits
well some of the bits are the scope some
of the bits are the lifetime one bit
says if this is persistent data or not
how do you then actually make that the
name be unique so there's a 51 bit
sequence number now for well no names
the first 32 bits are basically
characters kind of like a pool tag or a
heap tag it's for ASCII letters that
kind of define the the family the tag
that really is associated with this name
and you'll see some examples soon the
remainder of the bits the last 21 bits
are then used as a number within that
family so this is the let's say I don't
know it's come up with a tag called
BK HT event 1 all right so BK HT that's
your tag that's your first 32 bits then
one is the first black hat event and
then 2 3 4 5 and so on so forth that's 4
well no names for the other names I
wanted you to register at runtime the
persisted names the permanent names that
sequence number is a monotonically
increasing number so the first ever
permanent state name that was ever
created it's sequence number was 1 and
then 2 and then 3 and then 4 and the
last used sequence number gets rid in
the registry so every
permanent aim until you reformat your
drive will always be increasing
increasing increasing increasing then
the persistent and temporary names which
disappear once you reboot the machine
those have their own monotonically
increasing sequence number that
obviously gives reset to zero wants to
reboot the machine so somewhere in a
kernel variable we basically remember
this was the last you know
non non permanent sequence number and
we'll just keeping incrementing that so
here's an example of a state named W&F
boot dirty shutdown like that's its
friendly name that's kind of what you
can see in the symbols what it looks
like if you open this up in Ida is one
five eight nine zero a bunch of hex
numbers you XOR those hex numbers with
that magic key and then you get you know
something that still looks like magic
hex but it's a little bit more readable
now all right some of you can probably
recognize okay that looks like a ski
okay you know there's some meaning to
this and if we follow the data structure
from earlier well this one basically
tells us this is version one this zero
over here tells us that this is a
well-known system scoped name and then
obviously these ASCII characters
represent the word boot and then the one
over here and this isn't one shift that
obviously so it looks like an eight
means that it's the first event by part
of the boot family so wnf boot dirty
shutdown is that number that's
internally like how its represented by
the WUF system so to register names that
are not well know names there's a nice
little API a system called Korea W
enough state name you pass in the
lifetime to scope whether or not data
should be persisted this is the size a
security of scripter it goes in the
registry or if it's temporary it doesn't
and then it creates this name for you if
you want to get rid of it at some point
you called Z W delete WF state name and
then this will then get rid of it then
if you want to add data if you want to
send some sentinel if you can
notification there is a update WF state
data in which you pass in the state name
a buffer size and then something called
a change stamp and the change down
basically lets you say look every time I
publish data there's a unique timestamp
that's basically a monotonically
increasing number
that says you know data entry 37 was
written to and then it's 30 and then 39
and so on and so forth you can say look
I the last time I published data the
time stamp was 40 and so now I believe
I'm publishing timestamp 41 so I can
enforce that basically says if someone
else has already published something
then ignore what I'm saying so you can
put a matching change tab that basically
says I expect the data to currently be
40 if it's 41 or later than me some
someone argued an update or we can say I
don't care if someone updated data just
go ahead and publish it so that's what
that change stamp of the concept is
about it's kind of like a sequence
number that you can use to see if
anyone's made a change or not if you
want to delete data you can call ZW
delete WF stay data and then this gets
rid of it to read W&F data there is a ZW
query W&F state data which gives you the
data the buffer size and the current
change stamp of the data that you just
read now the real power of WN f though
is that both for consuming data and
querying data the name doesn't yet have
to be registered unless it's a temporary
name which wouldn't make sense if it's a
persistent permanent or well-known name
even if it's not been registered by
anyone yet you can still publish data to
it the kernel will basically allocate a
buffer where it says okay for this name
that I don't know about yet here's the
data it's gonna be associated with it so
when the consumer or the publisher comes
in and says now this name exists well
then I could just associate the data
that was already kind of associate with
the name even though the name wasn't
even published yet and vice versa I can
ask for data even though the publisher
may not have published it because I
could have it from a previous reboot for
example so this kind of this associates
the data associated with a state before
without the state needing to really
exist yet with the difference of ten
with the exception of temporary names
because obviously temporary names are
completely based on a sequence number
that gets updated every time you reboot
if I probably get up to a temporary name
before the temporary name gets
registered I don't know how to associate
those two things right because there's
there's no kind of static information
associated with it and so when you query
or when you publish if the name doesn't
exist there'll be an instance created
anyway and then we got BL talks about
the data structures you'll see that that
name instance data structure
so so far we can see we've seen that you
can create a state name delete it and
then publish or read data from it but
what if the data doesn't exist yet well
then the last thing you can do is set up
a notification and so there's a bunch of
system calls that allow you to be
notified whenever data gets published to
a state name the way this works is you
call an API zlw set W&F process
notification event to first associate an
event with your process then you call a
different API subscribe state change
that lets you specify that you want to
be notified when certain things happen
to receive to the state either when data
gets published or when the state gets
destroyed or you can even register to
know when someone has subscribed the
event it's basically called a meta
notification it tells you when anyone
else has also subscribed for the thing
you're also subscribing for they you
could that's something you can do then
your event will get signaled so you wait
on your event handle every time you get
signaled you call get completion W&F
state subscription this gives you a
delivery descriptor that basically shows
you the last update that was just pushed
what data what size what is the change
tab that caused you to wake up and so
initially I had a POC that use these
system calls to basically be notified
and I was trying to hit various
keystrokes launch various apps and see
what wmf IDs were being you know lighted
up when I was when I was doing things
eventually I'm not sure the code with
Gabrielle she found out that I wasn't
working on some of her systems that my
code is basically failing and the reason
for that is only a single event can be
associated with the process so as soon
as someone wants to be notified about
1wf state no one else can be notified
about any other states because only one
event can be associated with one process
it's like well how the heck does this
work then if there's multiple WF
consumers and it turns out that in 80
DLL there's a higher level API you're
not supposed to directly call the system
calls those are actually meant for ntdll
itself which does assess process startup
registers its own event and then
everyone else is basically getting
multiplexed my NT DLL and so there's an
API called RTL subscribe W&F state
change notification where you're asking
ntdll on your behalf to subscribe for
this it uses its event and every time
it's even get signal
it goes over the list of all the current
subscribers in the process figures out
who owns this particularly event and
then notifies that subscriber by issuing
a callback
so you're supposed to rely on this not
on basically calling syscalls yourself
if you want the notifications to work
and this will have some interesting use
cases I want to talk about forensics and
some attack surfaces so that callback
basically gives you the name the stamp
the buffer and the buffer size and this
is how inside of your process you can
know that there's data has been
published for one of these W&F state IDs
that you're registered for now there
also is a kernel mode API so in kernel
mode there also is a e^x subscribe W&F
state change which let's do the same
thing as the kernel driver and then the
driver gets that gets a call back and
the driver calls e^x query W&F stay data
to read the information that's there so
both drivers can publish and consume WN
f data both drivers and user space
applications can can get notifications
for W and F as well so you can
communicate across process boundaries
across session boundaries across user
kernel boundaries and obviously it's
very interesting when you have you know
an IPC mechanism that's that's this rich
that crosses these many boundaries and
kind of hands the interest of looking at
it in more detail because no one's
really talked about the W and F in the
past so that's kind of the basic basics
of how it works and we're gonna publish
all these slides obviously so you're not
have to memorize how those api's work
and what's good is that they
accidentally all leak them in an old
windows header file so they're available
you know if you know where to look but
you'll have the slides sound as well so
next up I'll pass it off to Gibby to
talk about some of the data structures
that are involved in the internals of
keeping track of all this data so now
you have basically prudent and
understanding about the WWN F mechanism
so let's dive into the structures so W&F
events is indentified in memory as a
name instance these structures basically
or the all the information rich it to
the event for example you can find the
state name the scope in which the event
occurs so security descriptor and so on
you may notice that the first field of
the structures is tiny tiny circles
names the W&F context vida
in fact this to choose keeps information
about the type of structures and decides
and in fact most of the deputy minutes
to choose as these videos so it's kind
of convenient when you're in memory and
your 1 25 something you don't know
because you just have so Ada and also
things such as interesting is that in
the instance name you have a pointer to
the data that will be sent to
subscribers this data start with a
double unit state data structures that
gives information about the size of the
data and for example the number of time
it has been updated as Alex told you an
event occurs in a specific scope so
since the scopes are represented as
scope instances just cut this cap
instances gives all of the stuff needed
to identify this cap and they also give
got a list of name instance that are
available on this cup well when I said a
list is not a list it's more like a
binary tree that enables a quick lookup
and all these scape instances are stored
in lists and tree and escape map enables
to keep track of all of that you can
find the scope map in the server side or
Global's and basically yeah it's bound
to one side but for bond to other side
okay so
when a consumer wants to subscribe an
event it created the Burien f
subscription this situation basically
stores all the information needed to
have four W&F to to notify the consumer
it's also star as the state of the
switch question and the submitted the
way so the option in fact
okay last structures in canals i
represents is the process context in
fact the ISIS structures that keep
tracks of all the different objects
ready to a process and you can find it
in the a process object so oh yeah you
may notice that the last field is
actually syndication in notification
event so that mean yeah you can just
have one event as Alex told you so how's
the WEF managed to circulant program of
having only one single processed
notification well when you you even when
you are using high-level api's you
actually are dealings with a set of user
none structures this another's
multiplexing of subscriptions and to
keep track of all these different object
you have the subscription table and
basically if you have the sub consumer
that want to subscribe an event you will
create a W&F name its description this
structures is a unique for a state name
in the process context and then you will
also have W net user subscription to of
the information about the notification
mechanism for the soup consumer so this
way you can have one
the various names description and
several the Burien excuse of
subscription so that's how the kaepa the
issue is a managed and I think that's
quite cool okay so I finished those are
structures and I will present some tours
oh well we are making some kills
so as you can see there's a lot of
structures and it's quite an answer to
keep track of all of them to intensify
them when you're debugging every you
have let you win the back command which
is called bang W&F that's provide and
play relevant information about the
structures the thing is it doesn't work
out of the box because it's realized of
the symbols and obviously we don't have
any symbols but you can fix it by adding
the structure definition to your PD B's
and with that so WM f is a W and F
command is working the problem is well
even if you manage to fix it you would
still have a bunch of error popping out
I think well it seemed like ii wasn't
really finished and it's not totally
polished yeah it's quite strange
particularly I had to patch the DLL for
for this beings spot some of the
features so it's quite strange
so for artists reason I decided to
create my own extension it's nothing
fancy in basically do all the things at
the command line the command does
already but it doesn't rely on your PB
symbols so it should work out of the box
and smoothly
nothing region I created a tiny Python
modules
thanks to your script
for in a ping communication ya deberías
basically with this module you can read
and write to existing name instance or
even create a new temporary state name
for creating some kind of server side
and the wizard supply inside you can
just create it and it's pretty pretty
easy to use I show you an example well I
just created a server and youngsaeng
second join cakes
yeah alright thanks a real fun and
apparently this is what goes for not
very fancy it's just she just put 50
commands in there and that are super
awesome but it's nothing fancy I created
something that's really not fancy which
is a little see tool and I don't do
Python because you know I suck so this
see tool WF dump and basically lets you
do is just dump all the state names and
I'll do a little demo
it lets you brute force state names as
well should have how actually you can
root for the names that are not
well-known lets you read a state name
right into a state name or register for
a notification on a state name in a very
very simple tool here's you know me
running it with with Daphne saying you
know just just dump all the states and
you know it just starts dumping all the
WF IDs some of these you're gonna see
look pretty interesting and we're gonna
talk about that very soon kind of tells
you you know if there's system wiry door
for process if you have write access or
not there's any current subscribers to
it if you have sorry this is the scope
read write read only and then it gives
you kind of the current change stamp so
that kind of tells you how many times
just has been updated obviously if it's
zero it means no one's ever written into
this and then basically how much data is
currently nasty event so once you have
the tool to play around with obviously
the he'll probably make a lot more sense
but it's kind of something I used
initially to kind of figure out you know
what are different WF IDs out there that
we can start looking at and you know
playing around with and again many of
these seem very
interesting just from kind of looking at
them from the beginning and I can start
dumping them looking at a security
scriptures and so on and so forth so
hopefully with these tools in the
extensions once we release them you know
you can do your own research and find
out more because we've literally only
scratch the surface of everything that's
out there and so let's talk about about
kind of what are some of the interesting
areas you can start poking at w enough
the first and some of the kind of
findings that I had because some of you
know me I'm I don't do fuzzers not
because I look down on them on anything
I'm just not a fuzzer person I I like
finding these on Logic issues but
accidentally as I was writing WF dump I
kind of turned it into a fuzzer because
one of the ways I wanted to see if I
have access to modify state name is
instead of getting it secured descriptor
I just tried writing into it and I said
look if I just write zero bytes what
could go wrong right it's actually
pretty naive because if you write zero
bytes you're overriding anyone that had
any had ever written anything in there
whose data hadn't been consumed yet so
when the consumer comes along they get
my zero byte payload instead of the real
payload also every writes changes the
chained stamp so anyone that was trying
to write to it legitimately with
enforced change stamps saw some other
things already modify the data so it
ended up happening after I wrote zero
into every single W and F ID on my
system is explored just disappeared I
could never relaunch it I rebooted the
Machine and I was greeted by a black
screen my that's not good and I had to
fix it by basically going on a different
machines registry exporting all the W
nfid data back and I was like right data
is persistent so I probably wrote a
bunch of zeros any persistent W enough
state ID that something gonna system
relies on but the interesting thing is I
had run I had run WN f dumb as a
standard user so like Oh a standard user
King Nuka box cool I think I should have
more research on this another thing that
I did is I eventually dumped every
single byte that was there in every
single W and F ID both his admin both
the system both the cemented user and a
standard user when I started reading
some of the data that's there I start
seeing things like you know wireless
network names and things like pointers
you know they
that's privileged across process
boundaries user boundaries there was
some globally scoped you know world
accessible W nuff state names whose data
really shouldn't be exposed that way and
you know I submitted these to nsrc last
week because I was reminded that
actually these types of issues do matter
information disclosure czar considered
security boundaries and it's hard to
keep track of all that so that's one
reason why I can't share the tools or I
won't name names because if you run the
tools you would literally see that in
like the first three seconds so please
don't do that wait for them to fix it
and so that's why these tools will come
out once these issues are fixed because
we don't want to make it easier for
people to just rediscover the the same
bucks another thing that I have noticed
is when I accidentally wrote some data
in one of the WUF IDs I wasn't able to
launch any modern apps anymore so calc
actually calc is modern nowadays regedit
work fine your notepad work but
calculator the new one in Windows 10 or
any other metro modern payal app wasn't
launching anymore because I accidentally
corrupted one of the state names reboot
it and it worked again right so I wasn't
trying to like fuzz and find these types
of issues but just kind of while
accidentally riding into the wrong thing
there these things are happening the
last one is when I run my tools as admin
so again I had to be admin so it's
probably not an issue but as admin and
when I started writing garbage over the
WUF world
I started getting service hosts to crash
with no point of dereferences so you
know probably not exploitable have to be
admin anyway who cares about an admin to
service null pointer but it kind of
showed me you know what if someone is
actually competent in the arc of writing
fuzzers and you know crew creating
polymorphic data and you know doing all
the things that good fuzz are supposed
to do and then logging what right caused
what crash I'm sure you could find
something right I mean if like me
stumbling around I got some things to
happen someone more competent and
probably do a lot better there so how do
you kind of discover your these names so
the first approach is to basically go
for the well-known permanent persistence
names there in the registry so if you
just enumerate the registry keys that
are on an earlier slide also on the
kernel you can basically get all the
state names and the registry data that's
there is the state data that's there
right now plus is the queue descriptor
so
the secure descriptor and the data
that's there and that's what my tool
does basically parses that and shows it
to you in a nice format but ten three
names they're only known to the kernel
they're not in the registry so I also
wanted to do fahza to play around with
temporary names I'm like well how do I
get those without having a kernel
extension well if you think about a
temporary name or volatile name again
it's a state name like any other so it's
got a version and the version is always
one it's got a lifetime and the lifetime
is temporary it's got a permanent flag
which by definition is 0 because the
temporary name can't have permanent data
and the scope is one of the four
possible scopes right Machine scope or
process scope or user scope so what the
only part that's left to guess is the
sequence number and a sequence numbers
51 bits how are you gonna brute-force 51
bits you don't have to because remember
the sequence number is a monotonically
increasing number that starts 0 so for
permanent names you know those are in
the registry but for temporary names you
remember that this is it gets reset so
once you reboot the machine how many
stadiums can there possibly be 20,000
50,000 a million let's say a million so
I just basically loop from zero to a
million try all the sequence numbers and
it turns out there's an API query W&F
state name information with W info state
name exists and this tells you if this
state name exists or not now this thing
name doesn't exist that the returns
false if the state name exists and
you're allowed to know that it exists it
returns exists and if the state name
exists and you're not allowed to know
that it exists it returns access denied
so you know it exists right so very easy
to be asked a brute-force what the names
are even though you might not be able to
access them at least you know they're
there so you can you can start messing
with them now the last problem is the
secure descriptors how can you know what
access you have to the state name again
with the kernel I could just dump the SD
and see it but from user space the skews
creeper isn't anywhere there so I said
ok well if I can try reading from it
then I know it'll work rest illustrated
in the read ok the read doesn't work I
know I don't have read access how can I
tell if I've write access well again you
can do this stupid thing I was doing
initially which is write nothing but by
writing nothing you're destroying what's
there but remember that when you run
you can enforce the current change them
and when I thought it is what what if I
make the current change snap be F F F F
F F F F F F F F F well if you have write
access you're gonna get back status and
valid change that which basically tells
you it's not an F F F F F F F F right
now no rights gonna happen so you didn't
corrupt anything if you don't have
access you're gonna get access denied
and it's still not gonna change anything
so if I get access denied I know I don't
have write access
if I get invalid change stamp I know I
have write access but thankfully I
didn't modify the data the only way this
can break is if there is a legitimate
event out there whose change that really
is F F F F F F F yes by writing into it
I will now make it overflow into zero
and potentially break something but that
would mean there's been four billion
writes in a temporary state name which
which should never happen so that's kind
of the approach I took when creating WN
f WN f tap now what are some things you
can do with would that be enough other
than trying to like once you know these
names are well one of the things you can
use that PMF for is basically a covert
side channel right let's say you want to
communicate across process boundaries
there's lots of windows EP outlets that
lets you do that
but what's cool about W&F is you get
these well-known W&F names that already
exists that you don't have to register
so there's no windows api that anyone
any EDR vendor can hook that tells you
someone is using a well known name
because the well-known name is is
already there and so you can publish and
read from a well-known name and the only
thing that anyone's ever gonna see is
that you did a system call but you know
in Windows there's no way to hook system
calls officially right and so reading
and writing into wnf names doesn't
reveal anything that vendors know know
about unless they know the registry keys
where the data is being stored so with
well-known names you can basically store
data and read the data later by relying
on parts of the registry that most
people don't know what was in there and
without these actually being registry
reads or writes right cuz if you're an
anti Meyer vendor who's doing the
registry right it's the kernels WF
subsystem who's doing the crud that
registry read it's the kernels w nuff
subsystem so by using state names that
are defined but not used by anyone you
can kind of by piggybacking on your
registry
you know achieve a side channel that
most people don't know what to look for
the other option is to actually create
your own names
now if you create your own temporary
names this completely avoids the
registry all right so these are now
gonna be names and data that only exists
in current memory where most people
don't know where to look with the caveat
that you do have to register by now
calling zlw create register name but as
you're gonna see there's no etw event
there's no kernel notification and
there's no event log there's no auditing
of any kind when someone registers a
temporary name so unless you literally
hook that API which you know you all
know you're not supposed to be hooking
Windows api's it's a completely
invisible way to basically exchange data
between processes and there are many
other such ways but this is one that you
know no one's kind of named and put a
logo on it yet you know you know about
atom bomb being now you can call WF
bombing or something like that so that's
kind of one you know interesting thing
here and so from a EDR and time our
perspective if WF permanent or
persistent names are used you'll kind of
see registry reads and writes if you
know about those values they'll come
from the kernel behind the scenes or
some processes doing that if they're
temporary names there's nothing you can
really do to see that people are using W
enough although there are ECW events
there actually is an ECW event for
subscribe and I'm subscribed for
callback and for publish but only for
user mode callers and only if you're
using the RTL api's so if you're in
kernel mode and you're using WF no etw
trace is generated if you and user space
and your genius is caught the system
calls directly no e2w trace is being
generated at all so it's a very
invisible kind of IPC mechanism which
makes it interesting for me now the
other thing that's interesting is what
are some names that that reveal
information about the system that really
should perhaps shouldn't be revealed
right now there's like 4,000 well-known
names so we're just going to go over a
few of them but for example there's a W
nfid called w NF Wi-Fi connection status
this tells you the machine is connected
to the Wi-Fi network and the current
signal strength and if you register
notification on this even from Kermode
for example you'll get this data right
now if some of your kernel programmers
you know the official way of doing this
with like an end this lightweight filter
and like sending a light diesel all you
need is one API and you get notified
every time the or else that will goes up
and down there's one for Bluetooth in
fact there's even one called tethering
States every time there's tethering
enabled or disabled
you get notification there is one called
power source which tells you if the
machine is current through an AC adapter
or living off the battery if is living
off the battery you can get the battery
level from another W nfid there are cell
phone w NF IDs on this thing called a
Windows Phone which here you can bind
some archaeological stores which had
information like the network you're
connected to LTE band that you connected
to you know if one day there's Windows
phones again you know those would be
useful there's one that we came in for
user behaviors for example there's audio
capture all your render this will give
you notification anytime someone plays
any sound and or anytime someone
captures any sound so anytime I use
Cortana the capture Wi-Fi D gets
notified TKB an touch event registers a
notification every single time I touch
my touch screen press the mouse or press
the key boom that gets notified in fact
if you might want to do user detection
Windows has already its own built-in
user presence detector and it will
notify SCB user present or SCP user
present change when the user leaves or
approaches the Machine based on the
machine learning heuristics that Windows
already has so these are all things you
could already do but now you have a
simple way of just registering for an ID
that tells you when these things happen
there's also things that there's already
API support like there is an API to get
notified when a prosecute started but
everyone knows about PS register across
the notification but did you know that
there's a WN f shell desktop application
started WN f shell application started
and terminated that if you listen for
these events you will get the name and
over the package name in the path of
every single process creation and
destruction as long as it's down through
shell execute so sure you won't get like
non shell based launches but it's a nice
way to get most interactive law launched
applications without calling any other
API you know one of my favorite ones is
WN f edge last navigated host which
basically you know I I'll just do like a
live demo hoping the demo gods are with
me
WUF dumb dash n BB enough edge last
navigated host all right let's see if
that works
cross fingers open edge I'll be not
gonna work
let's see google.com I'm not connected
so what else oh there we go
mvlr which is probably the Mandalay base
Wi-Fi network so you know now I can get
every every URL that's ever piped or
clicking the edge without any DLL
injection or anything like that
including from kernel mode right another
one is shell lockscreen active over the
shells every time the lockscreen exactly
right and there are thousands of these
right so I'm sure you can find something
interesting if you go over that list
there's also Wi-Fi deselect you change
state like there's one called FS RTL opt
lock break where you write a bunch of
pits and there's a servicing user space
that terminates those pits for you so
you just write like eight and it just
kills pit number eight now you'd have to
be system so this one is not something a
you know app container can write in here
you have to be system if your system you
can already terminate process right but
you terminated process going through
mechanisms that have no CD articles know
how to look at who the heck knows that
if you write eight in there
it ends up killing process eight you
know there's other things like that BNF
surd flushed cache sugar which flush to
the certificate cache or boot memory
partitions restore which restores memory
allocations so there's nothing nfid that
by signaling them you get the system to
do certain things they almost behave
like API is where you put some
parameters you signal the event and then
some service does some action on behalf
of that and you know there's really lots
examples people will find and so if you
want to kind of find things to have fun
with one of the things you can do is
basically dump the WUF process context
and instead of a double eunice process
context you're gonna see all the active
for subscriptions now if you look at a
system process all of its subscriptions
are basically subscriptions owned by
kernel mode drivers as you can see what
are all the kernel mode callbacks
that'll get notified based on what W&F
ID that kind of gives you know this
driver is my attack surface right here
and then the callbacks office again you
get a payload and the question is you
know if i statically analyze the driver
what does it do with the pay with its
payload is it actually correctly
handling the data that comes in there
now in some cases you're going to find
aggravated driver there's a driver
called the event aggregator ei dot sis
and it a great supple unified ease and
it has its own sub callbacks
so there's drivers that rely on CA da
sis which then registered some callback
kind of like in userspace yet ntdll
acting as an aggregator as well in
userspace there's an RTL pwf process
subscriptions table and this table has
underling lists of all the active
subscriptions as Gabriele talked about
for each subscription all the callbacks
that are associated with it and given a
process you can see what are all the
user mode functions inside of every DLL
instead of every function and what name
are they basically listening on so that
kind of gives you a good mapping of here
all the code paths that I can hit by
modifying or writing into certain W and
F state names and let me statically
analyze the code right so you can have
the Foss things and just write garbage
or you know look into what you know the
callbacks are and seeing what they're
gonna be doing and so once you know that
you can basically signal arbitrary
subscribers to see you know what's the
impact the system once I do this are the
fun things that I can do one of the
things actually wanted to talk about is
how you can play with windows insider
features because all of the wind side
windows inside insider preview a be
testing that Microsoft does where they
enable dark mode for half of you but not
the other half and they see if one half
is jealous of the other half for other
good reasons or bad reasons is they
actually encode thousands of a be
testing features asked w enough payload
inside of w nfid and that's so figuring
this out rafael Riviera
really great you know windows MVP and
internals kind of person he ended up
figuring us out as well and he actually
created a tool on github called mock to
where it actually uses WF underneath the
scenes to modify which windows insider
preview features are activated on your
machine so even though you didn't get
selected to try this cool new dark mode
feature with this you can kind of force
it on or if you're like yuck dark mode
you just want to force it off you can do
that so that's kind of you know one of
the many things that rely on top of that
up that'd be enough and if you go over
and you look at like what are some of
the interesting insider settings you can
enable one of them is Windows
application guard container for office
oh cool office under application guard I
know
gonna happen the Andromeda store oh so
there is gonna be a device called
Andromeda the CNN anti-spoofing data
collection not I'm gonna get into that
deep inferno I don't know what that does
dev mode internal alright so you kind of
see you know new features that they're
testing internally and what W&F you can
enable the enable those on like HV CI
everywhere or you know virtual machine
chipset load firmer from file so
interesting things show up there you
know in the world of things that rely
behind WN F so if you interested in some
of the insider stuff here definitely
check out Mach 2 by Rafael Rivera on
github he uses you know they'll be
enough to kind of mess around these
things and there's lots of other things
you can mess around with as well another
thing you can do with W&F that's kind of
not by design is code injection right
lots of people love to migrate code from
one place to another and the way they
normally do that is by either calling
write process memory or using file
mappings or using add some objects or
Windows messages or GUI objects because
these are all Windows epi is where one
side can send some data and the other
side can receive the data well W have
lets you do that as well so if you
actually know there's a W nfid that a
process already kind of reads from time
to time if you signal that ID and put a
payload you know your payload is gonna
end up in the other process right when
that process sends a heap address to get
the result the result is basically your
data so you can use this as a way to
inject data or code into another process
without the standard techniques that you
know everyone on the internet knows
about you can also redirect code
execution right because you want a
process the or threat to do something
else and what it normally does typically
use an EPC or remote thread or we change
the thread context or you modify the
window long there's again lots of things
that hackers and you know designers know
about but remember that instead of every
process there's a list of very
subscription and every subscription has
a callback and a context and so
basically if I can find out a WF IDs
callback inside of your process all I
have to do is modify the data structure
by passing a different callback now I
have to worry about control flow guard
signaling the W and F ID and now that
other function runs instead of the real
function and parameter five and six are
the buffer in the buffer size so by
stimuli that the nfid I now get your
process to execute
function it normally wouldn't execute
now there's million other things you can
do like this but you know it's another
kind of use case for this um or we can
modify the context a lot of double Univ
callbacks what the callback code does is
it gets a context and then it made on
that context there's a V table there
there's another function pointer there I
could just modify the function pointer
in the call in the callback context of a
callback signal W nfid
the real callback runs but when it reads
its context its context is different and
something else ends up basically
happening alright so those are kind of
some ideas of things that you can end up
doing to kind of wrap up here w NF is a
very interesting well-designed kind of
feature that was added to Windows 8
provides lots of useful legitimate
functionality but because it's highly
undocumented and provides almost no
visibility other than a wind back
extension which doesn't work until a
Gabi fixed it
you basically have no idea what's really
using W net behind the scenes and
there's really no reason where Microsoft
shouldn't just publish the symbols for w
NF ID and they'll be enough it's not
like there's some sort of super-secret
PII and mojo in there they probably just
never thought about adding the symbols
that again creates a breeding ground
where people can kind of hide and the
last thing here to note is that uh BNF
is basically growing beyond just
providing notifications right you've got
a kernel user mode above buffer you've
got things like every edge tab being
like sent and W enough so there's more
and more things use W&F well the
question is like our people gonna start
doing silly things like putting code in
W&F state names or putting pointers and
W in a state names like one of the ones
we found and so because it can be used
to transfer data across boundaries you
know add marks don't have to be very
careful that they make sure that they
know you know WF is not documented that
doesn't mean that it's secure so
definitely if you're a defender start
fuzzing start building your own
visibility tool start poking at this
because I'm sure you'll find Dragons and
hopefully once you release the tools
that'll give you kind of some more some
more ideas there all right and so thank
you very very much thank you to
Gabrielle for assisting with the talk
and helping here I hope you liked it and
if there's any questions I think we can
move to a different room and I'll be
happy to feel those so thank you very
much
[Applause]