um well we're going to go ahead and turn
it over to you both uh noah and john
thank you both for uh for for joining us
here
both coming to us from straws freedberg
as you see and uh with a very strong
software development background and
especially when we look to
uh you know these really hard problems
of addressing an exponentially
increasing volume of data that comes
across in our logs as well as many
different formats uh sometimes the old
standby is when it comes to the not
necessarily just the tool grip but the
approach that has become known as
grepping um i'm eager to see what uh
what all you're bringing to bring to the
fight in the modern age of searching log
so
glad to have you on board with us and i
will turn it over to you both
all righty
howdy everybody
and uh uh welcome to uh grep and logs
we've got a lot of get through so we're
just gonna get started
so
just to go through our agenda real quick
before we do introductions uh we're
going to talk about some guiding
principles
we're going to talk about
sort of these new fields of data
engineering and data science we're going
to go back in time to the 1970s and talk
about core unix command line tools we're
going to talk about how to approach
structured data like csv and json
they're going to talk about my favorite
doc topic which is performance
uh we'll talk about a tool that we have
um that's open source called light grip
and then we'll talk about how the cloud
affects all of this
so uh
introductions my name is jon stewart uh
as corey alteid once said not the one
you miss the other one
and
i
do
forensic software development i've been
doing it for 18 years now
before at uh guidance software on encase
and then i had my own company lightbox
technologies strike straws fredberg
acquired that in 2015 and i've been with
straws for the past uh
uh six years
um noah
my name is noah rubin nice to meet you
all i'm newer on the scene than john i'm
a director
in our chicago lab i head up our chicago
lab which is where john and i are
standing right now
and before coming to straws i was a
software engineer and a data scientist
at some startups and doing some natural
language processing at a tech company in
china i no longer have the computer i
was using when i was in china
and i'm i am very passionate about
automating stuff because i'm lazy
and scaling up how we do forensics
and when noah's uh not doing client work
which is
you know
for about three hours out of every week
uh he likes to show me up by writing new
tools himself so it really keeps the
pressure on me
um
so our guiding principles uh really
sorry like the core here
is that you want to go back we want to
use those old time
unix command line tools for processing
logs because that approach
allows you
uh to get a good combination of
performance while still coping with all
the variants that each set law a set of
log data comes to you so you want tools
that
our command line can be scripted out
so you can create complex pipelines you
want simple tools that do a single task
well
and then you want to compose those tools
by putting them together like they're
legos
you want to make sure that you're paying
attention to performance so that you
don't miss your deadlines so that you
don't when you get a large log data set
that you don't have your tools break on
you and and miss your deadlines and have
unhappy clients um and then finally uh
and this is sort of like the new thing
to talk about is that forensics is
really sort of like uh data engineering
and data science and we should approach
it as such
so i'm going to try and convince you
that that is true um because i don't
often hear people talk about data
science and forensics together but i i
promise you that they are the same thing
forensics is in engineering and data
science so to define some terms quickly
what is data engineering it is shaping
data into a usable state so that you can
use it to do
data science which is interpreting data
to extract actionable insights and for
anyone that works dfir if those don't
sound like what you do every day then
i'm not really sure what you're doing
so that the high level process for data
engineering and data science as follows
you get some raw data set it could be a
set of logs from a client could be from
insert some internal tooling whatever it
is
uh ideally you define a set of questions
you want to answer
about those data
and from the questions that you want to
answer you can determine what are the
necessary steps i need to do
to answer those questions both from an
engineering side and from an analysis
side
then you actually do the data
engineering shape the data into the
state that you need it
and then you do your analysis and then
rinse and repeat
so
here's a nice high level diagram of what
this should look like in our opinion
you get your data you define your
question set
engineer it
really important step is generating
intermediate data sets
which i'll get into why that's important
on the next slide
um i what i like to do is do some triage
analysis like i'm going to pull out my
event logs process them quick and just
see if i can get some quick wins you do
your in-depth stuff communicate the
stuff to the client or internal
stakeholders rinse and repeat
this is what i see a lot of people doing
not just elsewhere but sometimes it
straws too
this is important for everybody is
you'll get some raw data set some people
will just grab for iocs and that's it
just go straight to communicating that
and that's it sometimes the client will
say hey i have this one very specific
question so you take your raw data you
process it to answer that one very
specific question
and then council come back comes back
it's like oh well actually i have this
other kind of related question but it's
a little bit different and you realize
shoot i missed like a couple fields in
my original processing that i actually
needed for this other question so then
you go back and you reprocess the data
you gotta wait three hours for that to
be done
i've seen people just like
popping open sublime text and manually
reviewing json
some people are like you know what i
don't even want to deal with this
command line stuff i'm just going to
throw it in spelunker elk and do it
there
um it's it's a hodgepodge and so here
are the key takeaways that
i just want to impart on everybody one
the quicker you do data engineering the
quicker you can start doing your
analysis
another thing is define your question
set to the best of your ability before
you
shape your data because then you don't
have to spend hours reprocessing stuff
never mutate the original data set
always generate intermediate data sets
from your transformations
and it will save everybody a lot of time
one final thing i want to talk about
there uh noah i'm sorry to spark in on
you uh
contemporaneously but um the
with data engineering and that approach
while your log data might change from
investigation to investigation to
investigation
the data engineering approach allows you
to do some preparation beforehand when
you're not in the thick of it and so by
you know
when you have a new uh case come in with
new set of logs you can say let me adapt
those logs to my existing process and
then i have all this existing
infrastructure that i've built up that
lets me get through things quickly and
it allows you to actually take a smarter
approach um but not have to do it just
in the moment of the investigation
so let's talk about uh these core unix
command line tools uh i'm guessing that
there are two groups of people uh right
now there are those who know these
commit unix command line tools and
they're they're really afraid that we're
going to go into depth on them uh
to to that group of people and say just
be patient we will we will get through
this very briefly
and i'm imagining the second group
of you
don't have much experience at all with
these command line tools and i don't
want to go through those tools in depth
we don't have the time right now but i
really
urge you
to take a moment and and learn these
tools and here's the set of tools that
we think are uh these are your daily
drivers that will allow you if
if you learn these tools you will be
extraordinarily productive
it's only like less than a dozen right
and and you'll be able to cope with
anything that comes your way in a
performant way
some of them have to deal
do with uh dealing with input and just
transforming the input some of them
actually have to do with with processing
the data like graph and cut and sort and
unique
um sed is an interesting tool it's not
so easy to use but you could there are
lots of examples online that you can
just copy and paste from that that's
what i do and said really allows you to
do um search and replace at scale just
right on from the command line
the final one i have to confess
uh is awk and awk is its own programming
language um and i don't know it very
well i can't use it very well uh so
that's something that i need to bone up
on more myself but i am in awe of those
who can use ark well if you know awk you
can do anything in about five lines of
code um and i think it might be the
secret to help palmer and success maybe
uh or at least one of them
so
uh we're going to
skip on now to talk about
processing structure data but we do have
a lot of links in the slide deck and
some other
slides about
all those core command line tools
uh i will say we have one we have one um
example of an aux script in the appendix
slides where you can convert uh my sql
output to sqlite compatible output and
that has helped me in a number of cases
it's a ridiculous aux script if you want
to see like how far you can take it you
take a look at that script
okay so we're going to talk about two
types of structured data that i'm pretty
sure everybody here deals with from time
to time one is csv data or more
generally tabular data there's one
specific toolkit that i really like to
use it's called csv kit open source
written in python available on github
they have documentation as well on read
the docs
and it's a collection of command line
tools
they're more than just the ones that um
mentioned here but these are like the
core set of tools that i like to use
from csv kids so one is csv clean that's
a really quick way just to see hey does
my tabular data uh is like a uniform set
of columns for every row that's a that's
a pretty basic one because sometimes you
get stuff that's from clients that's
messy super messy so you just want to
see is it clean enough for me to start
doing analysis or do i need to do some
data engineering to clean it up
csv format's a simple one if you get
some that's like
some random encoding
csv format will encode it and use the
proper
field delimiters and quotations which is
really nice
csv look uh have you ever like catted a
csv file to standard out and just tried
to look through the rows it's very
difficult and i find myself squinting at
it if you look if you use csv look it
just formats it really nicely and it's
it's easier to look at csv stat if you
want to get basic descriptive statistics
for a set of columns in a csv super easy
tool
csv cut is a lot like the unix cut tool
but it handles csv data better and there
are some intricacies there that it just
you don't have to deal with them
csv join is a is a really useful tool if
you have two csvs that have some sort of
column that you can join them together
with
you just run csv join and you can get a
joint data so super easy
so we have some examples in here i'm not
going to play this whole thing because
it's too long but obviously you can take
a look at the slides after so this shows
a good workflow for using the tools i
just talked about using csv clean to see
if your data sets
are
clean and if they're not creating a copy
at a cleaned version of them so that you
can do your analysis you can use csv
csv stat to look at the headers just do
some exploratory analysis on it
this is an example of using csv look you
can see it's much easier to look at that
than just raw csv data
and then i use csv join to actually join
two csvs together on an id column
we have a repo which we'll talk about
later but we have a repo associated with
this talk up on the stratosphere github
org
all of the data sets and examples are up
on that repo you can take a look at the
map
the next is json data i love that name
it's absolutely fantastic
json data we see all the time o365 bc
type investigations we see them in aws
with cloudtrail logs
all the time and jq is probably the best
tool for command line json processing
it's written in c it's super fast and it
can do pretty much anything you can
think of with json input
so this is an example of cloudtrail logs
for those of you that don't use aws as
much it's essentially the audit trail
for
admin level actions in aws and then it
can also do some s3 access logging as
well
the format for cloudtrail logs is their
gzipped json data and each log file
contains one or more records so what we
show in this example is you can unzip
the logs do some exploratory analysis on
what the json structure is all using jq
all from the command line and then you
can actually take each record generate
some tabular data in csv because dealing
with json can be a pain
and then run some descriptive statistics
on the csv data
so my favorite topic
performance
all the tools that we've talked about so
far will make you productive and being
productive is the best performance win
but there are some times when the client
calls you up on friday afternoon and
says i've got 20 terabytes of logs
you've never seen before and i need your
preliminary analysis done by
monday morning and no one else will take
the case but i know that you will
right so
those times you need the nos button to
go really fast
um so here are some tools that will help
you do that
the most important of which is gnu
parallel we'll talk about that a little
bit later in another slide um no i
showed you all sorts of fantastic things
can be done with csv kit csv kit is
great you should learn it um but csv kit
is written in python and python is slow
so csv kit is not as fast as it could
possibly be there's a new tool called
xsb it's written in rust has a lot of
functionality itself a little different
than csv kit
but programs that are written in rust
are fast
so that will help you get through
loads and loads and loads of csv if
that's if that's the kind of data that
you're working with
um
for those of you who
use python for scripting working with
json data and python is amazing it's
awesome it's so easy right you just like
parse the string boom it's addict there
you go you're off to the races in python
problem is python is slow and so
processing json in python is slow um
there is a rust library for parsing json
called or json
and although it's written in rust
it is designed for easy usage in python
you can just pip install it and import
it it is a drop-in replacement for the
standard library module i've there is
the uh absolute best thing to use
because there's there are a few things
in life that can make your python
scripts five times faster but or jason
can and it has for us and it's just been
fantastic uh you should just always use
it by default for everything
um for those of you who've got a little
more tech uh skill with with being able
to use c or c plus plus and some
compilers even if just a little bit
and if you need to go really fast if you
need that 900 horsepower charger um
there's a tool there's a library called
simd json cindy json uses the sse and
avx vector instructions uh on intel cpus
to highly accelerate uh json parsing and
it is the fastest json parser out there
it's not even close it's twice as fast
as the next fastest
and it can process gigabytes of json a
minute
so
um
some performance principles to keep in
mind the most important one is
procedural and that is just to start to
benchmark
however roughly whatever your throughput
is on your pipeline as your processing
data i find a lot of people don't do
this and then they get close to the
deadline of when they've got to make it
deliverable and they don't know when
it's going to be done and they start
calling me and by that point there's
nothing i can do
if you
uh are able to estimate what your rough
throughput bandwidth is for your whole
pri pipeline
you'll be able to extrapolate from that
to get a sense of when you'll be
finished processing and if it's tight or
if you're going to overshoot it
you can do that you know if you've done
that early on you can adjust your
approach or
set client expectations appropriately
right you can batch things up into sets
and get at least a few batches done as
opposed to having being zero percent
done when your your deadline comes
um the second most important thing with
performance these days is of course to
make use of all the cores that you have
on your system
the new parallel is the key to doing
that because it will launch
a command for each set of uh file paths
that it has as input and can you and it
could saturate your cores we'll show you
a demo of that in just a moment um
finally when it comes to nvme or finally
when it comes to io
you got to use nvme there is no excuse
in 2021 for not using nvme to its full
it is absolutely the best money you can
buy the cheapest money you can buy to
accelerate your forensic processing nvme
drives are just amazing don't bother
around with spinning rust ever
don't even bother with sata ssd drives
because sata is actually the bottleneck
the drive itself can go way fast it's
the same hardware as in as this in nvme
but the protocol is so slow it can't set
it can't fully utilize the underlying
hardware
so use nvme
finally if your processing is going to
produce a lot of output
you should consider using a second i o
device that's dedicated for grabbing
that output and that way you avoid
mixed i o so you can read from one
device
right to the other they're both going to
perform as fast as they possibly can
then
even if you put even nvme suffers under
mixed i o
okay so this is an example of the kind
of throughput that you can get using gnu
parallel
so you can see on the bottom we have
h-top running showing you how many cores
we have eight logical cores on this
machine
it's not a great machine i'll just say
that up front so that you can do much
better in this example we have five and
a half megs of compressed aws cloudtrail
log data
and what we've done is written a script
that operates on a single file to unzip
the file and then run jq on the json
data to extract individual csv records
so you can see me typing here is
i'm going to use the find command
to list all of the gz which are the
gzipped cloudtrail logs
and then i'm going to pipe them to gnu
parallel i'm using the jobs
command line switch
to schedule essentially five files to be
processed on each core and i'm gonna run
the script on each one so you'll see in
a second on the bottom
our cpu utilization is going to spike
once i hit enter
now it spikes there we go right and
that's the difference between using a
single core to sequentially process all
your files and actually using the
computing power that you have
at your fingertips yeah and eight cores
is one thing right but uh you know there
are a lot of tools out there that are
eight cores but you probably have more
than eight cores these days you might
have 20 you might have 30 on the servers
you might have 64 cores and so
um there aren't any other tools out
there other than this kind of approach
that can really saturate
64 cores at once and it's awesome when
you can be able to do that
so uh light grip
light grip is a search tool
i wrote i started writing it in
uh it's over like 11 years ago now the
spring of 2010. um
had i known how long it was going to
take me to finish i never would have
started i got it uh kind of running it
was really fast it was like three times
faster in nk so i made some changes ten
times faster in case uh and then i
finally came up with like a really good
set of
uh qa tests and it took me two years to
pass those q a tests because it's such a
hard problem
and that's why no one has really ever
before solved the multi-pattern grip
problem um
so we released it as op we released it
as a add-on product for encase back in
2012. in 2013 uh
partnership with simpson garfinkel then
he was at the naval postgrad school at
the time uh we open sourced it and
integrated it into bulk extractor
lightcraft features standard grupp
syntax not its own frank and grep um and
so
and what really distinguishes light grub
is its support for different encodings
so utf-8 utf-16
ascii abdict
everything every encoding under the sun
light grip can say can look at a pattern
and identify it in whichever encodings
you want to search for
in the raw binary data so it doesn't try
to decode the binary data it look it
changes your keyword to recognize it in
binary data
um and light grip powers a lot of the
forensic processing at straws free work
so
we are pushing out a new release of
light grip uh it's probably gonna slip
until tomorrow uh i gotta finish up some
documentation changes on there um but uh
uh
it will come with a new command line
tool now we've had it for a long time it
still probably needs um you know
needs your it really needs your feedback
uh for me to take it to the next level
but it'll allow you to search binary or
uh or log data text data
and we'll have a
windows build available so that instead
of just like having a library for c
developers um you'll be able to use
lightroom from the command line um we're
also changing the open source license on
it
today uh it's been under the gnu public
license uh and with this new release
we're switching the license over to the
apache 2 software license which is far
more friendly to other businesses so
hopefully we can get
a greater adoption for light grab and
see it in other tools and
get get more usage of it from from lots
of folks
this release will also
feature reduced memory usage on really
complex pattern sets so you can check it
out at our uh straws freebird github
page
um
the thing that distinguishes a
multi-pattern search
the algorithms get complex but at the
high level it's really easy to
understand
grep is a fantastic tool it's
really fast it's hard to beat um
but if you have 100 keywords and you've
got to search a terabyte of log files
you're going to have to research that
log file 100 times
light grab can take those hundred
keywords bundle them up together in a
principled way and take one pass through
that uh one terabyte file now it's not a
hundred times faster but it's still
usually several times faster than doing
a loop a hundred times over
uh uh with grub and so that's that's
the thing that inspired this talk is uh
all the half game cases that we had to
deal with um
uh in march where we had like tons of
iis and exchange logs and we had a lot
of uh ioc search terms ip addresses and
aspx web shelves and we just needed to
triage exchange logs as fast as we could
to um to figure out you know like was
this exchange server uh uh hit with the
web shell do we see anything that
indicates that it was and so this little
gif here shows us searching uh 339
megabytes
of uh iis exchange log data for 67 uh
half name related uh terms and you can
see it takes like four seconds or
whatever
okay so we've talked about some core
command line tools and how to compose
them together to do stuff fast now we're
going to talk about taking those
principles and applying them uh using
cloud infrastructure and scaling up with
aws
so aws i think at this point has in the
hundreds of services that they offer and
they add new stuff all the time but
we're going to talk about three very
critical ones
uh the s3 simple storage service
sure most people have heard of it if not
it's a it's an object store you can
store
stuff whatever you want as discrete
objects kind of like a file system
but it operates over http
and it's cheap if you want to store a
whole bunch of log data or images or
whatever in s3 it's super cheap and
you're you can be relatively sure that
they're not going to lose your data
the next one is aws lambda it's their
serverless compute platform
or in other words you run functions so
each you can think about each lambda
like a javascript function or a python
function or rust or c plus plus you can
run a whole bunch of different stuff
um but it's really just at the end of
the day a function and the nice thing
about lambda is you can pair it with
other services like s3 so you can
trigger
lambdas to run when other stuff happens
in aws like uploading a file to s3 the
last thing is the cloud development kit
or cdk
if anyone's familiar with hashicorp
terraform it's kind of the same idea it
allows you to write code to describe
what you want to build in aws
and then it will deploy your
infrastructure for you
and that integrates with aws cloud
formation
so if you remember the previous sketch
that i made of showing like find to
parallel to like lots of uh uh greps
that are happening simultaneously um
that sketch kind of illustrated
that a traditional computer has
bottlenecks we're bottlenecked on our
input
aws is essentially a new type of
computer
where
we can put up lots of data into it right
near infinite amount of data
into s3 stored very cheaply extremely
reliably
and
that data amazon takes care
of striping that data across their
entire data etc right so you're
utilizing lots and lots and lots of io
devices
and lots and lots of storage servers
at the same time then you can pair
your lambdas
with individual s3 objects to do your
searches in parallel
so
while gnu parallel is great if you just
have a single system and a hard drive uh
hooked up to it with you know a couple
of terabytes of logs
if you have dozens of terabytes of logs
thousands of files
aws can scale to that without any
bottlenecks and that's really kind of
like the revolutionary part of what
makes aws
a new type of computer
okay so i'm going to show an example of
what using the aws cdk looks like
there are some tools that you have to
have installed which i'll talk about in
a second
we have a repo associated with this talk
like i said before
one of the things inside of that repo is
a template cdk application so you don't
have to do this from scratch we've given
a template
for you and we have an example lambda
function written it was just shown in
this example
and all it really does is it prints out
hey there's a new object in s3 so what
we've done in the cdk ad is we have an
s3 bucket and then this lambda
and we've hooked them up so that every
time a new object gets uploaded to the
bucket
you run the lambda and
thinking about how you could use this
that's great it you could use it however
you want right every time uh someone
uploads a file you could grab for
keywords you could process the data do
some data engineering and then throw it
in elasticsearch
um although i would i would encourage
you to do some enrichment or more
analysis before just throwing stuff in a
search tool
um you can do whatever you want and it's
up there in the repo for you uh as you
can see it's really just as easy as
writing cdk deploy it deploys it
so last like i said the repo link is is
right here we have this template awk aws
cdk app and a bunch of documentation on
how to install the tools to use it and
deploy it and then also how to change it
so it's actually useful for you to
process data
we have a shell scripts with all of the
commands from the examples and we have
the data sets that
we used in the examples
we also have a docker file with the with
a static build of light grep in it so
you can play around with like rep we
have all of the tools i'm pretty sure i
got all of them uh in the docker file if
i'm missing one i'm happy to add it
so you can play around with all of these
tools without having to install them
yourself
um and i also added some core data
science libraries from python and from r
if anyone are fans of those
all right i think we have a uh a few
questions that have come in
um
the first i will pose to uh noah here
around the fly he hasn't seen it
but that is can one pipe unix command
output to csv kit
so because oftentimes the spacing of
stuff like that uh will will have
problems
yes csv kit all of the tools in cst kit
are designed to read from standard in so
if you use one unix tool to output some
data you can pipe it directly to the csv
kid tools and they'll read them by
default you can also
just read from a file with the csvk
tools but they're really designed with
the
unix
unix usage style in mind so yes
okay and then two questions about light
grip
i'm going to answer the second one first
um did they mention a flight grip will
parse the information in compressed log
files like secret the answer to that is
no
light grip just deals with the data as
it is searches the data as it is um
that's why the bulk extractor uh
integration is a great thing i've been
talking with simpson garfinkel about a
bulk extractor 2.0 that's that's kind of
coming later this year i think and uh
it's able to deal with the actual
extraction and present that data to
bulk strength i will say there are
command line tools to solve those
problems so you don't necessarily need
to write a new one you can use g unzip
or gun zip if you use gun zip dash c it
just pipes the standard out you can pipe
it to light crep you can use zcat is
another easy one so
if you compare other existing tools to
handle those problems
so then the other one is how does leica
compare to silver searcher uh that's a
good question that i am
not super able to answer right on the
off the cuff but i'll do my best um my
understanding is silver searcher it's a
good search tool uh it's designed for
searching code repositories and
i believe it indexes the data first so
it's creating a search index of of data
usually based around text
and
then can answer you know queries very
quickly based upon that search index uh
litecrep is not
a index search tool it is just a
straightforward one bite at a time grep
tool it just can do multi-pattern crap
and has support for lots of encodings um
so so lycra is really geared more
towards doing um
binary searching searching of binary
data that's really like how it got its
life was i need to go through
unallocated space and find all the
things all at once
um but we have found it useful for for
searching logs as well
silver searcher great tool though that's
uh that's a nice one to put in your your
tool belt as
well any other questions
how are we doing
that's it
um there's there's one in here about a
comparison to yara i don't know if
that's enough of a difference from a lot
of what you just talked about well oh
yeah we're streaming yeah
i mean so yara has like a ton of
yara has a ton of functionality uh i've
looked real hard at what they're doing
and
you know like okay should i just drop
like up in the yard and stuff and it's
just it's not possible i wish it were
um
but uh
with all the other things that yara is
doing with parsing pe files and
uh the hashing and everything else is
doing it's its own thing um but in terms
of raw search performance like
uh search term search term like grapple
will beat yara
yeah and you know
i kind of figured that's the the
direction that you would lean in that
answer and i think that goes really well
with some of the commentary that we had
in the slack channel which was you know
using a tool to do two things versus the
individual tool and then chaining it
together with pipes and such and there's
a lot of benefit that you get out of
either of those approaches but i agree
like pick the tool that's best for the
specific task you need instead of you
know
you're not going to use zeke to replace
uh your ids like that's just not what
it's designed for and kind of like you
said with yara versus light crap i think
that's another good analogy there
uh yeah so the the link to the docker
file
and rip the repo in general um it's it's
uh it's in the slide deck
we can put it inside out man yeah we'll
put it in the slot we'll put it in slack
too and respond to uh questions in slack
over the next couple days so please hit
us up there for sure
awesome
the last thing that i want to say before
before we go into lunch here is when
these slides do become available in your
portal accounts um
we didn't even get to what i think might
be the hidden gold nugget in uh in your
slide deck which is your appendix holy
cow this is like i i've sneak peeked
through there and you've got a slide on
each of the various tools that you
talked about um i am absolutely going to
be pointing to that for a lot of reasons
because that is a fantastic collection
of just the what's the tool what's it do
and and how do i make use of that so uh
just a little bit of a preview for
everybody when this does show up in your
account you are going to be uh very very
pleased to go back to the slides that we
didn't even you know have a chance to
see here so thank you for putting all
that information together
that was a necessity we realized it
would be a 90-minute talk if we covered
each one of those yeah
well you know it's going to be good
reference for those that want it and uh
something that we'll refer back to for a
long time i think
you