the victory
sure
[Music]
i was kind of asking the video guys
so first of all
you should check this way ahead that's
why you should feel 50 minutes
streaming
me
yes
so welcome to almost the last talk of
this year and this is the time where
morton gets to brag about how well the
network has run through the camp
[Applause]
so it's nice
sorry
it's nice to see so many people um
i have um
added something um
by request from the noc team
um so this is the usual end of camp
network
network um talk where we will go through
what we've been doing and
we have done all kinds of interesting
things and you guys have also and this
is the talk about that so
um
you all know hypnotoad right
okay
so first things first this is the
mandatory slide about how much bandwidth
we've been using
and last year i had this
recurring thing saying use more
bandwidth and
well i just skipped that hashtag because
apparently it's not working to say it
so just
a quick one on the slides
yes
oh this is much better anyway so what
you see is the red line that is 200
megabits
um
i'm
yeah and i'm pretty sure that um
the big line here is probably someone
doing an iperf or maxing out the network
or whatever testing you could do
but um when i look at this slide i'm
thinking
i'm gonna have a hard time convincing
orca to give a three gigabit next year
or five or ten
so we kind of need to
do some design changes in order to use
massive amounts of bandwidth because we
of course only like bandwidth it's just
not something we use but we like it
so
i have divided this token to two parts
all the core stuff and all the non-core
stuff so um just to give you a bit of um
agenda for this
so we of course started as we always do
in the weekend and we start
looking at all the stuff we have and
there have been a lot of switches and
stuff that we brought we being
my team not me
um and then then
sunday or was it saturday oh it was
saturday
yay now we have the fiber link you know
the converter from mx to lc you know if
you were here last year you probably
remember me talking about mx connectors
nobody uses that except broadcast people
so of course nobody has that in stock
but this year we were well
we were well prepared
and um
the thing that happened was that um
espeon he brought the
mx to lc converter and there was an mx
thing in the well so what's the problem
well
well of course then some bright person
said
didn't we have two cables last year
the thing that happened was that if you
see here
this is a connector with a flange which
is you know for built into equipment
and this here is the thing for the
connector cables
so we had two of those
wonderful
um
so um we um
well
i went through my phone book to find
broadcast people who actually had some
of this stuff but all of them were when
had gone to le mans and some place in
jutland so
my connections were no good but we
acquired one in a proper connector cable
in
during saturday but before that
we actually punched a hole through which
i think is immensely super nice
um so
this is um apparently a picture we're
gonna do every year because i like this
this is the uplink and we have light
awesome um
um as i said we were short of cable so
how to fix that when you work with light
yes
we um we use the scratch in order to
have the two um flange ends meet up so
that we could actually test the if we
had a connection
which
worked
well
actually it worked well
it was just that you know um
shouldn't be too windy or anyone
touching it because you know light and
you know different angles would not be a
good thing so but we actually had them
light through the um
the um
the equipment on saturday
this was
quick
um
so
we of course
ran into other issues
because you know
this is born hack and what would
networking be without extra issues
uh this one was a new one you know we we
plan for a lot of things we bring a lot
of equipment and you know spare fibers
and all kinds of stuff and what we
hadn't planned for was a beautiful red
digger
next to the well
so um
well i don't know how to say this but
you you see the the red digger this is
um
this one here is our pole
you know that for the crossing road and
we have this nice large digger next to
it
and it's just the the the strings we
attach in order to
make the pole not fall over was actually
going across the digger
so we kind of you know
um
this might be an issue you know
um and then so i wrote this a nice uh
thing and put it in the windscreen with
uh with some of the bone heck
flopper tape
flower
flutter bunt i'm learning touch with
some flutterband and
wrote that hey please take care of our
fiber
and the guy he uh he called and monday
morning i was not here we were all um
we you know planned for the worst hope
for the best situation um it could have
been some idiot driving this thing and
the
complete no-brainer start digging
everywhere
but it turned out to be a nice guy who
was super helpful
and
we had some
we had some help building this actually
i've inverted these two slides let's do
the next one
so we had this guy and we actually
installed
an extra little tube going from our well
to the fence so and then move the pole
and he was helpful doing that with us
and then we have our two and these are
not
publicly employed these are from the
network team
you see we have this i'm the manager i
don't do much and then we have our
supervisor and then we have the ticket
people doing the work right
this is moral support i've heard that is
super important so you don't feel alone
when you work hard
yes
and of course we have tried to anonymize
them so that
to protect the innocent and such
anyway i just wanted to show you uh this
one where i um
this is how it looks uh yesterday
i tried to pick a panoramic view of this
and you see there's a big hole here
we have our well here and then there's a
big hole on the other side so there's a
big hole two meters including our well
and a big hole in the other side and it
was also there that they you know
killed the water pipe earlier
but they were nice and they killed the
water not our
fiber
we like that so sensible people kill
water not our fiber because that would
have been problematic who wants the
fiber cut but um he was really nice that
guy and he got two packets of stroke
rifle and
so that worked
and
this is um it just makes me happy when
you meet people who are sensible who
just
find solutions to crap problems that
none of us have invented and just
ram into them um
and this is the kind of problems that
since we actually were well prepared we
had
actually configured all the switches and
start in advance
we can
i think that when you do good planning
and are well prepared
you have capacity to handle
uh yeah who foresaw this one it might be
in some book in at the municipality that
they're gonna dig now but
uh i'm not gonna look into that one i
don't even know where to find it so a
lot of crap will appear and they will
have a lot of problems we also had this
issue with
all our knock equipment being at the
furthest end of the container so power
cables for the
switches and such
it's uh we
it's not something that the dutch people
have that brings most of the equipment
they use you know shuku which is
not what we use in denmark because
safety
monopoly i don't know why we use these
three-legged things um
so but that was foreseen we actually
bought an extra box from my home i have
spare
because then we could get started this
is planning to make stuff easier and
then we have capacity to handle weird
which always happens for some
reason
okay
so
the end result of this was that we
actually got this um
light through so when you when you when
you build something like this um we know
that
as soon as possible we want to know if
we have a light going through from
our end to the data center in gilster
because that means that we have layer
one up and running we have you know
um stuff has been configured ish right
and when you have layer one up and
running you wanna have layer three up
and running also and of course there was
some configuration issue so that we
didn't have layer 3 at once
that's fine that's happens every year
that we have some non-standard
configuration and
our provider kind of forgets something
so we call them and we know that this
happens but what happened this
this bonhack was that we actually had
internet up and running since monday
afternoon i think that is super cool and
i think the network team
should get an approach for that
[Applause]
okay um we continue as always um
[Music]
this is one of those
marketing
pictures where this is after we cleaned
up
it didn't look like that all the time
but now it looks nice and clean right it
also helps with other things like
finding the right cables and such but
this is our server room um we actually
have room to move now we kind of move
all the firefighting equipment elsewhere
i think that's a super nice idea we're
going to do that next year also
um and then you have all our equipment
we have
our
nox server which runs
virtual machines for dhcp and dns and
what's the third one
and
we have some equipment in the stack
which is the core switches the wireless
controller and
this year we also had an extra
virtual machine
host we had another server and then we
have all the cables coming in and out
and that's a nice setup
one of the
designs that we use here that is
different than from most places is that
we really don't want your data
we want to make an effort in preserving
your privacy and that includes turning
off a lot of logging on these devices
and when we leave we are going to wipe
the servers
that's just how it works so that we will
not have your mac addresses we will not
know
when you went from one tent to the other
you know normal wireless systems they
can track you by mac address when you
move from ap to ap and such
and um all this dns stuff and so on this
is simply not something we log and now
when we're done here we're going to wipe
the servers as we always do so
[Applause]
yes
so this was a little view into our r31
our server room it's not the toilet it's
the one between the toilets just saying
yes
okay
we um we use a bit of fiber on field
and what you see here is me and my phone
going for a walk
a long
walk
and for some reason somebody decided to
put him through the nettles so that i
you know
it's wonderful you know might have an
issue with that you're saying
um but the interesting part here is that
we
we have kilometers of fiber and you can
see this design we have where we
you know
this looks like a standard star topology
no actually it doesn't but it is
so we have
r31 here
in the middle of everything oh i forgot
noisy on this one noisy is over here
i have that one in stock also
so
cute
so we have um a fiber going from we have
a distribution point next to r31 and we
have fibers coming in and out and what
you can do with fiber which is which is
super cool is that you can make passive
connections so what you have from all
the way up to the well through campsite
through down and
down into r31
we have a passive connection for the
fiber which means that if power drops
everywhere else than in data center
gilster or data center r31
then we actually still maintain internet
connection and it means that when you
are on site like imagine you have you
are in the general camping
and for some reason is power outage um
different places you are actually not
affecting the other areas
and that is a super nice feature of this
um
of these fibers so we have fibers with
two cores with virus eight core four
twelve i don't remember numbers
but one like the one that crosses the
road from r31 to our distribution point
it ha it's a twelve core thingy
and it just means that we have um a
different different site or different
area per
fiber and that's that's actually quite
nice
um this is something we have been
discussing
because i'm i'm i'm always doing this um
stupid drunk guy scenario
and it turns out that the
stupid drunkard is not someone who
touches our network at the bone heck and
it's really nice to
be around people who treat our equipment
nice and you know play along because
otherwise we really should have insane
amounts of protection and ensure that
everything is super armored and locked
down and all kinds of stuff that we
don't want to spend our time doing so
you treat our equipment well
and that's that's all we can ask for so
thank you for that
um
these fibers yes some people have them
under their pillow or something we
borrow some left and right actually the
2.4 kilometers i don't think they
include the 300 meters from kamsa so
it's actually more we have
but we still have a bit in spare so we
of course have not abused only used a
bit more than two kilometers why not
um
and all this stuff we get it from event
infra
event info is an organization in holland
that just has
a lot of equipment and now we get back
to the good part about doing bone hack
during corona
there are not other hacker camps
which means like last year we can just
say two of those three of those one of
those oh that one looks nice and then
just pick and choose right
and that's really cool and um
we might need to do a bit more detailed
planning and borrow a bit less in the
coming years if there are other hacker
camps
so
we uh that's that's actually one of the
reasons why i do this um
fairly detailed map about where stuff is
with gps and you know which cable we use
for wear because when we get pressed on
the equipment we want to know
in fairly great detail where stuff was
so that we can you know do a more
minimal solution than this thing where
we can just you know
oh 100 meters that's fine here we have
200 meter cable that's not going to be
as easy if we cannot borrow
all we want
bonheck actually has very little fiber
if any do we have any fiber i don't
think so
born heckles
awesome so
i'm glad that we don't have a microphone
in the
in the audience with the audience
um
some people might say
slander but um the point is that this
will simply not happen without um being
able to borrow ridiculous amounts of
stuff from somewhere this is not
something that we ever want to buy this
is
to use for a week well i don't know
maybe you can rent it but that would
also be very expensive
so
sorry no sorry one of the things that we
have been discussing which we have
kind of shelved for for now
is talking to juniper and have them
deliver everything we point at
but we don't want to draw that card
before we actually
know that everything is going to be
peachy and corn is kind of settled
so this would be one way of handling
some of the equipment
it's much easier for us to have a lot of
the same equipment but
well we're pro so it might not be
necessary it's just way easier okay
so i just want to send a lot of love to
event infra and say
thank you should give them an applause
[Applause]
yes
so so when the dutch people arrive they
have their cars packed and this is very
cool to see and perhaps you should you
know
rent something bigger next year let's
see what happens
okay
that was what i wanted to say about our
core functionality the non-core stuff we
have
a lot of stuff that if it breaks it's
well doesn't affect everybody
only a lot of people
so what we have done is that we have set
up 24 access points
and um
just um take notes because this is going
to be on jeopardy next year
so how many access points were connected
to camp in 2021
i said to the camping
so the um the idea is that well this is
our internal documentation which we are
going to put somewhere sensible but um
we have uh put a lot in different places
and um
actually
i didn't know we had a
a location called hammock hill
i find that to be a super cool name um
so
i went on a field trip to find it i
didn't i just knew that there were three
access points in the bar i forgot to
read our documentation so it was very
difficult to find but hammock hill
the hill part was correct
and
apparently my guess is that this one um
the end of camp is the last one to be
taken down i don't know
maybe
no
so um and then another interesting
detail is that the information disk they
have their own uh
access point
it's because you know a big metal
container is not really good for
wireless traffic so
we we have an access point just outside
the information disk but still doesn't
penetrate and that's very cool to just
so they have had their
access point
um
yes
um the aps were of course used
um and as you can see
um
apparently we have a day night cycle
and
[Music]
i didn't check but um
night time is
i don't think you guys go to bed at
midnight
and we had some
some issues we have one over there which
is who knows and we have
a dropout in the collection but
otherwise this is a graph that looks as
we expect
so
good question two seconds
i remember last last year's average was
1.5 per
participant
so we are actually doing less less than
that this
year but this is um i actually like this
graph it just it actually says a lot
about the activity right
so um
we apparently are at the
40 60ish and then people start arriving
thursday at 12 right
and then we had some extra activity over
the weekend which actually continued
until monday so
that's cool
um
when i look at this graph we had a
discussion about um
[Music]
iot devices
so if we are 300 people and we give
every and everybody has wi-fi on their
batch like they do on other hacker camps
we kind of perhaps need to know this in
advance in the network team because that
will basically double the amount of
people connected it might not be an
issue if they are using really really no
power no traffic but
i think it's worth discussing if you
want twice as many devices connected
so we are going to
have a wireless discussion
the comment is that um last year we
actually had pixel flute running over
wi-fi which gave us extra
connected
yes
um
yes i remember two years ago when i had
this when i held this speech um
this talk i said that having a wi-fi guy
on terrain
is really really cool it solves a lot of
problems before the rise and
we have had this this year also that
well when we set all this up we actually
don't know where people is going to make
their camps we have some black spots we
have all these things that
we so we kind of need to move the access
points a bit during camp
and that requires to have on-site
knowledge about this
so
that is what we have been doing this
time i think it works
ish
it my impression is that it have worked
fairly well i know that there have been
some
issues in different places but we'll try
to rectify them
if we have a guy coming in
at the beginning and taking it down at
the end
we it would not we would not have the
option of um
of changing the topology a bit
so i think that's
a plan that is here to stay that we
somehow run the aps ourselves
okay
um
yes
i'm i've decided that i'm allowed to
spell pixel flute however i want to
anyway this picture is from the bar a
couple of days ago and
you of course see that this is a big
mess as pixel flute is supposed to be
we have
but i actually like this one where i
don't recall his name from
the lion
[Music]
what's his name
rafiki that's true
and he's just sitting there super sin
and it was
a really powerful connection that just
make sure he stayed there that was very
cool and then we of course have our nog
weather map
just because
and then
i hope this is not a spoiler but my
guess is that this is a token
that's my guess i didn't play and then
some weirdo decided that we should have
our nem id login screen also
when i saw it the first time i thought
oh it's a windows machine and some
windows popped up
but apparently
apparently not
anyway as i wrote
we do pixel flute because because
because because why not
and um so we had some infrastructure set
up in in the buy area this was
this was espeon's doing we actually did
not have much to do with it otherwise i
would probably have found
some graphs on that
and that there was something we
discussed last year also that what we
did
we set a pixel through last year also oh
they set up and then
you sat in the bar on wireless so all
your floating of this device was sent
over wireless
to the access point the access point
sent the data back to the wireless
controller which sent the data back to
the pixelfloat machine
yeah about that
so we decided to have this stuff in the
um in the bar so there was a switch and
you could sit there and um
we uh we kind of killed it from wi-fi
and then rate limited on cable
so that was our solution so you could
play along if you were not in the bar
but
it was about it was a bar game it was
okay and then um
the other day um someone from from from
pyjamas
pyjama yes whatever like to be called
he came and said
how many public ips can we get
when i get a request like that i'm
always thinking
what are they up to
because of course i want to say yes
but it is it when they want a lot of
beatrices it usually means that we
should have a chat about what they're
doing so we can see how it fits with our
infrastructure
so um the solution was um
sure do dhcp and when you run out of the
dscp pool subtract 20 so other people
can connect also
um but um it was um
in my opinion a pretty weird thing that
is super cool
so perhaps if you were here an hour ago
you would have heard that talk about
this but they have of course
set up a raspberry pi cluster where when
you connect to this you get your own uh
docker instance with root access where
you can do whatever you want of course
you do
yeah yeah that's the link right so ssh
root whatever and then you get your own
um
you get your own daca instance and as i
also said um
yeah yeah
this can be abused to make problems for
us but hey if that happens we're
probably gonna do something and fix it
and that was fun anyway this is um this
is interesting this is basically give
everybody root access to a hacking
capable machine on our network yeah why
not this is born hack so of course we do
that
and the network team just says yes
they are not they're not all there but
hey come on
okay and then i got another one from the
pajamas
by jamie yes whatever
oh vlan for our esps
we want it for our pixel flute
it's just
what
hm
okay
sure
we can set this up
um
i i i wasn't even going into the
discussion about comparing some wireless
vlan thing with
the 10 gig cable connections in the bar
but
so
how did it go for them
so the question is which of the images
you saw on the other pixel flute thing
was them
well
this was the pixel flute thing
that made so much more sense
i actually think it's really nice it's
just a bunch of diodes and then
hammer it just like you do with the
other pixel flute and then
get a nice blanket out of it it was nice
idea but you know first things
we want to vlan for for pixel flute
[Music]
good luck good luck
i've seen the machinery people have
brought i don't think you're going to
rule that machine i don't think so but
anyway
that looks nice
and then we had a workshop on tito's
yay
yes
hamsa had a
super successful workshop on dtas
it was so successful it took down
network on the entire camp yay
[Applause]
so um as ddos goes i think that was one
of the more successful workshops
but
the thing that actually happened was
that the
clemson moved from noisy to camping
who would have sought that maybe even
perhaps
people in the nog team like cramps might
have known a bit about topology but hey
but the the um the thing we have done is
that we have a
south
vlan
for the camp and the north and uh noisy
in the south and the building is in
south and camping in the north so if you
do weird stuff like having your own 10
gig connection in your tent and do a
workshop on ddos it's smart to be you
know in the same
group
in the same segment
and um so moving to north means that
everything had to go through our router
so um it kind of just you know gave up
it was just
maxed out and that's that's fine it's
just
we kind of changed the design just a tad
for the second workshop so nobody
noticed
tell the people that it tools used were
hp3 and t50 so they might do it next
year okay i'm not to say they would use
h ping 3 and
t50 that's a secret
anyway
i i i think it's funny to make a ddos
workshop and take down the entire
network i think that's so cool
no anyway
that's what i've decided to include in
my
presentation for today
um i noticed that last year um i kind of
forgot this slide so i just we cut the
feed and then we started it again
because there might have been questions
so let's remember this today
i'm other any questions
mike
[Music]
how many ip addresses do we have on camp
that's a really good question
uh public
well we have um is a slash 23 or
something 5p version uh ipv4 and then we
have our own segment for ip version six
a permanent one i actually don't recall
these numbers
slice 21 okay fine so that would be
public ip version
six these would be um yeah some of you
may have noticed that when you go to uh
different sites
they think you are in some other country
um i remember one year in uh bonhag they
thought we were in poland
but it's about which geolocation
database you use and how fast they
updated and such because the ipv4
addresses we have are ones that we
borrow from ripe for this event it's
event ip addresses
and the ipv version 6 is ours and they
will not change so we of course are
going to transition to ipv version 6.
says kamsa
rp version 6 only next year good luck
with that
why did the wi-fi crash
i have this comment
this is the official not coming to this
aliens
it was a solar flare which um you know
and the ufo did and a little small
goblin and you know um massive over i
don't know
it's a secret
it wasn't a uh
it was the manual error in any way
i can either confirm no deny that it was
a manual error
how much data did we download and upload
this year and how does that compare to
last year
um i will um
ask my um one of my minions about this i
can see that he's always working hard on
that number
7.41 terabytes downloaded so we
downloaded
7.41 terabytes and we uploaded 2.74
terabytes
it's comparable to last year i remember
it as five last year
yes
we could for example use
we could for example use five times as
much bandwidth
for example
and even better
not to be mentioned to people but there
might have been a slight uh difference
in the bandwidth available on ip version
four and six
as in factor three or five or something
so
uh there also was uh used more bandwidth
than
visible there because uh
that
those graphs are five minute averages
yes we might have uh peaks that are much
larger we had a lot of peaks around uh
one gig
on 22 narrators
yes
but um yeah
this is farming averages which of course
means that
there might be instances probably a lot
of instances where someone maxes it out
for five seconds and such we would not
be able to see that here
yes
any more questions
then i think the network team deserves a
big round of applause
[Applause]