so you've seen these guys before have
you had a good day so far yeah awesome
this panel is going to be about bug
bounties over the last couple of years
we've seen an explosion in crowd surged
security bug bounty being at the
foremost thank you finally that's good
stuff you've all been on different ends
of the bug boundary spectrum I mean mark
you hosted by Buddy Program friends
you're obviously a bug bounty hunter and
added does bug found hanging its well
only do mostly in open source projects
is that fair to say there's not really
found Taylor on this no right so that's
this explosion in Christ or security
continues to move forward where do you
think bug bounties are going to end up
how what we what will we see in like
five years from now just go ahead anyone
okay I'll start because yeah so
basically what bug bounties are I mean
it's it's a pretty big difference
between bug bounties and I wanted to
talk with and I think we need to
actually define that if we're going to
have a meaningful debate because when
when the Microsoft who was like at the
forefront of this actually introduced
their bug bounty it was because
researchers were complaining that
Microsoft seem to expect people to
report bugs for free and this was not a
web box this was like buffer overflows
in internet explorer and that time so
bugs that typically takes a little bit
longer to both fine and develop a
working is about exploit for what we're
talking about now I mean the background
is seen today is like ninety ninety-five
percent web services or web pages web
service is like so are we talking about
everything
talking about the majority or what are
we talking about sure all right mmm that
it's now all of the above we'll see what
we get into of course there's no set
rules this okay I basically think that
bug bounties are to some degree is going
to replace traditional pen testing
because it's basically the same thing
but without you know actually having pen
testers on staff but it's mostly black
box I know that back road for example
does invites where they provide more
information about the target but we
can't really have a debate about that
because that is actually a pen test
company with three Lancers and a
different economic model so there's
basically no difference acceptance there
are more people but the thing that I'm
concerned about because my main goal is
to like think about how do we actually
improve security overall not like how
can we get people to have fun and earn a
lot of money at the same time that's
also good I'm not against that but we
shouldn't do it at the expense of
actually improving security and I am
kind of like for a couple of years I've
been skeptical about how useful
traditional pen testing actually is
because it's like putting bandaid on
someone who suffers from Hema failure
which is bleeding disorder that you know
it doesn't work I mean one guy is
patching bugs that are being reported
and another one is producing the same
type of bugs would you get a green
apparently it doesn't sort of meaningful
flow otherwise yeah it won't work all
right so penetration testing doesn't
work in that context what do you guys
agree I mean the biggest difference
between bug bounties and penetration
tests is that XP
tations like being a part of a bug
bounty program you don't have any
expectations at all so the company can
really expect you to look like the only
hope they have is that their target is
as interesting as it gets for you to
actually spend time on like Google or
doing this researchers grant with like
they realized already that there's no
way for us to actually be the most
attractive company to to spend time on
looking for vulnerability so let's take
the good like the best people pay them a
monthly like monthly fee yeah best
people yeah best people also thanks no
no but like pay the money just for
looking and I think that's a that's the
biggest problem every time you talk
about talk with these marketplaces cynic
hacker one bug crowd the problem is that
they can't really like talked with the
customer and say like okay so how much
time was spent on your target like did
people actually look exactly that is
also something that I've thought about
because when I'm not going to you know
do like a company pitch or something but
when when I'll get assigned to looking
at something the fact that I I tell my
client that I've looked at this and I've
read all the code and I've checked all
those things and I didn't really find
anything that's also that is you're also
all value because that means we did this
correctly can we apply this on other
areas and you don't get you don't really
get on that no absolutely no and some of
them trying to solve it like soon
Acastus VPN solution where you're
tunneling all the things that you're
doing through them so they can actually
start calculating like coverage and
stuff like that but but so so they're
like trying to figure it out and which
makes sense but that's just because they
want to be able to show the customers
that somebody was actually looking for
stuff this is kind of interesting
cuz I could never work like that i would
be i learned i would be like they're
going to laugh at me I'm doing see ya
ridiculous the hell are you doing that
all right I got a question for mark
because you've been on the other side of
this you might say running a bug bounty
program how do you think that bug
bounties complement internal security
reviews so this is working you might
have to turn it on I got the green line
really yeah someone do something no no
might have told me closer closer yeah
yeah really close so we kind of did
something slightly different we don't
really view book Bonnie as like the
silver bullet or the panacea yeah hold
it like that like right here yeah there
we go it got weird guys yeah it is feel
strange moving on really swiftly so we
never really wanted a Nessus or an nmap
report right when we do a penetration
test so we don't actually call them
penetration tests we call them attack
simulations and if you look at the RFC
stuff or if you vaguely remember it from
when I talked about it this morning
we've actually written in pseudocode
what an attack simulation should look
like when we launched various elements
of our infrastructure our products and
that actually starts but we actually do
that with one vendor possibly two and
we've built like those relationships so
that it's not a vendor it's actually a
partner and they're not like riders in
terms of like you know they follow our
culture totally but they get it they get
what's important to us and you get
higher we release products and they also
get what their focus and player
experiences so we actually used our own
feedback culture on our RFC process to
come up with something like that so it's
kind of different so we have a lot of it
actually down to
pseudocode or other people might call it
a process and again we realize it's not
going to be one hundred percent coverage
similarly with the bug bounty it's not
going to be a hundred percent coverage
but what you get with the attack
simulation is you get someone who's very
familiar with your infrastructure what
they may not be the best XSS are the
best SQL I or the best you know
similarly if you do like a secure code
review which we also have fairly sort of
not automated but follows a particular
structure you know they may not be the
best C++ person the spotter buffer
overflow but you actually get that to a
degree with the bug bounty that you get
the best XSS person looking at some
absolutely crazy did you never knew
existed and its really like insecurities
we talk about defense in depth a lot and
it's kind of similar to that and that no
one tool is actually going to solve
everything and that's the way I think
book bonnie is going to go it's just
going to become another tool in the
arsenal defender and you got to
realize that with bhabani you set your
scope right but and there's going to be
a lot of wasters that are going to find
things that you're not interested in and
then you're going to have the best
researchers who we talked about earlier
in terms of providing feedback you
listen to that feedback but also you got
to be prepared that some of those best
researchers are the best researchers
because they kind of skirt the borders
of what your scope actually is right so
you got to be lenient on that as well
and you got to be prepared for them
finding stuff that you're never going to
find but it's really just another kind
of tool in your arsenal and I can only
deliver so much and you're never going
to get a hundred percent coverage but in
my view it's better being in a bug
bounty program then not getting that
right because essentially what it is is
now you get the report they were
scanning you noe yeah they were reverse
in your code you just didn't know like
now you know right so one of the things
we did is we actually increased the
minimum payment from 50 to 250 right so
talking about the point the guys were
making is like you don't know how long a
person has spent right
but you want to reward them because you
want them to still be interested you
want them to come back so one of the
things as well if you recently did is
where change in our client our client is
based on adobe air which is a phenomenal
piece of technology but that's a joke
you should you should totally do it in
like no Jas stead yeah I hear from
totally submit something I was thinking
Java like Java on the client that works
really well with flash old Java yeah
flash and java 6 java 6 on Safari 6 as
well I'll totally pop calc what was I
saying so what we've done with the
league client update which is our new
client which we've actually blogged
about it extensively on engineering WI
gamescom but we've also released it to
people like this guy so I don't actually
know if he's looked at it given your
also in our research program you should
have access to it right so we were
incentivizing people to actually look at
it as opposed to you know hiding away
from it it'll make sense does that
answer the question yeah I think so I'm
not sure what the original question was
I can't hang can I just jump in ice
because i think i think this this whole
thing with actually racing the rewards
is probably a good way to go to reduce
the noise I mean and to actually get
people to look at things that you think
is interesting that I mean if you are
concerned about a certain function you
could theoretically at least raise the
rewards for that function and you'll get
more people looking at it so that's
actually a really good good way to do it
and I would the potential no I wouldn't
it would probably maybe actually
increased the noise because people would
want money did you just do a 180 what
yeah just turn around yeah change it is
360 it's only 180 360 that would be
pleased circle I think he argued against
i would i would like to oh yeah i would
like to i would like for the audience to
take no
at one point in my life I could do an
ollie 360 by starting to some don't
think I can do that anymore yeah
starting some like you could do debate
all by yourself yeah how have you seen
his Twitter yeah it's usually just him
in the group yeah just fighting I mean
we're no jabbing no we're basically
patting each other's backs I know all
right so I want to talk a little bit
about the motivation for bounty hunters
like you've been scanning we're
searching for bugs in open source
projects you've been looking at it
mainly on paying bug penalty project so
when it comes to bug bounties what is
the motivation there is a purely
monetary is there some altruistic
aspects only money no but like i see
like appreciation is is awesome also
being a developer from the beginning and
then go into security and figuring out
that some developers are have done wrong
is of course like you always feels good
being smarter than anyone else like of
course it's ego ego boasting boosting
but also like you did this like as you
mentioned like you did this stuff anyway
on companies that didn't allow it like
now you're able to actually do it and
you don't need to VPN the out of
yourself to to do it now you can
actually like you use your regular IP
without feeling nervous like so so like
people have hacked like you don't need
to be a black hat and like i'm gonna
earn money and like people has up
applications before without getting
money like now you can do the same thing
and you can actually get appreciation
like like I showed you like the first
interaction I had was just getting a
bunch of t-shirts and that was awesome I
needed t-shirts so like that was good
but I mean it's just a maturity of the
like as the question we had before and I
forgot to like add into that is that
it's like if you think about a company
creates a product
and like internally you have a bunch of
skills to build this product and you
need to like increase the skills
internally to build a better product so
you teach the team on how to build a
better product this is like in general
of the functionality but also in
security and then you use professionals
to see that you built a proper product
in terms of security you you use pen
testers and then you put the product out
there like the logical next step would
be to allow people to actually tell you
if if you got them so far to put up a
public application and being vulnerable
at that time anybody should be able to
actually report it back to you like it
makes so much sense having that last
step so it's it's a natural like the
lateral last proof of concept that your
application is secure I would actually
like like to point out that as while I'm
skeptical about the the long-term
benefits oh yeah I bug bounties I think
it's awesome that it has actually made a
lot of companies take the step to
actually create a vulnerability
disclosure process yes but you you don't
have to get sued all exact time with
that said I still think that you
shouldn't really just go on the internet
and think that it's your right to go
look for bugs in any website no it's
still like well but on the other hand if
I buy a car from general ya know ders of
course I'm allowed to hack it's my car
no if you want to sue me you yeah
initially anyway it's still good that
they actually have said that we accept
vulnerability awards but it's kind of
redundant because outside of the US they
can't sue anyway it doesn't matter no
you're right so it's the same logic work
for buying an application using your
computer would you say yeah I mean
Oracle and also Microsoft at some point
has been actually you know really
aggressive about when people have
reported bugs in their stuff but this is
a really long time ago
and people need to let it go because
it's I mean Oracle wasn't addressed a
long time ago but there they they have
no teeth no no no they're all talk and
everyone knows it you're breaking the
terms basically yeah like I mean so that
part I don't but I agree that it's still
good that because sometimes you actually
stumble across a bug in a web page yeah
and you're like well I didn't even try
and of course you should be able to
report it yeah i mean that's that's
common sense so I actually totally agree
that bug bounties and Katie mussoorie
and specifically has actually done like
huge iso standard I am in actually
getting that implemented again a lot of
cases because like he she helped the
Netherlands to actually get all the
banks in Netherlands must have a
responsibility ocean policy she was one
actually very involved in that program
so basically that means that if you find
a vulnerability in a bank in Netherlands
all of them have a responsibility OSHA
policy and most of them are also paying
like so all the banks basically have a
bug bounty program in netherlands which
is crazy yeah and I mean this is very
good I think we're all doing on that but
it's sort of different from the from the
idea that finding bugs is the way to
improve security because finding boxes
like of course one way but something
that I'm sort of concerned about is that
bug bounties bring more people into
security but they bring it into a very
niche area and currently I don't really
see a good way of getting people from
that niche area into the areas where
where more people are actually needed
because bug finding is not you know the
biggest problem in love security
security engineering is where people are
needed and right now I don't see a good
model for actually getting those people
into that and I'm a little bit afraid of
if you come from a country like India or
something where you don't make a lot of
money yeah and you make a lot of money
doing this you want having a reason to
move on no to something else which I'm
I'm a little bit worried about but I
think this can be solved but everyone
has to actually want to improve security
as long as we're stuck in in like I find
bugs I make more money than you do and I
work less and I have more fun like what
do you think about you by using google
google had this thing where you get
patch rewards like when you actually do
patches you get more work for for the
bug ya like what do you think and
Microsoft has also has one where is Sam
looks yeah yeah if if you can actually
improve a homosexual miss ya securely
control that you also get money yeah
this is the way forward this is much
harder yeah what would you yeah but I
mean someone like like like they said
all I say being regular easy from gr
security he should get tons of money
yeah he's done so much work which is
really underappreciated yeah and he he
is like I will not develop an expert in
my life because it's lame it doesn't
really help anyone know so i really
think that we're not really premiering
the people that we should that be
sharing and i think we could all do a
little bit better yeah but they always
say like being in the red team is easy
the blue team is the heart thing yeah
like preventing i think if you're from
North and Berg a hero is going to do a
talk next Thursday was about how to make
defense as far as orphans you should all
go there this was not planned to feel
good pitch but it is still so yeah
that's
yeah all right so what do you have
something no I think he could just come
work a riot Yeah right wow that would
make defense more exciting all right so
if anyone didn't hear that he wants you
to come work it right but he actually
has a valid point I mean you don't
actually have to go work it right but
you could try to implement what riot and
Etsy and yet a few others are doing and
it will be really fun those guys are the
real mean but do you haven't that's a
good argument also because a lot of my
like bug hunting friends a lot of them
has gained jobs being on the blue side
instead like bit pork for example he he
got a job at Tesla and his job is not
only to find bugs with Tesla he's
actually doing stuff to prevent bugs so
I think it's also a way in two like I'm
I tell this was for people who already
knew this stuff yeah but I I know a
bunch of like people that like joined in
through the bug bounty and then got
recruited two like Facebook team like
what like the biggest guys in the
facebook security team or guys that
hacked facebook like found bugs in it
like it so so there's a bunch of people
that gets to the other side just because
through the bug bounty and they get
recruited cuz of that so I think I think
a lot of it's because the quality of
their report right yeah it's not just
about hairs of vulnerability here's no
no there are a lot of people that
actually go hey here's how I would fix
it that we genuinely have seen a lot of
those discussions like so the talent is
out there and the interest is out there
yeah it's just that they're not
necessarily the people that are going to
tweet or like you know do a CFP for
defcon or like oh hey you I dropped
another Oh day we go but like the talent
is actually out there and there are
people that file amazing reports and
then actually get into a genuine
discussion that goes on for ages with
the engineer like watching both sides
learn I think this is this is actually
really important that's something that I
want
to include it in my talk but really get
in and this is mainly do about my
open-source auditing stuff that it's not
about finding the box it's about
reporting them in a way that makes
someone fix more than just a bug because
in a lot of cases you're what you're
actually finding is a pattern yeah of of
not actually developing or engineering
your your application in in in a safe
way so if you so as I said matter most
and this is I'm not saying that this is
down to what I reported to them but
they've actually made you know several
changes in regards to design which is
the best way to fix things because
you're actually mitigating things that
haven't even been introduced yeah which
is like the way to go and this is
something if you want to participate in
the bug bounty and you're gonna report
stuff don't just find a bug and then
report it as soon as you can with a
minimal amount of information which you
will probably do anyway because it's
basically the IOT thing its first to
market if you don't report it first you
won't get the money yeah but it depends
though yeah they're different different
but I do if you can actually report it
and actually you know analyze the root
cause and actually suggest a like what
they should be doing instead not just
one line use a random string just you
know actually you know check what what
kind of you know random number
generators does this language have
because a lot of languages have pretty
crappy random number generators which
will only introduce another bug so the
main goal of actually reporting bugs
should be to not fix the bargain to fix
the root cause of the bug and this is
something that I fear also it's like
often missing in bio boundaries because
of the I'm have to report it first yeah
so but that's less like an economic
issue more than yeah anything else
there's some differences like some
companies they can actually get the same
report twice and they will pick the one
that wrote the best report which is kind
of like they like you wrote it best you
are not the first one but you wrote the
best review actually understood yeah
exactly actually understood the buggy
and what so how do you I mean you said
that you get really good reports what
are your rates you like bad reports good
report I I need an exact figure yeah
like this is going on my blog actual
percentage like how much noise in Brazil
park figure yeah I think it I think at
the start a vast majority of it was
noise definitely a lot of clickjacking a
lot of Allah you know automated reply is
a clip herbs cancer yes not so much
burps gun was like dirt Buster little
bear buster you know like free Nessus
really not even n mop but like got stuff
that's easier than NM up so if someone
thinks that I'm maps heart that probably
gives you an indication of their skill
level yeah so I think as things have
calmed down and it's mostly the better
researchers that are in our program but
we also have a little bit of exclusivity
because we have a private program ours
isn't public so you have to be invited
into the program in that case I would
say that it's even more of a traditional
pen test it's crowd-sourced but I won't
agree well I'd say no because you can
still find something but you still went
public with the blog post so you're our
public but you still need to figure out
that you should email you guys to get an
invite yeah but like if someone emails
us and they're not in hacker one program
we're not going to go off look okay
here's the setup submitted through that
way and then we'll make sure that the
person is a quality researcher and if
the person is much more noise than Santa
than actual fact we'll work with them
we'll give them feedback
then if you don't improve we'll kick
them out this is also something that I
I've been this is not you know an issue
for me personally but I think it's kind
of it's kind of sad because this is in
the industry that I work in and that I
care about a lot but I saw this
presentation by Google guy who handles
their vulnerability rewards program what
is called and it was like over ninety
one-percent it's like yeah I'm sorry
this is not about and that is a terribly
high figure it's very common knowledge a
someone from hacker once said that yeah
we're working on some you know machine
learning algorithms to reduce that and I
think oh yeah I mean economically
speaking that's one way to do it but if
we actually want to have it an industry
that actually knows what they're doing
we should we that out yeah yeah on
another level but I mean Google were
able to wait it out because we are a
private program yeah but it agree Google
team did a cool thing they they got a
guy that started reporting like unlike
very very like non interesting reports
so they did daily like this they emailed
him and said can we do a skype like one
hour skype together and they call them
up and spend one hour with them
explaining exactly what they were
interested in like this is this and that
like look for this like if you can find
this that will be awesome this hour
resulted in him being one of the top
ranked hackers of the Google
vulnerability problems that I think he's
actually number two yeah yeah good yeah
so they like that's where we spend one
hour with him and he just ah that's the
things you gonna you want me to look for
and he was like super having read their
scope I kind of find it hard to I mean
how can you misinterpret that I mean you
just wanted I don't know he's not rocket
surgery no but he he needed to do
surgery yes yeah he needed some nice
it's a little bit harder than rockets I
am
science brain surgery brain surgery
science rain science rocket surgery
rocket surgery turns out of beer batter
your science actually exists a rocket
surgery is much more fun yeah rocket
surgery I think we'll get surgery all
the people that go like yeah I'm gonna
fill up on the but I mean there's the
Freelon must decision or something yeah
that sounds like something he was like
no time for that pass it off but now
you're now you're just talking about
different ways to learn stuff like some
people understand stuff by reading he
learned more about talking about it with
guys for an hour I agree to a certain
degree but 90 more than ninety
one-percent is more laziness and hoping
to get paid than absolutely than that I
think and we should I mean I would I
don't really I'm not actually impacted
by this but if I was running a bug
bounty program and I had that sort of
noise ratio I would actually suggest to
my bug bounty platform that they would
like implement some sort of if you if
your ratio is like 9221 yeah something
then then then then you're banned for a
month yeah yeah absolutely because once
one program had a class actually the
best solution to this one program had
this really long description and far
down in the description it said if you
don't include the word orange in your
report it's going to get automatically
cancelled so they had to read the whole
policy and they had an automation like
if the word orange is not there cancel
the reports I had a teacher did
something similar where like you have to
read everything before you start and it
said well at least go and then at the
end yeah it said don't do anything of
the above and everyone started doing
yeah and we we have the same thing so
we're hated that teacher we're all
idiots yeah it's gonna be but I think
that probably works somehow in some
sense I would love to see their noise
ratio on reports that has the word
orange and is noise I would love that so
mark which color you are is where I
going to pick for their reporting it's
gonna be orange or red or what are you
gonna go with
probably green green irish green yeah oh
my god that's cool all right cool it's
about time to wrap this up actually that
was 35 40 minutes that flew by we have
time for one or two questions from the
crowd if there's any out there is one
here all right I'm going to run down
with a mic at that you just spoke about
maybe cancelling your ability to report
for like half a month if the noise is
too high noise the signal ratio you pawn
just did that and it was very ill
received in the community to the point
where they've just the last week ago
they've gone back and retroactively Lee
paid researchers money for other stuff
that they found would you like to do
another 180 I mean I don't really know
what the background storage this was but
i think i remember seeing something
about them changing their scope yeah
okay so in that case it doesn't really
apply because they are actually behaving
they're not actually living up to their
word they said that this and this and
this and this is in our scope people
reported that and they removed it from
the scope and set noise that is I mean
that is not the researchers fault I I
actually I don't wanna I mean that
that's beside the point but so in that
case in know if they're using a platform
that might happen automatically but that
could be revoked manually and but I
think a lot of it is communication I
think what a lot of companies don't do
is actually communicate correctly so
hopefully no one will disagree but I
think we actually make a really concrete
effort on communicating there are people
in this room huge bug bounties I have
rejected and we had a very fruitful and
honest discussion and I think a lot of
it is because we were upfront and honest
and we took the feedback on and they
took their feedback and ultimately the
bug bounty program got better for it
yeah I think it's really down to
communication I think you need to
realize too that riot introduced their
bug bounty program
you had an application security program
you had something to actually feel or
you had something to feed it into which
a lot of people don't a lot of people
just start bug bounty programs because
hey this sounds like an easy way to have
a pen test and then you know it's
actually like my my example with the
band-aids and hemophilia that 11 on on
the one side you're putting on band-aids
and on the other side you're still
bleeding today so it's like it one guy
at ebay actually like eBay was really
very connected to paypal this is selling
Oh dayson ebay and not not not actually
hit no but he was working for the blue
team at eBay ok and I talked with him
and because ebay back then was very
connected to paypal and paypal ran a bug
bounty program but there was a lot of
assets on paypal that could be accessed
by ebay and ebay did not run a bug
bounty program so it was a really like
interest conflict of interest in that
sense where we were able to utilize
stuff on eBay which nobody reported and
and then my chain yeah absolutely but
but the interesting thing was I talked
with him and like why the hell do you
don't use like why don't you do a bug
bounty and the interesting thing was he
was like you know what will happen like
we will get like a report with an XSS
and we're going to get like if you
insert this in this input box and
there's an XSS and what would happen is
that the security team here we'll go to
the developer and say this input box has
an exercise and what will happen that
developer will fix that input box that's
a really good reason not to have it yeah
I won't be there for you have something
to feed it exactly so what happened then
is then you have 34 other input boxes
that nobody cared about and then it will
just be an infinite wheel of like
throwing out money and like not caring
about their not getting no facing the
design issue that's the best we have
courses it's important so I mean that's
that's that's also something that I feel
that a lot of the entrepreneurism if
that's a word in bug bounties is
actually if I'm if I'm allowed to be
cynical I have had three beers so I'm
allowed
cynical is actually taking advantage of
people's poor security practices instead
of actually helping them improve their
security practices which I don't like
either but this is a problem that I
existed long I mean that's a penetrating
I very much think it's the
responsibility of the company not the
researchers though it is but we are
supposed to be the subject matter
experts and we're supposed to help them
we're not just supposed to yeah to our
own but it's been stressed we we follow
their homes that they said are we going
to have a fight no no no this no this is
where things get started if it sounds
like to play area sleep no but I mean if
they put up rules and you follow those
rules and you do what they say like the
expectations on the research it should
not be higher than the actual
expectations that they want from you so
no but I mean and this is this is
probably where are where where are our
opinions really yeah yeah we the thing
is that me in France of discusses yeah
unfortunately matsu this discussion just
when we have to end it yeah really sorry
we'll have to pick it up again at some
later point have two beers yeah yeah
exactly find these guys after dinner
hash it out alright that was the last
trace all and and you will find me by
the trail of dead France no all right
those the last talk for today about 10
minutes we're going to wrap up first let
me please thank our speakers and
especially friends and ASMR yeah hog
friendly uh yes
I