so
[Music]
that actually is doing containers it's
the most
[Music]
you're staging on production and get
bugs goes back into dev that whole loop
and cycle is key and paramount as part
of the DevOps process being it to be
fast and quick helps things out docker
helps make that happen a perfect sample
bug fixes you want to be able to a bug
comes in you want to get it out ASAP
doctor can help facilitate that security
updates oh my god you know open SSL
vulnerability
maybe I'm vulnerable stat let me go
ahead and patch my container ship it
back out so I'm going to fix that patch
really quick that's another thing where
docker helps facilitate that very fast
sorry I collect one too many times
configuration management so talk a
little bit about docker now I'm gonna
talk about configuration manager
configuration management and the top
level is just a way to ensure that it's
a process that ensures your changes are
consistent it's you know based off of
what you build what you want for your
production or your development
environment whatever it is that you're
building you have a set of requirements
you have a set of what it needs to be
configured as and configuration
management is ensuring up actually build
that way one of the big tools that I use
its puppet
I like puppet but puppet is the only one
that you can use this talk I'll may only
be using puppet to show pace with
examples but there's other tools out
there as well such as chef and honestly
ant Ville is a little bit newer now it's
only been a couple years now on the
block hasn't been around too much so
most people might be more familiar with
puppets been around for waterway brought
a while now so again big thing while
like of it is the cleared of language
you know it's also it has the plant
server paradigm and it has a REST API if
you want to you know do a whole lot more
advanced things it's a mature framework
there's a lot of contributors to it
there's a public forge where you can
find a whole bunch of modules that
people have contributed to and actually
download them use them there's a whole
lot of examples out there so it's pretty
user friendly for someone that is just
starting out again the most work you
have the public master and a public
slave your slaves are all the notes and
when they run the puppet agent that's
running on the system you do have to
have an agent on the system some people
don't like that so if you're using
public be aware of that so if you're
running an agent on the system it runs
it goes back to pub master pull-downs
catalog what is my configuration
supposed to look like what am I supposed
to have so that's the sign on the puppet
master itself it then goes through and
defines on that whether it's you know
setting up particular sort of permission
whether it's you know installing
particular applications whatever the
case may be it then feeds it back into
the puppet master saying hey this is
what I change and this is what I did so
it's continues across but it helps
ensure that you have a set standard and
that standard is repeatable because on
the public master I'll get into this in
demonstration you can create a manifest
that can be applied to multiple
different notes which means you only
have to do it once and apply the same
change across everything which is very
beneficial especially in a large
environment when you start sealing to
you know tens hundreds you know
thousands of hosts we go right at once
and use it multiple times it's a little
bit about security so security a lot of
people this might be review some
examples good security concepts when
studying through secured us you are
disabled and necessary services you know
why
you're not using it it's bad you
shouldn't do it also remove unnecessary
packages a patch
even if it's on there and it's not
running probably still a bad thing he
probably shouldn't have it on there
keeping things as lightweight as
possible is in my opinion a good
practice for security when you're
setting up your environment for
operations even in development it's a
good up setting the limits on who has
access to what so again you don't want
every user to have access to every file
that is probably a bad thing you know if
someone happens to have access that they
shouldn't then things good leaves or
they do bad things in a production
environment that's definitely not what
you want in developmental environment
probably not what you want so you should
probably treat your development
environment the same as your production
environment if you can one of the things
is configuration SSH is a good example
of this
does he fall configuration for a reason
it will work for a majority of people
but all because it's a default
configuration does not mean it's secure
configuration should probably not be a
labs login as SSH
sometimes by default it can so going
through those default configurations and
ensuring they're set to what you want
for based on your particular entities is
paramount and important puppet helps
facilitate that one of the things that I
use in puppet is it's open sourced as
you can see here you go to github com
it's a collection of puppet modules
they're also on the public
port as well and basically it's a it's a
framework that enables a lot of default
compliance and security standards from
the get go out of the box by using sim
you can actually for the most part be
completely almost 100% complying with
most of like nest 853 regression for
like all the different standards that
they recommend you should do which in my
opinion is a good thing it gets you to a
good known starting location they also
include some tools in the sent framework
such as you know opens gap which is you
know the framework to actually be able
to run reports they have compliance he
built in so you can actually do matching
one to one from you know if you happen
to be using hippo or you happen to be
using
you know sig you know you can do that
one-to-one mapping between what your
compliance is dictates and what might be
you referenced within like NIST or
whatever standard so that's why I use
location and you know what you can do
from there on he's probably an oddity as
well so what are the common things a lot
of people like to audit package
installations login authentications
and if I'm using puppet I want to know
what puppet changed and if it changed
anything whatsoever I want to make sure
I disable the service some of the things
I use for auto box is a lot of people
might be familiar with the elk stack I
use elk just because I like rare fauna a
little bit more than kibana as far as
for view
alongs one of the big things why Allegra
fauna is hopefully no one is in your
prints belong or elastic yeah cuz I
don't like kebab with her fauna it's
open source which means there's a lot
more flexibility one of the things with
her fauna that you can actually do is by
default
lock it down to where you can do you
know use your authentication sometimes
with Cubana you have to buy the x-pac
and do some other drinks for free I'm
all about free if it's free I don't have
to pay for it I can use it also it's a
better business sale for sometimes in
companies
what's the bang for the buck and a lot
of people they ask well if I'm gonna
spend X dollars why does it really help
me security you might not see it
initially so selling freeze sometimes a
little bit easier so container security
this time where I think daughter is
gonna be a huge player in the field
moving forward if it already hasn't a
lot of people are getting up to speed
with it and it greatly improves your
security posture so not only can you do
with a post security but then you can
also have doctor security goals one of
the biggest things that it helps with is
using kernel features such as C groups
and you know needs these I'll talk about
those here in a minute but those are two
critical things that helps ensure your
doctor containers are running in a semi
isolated safe to help ensure that one's
not talking to the other all still in
the same host of webs you can also start
applying you know a Palmer which is by
default built-ins on the doctor or the
doctor daemon itself or selinux if you
haven't do running you know on that on
your host OS as well and there's a lot
of great talks out there if you want to
do
YouTube for docker a bomber doctor
docker selinux on they'll walk you
through actually setting up those for
your environment if you choose alright
so kernel namespace why does it matter
namespaces are really something I
started learning about a couple years
ago also as I started learning docker
doesn't realize the kernel features that
were available that doctor was actually
using and once I read about them I was
like holy cow like why didn't we use
this why haven't I been using this to
begin with you use without realizing it
but other times you don't so don't be
utilizing it utilizes it having the
builders actually mount a volume inside
your dog container then it sees and if
your namespace is written in such a way
it won't see the other things
surrounding where that comes into play
is for example the root filesystem a lot
of times you know you don't want
everyone looking approved but there
might be certain things that you want to
mount and for example if you're running
a container that is you know just
parsing logs you might want to mount you
know var log as a read-only so I can
actually read the Box the map see it
helps do that the application that's
running always starts as pin1
it's the first thing that starts up in
the container
well inside docker container the pig
namespace is unique to the post so
within the docker namespace it actually
shows up as one external it might be you
know one two three four five whatever
sequence that it actually
on the host OS which helps that
separation I mention it more so that you
are actually aware if you're trying to
debug and you're on the host OS trying
to debug what's going on you might have
a hundred different containers running
trying to understand the difference and
you're inside one container it shows up
this head one and it's not the same
extra so that's more just for is
critical because you can allow an
application to run as root internal to
your container that isn't root on the
host OS so that is a big one there used
to be some people that were scared about
you know getting you know elevated
privileges to read in the host OS in
earlier verses a docker that actually
was a problem that was actually patched
early on one dot X cycle so if you're
concerned about that look it up you're
seeing you read people how it's actually
been patched what the BraunAbility was
and why it's not an isolated issue
anymore so one of the things I like
about C groups is similar to like in
VMware or whatever the case may be you
can limit your actually VM so the amount
of memory in or CPU that they actually
end up taking so control groups allow
that within a doctor container so you
where it's really useful is for example
as an Operations perspective you can set
control groups on a particular set of
containers immediately like memory we
all know Java sometimes likes to eat up
a lot of memory well if you run a
hundred containers that all eat up 32
gigs of memory and you only have 32 gigs
on your system that's probably not going
to be a good thing you can sexy groups
to limit the amount of memory per
container and in essence kill the
containers you know when they get to a
certain part and restart them that's a
whole separate talk with Java and Java
containers in memory but it's something
to be aware of as you can
put limits which is very good all right
so now putting it all together again
like I said I use simple external
modules with puppet to initially set up
my secure our webs wouldn't see here is
a set of code initially within within a
puppet by default there is the site
manifest the site manifest is kind of
your defaults that applies globally
across your entire environment puppet
also has the construct of you can have
multiple environments
I'll get into that but to be aware of if
you can use the same puppet master for
both a production environment and a dev
environment based on how you set it up
as you can see here the environment I'm
in a descent which actually has to be
the production environment as well it's
just assembly but in here you can
actually see the type of clients profile
okay I talked about clients previously
what this compliance profile is you can
read the same documentation to get more
better understanding it's just
compliance to markup so you can actually
see you know what is actually hitting if
things are failing itself but I'm saying
I'm accent which means I want it
compliant and fully secure between I
want to use all the sim framework which
from setting something up from the
ground up and you're just starting out
that's what I would recommend and you
can start you know going from there
again this is the same site that PP you
see down there very bottom some other
options that are uses here as a database
it allows you to set different variables
for different notes and/or environments
and a higher level contract which allows
you to reuse that same manifest across
multiple different nodes like I've
mentioned earlier so once you actually
have your site
peep-peep you have and your see that
there's these are all the ones that I
have to find right now which is this
small test environment which I have
running on the laptop is the for host
names that I have running and I'm gonna
take a look right here at the puppet
site one basically what this shows is it
shows the classes that I actually want
to include that we're not part of the
standard site Fifi's and as you see here
I've included quite a few you know one
of the big ones that I you know decide
to add which is the FTP boot which just
allows me to pixie boot which is high
boot strapped all my other themes are
teacake is a key thing to mention real
quick if you're using puppet I recommend
you to take a look at our 10k it allows
you to actually sync your code directly
with a github or any other git
repository whether it's an internal base
kit or an external base yet you can
actually do that CIC be for public
manifests of modules as well and tie it
to particular tags and versions alright
so for puppet with docker how do you do
it
Gareth it is approved by on the puppet
forge there's actually a puppet docker
module that's based off of Garris I use
his as you to actually set up docker it
facilitates the framework around
installing docker as well as running all
your
patience so real quick in essence of
time I will go through the demonstration
because the demonstration is mainly
focused on this aspect so what I'm
logging here is I have both my puppet VM
and as well as my daugher VM within
puppet you'll see that I'm in the
production environment in the modules
and a site module which is the one that
has everything defined and your notice I
have both docker production and docker
engine X docker production all it
basically does is installs docker and
sets up the environment for docker here
at the very bottom you're noticed that I
have IP tables rules
that's because IP tables are needed to
for communication between docker hosts
and the actual outside you can't have
two things managed IP tables and puppet
manages IP tables so therefore you have
to add those in manually the docker
engine X is actually what installs my
containers themselves and over here on
your see that I actually don't have any
docker containers running no docker
images so over here I'll go into my
hosts if I can type
edit my daugher post configure see that
I have the docker engine X commented out
once I uncomment it go back over to my
docker host I'm gonna elevate to route
just because I'm forcing puppet to run
but in general publicly run
automatically in the background so it's
gonna go through this is what I was
talking about earlier it's talking back
to the master saying hey what's my
configuration what does it need to be so
I can actually you know grab everything
down and set it while it's doing that I
will show you my Firefox browser and I
can see my mouse you see that I'm trying
to get to the my docker VM itself that's
IP address but it's not actually coming
up that's because it's just now applying
the docker containers themselves again
if I do a talk at PS minus a or C it's
up your see that the one I really care
about is the first one that's port 80
translated to port 80 and you also see
that my IP tables also are allowing port
80 to now communicate as you can see
right here so if I go back over here
refresh now I can actually see in
genetics that was all facilitated by
installing the docker container the
image itself if I go back over here you
see I now have a docker image that's on
there you're see down here I actually
don't have any network access so this
was all done in a closed environment
which is some cases very important so I
did this by side loading the docker
image using a tarball
so that's kind of it in a nutshell I
know it was kind of really rushed but
let me get through to the very rim are
there any questions walk away yes so and
so
[Music]
I know we're out of time but you see me
afterwards I can answer questions