man Hertzberg will be holding the
lecture brace yourself
the darkness is coming thank you
ok I kind of first spread all over the
room so that surely helps with my ADHD
so let that let s start and start by
saying that this is a a part of the
workshop but because it was sort of a
last minute the thing it will be just an
hour so i'll try to squeeze in as much
as that we can hope it will be fun we'll
have some live demo and talk about
dildos and it will surely be fun
so first of all let's start with me i
have two children a boy and a girl i'm
on my career path was there mainly
offensive security and the development
and so that's my that's what is that
also heats what I like to do and
currently I'm the security research
group manager for a pervert incapsula
where we do those mitigation web
application protection and sophisticated
the automation attacks mitigation and
such so that that's what I do and
there's also my social media skills my
social media links so I disclaimer
whatever I say or do is the way the this
presentation is mine and not the
company's so if I say something i don't
know i will try not to say something bad
that if I will
it's mine and we also have a small game
rule because they will be in the talk
two days ago and I thought that there is
a tradition with the rockiest things
that the that's here so i think this is
a digital stock excluding this slide
which I have to explain the rule
and whenever I say amplification ok
there's the there's a shot for all food
whoever won from this area but I I need
a volunteer to do this so who wants to
volunteer I need something someone
responsible so come on someone to help
me out here and I need someone who's but
we can wait until the end of the talk
okay
no no stress come on come on
ok you ok yes the volunteer needs to
handle the shot issue when I say
whenever I say amplification that's a
but he has to be responsible i don't
also not give you two under 18 0 so lots
of responsibilities so here it is okay
if I say if i say amplification outside
of this light and they will so you see
anyone want to take a shot at work no
but yeah you give a shout-out to whoever
wants to wear
yeah tough game
ok it only the nao consider it ok ok you
can send as well
okay so well let's start with the actual
talk and so let's start with de dos
attacks because i'm i'm sure that their
many of you are familiar with the
attacks but let's do a small intro just
in case
so what adidas attack adidas attack is
any attack as that the that goes that
that that is aimed at this a disrupting
or add the RM RM denying service any
type of service and there are two terms
Addison the
and the dog attacks and the difference
is the extra day in the beginning which
means distributed so any dos attack is
basically an attack that is aimed at
disrupting service right
adidas attack is distributed meaning
that we are running it through a lot of
parallel a machines and the idea is
first to leverage and leverage yourself
so if I have one mega beat and and i'm
using a 100 other machines who have one
megabit i have now 100 feet or jacob it
so that the first thing in the end it's
another layer of separation between the
attacker and the and the victims as we
will lay soon see but the terms are used
interchangeably today so today mostly
when it referred to it Dios attacks
ok so let's make another distinction
between a volumetric attacks and and the
application layer attacks and volumetric
attacks are attacks that are aimed at
sending a lot of traffic
well usually it's either a lot of
traffic or a lot of packets a lot of
small packets to an a to the victim and
usually the this is established using
get and reflective amplification and
techniques
ok I needed someone responsible
ok you can hit so no no you go ahead
ok so I'm so usually that the context
that was speaking about that don't want
people to get drunk in the beginning so
I am so basically this Technic
reflective me is is basically sending a
command sending packets to a service and
usually over UDP where what's missing in
UDP in contradicted to tcp yeah the
triple handshake
so in UDP I can say
I'm the source and give a fake IP
address and then I'm asking a question
getting a lot of fair and a lot of
getting more data from a server that I'm
queering and that data is not time to me
sent to the victim and we will see that
the film we also around a small test to
see how it looks like network wise so
this is how basically it looks like in
in our systems to the left you can see
you can see a band with a event with
based the volumetric attack so we have
around 300 bit of traffic and going
through to the to the victim and the pic
that the top that we've seen so far is
470 gigabit per second and to the right
you see an attack that's a
a base that high makeup makeup packets
per second meaning that we're sending
smaller packets that we're sending a lot
of packets now what's the idea behind
this this think basically since we need
to deny the service we don't really care
how so one of the ways is to to exhaust
the bandwidth of our victim and another
way is to send so many packets that the
controls like the edge router and the
firewall will not be able to
to take care of and and then we also
have a denial-of-service a opposed to a
volumetric attacks layer 7 attacks or
application their attacks attacks and is
that are done not by spoofing addresses
or sending a lot of the packet but by a
by causing and operations that are a
expensive to the victim and and we're
sending them for example if I have a
price comparison website and the price
comparison website i don't know where if
how many of you deal with database
design but usually when you have such a
website you would try to index it
properly because a lot of people will
try to get the a product sorted by the
lowest price right or the highest rating
so if I'm an attacker i will do the
opposite i will try to to get to
probably a content that is it's not
catchable and their content that page 29
sorted by I don't know where company
size or a or something like that and
doing whatever I can so that each
request to the database would take more
effort and sending enough of these the
can can disrupt the service because the
database service its server will not
function or end or the web server will
not function so and the layer 7 attacks
can also be logical for example if I
have a bank account at a bank if I have
a bank and they don't have a bank but if
I had a bank and if the forgot password
mechanism it would when I am placing an
email let's say it blocks this account
until a it reset the password send the
new password by mail with the talkin
link
it's and the activation link to the a to
the client but then it blocks the
account infinitely if I can enumerate
all the email addresses of the bank
clients i can deny service in a logical
way by simply resetting all the
passwords of all the clients so that's
another type now there's something in
the middle between volumetric attack and
layer 7 attacks that a volumetric layer
7 attacks basically sending a lot of
fair HTTP request so it means that we're
completing the three-way handshake and
sending let's say a post request just
sending example you metrically sending
tons of them and usually using a button
it so that that's how those attacks
looks like so we see a LOL and a in
proportionate amount of traffic being
sent to a website and we're seeing tons
of requests sent to the to the website
and there's those are all a
and the attack you can see in the bottom
you almost can't see that the legitimate
traffic because the the attack is so
much stronger so that that's how it
looks like when the website is the being
being gay attacked using the application
layer volumetric attack what we do about
these types of attacks we fingerprint
clients according to my certain and
layers of the fingerprinting is to find
out that what they bought and what's not
there and when they're initiating the
connection so anyway before we go
a further just two more read statistics
ok so we make this quarterly report like
every research group make some sort of
quarterly report and so we make a
quarterly this report and in the
in the last one almost twenty-five
percent of the attacks were multi-vector
at once so and this keeps going a higher
and and the attackers are of course
getting more sophisticated and for
example they're using javascript
supported clients in order to to bypass
some of the adidas mitigation and a
tools they're using their supporting
cookies they're doing a lot of things to
to to steal and get an advantage in this
study this game and and these
percentages keeps going I of course and
second thing is that what we've seen
that sides are getting attacked
even though the sites we have statistics
for our site which are protected so even
though their tax fail and we see that
more and more a sites are getting greedy
attacked the reason to that i will not
go in in depth about that because I
deleted it from the presentation because
we don't have a lot of time and is the
digital economy which it's very cheap to
issue these attacks and just today to
Israeli guys from my country were
arrested for running an adidas a call it
does booter called videos and they were
arrested today but they were operating
for two years and and he is a earned
over six hundred thousand dollars and
revenue for doing the DDoS attacks so
they had some pocket money for it and
the
and and usually these types of attacks
cost between anywhere between five and
thirty dollars and $MONEY per month for
let's say for about an hour of attack
which is enough
and to cause considerable damage so why
why why would anyone want to do this I
mean I can understand that why i want to
do with a sequel injection and to get
credit card so I can buy stuff I can
understand why I want to do it with a
sequel injection attacks in order to get
information which I can trade with I can
understand why I want remote code
execution over a machine because of
reasons and I can understand why I want
their store excess why would they want
to do a two-run adidas campaign and this
is a question for you guys
anyone has a reason why but I didn't say
amplification ok now I didn't finish it
ok who said that this extortion
extortion is a good reason
okay whatever what other reason let this
we taking out the competition at Oh like
taking out the competition taking out
the competition to your site yeah taking
out the competition is good what else
ransom ransom extortion
ok ya too
ok you hate that you have something just
some bad feelings about their company
yeah this person get on your nerves i
can understand that written if you have
too much time you have too much time
right you have your board you have too
much time like more fun for fun for fun
okay okay anyone else more reasons
okay i think we probably summed it up
pretty good so let's see what i wrote
and see how we how close we are so
rivalry
I think we mentioned this right
business rivalry I i have a shop it
sells instruments someone else sells
instruments i want to sell more so I I
just the doctors right off it costs and
it doesn't cost a lot and and people
will buy for me again the the costs are
very low standards extortion and you you
send an email an anonymized email with
the Bitcoin and before you know it you
have some cash in your pockets because
basically what you're saying is at pay
me now
usually it's as ever eh way we see is
about 15 bitcoins and so it's a let's
say a reasonable amount for an
organization to pay and if you don't pay
me once i attack you will have to pay me
twenty-five and then each day and 10
more now did you know the attackers are
also they're saying I'm from X for
example from my Armada collective and
now since this is an anonymized the
personal sending it is either a
affiliated with that organization or not
but you're getting the
extortion anyway if someone pays and
again you you only need to either do
nothing before you send this extortion
letters or you need to do a short
10-minute 20-minute DDoS attack saying
hey I knocked your services of now if
you don't pay me i can do it for a full
day so this is a this is the one of the
leading reason there's activists and
performing attacks so for many different
reasons and they can be really many many
different reasons as long as it it's
trendy you getting even volunteers to
help you set up at the botnet even
people who volunteered to participate to
be part of that apartment then we didn't
mention state sponsor their cyber
terrorism like a allegedly Russia
disconnected the Estonia from the
internet a couple of years ago and now
the the great thing about it in terms of
course the attacker is if if let's say
Israel now
send striker brown bears to bomb Iran or
vice versa
it will start a war but when you're
doing something like this you can create
a lot of damage however you're not
really starting a war so it's so it's a
something that the state can play with
and of course in terms of defence
budgets its peanuts it's like the the I
don't know the spring waters a server
for meetings it's nothing for them so
state-sponsored is also a reason /
cyberterrorism nowadays some of the
terrorist organizations or it has the
funds of state so it's more or less the
same like ideas and such then we said if
you just don't like that person you
don't like that company so that that's
also a good reason why people a a doodle
attacks and and then there's another
reason
supposedly the latest attack in
Australia it was the smokescreen attack
meaning that there's a DDoS attack
everybody runs to the monitors wants to
get their network back up and then
a small attack
breach happens or any sort of more ram
and conceal the attack happens now this
can this this is one type of the
smokescreen the other type is you're
doing adidas then the then the
application switches to a dr and then
you attack the less the defendant maybe
it's not up to date maybe not fully
patched like the a production site and
so that's a again another reason and
last but not least laws and sometimes
people are bored and that's what bored
people do
we've seen attacks for example after
soccer games they're attacking the rival
city or the rival team or a rival
country depending what the what's the
game and then such a attack attack say
on
a pop stars rock stars the tetra just
because you don't like the same general
music music so that another image in
another and another reason so now what I
was thinking of doing is the to simulate
an attack
ok volumetric attack and let the let's
see what they were going to do it now
it's it's a simple a demonstration right
it's a very simple demonstration even
and and i think that there i hope that
it gets you to think also in other ways
about playing with network protocols as
well and see how fun it is if you're not
already doing it
so when we're starting to do the
simulation of the volumetric attack
let's just do a quick recap everybody
knows the seven layers always i right
ok so let's let's just do it quick let's
not deal with well the physical layer
and layer 2 as well as we're talking
about the attacks over the internet so
we're starting at layers three layers
three is the IP protocol and basically
the routing where you want to be going
like the address i want to go to nobody
thought okay I want to go to IPA . a . a
. eight so this is the AIP on top of IP
we have layer for which is transport
protocol
ok cool so what's your favorite
transport protocol UDP ok there's no
correct answer is a favorite their
protocol so anyway so there's mostly tcp
and UDP like we mentioned UDP a tcp has
the three-way handshake and so we will
not use the tcp for the demonstration
but we will use UDP what what is the
most common application layer protocol a
on top of UDP mhm
no no dns ok so dns and we'll use the NS
a pretty classic so this is a layer
seven layer 7 protocol that wheel we're
going to be using so in order to do that
and to demonstrate some level you metric
attacks and now I know that went running
this things will go wrong so bear with
me and always with the most this problem
so let's see what we're going to do a
tool introduction and wireshark that as
simple as possible wireshark we're going
to use wireshark in order to see the
packets coming in HB m3h ps3 is a very
simple command-line tool that you can
use in order to send packets escapee a
escapee which is a python library for
which you can do a lot of fat cool
network stuff and what we're going to
use it for today is the the cost of them
all which is to create your own packets
way you can control pretty much anything
you you want and when you're crafting
packets using escapee you can send
illegal packets with illegal checksums
you can you can do whatever pretty much
whatever you want you can say you're
sending for records but really include
five you can you can they do a lot of it
you can use it for fasting you can do it
for many other reasons and
and end it and I think that we should
all use it for one thing or another and
let's let's have a quick and the glance
of what we're going to do so first of
all this is in flat seam flat is
basically saying sending you seen a tcp
syn packet saying hi where the
destination which will go through ID so
high 1.1 . 1.1 I to point to point to
point to even though I'm not okay so we
can complete this three-way handshake
but left hand shake and the Machine on
the other hand will have to set to will
have to keep state of this connection
and and it will send sure to point to
point to point to let them shake and
attending the result that the response
to someone else
ok but we don't care about it or we may
even care about it there so where we can
change the attack but but that's a that
basically a syn flood let's look at a
simple and in flood so let's around
collie
ok so first of all so first of all let's
have a victim and who's better at being
victims and windows
let's have a windows victim a victim
machine and ok so this is the windows
victim now this is a machines are on the
net but of course since it's over IP it
can also be external ip's it's all the
same so this machine is 10.0
point-to-point 15 right and this machine
is is 10.0 . 2.6 ok so we can send a
simple let's open a wire shark on the
other side and we're opening that on a
windows machine and so we can send
basically Pink's 210 book the output to
. . 15 right so we can send these and
they will arrive and like when windows
it's not icmp beings it's a tcp things
so let's stop it
so we can send that but we can also send
say that we want to say seen
specifically ok and we want to send them
a real fast okay so we do a flood
ok and then we're sending the a lot of
lots of the request flowing into our a
server
ok now of course if we if we look up
here in the task manager so we see that
we're spending quite a bit of traffic
now of course if we have a botnet we we
can send a you know where send it in the
multiplication of where the the bots
that there we own
let's stop this attack now what you've
seen is very is not
is not spoofing the IP a source right
I'm sending it from my source IP so you
can also i think its run source but
maybe I'm wrong
ok-ran source and then when i send this
let's see if our shark is steel up and
when I do this it will send it from
random sources of course
ok so we send it from random forces
which is both more useful for a feeling
up at the and the table for a our victim
and also a more useful as in not sending
our IP and to the to the victim now this
is of course just a sample and with the
HP ink three and of course with many
other tools and the basically any
programming language we can send a ton
of feathers area of this packet we can
send different tcp flag for examples and
cmax send the
reset and other a flags to some of them
to trick mitigation this medication
appliances and so you're getting the
idea
this is the H pink and this is what it
does send lots of packets so we can also
send an axe lad which is basically
instead of dash S you're doing dish a
and it said that the the flag of act or
a or a scenic again mostly these these
games are used because in order to fool
a mitigation services of the four
victims so and we can do it again
reflected the attack by sending a scene
packets and saying I'm the victim and
i'm sending us thin and then all the the
victims all the machines that I'm
conducting will send back a snack to the
to the real victim which will get lots
of packets from lots of different
sources so so far so good
ok so this is just sending sending
packets so I let's a look at the another
example I think that this will be even
nicer
let's look at the dns amplification map
example
okay good
I are you drinking them yourself when
you're just everything it
no okay
come on ok good so basically with the
dns amplification with we spoke about it
before and and what we are asking from
the dns server is any data basically it
in this example and in most attacks will
ask just give me anything you have on
the thing on the on the domain and and
then and then it will send all this
reply to the to the victim now the
reason it's called the amplified attacks
is I don't know
okay good because I tricked you
ok this is a shot this is like five shot
that's that serbia serbia that's the
servants ok I'll try not to trick you
anymore okay okay so basically okay so
basically in this type of attack
we're asking for a lot of data so we're
leveraging our power where we can send
and 40 bytes or slightly more and the
attacker their victim get 400 so if we
have a1g gigabit connection we can now
have a 10-bit attack power so let's see
how we do that
ok and this is by the way this is just a
table is it took from an Easter a
website from the hour from the US search
site sorry
showing different III factors for of the
multiplication between sending the
traffic and receiving the traffic what
you said and what the victim gets ok so
let's let the run one of these attacks
ok and for that we will have another and
another virtual machine which is cool
bank
ok just a victim machine it it's just a
dns for this example at least it's just
a dns it runs bind on it behind is the
common linux said dns and and bind the
way Tory it's very simple to work this
is not that the skull but and we can
define and dns records on in it and it
replies with dns information so so if we
have this so this is the dns record for
cool bank.com it has bunch of I wanted
to say bunch of it is a bunch of records
in it so at the nameserver they record
the txt record the MX of course so just
typical a a dns a record and which we're
going to use another thing we're going
to need is the IP of our dns server now
this DNS server and let's not get into a
dns recursion recursion here but this
DNS server the one that we're attacking
doesn't necessarily need to be the name
server for the demand domain because it
can get all this information recursively
so there we have it and our IP is 10.0
point-to-point form so now let's say
let's do the attack first of all let's
clear to let clearwire shark and let's
say only look at traffic we have
from $YEAR to $YEAR . but it 4644 was
dns error on what it's for
yeah okay so we're looking for a for
traffic coming from and dns server now
let's say the
and start the attack and in order to do
so let's run scrapie and now escape you
can either run as a standalone or it can
run and and the model in Python so it's
because it's in Python it's
multi-platform it can they run on linux
it can run on mac windows for mac it
needs a little pushing to get it to work
but the but at least for me it took some
we're pushing but eventually worked ok
so we're going to define the packet that
we're going to send so let's start with
IP so we just call it creating the
object IP is the IP let's call UDP as
you p and we also going to need dns of
the dns and another structure we're
going to need is the dns a wiry very dns
QR ok so now we have the object now it's
very easy to play with with the escape
even if you haven't touched it in a long
time you you can just use display so
display shows all the property that you
can set for a for the the object so the
product that yeah he doesn't so I i
highlighted them so now it shows
okay okay so-so IP version 4 of course
we can we can send ipv6 a packet in it
and what we want to change is of course
at the
and destination because we wanted to
reach which server the windows are they
knocks their socks right the dns server
so we wanted to reach 10.0
point-to-point for right now once we do
that it automatically set the source IP
2 r.i.p just to make life easier
ok so that's about it about the the IP
of course we can play with it
so in other projects we can play with it
and then after I p we have UDP no UDP
comes by default with the dns ok so the
source port and destination port by
default it's a 53 the necessary support
and so we don't need to touch rupee and
let's jump to the dns QR dns QR we need
to set the queue name which is the
domain we are wearing about so let's do
that coupe bank.com and the queue type
which is what type of information are we
looking for MX record a record triple-a
records so we're setting it to 255 which
is any ok so that's it we reconfigure
the DNS a query record and now let's set
up the dns so with the dns what we want
to do it is a first of all we want to
set it to well in this case we don't
need to but still best practice a
recursive desired meaning that we want
the if the server we're asking doesn't
have the information we wanted to go to
to start with corruption and get the
information for us
ok and what are we missing dns cutie
count which is a query desired account
so let's set it to one because we sent
one query now for different tests we can
like play with this
send for requests and in the the NSA put
just the one or vice versa we can do a
lot of fact cool things with the escape
because basically we can set everything
and let the QD cutie is basically an
object of type a dns query so we wanted
to be the dns QR ok so now i have the
feeling that they that i forgot
something but let's see if it still
works so let's let's do sr1 which is
which sends the request and of Iping HUP
/ Dennis and we have an error
ok oh I it's not me it's the rocky okay
so okay now we send the packet and this
is the what we got a formatted in XML
sort of xml it's a it's the response we
can see here i will highlight everything
so we can see we're getting the NS
records we getting the a records we
getting the
yeah what else do we have here where we
getting everything that we have about
this the txt record so we getting
everything ok now this attack is still
not reflected right because we're
getting the data and instead of our
victim
so what do we need to change in order
for the victim to get that back the
source IP right so IP . source equals
10.0 point-to-point what was the windows
15 i think not sure first case someone
here will get there we'll get the packet
okay so when we're sending this if I
will run again sr1 i will have a problem
a slight problem and that that that I'm
the scape is now waiting for more a
packets because because i used sl1 what
they can do is you send then just send
it a synchronously and doesn't wait for
response so when i'm doing send it sends
one packet and now in wireshark that
clear it but we've seen that it got the
packet in wireshark it got it got the
packet okay
no this is just an example of course but
the length here is 4 402 bites of the
the of what we got
then actually by the way because I
because of windows it also sent an ICMP
of destination and reachable because the
port was unreachable because we don't
have a dns a a waiting on port 53 to
listen for this
so basically it lets say use pythons
built in length function to see how long
is the packet that we're sending ok so
the package we're sending is
it is the
is 58 bites and the packet we are
getting is 402 not including the ICMP
which is another 432 our outbound a
traffic but that means that basically 58
/ foreign to that means that the
amplification factor is about six times
ok now it all depends on the amount of
dns records we have but that the
amplification factor that we have here
about 126 so this is a how it works we
can also wear and and let's say we can
also put it in in a Python script so
we're still in this KP we can put it in
a Python script because of time
limitations let me just show you a small
test here but basically because it's
also a Python model we can use it in
Python so this thing does the same it
does exactly the same as we've done here
come online but then afterwards it just
run the loop sending gay
a hundred thousand their packets to our
victim so it imagine also not
necessarily about deals also about other
things you can use this
for many for funding and other other
things as well I want to show you also
how are the type of attack
looks like on different controls so I i
built a sort of fair and demonstration
that dashboard to show different types
of attack
ok now let's let's take a quick look at
what day we have here so we can just
demonstrate what happens in the
receivers and of these attack so we have
here in the top left corner we have the
edge router in the the inbound router in
the entrance to the organization network
and it has a cpu monitoring on it and it
have the bandwidth and packets per
second monitor for the edge router ok we
also have the firewall and the firewall
has the cpu monitoring's and the block
versus passed a monitoring and we also
have monitoring of the outbound traffic
and here we have just a simple and
high-level sample of we have a web
server and database server so the web
server we have cpu ram storage and the
requests per second and we also have the
amount of sessions and that are
currently running on our website and for
the database we have the cpu the memory
storage and the network a transfer and
the amount of connections on the
database and in here the fun we have a
chat window it's not just for fun it's
because a lot of times the we're not
we're getting the information about that
affect not from the actual network
control but they're from our clients
whether they're inside the organization
or outside so let's go to attacks let
the do a dns amplification attack
okay so when we're doing a dns
amplification attack and of course the
time varies
ok it the
it it may take a
five seconds it may take five minutes
but eventually what we have here is
first of all a lot of times you're
getting ticket you're getting supporting
it like we have clients who can they
can't access the website at the website
or any any other web infrastructure and
then the edge routers cpu goes up
because it needs to handle more and more
traffic but not not by a lot
not like if it has to handle a lot of
packets per second this is more also
been with issue but it doesn't need to
take care of that many packets so the
cpu stays about the same and packets per
second stays about the same the firewall
starts working harder and and and and
start blocking more and more illegal
packets because no one is expecting
those DNS requests coming at the port
443 of our a website so it blocks them
but it still works harder and the
traffic heart out
continue the same the web server and
database servers are a pretty much the
same we may get a call from our isp
saying hey you're using a lot of more
red traffic maybe you want to upgrade
because
because you're selling more or yours
you started the campaign and the web
server starts to get less traffic so if
we're monitoring this we're seeing an
alert not that it has a hundred percent
of you that it has less than less than
usual cpu and now that the basically
with dns amplification in most cases
what will happen after a while is a now
world meaning that your isp will catch
you down or you or you been with will
simply be full and and that it and then
your boss says can you please step into
my office for a second so that and that
game over so that that's the NSA
amplification like it looks in the
control of the organization of course
everything gave varies and i would like
to start show another attack just to
show where the difference who I
mentioned ipps attacked before so as our
attacks again in the network level but
we're sending a lot of fierce in packet
and and so it different smaller packets
so the bandwidth as you can see it goes
up but moderately not by a lot and the
packets per second
it rises you know more and this is of
course at them on this board so you
don't see all the fluctuations that you
will see in the normal network which
will confuse you of course and then
they're starting getting a complaint and
our firewall and edge router are now a
in a high PPS attack there now competing
on who breaks first depending on the
model depending on the configuration for
example if we have packet inspection
enabled on one and it's good it's
trade-off right unwanted it's good
because the because it's good for her to
Detective a certain type of of attacks
but on the other hand and because we
have the packet inspection it will take
more cpu / air traffic so again we will
see more and more blocked blocked
responses and then probably the firewall
will crash or the edge router will crash
so these two attacks also very similar
in terms of attack
you're sending traffic you're sending
small packets of offer probably seen but
not necessarily or you're sending large
packets using gay
reflective amplification but thank you
but I will drink water but on the on the
control of the organization they will
look totally different and I think that
this is one of the challenges we didn't
act that they look a totally different
different types of attacks i will just
give another example of a d-flat
database flat attack like the one I
mentioned before and this one this one
doesn't show anything on the a on the
natural control
why because the traffic is meaningless
today it's a marginal it's not it's not
it's not a lot of traffic coming in but
on the other hand the web server starts
working hard and the database servers
memory starts working very hard and cpu
also and again this really depends on
the type of database that you're using
the the configuration so if you set up a
lot of fair memory for the
for your database it may reflect more on
cpu if you put less memory it may take
more and more memory
it all depends on the current
configuration and there and also on what
the actual database attack is doing that
query information that's hard to query
that it do lots of inserts updates etc
so again these attacks are and very
different and how they portray in our
systems
ok so getting back to our i see that
there this is 340 so we have until 345
on something
ok so i think that i think since I plant
more content but you know how it is
usually more time because it sort of the
workshop so before questions I would
like to thank you all and I I i
practiced on this so I'm monogamous
Paula
ok and there again questions would be
lovely and of course there i can answer
questions and you know in the corridor
as well but any questions would be
lovely with my way whichever you want
what you what you do when you're under
attack
well this is a first of all it's a I
know that it's a always the the thing
with the information security and also
when I was in offensive security working
at the penetration tester and head of
offensive security we always had clients
coming up to us when they were under
attack and of course the simple solution
would be plan ahead and don't don't get
yourself in a position where you don't
know where what to do now because your
attack now it depends on the type of
attack but because the tax versatile of
course my initial instinct would be a
call in capsules are not me but the sale
guys wear which will solve your problem
but seriously because the tax deduction
attacks are
sometimes or most times using bandwidth
that is more than the bandwidth you have
mostly the the solution is to route your
traffic through the cloud either always
or or just when you're under attack
so basically what you're doing is a
again it differs between services but
you route your your IP a auric or subnet
is routed through it through the cloud
provider like us of course and and then
it goes
let's say through a GRE tunnel to your
infrastructure and it gets grabbed in
the cloud now there are also a lot of a
lot of solutions in the organization but
if you will get a you is saturated if
your bandwidth will get saturated then
you can have the best appliance that
will actually know and this is not the
the situation but it will actually know
for each packet in real-time what's an
intact and whatnot but about that since
you're limited in your bandwidth and
it's a
then you will still be down because it's
very easy to get a lot of bandwidth to
get you down unless your Google or
Microsoft Amazon where you have a
bandwidth to spare you know if you have
more bandwidth in the attacker so this
is not a problem for you
so most if not all dealers medication
services in the world are using the
cloud is there only cloud or a hybrid
solution and meaning that the part of
the attack is mitigated in the cloud and
part of it is in the organization hope
that helps
I have a question
okay it's okay Charlie song website
15 ok so the actual service so so again
this is this is a more or less the same
and I've seen a PLC lately i I'm sorry
but they don't remember who's the
researcher who did the the demonstration
but the same with a with the Google
because Google has the open redirect and
the they don't see it as a security
vulnerability so if you're you're
sending client yet you can send for
example xhr requests in a web page to a
client then he goes to google and then
Google redirected to the webpage or a
you can use some of their services and
use these services of an attack
there's also uh for example the google
translate where you can you know check
payloads without when actually your
google is the one sending the request so
yeah sure if if there is the service
that is that allows you to send lots of
traffic through it then
and of course a let's say that people
will be reluctant in blocking google to
their application of blocking facebook
and that that may be a good they're good
idea i don't know if it qualifies for
their bounty will have to ask them but
great talk where can i play with that
word where can you what lay with the
dashboard with what those words all the
one you song the one you are wondering
well first of all thats words are inline
machine so if you can give you my
password and you can play with it
okay and well because it's still i'm
working in a company still high hoping
that they after this talk with the rocky
idea which I didn't ask anyone about it
i will still be working in in my company
but anyway and so because it's a company
so they have to clear first it's still a
you know like a a Midway project but
once we will let ya i will be happy you
know to connect with you and once it's a
publicly available for playing with you
can you then i can send you the link
yeah
hi I have a question about details for
example you gave the example when I say
something like how it is if I said that
to everyone in this room hi I'm Ben I
want to can shake with you and everyone
sends acknowledged packet to you back
how traceable is that to me as an
attacker it's it's not in the internet
in a land it may be easier of course but
in the internet because of the way the
internet works it's basically
and I'm not saying
NSA impossible but it's virtually
impossible to detect you first of all
when you're attacking someone you will
probably a at least in the beginning use
use one of the details for hire services
so first of all that the first layer of
separation and then they will send the
NS a request for example and to the
server in order to create the end of
simplification attack and good you're
you're alert
ok so and then and then and then this
server replies to the source IP city has
so and of course because DNS requests
are so so common the and you will only
have the last hope
because of the way BTW works basically a
if he tries to trace route for example
you will try to trace route to the
victim not to you and are not saying
that you can't be caught but all of the
attackers were called doing that were
called for other isn't the two israeli
guys who got arrested or they also
weren't caught for for the attack itself
they were called because they fear the
vulnerability in the web application and
and.and someone use that in order to
expose them so and that's usually where
it goes
someone either traces the money or
something like that or someone Bragg's
or someone snitches
it's not that trivial to find the source
of DDoS attacks
thank you but don't do it different
actors because it's a on keeping it's
hard to detect
yeah
hello great presentation and
organizations a i would like to ask
about the apt attacks know what ntp
database attacks that you messaged him
ok with the barracks and is it actually
the configuration of the database or the
application that is reason behind it can
be both you later the application you'll
its application and when I was back in
the days and the good ol days when we're
used to excite for a living and be a
penetration tester if you think before
that I was a developer so if you think
like a like a developer when you're
accessing the database the accessing the
database
let's say for an e-commerce website is
enough of a challenge as is and thinking
of not what the a how-to you're trying
to work for the benefit of the majority
of your clients so you're setting the
indexes that way you can't index all the
columns in all the tables and you have
to do trade shows and usually it's in
the application layer some of the times
it may be a process so you may and let
them i called two females and talk from
the first day you may use for example
had this browsers in order to complete
the full cycle of some sort of a process
that will cause the big gas training
together on the application i can
remember for example there was an
application and mapping application it's
got as a parameter it get the it was
sort of get image . whatever and then as
a parameter you get the the size of the
image that you want to do and they use
something like I don't know
SP jpg image magic or whatever in order
to resize it but it wasn't limited so
you could set it to 52 debate and
chicken gigabyte and when you do that it
consumes tons of memory this is not
database of course this is layer 7
attack not thats related but I think it
also answers your question when doing a
sophisticated the web application and
unfortunately a lot of times I
the the security comes in only when
everything is finished and you're just
doing a pity to get it published in the
best-case scenario in the worst case and
are you don't even do that so and when
you do the penetration that think net
usually a DW neglected doses neglect
like neglected the penetration testers
and are always looking for the sequel
injection and that's good and that's
what i was looking for as well and
sequel injection remote code execution
the pastor of ourselves etc etc all the
sexy stuff that you can get actual data
from the system as a like measuring
latency is between request so you can
prove that someone with one single
machine can knock off your website that
something that most penetration testers
don't do it's usually even outside of
the scope of the project so usually the
application not the configuration
because I tea and I'm saying this
carefully but I tea and DevOps usually
well I wouldn't say they usually follow
best practices because they don't but
the but i would say that most of its
application steel
yeah
come on
work isn't
I would i will give the the bottle to
then the next to the next question I saw
that this this technique was done here I
so I'm copycatting ok yes you have a
question say no again but better
normal holla know where pour me a drink
and then i can say two in-service
Medical Institute oh right we need to
drink it like this location in the right
can go go gala