welcome to the third day or welcome to
k-16 the next lesson will be about las
veo founding the hackerspace presented
by Gordon message
huh well what the crowd first talk after
a rocky workshop and there's this
fanbase thank you all for coming
so my name is maker and I am co-founder
of headspace analysis side it's a
one-and-a-half-year-old baby and we had
our share of problems and some of them
were solved attacked by free software we
wrote so i'm going to talk about our
experience in huh well how it all went
and so for start way we had a
hackerspace we have a hackerspace and
it's a nearby i'm going to talk about it
a bit more later but for now it's it's
growing and it's it's doing nice it can
always do better
of course and but if you want to find
something with which open-source you
need a project definitely you need a
project in a in a unpleasant way of
thinking of your new idea that is
developing as a project and
we try to avoid really boring stuff and
that that aspect of funding is not not
fun at all
so we try to automate it because mostly
were systems and we're lazy and we
automate stuff and when i get on a call
for papers we had funding and I was all
happy to announce that we have funding
as open source project but we had it for
two months and over two months we don't
so the question mark is what do you do
when you don't have funding and there is
some experience from the from the
project that you can use to while keep
on going and as I said we are we're
young we were babies and I invited to
stay on an axe talk which is about a bit
more mature hackerspace and their
problems and so i'm going to talk about
problems a lot but that's because i want
you to be aware of them and
the moral of the talk is a fun one
creating your own town one and this is
one of the examples that can give you
funding which is mostly the problem and
we realize that were young but mostly
web developers and systems so if we want
some funding we better do something with
it because that's this what we can do
that's what we know and we realize that
the one hackerspace actually is a bunch
of crazy ideas
well that's a crazy and of in a
hackerspace environment but to the
outside world it's just craziness and
some formulas or code or whatever but
your understood in that environment so
you can expose your ideas to really
crazy people with a lot of smart ideas
and experience how how they did it in
their own projects and one aspect that I
like to emphasize is a will to do
anything so Justin a as an example
there's a not our initiative about the
hackerspace and the moon by 2027 I think
so that that's a really strong will to
do anything and now we created a project
which is actually his fault
this little guy and
we're citizens and what we do is
administrating wordpress and more
wordpress and we're up to here with
wordpress and the initial idea was ok
can we create a button so that our
client can click on a button and poop
person wordpress but since then the the
idea evolved and ok so we are using
danceable right now does anyone here
know what a school is well quite a few
so Ansel is a fancy script you apply to
your server and it creates whatever the
script is meant to create so you have
this among others wordpress and whatever
you put in a script it's there so
ansible galaxy is way is a market in a
in a way where people exchange their
their scripts and answer all calls them
rolls so on the other hand if you want
to create a some server doing something
you probably do something with the
provider and we realized well yeah we
could use API its modern why not
and what we didn't know what the pain
was 24 bunch of system ins is to learn
front end and it was really painful
experience I think it's worthwhile but
while I don't wish to go through that
again
so front-end we're kind of stuck with
modern stack with the redox material you
i read and react and socket i/o which is
just a bunch of list of
frameworks we use but i think it's
combined in a system anyway so let's not
touch the code at all let's make it do
its own job kind of thing and once there
was front and we needed design and we
really suck at design so material you I
helped moral of this story is you have
to realize what you're strong at and
what were your weak points and deal with
it
I mean that it's there so you better
deal with it so we know we don't know
design and thank you material you I but
worse
this is our strong point so it's
basically we we've done everything in
backend of course and the idea was that
has this advanced we are using Python
all the time so how about we learn to
program a bit so we create something
useful and we are obviously scratching
our back with whatever we have and it's
convenient and so it's a by the way if
if you're seeing double that's not
because of rocket you find so back to
topic we try to use as a small stack as
possible as minimal frameworks as
possible and i think at the end because
of the develops I'd actually I think we
did in some aspects better job than
ansible tower which is official
application which is not open source
that does the same job and we'll GPL
three
even if we wanted it any other way we
couldn't because the code and a license
offensive rebound us to use GPL three
and i think it that that was a lucky
coincidence so we enjoyed so on the on
the develop side here you have to
publish something an ansible galaxy in
order to have something in market and
likely other people did and it's a huge
market and you you kinda have to know
right now how to use it as we're
officially last version was 001 and
using dr. compose gave us ability to not
bound ourself to any provider or any VN
implementation so you can write on your
laptop as a on one command or in a cloud
or wherever you wish and please do and
let us know they're bugs of course their
box itself version so please report them
but now once we had a project and a
hackerspace of course we are we're back
to funding and to me that the most
important thing I ever heard as an
advice was this Congress three years ago
I heard a talk by ego who said you need
a local context you need to know local
context to make something with local
people and
that's that's basically what we did ok
we have a hackerspace way to need and we
have a project with which provides
something and how about we do something
windows too and our local context said
well people are not so much able to give
him money as a donation but they're
really willing to put an effort and
their will and their brain power into
creating something that's wonderful
actually
and here we are with one of the greatest
places like a class of places called
hackerspace which collect people with
high IQ and we need to find a way to
figure out a way to raise some money
from my help
how hard can it be right i mean we
should be smart
let's do it and we did by being really
loud or at least trying to be really
loud and being really loud in in digital
age probably means facebook twitter
youtube whatever you come by as a free
way of saying hey I exist and we do this
and we want this can we exchange or kill
me
can we find some some common interest
and of course is version 001 was a
proof-of-concept we had to have one in
order to kinda sell the idea and your
order to do anything we needed a team
but that team was
the kinda afterthought and the reason it
was an afterthought be aids because we
knew each other for years and we didn't
think about a team we were already
drinking beer together so let's do
something together but i have to point
out it's really really important . and
don't neglect your team so funding was
as a funding on its own was a project
way with its ups and downs awaits
we're with problems that we were luckily
we were lucky to solve one-on-one
interesting way and interesting way what
was that we encountered a guy dad said
okay I really am stuck with some client
and I know you guys from the previous
projects can use speed up development
please on this and this and that
happened to us and we were kind enough
to say okay cower expanses of a
hackerspace and we will make it happen
so that was happening for two months
that that was the funding for and we
ended up being better at project
management and management
overall we kept it kind of fun that that
that funding side we kept fun as much as
possible and actually our landlords
helped the
everyone involved in till the center is
a hackerspace were super cool and
helpful so it kinda didn't fail if we
put enough brainpower and we'll into it
so it was funny in a way its own ways
and you're going to discover on your own
how it is bad a project
well we're were system means for 290
fifth time and we're lazy of course so
that the only product and the only way
of solving a problem we know is
automation so we did it and a huge part
of that is answerable if you never heard
of defensible please do look up the
windows and it's super easy to install
so automation everywhere generators
everywhere so don't write your own code
it's terrible but the project was
interesting because of 11 collaborative
effort and its new people and old people
that know each other I have no idea
what's going on how do you how do you
cope with it and me personally as a
technical person I'm not really good
with people and then that that that was
my obstacle and my challenge to to solve
and rejecting ideas and pool requests
and in some people was hard and
desirable to protect the rest of the
project and the rest of the team from
the fools and from the wrong route and I
read once
I think it was Jesse frazzle who said
for a pool request and the project's
your your maintainer off saying you know
it's it's a temporary thing because when
i say okay this can go i give you the
reasons or can work on this can we
improve that but saying yes is accepting
the the pool request or a person in a
team who can destroy it and you have to
be careful about it so the reason i'm
emphasizing saying no is a be careful
for you we choose to be like your
friends i'm not saying it is your father
but I didn't sound like it and a project
is your baby so you kind of have this
parental thing going on with your
project and just slip into emotions
sooner or later and I'm so the project
didn't end by the funding did and now we
can do something with it
honestly the thing we were asked to do
was totally not fun it was Asia API and
we couldn't figure it out in two months
if anyone can figure it out please let
us know we were not smart enough to do
it which microsoft support help it was
that ridiculous
so after the funding stop we could
really do some cool stuff away we could
break the project again if we wanted to
and we wanted to because it was ugly and
we needed some new design
and new rope and it's a wonderful new
opportunity for new ideas and because
we're already kinda breaking the project
we are keeping the version stable but
God forbid if we have something stable
right now and I'm master wrench so it's
a it's a start of some new ideas and
your research but we kind of cool our
heads we with the research right now so
it's it's also time to invite new people
now that we finally know what we're
doing and any physical entity has its
own inertia so does a project always
were a virtual but it has this inertia
of cool people doing cool stuff and we
kept on doing it and that inertia gave
birth to some other projects that are on
the same stack based on the same stack
and are totally different than what I
hope for which is great i really love
diversity as so that inertia is a is
kind of important and once that that
real good feeling stops inertia keeps on
going and don't neglect
so what we're doing right now what I'm
doing right this second is putting the
word out we're out of funding and we are
in for the new people so that's
basically putting the word out and we
think of scaling not only as system
means although I I'm afraid we're gonna
use the same solutions but there that
this is only one project and it's only
one license since then we some of us
grow to like PSD and we want to expand
that even legally so and we don't know
how to do it where we don't know what
are the consequences
so not only the digital world has to
scale it's it's our knowledge and it's
our membership and as a project is now
in a in a alpha state I I did my best
and inspiring people to write docks and
we have pretty much covered it all but
we need people who are not so technical
as we are as we need proper a new
perspective into a project we can't
explain it to people what it is
normal people are
I kind of said you're not normal sorry
check that but Yamin
I could talk to you about these IDs and
you're not in a position where you need
a spoon feeding and for the people you
trying to ask for money you need to
spoon-feed them so we don't know how to
properly put it into docs so if you know
it please let us know we were more than
willing to listen to you so that was all
by me and if you have any questions
please if you can use the mic please do
know
okay so we're gonna have a torture
hackerspace which is I don't know seven
minutes in that direction by foot
follow the beautiful lady with similar
shirt in 3pm and thank you for being
here even on on hangover
yeah