i'm sure most of you here are such
security experts aren't you huh
so I'm not that special so I'm going to
start with little background us how I
how I got to this idea i've been brewing
is me for some time actually
so it was 2010 i was studying in Sweden
and I got a great idea for a master's
tvs i was gonna try and understand Skype
if some of you may not remember anymore
skype oh that's cool technology where he
could chat and and send pictures and
videos and everything right
no one uses that anymore but six years
ago it was the thing it was it worked
everywhere so there are many questions
about how it works is it secure is it
back the word is really fair to peer are
someone listening in on our
conversations so I selected that as my
preliminary master status
some of you might know why did not
actually finish my thesis using that
topic because skype lawyered up so i was
i was living in Sweden at the time and I
heard a doorbell
one day there was a gorgeous blonde
woman standing at the door but
unfortunately she didn't want any fun
she just wanted me to sign some papers
so signed receipt of of some super
important super secret document I've
actually given a short presentation on
the legal side of all this story at 2073
couple years ago arm so you can look
that up but basically skype said well
you gotta stop what you're doing great
everything and never user
product again which I happily obliged
the last one I mean so I was cut out how
it happened i did not have proper
anonymity so they found me in the end I
didn't have to pay anything but they
went after me for a year-and-a-half even
after i change the country they found me
again the letter in the mail so it
happened probably because it was done i
use my real name real country Sweden are
in my skype profile they were smart they
can access to some databases access to
lawyers so I learned that having real
name and telephone number is
$FULLPHONENUM and luxury you don't
usually need to take to use services
that's why i don't use what's up for
example well there is a veteran now two
weeks already
but also i became interested in the
technical part defendant anonymity and
that is what this lecture is about so a
little bit about me I myself come from
latvia not Sweden where I was studying
is my first time at bulk own and like
many of you I started programming when I
was seven years old but I started doing
that in the homebrew Computer now don't
get me wrong I didn't solder it i didn't
i didn't know much anything about trying
to the point but some of my relatives
made made it and they moved to a better
occupation so they gave it gave it away
and seven years old I started mashing
the buttons and and drawing circles and
and learning about sinuses and cosine
systems and stuff like that so our
that's that that's probably story for
for at least some i think many of you
here in this audience today
what was different that point is that
not like most of you probably i did not
have access to the internet for the
first eight years of my working with
computers so
was it was a fun time it was a different
time you can actually keep a lot of
information in your head
no online lookups of function parameters
you for good so PHP could not have lived
back then right with all the random
random sequences of function parameters
there are so you started programming and
and then I gradually moved to
administration that happened through
hacking so I was in the seventh grade
that's personally seven years seven
years later arm and you know people's
often often get fed up with their
teachers so I got fed up with one
t-shirt remember the subject are and i
decided i should spoof an email i should
use her source source email address to
write a terrible terrible email to one
of the admins are in the school i was
studying are choosing the destination
addresses one of them is probably not a
smart idea
I did write it was it was an ugly email
and my surprise week later they found me
even though i took the precaution of
going all the way to a different
apartment in my building to my friend's
apartment they actually they actually
manage of course look at the header find
the IP address find the real home
address and look the people database
where you know I my address was only
different by the apartment number so so
they got me that way are also during the
period I I tried I tried to mix my
programming skills with this new
administration thing that was going on
up some of you may remember a program
called windows 95 there was an export
for it called when Duke who knows when
you okay couple couple couple old old
old people here that they're okay I'm
all to my doctor said that I'm that I'm
finally old hag when I went to him at
one month ago that sorry your old
nothing we can do about that
if only so anyway when York is it is a
fun story so remember I did I didn't
have internet at home so I I looked up I
i looked up at the speck of of the
exploiter online on script a level right
school I went back home when I had more
time I opened my i think it was either
as a visual basic or Delphie so I opened
that I I wrote in my payload everything
that ethanol my computer had one
computer to come right
I tested it bomb got the blue screen of
death on my computer perfect so no other
computers test on so went to school
that's the draws an IP address of a
neighborhood computer perfect . is there
so it worked by using that BS tcp 139
arm you set an urgent flag on all that's
beyond the point of the presentation
anyway so so I thought okay but you know
people people use these cool or cool
things called the DNS names are referred
to computers and I could just type and
another that point at my school all the
computers had had a domain local domain
names for letter names really easy to
type so I thought what I want that
additional functionality in my in my
cool exploit here
so again I looked up to the manual there
was a function called get coached by
name so we added that inside that sitcom
again my only computer no internet or
bluescreen best I went back to school
are against it like a future look at the
coast and to my left I poutine press the
button
suddenly my computer get the North Korea
best I thought you ok gotta get to fix
that I look left
that also works great i look right that
also work i turned out the classroom all
the computers got blue scared s
apparently also also computer is not in
the classroom the call school was a
single subject so
everybody got a little scared as I
quickly shut the thing down right away
so i don't know if they if I know that
it was me but so apparently function
function gets called by name returned
minus one in case of an error are so I
didn't configure dns servers or
something in in the code so i get minus
1 then we have the signed and unsigned
integer saying right and n minus 1 is
also FF FF r which in decimal is
$OPERAND to 54 x which is broadcast on
the network so a small bug there anyway
so here today I'm going back to my roots
I'm still an inventor at heart even
though I I work mostly with security now
moved on to that of course and and
recently also cyber security policy
paperwork Nouriel normal damage their
arm but i wanna i wanna talk to you
about something guy i can find it i mean
i did a google search
I didn't find anything like that but i
didn't i didn't a proper academic look
up maybe someone cover this crap just
like 10 years but that would be a bummer
well okay so what is this talk about
here i want to introduce Simpson the
world are and I want to have a
discussion with you guys and gals here
on real-life applications of the
technology and I also would like to hear
your critique and comments on my
proposal of course code edits are very
welcome to so I think it's a really
important for everyone to be able to
follow what I am to what I'm about to
tell here so I'd like you to be able to
do this regardless of your background so
those of you who how many of you have a
networking background in your
professional or packing careers bit less
on top okay so I want everyone else to
understand what I'm talking about so
we're gonna go soo through some some
basic basics we're going to cover I
saucy model
all the layers we're going to look at
the CP and UDP and again I want to
emphasize think understanding is really
understanding the basics really
important I remember myself in lectures
at the University sometimes you know you
you you're bored then you suddenly mr.
topic and then the rest of the course is
unintelligible to you just basically use
so i don't want that happened
ok so we're going to spend spend some
time here on this chart this is of
course known as iso OSI model arm it's
one of the ways how to look at data
that's traveling network through our
single Network there's also the tcp/ip
model which is simpler ate it basically
groups layer 1 and two together and we
have straight for and groups 567
together arm but this allows for four
more precision i somehow you know the
academic and he wants to use this which
has more detailed it so let's go can
talk in detail about what this is what
it is out of the picture here is the
media the wire or whatever the media is
it it's on the bottom there so your wire
is there and on the top
what's called a rate is a user it's you
sitting get your application your
computer so when you type something in
the application it goes through all the
layers to to reach the media and when
information comes to you and you receive
an email for example it comes from layer
0 all through these layers to reach you
on top of layer 7 so let's take a look
at physical layer here
so in the physical layer of the Peace of
the one piece of information because
it's called a bit now all of you have
heard of it i'm sure 01 right and its
physical layer in includes some method
of representing representing Bates
manchester encoding for for legacy isn't
that the slow one and it also deals ways
the physical representation of course of
of your bits so for example on the wire
you might have voltage levels are actual
also journals like real world that's
that's where we have the real world and
later one we might have optic fiber with
with different patterns of of lasers
going in we might have a radio if we're
using Wi-Fi or some other obscure
protocol are we might use pigeons
there's actually I think there are sea
on using pigeons for transmitting you
can actually do it with our pigeon I
mean if you have the physical layer set
up so the goal of physical layer is to
transmit and receive raw streams over
the physical medium arm there's nothing
much a theoretical scientists can do
there
so let's look at layer to the data link
layer are it's a layer that contains the
mac address and and this is where we're
not network people's really listening so
mac address is a supposedly a unique
address assigned only to your network
cards in your device armed it consists
of six bytes is usually represented to
the effects like starting 00 up to FF
and the blues with colons we're going to
have a demo and then so so you should
you should understand that so we have
frames on data link layer and just how
it's called data link layer arm is only
relevant on the same physical networks
so its goal is to allow for reliable
transmission of frames between notes
that reside on the same physical network
so unless there's some physical medium
connected
between the two nodes data link layer
alone is not enough we'll go we'll need
to go up to network layer layer 3 the
network layer it contains the packets
oh right for that link layer are an
example as a rent right so network layer
it contains the packet and here we know
of course everybody knows ipv6 then
there's also a more obscure particle
called ipv4 that's also sometimes used
and ICMP is another example I would give
network layer the oldest routing traffic
control and internet addressing in the
original idea of how the debate model
was created and now the founding fathers
wanted it to work
apparently it should be able to select
the source IP address in this nation IP
address and it would not change for the
lifespan of the packet it would actually
reach the destination computer that has
that IP address IP addresses of course a
part of the network layer packet are at
layer for the transport layer we add the
thing called port so for HIV address
what's called computer freaking future
you can have a specific for starting
from zero to 65,535 40 isn't really used
but you can actually use it but it's a
different tack not going to talk about
that either so examples here tcp and UDP
segment is the name for daytime layer
for if using TCP so that segment and the
data Graham is for UDP so we're going to
have a separate slides on tcp and UDP
now we're not going to go into details
on the upper layers in part because they
always confuse me I mean the division
between layer 5 and later six is really
blurry for me I think for most of you
are right so but they taste called data
on layer 56 and seven armed it is
basically your application with every
cab like Apache with or without pls
your application top of Apache that's
that's all in there and then we have
user on top so final thing I want to say
for the slide here is there is a process
called and cancellation and a process
called the cancellation and capsulation
simply means going from the user down
through there through what we have here
on the screen and encapsulating the user
data adding different headers and
footers to it so if say you want to send
an email that says that teachers can
then you would have that on what we call
a rate and layer seven six and five
would encapsulate it may be changed
something right if you have some special
characters and there they will be
changed on these layers transport layer
without the port 25 network layer
through some quite not get process we
would have found out there p address it
would have the IP address of the they
mail server where the mail is about to
be delivered and of course the source
source IP address of my neighbor data
link layer would contain local mac
addresses on that Network segments so
those would change when the when the
frame is destroyed and created visit go
through the internet and physical layer
of course depends depends on the medium
right and the calculation is the same so
for every Network device it goes down to
the physical and backup
ok so let's take a look at tcp vs UDP
let's compare these two popular later
for protocols so features of tcp of PCP
is a state full connection-oriented
protocol it means it's remembers the
state it's in it doesn't have to send
all the previous data relating to your
session are with every packet sorry with
every segment arm it actually has enough
information so that computers and other
natural devices have to read
member what's happening there was tcp
and it's a it allows for creation of
connections we're going to take a look
at that right in a compliment here
it provides what's called reliable
transport meaning that are meaning that
it tries to it really tries hard to
deliver the message
so if you should come back like in 10
minutes when we when we talk about real
stuff and unnatural guys sorry it's a
bit boring right and ok so it's kind of
reliable I mean it really tries to make
sure the message delivered and if it
doesn't rise again so it has some
notable features for example the
three-way handshake also one more speed
one more thing to see because our flags
for the tcp segment there are numerous
flags like like around ten three-way
handshake is a process that tells two
parties to IP addresses client and
server that the connection has been
established between them so a packet
with sin flag set is sent server replies
with a packet that has a ck
acknowledgement and the since likes both
that and then the client finally replies
with a tacit acknowledgement flight of
like set and that creates a connection
between the mouth each of them including
all the devices in the middle
remember that a connection is open are
of course the connection can also be
turned down when it ended the party
would like to close the connection send
packet with flag set we get an
acknowledgement and feedback and then we
send an acknowledgement so the only
thing changes is in changes to Finn it's
quite so easy protocol actually up so it
also has error detection like check
something and confirmations the
acknowledgement flag we talked about our
it allows for ordered transfers so all
the segments have a6 sequence numbers
and as packets and segments within those
packets would sometimes take different
parts on the internet they might come to
the recipient in the in different order
tcp allows for that to happen
it's fine it actually ordered them in
the correct order at the destination and
flow control since coast have different
network quality and the network speeds
in latency it is important
PCP is also something called window that
allows you to control the speed of flow
but let's look at UDP it's it's it's
more useful to us here for this talk it
is space station 10 transaction rented
so coasts are not required to remember
anything about about UDP session let's
call session because it's not the
connection
this is a but intermediate intermediate
devices like firewalls or routers still
try to infer when a UDP connection is
happening just metadata some car
actually has an ice pack that uses this
feature of UDP that allows you to
connect to host behind the net without
the middleman you should look that up
with you haven't heard about that so it
is a best-effort transferred it just
sends a packet and that's it i mean if
it's if it's delivered that's fine it's
not known cares are so some notable
features include it's simple
it has non control mechanism 7003 it
doesn't trust the date again so this is
this is the UDP datagram is just a
source port destination port length
checksum and and the datasource it's
really simple even like 10 times more
simple than the tcp we had guys saying
that 75-percent of statistics are made
up i just made up that number ten times
but well it's simple
ok so you a piece perfect for what we're
trying to do here are let's look about
let's look at an Internet here's here's
a comic for you so you have seen that
right on the internet nobody knows
you're a dog so unlimited internet can't
exist right but i found one more comic
here so
here's a Coast saying that our next
guest has chosen to remain anonymous
circle remain because the screen during
the interview please welcome mr. Isaac
Phillips h26 from Amarillo Texas so is a
limited internet real my skype story
tells now the fact that we have tour
also tells us something but is more
effective against eight attackers the
current research which your community
eagerly tries to ignore says no it's not
really effective and I i joined the
research in that opinion are so one
final thing up on the network
here's the random Network background I
pulled from the internet and so let's
let's talk about how routing works on
later three earlier in this room there
was a dog by anymore and it was titled
why can't we have nice things
while our this slide should explain why
can't we have a limited in the network
so we have three networks here indicated
by those blobs of different color we
have two routers so how routing works is
that one for example this pc one on the
bottom in the yellow in the yellow blob
tries to connect the pc three it has to
set the IP address somewhere
well it usually says the pictures today
. recipe 330 does 0203 otherwise the
routers in between indicated by the
router symbol and cutting text router
below those would not know which
interface the forward through so say a
pc one would like to send data pc3 but
would like to analyze the destination
address say send it to 1000 to router
one would actually send information to
the blue blob instead it's a green one
and PC would never get the data so
changing ip's or hiding a piece in later
threes least to fail so we have a
problem
IPL alteration fails i beez our own
layer three are needed for routing
that's why we can't simply remove them
from there are we cannot encrypt them of
course we have ipsec but it's a
different story
it doesn't work so yes we have a problem
here so I propose a solution i use more
bandwidth so with that cons that I
frequent often have this sign arm up
first years at the catkins i was i was
wondering why why do they have this
signup really couldn't understand that
but but well as years went by I I think
I figured out so the bandwidth has been
paid for so why not use it rides
this is this is real statistic it's not
it's not invented so more speed
everywhere is what we are getting in my
hotel here in Serbia of my big speeds
for the Wi-Fi my hotel reach four
megabytes per second
I'm lucky right not everybody has that
kind of tell butt but i mean that's
that's something our in Latvia where I
come from our normal home internet
connection is usually between 100
megabits per second up to half a gigabit
per second we are think the the force
fourth country in the world ranked by in
Texas space so Japan because it has a
better are so let's fill the values then
we need more data grams it is a
statistical solution that I will provide
to you it's that basically makes it less
likely for therefore an adversary to
determine your IP address so all the
network girls should now pay attention
again so we finished the network control
ok so i present to you sick source IP
spoofing for a minimization over UDP
let's look at a small overview of how
this technology works six protocol goes
on top of layer for but below later
three
so here's a here's a cool diagram so you
could consider it a tunneling protocol
this way are because it allows later
three where they really like the others
are to be incorporated on top of it
again but it's it's actually if you look
at the network stack on the wire it it
looks as layer 5 protocol from that
perspective and we will see that in
wireshark of course if someone wants to
write the patch for white sharks to
interpret this there are more than
welcome
so the idea is sending multiple UDP
datagrams for each single bedroom that
should be
Emily sent ideas easy enough are in
those multiple datagrams on layer 3 the
IP addresses are replaced the source and
destination IP these are randomized so
for example we would get one real packet
was a real source and IP and 63 fake
packets with all the possible
combinations of fake source IP address
is generated and fake this nation that
is generated also the current version
uses the IP version in layers are why is
it important to use them to generate new
pairs there's something called PCP 38
which will have a slide on much later
today and this presentation though bc
p38 my block stuff going from different
subjects so we just to make sure we also
create 11 IP addresses in the same
subject when the same classy are but if
we can just that then it'd be easy for
the adversary defines a real subjects so
we do that for all the subjects
including the fake ones protocol of
course allows for expansion version
support that's possible
current version version 4 choose ip's
within classy network so we don't bother
with finding the actual actual subject
is relevant for impact our outside your
network so and metadata currently
includes the real IP addresses and the
list of the fake IP addresses used in an
encrypted form payload is not encrypted
because we have the less for that if
someone wants to do that were any any
other type of my pset whatever so a
single TCP packet is being sent here i
have a question to the audience which IP
addresses communicating with which any
guesses
yeah
you can you can refer to the right
answer but the line number
look at that
ok so one more thinks it does is it it
always select the same the same list of
fake source and destination IPS for
specific network parameters so and those
brands include real sergeant stationed
piece so that's that's thought about
anyway the right answer is like 25 but
as you can see it's not really possible
to do that to figure it out from this
screen so it should work i think our but
right now it's a nice addition with a
lot of asterisks and will of course
discuss possible problems with that
so this is my proposed format as
implemented inversions there are four of
the protocol i hope everyone can can
read the phones they're so we have a
header that just a ski is as the pizza
in asking 5 bytes we have reserved bites
that's always zero at first I at first I
had the version numbers are because the
first iteration of the protocol it's the
version number is also asking which was
a waste of time i decided to make it
binary arm so now we have reserved by
there which is cool we can use it so we
can set it to one when the protocol is
actually used in production
ok so version version bite says has
version 0 4 in this example are in in in
this version of the product then we have
a then we have length of the metadata r
is $OPERAND / 16 bytes because we
encrypt the metadata and and we can save
space that might are so there's also a
limitation here we can have you cannot
have an infinite number of sources IP
addresses in this example because it has
to fit in 16 x 256 bytes x services but
we have the initialization vector 16
bytes it's random for every original
datagram and the same for every every
duplicate effect diagram
and then we have a blog that's encrypted
with ASD 56 CBC mode sixteen byte block
our total size of that can be can be
found by the formula metal n minus 1 x
16 bytes now i should i should stress
and I can't stress this enough that even
though I've taken some crypto intro our
university many years ago i'm not i'm
not really equipped experts are probably
the Crypt insecure don't use that in
production but it's well I couldn't
break it but you can never break your
own stuff right so and then you have
become the payload so here's an example
of the datagram oh it's nicely colored
so we have you can see the blue one but
it does matter said just as later three
so that's the underlying information
whatever that is layer 3 is where the
fake addresses are the the blue one you
can see and then we begin with six in
dark blue and then we have a all
information there
the larger portion in in brownish is
encrypted part and then payload is
implanted that you can see it starts
with e 45 are so it starts with layers
three IP packet header
ok now let's take a look at bc p38 real
briefly it's the best current practice
so this slide talks about wires why
things aren't as good as they could be
it's 16 years old so it should be
implemented everywhere right
well it's not really implement
everywhere it talks about network
ingress filtering which means that your
provider should check the source IP
address of your computer to make sure
that it's within the range
Thank packets are not forwarded this is
supposed to solve denial-of-service
attacks it does not really solve them i
mean it worked well for some time for
that worked was implemented but it's not
widely adopted and the noodle service
techniques have emerged for example our
botanist and these things don't rely on
source IP spoofing necessarily so let's
take a look at six results
the good the bad and the demo so bc p38
has been partially implemented which
allows us for greater success rate 62
may provide an additional layer of
anonymity it needs to be combined with
other techniques though it also provides
the ability UDP doesn't do
acknowledgement if you configure your
box correctly UDP also does not send
icmp original packet so if you make sure
to do that it's really allows for some
some nice legal magic to happen
I'm not a lawyer so it also uses fixed
symmetric part numbering which should
confuse the attacker about the direction
of the connection and if a new
connection is initiated or not so that
the liability goes like this imagine and
investigations happens for some reason
and so it gives you the possibility to
answer to judge no your honor my devices
neither requested or acknowledge receipt
of the communication question you can
get your torrent's not acknowledge any
packets and say that some bad guy just
send it to your feathers
or do something you know our terms of
you 12
I says okay so the bad things here I
think bc p38 is not going the way it's
being slowly deployed additional
networks six that gives only statistical
improvement not a hundred percent
vulnerability not a hundred percent of
limiting so statistical attacks are
likely possible in addition of course
the physical attacks that i found
possible against my Krypton here in this
version for our success largely depends
on internet service providers that you
use it increases the network load but
hey we have been with the paid-for right
so these are our the tested for a large
datagram of 60 kilobytes for smaller
data will see a more significant
increase in the network load so if we
configure if they configure a sister to
use three sources and three this nation
dresses including the real one
r it would result in eight times more
natural traffic being transmitted to buy
five source IP addresses it's nine-time
increase six-by-six it's 35 times
increase starting with a by eight we can
actually use a formula to determine
increase in just two counts of source IP
addresses by the count of this nation IP
addresses multiplied so a buy it gives
64 time increase and so on hundred
hundred gives thousand times increase
the network loads so okay I think it's
finally time for the demo and we
can we get that going ok so i should
have opted for the longer cable but ok
he's going to have to do
ok so r for love you with laptops and
nothing better to do I want you to
follow this as as a hands-on if you have
two machines available with three ladies
are self somewhere on the internet so my
my github is a gift card / 0 ki three
characters 0ki arm so that I found out
yesterday that there are no real ideas
here on this network which is
unfortunate so I I scrambled to create
the virtual network this morning on my
laptop here but actually works for
internet and I tried it so
ok let's i'm going to show you going to
accept my cab
yeah
ok so i have three virtual routers 123
arm and my laptop is going to act as
center in one of network there and
receive another network there are you
can see the schematic here since I only
have one laptop i needed to to make a
small crack in read on Roger three are
in order for linux kernel to play ball
on the sender and receiver machine are
so sorry for that i will actually be
sending a packet 210 5757 103 will do
this nation that to the real IP address
of the receiver so don't kill me for
that but everything else is as it as it
should be
so let's start on the network
so if you hear her heart of Microtech
wow ok ok it's a great life and company
that makes makes great report by the way
can you hear me can you hear me market
ok and then on the recording to speak
like that
yeah Mike works like that ok let's
assume it does ok so let's start my
street routers here
yeah
and i will also set up routing on my
machine here
sorry for using grout into the fire out
i still come get the hang of it
ok i will add so remember this kinetic
here i will add the default route from
this machine we can be sending from 192
168 562 those routers in here with this
IP address
ok
so all we have that right
good
now let's take a look at the product
ok
this is from a good cup
now if i launched the client
you will need the root of course that's
one thing for server you do not need
root so I'm gonna watch server but even
even so if you have wrote i have a check
building for fake of sorry for private
night the other space so we're gonna
we're going to do a little bit of
editing and also represented to take a
look at the source code
let's get colors
ok not colorful nevermind so what we'll
do here is we would like to remove this
morning here as suggested by the morning
itself
will change this nation from this
example address the 10 network diagram
so then 57 present . one
and we need to create a secure key
right here
so i have this cool batch here let's
give a round of applause for creator
it's really good stuff so okay I'm gonna
I'm gonna take the password mode and I'm
gonna hope that I come up a password
here in this fit
ok write characters are we also going to
need that in the server
right permissions
i'm going to copy this
the server so it can understand the
packet
and finally in the server i usually
listen all the interfaces but it
wouldn't be fair so we want to listen
only an interface of the second simulate
love them so that is stand 5711 ok let's
try it out
so we can run the server the receiver
part as a normal user
and let's run the client as wrote
because it craps packets on low-level
alright
so it's a colonel screaming this again
so we gonna we need to specify a
sorceress to so since we have multiple
IP addresses on this machine we just
going to add a small pack here instead
of finding a dynamically let's specify
it manually
and let's run it again
now it worked if you guys do a poster
whenever works you can do that now
so the server actually received five
different packets of the one being sent
I found it decrypted and found a match
and printed the data inside the payload
of 6 here starting with b which
indicates IP packet let's take a look at
where sharp
so we're not looking at the network of
the center
we can see all the others in there
and as you can see beyond layer-3 it's
identical you can see that was right and
you can also see of course that data
payload is unencrypted there if you look
at this we will be able to count five
times three adding 15 packets
right 15
and now let's take a look at the
receiver network
so
the receiver network clearly receives of
stop packing
clearly receives only the five packets
that the word this nation's matches are
so we got the statistical probability of
twenty percent of guessing the real
source IP others they're ok I can move
on back to the slide please
and that's not my slides
let's have lots of my sites
yeah
ok so i called the slide is coming up so
are what i would like to finish with is
the future testing and research of six
up and i would like to talk about
possible improvements to anonymity
general security and of course some
other features so it doesn't mean I will
do all that myself so I really invited
to join me arm since it doesn't 16 we
don't do not need to actually you don't
need to be part of a team like to join
and commitments I think I don't get help
so use your magic merge full fork
ok now we really need slides please
perfect around their claws
ok so for anonymity the demo of the
source code and it can actually include
commented outlines that does these
things for limiting you can cause
they're not including the real source of
even in the metadata that's even the
server will not be able to tell what the
client is so full deniability no logs
huh
you can alternatively consider not
sending the package from the real source
at all if you do both things at the same
time of course the server will not be
able to reply you but if you do any
single one of those separately server
will still be able to reply without
knowing your appearance the first and
first option here and in the second
option without highlighting European
dress at all on the network level for
search party adversary's in general
security
well there is work to be done to check
the validity of the crypt of course arm
we would need to think about key
management static shared key suck so
something has to be done about that our
penetration test is in order some
funding maybe we might think about
obvious obfuscation currently it's super
easy to detect that it seeps are you
just look at the first five bites that
has six up some other ideas
ipv6 of course I might actually be doing
this one myself unless someone sends a
pull request before I am able to finish
this
it's also currently already possible to
include random seed instead of the IP
map instead of the full like a map in
the metadata thus we have smaller
metadata and smaller payload oh sorry
and smaller datagram we can have
stateful sister
this will give a bit less bandwidth
usage but we will abandon some privacy
as it might be possible to detect when a
new connection gets created and the
night of course it's a card problem i
would say even more so than BC p38 are
so any ideas even not in not in written
form just come to me any ideas about
about having sex worker net would be
appreciated
so to conclude please please give me
feedback you can say it sucks because
there's a reason
are you can say it's great and we should
use it in products whatever plays for
implemented in real-world if you think
it's useful if you think it's saying
okay I clicked on a link because it is a
link so okay here's the link to my
github arm and here's my Twitter so yes
so that's everything from me thank you
very much
arm if there's questions and we have
some time then it's a time or feedback
already going to get Mike
yeah
hi you said something about protocol
application because every snort or bro
is going to pick up these packets
running just yesterday any kind of
sniffer
what can be done about hiding the fact
that you're using it
well you know there are there are
multiple protocols already are being
confiscated two are namely has had some
protocols are well as a long-standing
fun of truecrypt we could we could use
that and sent over or network so and
then see if the crypts are not of course
the the the real stretch here is active
fingerprinting is used by my great
firewall of china allegedly so well I'm
we need more smart people to to fix that
any any more questions suggestions
anybody already installed it rides
around it work okay well you have the
link you have the time
oh we have a question yep
is that the final question or do you
have any more questions okay great
if you do know the address you get
hidden behind you to hide not into you
reach revocable if you include the
address where you're going to be
hydrated behind in the the list of the
aps sorry Kenny can you repeat that
again baby microphone bit further from
you mentioned that it doesn't work with
height not
yes reason probably because you include
your original IP address in the list of
the IP addresses but later on it gets
changed to another one that you don't
know we hand but if you do know that
you're going to be highlighted you could
easily the exchange your true IP to the
one to be knotted right okay III get it
yet so are in in one version of the
protocol in theoretical version of the
protocol you can actually not include
your real source of the others at all
and work the problem is that is that
your local router will translate all the
addresses the same output address and
you
do not have control over that and you
will all their packets will come out
with a real interfacing address
ok so I see there are no more questions
so thank you so much for joining me and
have a great conference