okay we're talk about how to fix
diversity gap in cybersecurity which we
know is kind of an issue right now so if
we're gonna kind of go through some
agenda thing but first we're going to
talk about Who am I kiss your probably
wondering who I am some statistics then
we're gonna go into some cognitive
science and then we're gonna do a quick
little activity and then a little bit of
storytelling and then I promise that
you'll walk away with some Q&A
possibilities but also three takeaways
of what you can do in your own office so
first thing is Who am I so since I was
about five years old I wanted to do
something which encouraged equality so I
thought that was education with kids and
I still do that today my background is
that I have a bachelor's in
international relations I have a
master's in science and political
research and then I have ten years of
nonprofit experience before actually
going into cyber security so it gave me
a very different feel of everything I do
sit on numerous different boards that
are humanitarian but majority of them
are somehow related to kids equality
through education and health
I do mentor and give talks about how to
break down barriers and walls these are
some of the students that I actually got
to mentor recently at a conference back
in UC Berkeley in June about trying to
get them interested in cybersecurity and
then I also like to do blogging I do
have a nonprofit called rap labels and I
also had now cyber Lai's which starts in
January which was actually started in
Israel at least I worked at bugcrowd
so overall women make only 11% in the
cybersecurity forest this is Ben says
2013 and has remained unchanged
minorities on the other hand is less
than 12% make up the cyber security
force and we're looking at a one point
five million shortage of cybersecurity
professionals and most likely this is
the worst part of it all is that
underrepresented persons are always the
most likely to be let go or fired so
let's dive into some facts but first
more companies are realizing that the
only way to get great people is to
invest in workforce diversity and social
responsibility companies seeking to
become more inclusive in their hiring
should examine and question their own
assumptions and unintentional biases in
their hiring process so I'm going to
show you a quick video and I want you to
try to listen as much as possible
without trying to think at the same time
and no that's tricky but try
[Music]
so yeah that was definitely a push to go
check out my nonprofit no but on other
notes is that this is another one of
those moments were your first thinking
of like okay I just heard your story now
the next thing you need to get to in
life which is very hard when thinking is
what am i doing that's causing this guy
to have these issues still and you might
not even know that yet you might not
even think about that yet until maybe
one of those days where you're in the
elevator and you're fighting yourself
clutching your purse a little bit
tighter or believe it or not when you're
driving in an area you decide you know
what if you like locking the car doors
for a reason so let's break down how
that works in our brains
so first is we are afraid and we act on
our fear so how this works is in a part
called the amygdala it's where we're
programmed to sort who is like us and
who is not like us and this occurs
unconsciously and at the same time it
could be something of a survival
mechanism of our potential threats and
these tend to be stemmed from like our
socially constructed beliefs and norms
you know ever since like you say you
watch some movies or documentaries or
you have parents that said don't hang
out with the kid next door and
you're like why because they have pink
hair don't trust people they ain't care
now you're always gonna think about this
later on in life unconsciously that I
will always be afraid of a person with
pink hair but the good news is that it's
always verified so in the frontal lobe
it actually perceives and checks in with
the amygdala so the Migdal is like will
be afraid be afraid the prefrontal
cortex can actually turn around and be
like you know what you need a chill and
let me tell you why I need a chill and
the reason for that is because one we
just heard of a story of some guy saying
you know sometimes people clutch the
purse a little bit tighter because of a
stereotype that is false next thing that
happens is is that you're questioning
the stereotype this belief and then you
end up making the final decision so
think of the prefrontal cortex as a CEO
it makes the final call and then last
but not least then it turns into action
the prefrontal cortex let's know what's
the next step so just note overall you
can always question your own biases and
it's really okay to be uncomfortable I
know that's the worst thing ever to
actually look at ourselves and see like
what did I do wrong here but at the same
time it's the way that we learn from
each other we get out of our comfort
bubble with each other and that's how we
actually make changes happen so we're
gonna do a quick activity I want you to
sit next to someone you don't really
know so not quite yet so the first thing
you're gonna do is this is gonna be
maybe uncomfortable for you but I
promise you you're gonna find a lot
about yourself and your thinking and
also you're gonna learn a lot about this
new person you're sitting next to so
what I want you to do is someone say hey
the other person is B to the other
person I agree who's a and B let's just
do that
all right we've all sorted it out okay
so now the next step is whoever said
they're gonna be a you're gonna talk for
five minutes about anything you want
about anything you want
now person B you're gonna just listen
and now anytime you catch yourself
thinking I want you to go back to like
no no no pay attention don't question
you can't ask anything you have to let
the person talk the whole entire time
you can nod your head but you cannot
talk you cannot ask for further things
you have to just listen now I'm going to
set the timer for five minutes ready set
go
[Music]
and stop alright so now you guys are
gonna switch now remember you cannot
respond you cannot talk and the other
person's going to now talk for five
minutes about anything and afterwards
we'll do some quick review but Ready Set
and person be vegan
[Music]
and time okay so that must have been
very awkward usually I worry this is
like the first two to three minutes
you're just like well if you're the
first person speaking you're like oh my
god what am I gonna talk about it so
then you go down like this rabbit hole
where you start getting really serious
very fast you get really like oh my god
I can't believe it just totally stranger
this oh my god
and then the other person who's
listening it's always like the first few
minutes you're like stop thinking why
don't you want to ask oh yeah I have
that same - oh wait what am I do
No pay attention pay attention and then
you've drift away like oh god here we do
it again what were some of the things
that you guys felt or better yet tell me
how did you feel about doing that
exercise or that activity Yeah right
what else yeah did we get really deep
somehow at 4-minute a little too deep
ooh that is a good question how the car
says you would be a bit different right
good okay you can stay in there Sam sees
if you like it's up to you all right
so there are not as many minority cyber
security professionals in the community
or in movies did you pick those roles
the minority cyber security
professionals that I know made a career
switch to pursue technology after
leaving the cyber security industry
unfortunately this is very much true
and the reason for that is that they're
not being heard they're not getting the
titles they want they're not getting the
pay that they're supposed to be getting
so what ends up happening and they leave
so I'm gonna tell a few stories at
different people that I interviewed so
one is named Rebecca Rebecca sassy so
Rebecca has over heard the board several
times saying oh she's not technical
enough no we can't hire her because she
has she's not that good at what she's
probably knows what to do because she's
technically challenged you know woman
might be an engineer for a long time has
been in cybersecurity for like ten years
somehow she's still not technical enough
rémi who's a salesperson complain about
the broad culture at her company and
within a month she was let go and the
reason for that was that the borough
culture star I gained a little bit more
and more intense and they kept hiring
more men instead of women and yeah which
unfortunately she got laid off because
of it died who's in sales she was she
asked for a raise because she was her
top sales performers for a few years and
what end up happening was that when she
went to you talk to her manager her
managers like sorry I cannot give you a
raise because if I do then everyone's
gonna think that I am trying to give to
someone from the same races I am and
she's a chinese-american he's
chinese-american so he said to her I
can't give you a raise because that but
then he ended up giving a raise to a
male colleague who underperformed her
who is also chinese-american clio who's
in marketing what happened was she
starts seeing a shift she was like
basically she was at a company for a
while she was doing a lot of things from
marketing and when I end up happening
and they kept hiring some kept hiring
men on this team so she ended up being
the only woman and she kept walking by
meetings and lunches that ended up not
having her included even though she had
the same title as them but she also
noticed I want should we go into their
office or a meeting
they would always say hey Cleo can you
dial in or Cleo can you take down notes
even though it wasn't her meeting to do
that Anthony he's actually a designer
and believe it or not and his company
they decided they want to throw a hip
hop party we're basically ahead on the
pamphlet itself it's okay to have
cornrows to dress up listen to rap and
hip hop music and this is the same
company that decided they didn't want to
celebrate MLK day off that they can use
their paid time off instead Tania a
security manager she's been in this
field for 20 years and she left to go
work for a tech company and because she
could not go past the title of manager
and she's african-american
a woman 20 years at a company that's
very well known and and it's just
unfortunate because she's someone who
gives back so much to the community and
she can't even go past a manager title
Rita a pen tester she's actually
applying for work and the first thing
she told me that I look at is to see who
is on the board if there's a woman on
the board that is not HR she will apply
if there isn't a woman she's like I do
not want to climb up that hill
the other one is Frank Frank is
african-american
he works for NATO for their security and
he told me he has never taken one day
off and the reason for that is because
he's the only African American male and
his team and he's worried if he takes
one day off someone will say something
and say that he's not doing a good job
because he took a day off so from
stories it changes our perspectives and
beliefs and also can remove blindfolds
bring awareness and overall it can make
us really uncomfortable because the best
part about stories is when it questions
yourself what am i doing
that's making this situation continuing
so how do we apply this to solve the gap
well one you can speak up and push your
company to have more diverse execs and
board members sometimes that works
sometimes it really doesn't you can also
do a start early to promote the field so
this was taken from a cybersecurity
conference which had a bunch of kids
from East Bay to try to get them into
cybersecurity and this is one of my
students that I got to mentor during
that time and he actually did a
spoken-word thing that you guys get to
hear if it works okay here we go
[Music]
[Applause]
so this this kid right here he's
actually he's a well he's like one of
those students that like is he loves
everything and all the times they can't
focus on one thing in particular and
he's also kind of quote-unquote he
doesn't call him a troublemaker but in
reality what he had was a rebellious
streak and what he liked to do was
trying to figure out how to like break
into classrooms and how to unlock things
sounds like kind of like our culture a
little bit here right so I connected him
with a hacker and now he's learning
Python believe it or not and that's what
he wants to hear so the other thing is
you can attend conferences that empower
underrepresented persons it doesn't
matter if his day of Shaqiri which is
like on my laptop
yes I know David security is a great
conference it was for a bunch of women
um over 200 women uh came to this
conference and it was wonderful but also
what we needed to see was more men even
if it says you know they are she curity
still come so go because it shows that
you care about women being in the field
and women need to see that more than
ever before also there's other types of
organizations that are doing conferences
you have the Diana you also have oh
there's just so many especially during
DEFCON there's like all these like will
small ones like hacking diversity is one
of them I highly recommend going to them
also get involved in outreach
participating volunteering like those
students that you saw on those pictures
from East Oakland they have you can
actually get involved and push your
company to get involved too now remember
when I said you can go up to your board
or you could go to the CEO or the sea
levels or why not
that's a little bit tricky but you can
go to your managers or get other people
at your company to recruit them come
onboard and you do volunteer in over the
weekend then post a bunch of photos on
slack I swear to god what ends up
happening is the HR person will see them
be like huh this is a good idea we
should be doing this more marketing it's
gonna love it because you're like we got
to do this more people like people that
like people so I mean this is a great
opportunity
push your work to volunteer there's
black girls code there's there's hidden
geniuses there's tons of organizations
and if you are still don't know where to
go and volunteer come and let me know I
will let you know what organizations now
most importantly though I hope from the
exercise and a little bit before diving
into our brains and what not but the
this start really does looking at
yourself in the mirror what am I doing
here how can I make things better and
also share the stories the stories that
you hear from other people share that
because stories are life-changing to a
certain extent so the three takeaways
like I promised is personal stories are
powerful push your company and increase
the their diverse talent by volunteering
sponsoring and listening in return
awareness can happen and last but not
least allow yourself to become
uncomfortable and vulnerable and lastly
it is only with the heart that one can
see rightly what is essential is
invisible to the eyes yes as you
probably know us a lot of slides happen
to have a little prince in it because
this happens to be my favorite book I
even loved foxes but you'll see on the
next slide on the questions any
questions
[Music]
so a lot of the reactions is one the
person it gets if it if it's like right
after my talk or whatnot sometimes a
little message me the saying I'm really
worried someone is gonna share my story
and I didn't want them to share that and
then I remind her that it's a safe space
but also you're her story probably is
gonna change someone else's story that's
one the other thing is that they felt
really really uncomfortable and nervous
for the first two three minutes but then
I started realizing that somehow
something triggered where they felt
morally also brings two strangers really
close really fast that's the other
things I usually hear any other
questions yes you brought up the concept
of business people of this core set of
beliefs they vary the uplinks president
very hard to change and you have this
more dynamic set that's tends to persist
for a few years or whatever and handy
buddy
[Music]
yeah well I mean okay so going to the me
to movement really fast on that um well
the thing is is that even though it's
gained more attention than ever before I
would say definitely with social media
the one thing for sure is that still
prosecution in itself is not it hasn't
really changed as much and we have seen
that now today unfortunately now when it
comes to understanding another person I
think when we get out of our comfort
bubble especially like if you're
traveling or whatnot and actually just
getting out of your comfort bubble you
start learning a lot more about the
world we live in and the people that are
in it so one of the things is that I
worked with some special kids special ed
kids and sometimes there's always this
belief in the textbook that like oh a
song with like who's extremely autistic
high on the spectrum that they're just
all over the place they could be violent
and whatnot I sent X to akin I worked
with this kid for like almost a year
is autistic high on the spectrum it was
the sweetest boy I've ever met the
reason that he kept acting on classroom
was because he his teacher kept putting
him down and didn't believe in him his
parents didn't want to accept him so he
had a lot of anger built up so I think
one of the things is definitely is
getting outside the bubble we tend to
find more about other people but we also
start accepting and trying to understand
other people with empathy and I think
that's the key right there is actually
empathy itself not compassion but
empathy any other questions
[Music]
yeah all right let me try to break you
down three things okay one the lack of
confidence is something that's actually
been programmed in most people that are
minorities and also and women as well
for example when it comes to sending
resumes for a white male they'll be like
sixty percent might be like oh yeah I
have that I meet all that criteria 60
percent of that criteria that is and I'm
gonna apply women we have to do over 110
percent and that's the same for
minorities is because there's this lack
of confidence because I think it has a
lot to do with Society I think it has a
lot to do with maybe you know seeing in
movies for example you know not seeing
someone who looks like you being able to
achieve something is something that
really holds one back but it also makes
them
about the possibilities I think of all
the times where I hear about women that
are trying to start a company and I see
them and I know that only 2% are going
to be funded and I just look at them and
I was I'm worried because the thing is
at the end of the day is that they
they're still pushing they're giving
more than anything possible and they're
working their butt off and then they
don't get funds at all because of their
own gender and I see that even with
minorities some will actually sit in the
back of the classroom instead being in
the front of the classroom and I think
that's because you know the lack of
conscience because we don't meet
criteria that society has placed on us
since a very young age
[Music]
define this part of you that believes
that you're worth something and if you
feel like you're not worth something try
to find out why that is he's gonna think
at the end of the day is that when we
start doing like we're not worthy of
something I feel like that's a challenge
look at as a challenge where you're like
start remembering everyone who says you
can't do this you can't do that
think of all the stereotypes I saw here
the biases though placed on you and use
that as a fuel to be like you know what
fine I'm gonna prove you wrong and by
prove you wrong I mean you're proving to
yourself you're worthy at that point and
I feel like that's where the start
starts it has to happen within you and
unfortunately we cannot change other
people's opinions and thoughts
especially if it's very much ingrained
but at least we could share stories
[Music]
like equal like you know the love are
equal like men and women then when I go
to RSA and look at that like oh my god
and then you're like okay please see my
assistance please say not assistance
ends up with them being assistance
you're like oh man but at least there's
no line for the bathroom and that's a
good thing in some ways but honestly it
it's unfortunate but you are right
there's a shortage of protein and it's
giving people are gonna push in now at
this point you can't say you know
anymore I'm any other questions all
right well thank you oh wait
okay why it didn't hit me that that's
what I was dealing with because I was
not proper for last time that suddenly
went to cybersecurity I'm here and then
what happened was when I went to RSA and
I started seeing like there was no women
here and now all white men Leon St I
remember going back to the hotel room
which stretch the bathroom like why do I
feel like there's something wrong like I
just don't feel right and then I just
broke down crying and I think that's
when it hit me something's wrong here I
literally like I just thought there's
like and that was it the tipping point
was that was like in April right two
months go in and that's Lilly I start
thinking like I want to leave this space
because I but something changed me where
I just kind of got to a point where some
life things happen and I was like I got
proved to myself I'm worthy of something
so I submitted a talk and it was
accepted and my voice is cracking
because they have got over a flu I'm not
crying
but yeah Sarah that was that was my
tipping point was that moment was that
somehow he had to prove to myself that
I'm worthy of something and then I just
kept going forward and every time I felt
like I needed to take a step back or
anything like that I would just throw my
throw myself even harder and keep going
against the current and now I'm very
fortunate is that I built
number because I kept kosher things and
that Network has been supporting me more
than ever before and I help them too but
most importantly it's helped me grow and
it's also given them the ability to see
you know these issues that are around
the area because it is men and women
that are champions for women and for
minorities as well so thank you guys you
guys are the trooper submitted till the
end and all those other guys I'm doing
do is great so we'll see you tomorrow
we'll have a chris Roberts tomorrow
which is the play hacker you know the
Chris by nature is very comfortable
versatile so I'm looking forward to stop
tomorrow and we're gonna keep trying to
capture the flag and then we'll just
have one one room tomorrow we're gonna
have the common area we keep the one I
love big in our stuff and we should have
a hopefully you guys like it today
I'm inclined to announce tomorrow that
we're doing it again throw the always
starts the source or finish I'll see you
next Amaro
[Applause]