this is actually one of the ducts that I
was I myself was looking forward to see
we're gonna have a tech corporal from
Verona in getting left of Boone and I I
haven't seen the entirety of it but I've
been told that this is say a a
presentation about dealing with
detection of IEDs am I correct in
Afghanistan or Iraq as I previously said
Iraq let me correct myself Afghanistan
so without further ado here's Ted Carell
thank you I appreciate the invite today
to speak thank you even more for putting
me up against the happy hour
so I thank everyone for being here on a
Saturday afternoon and I know there's a
networking event going on right now so
if everyone would turn to the left and
introduce yourself to that person
then to the right right now you haven't
missed anything right you've got you've
got networking out of the way and now
you can focus on on the talk today so
like rod said I'm a retired Marine
intelligence officer so my previous life
my job was to provide timely relevant
and accurate information to support
decision making to mitigate risk right
risk of military operations now my job
as a cyber security effectiveness
advisor is to provide data once again to
mitigate risk drive decision-making for
risk but it's business risk from cyber
alright so the topic we said it's gonna
be left a boom so I'm gonna share with
you as some of my military experiences
related to driving data-driven
decision-making to support and defeat
counter ID activity our improvised
explosive device activities Mike as as
we as you can probably imagine right a
boom after the bang
mitigation forensics it's kind of messy
right it's expensive to deal with so
getting left the boom is where we want
to be and that same stuff translates
here and when it comes to cybersecurity
right so a big part of recently retired
from the Marine Corps so I'm just a
little over three years out of my
military service and a big part of that
military transition is being able to
adapt what you did in the military to a
new space so many of
you're gonna hear me say today is gonna
be translating military tactics and
techniques and procedures into
application into cybersecurity right so
a lot of people here are more technical
than me probably from a cybersecurity
perspective so you may not hear much new
but I guarantee you will hear it in a
new way so the term left the boom was
adopted in about 2007 to describe our
shift in tactics and techniques and
procedures to try to get a left of boom
so in the Marine Corps all mission
planning begins with mission analysis
and problem framing we define what
success looks like first and then we
backwards plan from there with the time
and materials and personnel available to
accomplish that mission all right when
it comes to cyber our mission is to
protect critical assets almost every
modern enterprise today every company
every organization has some kind of
critical data assets whether it be I pee
or financial data something from which
they derive their competitive advantage
from right and a loss of that data would
be detrimental to their ability to
conduct their operations so as we see
these companies are now spending
billions of dollars right on security
tools and services for 2019 gartner
predicts companies will spend 128
billion dollars on security so this is
becoming a strategic business imperative
to get the biggest bang for your buck no
pun intended right all right so like I
said this is all about adapting military
experiences to the cyber space so first
the good war story everyone loves a war
story so if you recall shortly following
the terrorist attacks of 2001 we
declared war on terrorism and we
launched campaigns against insurgents in
both Iraq and Afghanistan to fight them
on their turf right and prevent them
from conducting to continual new
operations here on American soil all
right so one side you have the greatest
fighting force in the history of mankind
right trillion dollar budget
highly-trained high-tech weaponry and on
the right you have a bunch of insurgents
in sandals and go fasters running shoes
with 70s and 80s era weaponry I
shouldn't have been much of a fight
however we were surprised to see that
the it wasn't quite as easy as it set
out right insurgents had several
advantages over us that we didn't
anticipate first they had the advantage
of anonymity it was easy for them to
blend in the local populace right we
realized that they didn't have to fight
fair right they could adopt asymmetric
warfare but the most surprising thing
was it took a relatively low amount of
Technology and simple tactics to have
devastating impacts on us right for just
a 500-pound bomb laying around anywhere
can be fashioned into an improvised
explosive device and defeat our armored
vehicles with catastrophic effects so we
do what any good Marine does you give me
crappy gear the first thing I'm going to
do is Hillbilly tup bolt on some armor
right to try to protect myself from the
blasts then we invest the Department of
Defense and vendors get involved
security vendors they developed strap on
arming and then up-armored hmmwv
variants and Hesco barriers right all
hardening the perimeter right so make it
make it make it so we can try to
mitigate the effects of a IAD explosion
but as you might imagine it doesn't
really matter how hard you hardened the
perimeter of a vehicle the soft Marines
and soldiers inside get dead nonetheless
right so spending right a boom was just
uneffective it didn't matter how much
armor or you put around them a simple
bomb could still have devastating
impacts on them in fact some of the up
armored vehicles just made Marines
survive with catastrophic injuries and
traumatic brain injuries so it was
exasperating the problem we see the same
thing in cyber right spending hundreds
and millions of dollars on cyber Hesco
barriers right from proxies and
firewalls
DLP IDs IPF endpoint right antivirus
software hundreds of million dollars
Harding the perimeter and just like we
saw with IEDs simple technology can
undermine that right perfectly example
is Experian last year you see before
Congress CEOs testifying spent 250
million dollars on cyber in his budget
and yet simple Apache struts
vulnerability resulted in the largest
compromised of person PII data for
Americans in history right high tech
versus low tech challenging problem so
just like we saw with spending lots of
money and not being able to defeat the
counter Aidid about your ID devices we
see the same thing in cybersecurity
right large amounts of investment and
resources and effort is now equating to
cyber security effectiveness right
something's got to change we got to
think about doing this things
differently some of the common
advantages that I see over the threat I
face then right to the threat I face now
in cyber as it's relatively inexpensive
right it doesn't take much to fashion a
naive device from a 500-pound bomb or
take a laptop on a few lines of code or
if someone saw the first briefing of the
day right very simple to hack into IOT
super scary right makes me want to go
off the grid right does it it's not
expensive to have devastating
consequences low attribution just like
the insurgents I explained before could
blend into local populace hackers can
hide in anonymity behind a keyboard you
see it's very hard to and when it comes
to attribution for who's conducting
these attacks it's relatively easy to do
right simple tactics simple technology
can have highly effective when it comes
to cyber hacks right frustratingly and
last but not least you see a high payoff
for a relatively small investment and a
little bit of equipment a little bit of
energy sweat energy on a keyboard you
can get high high value compromise and a
steal lots of money worth of IP right
very common advantages makes it very
very difficult fight
it's not on women it's not unwinnable so
in a terms what I camped encounter I DS
we realized that we had to start
thinking differently we started we had
to start focusing our time and resources
and energy to getting left of boom right
we formed the joint improvised device
defeat organization by dedicated to
coming up with tactics techniques and
procedures to get left of boom so big
part of that was the fusion of
intelligence analysis right and and to
try to identify techniques and
procedures to try to defeat the device
right and to attack the network prevent
those networks from even deploying the
devices themselves they they gave us
hundreds of millions of dollars in high
technology gear radar jammers
predetonation all kinds of technical
gear that required extensive training to
operate and when you get out into the
field conditions with this stuff it was
even more difficult to operate properly
and he won't weren't always sure that it
was gonna work the way the vendor told
you was gonna work
he just had to help and pray that
because you had that latest I could gear
that's sure gonna be safe but in my line
of work I was all about the analytical
effort I was doing the data analysis and
the research to try to identify the
attack network they insurgent networks
who were they getting their financings
from to try and intercept their
financing try to find out who was the
bomb maker doing forensic analysis and
identify and who was the technical skill
level building the devices going after
them and then we were also introducing a
lot of technology to establish baseline
so monitoring the the roads we were
gonna travel in advance and then using
coherent change detection to compare and
contrast you know see if there is any
changes disturbed earth that might be
the signals for emplacing ID devices so
left of left of boom thinking now we're
starting to see that same mindset
applied to cybersecurity we're starting
to see a lot of companies invest in
technologies to get left of boom a lot
more spending on prevention and
detection right instead of Jeff
Mitigation right so while it might be
sexy to do forensics can identify who
did it after the fact right there's
already a damage is already done you've
already lost that IP you've already
sustained that brand reputation of
damage that's very hard to come from
when consumer lose confidence in you
so you want to focus on left to boom
right we see risk assessments
vulnerability scanning penetration
testing security instrumentation right
very similar mindset let's focus left a
boom so how do we get left of boom right
this is going to be about mindset
changing the perceptive perception
looking at the problem from a different
direction so we're gonna talk about
knowing your enemy training like you
fight and then inspecting what you may
expect right military principles applied
to this problem set so let's take a look
first at knowing your enemy right so all
of you who's familiar with this quote
most have you heard of Sun Tzu before
right art of war great read right this
is all about context and relativity
right what he's saying and it is it
doesn't do you any good to be successful
and defeating your enemy you need to
know what your capabilities and
limitations are what your strengths and
vulnerabilities are and you also need to
know and context to the strengths and
vulnerabilities of your enemy and apply
your strengths against their
vulnerabilities and sure your defenses
up against their strengths right this is
this is what this is all about so when
it comes to cyber threat actors we're
gonna talk about four groups it's
important to understand their
motivations their mindset what's driving
their actions so you can focus your
efforts to counter that appropriately so
we're talking about insider threats
cyber criminals activists and
nation-states
again this is going to go back to
another war story so on December 2011 a
week before Christmas I deployed to
Afghanistan right our mission at that
time was to set the conditions to turn
over responsibilities to the Afghan
government right our job was to set the
conditions for the safe withdrawal of US
forces because President
did me the favor of announcing publicly
that fall that we are withdrawing and
set a date by which all US troops are
going to be were moved from Afghanistan
so complicated our problem so we were
over there primarily to focus on the
Taliban insurgents however when I got
into theater I quickly realized that it
was more complex than that
there were many threat actors in my area
of operations that were interfering with
my ability to accomplish my mission and
these aligns very specifically to the
cyber threat actors we're going to talk
about we had insider threat from the
Afghan army we had criminal Patriot
network over there concerned about drug
financing we had Taliban insurgents and
then we had to deal with nation states
ourselves interfering with our ability
to our operations start with the
insiders right whether it be your
grandmother who keeps clicking on that
phishing email or your Uncle Jack who's
tired of being a dull boy right these
guys can be very difficult to counter
and can have devastating effects morally
because they can have catastrophic
damages based to their access and
privileges that they have any
organization why are they so tough to
defend against because most of our
defenses are geared outwards and not
inwards so very challenging three main
types there's more than this but
generally in our practice we see three
types of insider threat you have that
careless insider right that guy that no
matter how many hours of security
awareness training you make and you mic
him sit through he's still gonna have
weak passwords he's still gonna write
them down on a sticky and stick it to
his clap top right take a selfie with it
in the background and post it on
Instagram so everyone knows his login
credentials right he's still gonna put a
large amounts of data unencrypted on a
thumb drive and then lose it or lose his
company laptop that he doesn't even have
a password set on right careless
insiders are a constant problem
malicious insiders those other people
could be disgruntled worker that wants
payback right that wants burn bridges on
his way out of town
or you're not paying him enough so he's
gonna go get his some other way right or
someone that's just trying to destroy
something and the last one is
masquerading insiders so those are
people that
are not company employees but they get
into through alternative means whether
that be malware ransomware or an actual
person breaching into your perimeter so
in Afghanistan we had the largest I went
over there with the mindset that we were
gonna primarily be threatened by Afghan
assertions but it turns out as if you
can see in this table here that in 2011
and then the year I was there the
greatest threat to our forces the
greatest amount of casualties was
actually from the Afghan army a true
insider attached right for whatever
reason well we started to do you know
just imagine how frustrating that is
when we were there once again with the
purposes of training side-by-side with
them so they could take over
responsibility for security of their own
country and they're shooting us in the
back right extremely frustrating and
demoralizing but even worse than that
was no matter how minor the incident the
PR implications that the Taliban could
leverage that to reinforce the narrative
that they were driving us out of the
country was irreparable to our brand
image right our brand we're supposed to
be mighty American forces we're supposed
to be training them to take care of
themselves and yet we can't protect
ourselves right devastating to our brand
reputation right difficult to counter an
insider threat
sadly 17 years laters it's still going
on so I know if anyone saw the news
November 3rd governor Afghan army
national guard killed by an insider he
was over there a training cadre killed
so still still happening 17 years into
the fight businesses could see the same
detrimental impact to their brand
reputation so here we saw this this
summer with Tesla you can see
highlighted in red here the impact of
their stock price when reports came out
of sabotage by a disgruntled employee
allegedly he was passed over for
promotion wasn't too happy about it so
he hacked into the manufacturing
operating system on the Tesla 3
production line right and and caused it
to to mal phone
right did anyone tell me why the stock
peaked on August 7th does anyone know
who knows someone knows oh yeah
all right tweet all right Elan must
tweeted out that screw this I'm gonna
take it private right and we saw an
artificial spike in it but you can see
it quickly dissipated because that
opened the hope hold another can of
worms for Tesla right they didn't so we
can see the double whammy right first
malicious insider hacks them are then a
careless insider right it's a double
whammy so insider threats right very
very difficult to counter the next
category we're going to talk about is
cyber criminals so these guys are
motivated by money right cyber criminals
are in it for the money but what's
challenging about dealing with cyber
criminals is you have to fight them and
abide by laws that they don't they don't
want to fight fair right so it's oh it's
hard that the deck is stacked against
you when they're allowed to do whatever
they want and you must abide by laws and
regulations and policies as with insider
threats there's a couple of different
categories of cyber criminals now
granted sometimes insiders and in
insiders and others and can be motivated
by money but we're gonna talk about them
separately for when it in the context of
cyber criminals we're gonna focus on
three types so you have the
professionals purely in it that's their
cottage industry that's their business
they're in it for the money we see them
now even automating a lot of this
through technology or offering
cybercrime as a service right making
money by doing this on your behalf you
see the Mules in the middle who might be
naive or coerced into laundering the
proceeds from illicit cyber criminal
activity and then you have the getaways
this the youngsters that aren't aren't
as punishable under the law as older
people or they're just they're motivated
out of curiosity or prestige right or
maybe money but they they can they can
be quickly groomed into true
professionals with the right mentorship
so Afghanistan like I mentioned we had
to deal with cyber criminals but before
we talk about that let's do a quick
geography lesson so you can see up in
the upper right hand corner Afghanistan
is what the Hindu Kush mountains slowly
it's going down into a desert here in
Helmand province which was my area of
operations so why would it does anyone
know why you would care about this arid
piece of dirt flat dirt does anyone know
why not oil in Afghanistan but there are
some minerals but it turns out that that
is actually the most fertile irritable
form land in an entire area of of Asia
so beginning in the nineteen forty six
the United States supported multiple
projects for the Helmand Valley
Association which was mirrored after the
Tennessee River Valley Association we
built a bunch of dams and canal systems
to help irrigation because in this part
of the country most of the tribes are
subsistence farmers right they are
growing crops primarily to support
themselves but as the population was
starting to grow we we supported these
type of activities in order to increase
crop yields to support a larger populous
right anyone tell me what the primary
crop grown in Helmand province is now
poppy you are right sir it is not to to
to soup lie the demand for poppy seed
bagels right in the country it's because
what's poppy what anyone know what the
SAP of the poppy plant can be used to
produce yeah opiates right opium right
so you can imagine right for whatever
reason right mostly there are either
that's the highest yield crop that the
farmers could grow right so why grow
wheat or corn right when you can grow
poppy and make much more money or you're
coerced by Taliban insurgency will cut
your head off if you don't grow poppy
but we had many different actors in this
in this our area was disrupted by the
fight over this élisa élisa
the drug trade the funds from this so as
Taliban insurgents there was criminal
Patriot networks and in some cases sadly
it was Afghan officials all wanted their
cut of it so a very very complex
situation to maintain good order and
discipline and stability in a region
when everyone's fighting over a drug
money and we see business also have
trouble conducting operations due to
cyber criminals so we saw last summer
HBO
hacked right allegedly by an Iraqi or
rainy and hacker right threatened them
they wanted six million dollars in
Bitcoin in exchange for not releasing
unaired videos of episodes of ballers
and berry or an unaired script of Game
of Thrones finale but you know it takes
more than just a little bit of a cyber
hacker to take down a Khaleesi right
because they still had the largest
ratings for Season Finale than all seven
of their seasons the next group we're
going to talk about is hacktivists so
hacktivists aren't motivated by money
they're motivated by a political agenda
right they want to fight against
injustice but in my mind
terrorists and activists are the same
only their tactics differ right they
both are motivated for a political
agenda or social agenda terrorists
choose violence and hacktivists choose
subversive use of computers so in
Afghanistan the biggest problem we had
to face was a Taliban right again we
were there to legitimate to defeat
Taliban influence and legitimize the
Afghan government as the legitimate
rulers of that country but you can see
on the right of recent Wall Street
Journal New York Times article show that
after billions of dollars 17 years
thousands of lives they still control a
majority of the country right because it
just shows you it doesn't take much
effort to win that PR campaign to win
over popular opinion we see the same
thing when it comes to cyber right cyber
activists groups right leverage
low scale attacks to push their social
agenda so one example here is anonymous
right you see two attacks here recently
one here in the area one in Ferguson
Missouri rights activist attacks against
these governments for violence against
unarmed black use youths right so again
it didn't take much effort to win that
PR CL to get mass visibility and bring
awareness to their cause the last group
we're gonna talk about our nation states
does anyone know what this picture is
from the interview and what happened to
Sony when they were gonna release this
this movie crippling devastating impacts
right from attacks from North Korea
allegedly right so we see many countries
now building out cyber forces so it's
becoming that fifth domain of war the
challenges international arms treaties
don't address cyber warfare we haven't
updated those terminologies to do that
and in some cases cyber attacks can have
more detrimental effects than nuclear
you know just as much as a nuclear
device right we see taken to you hack
out the hack and take down the
infrastructure electronic grid right our
water treatment facilities can have
devastating impacts against the civilian
populace as a result we see most
countries doing these types of attacks
surreptitiously right to avoid
attribution but that doesn't make it any
easier to defend against these type of
attacks so in Afghanistan we had to deal
with nation-states it was no secret that
Iran in Pakistan were openly supporting
the Taliban and in the case of Pakistan
they offered them sanctuary from which
they could plan and conduct operations
from so in my area of operations we had
the village of power of bomb Shah so
this village spanned the border between
Pakistan and Afghanistan so they would
conduct numerous operate
against them right to where there were
staged to prevent the staging of attacks
and movement of materials and manpower
into our area of operations but we had
to stay north of the line Brian our
hands were tied right again we had to
abide by laws and regulations that they
didn't have to so I was extremely
frustrating not being able to retaliate
against someone because of some
arbitrary lying on the ground
does anyone else know anyone that gets
frustrated by not being able to
retaliate against someone from an
arbitrary line in the ground right
poor dog right foghorn leghorn stand on
the other side of line right so I'm not
saying that the Taliban or Looney tune
fans and I'm not saying that Warner
Brothers supported the Taliban I'm just
saying that I can't help but note the
similarities here between this situation
and the situation we faced in the
southwest Afghanistan but right now
we're witnessing the largest transfer of
information knowledge in the history of
mankind and most of that is happening
illegally or have the United States is
struggling with preventing nation states
from stealing our intellectual
properties and this is illustrated here
in the case of American Superconductor
so they have signed they were a
manufacturer of wind turbines they had a
proprietary operating system right that
would produce energy from these devices
China Chinese company had a contract
with them when they couldn't
reverse-engineer the solution themselves
they paid a Serbian contractor to steal
that for them so after seven years
lawsuits write American Superconductor
they had to lay off half their company
it was crippling and they lost a billion
dollars in share and market share but as
you can see we successfully convicted
China of InTouch of a threat and they
had to pay a 59 million dollar fine 59
million dollar fine as a result of a 1
billion dollars in lost value to
American company I do not know if they
have paid it this was July when the when
verdict came out the sentence was put
down but just show is extremely
frustrating when your limp when your
hands are tied and limited see what you
can do against nation states the next
military principle is train like you
fight so one of the tenets of Marine
Corps training is we train like we fight
right you heard the old adage practice
makes perfect right but I would argue
that that's not true practice makes
habits right so realistic training
develops strong proper habits piss-poor
training develops poor habits right so
as we see in preparation for our
diplomat deployments the one of the last
things we did was conduct operations in
what were called a the immersion trainer
so these were purposely built villages
fall to scale that mirrored villages in
Iraq or Afghanistan
they have professional hired role
players Iraqi or Afghan speakers foreign
nationals here that play the roles they
were cooked at open Bazaar like fully
manned we would patrol through and they
had Hollywood level special-effects
pyrotechnics to simulate devices going
off and moulage kids to put blood and
gore on people that simulate lost limbs
and such so highly realistic training
the last thing you did before you went
downrange
so you can train like you fight in a
realistic situation we see this starting
to be developed here in a cyber side
right with cyber ranges so specialized
socks built up running active
simulations putting cyber sock analysts
through scenarios simulations to test
their skills right anyone here
participated in cyber ranges there we go
so I'm not just making this up I found
it on the internet so it must be true
right there's a picture of IBM cyber
range I saw in the back of a tractor
trailer they'll drive up to you on site
let you people walked out in the back of
this thing and do some drills some
simulations right or some other ideas an
audience that anyone do cyber training
any kind of realistic type training put
their people yeah so train
like you fight so some of the challenges
that we saw between you know insurgent
activities in cyber is you can't defend
anywhere or everywhere so you must
identify our critical assets so raise
your hand if you have unlimited security
budget yeah nobody right right nobody so
you you're forced to make decisions on
where you're gonna spend those resources
well to Liz you're gonna buy what
service is where you're gonna apply them
so identifying your critical assets is
critical but even if you had all the
money in the world throwing money at the
problem isn't the solution right it
doesn't work because technology doesn't
always work the way you think it is and
all these security tools can be
complicated to to set up and configure
properly and even if you had unlimited
budget even if you bought all the best
technology security tools in the world
and put it in your environment to
protect yourself it wouldn't matter
because it's not a static situation
right it's a dynamic fluid problem we're
fighting with right so on the bottom
here at corner you see the ODA loop
right observe orient decide and act so
you observe what your enemy is doing you
orient on that action you decide on
appropriate measures to defend against
that and then you act and carry those
out and you're continually evolving your
perspective and watching what the enemy
does to do that and the trick to this to
being successful is to get inside the
UNA loop of the enemy make big get the
initiative and make them react to you
which is difficult to do in a cyber
environment right but the biggest thing
is it's hard to measure success right an
ROI on your measures where to be
effectiveness a cyber of counter ID
operations or your cybersecurity efforts
be very difficult to quantify right with
metrics in calculating ROI which leads
us to our last tenant right Melissa
philosophy here inspect what you expect
so pictured here is the armor of the
Roman legion ear so in the time of Roman
of Caesar 12:12 Caesar they would line
up for morning inspections
and the commander would stand in front
of each Legionnaire and when he stood in
front of them before battle they would
strike their chest with their best play
baseplate and they was sound off Integra
toss or integrity right meaning that
they were whole of mind and body and
ready for battle and the commander would
listen for the sound of the armor to
make sure that it was whole and to make
sure that that protection was in place
so they were gonna be prepared to defend
themselves against the attacks of that
day swords or attacks so when it comes
to cyber security right how do we
measure effectiveness how do we measure
success so on the left you see most
organizations measure with you know some
kind of executive dashboard but
ultimately results in everyone's
favorite heat map right which whatever
random data you might be able to collect
and quantify you put it you sprinkle a
little bit of subjectivity in there and
you have a heat map that shows you green
we're good red we're not yellow we're
somewhere in between so on the left hand
side we have our flagship intelligence
product that I put out twice a year
there was a Taliban versus Afghan
government influence map so it would
take six months mark working with
multiple stakeholders gathering some
kind of data like number of attacks
right atmospherics in a village right a
leader engagement right blend that all
together and draw that piece of dirt red
green or yellow to measure our
effectiveness of our counterinsurgency
operations on the right hand side as a
heat map that was presented at RSA 2016
right same concept here bunch of random
metrics they put together sprinkle in
some subjectivity and measured against
the different categories whether they
were good or not good so what kind of
cybersecurity metrics do you guys use
here to measure effectiveness of your
programs any examples that you might use
anyone use time since last breach yeah
so they compared it year-over-year
comparison between money lost by
cyberattacks and if it was decreasing
that was good no we're doing right we're
doing better right they didn't steal as
much so we're improving right but if you
think about that's not really a
measurable effect of this is it because
you don't know if the number of tax went
down right you don't know how many you
blocked right if the only metric is the
damage inflicted by attack that's not
truly measuring effectiveness but you
got to have to do something right any
other metrics any other examples so what
we see is very difficult to measure
effectiveness of security because we're
forced to manage by assumptions right
we're forced to believe and assume that
the security technology works the way
the vendor says it does right we're
forced to assume that we've purchased
and set up and configured the piece of
technology security tool correctly we
have to assume that our people know what
they're doing they know how to use it
they know how to follow the processes
and procedures for a malware attack but
most importantly we assume that nothing
ever changes that once we get everything
dialed in right where we think it needs
to be that nothing ever changes right
but you know what they say about making
assumptions right you don't want to
manage my assumptions hope is not a plan
so what if I told you there was a way to
get quantifiable metrics evidence of
effectiveness of your security tools
people and processes do a security
instrumentation so security
instrumentation by integrating into your
security stack it will gather
quantifiably the evidence of
effectiveness of your tools that allows
you to measure manage and improve and
communicate the effectiveness of your
security program right so security is
rotation isn't just new it's something
completely different it's shifting that
mindset and looking at security a
different way
security rotation allows you to identify
gaps in your security controls by in by
integrating unique control stack and
gathering evidence that shows you
whether that's attack is being blocked
or night blocked or not allows you to
identify those gaps but because you're
instrumented you get that data you can
prescriptively tune where your where
your controls are failing and fix those
makes fixes to get those controls to
where they need to be and because your
instrumented now you can rerun that same
test and you can validate that those
changes corrected the problem and
improve the efficacy of your security
controls and then security
instrumentation will allow you to
automate that process and continually
validate the effectiveness those
controls and alerts you if something
changes and last but not least because
you've quantified this in data now it
allows you to clearly communicate the
effectiveness of your program and clear
metrics and quantify it on ROI on that
investment so now I bet you're asking me
how does it work so a simple concept so
the main component you have a cyber
security effect in this brain this is
the central core component that will
plan the attacks and then they'll gather
the and I great with your security stack
you know gather that evidence of how
they're responding to those attacks what
actions are they taking what information
is being sent from your firewall to your
sim is there a correlated rule that
triggered an alert so your analyst saw
it right it integrates with all that
collects that data and then it
integrates with sensors or standalone
agents that you deploy throughout your
live production environment so these
aren't 2,000 agents were us embed them
in your database or on your mainframe or
in your servers right are on every
endpoint these are standalone agents
that are deployed throughout your
environment so here's what a basic
network looks like with all your
business zones right you see your
standard security controls right your
Hesco barriers right from your firewalls
your proxies your DOP your IDs IPs
now here's where it gets cool right
because your agents act as both an
attacker and a defender they only attack
themselves
so it's completely safe and they act
they actually execute real test
behaviors so it's not a simulation they
don't copy and and emulate behaviors
they run real live attack behaviors in
your production environment and they do
it safely because they only attack each
other right so you deploy this and you
want it to go through all your security
stack and the integration to the
controls effect in this brain allows it
to capture all that data measure the
effectiveness of it and generate those
reports that lets you know was the
attack block did your palo block it yes
or no did it detect it if it detected it
then it's ended up to your sim did your
sim receive the message when the sim
received the message was there a
correlated rule that triggered an alert
and then did that alert fire and until
your analyst saw it and was actually
aware that the attack was happening all
right all quantifiable evidence you need
a few security if you instrument your
network now once you have that data you
can start having data-driven decisions
around risk right risk to the business
based on cyber so across the on the
right hand side you see all the
different use cases by which security
instrumentation will support with
quantifiable data at the bottom you have
breach and attack simulation throwing a
bunch of attacks against your network
and seeing if something is stopped or
not
tactical low level right you can map
that to whatever framework you prefer
mitre attack sans 20 right hi-tech if
you're in health care now you can start
communicating the effectiveness of your
cyber security problem in terms of a
framework that the business understands
so they have a business risk decision as
you move up the maturity level you can
start using this to evaluate the
effectiveness of your people and
processes if you're launching the attack
and you know what's happening now you
can measure if your people are actually
performing the right processes in
response to those behaviors you can
validate if you have an MS SP you have
the data by which you can evaluate they
SLA with them
are they blocking and detecting and
responding appropriately right are they
even seeing it and although at the top
what is really important about this is
now that you have the data you could
turn cybersecurity into a risk business
decision so for example you have
efficacy that shows if you're concerned
about data exfiltration and you're
spending you know 80 million a hundred
million dollars on all these tools and
you found out that you're only 80%
effective and for a million dollars you
can buy an a DLP tool that will give you
an extra ten percent effectiveness
now you just had a business now you can
have a business level discussion around
it is 10 percent risk worth a million
dollars to the company or they'd rather
spend that million dollars on something
else and accept that risk right business
level conversation as I said in a former
life I was providing timely relevant and
accurate information to support
data-driven decisions to mitigate risk
to military operations for cyber
security you can do the same thing if
you have security instrumentation right
executives in corporate America rely on
data every single day to make business
decisions and they use metrics and KPIs
to calculate and measure improvement and
calculate ROI and their investments so
why shouldn't cybersecurity be the same
thing so during this talk I covered some
of the similarities to my military
experience how you can adapt some of the
military tenets of training like you
fight inspecting what you expect right
shifting your perspective and focusing
on the metrics data-driven decisions
around cybersecurity effectiveness to
mitigate risk right so hopefully
incorporating some of these mindsets and
some of these techniques into your
programs will allow you to get left of
breach so with that I'll open it up to
any questions yes
right so your question was security
instrumentation is there risk to over
automating some traditional functions or
becoming overly reliant on right you're
right so that I mean that's what's
what's important about security
instrumentation it's not meant to
automate behaviors it's not meant to
replace humans it's meant to automate
some of the functions so you can collect
that data that you need to drive those
decisions so you could choose what tests
to take right it's not meant to replace
a threat intelligence feed it's not
meant to be anything you know you can
program and build your own attacks but
the security instrumentation allows you
to measure the effectiveness of that and
have that data you need to know whether
what you're doing is working and what
you watch if you're protected against
the threats that are most important to
you and protecting the data that's most
critical to you you're right there's
always a trap right technology
automation can breed laziness but if you
if you can automate some of the
lower-level sophisticated techniques
then it frees up your people to be more
to focus on those more advanced
penetration techniques or exploitation
great question any other questions of
getting left a boom security
instrumentation
so there was a whole coalition we
weren't there ourselves unilaterally
Pakistan was actually an ally of us they
let us use their rail system to move
materials and stuff in there's the same
but it's a philosophical debate they're
Muslim country Taliban is Muslim so
sometimes the enemy of my enemy is my
friend kind of thing Iran didn't they
they would provide training or sanctuary
to conduct operations from so it's just
it's just a tumultuous chaotic
environment in that country even or in
that area of Asia Oh already yeah so
lots of countries bordering that to just
view that Afghan as a place to do proxy
fighting we won't fight each other
directly but we'll fight each other
through the insurgents so enemies of us
wouldn't fight us openly but they would
support the Taliban to fight us
indirectly which we did to them the
Soviets in the 80s right turnaround is
fair play we supported the Taliban in
the 80s when the Soviets were in
Afghanistan until they withdrew and then
now we take our turn in the barrel so to
speak so that's awesome thank you it's
awesome more hands
yes right so her question was you know
it's India refers to that territory as
something other than Afghanistan right
am i right he has everything about
Afghanistan is a European Western
European Convention right British
colonized most of the world and you
arbitrary lines around people that
aren't necessarily view themselves of
Afghanistan
so if you recall I mentioned in my
particular area it's mostly tribes right
so the majority of the Afghan people are
loyal to their tribes and it goes back
thousands of years they don't see
themselves as Afghanistan right so they
weren't open to interference from us or
the Taliban or even the government of
the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan at
that time President Karzai they didn't
care their subsistence farmers they're
taking care of their tribe they don't
want anyone coming into their lands and
bothering them so it's very very a
challenging dynamic situation so lots of
lots of things different things at play
in that area of the world and many other
areas of the world to include the Middle
East right sometimes not everyone agrees
those lines on the draw that the lines
on the ground are drawn appropriately or
they every choose to follow them
right so your question was are we
collecting data by which we could turn
over to government officials or law
enforcement officials to help go against
some of the criminal activity or insider
threat or such right we we don't collect
the data right our my particular company
we sell a product that does security
instrumentation so full disclosure right
we it's a more of a business analytics
tool a platform from which companies can
collect and do that data themselves we
are involved in a lot of the ice acts
and we do a lot of work embedded with
the government we work with mitre
so we are leveraging our platform to
collect the data that they can have to
use they collect the data internal to
their stuff but what's important about
the point of the knowing different
threat actors was security you can't you
have to look outward when it comes to
the security right you have to decide
first what are your critical assets what
do you want to protect and then you have
to understand and put that in the
context of what are the likely threat
act vectors actors and vectors they're
gonna come at me with and design your
attacks around the primary threats right
or in military terms the most likely
Avenue of approach right because you
don't have unlimited resources you have
to prioritize those
so you have to prioritize those in
accordance with what you think is the
most likely threat right and then you
just have to start while the other
actors could potentially breach you and
you could have you there you assess that
there are lower risk to you so you have
to prioritize your limited resources to
that so I answer your question Thanks
sure so that's a great question I can
tell you that Gartner has put us in the
breach and attack simulation quadrant
category so our primary competitors and
Essbase are safe breach to attack IQ
simulate right but when in terms of but
we are not a cybersecurity tool we're a
business analytics platform we just
happen to reside in cybersecurity for
now so breach an attack they'll tell you
was an attack successful yes or no all
right security instrumentation when it
comes to breach an attack it's a yes and
response yes you can leverage our
platform to conduct breach an attack
simulation
however our attack behaviors are not
neutered they're not simulations our
emulations they're real attack behaviors
right but on top of that the
instrumentation integration in your
entire stack gives you evidence of how
your security controls actually
responded did your palo block it yes or
no did it send an alert that it alert
arrived to your sim did it receive it
was there a correlated rule that
triggered an alert so an analyst saw it
right that is all what security
instrumentation that the evidence of
effectiveness and the data that it
collects above and beyond reach an
attack correct they do yes
so they'll deploy yes they'll do
simulated attacks against your network
and tell you if they were successful or
not great question
any other questions comments concerns
any other veterans in the room no all
right well I appreciate you all coming
out
appreciate your time I look forward to
getting to know more for the rest of the
day if you want to know more about
security cementation are here any more
war stories come find me or desiree in
the back she also works with me we'll be
more than happy to tell you more about
us and our company nice
[Applause]