all right thank you so much everyone
Rohan take it away I'm really excited
for this talk all right hell
everybody had Sam mentioned the title of
this talk in g-suit security everyone
wants it but not everyone gets it and
just FYI I will be monitoring the chat
so after the talk if I have some time
I'm happy to answer any questions you
guys have but let's get started right on
this and we'll see what we can cover
today so a quick background of Who I am
I'm a full time student at Cal State
University Fullerton and I do bug
bounties for fun so bug bounties are
something that I do for research for
finding unique ways to get into
companies so even though there are web
security stuff that I usually find I
also tend to focus on getting into
internal access through different means
so you might have seen some of my weird
things that are fine and disclosed so
those are the things I focus on these
sweet is one of them since there's a lot
of things you can do on G suite and
there's a lot of ways to mess up on that
as well you can find me on Twitter as
uranium hacker I usually post a lot
about security things blogs that I find
interesting and everything else like
that I have my own blog sites the Google
allcom sestok you find COMSEC blocks so
you guys go to that have multiple links
to different things I find some of them
are specific vulnerabilities so it could
be like ID or and some company or some
of them are more generic that are
widespread and some of the things that
I'm covering today are already like some
of them are already on the block so you
guys can refer to the blog and use that
or your own use as well so let's kind of
get started into what it G sweet for
people that don't know what G sweet it's
it's basically Google's version of Gmail
Google Drive Google calendars pretty
much everything combined in a
software-as-a-service designed for
companies so for example when we use
gmail.com we have access to Gmail Google
Drive school calendars for that email
and Google decided let's bring that to
companies so now we have if you have a
buck route if you're a buck or employee
be up at baccara calm if buck are using
G suite you can use that to send emails
directly so you don't need to worry
about setting up email service through
other companies Google will handle that
for you so there's like you want email
you just ask that you want calendar this
will give you that you want shared drive
speed on companies you get
of those as well so it basically has
combinations of everything and then the
best part is you can use that to log in
to other places so if you have Google
cloud platform that's another thing you
can log into just basically a combined
product for all the Google features out
there and that's the best part of it
since everyone wants to use it but it
also leads to super easy verne abilities
because what happens is admins will sign
up reduce weight and start importing
employees but they will not realize that
there's gonna be security issues with
that there could be employees sharing
things that this will not be sharing
outside to everyone so the admins won't
realize there are settings that gee
suite has where you can click on a
button and prevent the whole leak that's
why it's really fun to look at G suite
because if you get something it can
usually be a critical issue for a
company if they disclose a lot of info
or you could use that info out there
that they have disclosed to chain it to
further attacks and I will go over those
when I'm in some them so let's first
start with the first one and that's
Google calendars and I have a small note
for everybody on that is I probably
similar be able to see your meetings you
know just saying that because everyone
tends to leave their meetings open so
for example the Khoisan behind this that
resulted on us looking at google
calendars is we were testing out a
couple of bucks in a platform and we
noticed there was Google counter being
used we were curious like what happens
if I put an employees email on my Google
Calendar since Google allows sharing
calendars and importing calendars so we
decided you know let's give it a shot
and I really like a company to hack
which was uber so we decided to try some
uber emails and see if it would work and
it did so that's where we knew that it
was gonna work perfectly and to go from
there so a couple of things that
motivated is calendars are pretty
sensitive you know when you create a
calendar when you create events you kind
of tend to add a lot of sensitive data
there for example if you're flying
somewhere your information or if your
flight will be there for companies it's
also more of meetings so we wanted to
see what kind of information we can get
and can we automate this process
so for example let's say we can find one
calendar for each company for each
employee instead of manually putting
this email every time we wanted to see
if we could automate so it was a
programming challenge as well for us to
figure this one out and also as I said
we wanted to see more info because
personally for me web security is a
really good topic but I also tend to so
do companies that your websites might be
secure but your employees are kind of
giving out details that this will not be
giving out and calendar was a perfect
way to show that so we started creating
test cases we started looking into
different things and I'll be going over
like a little bit technical aspect of
that in the next slide so when we're
looking into this we decided to first
check on Google calendar the calendar
the Google section where you can add
other people's calendar but it was
manual so you go there you put an email
and you're putting companies in email
there but there's you know it's manual
you have to try for every email
copy/paste and see how it works it's
kind of sucked so we found out that
Google also allows you to embed
calendars which is even better because
now I can just add emails and then see
the response because there are different
status codes for different things so 200
means the calendar is public or
something could be accessed for that and
if it gives 404 then the calendar is not
public or it does not exist knowing that
we could easily create a script because
now we don't have to worry about
anything we already know it's 200 right
so if it's hits like if you are giving
it 100 MLS
50 of them are 200 likely chances it's
public so it's it was pretty interesting
for us to look at that aspect and that's
like an example of this is when you look
at the embed
I have a picture here for my calendar
and when I go on it you can see it gives
out some informations since I'm a
student there's nothing much but try to
see it from a company point of view
right if I have a buck rowdy fab goober
some employee has this public calendar
out there there could be a lot of
sensitive data for example zoom meetings
which can be accessible by everyone
since by default zoom doesn't have a
password requirement so as a sysadmin on
Zoom you can set that but not every
company does it so it was just
easy to just jump into meetings and have
some kind of sensitive access with that
so for example we'll see Jim links join
any meetings you want you have internal
Google Docs I'll also explain why that
matters when we go over the Google Docs
section and why private Google Docs soon
remain private and also saved password
for internal sites so I guess we'll have
a story to tell about that and before
that let's look at this so here's an
example of a real meeting we joined when
we were testing and it was pretty
interesting you go to the employees
calendar you click on it and there you
go it had a zoom link and we knew
exactly what time it was so we dropped
into it right then and it was the
meeting was like barely starting so as
soon as we knew that will happen we
decided to leave right away since we
didn't want to stay on the meeting and
the best part of this is when you click
on it
since zoom allows you to rename your
names so for example in this talk I
already know had my club name I changed
it back to my personal name you could do
the same thing when you join this
meeting because at first it's based on
your login but since you already know
the employees name
you just plug that in and you have
access to it and you can like kind of
fist people just think you are a real
employee so now we decided to automate
it that's where a little bit of
technical part comes as of this morning
we have disclosed this exploit /script
that makes it easier to do all these
checks it uses hunters our IO which is a
email fetching website so hunter IO has
a public list of all emails out there it
makes it easier for you to see all the
employee emails and then go from there
and do any other test you have to so
what we did was we decided to use hunter
to fetch all the emails create a Python
script that would check all the emails
for the calendar link and see if it's
200 if it is it will save it to a txt
file and if you want you could even go
to the length which we did but it's not
on the script is you go take pictures of
all of these calendars so you know which
one's valid which one is not and it
reduces a lot of work in your side after
you have the script down but there is a
little bit of a con and pros pros and
con kind of thing for the script is
after we disclose the blog so we wrote
about the Google Calendar
quite a while ago and after we disclosed
it I think a lot of bug bounty hunters
decided to try it out so obviously it
was easy to script so a lot of people
decided to create scripts out and Google
probably noticed that so they have rate
limited calendar the Google don't come
now so you probably want to be careful
of how much requests you've sent because
you probably don't want to send like 500
requests a second or something since
you'll kind of get rate limited on that
there are probably bypasses to it the
script doesn't cover that yet I am
looking at some of the bypasses this
week so there have been couple we have
found to bypass the rate limit but we'll
see if we can embed that on the script
or not we'll have to discuss with Google
in regards to that so if you are
interested in doing this attack if
you're interested in Google Calendar a
quick TL DR is basically you run the
script it allows both a domain and a txt
file so let's see if you have a txt of
all emails for a company you can just
pass that into the script it will
analyze those or if you give it a domain
it will grab hunter and then you know
use hunter to grab those emails you just
have to make sure you have the hunter
API key so make sure you have that on
the hunter API the Python file and you
still be able to run it so let's see a
sample so here you have a sample where
I'm showing you the test desta txt file
with emails I run that with Cal dot pi
and then you can notice that it defines
all of those are awesome calendars that
you can access some of these will go
private today I made them public just
for this talk so I will make them
private after this talk but you are
definitely for you to try other emails
so if you know company emails if you are
on a pen test and you want to try it out
feel free to you know use those emails
put that in on the script and see if
it'll work and I have modified the
script on this video a little bit that
you guys are seeing because I wanted to
so the real output as it was happening
otherwise what the script will do is it
will output the content to the test txt
file now
we covered the exploit part you know as
a hacker it's real easy to exploit and
some bug bounty hunter is really easy to
find but the problem is knowing how to
fix them that's why when I was creating
this talk when I was discussing with
some of my friends we're thinking so we
covered the aspect of how to fix this
because obviously there's no point in us
disclosing a security issue or
disclosing things like this that can be
mass exploited and not have a fix for
companies so that's why we are each part
of this talk will have an aspect where
you can fix this if you are a G suite
adding it for a company so if you are
watching this talk and you work at a
company and you don't you haven't
received a report about gold calendars
and you don't know if your Vernal yet
just try this out and make sure your
company is secure so for example here we
have a simple g-suit admin panel what
you'll do is once you go to the panel
you can go and search for calendars so
when you look for calendar settings it
shows you the calendar service so how do
suite works is each app is known as a
service and you can turn it on and off
for everyone obviously you don't want to
turn it off for all your employees to
make yourself secure because at that
point no one can use it but what it can
instead do it change the external
sharing options now how this works is
let's say employee is super into making
their calendar public there are cases
where those are needed for example if
you work in HR if you work in some kind
of a marketing team and you want to late
your client customers know when you are
free and when you're busy so you
probably want to calendar public but as
a DC I mean you don't want to employee
disclosing meetings to other people so a
perfect way to do that is you'll change
your calendar settings and you'll say
hey you know just make it free slash
busy so what that will do is it was a so
on the public calendar when it's free
and when it's busy so it wouldn't
disclose anything else for example if
you were to go to worse or someone and
if you try putting one of the employees
email even if they have it public it'll
just say when they're free and busy we
doesn't give you any vital information
at all so that's why it's good as a
g-suit admin - you realize this usually
it's not by default turned on
so you probably want to go there and do
that if you do this it will force all
employees that as the maximum Sara
ability because sometimes the employees
can override some of the juice which
settings when they are doing manual
stairs but for this case it will be the
maximum they can do so they won't be
allowed to do any public disclose
information so they won't be able to
disclose meeting details or anything
like that and before I move to the other
part of this talk I just want to recap
to the Google Calendar Bart as I said
the script is out there now so you will
be able to use it the script is on bug
bounty - site github account I'll also
probably share my screen and then so the
link after this talk so that you guys
can follow up on the talk link or the
tsukuba slides will be made public I'll
probably put it on my Twitter so you
guys will have access to that as well
but as I said the script is online you
can just utilize it just make sure you
use it in a way that you don't get rate
limited otherwise you'll get a lot of
false positives out of it and see if you
can find some companies we did find it
on a lot of companies so for example on
the report we mentioned we found it on
uber saw FIFA and others our soft flight
report is actually already disclosed so
if you want to see more detail in it if
you want to go more technical or see
like what kind of impacts we try to
prove it that might be a really good
report to look at now let's look at
private docks
I did mention on the Google Calendar
that when you have access to a calendar
probably start looking for Google Docs
and see what you can do with it and the
reason is private dogs need to be remain
private right you don't want anyone
random in the internet to access it and
we have found a lot of companies miss
upon that as well so we're kind of
looking at how can a company's like how
often are employees sharing internal
links and giving it to other people
turns out it's a lot so you'll see this
this is fine picture on the side on all
of the slides today because pretty much
every company is messing up on this and
sadly it's not a fault of a jisu admin
since you probably want to allow ser
dogs but it's when employees share it
with anyone with the link in access and
think that it won't go on the public web
when they put it on like trailer
something so let's look at it from
attacker viewpoint before we start
looking at fixing it so one of the
common ways to do it and I have tweeted
about this other hackers have also
tweeted about it is finding internal
links through Google Docs so if you do a
google dork which is basically you are
giving it a certain parameters to
specifically look for you'll say in in
text find every links that have mention
google.com slash a slash company com
so for example if it's Buckra a little B
slash bar of calm and you'll probably
see you know you're probably pasted on
Google and then try to see what it does
right so when you do in text it will try
to mention everything and it's not just
a dark side wall comma do list you'll
also see groups Volcom you'll see other
cool links that this company is using
and sometimes it is pretty interesting
to test out on Google and see what kind
of links you'll find so for example if
you want to go and find for DoD you go
try that for the DoD since they have a
PDP and see if you can report that I
know for sure
uber also had some of those incidents in
the past we did find those issues and
report it to them but as I said the
problem is like you cannot enforce this
perfectly in Google so or in G suite so
you have just have to monitor these
things and we'll cover that on the
defense point of view some website that
are useful you can look at also if
you're not using Google Dirk is pasted
that same query in github since yeah if
there are github issues get up comets
they might mention that saying based on
this Google Doc for our company here see
how it works right and you can probably
try to find some internal links with
that
another one is Trello a hacker I forgot
his name now couple months ago found
that employees were sharing a lot of
sensitive data on Trello and one of them
definitely is Google Docs since they
will crea like internal cards internal
tasks and then put it on a trailer
instance and then they'll start sharing
Google Docs based on that task so even
though trailer won't have much sensitive
data for that task if you click on the
Google Doc you can see like meeting
details you can see product reviews we
have found for a specific company
cannot mention the name but basically
we're able to get their Google Doc that
had all upcoming products till 2020 so
basically accessing every upcoming
features out there and we already know
what this features will cover so you'll
usually find this kind of info and as I
said before it's not necessarily a
critical issue right away you can
probably even escalate it further we
have found internal links within Google
Docs so when you find a Google Doc that
you can access probably look for
different things you can find there and
you start querying
look at the Google Doc obviously don't
download it just look at it from the
online point of view and see if you can
find internal links we have found
internal links that no one could find
since that it was a random thing at the
end and random thing at the start but if
you click on it it was accessible to
everyone and you could login so there
are like you can go from a medium
severity just finding a cool dog to put
into a critical by logging into their
internal instance which probably has a
lot more sensitive info and another
quick example is PAP al wipe appellee
it's a own bookmark thing not a lot of
people use it but we have seen a lot of
companies have employees that are
personally using it and they will say
like some internal links the picture I'm
going to so next has a lot of
information but you won't be able to
access any of those Google Docs you'll
just be able to see the name so there's
no point in reporting so for example
this one is an example of us getting to
some of the links this were Google
slides for onboarding new employees and
also onboarding new features for March
2019 and then we also have for Ober
here's a employee that had mentioned all
of their trackers all of their documents
names and stuff but all these are
private since goober kind of forces
employees to not see them since they do
have monitors and audit logs and all of
those so that's why I say this picture
is there's not a lot of sensitive data
coming out of this but definitely for
example some of the internal links you
can use that to do more recon so
sometimes just finding these data are
not worth reporting I just want to
highlight there so that you guys like
anyone watching it
listen create a lot of noise for
companies but definitely use this to see
if you can find more
out of the Recon and then try more
attack vectors from it so how do you
actually fix this right because as I
said there's no point in disclosing this
and then telling the company good luck
so what do you actually do is in Google
you can create alerts and audits so when
you go to your homepage and click on the
menu bar it has an option for reporting
audits and alerts so on the audit
section you select will drive which
makes it easier and then you'll select
anything that has the visibility change
from internal to external so for example
here you'll see I have a couple of
documents one of them was anyone in it
with the link within the domain to
private for Sakura Inc so you can also
have only people within the domain to
access it if they have a link you can
also make it private for a specific
domain and they're also like none to can
edit so when you share files and if your
g-suit admin you can utilize this to see
if employees are externally sharing
files to other individuals and you can
even see the logs of who are accessing
it so it makes it easier if you get a
report if you are working in the g-suit
admin section for a company and you get
a hacker one or a buck or a report that
says I got access to all of your Doc's
that has VPN quest that has password all
of these sensitive info you can use this
to actually get the locks of that and
see if someone had exploited this in the
past or even the hacker reporting it's
not reporting you all things needed so
now before I'm moving to the other
section I do know there are some
questions that were asked on the chat so
I'm just going to quickly answer one of
them someone asked if we could share the
calendar script it is already public on
the background EDS site so I will show
the link at the end of the presentation
here so you'll have access to it even
after the slides but let's move on to
the next one Google Sites now this is
where the fun actually is if I were to
say it because we have found things on
Google Sites recently due to a new
change that Google added that not a lot
of people realize has happened yet so
internal informations are always fun
Vasili in Google Sites you find a lot of
crazy
I'll say a lot of internal infos
onboarding datas VPN creds we have found
internal login informations and olives
so the question is new Google Sites came
out so how can we exploit this what
happened was originally I was full of
comparison in a while is there was an
old Google site that allowed you to link
or see all the google sites a company
had and then Google decided to make a
new design with new features on it so if
you go to secure if you go to my blog
which is on secure firing comps at SEC
blocks it is using the new Google site
version that's when I was looking at it
and looks super interesting to see how
it works so this results can a new
exploit that not a lot of companies are
aware of so let's compare the old versus
new Google site right now
so the old one for example if you were
to go for uber you'll go to
sites.google.com slash a slash over comm
and what this will do is it will show
you my sites in uber and since you're
not an employee you don't have any sites
but if you click on browse sites it will
list you all public sites that it can
access so this was in the old version of
Google Sites and it was super easy right
you don't have to guess a company's
google site link you don't have to do
anything you just go click on browse if
it's public you see it and see if
there's sensitive data there for most of
the companies we cannot find a lot of
sensitive data on this cases because
those are user like public data there
they are sharing with customers in case
of uber it was with drivers and riders
so it'll be like coupons
it'll be upcoming events referral
programs and all that so those were not
sensitive but then Google decided to add
a new Google Sites feature so now all of
the Google sites link if you're using a
new Google site is sites Google com
slash over coms last the title of the
block so it is not something you can
easily list for all the come all for a
company or like all of the Google Sites
so you'll have to actually brute force
it but then at the same time one thing
googled it easier is on the old Google
Sites if you were to try to find these
by brute forcing it you have to make
sure you're logged in to your Google
account right so if you need a gmail or
anything you'll just need to be logged
in with at least one account in Google
and then you can view these things
so what Google did was it made it easier
to brute-force with the new one so you
can just have a W first link with a
destiny of files and then brute force it
for that company so here's an example
for secure Viacom that I utilized to
test all of these things is you'll pass
in the rough large directories which is
a simple online brute force directory
from SEC list and you'll look for all
the 200 content out there so 200 means
these sites are publicly accessible with
anyone you don't even have to be logged
in and you'll go to site so cool calm
Satsuki fine calm and then fuzz that and
you can seen the result we have minimum
of like four that were found so if you
want to test it I have some flags on
this Google Sites for my domain so you
if you test the script if you want to
run those you'll be able to find them
there there are some Google Docs or
Google Sites that have made just for
people to test it out and see if it
works for them so this one is really
nice to have and you're really easy to
test as well so just run AWS and you
have access to a lot of sensitive info
we did test it on a company I asked for
permission from the company when I was
doing this presentation and they
declined to be mentioned so I won't be
able to mention their name but it's a
it's a really useful thing to test out
on all the companies that you're part of
and one thing I recommend corporate
employees so if you're a bug bounty
manager working for companies to
actually try to add g-suit security to
your bug bounty measures there are a
couple of companies that do that so i'd
like to give a shout out to Netflix
series they recently added that on their
bug crowd briefing where they mentioned
that if you find a security issue under
G's would convict so not a security
issue on G suite but something specific
to Netflix they will pay bounties for
that so for example if you are able to
find their internal groups that equal
access they'll pay you bounties for
those as well so I'll request like if
companies can do it this is a really
good measure to tech because if you
realize like as I have sowed in the
pictures here there are a lot of
sensitive infos that these dogs could
have even though they won't give you a
full critical impact it is not that hard
that once you deep dive into this that
you can use info from these dogs and
link
to other places and actually get a
critical out of this so now how do you
actually fix this and this is kind of a
bad part for the new Google Sites is
there's no easy way to fix because what
Google did is the and integrated the new
Google Sites into Google Drive so what
that means is previously is Google site
was a site in itself so you could have
security measures implemented on G suite
but with the new one is actually a file
in your Google Drive so companies cannot
say that all G suite new Google Sites
have to be private because there's no
way to restrict that in a way what
you'll have to do is you have to
restrict permission sharing in Google
Drive itself and limit it through that
so that's kind of a bad thing for some
of the companies it's really hard to
prevent this and one thing else
recommend is using the previous idea I
sort of about Google Docs is auditing
these and monitoring changes on the file
permission chains and actually fixing it
based on that
so you could send emails to your
employees saying we just noticed that
you have disclosed this you know Google
site to the public what is going on why
are you doing this and the past places
that I have worked we did actually do
those to make sure employees when the
shared files we were alerted of that so
if you're on security team probably
start creating alerts to get monitored
for those and try to see if we can find
other companies doing it and report it
to them as well so I would like to do it
in conclusion real quick this was not
that long of a presentation because I
wanted to answer some poisonous people
probably have in the conclusion going
over Google Calendar real quick most
companies have public calendars X civil
for all so it's super easy to test and
what I'll recommend is once you find a
Google Calendar with the script or
something go to your personal calendar
and import it there since Google allows
that and what you can do from there is
you can actually search that calendar so
there are previous things that they had
public like their meetings their
upcoming meeting links you can search
them by string so once you have added a
you go search for like resume and see if
there are candidates like interview
candidates whose info you can get out of
it or if there are zoom links that you
can publicly access and then access to
their meetings from that so find zoom
links Google Docs internal
swerd I actually mentioned we had a
story for that so what happened is a
company we're testing we didn't find
this in a lot of companies but one
company specifically we decided to see
if they have a password so he put
password on it and we were like all
right let's see if we can get something
out of it and there was one link that
came out was just super interesting like
it had a Google Calendar with a username
and a password on it for an external
link that was being used so it was a
third party the company was using to
store some of their videos so there was
interview candidates and they'll store
the videos there and since it was shared
with other employees they wanted to make
sure everyone could log in so they
decided let's just put the password in
the calendar easier for everybody and
one of the employee had the calendar
public so when we logged in we could
access all the videos for interview
candidates for their better release for
their password also like if they're
hiring someone you can find those links
as well and the tool as I said it's
already public I think Ben already
posted the link as well there so you can
find it on github.com so that's a bug
bounty des cités last Cali XE I'll also
highlight the bug bounty that site is
expect to see more tools coming out of
that it's a resource project I'm working
with a couple of friends so we will be
posting a lot of new exploits for like
things like Google Calendar or any other
research that we do so there are a
couple of the experts in the pipeline
there right now that we probably will
discuss in a couple of months so be no
lookout for those as well for Google
dogs as I said most documents are shared
in a way that's accessible by anyone
with the link and the point is employees
try to think that if I sear this you
know if I create this in a way that only
people with Lincoln access it's secure
right because the link is hard to guess
but what is not realized and out in
those matters is someone could put that
on Trello or someone could put that
somewhere that got googled or cool so it
so for an attacker it's a perfect point
of view where you can just grab it and
then attack it from there so as I said
look for you can either look for dot
Google Chrome slash a slash dohman calm
or you could go for docs.google.com
slash a slash Dillman calm because dogs
will want to show you Google Docs if you
just do all calm
you'll see more of groups you will see
spread sits slides and all of those as
well so there are like more things you
can access with that I pretty
super-sensitive report it as I said if
not try to escalate it do not report
like if it comes to it yes it could be a
medium and you could report it but I'll
always recommend using the info there to
actually try to get a critical as I
mentioned before you can find internal
links so try going to those and see even
if you can't log in like if they're
credits for those links you could
probably try to log in with credits and
once you do you have a full critical
there most of the time because these
links will have sensitive info we have
had where we could log in get access to
all the user info for a company since it
was an internal admin panel so you
probably want to check those out and see
if you can escalate to the max do not
make the mistake we did is we will
sometimes report it right as soon as we
found it and it will get marked as a
medium then when we go back we're like
nevermind we can get it to a critical
here we go and we give them more info
afterwards but I feel like it's better
to actually escalate it at first before
you even report it because it's easier
for companies to actually read the
report see what the issue is and then
categorize it for their internal fix
because when you send a report at first
and if it's a medium at first like if
you have an escalated yet then might
categories at medium and then start
fixing it based on that
compared to you actually escalating into
critical at first and them actually
fixing it right away
another thing is Google Sites as I said
wfos is super easy there is other there
are other directory brute force so study
guides can use I just tend to use W but
since it's easier it's easy to install
and it has other stuff where you can
import it to Python scripts and actually
create automated tools out of those so
you can use a dictionary file I have
shown some of the links you can just
send a distant file and then send it to
Google silence and then brute force
links out of those so in my case is
secure Viacom just put other links on
there and you'll be able to find those
so that's pretty much from my side I'll
try to see if I can show you guys the
github link so as you can I just can see
this is a super easy to square use
script so we have the hunter API the py
file and this is where you have to
your script um if you want to make it
safer just use the environment variables
for Python and then you'll be able to
just export your API key as environment
on your terminal on your Linux bass
whatever you use and then directly use
the tool so how the tool works is you'll
just specify Python 3 it's a Python 3
applicable tool and then the domain and
output dot txt where it saves it if you
already have a list of emails just
passing the txt file and then the output
txt file and it will be able to scan it
for those sewing in how it works
it's a super simple logic it checks if
it's a txt file if it is it will go
through the txt check all of the links
that it can and if it does it will start
writing it to a file that's already
created so that's the output file that
you pass in if it's an email it will use
the hunter API functionality that's on
the get emails function and it will get
all the emails out there the one thing
that will probably be a disadvantage is
you can probably try stuff like you can
try this with Hunter API but the problem
is if you are not getting a growth link
or something like that it will not work
because you want to get all the emails
so that's probably gonna be a bad aspect
of it is you might not have all the
emails of a company's since hunter will
limit that and I kind of wanted to
mention what Ben also wrote is you can
use burp intruder for this for sure we
used burp intruder at first so it's a
easier way to use burp intruder if you
don't want to install tools just passing
all the emails that you have so with
hunter you can even export a CSV file so
you can directly import it on a burp
suite and then start running scans with
the intruder but as I said before make
sure to try to go not beyond the rate
limit because that'll probably hinder
your work so the rate limiting is pretty
fast
in Google Calendar now so you probably
want to make sure you are threading it
properly you are doing if you need to do
timeouts you're doing those properly as
well because if you look at this group
right now the script doesn't cover that
it just hits all of these requests with
the head call and then just see if it's
valid or not that's for the calendar yet
see I also wanted to mention for Google
Sites you can also use intruder for that
so you don't miss
wfsu can also pass all the directories
there and then just make a hit for that
specific domain so that's another good
way to approach this as well I think
that's all I wanted to cover for this
talk if there's any questions I have you
guys have I'm free to answer that I have
this talk booked till 11:00 I believe so
we are like half an hour early so feel
free to ask any questions I'll try to
start answering them
I think someone asked about AG suite
takeover so I'm not actually sure what
that means but I know in the past what
you could do is you could take over G
suite accounts in a way where there was
a security issue on G suit itself where
you could redirect a company's email to
another instance or a company's domain
to another instance so that is no longer
possible there are cases where I have
seen people try to report things like I
have I can claim X Dot company common G
suite and you won't be able to sign up
anymore but the thing is those are not a
security issue in a way because
companies can just reach out to Google
and let them know and get that account
closed and re-register if they need to
do it so if that's the D Street takeover
you're mentioning even though it's
possible it's not a security issue but
if you do find a way to redirect your
company's domain a email or anything
like that from G suite to other places
then you'll probably want to report that
to Google I'll just highlight something
let me see if I can load that real quick
regarding G sweety's I had that similar
incident if you guys before my username
used to be uranium hacker on hacker 1
but if you guys check the disclosure
reports that I had there was one with
uber where you called authorized issue
in G suite so what happened was I was
able to redirect ubereats calm to a
different domain or a different
subdomain up theirs and basically it
allowed for me to transfer it to other
places so the worst part for this is it
was a Google bug as well so I have to
report it to Google so in those cases
keep in mind of like what you're finding
the Google Sites Google counters and
Google Docs kind of miss convicts are
not something Google has to fix since
they already have a feature for it so
it's more for companies to fix it on
themselves and those you
rapport but if it's things like where
you can redirect a whole domain or where
you can snoop into emails with that so
Jesus would had a Verne ability where
you call if a company had an emic set to
google.com or whatever G search requires
and it was not registering this would
already you'll just go and sign up as
that domain and you'll be able to listen
to all the emails coming into it since
they didn't have valid that you actually
own the domain or not and those things
you actually want to report to Google
and not to the company's guts it's not
something they can prevent hopefully
that answers that question if anyone has
questions about other things about G
suite there are other things you can
find with this with miss convicts there
are still like kind of private and I'm
still looking into those more so I'll
probably add more of those in the slides
or anything else in the future and
probably tweet about them so they'll
really fall on the Twitter account and
I'll be able to share more details there
as well let me see I don't think there's
any more questions on the chat if there
is I'm happy to answer them yeah
everyone that's watching you guys can
throw in questions in the chat and like
Rohan said we can just fill in the next
20 minutes riffing on questions so it
looks like we just got one in actually
yes so it seems like someone's asking
about token api's with like if the
Google Doc has it or if a Google
Calendar has it ah
if you cannot verify it so some of the
token API is you can probably test it
out so if these are Dropbox slack
mailgun or anything try it out and then
see if it works but if it does not and
if you can't verify it I'll recommend
still reporting it to some extent so
like let them know on Hacker on a buck
route but do expect that it won't always
be a critical right away and you
want to be careful about like how you're
reporting it to you right so don try to
go as out of scope as possible
obviously if it's something really bad
then you probably want to report it
right away so if it's a token you Canada
use I'll say it will be a medium
severity depending on the company so not
always a guarantee that it will be a
critical that's like like a look at the
doc more see if you can find more info
of it
someone asked why a doc Sagwa comes to
us ASIS that is going to SSO so with the
Google Docs how it works is specifically
that link that is shared that's just a
link to load Google Docs so it's not
actually loading the documents directly
so those will depend on how they're G
suite login works for example if you
work on a company site you'll know that
you can have octa and Wan log in and
then make those log into Google accounts
so that's why it's probably going to
that Microsoft account is you have a the
company has an SSL where it says you
have to log in at Microsoft first and it
will actually let you log in to all the
apps we have and c-suite each one of
those apps so it will have a similar
release on sites that google coms that's
a slash Dillman calm and you probably
want to make sure that you don't
actually just rely on that and say hey
they have ISO so it won't variable
because I documents can still be public
so the end point anything you want to
look at is the document links directly
not just google.com slash a slash domain
calm yeah that's a great point the link
that for those watching on the stream
later the link that was shared in the
twitch chat was docs.google.com
slash a slash you know whatever domain
that is the company like so for example
would be bugcrowd calm like real han was
saying you can't just like go to that
and necessarily load up the docs because
it's going to go to a login flow and in
this case the user in the chat tried it
and it went to Microsoft or like Rohan
was saying it could go to octa or
something else so that's how that kind
of login flow works
see if we have any other questions and
chat hmm
do you work from your local machine or
you do you use a VPS set up and work
from that so we do have a VPS Center for
this instead of a local and the reason
is as I mentioned there will be rate
limits so we didn't want our IP to get
banned specifically about Google
calendars and stuff since if we get the
IP banned we're pretty much banned out
of Google so it kind of feels suck
that's one reason why we do use a VPS
set up
you won't need a really crazy VPS set up
you can get us simple like Ally node
instance for things like five dollars a
month and you'll be able to use that to
run the basic scripts these facility
things like the Kali XE or w fuss those
won't take a lot of memory space or take
a lot of like God uses from your VPS so
you won't have to worry about running
out of bandwidth or running out of
memories on those
for wfos usually not there are people
who have specific files they create
themselves so I'll say once you start
noticing a pattern for sure do that and
create their own directories or addition
Ares out of it
for a start I just tend to use raft -
Lars - directory start txt from SEC list
since it has most of the files or the
distance that I need and I just tend to
run that and if I see a pattern then
I'll try to create it based on those so
for example just throwing it out like if
a company has all their Google Sites
title named after a food name or
something right then you probably just
want to have a dysentery file or a txt
file with bunch of food names and try
those and then see if it'll work because
if it does then you'll just be fine like
you won't have to create other noise
you'll get a higher rate of success so
most of your links will come out being
valid instead of just sending circulars
link and then getting a lot of invalid
links out of it so it just depends on if
you see a pattern created on dition
areas otherwise any distance okay fine
you
thank you yeah it has it has been a
really fun thing like the reason I
wanted to give a talk is when he worked
on a specific company in buck rod I was
like this could get pretty bad for all
other companies as well so might as well
let all the hackers know it's useful and
at the same time cover it for a
corporate part so as I have mentioned
like if you work in a company and you
have Jesus we probably start looking
into how to secure it since that is the
biggest I'll say one of the biggest
attack vectors at this point because
there's a lot of things that people
could access with it awesome well if
folks have in the twitch chat have any
more questions feel free to throw them
in and while we've got it got them here
on the stream otherwise we can fill in
the next you know 10 15 minutes and
other ways to and you can also always
like message me on Twitter I think my DM
is always open so you can feel free to
hit me up on uranium hacker on Twitter
and I can answer questions there as well
use a light trend to respond pretty fast
it's just if you don't hear a response
for me it's probably because the message
went to Twitter spam filter that they
tend to have so it probably will take me
some time at that point
all right then um I guess we'll we'll
move on thank you so much everyone
please throw whatever emoji you want to
use in chat throw it in there Oh
actually we're already getting we just
got some more questions and so maybe we
can keep it going here cuz it looks like
we just got two right there the first
one was um well actually let's go for
the the second one that came in and then
we'll go to the first one so the wolf
Droid asked when finding bugs in github
like information regarding people a
company let's see
trying to decipher what their question
is how to be sure when you're finding
that information yeah I think the
question is more of like if you get this
if you get a token in github or if you
find something about an employee like
through an employee of a company I'd get
up like how do you realize it's a bug
and it's not something yeah they're
personally using in those cases it's
probably best for me like personally
what I do is I don't there are personal
get up accounts with the employees I can
to look but we are I also tend to find
specific employees github accounts that
are registered with the company so I
think I tweeted this in the past is if
you look up company - and then asterisk
and look for all the users those usually
are getup accounts for employees working
at that company and what I tend to do is
from there I decide to do similar things
that all the other hackers do is
download the github repos and then use
get robbed or other tools to find for
info informations on the repo files and
usually if you find it open there try to
validate it so you might want to see
like if the information is actually
accurate even if it's all like some of
those tokens could have been committed
like two years ago but they could still
be valid so one classic examples France
has done this mentioned it has mentioned
this in the past is to slack API tokens
someone will put it out on get up
they'll delete it but they'll forget to
rotate it so you'll just be able to use
that token to actually read messages and
read other informations out there so if
you do get a token and you want to test
it up but you don't know how to do it
there's a really good rep oh by streak
G hacks that has bunch of links that you
can utilize for a specific third party
so if you have a slack token just plug
it in there see what permissions you
have obviously if you get it as invalid
permission or something that means the
token was removed so at that point
unless there's anything else on the
document or on the repo I don't think
it'll be worth reporting it but if you
have other tokens that are actually
valid see what else you can get out of
it and thus in regards to that I kind of
want to give out a upcoming feature
really it's kind of thing is in about
three months I'm realizing a feature
close to key hacks it is going to be
automated script where you can just plug
in tokens and it will do a full exploit
for it so if you were to give it a slack
token and if you choose aggressive mode
it will dump you all the messages for
each channel that the token can access
so we're trying to utilize key hacks for
that so you will see the script come out
within three months I'll say at the end
of December yeah random Ravi has a
really good up yeah I think he also has
red X for things you can look for
directly and get our bure pose which I
have utilized in the past I don't know
if it's random Robbie or someone else
would disclose that
you
just got a good question from paper-bag
Prince asked or you know that first they
made a conservation that it seems like
chaining bugs together is what gets you
the big bug bounties are this thick
bounties so are there any bug chains
that you find yourself chaining together
over and over and your bug bounty
hunting
there are while so there's multiple
chains you can do so like if it's web
security there's XSS two CSRF to account
takeovers and all of those attacks you
can do one thing that has happened to me
a lot recently and I even wrote about
this is following up on ticket trick
that inti looked at is when inti
disclosed about the blog or the exploit
you could just go to company's domain
and then you go to the ticket trick and
you could get into their slack and other
stuff but slack decided to secure that
so there was no like ways to exploit it
and when I started looking to deeper
ticket trick will still work on a lot of
companies but I wanted to see how I
could chain that to other places and we
use Google logins so we verified the
email on Google and then log into every
internal places we could from that and
got access to a lot of sensitive info
that has worked for me a lot in life
hacking events and other events and it
still works so it doesn't necessarily it
hasn't necessarily been fixed by any
companies I will say there are still
ways to attack it it's just to chain
them you have to know what your next
chain will be once you start looking at
it further like once you start looking
at ticket trick and then start testing
how it works I think you will have an
idea of like how to chain them so that's
one of the biggest attack vectors that
have seen myself doing a lot of chaining
over and over right now because there's
a lot of different ways you could if
like one door closes there's another
door always open and ticket trick to
actually get into internal panels with
those there was a question about what is
the most critical thing you found
through the msconfig in G suite so there
were a couple of them one of them in
terms of Google Calendar one of the most
critical was getting that credentials
that allowed us all the videos for
internal interviews
we also had for Google Docs we had
downloaded product or we have got access
to all as I said upcoming product
features until 2021 or 2024 companies so
not a critical but like a high
information disclosure for them we also
had for a company we were able to
download their unreleased tools and
unreleased features so this is a company
that builds softwares and other things
and we could actually download their
upcoming features that's not even known
to the public yet and the kind of a good
part on that is when we escalated it
further the internal software's that we
had actually allowed to find internal
domains and they had like test usernames
and passwords for those so we could log
into those as well so those have been on
other critical findings we had someone
asked what are public sources to find
sensitive so there's a lot of sources
out there that have sensitive data
Trello is one of the biggest ones right
now we have we have found a lot of those
I keep forgetting the hackers name but
he found a lot of those and he has
discloses in the past I think upon one
on the United Nations and other
companies as well basement is a pretty
useful one it's not as useful now I
think is if you find it is probably some
other hacker testing and putting
information there as notes but we have
found stuff on like the happily the
bookmark which that I mentioned there
are also slideshare.net where companies
tend to put their internal slides there
and not realize it's public so you can
not always like a security issue but you
can find internal info that you can use
so let's say a classic example is let's
say if you find it necessary app and you
don't know internal domains to hit you
can probably find slides that mints and
internal domains into strago's get but
github is a perfect one asana is even
better I really like asana I'm not gonna
like we have found a lot of this stuff
with that JIRA's are good you
specifically look at the cloud or class
Ian instances for companies and see if
they allow public sign up if it's like
let's say bakra docked on CNN and if you
can't go there and so see all the
tickets there it's already bad so you
probably want to check those out as well
obviously internal jiriz are even useful
because those tend to have more security
issues I think that the cloud version of
it
um bitbucket is another good github is
always useful there's always a lot of
things can get up to cover
there's also another slide sharing
website called Prezi which allows you to
do animated slides and we have found
internal documentation some new features
internal even tickets info for support
tickets so employees will be doing a
Google Docs or like you'll be doing
presentation on internal support issues
they got and those will be made public
so that's really good for escalating it
I don't know what do you mean by GSI
issues and what do you mean by open sup
fiha API so I'm not actually sure wolf
droid what do you what do you want me to
spell out I can probably type it in the
message easily easier which will
probably easier for everyone in that
case there's also another one that was
asked to me is can you talk about some
crazy bug that you recently found so
this one is a really good thing I was
doing some kind of recon on a company
and there was a domain that allows
signing up as referrals slash partners
kind of thing so one signed up you call
actually like it will take time to get
verified so they all verify your account
and they'll add it to internal referral
instance but the interesting part of
that is their internal instance had no
access controls so instead of just being
a partner I could be an admin and it
actually allowed me to get list of all
their customers monitor their customers
in real life so whatever like for
example if the customer was paying 100k
for their services I could see when they
had paid that when the next due date is
what they're billing details is and all
of those sensitive info so it's always
those recon things that you don't think
it'll work and it ends up working that
are pretty critical I've also had not
recently but in not in bug bounties when
I was working there was a company's
website that allowed you to create
badges so I could discreet there was a
API requests to create badge for the
building and you'll just send a request
put your name and your picture and it
will create a batch for you with RFID on
there and you could just go to the
office scan it and you could get access
to the building so there have been like
pretty fun things that you can know that
I've found with different recon
strategies on them I think that answered
pretty much all
yeah he was asking about Prezi I think
it was which is PR easy I I believe yeah
yeah that's what wolf joyed was asking
to spell earlier okay yeah that's that's
a really good words that I have used in
the past for a finding infos for
companies well thank you so much
everyone in the chat again give them a
round of applause Rohan where can people
find you on Twitter and everywhere else
if you want to put that information up
on the screen
yeah if you want to find me on Twitter
it's pretty much the Iranian hacker
super easy to spell you can just message
me there I'm also on bug Monday forum I
don't go by my uranium hacker handle
there so you can just find me as laundry
a LAN bug round a forum and you can also
message me on any other places you find
except for LinkedIn don't message me on
LinkedIn I don't use it a lot so
probably I think Twitter will be a
perfect approach if you ever want to
mess any sense my tutor is always open
to DMS awesome
thanks man I hope you thank you awesome
rest of your day thank you for your time
thank you yeah