all right I first talk is from buses can
fly thank you so much man for kicking us
off on the Saturday morning I really
appreciate it
this first talk is a hardware hacking
for the masses and you buy buses can fly
so take it away man hey thanks everyone
for coming really excited to give this
talk yeah my talk is hardware hacking
for the masses and you first boring
disclaimer you know all the general
stuff not a lawyer
don't crime be responsible have fun
don't be dumb cite your sources so I am
buses can fly you can find me on twitter
at at buses can fly and really around
the internet with that handle I'm just a
new exploring when I find for fun it's
it's a hobby for me I love embedded and
automotive hacking car hacking all sorts
of hardware I'm a student I love rock
climbing quadcopter flying and just
generally messing around with
electronics so first off a little
overview of hardware hacking you know
what is it and that kind of raises the
question of what's regular hacking it's
making stuff what it's not supposed to
do finding out secrets it's there's no
exact definition it can be there's some
overlying topics between hardware
hacking and general hacking but overall
it's all just trying to do whatever you
want to do it's you can touch it
make you do stuff it's not supposed to
do and it's fun your hardware hacking so
some really common questions I get is
isn't hardware hacking hard which no yes
it depends depending on the level you're
looking at what you want to do there's
there's something for everyone but can
you hack hardware absolutely what do you
need to get started well that's what
this presentations for and then isn't
hardware hacking expensive it depends
there's some extremely expensive tools
out there there's a lot you can get for
really cheap or for basically free
actually the way I got started with
hardware hacking was out of a dumpster I
was
at a local conference and they had a
Destruction village for the kids and
there were a bunch of old routers in
there so I took two out that were the
same model column together into one
bought a $3 serial cable and that's that
was my first time hardware hacking
there's this big misconception I hear a
lot at conferences there's brilliant
people doing web stuff and crazy cool
you know exploit development but they go
like hardware no man that's who that's
the scary stuff that's hard stuff and I
disagree with that I think just like
anything else it can be you can
definitely get started in it for not not
too much money and not too much
difficulty so how do you learn the way I
started was doing a lot of electronics
projects I love little single board
computers or answer a pies banana pies
orange fries though the whole single
board Linux computers are great and they
have these GPIO pins similar to the
Arduinos which are also on this slide
and then general electronics projects I
think they're super helpful
actually it's see over here actually is
one of the first electronic projects
I've ever did which is kind of a very
simple one it's a 555 timer which is a
type of integrated circuit and with that
you can do a lot of stuff you can make a
little circuit to change how fast it
pulses something out but there's this
great project on magazine where you can
make your own rapid-fire Mouse using
this timer and entirely just hardware
you can make it you know rapid-fire for
whatever you want to do video games or
whatnot but you know be responsible but
there's a lot of really good resources
between projects there's a lot of good
books and at the end of the slide I
dumped a lot of resources links to
things things to watch things to read
the whole list up there web greece's as
always Google is your best friend
there's a few good great YouTube
channels right here and some more at the
end and then forums that I'll add more
also at the end of the slides but
there's a ton of really accessible and
easy to understand resources but I
highly recommend just going out googling
stuff finding a project that looks
really cool to you and just doing it
don't worry if about if it seems too
hard or if it seems like you don't
understand it just have at it and
eventually you'll get it and you'll
learn a ton on the way and just do a lot
of random
so some really quick things to know in
basics that are pretty important the
first idea is baud rate so that's the
formal definition you can see up there
but basically just you know you how fast
you can transfer information this is a
graph over here here's a graph of that
just you know ones and zeros a lot of
hardware you have a thing called a clock
speed which I'll talk more about some
hardware terms later but it's how fast
and how often these bits are transferred
on a network which as you can see it
gets pretty simple but there's a few
common baud rates we'll talk about it
later about how to interface with a lot
of hardware simply but a few thing you
need to know is that communication speed
because if you're hooking up to some
piece of hardware and you're trying to
talk at a different speed that it then
it's listening or you're listening at a
different speed is talking to you only
give you a gibberish out so there's a
few really common baud rates as you can
see right here but the really main ones
are 9600 and this 115 200 that's the
number of bits per second and the most
common there's a Python tool I linked
somewhere in this presentation also at
the end of the slides that's really
great you just run it and it tries all
the different baud rates and you can see
where the sensible information comes out
so you can figure that out but generally
whenever I'm doing something I just try
this and then this one so yeah that's
important to know just the speed of
communication what's going on then some
really common electronics terms I'm sure
most of you if not all of you are
familiar with really basic circuit stuff
which is basically there's a positive
and there's a negative and each circuit
has to complete in a circle
obviously PCBs printed circuit boards
and a lot of hardware it's a lot more
complicated than just a loop well all
the terms are still the same you have
VCC which basically is just you know
voltage there is voltage ground is the
negative connection you have R X which
means receive and T X which is
transmitted and this will come later so
you are as a communication protocol you
usually have your power and your ground
somewhere on the AC IC and then you have
a transmit connect to some the other
things
receive and one things transmitted
connected Taylor when receive so these
do can talk back and forth to each other
but we'll get more into you are not
there stuff later on yeah and then how
to find information about hardware this
is really underrated with everything
recon is a huge thing beforehand and you
can figure out basically everything you
need to know without actually touching
the hardware so there's a ton of
information online data sheets are a
goldmine data sheets and schematics can
contain that you would ever need it's a
ton of information but it's all super
useful so information about the ICS and
the board of processors normally I don't
know it's the best picture you see down
here there's usually words on these
chips and a lot of other stuff if you
just type that right into Google you
don't you don't even need to know what
it means just look it up like Texas
Instruments something or nxp or whatever
just Google at-at meg chips you'll find
like 20 page PDFs with data sheets and
they'll tell you whatever you need or if
you don't understand everything whatever
you can find there is gonna be super
useful then a hugely underrated resource
is FCC documents online so any device I
believe sold in the US has to have that
that communicates over some sort of
radio frequency has to have an FCC ID I
put some example stickers here I just
found online like right here there's an
FCC ID here that's the MAC address
there's someone whatever it's somewhere
on this one but like right here and
right here examples of FCC IDs there's
usually it has to be a specific sticker
for this and that number there's a way
to do that so you see his official
website but this as you see that i/o
site is amazing
it'll forward everything you'll get the
documents there it's great and these
documents generally contain a lot of
information about what it's doing so
which frequencies it's communicating on
sometimes you get well usually you get
internal pictures of the hardware which
is amazing
we'll talk later in this presentation
about finding debug pins and what to
look for in the circuit boards but a lot
of the time before ever getting piece of
hardware I go to these FCC documents
look at internal pictures you can try
identify stuff just from the pictures
they provide
and different specifications about the
hardware and this can vary sometimes the
company can request to to suppress some
information and file that but usually it
still doesn't cover internal pictures
and you still know what frequency
everything's operating on and even if
you don't know the frequency there's a
lot of ways you could figure that out
and we'll talk more about that later too
and another way to get information
obviously is the firmware sometimes
that's just online you can just go to
the manufacturers website performing the
hardware download the firmware and
reverse-engineer it from there
if not you can dump it off the hardware
itself but we'll talk about that also a
little later so then getting into the
hardware what do you look for you know
so now you've got you know this router
you've cracked it open you know what's
inside so the main thing we look for is
what we call debug informations so like
when you write program you need debug
information you just extra information
to help facilitate whatever you're
making
so the code has to be loaded on devices
somehow right and the devs need a way to
see extra information or interact with
their devices so there's a lot there's
these different standards for little
things on the circuit board for how you
can hook it up and how you can hook up
to those debug in from ports and get
extra information out of them and
sometimes if you're lucky you just plug
in a cable basically to these pins and
it drops you straight to a root shell
it's unfortunately common there's not a
ton to it sometimes it'll end into a
busy box shell some sort of limited
shell something custom and then one time
I was looking at this one piece of
industrial equipment and no joke it
dropped me for into ARM arm
arch linux forearm which I didn't know
is a thing beforehand and probably
shouldn't be the thing that this
industrial equipments running but you
know anything's possible route chills
are common sometimes you just get
information as it's booting which can be
super useful you can pull off from that
and there's ways to kind of get it to
then give you a shell or mess with that
to put it get into that and I won't talk
about that a ton here but it's
definitely something to look into
but how do we get this information
there's a couple as I mentioned earlier
protocols and standards for how to
okay with hardware these things like you
are in JTAG which I have slides that
later which are just pins or things like
test pads on a board that you can talk
to there's these communication protocols
like SPI I to see your I square see
however you want to say it just worth it
Google you'll see that a lot in our do
we know projects you do that this is the
SPI interface model then you have some
more common interfaces like if you're
looking at a router USB an ethernet
really common but very underrated
there's a lot you can talk to it up
sometime because there's a bit going
there that's always useful and then oh
yeah you're gonna use the link toast
document with a Python tool to identify
baud rate there's four tools I put right
there
I don't know screen mini-com mini term
puddi whatever you want they all can do
serial connections there's a bajillion
more I don't know if it works for you it
works yeah use whatever you need and
then I have some pictures here but we'll
talk about this later these are the
tools you can use to interface with a
lot of hardware and yeah I'll get deeper
into it so you are this is a huge one
this is basically if you understand this
like 60% of those low-lying this is the
low-lying fruit and a lot of hardware
talking and a lot of hardware hacking so
you are it stands for a universal
asynchronous receiver transmitter that's
a mouthful but Universal makes sense
asynchronous also kind of makes sense
and then receive transmit that makes
sense we were looking at a model of this
earlier so you are is generally four
different pins here's a picture of a
UART breakout there's also one here
where the company helpfully pre soldered
the pins on but it's generally four pins
and the thing is you really only need to
hook up to 3 because VCC is the fourth
one so there would be a VCC up here and
we talked about that earlier voltage the
thing is normally let's say the router
example again you're powering the router
and you want to hook up to UART the
router already has power so then when
you hook up the VCC pin on your uark
cable stuff isn't super happy and even
though this is like a super basic thing
to know this is how I blew up one of the
USB ports in my laptop it's a huge new
mistake
so many pieces of hardware like that
generally just hook up our XTX in ground
and this cable I have a slide later
showing that but red is generally VCC
black is ground and you have our X TX
which are green and white just don't
don't hook up the red one right is for
danger and snip it off or something
probably won't need it oh yeah how do
you identify you our breakouts on
hardware but general you can just do
trial and error but there's kind of
small tricks and standards that you
develop over time ground the ground pin
is usually square like you can see right
here it's a special square but also
ground is shared across the hardware so
basically every component needs a link
to ground because that's how circuits
work in that loop so you can find
anything that is ground which you know
there's a like RF shields on hardware
which is like this looks like a little
metal box covering whatever is
broadcasting RF that's usually grounded
I mean every piece one side is gonna be
grounded yeah but it's shared across the
board if you don't have a specific pin
or you want to like hack your way into
UART the VC C the voltage trace is
usually a little thicker that's just its
standard just because that's to carry
the power but again you don't really
need to hook up to it so if you can
figure out ground which is pretty easy
because it's either a square labeled or
you know something like that
Rx and TX are can I just you know 5050
like if this was voltage we're not gonna
hook that up this is ground and then
these two are Rx and TX I choose one
just like put one in each
and if gibberish comes out flip them
just do the other combination because if
you flip these it'll just look weird and
then you just flip them and then it
works but tools for identifying this you
can use the civil scopes and logic
analyzers they're super nice an
oscilloscope is a tool that displays
kind of voltages over time so you can
visualize what's happening in a certain
place and logic analyzers do similar
things but basically it's just a magic
device you can hook it up to these pins
and see what kind of voltage is going on
so if you see a solid line at the top
and it says like five volts it's
probably BCC and then Rx and TX might do
you might have these little like crazy
waves or something depending on what the
broadcast yeah that's you are this is
the thing to go for and a lot of things
if you see four pins in the line on a
piece of hardware
either that or in these kind of headers
or holes probably you are probably can
drop you straight to a shell or it will
get you at least more information great
to go for and then okay that was weird
slightly out of time but whatever so
here's some you are at examples I took
this picture a day ago I was just
prepping something for slides but this
router and I have some pictures later
well we can look at identifying these
things but you can see here ground Rx
and TX all right and it just hook up to
a router hooked up to a serial adapter
and then going to my computer so this
can drop you to different stuff these
are online but I found like tp-link has
their weird specific shell for some of
their routers and you can try escaping
out of this limited shell and to busybox
chela for permissions and then doing
whatever use the screenshot of that baud
rate tool where it hooked up using this
padre and you get a bunch of information
and stuff boots this is a you arc cable
missus like adafruit's fancy one but I
was just looking I wanted a picture with
the different pins and these are the
colorings for the pins oh that is not
green okay well this is green and this
is blue don't worry about it but our XTX
ground and VCC don't hook up the red one
if the device is powered or else stuff
goes boom and the question is you know
what now if it lands you to a root shell
you know it's kind of to you this is
where maybe hopefully a previous
experience kicks in you know what you're
looking for like a Linux environment you
can look for private keys or different
stuff you know changing firewall rules
on routers is always fun and then kind
of a you know a community standard and
my personal favorite thing to do is just
load doom on things I've played doom on
tons of automobiles on a 50 kilowatt
hour car charger and so many things just
aren't supposed to run do them and are
so much fun when you play duel on them
but these are some things you can expect
when you hook up over serial another
interface is JTAG which was made and put
into effect by the joint test action
group it's this is a weird one for sure
so the
pin count can vary and you can see
there's some different standards for
that but they have basically the same
core pins yeah Pinkham can vary court
battle amount stays the same it can be
and then clonal quote secured with a key
or password which is common do you uh
have the manufacturer put some kind of
key in but if the key is common across
all of their devices the same key and
one person dumps it and then shares it
to everyone else then you can you know
bypass that je tags kind of hit or miss
when you're playing with hardware if the
manufacturer labels it they're being
amazing or if they tell you know which
one a corner and they follow this
standard well there's tools like the
jtagulator and makes it alot easier to
identify what pins are doing one how you
can hook up to that and after that the
information you get is pretty similar to
what you get out of you art oh yeah so I
took some pictures a little bit ago of
some routers I just crack them open took
a picture of the inside I thought it'd
be fun to just kind of look over it so
right now
you if you're watching this take a look
you know what do you see that's
interesting so I don't know right off
the bat there's a lot here so this is an
example of the RF shield I was talking
about this little metal box which
helpfully is grounded which is nice and
usually these huge pads would be
grounded too but this is inside here is
something that broadcasts RF this
heatsink means there's probably
something that put the heat out under
that so some sort of CPU Broadcom chip
for RF this is a bunch of Ethernet ports
and MAC addresses like USB ports this is
power in reset button and antenna body
capacitors some chips I would definitely
look up these IDs the FCC ID is on the
bottom of this but the really neat thing
you can see right off the bat is over
here looks like we have a Jacob breakout
JTAG breakout something else I'm sure of
yet but if you look right there they
were helpful enough to solder on the
headers for us at the manufacturer and
look they even labeled them VCC rx T X
and ground that's great so when you hook
up the cable to this dumps you actually
this one to a busybox shell
it's pretty nice and then another
example this one
did not blow up super well so I'm sorry
it's really blurry but you can see right
there JTAG and you can really not see
right here but there's another four pin
you are and what's interesting is you
know unsoldered connectors here that
could be pretty fun to see what's there
another example yep this one blew up
kind of better but it's still pretty
grainy so sorry but you look here still
a lot going on not sure what these are
worth taking a look if you look online
more chip names saddest LEDs you know
voltage regulator and then right there
looks we have JTAG and UART with pre
soldered headers love it when they do
that another example same stuff JTAG
something else more thing you look at
but yeah over time when you start to
look at these things you just start to
see them a lot quicker and it's just
worth picking that up and it gets weird
there's lots of different standards and
techniques that the manufacturers of the
hardware use there's different formats
like this kind of JTAG breakout this one
is helpfully labeled but it changes
there's these things this is kind of a
crazy example I found online but these
little like gold circles that are a
little wider
those are test points for testing
hardware they're not always super
interesting you can use something like a
logic analyzer to map them out you might
be able to like make you on you are
interface out of like that one that one
that one I don't know so I'm an extreme
level and my people fund mapping those
out but you learn a lot of this through
experience you know the more things you
watch the more resources you look at
there's just a lot to know and it's hard
to figure that out to find that out all
at once so this is an example of a PCB
with vias which are these little dots
here the ones with the hole in the
middle they just connect different
layers of the PCB because circuit boards
if you didn't know very commonly have
multiple layers just you know to fit
more stuff on them and communicate and
some of the layers communicate this way
this makes it sometimes hard because you
can see these traces on the PCB actually
let's go to a previous picture you can
kind of see here these little lines and
circuit board connecting parts that's
exactly what they're doing so you can
actually trace these lines a lot and we
were looking at the you are interfaces
let's see if I have a better picture
yeah here you can look at the UART
interface these lines coming off of the
pins or what the pins are connected to
their like instead of a wire on a
breadboard or something these are on the
circuit board and manufactured in with
the a in the silicon so you can usually
trace these out when I say the VCC trace
is a little thicker that's like this
line it's generally it's a little
thicker so let's go back and be is can
connect those layers and traces so
sometimes the vias make it hard to
follow but you can usually just kind of
with your finger look at that and if the
via ends up on the other end you can
follow that trace there but just you
know skills to gain over time and then
there's a lot of different hardware
hacking like anything else you know web
or just hacking in general it's not one
thing there's so many different kind of
sub subcategories I'm a huge fan of
automotive and car hacking I think it's
a ton of fun and these two pictures over
here are kind of like very core to car
hacking this is the obd2 connector which
is the thing under the dash your car
that gets plugged into when you go to
emissions testing there's a couple
really important pins but you know 614
and 311 are the ones you look at a lot
and this is an example of a cam frame
which is how that how the can network
works in a car but to find out more
about that I link to another
presentation at the end by a good friend
of mine inspectors he did a LevelUp talk
and level up 0x0 for about getting
started with car hack so check that out
if you're interesting IOT devices are
you know huge for hardware hacking
whether it's I don't know doorbells and
locks to smart TVs and routers there's
just so much going on and honestly a lot
of them are terrible as we've learned
from things like Murai and all that
security isn't really something people
pay for so there's a lot of devices just
hook up a serial cable and it just drops
you to root shell and then from there
you can do you know more recon find bugs
once you have a root shell or the
firmware you can do a lot of stuff to
try and get more info like if you dump
the firmware off a device you can use a
tool called bin walk
car files out of n you can sometimes get
the whole file system whatever you can
look for that look for vulnerable things
and get a lot of information that way
there's a lot of ICS SCADA stuff and
hardware and this is the scary field
this is a industrial control systems and
I freak at this kid AK acronym honestly
but whatever industrial control stuff
this is like the super important nuclear
power plant
powering electronics and they're not
always the most stable like if they have
some sort of a network connection a lot
of them crash when you end map them and
stuff like that which is kind of scary
but it's a cool place to be
Planes Trains pet Predator drones
they're all hackable and they're all
hardware so I know planes and trains
communicate over can in the same way a
lot of cars do and a lot of things do
Predator drones I'm not sure but I'd
love to find out if anyone has a
predator drone and would let me mess
with it hit me up who car chargers
that's a ton of fun car chargers
actually implement sometimes the same
can communication technology and usually
that they're just running you know busy
box or something in the background
there's one I was playing with that just
ran excellent oh that was fun voting
machines check out the voting machine
village at DEFCON but you know don't
destabilize governments or anything but
this is a picture I believe from the DEF
CON voting machine voting the voting
machine village a lot of voting machines
are actually like pretty terrible but
we're not gonna get into that follow
stuff online for that I don't like at
hacker fantastic I think it did some
stuff with that and then you know
regular phones years and years ago phone
phreaking was the big hardware hacking
it still is it's pretty awesome but just
regular phones now have a lot going on
to think just recently with the
checkmate exploit for the iPhone boot
ROM stuff someone also published a JTAG
debugger a physical hardware thing for
iPhone so that's one too um and then
tools this is my favorite part
hardware hacking is a ton of fun I don't
know I love tools and my little kits and
a lot of these can get kind of expensive
but a lot of them are pretty cheap like
we were talking about serial break outs
getting a you are cable for like three
dollars that can break fine it's worth
it
I've had the same you are cable for like
a year and a half now and it's gotten me
so many different shells it's wonderful
just three bucks pull a thing out of a
dumpster and you're on your way there's
a lot of other you know more expensive
tools sometimes very very specific use
cases and sometimes not the black magic
probe is a great JTAG adapter jtagulator
and the SheiKra are pretty nice multi
tools for communication this is a
cannibal which is hooking for one of the
things you can use to hook up to these
Oh buddy two ports but there's a lot of
different tools like that chick
whisperer you can do advanced like
glitching and power side channel attacks
it's pretty sweet the great FET it's a
general purpose tool it's amazing logic
analyzers super useful we talked about
it earlier jtagulator is a huge
wonderful tool for JTAG stuff and then
you know some random stuff I shout out
to the exploit tears and yeah I have at
the end of this presentation a bunch of
little information dumps lots of links
for you to follow talks to watch things
that have helped me a lot in the past
wow these are great use of resources
there's just so much with hardware
hacking I can't really outline it all
even in like a 30 minute talk or a 40
minute talk there's it's like it's a
really wide world
I really recommend just googling stuff
and just going at it just information
overload watch all the DEF CON hardware
talking a hacking talks just you know go
crazy do a bunch of projects I put more
links into here but you just add
anything else you pick this up over time
with little chunks see you and then yeah
here's some shoutouts my mayor amazing
friends family and teachers didn't my
outline a ton of people here but you
know who you are you guys if I know
you're super helpful and I appreciate
you guys being around shout out to the
thug who was actually I believe in chat
mostly right now our chat these are
amazing people shout out SAE cyberauto
event is awesome takes place in Michigan
it's only for high school and college
students you get yourself to Michigan
and they give you amazing training and
you get hands-on hacking time with a
bunch of cars yeah shout out to the car
hacking village
crowd was give me a lot of opportunities
with hardware hacking and some of my
friends here oh yeah
I didn't get to list any people here but
you know who you are and then I have I
believe my images yeah I'm not sure how
much time we have or if I went over but
if anyone has any questions you can feel
free to hit me up on Twitter my buses
can fly seriously that we can talk about
anything I'm happy to chat about
hardware hacking if I can help thank you
so much man are you gonna let's promote
your Twitter account because I imagine
people will want all these resources and
will try to share them as well obviously
we'll have an archived version of this
talk up online so people can check out
things but how can people follow you on
twitter yeah I am at buses can fly as
the handle on the slide say that's it
that's that's how you can find me
probably the best way to shot I'm on
discord as well I'm in the bug crowd
official discord you can find me there
and DM me there if you want but I'm very
reachable online awesome well thank you
so much for doing this talk thank you so
much for everyone in the chat for
watching buses can flies talk here give
them a round of applause we're gonna
have to move right into our next talks
pretty quickly but yeah thank you so
much
buses can fly really appreciate your
presentation here thanks for having me
it's been a ton of fun awesome