first of all
thank you very much for inviting me as a
speaker and
i'm very honored to have a speech in
this event hit contestant 21.
today uh title is
10 is
key challenges in line cyber security
and privacy
since we launched
our online messengers in 2011
dca is our 10th anniversary
so today i'm gonna talk about our key
challenges that we have been doing for
these 10 years for cyber security and
privacy
this is my profile
now i'm in charge of the head of cso
department
since i joined line in 2015
i have been in church of trust and
safety security consulting for line
services and have been
handling many kinds of security issues
online not only in japan but also taiwan
and other asia countries
and
also been leading the security teams and
also working as a fighter board member
of fighter alliance
basically i am working in japan and in
line soccer office
but
actually i was working in line taiwan
office
in taipei since last year's december for
almost six months for some reasons
so i wanted to uh visit conference venue
physically of this event in taipei but i
couldn't do it due to copyright90
situation
anyway i'm gonna start my
presentation closing the distance
this is
lions mission
that means bringing together the
information services and people to get
them closer and closer
this is the dynamic user base
for line
we have
189 million in global
mau
uh
in japan we have 89 million in taiwan 21
million of thailand 52 million
and for these three countries
uh almost more than seven percent
mau
population
especially in taiwan it's over
it's almost 90 percent
this is a history of line
in 2011
we have launched the line
after that
we release
line pay line global blockchain
and line bank thailand and taiwan and
also in the media
and line bank japan will be coming soon
in the
next year
uh line services could be
a part of our daily life
currently called
life online this is a concept a story of
one day of your life
for example
uh when you get up in the morning the
first thing to do might be
checking the news by using live news
online today
and all the pizza delivery for lunch and
time with uh the maicom japan orlando
thailand
and get get coupon from official
accounts
and
get shopping using line pay
and enjoy music with live music or line
tv of taiwan thailand on the way back
home after work
in such a day of life
we could say that
this user could spend
um much time of daily life in some of
line services
this is the concept of life online
it is also natural to say that line is
expected
uh
to provide safety service that protect
and handle the user data and its privacy
appropriately
and practically we have been doing that
it is
always important for us to keep the
user's trust for line while our users
can enjoy our services
and
if we could uh
keep such a condition we believe that
line could become a sustainable digital
platform that meet our social
responsibilities
tim cook of apple
has said
like
we shouldn't ask our customers to make a
trade-off between privacy and security
we need to offer them the best of wealth
this is just a challenge for
all the line
in today's presentation i'd like to talk
about
three
perspectives technology process culture
by these
three perspectives
we have been working on and challenging
for cyber security privacy
is by technology
this is a story of lion account security
line account security model is based on
mobile so
and not based on web so
[Music]
in general the potential risk of account
hijack is potentially
is a different
from the the case of web
because the mobile device service
account can exist
based on one phone number
and
let's say
the two mobile device cannot bind to one
phone number
it's true
and so
as soon as the normal user's account is
hijacked by the user abuser the normal
user's application let's say line
application becomes unavailable
this is a
different from web
and in early days of line application
the line account login certification was
very simple without any two-factor
authentication
so
it was very weak against password list
attack
um so potentially we had an account
takeover program
and
uh in real
after
2012 we found a huge number of victim
users of uh come takeover
especially in japan and taiwan
it was a
kind of big social problem remember
remember remember that
so in 2014 we have introduced four digit
pin code for blocking
password list attack
but as you know it's really old style
and it's not
uh
it's not a good countermeasure for
possible lease
you can easily imagine that many of
users tend to use the same four digits
from four digit number with the password
or email address
so that's why it was still weak against
password list attack and we found so
many abuses and
many victims
then
2016 we introduced a new migration rule
uh which is line
will check if the user has previous
device or previous phone number when
migrating to new device with new phone
number
in the settings
menu you can
check
the account migration switch
offline application this is one of them
and we found this approach was very
powerful to password list attack
and we found there was no password list
attack
available and succeeded after this new
is released
that was powerful other time
yeah but at that time
after that after several months
we found new type of abusers
uh
the approach was social engineering
abusers tries to talk to the normal user
after taking over his or her friend once
the abuser pretends to be
a friend and start the communication
hi help me
on what's up
uh i have lost my phone and
could you tell me your phone number
and yeah my phone number is blah blah
blah okay uh the pink order is sent to
your sms
please tell me the the pin
okay this is
7.158
that's all
um but doing this approach
abusers
succeeded to uh get account and
success
and we also found
then the the number of victims has
increased again unfortunately
speaking decision line it was was worse
situation
because we know that
changing our specification will never
improve this situation and the problem
so
we change it
the approach
the data analysis and machine learning
when the victims report to the situation
to line
we start analyze
the data and develop the model to
identify such abuses
by
using their business behaviors and
operations
and attributes as well
and in
september
almost three years after new migration
rule is released
finally we have succeeded to examinate
lion contact over cases made it zero
since then
we don't have a massive accounting of
cases like before so
data analysis and machine learning was
finally very powerful
even for social engineering
this is a story of lion consecutive and
our challenge
next one is pyro
pyro is a new authentication standard
using public key cryptography and
specification
is standardized in file alliance and
major platform ios android windows are
supporting
for example uh the web wilson is really
well known standard
based on file specification
okay
this is story of line and vital
since
line joined in fighter alliance as a
board member
we have been releasing file enabled
services in line pay and line
and this year we have open sourced our
files to server software
and i will
explain
passwordless line in detail
from the next slide
this is the use case of passwordless
line
basically
password
uh will be never required to input in
login
with desktop line application
in this scenario
uh
only for the first time log in 6 digit
ping is required to input
yeah but
after that password input is not needed
in that device
this is a
high level system artichoke passwordless
line protocol
when the file protocol
is initiated
line application will
be woken up by push
and generate the key pairs of firewall
and make signatures
as a part of file protocol and so on
so
but we have several issues to implement
as in general
most of the developer will face the same
issue
first one how to
on
where to manage the
the public key periods for viral
the second one is how wide os versions
and platforms do we support
how do we realize a file policy flexibly
for example one of the application
allows only biometric but another
application allows biometric and ping
and
several kinds of authentication methods
that can flex
flexible policy
maybe we have to handle
so in order to resolve these issues
we have developed line trusted security
module ltsm
um this is the client-side architecture
or for a file or enabled application
based on ltsm
rp can uh
call the file client api
that is supported by ltsm core um ltcm
core will
provide the
um
some basic functions that in reality the
file features
and
it the adsm also supports the
abstraction for
uh
the authenticator user key management
and attestation key management
and especially
adsm can
support not only
android keystore including te
ios keychain but also whitebox
encryption
this is a safer protection software
module to protect
the cryptographic keys
in software level
in case that device doesn't support
android keystore or
in that case dsm can support that
so
thus the ldsm has been developed to
support as many types of platform and
services as much as possible
um
as you can understand in the previous
slide lion has developed the atsm which
is like
um
adopting the white box encryption
and supporting the wire coverage of both
ios and android version
and
abstraction of different
uh
of platform features like api in each of
these or each os or authenticator and
sequestration and so on
okay next one is letter seeding it's a
end-to-end encryption
uh
into an encryption is
the
by design
the server side let's say line server is
not able to decrypt the
encrypted message or obtain the
encryption key
it's different from tls
uh basic concept of letter sitting is
design
uh
like
any line application must support
latency
second one is any secret key must be
handled only in line application in the
client side
in third one a line server
is responsible only for limited
functions
gateway for key exchanges
message transmission
and
public key management
and so on
this slides to explain how the
encryption key is shared and how
the message is encrypted and decrypted
between one to one user
basically every line user has ecdh key
pairs
uh this is generated in line application
no not in the server side of course
and each stock room of line
share secret key is generated by using
the the room members
then the
plain message will be encrypted
using the shared secret
uh always using
sha256 and the asgcm
and
and c
and tag generated by
aes dcm will be
sent to
uh for sent from a to b and
the user we can decrypt it
uh
yes and uh
as we apply asgcm um
so receiver side can
obtain the play message wizard
uh
with the decryption key
and also the check the integrity
by using
uh this
this one date of authentication file
and here by assuming that
when this user is
using line application in iphone
but also
using the windows at the same
for the same line account
so
line application will be required to
synchronize
the ecd is key
key pairs including a secret key
and shared secret of the room
and also messages
the
question is
how we design
the
security for
such synchronizing the keys
the point is when they use the login
in the
line account in the new devices
how to synchronize
i will explain that
on the left side already
the account is
logging in this smartphone and the user
i would like to
log in in the new device with desktop
line application
starting from generating the ecd's kpi
for desktop line application
in the client side this is also in the
client side
and send the ecdh public key
that is encrypted with six digit pin
code this is the point and
the user can see
and input d6 this is pin code and then
the user side can
create the decryption key
and then
so then the smartphone site will get the
public key of this
of desktop application
so then
both sides can compute the shared secret
by using
uh this ecdh
cryptographic algorithm
so
this temporary
shared secret
can enable the two application to send
e2e message
i mean
by using this
e2e connection
the smartphone side will send the secret
key of ecdh
to desktop from smartphone to desktop
this is a solution
in in case of lines letter setting
so then
the two application can synchronize the
cryptographic key especially in case you
see this
public hand
private key
and
next one is ongoing challenging
first one is future of letter singing
the scope of the letter setting includes
text message locus location based
message and voice call video call
for limited features
but point is how
can we expand the scope
so in order to do that we need to
resolve the issues regarding for which
format like thumbnail generation
optimizing
uh the encoding
and resizing and resending and
transferring and storing
and so on
uh anyway as of today we are still
unchallenging for this issue
number two
is uh
assuming that situation like a user a
sends
a third message content to user b with
with end-to-end encryption but
uh
line would like to use study data even
though line doesn't need to know their
content itself for example the free
sticker
if
we apply the free sticker with e3 in
future
we can see that content
uh technically
but if line
could know
uh
what type of sticker free sticker is
popular for teenagers in christmas
season for example
this
kind of information will be a good
reference for creating new popular
sticker
in future so
it might be reasonable for the
reasonable that line
would like to know that
no
this kind of static statistic
information
but in order to realize that uh
there's several problems regarding the
privacy
uh so uh we look forward to
federation learning technology as a core
technology for solving the program
while keeping the user privacy with e to
e
and never send out the raw statistic
data to line server that line could know
a rough
but privacy protected statistic data
getting by getting
inputting
noise
[Music]
into the
into the the world data
this is also ongoing challenge though
we expect that challenge could
realize the best balance of privacy and
best business
in future
still on going challenge
next one is a by-process it is also
another important factor in
cybersecurity and privacy as you know
uh there is a famous quote by blue
schneier security is not a product but a
process
as we have many product release
in every month
sometimes in every week
our service production lifecycle is
always in operation
and we also have a security privacy
development life cycle
on that for
creating this better security and
privacy for the product
and i will pick up some process that we
are doing
first one is pia
pia is a private privacy impact
assessment process
it's uh in line it's a manage mandatory
process for any kind of services
that handles the personal data or
sensitive data our
privacy related information and so on
this process is to confirm the services
compliance with existing laws and
internal rules
and
also policies and in addition to that to
meet the expectation to privacy or
expectation from users
um
government media or other stakeholders
during the course of the process
pia team
uh consisting
uh
legal and data protection expert
sorry
check that what kind of data is
collected and why
and
who access and
how to control
and environmental control data
what the system or operational
environment
to control the data
um
anyway recently we have many services
that need to handle user data for
in mainly improving the user experience
of the service the number of pia
requests is increasing rapidly year by
year
we also have another management process
called risk assessment
this is a
kind of manual security test done by our
security engineers
basically any services are required to
pass the risk assessment process in qa
stage before releasing
but
we have so many risk assessment requests
recently
because the number of services are
increasing
so
our team is also challenging to develop
automated security testing environment
for supporting
the risk assessment process
this is called sims
security issue management system
the concept is based on deficient office
and for example triggered by the event
from git or jenkins security scanner
will start to scan the product
automatically
and notification of the report will be
also automatically sent to the
communication channel like slack
we have already developed and adapted
this system to
the some part of the real product
and
now we are going to expand the scope in
the next year
and i hope this system could optimize
the security engineers resources for
risk assessment process
next is our three processes after
releasing background program and
reporting and awareness
uh we are running running security
banquet program since
2016. now it is on
platform
we can have uh reports regarding
vulnerability or security problems of
our product from outside engineers in
global and the number of report is
increasing year-over-year
especially
2020 the number of report has
reached the maximum
these are figures related to the
background program um
valid
valid report
is over 30 percent out of all reports
are found to be valid
just more than 100 reports in a year so
it's so helpful for us
amounting bounding in last year we paid
almost 1 000 usl
type of vulnerability there are
many significant type of vulnerability
you can find for example for example
information disclosure uh reflected xss
an improper access control ssrf that
covers almost 50 percentage
only by looking at this uh we can
understand how wealthy activity the bio
bounty program is
since 2017 we have an annual
campaign focusing on
account takeover and fishing and so on
as a awareness activity
uh something people have to care about
in the internet life
in this recent
few years other internet companies also
join this campaign with line and
to live on up the campaign
now we have a common website and here uh
provides interactive quizzes and
external links to the web website
of participating companies
this is another awareness activity
online privacy
january 28th is internationally known as
a
uh privacy day and
since ninth
2019 line organizes an event called lime
privacy day
to help the users and
employees also understand
the risk of the privacy how to protect
your privacy and how to do now
and the better understanding and
awareness privacy in user user side is
one of the most important
issue
and it's also our challenge
this is uh
done in
in japan site
and this is in taiwan side
we also have a certain awareness
activities in taiwan
line timer has been running a large
campaign for users awareness
addressing the cyber security and
privacy risk and internet safety
for these several years lion has
partnered with irene
irwin is a taiwan same government
organization
dedicated to
promoting safety or internet environment
and this year's awareness campaign
address a program
related to teenagers and children's
safety
as
they
are uploading their private photos
usually
however which might be spread
involuntary
uh even the 40 percentage of them don't
know how to deal with it
this is a one of the big social problem
in taiwan
during this campaign we utilize this
online timeline line today live music
and an irene official account as well
and
this kind of
campaign is not only for awareness
for users but also contributing to
eliminate such a social
uh program
this is about reporting
this is also important activity from
uh
transparency point of view
every year line publishes um
transparency report
in this report we disclose a number of
cases we respond to
government
data requests based on
legal instruments such as such warrants
and we also show the
breakdown
by country and
quan type also
in addition to that we also disclosed a
content moderation report where
we show how
how many contents are taken down by
our monitoring activities in violation
of our time of use
uh example
the
promotion of illegal activities and uh
obscene content and spam and so on
for line side we could be aware of our
social responsibilities through
uh disclosing this type of report
and
for user side they could have an
opportunity to understand and judge the
soundness and social
significance of line's relationship with
government and also this activity itself
as well
we also publish this encryption
encryption report that includes uh
which cryptographic
algorithm we are using and what the
message what type of message the data
setting applies to
and
how much message are encrypted
as a statistic data
and so on
such information are updated and
disclosed
almost every year
the third factor is the culture
in most of our organization
uh i think
we have a big issue that how to educate
and improve skills of employees and
engineers for security and privacy not
only employee
like phishing and ipt
but also the for the engineers like
infrasecurity and server side engineers
and security engineers secure coding
configuration secure process
and so on
then we
have developed called line class
this is an internal education
environment
supporting the content management
education content management and
participant management
and score on achievement management and
so on
we value such a
skill development for security members
and we want it
we want it as
one of our culture
and also value to develop something we
are something by ourself when we need
something
this is also one of our culture
first motivation
of this line class was actually the only
fall
and focusing on our security members
skill development in two years ago
but currently this is used for old
uh
uh every line employees
since last year because the quality was
good enough
interaction
interaction with outside experts is also
one of our important culture
this slide shows
the security engineering event hosted in
japan taiwan korea called bex
io
our team member is planning and hosting
facilitating this event and
inviting guests from outside
uh this is a photo of
our best japan in tokyo tokyo office
and this is a list of presentation the
past event
in japan
uh we have all seven times in japan
since 2019
this photo is also big taiwan held in
taipei totally we had eight times in
taiwan
and
we also had a big korea one time
and basically we strongly
support this kind of event for
constructive community building and
providing valuable
opportunity for
the growth of security engineers in each
country and region
this is also past
presentation list
in the
event in taiwan
in time in case of taiwan we have around
30 up to 50 attendees in each event
this is an another event
we also organized the
uh event
called security summit since 2017
we hosted in san francisco rome paris
and tokyo as well
and this is kind of international summit
focusing on security data and privacy
in this event
uh we invite security and privacy
experts of global authorities
and have their keynote speech and also
open discussion to share the current
security and privacy data identity
identity issue
each countries and the region situation
regarding the data privacy regulations
interpretation
and practical operations against such
situations like
gdpr and so on
future visions
against that topics
and situations
um past speakers are really gorgeous
robot telling
he's famous as a winner of
touring our in 1986
um
kind of legend of computer science
and i called
from taiwan board of directory
a former icon board of direct directory
in taiwan
and also sakin rasan are the chairman of
opid foundation from japan
and university processor dp minister of
taiwan in a world economic forum
and
we have so many
professionals and experts
to invite in this
secret summit event
okay this is summary
okay in today's presentation
i have introduced lines key challenges
for these 10 years by technology by
process and by culture
that
included multiple directional approaches
and challenges
and of course to keep on such challenges
is
necessary for lying as one of important
social responsibility
and also we know we have to keep on
updating
finding better things for getting closer
to the best for cyber security and
privacy
we believe that such sustainable
challenge could be the source of our
users trust for
life that's all my presentation thank
you very much