the next session will welcome thomas
miller from the cesar
to talk about some of the threats that
was faced
by the infrastructures in
in the u.s and in asia pacific
so
it is rare to to have someone this high
level
from cesar
to talk about something
like this and
in the eve of thanksgiving
so um let's welcome thomas miller with a
round of applause now i'm
[Music]
i guess uh everybody can hear me now
do i have an echo there
everything's fine
okay great um all right let's get
started um
good uh good morning i guess to everyone
um
i'm tom milar from the u.s cyber
security and infrastructure security
agency
um it's a great honor to be able to talk
to you uh today
and um i really hope that uh that i give
you some information that you can use
um as well as give you some uh some new
information about sort of what my agency
is and what we do in the united states
uh the top threats that we're concerned
about
and uh and how we can better work
together to deal with those threats um
going forward
so um
on to the uh on to the presentation i
suppose
so here's um here's the outline of what
i want to talk to you about today
first we're going to give a little bit
of background about sizza
um to explain what we are as well as
what we are not
then we're going to talk about the top
threat to u.s critical infrastructure
today
uh since that's um one of the number one
things that sizza is responsible for
trying to protect in the united states
we're going to talk about different ways
we are trying to fight that top threat
um
going into
how we can work together collaboratively
how we already do it in the united
states and how we do it internationally
as well
and then i hope we have uh
then i hope we have a lot of time at the
end for uh questions and answers as well
because i'm really looking forward to
the questions you have and hopefully i
can give you some really informative
answers
so
what is sizza
and we call ourselves nations risk
advisor
and the reason we say nation's risk
advisor is because we are not a we are
not a cyber regulator
we don't go around
imposing penalties on people for having
poor cyber security practices
um we do make recommendations on how
people can improve their cyber security
posture
we perform assessments of people's cyber
security posture
um to let them know where they can
improve we also perform incident
response in case of cyber security
incidents um so we and we perform hunts
so when we know about different types of
threats and indicators of compromise we
will send teams out to certain
organizations to perform a hunt action
which is a proactive way of finding a
threat that may already be in your
environment that you're not aware of
and we develop lots and lots of
recommendations and guidance that are
targeted at different audiences
throughout the united states and abroad
because any of our allies and partners
can take advantage of the the
recommendations and the information that
we publish and i'm going to talk a
little bit more about that later on in
the presentation today and hopefully
there's some stuff that you can use as
well
and our um our key constituents and
partners or stakeholders as we sometimes
say
uh include all of the u.s federal
government agencies
with a few exceptions but the vast
majority of the u.s federal government
falls under sort of our purview and u.s
critical infrastructure
and the way we divide up critical
infrastructure is uh there are 16
different sectors within the united
states that we are mostly that we're
most concerned with those include
everything from government facilities
including like schools to health care
and human services like hospitals and
hospital networks as well as chemicals
the chemical sector the energy sector
different types of critical
manufacturing
transportation um and uh and various
others as you can imagine
so it's a very very broad mission uh we
have a wide scope um a lot of a lot of
different you know thousands and
thousands actually of different
organizations that we're trying to help
protect from cyber cyber security
threats as well as um
other types of infrastructure threats i
should point out like i'm on the i'm
definitely on the cyber security side
and that's the most important for the
talk today obviously but we also do
things for infrastructure security like
how to secure um federal buildings or
how to secure like uh broadly attended
uh widely attended gatherings like um
like sporting events for example or
something that we're also concerned with
protecting
and
so that brings us to the number one
threat to that critical infrastructure
that we're concerned with the number one
cyber security threat is definitely
ransomware
um i even have a colleague who likes to
joke that the top three threats to
critical infrastructure are ransomware
ransomware and ransomware
that's because it's disruptive by design
when um
other types of cyber threats uh commit a
compromise of a critical infrastructure
network usually it's not to be
disruptive maybe they're trying to steal
um you know you know economic
intelligence or industrial espionage or
something like that but that doesn't
break the infrastructure down it doesn't
cause things to fall out of operations
for for a period of time
and uh and that's a huge concern for us
because we know
um in recent cases we've had uh
incidents that affect uh energy food and
agriculture supply chain and our
hospital networks and all of those
things have led to uh really severe
costs to our society and our way of life
you can imagine if certain types of
foods stop becoming available that makes
it difficult for families to feed
themselves
when uh the colonial pipeline incident
occurred
in may of this year that was a
ransomware incident and that um
that caused severe impacts to the uh to
the energy supply chain for uh
probably half of the east coast of the
united states if not more for uh for
quite a long period of time and that was
very difficult for people trying to just
put gas in their car
and also hospital networks is a huge
concern if ransomware knocks out a
single hospital in a region
and uh and we're already under pressure
from the uh or strain i should say if
we're already under strain from the
pandemic as it's ongoing then you can
imagine the effects that has on people's
health because they can't get um
they can't get access to treatment as
quickly as they would normally because
you've got one hospital that's having to
redirect patients because they can't
support say imaging is down right or
some other function of the hospital
doesn't work because of ransomware
and uh and these attacks are occurring
all the time there are on a daily basis
across all different sectors of critical
infrastructure and all different sizes
of organizations
um it used to be i think that we
considered ransomware not as great of a
threat as it has been in the last couple
of years because ransomware mostly
targeted smaller organizations and the
amounts of money that were being
demanded were
um
were not as not as large as they are now
so now ransomware is is more disruptive
more sophisticated and um
and they've gotten uh much more
audacious
in um
in the different types of organizations
that they're targeting for uh for
attacks
so
how do we uh how do we work together to
uh to try and defeat ransomware
so in the united states we work with
different agencies throughout the uh
throughout the government and with our
private sector partners um especially in
the uh in cyber threat intelligence
uh in the it sector and the telecom
sector to uh to combat the threat
uh
our main partner agencies obviously are
our law enforcement partners
they perform investigations and bring
charges and try to interdict
and disrupt the uh the operations of
ransomware gangs
um so that would be the federal bureau
investigation
as well as the uh
united states secret service and then
the treasury department can uh can lay
sanctions
against uh against different
um
recipients of funds which means that uh
it becomes illegal to pay those people
and uh
and that's another way that we can uh
possibly disrupt their operations is
making it illegal to pay them off so
that there's no way for for them to
actually collect the ransom
um we also work with our defense
agencies um diplomatic and intelligence
agencies all work together to uh as we
say take the fight to the enemy which is
to um
to make it clear
to uh to countries that host ransomware
activity that it's unacceptable to us
and also where um where possible
possibly trying to disrupt their
infrastructure
and lastly um
we uh
last but not least sizzit is leading the
effort to harden the targets for
ransomware we want to make systems more
secure and resilient um and make sure
that our critical infrastructure is not
a low-hanging fruit for these criminal
gangs that are profit profiting off of
ransoms
so now i'm going to go into more detail
and talk specifically about that effort
to uh to make systems more secure and
resilient
and uh and walk through some of the
resources we've already made available
on that front
so this is um this is the main page of
our stop ransomware.gov
website
which has a huge amount of resources
available to everyone for free
um on
you know explaining what ransomware is
obviously um helping people respond to
ransomware if they've been attacked
and most importantly helping them
prepare
and prevent um
their organization from being
you know hit by ransomware in the first
place so we have lots of different
resources available on stop
ransomware.gov there's um about a
22-page guide that goes into lots of
technical information on how to protect
your organization from from ransomware
attacks and also includes incident
response checklists in case the worst
case scenario does happen and you are
affected by ransomware
there's also specific guides on this
site for different um audiences like
i've already talked uh talked about
healthcare quite a bit we have a special
page for healthcare under this site and
the resources section we have another
one for educational organizations
because we knew that um
especially when uh
schools started going to uh mostly
remote learning during the the worst
uh phases of the pandemic here
um we were concerned that schools were
going to be hit more often by ransomware
um and knocked out of operations and we
uh we wanted to help them protect
themselves as well
so there's a ton of resources on this
site
um
i you know if you are concerned about
ransomware or want to just want to learn
more about how we're dealing with the
threat i'd advise everyone to try and
check it out and just browse around or
look use the you know the classic search
bar to find out if we have anything
specific to your industry or sector
um
next is our bad practices page
this is um this is something that we
started uh publishing just very recently
um and everybody's heard of best
practices
uh bad practices are the things that you
shouldn't do
ever because they're a great way to get
compromised and it's an extremely short
list we told ourselves when we started
publishing the bad practices that we
wanted to make sure that we didn't get
to like any more than seven or so
because we didn't want to overwhelm
people with all the things not to do
as it stands there's a list of only
three
and i'll tell you right now they're very
simple the first one is not to use
unsupported or end-of-life software so
no more on-premise windows windows 2008
server server we know that the bad guys
love that sort of thing when they find
it um during the reconnaissance phase
because there's tons of vulnerabilities
that are very easily exploited that way
um so we want people to try and
eliminate as much and eliminate all of
the end-of-life software in their
environment um to the greatest extent
possible and if there is any sort of use
case where end-of-life software is
required and we know that those use
cases do exist in critical
infrastructure unfortunately that those
systems are protected and segmented as
best as possible so in case they are
compromised it doesn't lead to a
compromise of the rest of the network
the second one the second bad practice
is no use of default known or
unchangeable passwords
um especially for critical systems but
in any case uh we all know that weak
passwords are a really bad idea but we
know that you know
known default and unchangeable passwords
are still a fact of life in a lot of
places so we put that on the bad
practices list because again it's
something that the bad guys know how to
identify and quickly take advantage of
and then that leads to a compromise of
your systems and data
and lastly the third bad practice
is uh is the use of single factor
authentication for remote or
administrative access
um and that means basically that
everyone who is um everyone who is using
remote access should be using some kind
of token other than just a password uh
to uh to authenticate and get access to
the network
uh here at the department of homeland
security which is the uh the parent
agency of sizza
um everyone uses a uh
an id an id smart card with their uh
with their laptop or or derived
credentials with their mobile devices so
that everything is um everything has at
least a second factor of uh not only
something you know which is your pen but
also something you have which is your id
card so that's how we make sure that
everything is multi-factor for our
remote access we encourage everybody
else to do similar
um again in some cases we know none of
these are necessarily inexpensive
investments for for people to adopt but
we do know that if you don't
avoid the bad practices again you will
find yourself compromised uh sooner
rather than later
um from our own experiences our own
incident response and uh and as well as
the experience of others that we've
worked with
um the next thing i want to talk about
is uh is our alerts
um we have a system we call the national
cyber awareness system which is uh
sort of a combination of uh rss feeds
social media and uh an email
subscription lists
all of which are ways to get access to
the same information and these are all
of the alerts that we publish on various
things here i'm just sharing an alert
that we published uh back in october on
the black matter ransomware
um
and uh we suspect black matter is
possibly um
a rebranding of another ransomware
family that was involved in uh some
pretty critical incidents previously
and uh and now we know that this one is
this new rebranded black matter
ransomware has targeted multiple
critical infrastructure entities as well
um
and uh and so we use these alerts to get
the word out and share indicators of
compromise with our partners and all of
the people who subscribe to them and
these are freely available to everyone
so i would suggest if you're if you're
interested in getting free public uh
threat intelligence from sizza or just
having a situational awareness of what
we're most concerned with on any given
moment
you can go to our go to our website and
uh and sign up for these alerts and and
get them however you want the rss or
email or
just uh just follow our social media but
we publish a lot of this type of thing
just to make sure everybody else can
stay abreast on uh on the most emerging
threats
and lastly um and then we're gonna stop
talking about all the free stuff
um
i wanted to share with you this tool
that we've developed and share with
everybody
which is called the cyber security
evaluation tool that's what the cset
stands for
and
and the most recent version of it
includes a ransomware readiness
assessment module
and this is a standalone tool you can
download it and run it whenever you want
um at your leisure it does not send any
data back to sizza so it you know your
data that you enter into the assessment
tool stays private
um and what it is is basically a
questionnaire
um you run the assessment answer the
questions um
about your own organization and your
posture and it will feed back to you a
different set of rec depending on your
answers it will feed back to you
recommendations
on uh
on what you can do to improve your cyber
security posture and better protect your
organization
and so
that's all of the stuff that we're doing
to uh to help shore up sort of like the
uh the critical infrastructure in the
united states
just in uh just sort of independently as
cisa but all of this happens in
collaboration with our partners like i
said align a lot of these cases when
we're you know when we're talking about
what really is the bat what really are
the bad practices or what should we
publish in our next alert or where can
we collect the most you know valuable
and timely threat intelligence we're
doing that in partnership with um with
allies and uh allies around the world um
and with private sector and with our
critical infrastructure partners and
with our sister agencies and with our
counterpart agencies in other countries
um we know that we have been able to
alert potential victims before the
ransomware
the ransomware fires so to speak or
detonates
um so that you can see for example
the initial infection or initial
compromise will call back to a command
and control system
if we work together we can identify the
command and control callback before the
ransomware itself has been dropped and
detonated and if we're able to do that
we sometimes have a window of a matter
of hours
but we can get the word to certain
organizations
before that detonation um period and
they've been able to protect themselves
and minimize the impact of the
ransomware so that's been tremendously
powerful
um
we uh again like i said getting this
threat intelligence compiling all this
information and sharing it in a timely
fashion um all of that is enabled by
uh enabled by partnerships both domestic
and international
and uh those can be formal organizations
like uh
our information sharing and analysis
centers
like uh like we have here in the us that
represent each sector um information
sharing and analysis organizations which
is slightly different um are sanctioned
a little bit differently by the
government but perform most of the same
functions
um and all of these are sort of formal
membership organizations usually there's
a
dues or membership fees
and you get you know sort of nominated
into the uh information sharing and
analysis center by your home
organization that's paying your dues
um and then there's volunteer groups so
there can be people who just meet at
conferences like this one right here
today and form slack channels or form uh
uh form mailing lists
or uh
you know whatever your communication uh
your communication channel of choice is
and then share in threat intelligence
and answer each other's questions and
tackle the bad guys together that way so
there's many different ways to um many
different ways to collaborate we try to
leverage um as many of them as we
possibly can within the bounds of the uh
within the bounds of the law as you can
imagine
and uh
and uh encourage you to also like join
your local trust groups uh participate
in your information sharing and analysis
centers or the uh the counterparts to
those in in your countries
and uh
and work with us
so
that is um
that concludes my prepared remarks for
today
um i'm sorry if i went through that a
little bit quickly but i wanted to save
a lot of time for question and answer
so thank you again for having me this
has been an honor to uh to speak today
and um and really looking forward to
your questions
thank you again okay yeah so um thanks
again um um thomas for coming on the uh
thanksgiving uh night yep um
okay
now what is
so i have one question
so
uh
just now you mentioned uh one of the
most important thing about the bad
practices is to run legacy softwares
like windows server 2008 or
those software that's not supported but
i think one of the issues that um i've
seen with some of these uh critical
infrastructure is that those critical
infrastructures are underfunded so
there's a problem uh whereby
we have a hard time trying to convince
them to kind of migrate from these
systems and um sometimes these systems
are running a lot of their
um are tangled with their the rest of
their infrastructure so
it can be pretty difficult to or costly
to do so um what's kind of the the
general strategy um for those especially
for the private entities whereby we
cannot just like fund them directly
so one thing we have um
and uh
this is a little this is going to be a i
realize you know we have we have uh we
have a lot of different people in the
audience here today but uh pretend this
is kind of an off the record uh off the
cuff remark one thing we have started
talking about a little bit within within
sizza
is whether it would help for us to have
a grant-making authority
um so that we could provide different
organizations with um
with funds to um to improve that
situation unfortunately i don't think
that solves like just having the money
doesn't always solve the problem because
uh it can be a big supply chain problem
i have a
i have a friend of mine who works at a
at an academic institution
who is just now um telling me he was
trying to install
some completely unsupported version of
windows on onto a machine
um
specifically because it was connected to
a milling station
so it works in like the architecture
school and they use a lot of different
milling they use actual industrial
control systems there
um uh to teach the students how to
interact with different types of uh
um like metal working tools and blades
and things of that nature
so he's working he's gotta install
windows
i can't remember which version but it's
way out of date and um and it's only
because it the the software to run the
mill or the lathe
only works on that version of windows
and we know this is just a microcosm
of what the situation is like in
critical infrastructure because it's not
enough to say you know like oh you have
to invest in this
it's like can you really replace the
machinery
and you may even have machinery
that no longer you know is no longer
supported with uh with modern software
just because of the supply chain for
these devices and how things get you
know companies get bought
or uh or you know they get involved in
mergers all this all this sort of stuff
changes about the economics of uh of
software and and what has to work with
what
um
so just having just being able to throw
money at the problem
doesn't necessarily uh
doesn't necessarily solve the issue
um
what we wanted to do when we published
that bad practice though what we really
wanted to to
to start was
start to have that difficult
conversation
about you know like why is there so much
unsupported software especially in
critical infrastructure and what are the
uh what are the investment decisions
that need to be made to change that um
and where do they belong in the supply
chain one of the other effects we wanted
to have with that with that bad practice
was to have a conversation with uh cyber
security insurers
so like say if a cyber security
insurance you you ask a cyber security
insurance company for a policy
and uh and then they find out you're
running a lot of unsupported software
then that you know that might create um
additional costs for your policy or you
might be deemed uninsurable period
and that turns um that turns investment
decisions around very quickly right
because you think oh i can offset risk
by buying cyber security insurance
go find out because we run so much
unsupported software the cyber security
insurance is now very expensive well we
could save money on this investment to
buy down risk by buying down risk in
other places
so those are the conversations we were
trying to start and it is a very
difficult
um i guess this long rambling answer is
just a way of saying like it's a very
difficult complex thing
we tried to boil it down to one bad
practice though to start that
conversation about how to solve that uh
difficult problem
okay cool so um
uh the general idea is that uh it is a
difficult problem and um we can't just
throw money at it and we try to set the
right incentives like um having higher
insurance premiums for
for um
organizations that run these um
legacy software so that's kind of the
general idea right
that's right
um
she's doing a bad practice joe
here is the question this is a required
agency or sectors to patch nearly three
or three countries vulnerabilities
how could you
how could cesar make sure the the sector
the government sectors or agencies
already patched these vulnerabilities
so uh we have some visibility into the
uh the operating system status of uh of
at least the parts of the federal
government that we're tasked with uh
securing
um
so
everybody every government agency runs
its own i.t
um but we uh we have visibility into
different uh host-based agents that tell
us the status of at least some of the uh
some of the endpoints in their networks
so we have some visibility into their
patch status that way
the other way main way that we uh
determine we determine whether they're
uh whether they've patched according to
our directions
is uh is simple attestation
so we will just do a data call we just
ask the question have you know like
report the number of systems or the
percentage of systems that have been
patched and uh and they have to tell us
and um
the uh the enforcement of this
is not done by cesar per se it's
actually done by the inspector general
of that agency
which um which actually gives it a
little bit more uh more weight
because uh you can't run from the
expense inspector general and they will
publish what they find if they if it
turns out
hey hello can you hear me
yeah uh thank you your talk is very
impressive
um but i'm very interesting about the
ransomware because
many taiwan vendor is also being
compromised by the ransomware group
and in the past we saw that
law enforcement may be useless
in the case of rainsongwear because they
may not locate it in u.s or taiwan so
our law enforcement may not have the
power to take down lamb but however
recently we have noticed that many
groups like the black matter is being
shut down
and
it may because some pressure from the
u.s law enforcement government so i
would like to know
why uh u.s government and maybe see sisa
take important role here that can take
down
this ransomware group and why see
suspicious position
when we do this take down operation
yes thank you
can um
the microphone was a little bit
distorted on that question
can uh can i get a repeat or
uh
okay
or yeah or generally uh what he's asking
is um how does the u.s uh like just now
he mentioned that uh
um
the the threat actors are not in in
taiwan or in the u.s so he's wondering
how the u.s took down those um
ransomware threat actors uh that's the
okay yeah that's what he's asking
um
all right well so
generally uh we will for takedowns which
scissor scissors role in a takedown is
to do victim notification um for um
organizations that are already infected
with the the malicious code that we're
concerned about
but
we work very closely in coordination
with our partners who are usually
a combination of law enforcement and
private sector
um when a takedown occurs
so in most of the cases where we've done
takedowns
it's become it's be because of uh the
fbi working together with private sector
in very close coordination
um where both both organized both the
private sector side and the fbi will
have access to um to specific
information that's really key
and uh and they share that information
and coordinate when they want to do the
takedown
and then uh on a particular
particular date and hour when they've
decided they can uh they can seize all
of the evidence that they want to uh to
make the case
um
excuse me
we uh
we uh they they i should say big we not
not sizza but they the uh the law
enforcement agencies especially with uh
the cooperation of interpol for example
or europol
um go in and uh
seize the evidence that the need um and
uh disrupt the infrastructure
it's it's basically it's a combination
of usually of private sector and law
enforcement agencies and then sizza is
basically um doing
domestic victim notification that's all
we do
i see
yeah i understand thank you and the
other small question is that the sysa
has a project called stop ransomware and
we also know the layer on the other
group like a normal ransom so what do
you think what's the difference between
these two group
yeah
it's clear
i think you're holding i think you might
be holding the microphone a little too
close to code okay
yeah is that better
oh yes
yeah my question is that
i know seesaw has a project called stop
ransomware
and
we also know that the other group lies
called normal ransom and i wonder
what's the difference
in your opinion between these two group
um well stop ransomware is our is our
page mostly for resources to help you
prevent and respond
um
no more ransom is uh largely a group of
it's got europol involvement so there
are government agencies involved
but it's largely a group of private
sector uh partnerships working together
and they are sharing
um my understanding of no more ransom is
that their main goal is to share as many
decryption keys as possible so that if
you are victimized by ransomware you can
visit no warmer nomoreransom.org
and hopefully get the decryption key
um if it's already known
and then you know you render the attack
uh you can just decrypt all of your data
that way
but
the thing about publish the thing about
the uh
the adversaries in this case is that
they know they watch no more ransom and
they know when their keys have been
published
so it's it's kind of a
you know it's a it's a constant struggle
to try and stay ahead of them as soon as
you know like we publish keys and they
change their keys and it's it's never
ending that way
but i admire i admire the work that
they're doing and uh and
i think the only i think the only reason
that um we have not i'm
actually you know what i'm not really
sure what why there's not like a direct
partnership between what we're doing on
stop ransomware.gov and
netmoreransom.org
yeah okay thanks
okay um thanks um
uh
so um one of the
issue with the cryptocurrency or
ransomware is that uh the the ransoms
are paid through cryptocurrency and
there are advancements in the
cryptocurrency space for instance uh
right now most of them demands bit uh
bitcoins um and bitcoin is traceable so
that that makes law enforcement much
easier but there are um
more anonymous or um
uh currencies like monero available so
um if uh say the threat actors say they
switched to this sort of uh more uh less
traceable um cryptocurrencies for their
say ransomware operations uh what do you
think is the um
uh best response um
in in this kind of situations
[Music]
i can't very i can't speak to that very
well unfortunately um i wish i did have
more more uh detailed knowledge of that
aspect
of countering ransomware and disrupting
their operations but that um
those issues uh fall almost entirely
into the uh
under the responsibilities of our law
enforcement partners and uh and the
treasury department
that's not like scissor doesn't
typically um concern itself with i mean
we just tell everybody to not pay
that's the official u.s government
policy is to recommend everybody do not
pay the ransom
and that's why stop ransomware.gov is
full of so much advice on how to make
sure that you've got offline backups so
that you can restore yourself back to
operations without having to worry about
paying the ransom
um so we're not too concerned we don't
concern ourselves too much with the the
aspects of how they're trying to
monetize this we want to prevent the uh
we want to prevent the harm from being
done in the first place or minimize the
harm by making sure everybody has a
great incident response plan
i see so um from a seesaw standpoint
the primary goal is to uh for to
reinforce maybe recommend um preventive
measures and to guide
the victims if they if they get hacked
but not deal with the uh investigations
or law enforcement
right if you think about it um
one metaphor we like to use where for
our incident response work is that um
uh we are we're more like the emergency
emergency services in the fire
department
um we show up and we want to make sure
that everybody is safe and sound and uh
and can get out of the building and with
you know with all of their loved ones
and everybody survives we don't care too
much about who did it there's police
that show up and that would be our
partners in the fbi and they're very
concerned with who did it who's
responsible how they're going to build
the case and make sure that it never and
make sure that they can't get away with
it so they don't do it again but we're
just we're there to make sure everybody
is safe and sound so that's the
difference in our responsibilities when
it comes to incident response
that's a very very very good analogy i
think a lot of people will understand
better that way yeah so
um
so there's a question from one of our um
online participants um
and um the question is um
uh in in in taiwan or us we frequently
get hacked by
um
one of the uh
state actors um but i'm not gonna name
the country to avoid being too too
political and um what's what's the
general um
directions or guidance on how to prevent
those um state actor hacking incidents
um
i'll have to say this right the thing is
is that
persist the reason they're called
advanced persistent threats
are the reason we started calling them
that and uh and i don't think
scissor came up with that term that was
a that was an industry term and then we
just sort of adopted it
um
but the reason they're called that is
because they they do use sophisticated
tools but most importantly they are very
persistent
and um and based on our experience the
thing is is that
they they uh
we know from defending our own agencies
against these types of
nation-state-sponsored intrusions
that if uh
if these types of threats want to get
into an agency and find that data they
will spend enough time
to uh they will spend long enough to
where they will gain that access
the uh the most important thing in most
cases is to detect it as quickly as
possible
and then uh share that information and
eradicate their access as quickly as
possible so it's really about um
for those types of compromises i don't
think prevention is always like
making it difficult is is important um
but prevention is extremely hard because
of how much time they're willing to
spend
um you know
working on phishing your um staff and
employees um working on you know like
waiting for that one moment when you
aren't patched and there's a new zero
day that's floating around in the wild
um developing their own zero days that
is another thing that's extremely
difficult to defend against so all of
these things stack in their favor but
the main thing is they they want access
for long periods of time that's why they
do these uh these intrusions because
they uh they want to compromise you and
use you for you know use your networks
for their own intelligence gathering
purposes
um or to uh
you know to pre-position malware for you
know possibly other purposes down the
line but if you can detect it and
eradicate it in a in a quick fashion
then that renders all of their
investment uh you know more or less
worthless
so i think uh
i think that's the real lesson to learn
here from what we've what we've
experienced um helping defend our own
agencies here in the united states
and that's why we do uh that's why we do
a lot of those hunt engagements where we
just assume there's already a compromise
and we go in looking for it so we can
eradicate it um eradicate it from the
network okay cool that's a
very different perspective than well um
because i think a lot of the mindsets is
to kind of prevent these hacks but
that's a very interesting um kind of way
to view it is to get them out if they
get in instead of like trying to stop
them from getting in at all
um
so i think we're about time so um let's
uh end here and then uh let's uh thank
uh thomas again uh with a round of
applause
[Music]
um thanks
no thank you this was this was fun i had
fun