[Music]
good morning everybody and and welcome
to our talk entitled collaborate from
home the japanese and uk edition
so to begin with i'm going to give you a
bit of a background about us as speakers
um our our history together and then
what our talk is going to focus on
and contain
so to begin with i'm
joshua hopkins a threat researcher with
team cumry
and i'm the the uk element of the
the japan and uk edition and with me
today is is manabu who i'll let him
introduce himself
okay i'm
i'm japanese and i'm um ex speaker of
stockholm
so
maybe this is not the first time to meet
you
it's a great honor to give a talk about
again and it's really sad that i cannot
reach taiwan this time i wish i could
meet you shortly soon and also
i wish
our presentation will be something
useful to you yeah right
yeah thank you thank you manabu um and
and i guess i echo some of those um
those sentiments as well um it's a shame
that we can't be in there in person um
to meet everybody
um and i think that's what
is is behind our talk in some ways is is
this idea of how we
can continue to collaborate in a in a
new normal
so when we were first submitting this
talk
as a call for paper we were kind of in
the in a state of flux where
everybody was working from home we you
know we couldn't collaborate with
each other but we also almost couldn't
collaborate with our colleagues in the
same way and we couldn't meet in person
so
as as the year has gone by this talk has
evolved in some ways
to look at how we can
speak about our our own experiences of
collaboration to hopefully
encourage others to do the same
uh based on
what a new normal might look like if we
you know if we're moving towards remote
working how can we continue to have
these kind of
conversations and and joint working
efforts
and and what are the the mechanisms and
the the ways we can
ensure that that takes place
um so we'd come up with the
the strap line of work from home
collaborate from home
so the talk today will contain
examples of the the collaboration that
myself and manabu have have undertaken
together
and then we'll talk about how we've then
shared those collaborations with others
some successes some failures some
advice for others i guess
um and and so yes there's some tips on
sharing who to who to share with in
order to make the the largest impact
possible i guess we're all in this
industry for the for similar kind of
reasons to
improve internet safety to mitigate
losses or harms of victims
and so it's important that we we kind of
all work together to achieve this
objective
so we're going to use a couple of
examples as as i mentioned and the first
one is ghost dns
and i'll give a brief introduction into
what goes to ns is first if if it's not
something that people are aware of or
have come across before
it's not really a threat that targets
directly the the asian region but as as
we'll discuss it's something that in
theory could do in the future
or has done under different guises
so ghostiness is a
dns hijacking campaign or toolkit which
is sold on the dark web for about 450 us
dollars
and it incorporates a number of
different open source elements so it
it's basically a toolkit that's
you know
put together based on tools that are
available to for anybody to use
effectively um so in the example here
it's using mass scan for it's it's
scanning scanning element
and and based on various different
numbers
that we've seen being mentioned there's
been upwards of a hundred thousand
soho routers uh that were compromised
using this uh infrastructure
um so it mainly targets residential
internet users um you know based on
issues around
credentials outdated firmware they're
the easiest targets for this
and there's a real focus on south
american users
we believe that the
at least the developers and the creators
of ghost dns are
likely brazilian based and then also
some of the the users of toolkit as well
and the main focus is in credential
harvesting so taking
credits from banking e-commerce
a number of different other services
like we mentioned here with netflix
and then selling those credentials at
scale on the dark web so you know
taking bank account information and
selling it for a couple of dollars and
then
repeating that um across you know the
hundreds of thousands of victims that
potentially lost credentials in this way
um
so in terms of why this is relevant um
for a threat that's
you know targeting brazil
um
we think it it's still relevant because
it's
you know it's been around for a number
of years now uh it's not particularly
sophisticated as we mentioned it's
it's based on open source tooling open
source scripts it's
it's something that
you know you don't need much um
technical know-how to to use and to
operate but yeah it's still been huge
huge is successful
with hundreds of thousands of victims as
we mentioned
and the way that we work is changing
this goes back to the point of remote
working
and so we feel like soho routers are
going to become increasingly attractive
targets
um and and then the final point is um
using this as an example to consider
whether we're prepared for more
sophisticated actors using this
technique or using soho routers in some
form
and we point to the the recent example
um based on reports from
france that apt-31 have been using
compromised routers to target
organizations in france it shows that
this is something that you know isn't
restricted to
cyber criminals it can be used by nation
states as well
and then also interestingly um as we've
been tracking uh ghost dns over the past
year or so
we've seen a real spike in activity um
beginning
last october
up until around july of this year
and so we felt like
comparing you know like for like month
on month this showed a real uh clear
peaking activity that we felt might be
related to the actors who were operating
ghost dns or operating
similar exploits
to basically be making the most of the
pandemic knowing that a lot of people
were at home using the home computers
for various different things
and and effectively trying to
take advantage of that as much as
possible
um so now we're going to talk about how
we've then
you know once we've completed our work
together how we'd then shared that or
tried to share that with other people so
manabu first is going to talk about
um some of the i guess the failures or
the the the less successful um outcomes
that we've had
okay
let me share favorites i made relating
to ghost dns
i shared collected io sheets with salt
beer
the national south of brazil
so
my friend who works at the national she
said in japan
but
nothing happened
there is no reply no reaction from salt
beer
please go ahead
in retrospect
i think
my attitude towards information sharing
is not good
i just shared a list of biosheets
i should share a context
of information because
you know
context matters
also
yeah information makes sense with a
context
just a
list of io sheets does not make any
sense
also
i have to set a shared goal of
collaboration with the opponent
okay and then now i'm going to talk
about um some of the successes i guess
that we had
um in follow-up to that so
taking uh manabu's experiences in in
interfacing with vr
we we established some further contacts
with them um
as manabu mentions um talking about
context
talking about
effectively their objectives in in
tracking ghost dns it's a very
interesting subject for them as you can
imagine with the the number of victims
and and you know we were able to do that
in part because we have existing
relationships um we've we have um
contacts in in brazil who were able to
to to effectively link us up with with
people in serbia
and i think this really underlines the
importance of
of relationship building in in this
space um so c certs and certs are always
organizations that you want to be
sharing information with or
liaising with as much as possible if if
you come across something that you feel
like it might be of interest to
a country at a national level i think
those organizations the best place to
start but as as manabu mentions it's
about
establishing
the context and what that looks like um
i i mentioned here priorities and
patience
you know a cert is dealing with any
number of different threats it
at one particular time and it might be
that your piece of information is
interesting but it might not rank in the
top of their list
for priority at that time
so it's it's about being patient and you
know if
following up if you don't get a response
but but being patient waiting for the
answer and and then working towards
not just sharing your information
because you think it's interesting but
also working with the other party to to
establish what would be of of use to
them it might be that they've already
had that information shared in the past
um
and i think another important area is in
in social media
and and
maybe the way that we use it within
uh the cyber security community um you
know a lot of people are using social
media as a
mechanism for
ingesting iocs you know
we've turned something that is a a human
platform into an automated
um
you know automated data collection
environment effectively and
maybe we're not using it in the way that
we should maybe we should be you know
reaching out more speaking to different
people if we see somebody reporting on
something that is also of interest to us
can we be reaching out more
sharing the conversation sharing our
findings and i think that's a really
interesting area that we i guess we need
to we're almost forced to get into
because of the the changing landscape
with the with the pandemic
and then the second example
is uh mocau or xloader which manabu is
going to introduce
okay
is um
android marker
it is
spread via sms and login servers
a campaign splitting mukhau is known as
xiaowei in taiwan
required
at the moment
sms is the main attack vector of local
there is a url over landing page in um
sms
and a victim is navigated to
download look how if a big team uses um
android smartphone
otherwise
if a victim uses iphone
a big image navigate navigated to a
phishing website which impersonates
approval
yep pretty well
this is um
overview of local distribution on monday
in september
france
japan
germany south korea the united states
turkey and
taiwan are targeted
with why
again taiwan is one of the targets of
moko
mokau uses a transport service in taiwan
as a work
uh
excuse me i'm not sure how to pronounce
it in
your language i mean traditional chinese
but i can read a cubing in
in japanese and i know it's a it means a
transport service under
yeah
that's why
and then an another element of our um
researcher tracking of of how has been
looking at the network telemetry uh that
team comrie is able to provide
um and looking in particular at second
stage c2 servers
so at this stage we we know that
um
a potential victim has already
downloaded the the malicious apk and so
this is the follow-up connection
generated by by the malicious file
and as you can see here we we've
redacted the the victim ip addresses but
we have
have seen consistent victims connecting
from taiwan
and and we've we've replicated this
across different countries as well um so
one one of the things that we've tried
to do with our collaboration on mock how
is to show
um
show to different countries that it's
it's you know it's not a threat that
only targets asia as
manabu mentions we've seen victims in
france and germany and turkey around
europe the united states and i think the
more you raise the profile of a threat
the more that people can come together
and work on it
um so i passed back over to my nephew
okay yeah why is this really about
you know that you know
you know mario is working from home and
also
ordering from home
so
i think oster or transport service
becomes a private lawyer or a doctor
the transport services this is me
transport services in south korea taiwan
and japan are used as a rulers
by moka respond
and again
again let me explain my
collaboration periods period relating to
moko
i got a dm from a guy who claims he's a
researcher
and he took the legitimate
and looked like uh
looks like having a good reputation
online
he requested to share
more information i collected
then
i was so naive and i shared information
with him without any doubt
about
the he did not share anything with me
and also he published um article about
vocal without
credit
so appreciate
yeah excuse me yeah and yeah again he
didn't share anything with me and also
he published an article
about moko under his name without any
project of me so i was just robbed
yeah let's go ahead
lessons i learned is
be aware of the wrongs
trolls are everywhere
and
you should share information only with
possible persons or groups otherwise
you will be ruled
required
and the an issue to be solved is
creating a good relationship during the
pandemic because you know
getting to know each other well is
difficult nowadays
because you know the there are many
restrictions
for example i really
i really miss the peer bus of the
conference
in my opinion there should be a beer
brush of the conference because
it's a very good opportunity to make
friends yeah
i'm not sure because i haven't tried it
but
all boys gaza or something like that may
work
but i'm not sure yeah let me know if you
have a good solution or all that yeah
breathing right
and so to talk about
i guess again some of our successes with
collaboration
is is we look to work with a reputable
body so we worked with jp sir
um to to share some of our findings
uh and a lot of this was was based
around victim analysis and trend
analysis so so one of the
the questions that was asked was about
um
impact over time and so we looked at a
particular periods um in the in the
japanese calendar where
um there's public holidays the golden
week celebration and we saw a large
increase in in victim traffic over this
time period so it helps us to understand
the
the scale
effectiveness of some of the campaigns
you know targeting people as man of
being mentioned when
that they're more likely to be
doing online shopping or
um effectively you know that they're not
working so so that they're doing other
things with the internet at that time
and we saw that the actors really
targeting that period
and i guess
having established a
a collaboration effort based around
victim analysis it's allowed us to kind
of develop over time to look at other
areas
so obviously our our end goal in this is
to
help to identify and to to disrupt the
actors involved and to to identify their
infrastructure at a higher level
but but it started off with that initial
collaboration around around victims
and it's also opened up
you know manabu gave an example of a bad
situation with with a researcher but
it's also opened up opportunities for us
to work with with different researchers
on this topic
who've either reached out to us or we've
reached out to them because we've seen
that there's a shared interest in machow
and i think that's again a really a
valuable thing um is is just sharing
what you found and not being able not
being scared to to share what you found
is is really important
um and so now we're just going to
summarize um what we've spoken about
today uh and the sharing is caring um
i'm gonna be go ahead
okay
in conclusion
let me explain what i learned from areas
sharing information without
any context and
any commitment does not make sense
sharing is caring about the way of
sharing matters
and next point is
creating a shared goal with um
opponent is a key to success
yeah please why
and also
don't trust someone who you don't know
where even
he or she has a
good reputation online
because
maybe he or she may be a pro rather
everyone
and also
don't be afraid
be nice demand to take mother
yep
that's all
and then i've just got some some final
thoughts on on what we've spoken about
today and and for the future
um in summary um so the way we work and
collaborate has changed as we've spoken
about and as we're all aware
um and so we i guess we've got to evolve
and adapt to that um and so we're
encouraging people to you know to not be
afraid to reach out to others you know
look at the people around you at the
conference
um
maybe take the opportunity today to
speak to some people that you've never
spoken to before find out what what
areas they're working in what's of
interest to them and and maybe you might
find something that you can you can work
on together and then also don't be
afraid to reach out to others
um
you know in in the
social media space or offer other um
avenues
but just exercise the caution and that
that manabu mentions about trolls and
people
um you know not collaborating on the on
an equal standing
and and also i guess the other side of
this is to be reflect receptive to
collaborate collaboration opportunities
that come from others
so in the same way that you would like
somebody to respond to you um
you know if somebody reaches out to ask
about your research um as long as it's
okay to share it then i i would
encourage to do that and and to try to
work with other people because i think
that sometimes we're not aware of
um
different thought processes or
ways of understanding a threat that can
be aided by by speaking to others and by
sharing um
sharing what we know
there's lots of you know groups and
forums and
mailing lists that people are likely to
be part of but i think it's it's always
useful and valuable to to be expanding
on those
um and utilize organizations like the
the cert in taiwan um
or certs around the world
you know that they're going to be
reputable you know that they're going to
be interested in
in useful information
and and there's ways that you can set up
data sharing uh information sharing in a
way that's going to protect your
interests protect you know if you're
working for an organization
um
you know maybe setting up a
non-disclosure agreement or something so
that you can share the information but
it doesn't necessarily get used in
in an open platform an open forum
again as as as manabu experience where
somebody else effectively stole his work
um so that that kind of finishes up what
we wanted to talk to you all about today
um i hope it's it's been useful and
maybe generated some
some ideas um and i i hope that you you
go away from this and
maybe collaborate with somebody with in
a an area or region that you'd never
thought about before
and i think you know working together
like that we can all kind of make a
larger impact in the world
so now we'd like to open up to any
questions um
i guess this will be
online based i'm not entirely sure
but if you
also want to reach out to us we're on
twitter um ninoseki and at team
comradery underscore s2 um if there's
questions that come up after after the
event or after the talk and we'd be
happy to hear from you
um and and
thank you again for the opportunity and
and the honor of speaking today um and
hopefully an event in the future will be
able to me in person