(ethereal music)
(audience clapping)
- Hey, y'all.
We're gonna talk about
some cool stuff today.
The title is very intimidating,
but I sum it up as saying
we're gonna talk
about brain stuff.
That sounds important, right?
Now, as I go through,
I want you to be
thinking about a question
as we go through the slides
and as we go through the talk,
and to
provide this question to you,
I wanna tell you a little
ditty about Jack and Diane.
They're two American kids
growing up in the Heartland,
and they became analysts.
I want you to picture
this in your mind,
these are two kids
out of college.
Young, hungry, ready
to get into it,
security, that is.
They're ready to get into it,
and they get jobs as analysts.
They both have the exact
same level of experience.
They're both hired into
the exact same job.
Now, fast-forward five years.
At this point, you go in and
you talk to Jack and Diane,
and you find out Diane
has far surpassed
the skill level of Jack.
She is the much better
analyst in every way.
She's much better at finding
evil, describing that evil.
She's the better analyst.
But they both started
at the same time
with the same
relative skill level,
and they had the same job.
So, why is Diane so
much better than Jack?
How do you quantify that?
Well, let's talk about that.
If you don't know me,
my name's Chris Sanders.
I'm from a little town in
Kentucky called Mayfield.
That's it, right there.
That's the whole thing.
There's not much there.
We got a couple stoplights.
My background is
mostly in defense.
I worked for Mandiant, as
mentioned, for a little while,
and recently struck
out on my own
at a company called
Applied Network Defense,
and I also run a
non-profit called
The Rural Technology Fund.
I've written a few books,
if you like to or can read.
What am I talking about today,
and what is the problem
I'm talking about?
I think it's very
important to clearly state
what problem I
want to talk about,
and how we can address
it in this talk.
My thesis, if you
wanna call it that,
is that information security
is in a state of
cognitive crisis.
That's a big term,
and when you use
the term crisis,
that should mean something,
and I think it does.
I chose it very carefully.
When you say "Cognitive crisis,"
I think you can identify
that sort of thing
through three specific criteria.
I wanna talk through those here.
Number one is that the
demand for expertise
greatly outweighs the supply.
How many of you in here
are responsible for
hiring people right now,
especially in the hunting realm?
Show of hands.
Quite a few of you, right?
You know how hard
it can be to find
skilled, qualified practitioners
in this area, right?
Many of you are probably,
maybe not too long ago
were trying to find
jobs as a hunter,
but you know what?
If you didn't have
any experience,
it was also hard to find a job
because people only wanna
hire people with experience.
They need highly-skilled people.
They don't need
entry-level people,
and that's all because we have
a little bit of a skills
shortage in some degree.
The second symptom is that
most information in security
cannot really be
trusted or validated,
so we have this real
absence of peer review
in our industry.
Most of the information we
consume is consumed via blogs,
and anybody can post a blog.
It can go out of date, and
nobody will take it down.
It can say a bunch of malarkey
and no one can necessarily
refute it in a way
that actually changes that
content or influences it.
Someone can just
refuse to change it.
That's not really a
great scenario to be in,
especially if you're young,
new in this industry,
and you're relying
on this information
to help you advance your
career, fight evil, et cetera.
Number three is that we have
an inability to mobilize
and tackle big systemic issues.
Look no further than your most
recent ransomware infection.
I'm of the opinion ransomware
is one of the most significant
broad-spectrum threats
that we've faced in a long time
in regards to something
that affects everybody,
from the big mega-corporations
all the way down
to Joe's Bait Shop
when their computer
gets infected.
And Joe's a good guy and
he has good prices on bait,
so I don't wanna,
I'd hate for him to get
ransomware on his computers.
Now, interesting
thing about this,
and I talk about this,
I frame this a lot,
I frame a lot of things I
talk about through medicine,
because we're in a
cognitive crisis now
and I don't think that's
really too questionable.
Medicine, we think of as a
really, really robust science.
Medicine has a lot of problems,
but it's not really
about medical science
most of the time,
now that we have
evidence-based medicine.
It's more about
insurance and bureaucracy
and things of that nature.
But, 100 years ago, almost
exactly 100 years ago,
medicine really went through
this whole cognitive
crisis as well.
Really, these three symptoms
that are listed here,
they apply to medicine,
if you think about it.
Demand for expertise
greatly outweighs supply.
Most towns didn't have a doctor.
If they did, your doctor was
also your dentist and your vet,
and maybe sold you milk.
If that was the case,
you'd better hope you
have a doctor in your town
or you're not too sick to
make it to a town with one.
Most information in
the medical field
cannot be trusted or validated.
We still have artifacts
of that today.
Up until 30 years ago,
most medical
practitioners thought
that if you had stomach ulcers,
you should drink milk.
Now we know that's the exact
opposite thing you wanna do.
You don't wanna drink milk
if you have a stomach ulcer.
You're gonna have a bad time.
But it took us up
until just 30 years ago
to figure that out,
once that was retested
and re-validated,
and we weren't just
taking old wives' tales
for what they were.
In terms of
inability to mobilize
and tackle big systemic issues,
look no further than any
plague of your choice.
We have plagues that wiped
out a third of Europe, right?
That's pretty substantial.
Medicine went through a
similar cognitive crisis,
but they really came out
on the other end of it,
and we have this concept
of evidence-based medicine,
where you're doing
scientific research,
you're having this
concept of peer review,
and you're taking the
creation of knowledge,
and it's based upon other
validated knowledge,
which is something
we don't have yet.
Now, medicine is a
very specific field
in how you're trained.
I don't think whatever the
answer was for medicine,
in terms of medical school
and residency and all that,
I don't think that's
the answer for us,
but I do think we
can look at medicine
and how they formalized things
and how they researched
their problems,
their cognitive crisis,
how they came out of
the other end of it,
and we can use that to
really make judgments
and learn things about our own
field and our own practices.
I think that's a reasonable
approach to this,
and that's at least my approach.
That's what I'm gonna
talk about today.
That's the problem as I see it,
and why I'm taking the
position I'm taking here.
It's very critical to
talk about assumptions.
At risk of having people
throw tomatoes at me
for talking about a
definition of hunting,
I generally say
it doesn't matter
what your definition
of hunting is,
as long as you clarify it
so people can base what
they do on that assumption.
When I talk about hunting, I
think about investigations.
I have this thing called
the universal
investigation process,
which I've blogged about,
and maybe some of you
have read about that.
It's really the process
you see on the screen here.
I'll walk you through
that really quickly,
'cause I wanna talk about
where hunting fits in
so we can move on and
move past that quickly.
With any type of investigation,
you have some type
of observation.
If you're doing event analysis,
maybe that's an alert.
Pretty straightforward.
If you're doing hunting,
maybe that's something
you manually found.
You get some type
of aggregation.
Some of the great techniques
the other speakers have
talked about this far,
something with
PowerShell, et cetera.
Once you make that observation,
that's when the investigation
begins in earnest.
Once you have data to look
at, you're asking a question.
A lot of people alluded
to the same thing,
questions and hypotheses.
You ask a question
about that data
that will further
the investigation.
What you're actually doing
is trying to bridge the gap
between perception and reality.
That's all an investigation is.
We want our perception
of events that transpired
to match the reality of
what really did transpire.
Perception and reality are
two very different things,
but we want them to be
as close as possible.
That's the investigation.
We ask questions to pursue that.
When we ask a question,
we generate a hypothesis.
It's human nature.
When we have a question,
we lean a certain way.
Then we go out and seek
answers to test our hypothesis.
We seek to confirm
it or invalidate it.
Either way, we get an answer,
and that answer will generally
beget more questions.
This repeats over and over again
until we get to a conclusion,
which is usually, did
something bad occur?
If so, how bad, and
where, and so on.
That's the universal
investigation process.
Now, if you look at
this, you might say,
"Hey, this looks
kinda familiar."
And you'd be right.
It looks pretty similar
to the scientific method.
There's a reason for that.
We don't have the
scientific method
because a bunch of old
guys sat in a room one day
and said, "This is how
we should do science."
We have that because
they looked at how
scientific discovery in the
best scenarios was done,
and they mapped it out,
because they knew if we
could take this thing
that's occurring subconsciously,
bring it into our conscious
thought, and teach to it,
we're giving new
people in science
a better way to
get jump-started,
and we're giving them
something that we can teach to,
and it's gonna result
in more and accelerated
scientific discovery.
I believe this similar approach
can work for what we're doing,
and not only do I believe in it,
I've seen empirical proof
that we can do that.
I'll talk about some
of that as we go along.
The keyword here as
well is universal,
and I think that's important
since we're at a hunting summit.
How does hunting fit in?
From my perspective,
looking at the
cognitive underpinnings of
how we do investigations,
tools aside,
generally, the investigation
process is mostly the same,
whether you're doing hunting
or you're doing general
alert-driven investigation.
The only difference is
that observation stage.
With an alert, I'm giving
you something to investigate.
It's basically giving
you your question.
I wanna be clear on that.
An alert is not an answer.
An alert is simply a question
that you have to go
forth and pursue.
An alert gives you a
question, and certainly,
you could do hunting from
lower-fidelity alerts
and things like that, too,
but otherwise,
if you're trying to
manually find observations,
then that's gonna be
a bit longer process.
But it's still all contained
within this observation stage,
and there's of course
different strategies for that,
some of those which
we've talked about
here at the conference
with other speakers.
Again, the universal
investigation process.
That's what we're
talking about here
in the context of what I'm
gonna speak about next.
Let's get to some data.
We talked about Jack
and Diane earlier.
We talked about
experience, right?
And a lot of us like to
quantify experience in years.
I have five years experience,
I have 10 years experience,
when I think we all really
know my five years experience
is probably very different
than your five
years of experience.
Everyone's is.
Experience is not
simply a measurement of
years of doing something.
It's a completely
different thing.
So, I think it's
incredibly important to
figure out what that means.
What is experience?
What separates an
experienced analyst,
whether it's a typical
alert-driven
investigation-focused
person or a hunter,
what separates that from someone
who is lesser-experienced?
That's very important,
because if we know that,
we can teach to it.
I did an experiment.
I put out a call on
my blog, and I said,
"Hey, I wanna talk
to investigators
"of all varying skill levels."
I think maybe even a
couple of you in this room
probably participated in that.
I got on the phone or
on Skype with them,
and we had a phone call,
and I had 'em walk me
through at least one
of the investigations that
they had gone through,
oftentimes many,
and I recorded it,
and I did a key phrase
mapping exercise.
And that basically means
is I had a set of phrases
in certain categories,
and I would map the things
they said to those categories
to try to figure
out the breakdown
of how they went through
this investigation.
This isn't a perfect
research method,
but it does shed some
light on, I think,
the differences between
novices and experts.
Now, really quickly,
I wanna talk about
dual process theory.
This is kind of a big subject,
so I'll give you the
$1.99 description of it.
Dual process theory basically
says that, in our head,
we generally have two
complementary thought processes
going on at the same time.
We have intuition,
which is fast thought.
When you think of intuition,
you think about
driving home from work.
You don't really have
to think about that,
you just do it.
If I say, "What's
five plus five,"
you don't really have
to think about that,
you just spout out the answer.
Most of the time.
Maybe not if you're onstage,
which is why I'm not
gonna try to answer it
and accidentally say 12 now.
And you also have
reflective thought,
which is the other side, which
is more deliberate thought.
If I say, "What's 12 times 47,"
you're probably gonna
have to think about that.
You know, carry the one,
et cetera, et cetera.
Driving when you were 16
and you were learning
how to drive,
you really had to
think about it, right?
You had to think about
staying between the lines,
you had to think about
shifting if you had a manual,
all those different things.
Two competing or complementary
types of thought,
depending on how
you wanna view 'em.
There's a really
great book on this
called Thinking Fast and Slow,
if you wanna learn about that.
So, we have these
two types of thought,
and we have these different
categories that fall into them.
You see intuition on one side
and reflection on the other,
and we'll go through some
of those in a minute.
The thing I wanna talk about
briefly is metacognition,
which is the thing
you see in the middle.
Metacognition is a
really fancy word
that means thinking
about thinking.
Thinking about your
thought processes,
being aware of how you're
processing information.
Metacognition is
critically important.
Let's look at the data.
Now, what you see here are
the average number of results
amongst the people I talked to.
Novices, so, people with
very little experience,
are the ones in blue.
Experts, or the people with a
ton of experience, are in red.
There's a lot of data here.
Like, a lot.
I don't even know what
some of this stuff
really tangibly means quite yet,
but there is some of
it I think we get,
some conclusions we
can probably draw,
or at least some things
that the data suggests
which I think are important.
If you look on the left
on the intuition side,
you see incubation.
Incubation basically means
you see something
a little weird,
but you don't know
what to do with it.
So, what do you do when you
don't know what to do with it?
You just put it to
the back of your mind.
That's incubation.
You notice we have a lot
larger number of responses
related to incubation
from novices than experts,
and that makes sense.
It passes the sniff test.
If I'm a novice, I'm
probably, first of all,
gonna see more things
that look weird to me
because I've seen less things,
and I'm gonna see things
that don't make as
much sense to me,
so I'm probably
gonna incubate them
'cause I don't know
what to do with them.
Now, I want you to contrast that
with something on the
other side of the chart.
We see on the right side,
we have rule-based
reasoning under reflection.
Rule-based reasoning
should be really
easy for this crowd
to understand.
Think of an if statement.
If this, then that.
That's essentially what
rule-based reasoning is,
but in our brains.
We build this library
of rules or heuristics,
where we take certain inputs
and, based on those inputs,
we map those to certain outputs.
We see a larger
number of responses
for experts in the
rule-based reasoning section.
Also passes the
sniff test, right?
If you've been doing
this for 20 years,
you probably have a lot of
rules built into your head,
where, when I see
this bad thing,
or when I see a .top domain,
I know it's probably evil.
I'm gonna assume that's
evil and act accordingly.
It makes sense that
experts would have
a larger number of those.
I think what we see
here, to some degree,
is a bit of an
inverse relationship.
As incubation goes up,
rule-based reasoning goes down,
and vice-versa.
As you build more of these
rules, these heuristics,
to learn how to
do investigations,
you basically don't have
to incubate as much.
First of all, you're seeing
less things that look weird,
because you know what
those are automatically,
and when you do see them,
you know what to do about it.
That tells us, what
are those rules?
What are those rules that
we can boil things down to?
Chances are, a lot of
you have probably learned
a lot of those in the
past day and a half,
watching these talks.
When I see this thing,
it means this thing.
That's pretty cool.
The other thing I wanna talk
about is the middle section,
which is metacognition.
This is really neat
because, across the board,
experts generally have
a much larger number
of metacognition-related
responses.
They're more
metacognitively aware.
This is critically important,
'cause there's a
lot of really great
scientific, peer-reviewed,
validated research
out there amongst
many fields that says
practitioners in
mentally-intensive tasks
are much better
at that their job
when they're
metacognitively aware.
They've done this test
with doctors, with nurses,
even leaving the medical field,
they've done it with lawyers,
they've done it with teachers,
and they're all better or
seen as better in their jobs
when they're
metacognitively aware.
When they're knowledgeable
about their own
thought processes,
and when they can apply that
knowledge to their jobs.
That's a big part, I think,
of coming out of the
cognitive crisis,
and a part of why I'm
really speaking here.
We talk about how you become
more metacognitively aware.
This talk is part of that.
It's learning how we think,
learning the difference between
our novices and our experts
and how we bridge
that experience gap.
Next, what is the X-factor
that makes a good hunter?
I'm sure we all have a
lot of opinions on this.
I could probably ask 100 people,
and I'd probably get 70
or 80 different responses.
I have my opinion, and
since I'm the one onstage,
I'm gonna tell you
what my opinion is.
For me, it's curiosity.
It's the ability to see things
and the desire to go out
and do something about it.
There's a lot of really fancy
definitions of curiosity.
I think the best one is
simply the desire to know.
It's not the ability to know.
That's a completely
different thing.
It's the desire,
the desire to see that weird
thing and go out and pursue it,
go out and run a Google search
and figure out where you can
find out about it, et cetera.
The desire to know.
Now, curiosity's important
because it relates
very closely to experience
in a lot of ways.
I drew this chart up because
I think this really describes,
in a lot of ways,
how experience and
curiosity relate,
how they manifest for
security analysts,
at least in my career.
So, you see we have a
green area and a red area.
Surprise, green is
good, red is bad.
We have the top right, there,
we see High C, High E.
That means high curiosity,
high experience.
These are people who have been
doing this for a long time,
are insanely curious,
and as a result of it,
they excel greatly
in their jobs.
I think you would find
most people who you know
who have been doing this a while
and you would
consider really good
are also highly
curious individuals.
Now, that's an ideal state,
but with experience,
we don't all start with
a lot of experience.
Some of us start
with no experience.
But curiosity still matters,
and that's what we see on
the other side of the chart,
what I call Jumpy.
Jumpy's not bad, as long
as Jumpy is directed.
Some of us have been in
security operation centers
where we're the manager,
and we're responsible
for training people,
and you have someone who
is a year into the job
and everything
looks evil, right?
They're filing
tickets all day long,
and it turns out that
90% of what they see
is actually not evil,
they just don't know
what they're looking at.
And that's okay, as
long as that's guided
and they have mentorship
to get through that.
Low experience, high
curiosity, that's great.
Notice on the top side,
those are both related
to high curiosity.
You have to have that
high level of curiosity.
The level of experience
doesn't matter.
You'll gain experience,
and I would posit you would
gain experience faster
if you had that higher
degree of curiosity.
Our example of Jack and Diane,
I would say the thing
that separates them
is that Diane is
generally probably
would exhibit higher degrees
of curiosity than Jack,
and perhaps that's why she
was excelling more than Jack.
Now, there's conflicting
variables there.
Certainly could be some
other things, right,
but that's what I would
say if I had to guess
and all other
variables being equal.
On the bottom of this,
we see a couple things we're
probably familiar with.
We see the Apathetic area,
and we all know people like this
who have been doing
it for 15 or 20 years,
and they've just
kinda phoned it in.
They're either collecting
the nice paycheck,
they don't have a lot of
responsibility on them,
so they've got all
this experience,
but they're not growing anymore.
That's Apathetic in this job.
And then we have the
Ineffective section,
which is, very simply, low
curiosity, low experience.
These folks don't know
what they're looking at,
and because of a
lack of curiosity,
they're gonna have
a really hard time
getting to the
point where they do.
Hiring practices, curiosity is
something we want to look at.
Now, I did a little
experiment with this, too,
and I used a sim across a
few different organizations,
and I mapped,
these were organizations where
they have clear delineation
between people who are hunters
and who are just typical
alert-driven analysts.
Since this is the
hunting summit,
I thought this was
neat to highlight.
This is the average number
of investigation activities
per day for those groups.
So, for four individuals
who were hunters,
versus those who are
alert-driven analysts.
We see a couple things here.
One we see is the hunters,
which is the orange color there,
a lot greater number of
general activities in general.
When I say an activity,
I'm referring to things
like searches, pivots,
clicking on certain things
that are investigation-related
within the context
of the specific tool.
We definitely see that hunters
do a lot more things in general,
and that's interesting,
but I don't think
it's necessarily
the most interesting thing
related to curiosity.
But I think this part is.
Look at the timestamps
below there.
About how many of you have been
lying in bed, if you're
me, at 10 o'clock at night,
and you're on Twitter,
and all of a sudden,
something pops up.
Some new indicator was released,
or some new report was released,
and you say, "Oh,
man, that's neat!
"I wonder if there's
any of that in my data."
Right, a lot of you, probably.
I think that is a good
pseudo-indicator of curiosity.
The people who, again,
have the desire to know.
You found this new thing,
and you have a desire to know
if there's evidence of
that on your network,
so you go search it out.
You see that's
occurring, you know,
late night hours,
early in the morning.
I'm not saying you
have to do those things
to be curious and
be a good hunter.
That's definitely not the case.
But I do think that's
some tangential evidence
that curiosity is particularly
important in hunting,
because hunting relies so much
on generating
observations by yourself,
as opposed to relying on them
from alerts.
This brings up some
interesting questions.
Number one is, can
we measure curiosity?
Can we objectively measure it?
Psychologically, there
are tests that will
measure that type of thing.
They're expensive to do.
You have to have someone who
is a psychologist, basically,
to evaluate that.
They're a little tricky
and they're not super
domain-specific.
Can we do that in a
domain-specific way,
and if we can, can
we teach curiosity?
Is it something we're born with,
or can we actually make
people more curious?
That's a good question.
It's not a question
for this talk, but,
I would say yes.
I think we have to get there,
and I think some of us are
probably already doing that
whether we realize it or not.
So, curiosity.
Next thing I'm gonna talk about
is the sequence of
the investigation.
A lot of people would say
that it doesn't matter how
your investigation goes,
the path you take,
as long as you get to
the correct answer,
and I couldn't disagree more.
I'm gonna talk about
a few reasons why.
Studying the investigation
is really, really hard.
Everyone has a
different tool set.
We're all running
different sims.
Some of us have custom-built
stuff, et cetera.
This was not an
easy thing to study.
I had to build a custom tool,
an investigation
simulator, if you will.
I call it Investigation Ninja,
and it allows people to
go in and get an alert,
and investigate that in
a tool-agnostic manner.
They can't just go
look at the data.
They have to ask the right
questions to get at the data.
I think that's very important,
'cause again, this
is question-based.
When they do this,
I can go in and then look
at their investigations,
and this is a pretty
neat teaching tool, too,
when you can review
your own investigation
and how you went
through that process.
I can go through
and review these,
and at this point, it allows
me to do some actual science.
I can define an
independent variable
and see the effect of that
on the dependent variable.
Controlled experiments,
that's awesome!
So that's what I did,
and I wanna talk about
just a couple things
I found from that
here.
The first question I asked,
is too much data a real thing?
A lot of us have the
problem of not enough data,
not enough visibility.
But too much data is
a real thing as well,
and I wanna talk about that,
particularly in relation
to packet capture data.
I love packet capture data.
I literally wrote
a book on packets.
Like, I love it.
But I will say,
I don't think it's always
the best thing to start with,
and there are good reasons why.
I ran an experiment
with a group of folks,
and I had an investigation.
I said, "Okay, go forth and
solve this investigation,"
and I measured time to close.
So, the time from
when they started
to the time that they came up
with the correct disposition.
You see that on this chart here.
What I did is I measured
based on the opening move.
When I say opening move,
I said, "What is the first
data source someone looks at,
"and how does that affect
their time to close?"
You see on this chart,
it took people
significantly longer
to get to the correct
answer when they started
with packet capture data.
Well, that's neat.
I love packet capture, but
that's not a good thing, right?
So I said, "Let's compare
this to something else.
"Let's compare this to a
similar type of data source."
Packet capture is a lot of data.
It's a lot to sift through,
it's very time-consuming,
et cetera.
I said, "Let's take Bro data."
We all know Bro.
It takes a PCAP and
distills it down
to just really important
particular facets of the PCAP.
So I did that, and I took
the exact same scenario,
replaced the PCAP data
with the Bro data.
What do you all think happened?
Did the time to close
go up or go down?
Well, it would be a very crappy
presentation if it went up.
That wouldn't really
prove my point.
It went down, it normalized.
In this case, it brought
that time to close down
on par with Flow and
OSINT information.
That suggests some things,
and when I say it like this,
it sounds a lot more obvious.
Better organization of
high-context data sources
can yield improvement in
an analyst's performance.
This isn't to say PCAP's bad.
You're not gonna
find too many people
who love packet
capture more than I do.
But it means you probably
shouldn't start there.
It means you should start
with constrained timeframes,
constrained host.
Don't pull 10 minutes of PCAP
for a whole network segment.
Don't pull an hour of PCAP
for an individual host.
Narrow down to the specific
timeframe you need,
the specific host you
need, and start there.
Flow data is a great
way to do that.
There's a talk coming up a
little later on Flow data
that I highly
recommend you watch,
'cause Flow data's amazing.
I would say I love Flow
data more than PCAP data,
and I know that's a
little sacrilegious,
but it is what it is.
Next question, and
this is a new one.
The experiment I
just talked about,
I've done a writeup
about that on my blog.
If you wanna read more
details about the methodology,
it's all out there.
Now, for the next
question I asked,
"What data transformations
"were most often used
in positive findings?"
I did this specifically for
learning more about hunting.
I started out, and I
looked at all of the
declared incidents I found that
were spawned from an alert.
So, someone had an alert.
They investigated, and
it led to an incident.
Most of these I'll say are
just commodity incidents.
We're not talking
about really high-level
nation/state stuff.
I looked at these four types
of data transformations.
I'll list these really quickly.
A pivot means you have results
from some type of query,
and you take a field
from that result
and use that to search
in a completely
different data source.
So, like pivoting
from Flow to PCAP.
An aggregation is
taking a specific field
within a dataset,
like, let's say, the
user agent field,
and sorting on all
the unique values.
That's an aggregation.
Expansion/reduction,
simply making a search,
and then reducing or enhancing
the scope of that search.
And visualization's
pretty self-explanatory,
visualizing the
data in some type of
hopefully useful way.
For alert-driven investigations,
we see here, first of all,
expansions/reductions were
used 100% of the time.
That's what that
means, right there.
Pivots were used quite
a bit, 76% of the time.
Aggregations only
23% of the time,
and it's hard to
see visualizations,
but that was less
than 1% of the time.
Now, this is fairly
interesting itself,
but let's compare
that to hunting.
I did the same data
review, but in this case,
I did it specifically
for cases I found
where it started with someone
manually hunting
for observations,
and then going through
the investigation process
to find something bad.
Here's what that looks like.
In this case you see again,
expansions and
reductions, still 100%.
We've got those going
on all the time.
We do have quite a bit
more pivoting as well.
That makes sense.
You're gonna be
doing a lot of that.
You're not gonna stay
within the context
of one individual data source.
The thing I thought
was really interesting
was how many more
aggregations went on.
What I found anecdotally,
it's not represented here,
was that most of these
hunts generally started
from some type of aggregation,
just like the one I
mentioned a second ago,
where you're taking all the
user agents in your organization
and sorting on those,
and looking for the least
frequent occurrence,
and that's an outlier, right?
The great talk earlier
about the ShimCache parsing,
and that awesome tool and how
it did some of that for you,
that's amazing.
That's the kind of stuff
hunting often starts from.
So, we see aggregations are
a much bigger part of that.
We see visualizations still
not a big part of that,
and I will say that
this was a case where
visualizations
could've been used,
but were generally not used
in a way that was meaningful.
This isn't a way for me to
say, "Damn all visualizations,"
I don't think that's
the case at all.
They just weren't used
tremendously here.
I think this is neat.
I think this points out a
little bit of the difference,
what little difference
I think there is
between hunting and alerts,
in terms of how they actually
manifest in dealing with data,
and it also tells
us a little bit more
about maybe what we need
to teach to and build to.
If aggregations
are so important,
well, we darn sure
better make sure
the folks we're training
know exactly what one is,
how to build one,
make sure we have tools
that allow them to do that,
and help them find great
locations within the data
to do that in, right?
Just listing out place where
aggregations make sense,
and doing those on
a periodic basis.
So, pretty neat.
We're gonna wrap up here.
One of the questions
I get really often is,
"How can I do similar research?"
And I think that's important.
This research is hard.
I'm having to build custom tools
to do some of this research.
I think the best way I
can encourage folks here
is simply with the concept
of positive deviance.
If you haven't heard of the
concept of positive deviance,
very simply,
if you look back at most
of the significant changes
or positive events that have
occurred through history,
in our field or
any of the other,
they've been traced
back to someone
who was considered
a positive deviant.
That means a couple
simple things.
Number one, ask questions.
Ask questions of the
world around you,
and this applies well
beyond just threat-hunting.
Look at your SOC,
look at your data.
Look at how people are
interacting with your data
with sincere focus
on that last part.
Not every compromise has
the same threat actor,
has threat actors, has
human threat actors in it.
They don't all have malware.
They don't all have
threat intelligence.
They're not all
related to hunting.
They are all solved with humans.
I'm very thrilled to see that
that was the common thread
amongst all the talks
I've seen thus far,
is human at the center
of the investigation.
The human will always be the
center of the investigation
for as long as we're all alive,
and I'm certain of that.
So, ask questions of what you
see in the world around you.
When you do that, don't
complain about it.
It's very easy to
look at something,
'cause you're probably
asking questions about it
'cause you don't like it.
Don't complain about it, 'cause
complaining's not useful.
Instead, take that energy
and apply it towards
measuring something.
The key to doing anything
positive in life,
I feel a lot of the time,
is measuring something,
so that you can actually
see if it's a problem
and learn about that problem.
That's exactly what I did in
some of these scenarios here,
is measured something
to see if there's something
that can be done about it,
or to enhance it.
Once you measure
it, write about it.
Even if it's not something
necessarily consequential,
there's not a
significant finding,
write about it so that other
people can see you measured it.
That way, they don't
have to measure it
if it's not worth measuring,
or if you did measure it
and it's worth doing
something about,
they can also do
something about it.
And finally, don't
be afraid of change.
When I say that, I
don't mean necessarily
trying to change
whatever you've measured,
but also changing yourself.
If I've learned anything
through my study of the brain,
it's that mindsets are
incredibly quick to form
and entirely
resistant to change.
In my opinion,
that's one of the bigger
problems in the world
at scale today,
is that mindsets are
very resistant to change.
One of the things I've learned
to teach in my
investigation theory class,
where I have people go through
a lot of these simulations,
is the people who are
very new to the field,
they really excel in the class.
They really embrace the concepts
and they learn about
how to investigate.
The people who have been
doing this for a long time,
they really struggle.
That's because mindsets
are quick to form,
but resistant to change.
We have a really hard
time unwinding our brains
and unwinding how we
learn to do things.
I think if we really
wanna approach this
from a very
fundamental standpoint,
where we actually
really understand
our thought processes,
which we know, scientifically,
we know that's important,
it requires a little
bit of change,
it requires a little bit
of positive deviance.
(drums pounding)