all right hi everybody uh sorry about
the technical difficulties so so I'm
Dave Ferguson I work for Qualis so my
role at Qualis is solution architect for
the web application security products
that we have about a lot of different
roles there including a developer
consultant work for an enterprise
security and now I help with our web app
scanning products I help our customers
prospects in terms of getting them up
and running deploying scanning programs
and so forth so so I'm going to talk
about today is a list for better
application pretty
however it's it's not the list that you
probably are familiar with which is the
OWASP top 10 so first I'm going to talk
about the list that I'm not going to
talk about I want to cover just the
OWASP top 10 2013 edition real quickly
I'm sure most everyone is familiar with
this by now so it's been around for four
years now so what we have here is a top
10 list of most critical risk to web
applications and it hasn't really
changed in 2013 until this year and so I
have more on that in a minute
so the thing about the Olaf top 10 is
it's it's really been adopted almost as
a standard it was never really meant to
be a standard but the PCI DSS for
example has adopted PCI loss top 10
saying you know no payment applications
should be vulnerable to any of these
types of issues so
I want to talk about the release
candidate that came out just a few weeks
ago for the 2017 edition of the OWASP
top 10 and it's causing a lot of
controversy and confusion to be honest
so some of this changes real quick not a
lot of changes but some of the key
differences here are that invalid
invalidated redirects and forwards which
is a 10 has been dropped B the way this
alternative is not finalized by any
means but this is what the release
candidate has so the unvalidated
redirection for words has been dropped
the a 4 and a 7 which both relate to
authorization issues have been combined
into one a four which is called broken
access control I'm okay with both of
those and I think most everybody in the
app SEC world kind of has no problem
with those the things that are causing
controversy are the new ones especially
this new a7 here called insufficient
attack protection so insufficient attack
protection completely different than any
other type of a loss top ten issue in
the past in that this is not really a
vulnerability or risk it's a thing that
you know it's it's really like a way of
protecting applications that may have
vulnerabilities so it's not about fixing
vulnerabilities or knowing that you have
them it's just about protecting
applications so it's kind of a paradigm
shift going away and it's there is a lot
of controversy I'm just if you look at
the Oval off stop 10 mailing list you'll
see some of the comments that have been
made and there's a blog post by Chris
angle I used to work with on dark
reading about this and some of his
concerns with it which I tend to agree
with to be honest so let me talk about a
10 for a minute under protected api's
this is kind of interesting as well
because it's not a vulnerability it's
basically saying okay a 1 through 89
those apply also to AP is so it's it
doesn't both of these kind of like are
just a different way of dealing with
this and
the thing is with the os10 any change
could have a huge business impact out
there because of the fact that PCI and
others use the OS top 10 as kind of a
standard and so all of a sudden if
you've added insufficient attack
protection and under protected AP is
you're talking about possibly a whole
shift in needing to guard against these
things and api's is great as far as
protecting them but essentially it seems
redundant to me because if you if you're
saying that the olaf's top 10 is just
for web applications you can just say
that and say oh and also it's for AP is
so you don't need an actual item in the
hola sub 10 saying also protect AP is
just my thoughts on it but we'll see how
the final version comes out but a7 the
new a7 here being proposed if you think
about it if we have under protected
applications why don't we also have
insufficient apps Tech funding I mean
that's that's a risk
what about inadequate executive buy-in
for having a secure SDLC these are all
sort of factors that go into securing
applications so should they be on the OS
top 10 also know bug bounty program
understaffed on call our department lack
of cyber threat attack 3d blanking world
map all these could be risk that could
be part of the old lost 10k the mission
of the Lost 10 is not real clear right
now so we'll see how the comments work
out and I also need to mention that Oh
awesome core supposed to be an open
organization vendor free vendor-neutral
agnostic but there's some thoughts that
under under protected are the
insufficient attack protection a7 that
specifically benefits a certain class of
vendors up there typically anyone who
has a product that includes runtime
application self protection or web app
firewall anything that protects the
application if there's a product out
there
that fit that fits that or protects
eight against a seven they're going to
benefit greatly if that gets added to
the Ola stub ten so that's one of the
pieces of controversy out there okay so
I'm really done talking about the OWASP
top 10 now I want to get into a
different list for better app sec and
the list I'm going to talk about is the
OAuth top 10 proactive controls this
particular project you know again it's
from wasp but it's really targeted more
at developers and it's a way to assure
that development teams can build in
proactively protections and fight
vulnerabilities in their applications it
first appeared in 2014 so it's been
around about three years now it's on
version 2 right now an update is coming
later this year so it's actively being
worked on and the key the leaders on
this project are some of you may know
Jim Monaco also Jim Byrd and Katie Anton
for the three-count primary contributors
to this project and so as part of this
talk I actually reached out to them and
talked to them about it they have some
really good ideas for this and one of
the reasons I wanted to do the talk
today was just to make it known that
there's actually a better list out there
if if your goal is to have your
developers in your organization build
more secure applications they should
really be looking at this list versus
the oval top 10 you know even without
all the controversy that's going on
right now so they lost top 10 proactive
controls is a list of really technique
security techniques that need to be
included or should be included in every
development project and it's listed in
order of importance so a you know see
one is the first control bank most
important in descending order to c10 and
like I said the target audience is
developers so I did want to mention also
that the proactive controls there's
really a lot of supporting documentation
for implementing the controls and the
vast majority of that is going to be
found in the
cheat sheets I didn't even list them all
here but there's a very large number of
cheat sheets on different topics that if
you need to secure your application
against sequel injection how do you do
that there's a cheat sheet for that
there's a cheat sheet for almost
anything you can think of I was the
original author of the forgot password
cheat sheet which is up here somewhere
but this has been an effort by a lot of
smart apps like people it's like a great
place to go especially for developers to
reference specific topics all right so
let's dive into the proactive controls
I'm going to go in reverse order here so
we're going to start with control number
10 which is air and exception handling
so what's the purpose behind this well
it's probably pretty obvious but it's to
prevent disclosure of any kind of
technical information that could help
attackers and it doesn't necessarily
have to be technical information about
infrastructure I mean although things
like stack traces being returned to the
user and a browser that's also that's
very helpful to know what software is
running on the server maybe you can
attack it but it's also related to
things like application specific data
account enumeration is the big one like
when you have a login page in a web app
it shouldn't be disclosing whether or
not the username that was tried is a
valid username it should just be a
generic error message so that's if it
does if it does disclose whether it's a
valid user name then you're talking
about account enumeration so that's a
type of error message that needs to be
thought of during the design and
development phase so you want to you
know be very careful in error messages
that are returned to users they need to
be very generic and their handling
mechanism should really be centralized
you don't want to have each developer
roll their own type of exception
handling it's better to have a
centralized mechanism for that and you
know if there are errors you can
certainly log the details of the air for
debugging or troubleshooting but
should log that on a server side and you
know associate some sort of a reference
number to that and then you can display
the reference number to the user so they
could report that as an error and then
you know if you look up the details on
the server side but you shouldn't really
be exposing that information to users
I have contested applications where the
developers tried to do that where they
tried to hide the debugging int or the
stack traces in the HTML an HTML comment
so you don't really see the air looking
at the webpage but if you do view source
on the page you can see the whole stack
trace doesn't really work that's not the
idea all right I'm going to move on
control number nine which is leverage
security frameworks and libraries so the
important thing here is that any kind of
web development framework or a platform
that developers are using there's going
to be security features within that
platform or that framework so why not
take advantage of them it doesn't cost
anything
typically it's just a configuration flag
or maybe a few lines of code
so you get this security for free in
your application not a lot of extra work
some examples of this would be things
like anti cross-site request forgery
tokens you know there's a all kind of
PHP Ruby on Rails Java patchy struts
they all have ways to prevent cross-site
request forgery by implementing a token
within the in the forms also air
handling mechanisms we just talked about
configuration is available for handling
unexpected errors session timeouts is
another one any kind of web session
should timeout after a certain amount of
inactivity that's all configurable in
the frameworks cookie configuration this
is very easy it raises the bar for
attackers but making sure your cookies
are marked with secure making sure
they're marked with HTTP only if there's
any sensitive data being stored in that
cookie which hopefully it's not but if
you need to do that you should be
encrypting the contents of the cookie
output encoding a lot of the frameworks
when you're writing an HTML page it
automatically will encode the output to
prevent cross-site scripting and ORM
would be object relational mapping so
that's a sequel injection defense many
of the development frameworks provide
that out of the box and you can be if so
or you know hibernate would be one you
can be protected against sequel
injection there's also a third-party
libraries so maybe your native
development platform doesn't have what
you need there are third-party security
libraries you can add to the application
that may
have some of the features that you need
this is some examples here Shiro is a an
authorization framework to four
different you know permissions enforcing
permissions on user role different users
and their roles and Allah is another
library from a lost called isapi so
these are all available and could be
used as needed there is one big caveat
to this though frameworks and libraries
themselves can have vulnerabilities and
when they do and they're announced it
can often set people to scrambling so
some recent examples would be patchy
struts stress had some remote code
execution vulnerabilities well over many
years they could occasionally have this
happen so it seems to be never-ending
but just about a month ago it had some
very serious remote code execution
vulnerabilities and struts to framework
so a lot of our customers were
scrambling to get those patched and
trying to use our product to scan to
find it they had this vulnerability so
you got to be vigilant about the
advisories know what you're using so be
familiar with what's in your environment
and you can use another Olas tool for
that it's called dependency check that's
a free tool you can download it will
scan your analyze your application at
the code level and determine what
libraries are using so you can know what
you have I'm going to move on to control
number eight now which is implement
logging and intrusion detection so this
is a talk about logging first so logging
is a security point of view is not just
about debugging there should be some
logs in place to help understand when
and how your application is being
attacked this is kind of similar to the
a7 insufficient attack protection that I
showed in the regular top-10 the new
regular top-10 so remember these are
proactive controls we're not talking
about risk here we're saying these are
the things that developers should
actively think about on every
development project just to make more
secure applications in the end so with
logging it provides a lot of benefits
not just knowing when and how you're
being attacked but if you do get
attacked you can be alerted some sort of
monitoring can be set up if something
happens where you get breached there may
be some forensics information available
to help with the logging that you do so
when the logging is done you really
should you know list a timestamp when it
occurred the event that type the source
IP and the user ID if needed a user ID
associated with that and then you can
essentially as you're developing
application the developers know where
the important pieces are so you can use
that as a guide to know what to log and
where to log it and how much to love and
as usual you want to avoid logging
sensitive data you don't want to have to
have credit card numbers or passwords in
your logs so think about that also log
injection there's a type of
vulnerability called log injection where
a user can enter a carriage return line
feed for example and then basically fake
login puts in the logs so that's
important to avoid you want to validate
the data and code the data prevent the
log injection vulnerabilities and then
there is again a cheat sheet for logging
so that is helpful so all these cheat
sheets are supporting these proactive
controls now the intrusion detection
piece of this is kind of interesting
I once Penn tested a web application
that it was very frustrating as a pen
tester because every time I would try to
tamper with data in the request to see
if I could elicit some sort of exploit
of a cross-site scripting or sequel
injection or anything like that the
application would log me out and so and
it would kill me it would kill my
session so I would have to start over
again and I always to this day I mean
that was probably eight years ago
to this day I remember thinking you know
if all applications did pass that would
make it much more difficult for the web
app hackers out there because it's just
you can't methodically go through and
test this thing because you keep getting
killed your session keeps getting killed
so that's the idea a no-loss app sensor
is a way to implement this kind of
functionality it's built for sensing
when there might be an attack and then
basically taking some sort of action
whether that's killing a session or
something else maybe just logging but
App Center is a way to implement this
kind of intrusion detection within your
web application so where would you use
this so there's a couple examples are
three examples I have up here one would
be if your application receives input
that comes from a drop down menu in the
web page but the input received is not
one of the choices in the drop down menu
okay well a normal user that would never
happen but someone testing your
application or maybe trying to look for
weaknesses is going to try to exploit
that by sending in different data for
that particular parameter so that's a
clue that maybe this application is
being attacked by this user and so you
could block that or a killer session or
do something else similarly if you have
a non numeric input on an input field
maybe you have Java Script or your
JavaScript framework in the browser
enforces numeric values or digits but
suddenly you start your application on
the server side starts getting input
that's not numeric it's another clue
that there may be an attack or at least
a pen test going on and then also a
hidden input field so sometimes HTML
forms dozens and dozens of hidden input
fields in them again normal user those
values would never change the whatever
the value is it's going to come in to
the server that way but if the value
start coming in differently even if it's
not just you know sequel injection
attacks strings maybe it's just regular
data but that was different than set by
the application that's another clue that
you could be under attack
control number seven is protect data so
that's pretty pretty generic sounding
right so what does that mean
well it means a lot of different things
to be honest one of the most obvious is
encryption of data encryption of data at
rest encryption of data in transit in
transit of course we're talking about
TLS HTTPS type of communication it's
required for untrusted networks over the
Internet PCI for example requires that
to be done but you should also maybe
consider this encryption for internal
traffic as well you know we know that
you know Google and and Microsoft and
other companies like that once the NSA
revelations came out they started
encrypting their internal traffic in
their data centers so that's something
that you should consider as well
encrypting data at rest very very easy
sounding but not so easy in practice you
want to make sure understand what data
needs to be encrypted
you want to use vetted algorithms you
know peer reviewed crypto libraries all
these things are important you don't
want to roll your own crypto solutions
and then the key management aspect of it
is also huge because you have to make
sure your keys are not hard-coded
exposed rotated so forth there's another
cheat sheet for this of course this is
just kind of scratching the surface of
that topic some other aspects
protecting data that may not be as
obvious as encryption is storing
passwords securely the chichi for that
because you don't want to use symmetric
encryption for storing passwords pass
password storage shouldn't be reversible
which symmetric encryption allows also
protecting data means avoiding sensitive
data appearing in cookies URLs browsers
and html5 local storage so before html5
the only way a server-side web app could
store data and on a client-side was
really through cookies or something
fancy like flash cookies but with html5
there's a whole framework around servers
being able to store data on the client
side
that's called html5 local storage so you
have to be careful on you're not storing
anything sensitive in in that location
log files on the server temp files even
memory on the server PCI doesn't like to
have credit card numbers and things in a
memory on the server so there's ways to
kind of clean that out and then mobile
devices mobile apps haven't really
talked much about mobile apps yet but a
lot of these same proactive controls
apply to mobile apps as well obviously
you can store data on a mobile device
not recommended and you have to be
careful with that so you're not exposing
that data implement access controls all
right so control number six is
implementing access controls so what
we're really talking about here is
authorization authorization of course
different than authentication
authorization is enforcing permissions
on entities that have already been
authenticated so you need to have access
controls to avoid things like horizontal
and vertical privilege escalation force
browsing attacks things like that so in
the proactive controls document which
you can download on the website
they make it really clear that the
design of the model of authorization and
access control should really be designed
at the outset of the project it's really
difficult to bolt on an authorization
model after it's already been developed
it becomes spaghetti code and often in
that scenario so best practices they're
really to route all your requests
through a centralized security check and
do a default deny so that if the no
information is provided then access
should not be granted and then you have
to check and I know we do this in our
claws product but you have to check the
action that the user is trying to do is
one checked and easy to be done but also
the object being acted upon you need to
make sure that the user has permission
for that particular object so on some
code here examples the the
recommendation is to enforce separately
the access control decision from the
actual decision-making process in other
words let's say you have a method called
has access every user object has a
method called has access that's per and
then you pass in the particular action
being requested
so that's preferred over the second
model here where you're basically
checking the user role every single time
so in this case the access control
decision-making happens and it has
access method whereas here it's all
happening in one place the decision of
whether or not to allow and the
enforcement is happening together here
with this model it's much more
maintainable you know code audit
auditing is much easier with this with
this first model control
five is implement identity and
authentication controls so similar to
access controls then now we're talking
about authentication so this is more
broad than that though because
authentication is more than just
username and password please
authenticate me it also encompasses
session management password storage and
complexity and forgot password
functionality which is something near
and dear to my heart since I wrote the
cheat sheet on that but now each one of
these is like whole topic I mean an hour
long talk in itself so it's just kind of
scratching the surface for example just
picking session management all kinds of
best practices proactive steps you can
do in your application to make sure that
session management is secure for example
don't store or excuse me you should
store the session token in a cookie you
shouldn't store it in a URL for example
you don't want to expose session tokens
in URLs you got to make sure the token
is chris cryptographically strong you
need to have an inactivity timeout also
absolute timeout so one of the things
that Google does for example is you may
be logged in to your to your Gmail but
maybe once a month or something
it forces you to log in again and supply
your credentials so that's an absolute
timeout and it's something that it's the
best practice saying ok I know that you
have a valid token but you've been this
token has been existing for you know
like a month so now it's I'm going to
actually time you out and you have to
log in again another best practice for
session management is creating a new
session token when you log in so the
idea is that maybe somebody was able to
compromise your session token and hijack
your session prior to authentication and
then once you log in they've got access
to your account if you take the step in
your web app to generate a new token
upon successful login and invalidate the
previous one you're going to be
protected against
kind of attack and there's cookie
attributes around session management it
needs to be secure HTTP on the same site
same site you may not be familiar with
that's a new attribute of a cookie that
browsers are just starting now to
support chrome being the first one same
site is an attribute of a cookie that's
going to quash cross-site request
forgery so you're going to start to see
that probably show up in assessment
reports where a cookie is missing the
same site attribute so wanted to mention
that since that's new and everyone may
not have be familiar control number for
validate all inputs so this is probably
kind of a no-brainer
I think everyone's familiar with
validating inputs you know any data that
a user can influence in any way needs to
be validated so it's not just visible
inputs on a web page it's really
anything in the HTTP request whether
that's in the body of the request that
URL the headers anything in that can be
forged or tampered with so it needs to
be validated there's a concept of
syntactic validation which is
essentially you know does the format of
the data match what I expect so it's a
10 digit account number is the data
actually 10 digits that I receive as
input so that's a syntactic validation
then there's semantic validation which
is is that meaningful for the user so
that kind of goes relates to what I was
saying earlier like is the action being
requested is that actually valid for
that user so that's um you need to
validate that that request is permitted
for the object that's being acted upon
that's semantics validation can anyone
tell me what type of data validation
this is
he's on a unicycle by the way this is
blacklisting this is blacklisting input
validation and so he's flown right by no
problems so types of validating data is
a blacklisting approach better than
nothing but again there may be you may
have forgotten something so you can get
around it
whitelisting much more secure usually if
you can use regular expressions that's a
great way to do whitelisting data
validation and it's the most secure way
to do it also you've got to do the input
validation on the server side you can't
expect something in the browser that's
validating your data to help with
security now there's nothing wrong with
it you can certainly validate data on
the client-side in the browser but again
it doesn't know that doesn't do anything
for security that can be bypassed very
easily you know just use an HTTP proxy
like burp or zap or something like that
oh and now I also keep in mind that just
because data has been validated
thoroughly rigorous rigorously validated
it doesn't mean it's safe so you know a
single tick or an apostrophe and a name
that's a valid character you know for
O'Reilly and names like that but it's
also a dangerous character because it
could can you know lead to sequel
injection so keep that in mind
validating data hugely important but not
necessarily the end-all as far as
meaning the data is safe to use so the
next step in making sure data is safe to
use would be in code data so that's
control number three and so this is
going to give you powerful protection
against many attacks especially
cross-site scripting this is where the
data is converted to an equivalent form
that's no longer dangerous for the
targeted interpreter whether the
interpreter is a browser or a database
or encode this
characters that appear within the data I
need to encode it at least for
cross-site scripting need to encode that
data just as it's added to the HTML so
that's called output encoding it's
pretty tricky though on there's
different types of coding a lot of
different types of encoding some
examples just in the browser world or
the HTML world would be regular HTML
encoding and so I put some examples of
that down here this is HTML encoding
that's different than URL encoding URL
encoding is different if your data is
going into a URL you need to use URL
encoding it's also different than
JavaScript escaping JavaScript escaping
it's all different syntax so it's not
easy and there's libraries to help with
this encoding so developers don't make
mistakes
Oh wasp have some libraries and coding
libraries to help with that a lot of the
frameworks or platforms that developers
are using have these built-in encoding
libraries but if they don't do the
encoding then you could be vulnerable so
that's why this proactive control is so
high on the list we're up to number-3
now last thing is don't forget that
mobile apps back to mobile apps they use
a what's called a webview so that's
essentially a web page in the mobile app
itself and so you can still have the
cross-site scripting issues within a
webview and a mobile app so you have to
remember that if your mobile app
developers are doing that all right
we're down to the top two now or up to
control number two which is
parameterised queries and so the purpose
is to prevent sequel injection I'm sure
most of you have seen this comic for
Mexique ad but it's it's the Bobby
table's little Bobby tables strip so
there's one thing that's not right
though it's a great it's a great very
famous but I crossed out this part about
I hope I hope you've learned
to sanitize your database inputs because
that's not how you stop cross-site
scripting so in this example across the
ice could sorry sequel injection you
don't say you don't stop sequel
injection by sanitizing inputs you stop
it by parameterizing queries so I love
this comic but it's unfortunately not
quite right technically so I think the
best way to illustrate parameterizing
queries is with a code example so I have
some Java code here and we have a couple
of inputs coming into the application
from the HTTP request we have a new name
parameter and we have an ID parameter
and those get stuffed into a couple
variables a string variable and an
integer variable and then string
concatenation on the third line is being
used to build a sequel query and so this
is this is the very insecure part the
new name variable and the ID variable
are not trusted they're coming in from
the user in an HTTP request and so if
they are crafted if that data is crafted
in just such a way the user can modify
the sequel query and do nefarious things
so this is really the heart of sequel
injection here it's the string
concatenation code so let's look at a
equivalent in with using parameterised
queries and so again this is Java so in
the Java world we want to use a an
object called preparedstatement so in
this case we still have inputs coming in
new name and ID and they're still added
to a couple variables new name and ID
however the big difference here is that
a prepared statement is instantiated
here and a string is passed in called
update employees set name equals
question mark where ID equals question
mark so this is the this is where the
query is getting parameterised in other
words the parameters are the name and
the ID and so that's the question mark
the question mark are basically
placeholders for the actual data
the last two lines you see that the
placeholders are getting set to the
actual values using a set string and a
set int call so the the one simply the
one here are set string that just is
referring to the first question mark and
the two on the set int is referring to
the second question mark and that's
pretty much it your honor percent
protected against sequel injection here
because essentially the statement is
fixed and can't be changed the only
thing that can be changed as the data in
the question mark the placeholders so
that's parameterizing queries and
there's equivalent in the.net world on
the PHP world is equivalent statements
parameterizing queries is kind of a
generic way to say build your sequel
statements securely alright so the
number one proactive control so I'm
doing on time getting close here is
verify for security early and often so
this is talking about testing make
security testing an integral part of
your software engineering practice
there's different approaches to testing
you do manual testing dynamic scans
static code analysis they're all
complimentary and all valid testing
approaches and complimentary in many
ways as far as what to test for no OWASP
has a guide called the application
security verification standard which is
the ASVs
that's a really great document along
with proactive controls I highly
recommend the ASVs it's a guide for
saying what do you test if you don't
know what to test for if you don't know
what vulnerabilities I should know about
the ASVs has all that for you
really good document works well with the
proactive controls too and so another
recommendation is automate control
automate the scans so manual testing is
expensive it takes time you can't get
through you may have thousands of web
apps or any kind of applications they
need to be tested so you should automate
you know leverage api's leverage
scanning tools integrate with yours
GIC Siddhi develop environment so get
the scans automated as much as possible
so challenges for this control even
though it's number one control there are
challenges including modern web app
technologies micro service architectures
which make static analysis much more
difficult because static analysis works
great with a monolithic application
where all the code is there you can
track the data flow through the
application with micro services is much
harder for static analysis to do that
pentester costly testing can slow down
deployments make things slow down in
general you need specialized skills as
as a manual pen tester you do need to
act to know how to do that that's a
specialized skill which leads to why
it's expensive new types of
vulnerabilities are being discovered I
mean just for last month you know I
mentioned the struts more recently for
the beginning of this year there is a
PHP serialization vulnerability like the
bug bounty security researchers looking
at the the pornhub website at twenty
thousand dollar bounty for this PHP D
serialization vulnerability all these
things are coming out throughout the
year so you have to keep up with them
and that leads to a problem with testing
coverage so my only pitchfork Wallace
here is that we do have a tool to help
with that we have a cloud-based scalable
solution is a dynamic testing tool full
API for automating scans scheduling
scans so you can help get the coverage
and testing that you need so anyway i'm
wrap up here the the proactive controls
I just listed them here again as a
summary but if you do opt in adopt these
controls most likely you can stand
around and smile like these people so
these that's the goal anyway and so
final word is you know what's going on
with proactive controls in terms of
future development so like I said I've
already talked to the
America's the prime of the proactive
controls which you can download here
they have an update coming this year and
so interesting Lee I have I'm going to
be in contact with them talk to them for
this talk I have some ideas I wanted to
to throw into the proactive controls but
I actually recommend it as far as
developer centric type of lists it's
much better than the Oh lost top-10
especially with the new controversy
going on right now we don't know what's
going to go on with the Google loss top
ten document over the years helped to
raise awareness it's really an awareness
document whereas this is more of a you
know practical guide with a real solid
advice for development teams and that's
all I had thank you everybody
sure
[Applause]