three o'clock on a Friday and there's
beer somewhere around here so my
apologies for standing between you and
you and the weekend really excited about
about being here and having this time to
share with you we have a pretty
fantastic panel here today I do notice
the panel the the table is quite a bit
shorter than yesterday so not sure what
happened there but here we have winning
either Wendy now there's a principal
security strategies for do security
Chris burrows this chief information
security officer for Oakland County we
have Jeffrey the director of security
operations for Jackson national life and
Martin Valley who is the VP and chief
security officer for Diebold Nixdorf in
Cleveland Ohio so it came all the way up
here to hang out with us today so thanks
Martin and thanks thanks all the rest of
you over for over from gr Wendy where do
you live when he came up from Austin
Texas oh she she actually gets the prize
for being being uh being here from the
farthest so you know before you get
started my name's Dave Glenn I'm the VP
and not a chief business development
officer for creative breakthrough CBI
we're a cybersecurity consulting company
and one of the things we're one of the
one of the I don't know platinum diamond
whatever sponsors for this for converged
this year and and in the last couple of
years one of the things that I
constantly look at and that we
constantly fight within our organization
is how do we figure out how to how to
fill the knowledge gap how do we how do
we help people being able to not just be
great technicians and technologists but
also be able to build those soft skills
that help them engage from a
consultative perspective with with
organizations and it's so important I
was an engineer for 15 years before I
came over to the dark side of sales and
business development and one of the
things that I always tried to understand
is how what is my business trying to do
and then try to figure out how
technology impacts that and I think I
think that's the panel that we had
yesterday I think I think sort of spoke
to that and really trying to take this
one step further how do we fill that
skills gap and that knowledge gap one of
the interesting statistics that I've
heard recently is there are about 65,000
open
Rex in the United States for requiring
CSS PS as one of the credentials how
many how many active see Isis fees do
you guys think there are in the u.s.
seventy 3021 or something like that 75
320 on something like that around 75,000
so you got a figure that some of those
see Isis most those CSS fees are
employed or don't need jobs so when you
think about that that's an incredible
knowledge gap and the other thing that's
happening Martin why don't you share
with me what you were talking about with
[Music]
China and and and how they're turning
out engineers I just looked ok I just
want to make sure the story so I was
having a conversation with actually
friend of mine over at Ford and we're
talking about China actually in the next
five years they expect to the total
amount of people that will graduate with
an engineering degree in China would
would exceed the whole population in
United States in the next five years now
mining not in the next five years are
going to graduate 330 million it's going
to be current today and plus added on
within the next five years so that's
kind of what we have to compete against
right from a cyber security perspective
so it's not just it's not just about the
knowledge gap it's about it's about
being competitive globally and we
already we already know that the US has
fallen behind from an educational
perspective if we want to continue to be
a intellectual leader in the in a global
economy we really need to be careful
that we are we are paying attention not
just to not just to how many people were
graduating and how we're making that
happen but how well we're keeping ahead
of things however we keeping track of
things it takes people that like to
break things sometimes to the building's
back up again and to in to build we're
going to be moving forward so I think I
think I'm going to start with start with
Wendy Wendy when we were talking about
questions to ask on this panel I had to
I had a kind of a cool question I want
to start on to start this off with with
Wendy what's the worst or weirdest thing
you've ever seen somebody do in a job
interview oh this is going to be cool
so somebody showed up to an interview
stone
and he was really seriously stoned
because my deputy used to work as an a
drug and alcohol counselor in the US
Army so he knew how to spot these things
he leaned over and said yeah he don't he
also said we asked him why he was
interested in the position and he said
well so that I have to it so so many
times in a week so that I can keep my
unemployment cheques coming and he was
very open about that so we were like
okay thanks for coming in wow you got it
you got to appreciate someone's
dedication for something like that right
but put a little put a little bit of
that into actually working for a living
so we're going to talk about today
thanks Lyndee what we're going to talk
about today is really from two from two
perspectives from an employer
perspective how do you continue to
motivate employees but I think more
importantly for what we're talking about
today is how do we how do we grow as as
as employees how do we grow as people
and begin to be better impact both on
the companies that we work for be able
to enhance our careers that's something
we were just talking about on the hall
and that is how do we continue to mentor
the next generation of people that come
behind and do what we do so Chris when
you're when you're recruiting what are
some of the key characteristics you look
for in an employee or a team member so
the number one thing is passion to learn
I've just recently built a team from
zero to four over the last two years one
was a mainframe programmer one was a
helpdesk manager for helpdesk analyst
the other was a middleware person who
did iis and the last one was external to
the county and worked on as a helpdesk
manager none of them had security
background but they all want to learn
they all want to get better
they all had passion to figure out how
things are put together and wanted to
find out ways of advancing their career
they all had passion to me and that was
the thing I can teach them technology or
I could have send them somewhere to be
taught technology and since then the one
gentleman who's been
only on the team for two years is
already gone and got for certain from
fans because that was one of the
motivating factors was I will provide
you the training to get better on this
team and so all four have been receptive
we've done career development plans for
them all but they all showed passion
they all want to get better and learn
because I said the day you stop learning
the day you're not going to be in
information security anymore that's
right and arguably the day stop learning
is based up start dying right
guidon you know so one of the things
that we look for and by the way we're
also hiring a duo we're hiring a lot so
stop by one of the things we look for is
very specifically empathy if you can't
understand and empathize with what your
users or what your customers are trying
to do you're not going to be of any use
to them if you think of security more as
a service organization unless as a
control organization you're going to
interact a lot better with people and in
return they're going to interact with
you they're going to come back and say
you know this didn't really work for me
but I really appreciate if you could do
this instead or if you're a C so they'll
come back to you and say I think there's
something you ought to know and that's
the most useful thing you can do so you
know building those relationships with
people and the ability to build
relationships not to run off on your own
and go break everything that's what's
most important so thank you
jump on that one - absolutely empathy
and I would say character as well you
know because if you if you get members
on your team that don't play well with
others you really don't have a team you
have a group right you have a bunch of
individuals that are doing individual
things only when you have someone with
empathy and character that's going to
make the rest of the team around them
better then you know the product of
whatever it is you're doing whether it's
identity management or sauk operations
it doesn't matter it's it's going to be
better and especially we know this
security is high pressure and having
people with a lot of character you know
and empathy and being able to handle
that pressure it was really important
because those are the instances with
senior leadership that are most
memorable when you have a team that that
can handle the pressure you know you can
tend to shine no thanks Jeff and they
sort of a continuation of that maybe
maybe Martin you can start on this and
then if the rest you want to I want to
feedback on this at all I'm one of the
things that that Chris just talked about
that if I was interesting is that the
team that he built he built those skills
within within that within that team he
took people that were very IT savvy to
begin with and were in had passion and
were ready to learn and he helped them
build their skills help help mentor them
build their skills up on that so so
Martin when you're hiring or evaluating
a team I know you've done both you've
taken over teams that you didn't build
and you built teams yourself on what
skills and characteristics are most
important to you in hiring or recruiting
employees so are you so skills from
individuals that I'm looking at yeah
absolutely yeah I would say it depends
on the role right and I think they
touched on some those three elements
that were just discussed are very
important I think that the fourth is
really the ability to actually to teach
other individuals right because when
you're talking about a team it's about
knowledge sharing right because in a
team one individual can't be like the
go-to person all-time right because then
you're gonna have to cover vacations
when that person leaves or what have you
and maybe if how does that person get
advanced right so if you think you by
you being the expert in a certain area
right you're actually going to
pigeonhole yourself because you're going
to lock yourself in when you're not
going to advance so I think it's key we
look for individuals that wanna share
knowledge that can actually take
constructive criticism and learn from
that grow I think for myself I'm always
hard on myself you know I always feel
like I can improve I always and that
drive helps I do the same thing with my
direct reports they push it down at a
certain level right we want to put too
much stress on people but it's always
this continuous improvement cycle right
and how can we get better how can we
share knowledge I will be more optimized
I think that that's one of the key
things we look for you know and the
culture fit at it so so anyone else from
the panel can answer that but also how
do you grow those soft skills anybody
grow or mentor that
um well one of the realest thing that
really works well I find his example
leading by example you know when you are
in an organization where people are
looking after each other and asking
after each other and saying how can I
help out it rubs off on you and you
start learning but that's you know the
that's the type of behavior that gets
rewarded
contrariwise if you see some behavior
that the company does not want you know
you better make sure that you're
addressing it instead of just kind of
letting it go from a from a technical
skills perspective I've grown people
from you know no technical background
and no security background you know all
the way into certain branches of
security I had somebody who worked for
me as an executive assistant when I was
in working in the UK because at my level
you were supposed to have an assistant
and I said she's really too good to be
doing this and I put her in charge of my
access control group and now she you
know runs a large security department at
Standard Chartered Bank so you know when
people have that raw talent and you see
that and you give them the opportunity
and the support you know they will just
take off so yes we look for technical
skills you know for certain types of
things and but on the other hand it's
also very important to make room for
people who haven't come up in the usual
way I mean I'm a liberal arts college
dropout I didn't have any computer
classes so you just never know who's
going to be a really good security
person and you got to keep your mind
open and look for them yeah I'm not too
sure so I'm a huge fan of career
development for people because like most
of us we didn't really have bosses that
did career development for us so we want
to make the next generation better so
constant feedback and ask them what they
want to do because yes they have to get
their job done but everyone wants to get
better most people want to get better
some just want to sit there and those
are the ones that you have to manage but
most people finding out what their
strengths are we've run a campaign the
last two organization that I've been at
called strengths finder 2.0 and it's a
phenomenal assessment a half-hour
assessment it tells you the five
greatest strengths for that person
what you do is you leverage those
strengths rather than focus on all their
weaknesses because we get them those
skills because I don't like to do them
usually
so I've matrix entire organizations and
when a project comes up you look at who
is the futuristic thinker oh it's Rob
let's give that task to Rob oh it's
sandy
sandy is a developer so she wants to do
that kind of development work
give her a pet project to work on this
development project or make her the lead
on the project and let her shine so I
meet with my team often every couple
weeks about particular things that
they're working on do they like it
what's good what's bad and every quarter
we sit down with their IDP and we review
their mentoring tasks their technical
assignments or learning we do this thing
called learning every day
so I tell them every day go online learn
something share with your team share
with me because if you're not learning
we're going the other direction so I'm a
big proponent of learning and leveraging
their skills rather than bringing up all
their weaknesses I'm writing that down
every day go online learn something I
think that's cool share what I'm saying
I would like to add to that just you
know is you know you have to do it for
both from the top down you have to hit
from the bottom up also so like for
myself when I first went to Diebold I've
probably over 100 employees about 65 our
core cybersecurity people right and I
made it I scheduled a lunch with every
one of my employees do one-on-ones right
everyone to kind of get let them know
kind of what I felt a little bit of
input from them so that at least I knew
that I was interested and then with my
direct reports
I cannot said okay I need to mentor
these guys but not necessarily me
because it might not be honest right I'm
a boss they won't tell me everything and
it's funny because I've Chris's on here
and I had Chris mentor one of my direct
reports I'm sorry I set them up with
people where I felt they needed some
strengths and some of just peers that I
work with and paired them up and just
ongoing mentoring or what have you and
it's totally to whatever level they want
to take it right so if I see an
individual actually one of my direct
reports is nicknamed negan so for those
of you who watch Walking Dead because
he's that type of individual right so I
said hey you need to kind of
Alex yourself up so I paired them up
with a/c so that you know that can kind
of round them out in that way so I think
from the bottom up and from the top down
right so I focused on my direct reports
and talked to each one of my associates
directly so going back to something
Wendy said about the liberal arts
studies I majored in English modern
communications that I'd never sell
anything number working technology so I
don't I don't know how I got here but
but you know when you think about that
there's a three part question that I'm
going to ask that I'm gonna let you guys
go to it number one is what are the core
technical skills that you think and I
know this is a really broad thing we're
talking about information security and
cyber security data protection here what
are some of the core technical skills
that you look for in people what are
your what do you think are the most
valuable industry certifications and
then my last question is what what is
what's a college degree worth today so
let's start let's start with that let's
actually start a little bit backwards
here what what certifications do what
technical skills and certifications you
guys think are most important just
generally from a cyber security
perspective there's some people out here
that maybe don't have any certs and want
to go at certs or maybe you need to
develop new skills and are trying to
trying to move into that what what
advice would you give on that Jeff Riva
can you start that this was cuz say so
the certs are very this P is all about
knowledge right do you do know how to
answer the questions across all the
domains if you look at sans or the other
technical certs those are helping you
build skills I would say knowledge you
can acquire much more easily than you
can skills get the skills if you have to
choose between getting skills and
getting a degree get the skills
absolutely thanks good not saying don't
go to school it's a driving school all
that is necessary yeah I would say the
number one cert or skill set is ethical
hacking because if you know how to break
it you know how to defend it I I could
care less if you have a degree or our
note or you have a master's degree I've
got all waves on my small team and
they're both very good at what they do
recently we made a change to say people
on my team you don't need a degree
which was very hard to do at the county
at the a particular level but I showed
them that there's a person on the team
that doesn't have a degree but has eight
years experience and he's just as good
as they're better with the guy with an
advanced degree in his role so to me
experience and technical skills from how
to break things because then you learn
how to fix them
can you teach someone to be a hacker
sorry that's a philosophical question
never I'm not done that to that okay so
I'm going to disagree with just about
everything I like I said I am I'm was a
liberal arts major I dropped out I had a
CISSP once I let it lapse I went through
the same thing when I work for the state
of Texas convincing them that I did not
need to hire somebody who had a college
degree if I could prove through a hiring
matrix that they had the type of skills
I was looking for I did hire a lot of
former system administrators because I
believe that you need to understand how
something works in order to be able to
secure it I don't agree that if you if
you know how to break it you know how to
fix it because I know a lot of really
useless breakers were like how can you
not have this patched and they have
never worked in the real world and
seeing all of the different jury rigged
systems that we have to deal with every
day so building is very very hard to do
that's a that's a real talent that we
have to look for but also being you know
pragmatic and as I as I mentioned
empathy so now in terms of what duo is
looking for you know that's probably up
to the hiring managers I don't have much
visibility into that yet but I would say
get a good mix of hands-on work building
something fixing something running
something responding to things the
longer you do things the more things
break and you have to fix them the more
you learn about how they work so just
having that experience under your belt
if you're a student right now if you can
get internships and I understand that
paid
eight internships are only for people
who don't eat money so this that's a
very limiting factor but see if you can
volunteer in places even volunteering
for conferences like this where you're
helping to run operations that all looks
good on a resume where you've gone out
and tried to help people thank you learn
just like that I think everybody's
correct here and you know when you think
of security it depends on how you define
it so you have your like your governance
risk and compliance right and that stuff
you have to be really tuned to the
business you have like strategy and
architecture where you have to build
things right then your operations teams
are going to focus on more technical
skills right so it's a mix of everything
it depends on how your security
organization looks like I think from a
college degree perspective you know
because it's difficult to get good
talent and because of the lack of
individuals you know your organization
adjust requirements you know for us
right now
that used to be four year degree we're
really laxed on that now right because
there's a need and there's a demand
endures and capacity out there right now
I think I think it's interesting an
observation that I would have is that I
think that we've we've done two things
we've said that we'll hire people now in
at least from what we do we'll say that
we'll hire people now that that don't
have a four-year degree we also say we
also know from statistically in the
marketplace just a just a college degree
doesn't matter in a lot of in a lot of
industries now you have to get an
advanced degree if you want to teach you
have to get an advanced degree if you
wanted you know many many things require
an advanced degree if you take if you
take that route and I'm certainly not
advocating for one way or the other I'm
just saying that there there are many
paths or something like that sorry I
wasn't trained is unwise yeah um if I
could jump in on this yeah so a lot of
different skills needed in a lot of
different roles
don't be generic don't try to have a
little bit of every skill I would say
all interviews come down to one question
what can you contribute yeah and the
answer to that is based on what your
strengths are what your passion is you
only have to be good at the things that
you have strengths in and there will be
a role for that right teams need to have
a variety of skill sets so don't try to
have a little bit of every skill set but
just know what it is that you want to do
is your contribution and then when you
interview
make sure you're also interviewing your
boss and that you have a boss that's
going to continue to make your role
bigger so that you don't outgrow it
right you should interview them as well
and make sure that that as you continue
to advance your skills it's still going
to be a challenge for you and it's still
going to be interesting and motivating
thanks Jeff I'm so I'm an African I'm
going to ask one more question here and
then I'm gonna I'm on before you get a
job and then I'll talk a little bit
about employee development skills
training and stuff like that but um what
do you what do you look for in a resume
like what are the things that stand out
to you in a resume what are Dee's what
are don'ts are there anything that if
you see a resume and you're like oh man
I'm not going to hire that guy or you
see a resume you're like perfect I'm
bringing you in right now and hire right
away you think anything jump out at you
in that way yeah that's first shutter
plus if you don't know how to spell the
name of your company I'm not going to
hire you promise if you call yourself a
thought leader
no don't anything anything that you that
is generally a compliment that some you
would say about somebody else if you try
to say about it about yourself it just
comes out completely wrong and so yeah
if you if you quite lay claim to a lot
of buzzwords I'm I don't think you're
going to have the temperament good
friend of mine in Atlanta has a it's a
cybersecurity bingo that he has you know
you know you know this guy I'm talking
about but he you know he say cloud if
you say best practice if you say thought
leadership yeah you're pretty much say
five of those things everybody says
bingo and pushes the eject button and
you fly out the window what else guys
yeah I was just going to say that has to
be a completely air free because in
security you have to be right 100% of
the time 100% of the time I mean you
have layers most people so you have
layers of Defense and people catch it if
you're not on a percent of time because
those human error right but in your
resume you're in complete control of it
that should be locked down 100% with the
right skill sets that you can actually
do there's been lots of resumes that you
can tell within five minutes of a
conversation that they're lying don't
lie I mean if you're not
ready for that job don't put it on a
resume because the person interviewing
you will know in five minutes yeah and
before Martin jumps in here if you don't
have good written communication skills
and asked you for a sample of writing
hey don't lie to me because I'll figure
it out but but at least have some if you
know I'm a stickler for stuff like that
and and and I think every employer it's
um it's some to some extent is but you
know in a stickler for something like
that have somebody you have somebody
look at your work have someone you have
somebody else look at your resume you
know sometimes sometimes you have this I
can't spell the word separate they're
there these things there are these
things that are little there are little
glitches in our minds if you know you
have something like that I always have
people look at my documentation not
because I'm a great writer but someone
of these and that people look at my
documentation is I have those little
little glitches little quirks that I
always make and and I can't recognize
them and myself have somebody check your
work oh my god yeah I know I'd say you
know just to go on that is I have a neat
little tool grammarly right it embeds
right in Outlook and airing it so it's
kind of another tool that kind of takes
over for spelling but checks grammar and
everything gives you different
suggestions that's it take a look at it
I purchased it for my son he's in
college I said hey this is a great tool
now that he has a license I use it on my
my laptop so it helps but um you know if
you look at the resume thing I think you
know if you're putting down that you
these achievements right I look to see
if you know what value the business
receives them from those achievements
right so if you know why you implemented
and let's say some system or something
what was the accomplishment what value
the business got back and you illustrate
why you know you did this and this is
the return that the business got on it
that that helps right in the specific
roles right for managers and things
that's those are the things I look for
and from a technical perspective one of
the the probably most creative thing
I've seen is we were looking for a
security operation center analyst and he
wrote that he he automated himself out
of a job right that he created all these
scripts and did all this stuff and that
was real creative it kind of stuck out
right and so those are the combination
of things right so it really depends on
the job right if you're looking for
technical things you know technical role
you know those things that stick out
right but I'll tell you could have
versions of your resume for different
jobs right you're not just have one
resume eager to apply for every job for
because you can't illustrate all the
success that you've had over your career
right so you're going to certain things
for certain roles you're going to tie up
those those accomplishments for the net
version of the resume for that position
and you haven't you know spin off of
that majesty is totally different
there's you know there's certain things
you want to point out for each position
that would directly relate you know to
that job you're applying for
cool thanks yes so one other thing that
I look for is leadership in your resume
did you go above and beyond what you
would normally be expected to do did you
volunteer for your church did you
volunteer for your neighbourhood are you
the subdivision chair or whatever you
can still talk about those things those
to me those are important because it's
about character it's about helping
people and that's kind of the business
that we're in we're in there to help
people great thanks guys another
important tip is that tailor your resume
to the job that you're applying for one
of these reasons is that especially in
security because requirements are still
very non standardized when I would have
to hire and you know people would sue
the state for any reason if they were
not hired for something I had to be very
careful and very literal in writing down
what I was looking for and if they
didn't have the exact same words on the
resume that matched what I have in other
words if I said I needed somebody who
you know had Linux experience and they
wrote down that they had Ubuntu
experience I would have to explain to
the HR person no really it's the same
thing so it's really better if somebody
says you know five years of this
experience and you've got that write
down five years of that experience
because it makes it easy as a when I'm
reviewing resumes to be able to say yep
check check check instead of having to
interpret it anytime you have to start
interpreting a resume you get into this
gray area where you may have to defend
your hiring choice later yeah thank you
we're going to we're going to move into
it into and into a little different
category we're not going to talk about
skills development before I go on
there are any questions from the
audience you have any questions for our
panel so think about that and if you if
you have something raise your hand and
I'll call me I promise I'll look up once
in a while um so so my next Skills
Development thing first we're going to
talk we're gonna wear to conference
right now so what are what are the best
meetups conferences on club one nation's
perfect what are some of those best
things to to attend converge obviously I
found the capture the flag or the
technical folks are awesome because you
can make your own team or you can sit by
yourself and it's you against your
adversaries you get a chance to play
around with different technology and you
can basically learn from everybody else
around you typically people are friendly
I know they're competitive but in a
competitive in a in a friendly spirit
I'm not sure how the one is going here
but the ones I've been involved in over
the last three or four years I've
learned probably more by the guy sitting
next to me than I have the whole year of
studying up different technology also
networking events I probably get the
most benefit in the hallway at these
events because of all the people that I
get a chance to talk to how are you
doing this who are using for this
practice how did it turn out I mean it
could save me six months of time - no
don't use vendor B but go with a because
of whatever they're doing for me and as
C so as any position right your time is
scarce and you want to come to market
with whatever product you're looking to
get as soon as possible so what about my
sec besides you know jerk on Derby con
Burke on DEFCON blackhat I saw kaya say
like if there's an alphabet soup of that
Jeff what do you think about stuff like
that any anything that's going to be
hands-on anything that's going to be
technical anything that's got you
writing notes and command-line switches
before they flip to the next slide
because you don't want to wait until the
slides are made available any of that
stuff is good if it feeds your passion
and it makes you more effective
what you want to do and help you
benchmark against others that are
leaders in the field you know those are
those are great events to be at just one
of the only people that I know that
actually carries a notebook with him and
writes notes on things I can tell when
you're engaged as you're writing notes
Martin you have anything any conferences
anything I mean I think those are all
good ones right and I would even say you
know if you want to learn you know my
youngest son he's he's probably the most
tech-savvy kid that I have right and he
likes to self learn so I he goes out on
YouTube and he looks at the videos and
does stuff I mean he's learned a program
on his own right and that that's the
kind of Drive that you look for from
individuals that if there's this
curiosity he's like if you know he's a
sponge and he has any questions
he just searches on his own right and if
he finds the answer on his own easy to
retain it right it's a lot easier to you
know if somebody tells him answer it's
more likely to forget it so I think
everyone has a different element to them
right and how they learn it I mean from
but to answer your question I think all
those events are goods you need to kind
of build relationships and I would say
even the physical ones right and I would
say even online I gave one of my
analysts second he was asking me my
opinion I said you know I learned on IRC
right I went on IRC to go back out there
so watch all the good reports can you
they're probably on barge and then you
know I said you ever heard of torso
climate or networks right and kind of
learned because he's interested in Intel
and some other things that said gotta go
out in the dark web you got to get some
mud on your earring you have to go out
in those areas where those people are
kind of learn so just be careful though
right it's a great segue into skills
development on what do you guys reading
where do you where do you ask people to
go where do you suggest people go and
maybe one day you can start start that
one what do you read blogs that you read
stuff that you watch what what how are
you learning that is now how do you
suggest other people learn you know it
really depends um honestly most time I
spend on Twitter because that's where I
get my news I mean I'm seeing stuff you
know before it goes to the regular sites
and that sort of thing
I guess because security is so wide and
varied and there's so many different
cultures I've just
encourage you to dip into different ones
if you go to an infra Guard meeting
you're going to meet all the people with
the short and tight haircuts it's going
to be a very different culture and
you're going to learn some very
interesting and important things that
you would not learn going to you know
DEFCON or spoke on so you know for if
you talk to retailers you're going to
see a very different culture if you talk
to people in healthcare education if you
talk to people in policy and privacy
work you're going to learn a lot of
different things so yeah just varied up
I can't you know if you start with with
the very well-known news blogs you know
I like blogs by like Brian Krebs and so
on start following what they link to and
then just start you know surfing and see
what you read you know whether you like
things that are about narratives they're
about issues whether you like really
technical stuff
whether you like places where you can
just download stuff yeah not paste in
but you know whether you really like you
know tool archives where you can go play
with them you know just kind of surf
around yeah so if you were in the panel
yesterday if you were in the if you
didn't on the panel yesterday one of the
things that I said is I'm what I'm
connected to Martin on LinkedIn one
things that I do he gets up at four
o'clock in the morning in you reads news
so I don't get up at four o'clock in the
morning get up at 5:00 and so five
o'clock in the morning i jump on
LinkedIn I'm like hey what's Martin
reading today I play and then I follow
that rabbit you know it's kind of rabbit
hole so I follow that till I have to go
to work and sometimes when I'm driving
but anyway good Chris I was going to say
if you're not following Martin connect
with him he's a good source I will use a
site dark reading it's pretty
interesting
it's very tech not that could be what's
the attacks was the policy changes it's
pretty up-to-date I've found any rogue
information on there but it's
information that I use to summarize and
then advise my boss and the county
executives about potential things that
are happening in the industry or in
other industries that we should be aware
of recent events from the news
definitely I'll tell you an example
there was a hack in December of LA
County and it affected 750,000 records
so I did a quick analysis to say if this
happened at Oakland County
what would our impact be and I analyzed
that against our cyber insurance policy
and said if this was were to happen to
us based on our current controls it
would cost us 10 million dollars out of
pocket today what do we do we got their
insurance policy two months later so
it's using current events in the news to
help analyze your position to put you in
a more risk adverse spot so it's stuff
that we do every day and it's only the
only reason we did that was because they
were watching the feed this happened to
our neighbor let's make sure it doesn't
happen to us that's a really cool idea
and I think I think for for those of us
that aren't see says that's something
that maybe if we were to do that first
if one of your employees had brought
that to you as a side project they would
have said hey I just saw this I just saw
this this breach this vulnerability or
whatever and they said this is this is
what I think the financial impact would
be to us would that would that be
something you would reward and I think
was great yeah yeah good sure yes I
think go and run on the original
question Twitter that may be more a
generational thing you know we did a lot
of interviews over the last I based on
the experience of a lot of interviews
over the past couple years that we did
what I found was a lot of because we
always ask people well what do you read
this day current and I'm very very
surprised that the the range of choices
but it seems like a lot of kids are
getting good stuff off of Reddit we have
thread Intel feed so that's where I get
most of my information other than crabs
of course but but read it seems to be
very popular very approachable and yeah
a good source to start with well thanks
Martin saves you for last because I
because I stock you and Google I'm not
yeah no no in that I said this yesterday
there's two there's two streams I call
not I mean one is for the executives
right so like there's for those either
where there's an attack going on last
ten hours about
forty-five thousand seventy four
countries about forty five hundred fifty
thousand ransomware attack I think I was
just reading is it so it's um so that is
something from CNN or ABC News or some
Wall Street Wall Street Journal some I
would take that forward it to executive
level no make sure our team is looking
at it whatever but I want to give them a
credible source right because that's
what they're looking at for me for all
they all the techie stuff it's like
hacker news another good ones register
the register UK they have some really
good stuff and I just felt a lot of
different things get them in all
different kind of feeds even Twitter I
subscribe to some of the the dumps right
from everything that gets dumped uh
overrun pastebin and everything outside
my team looks at that make sure that
there's no credentials that are relating
to organization that were in that dump a
lot of good feeds a lot of good sources
out there I mean I think you got to kind
of pick and choose but make sure the
source that if you're going to forward
it on and communicate again know your
audience so the executives I give them a
credible source something that they look
at for other news right for my staff
there's other stuff that we look at
thanks Martin sticking with you for a
second um we go to rewarding I'm six
minutes till the end here from a
compensation perspective there are some
tips when you're asking for a promotion
or pay increase and then on the flip
side of that yeah hopefully none of your
employees over watch this right now I'm
just kidding on the flip side of that
how do you how can you proactively
reward employees so that you're having
that conversation faster it's really
good you know and I think it goes back
to what Chris is saying is this career
development path is you have to sit down
and they have to know upfront kind of
what your plan is and you want to know
some input from them what their
expectation is right what do they want
to do that that in itself is also
rewarding individuals the compensation
wise from you know when you're talking
about salary I mean I think it's a
little difficult right because people
jump around right they're taking these
bumps and the one thing that we notice
is I'm going to look at your resume and
if you've been short short-lived and all
these different jobs I'm not going to
hire you the answer because I can't put
the time and money to invest and use
you if you're only going to be here six
eight one you know months or a year but
from I could tell you that if money is
an issue just I would say well part
honest I just had an individual that was
telling me came to me it kind of came up
to me and it was about he felt he was
being micromanage
right and I felt it was kind of
concerning and stuff so I kind of sat
down with one of my direct reports we
talked to the manager said hey just be a
little bit more creative this you know
kind of gives some guidance a week later
that person came up and said hey they
got a job offer it's 20 percent bump and
pay da da da I was so pissed off I said
listen you know if this was the what you
really wanted you should have told me
this first because I just spent a ton of
cycles you know kind of working with my
manager doing all this other stuff right
so if it's money just be upfront right
but I would say don't think because you
did one task or one good thing it's
worth right erase it isn't right
we're looking for longevity and I know
it's a little difficult so we try to
provide diversity right because people
are going to get bored like I got sake I
got 18 people that sit in the Security
Operations Center you know eyes on glass
I really get bored of that in here right
so we take certain of in drills we
rotate them out in different areas
depending on how big the organization is
what opportunities are but we try to
rotate people around given some
diversity but again just be honest right
and and I would say do some diligence
don't go look at some of these other
things on the internet see you know what
the salaries are because that's you guys
saying what your salary is a lot of
people just inflate that number to kind
of say look I'm worth 60,000 or 80,000
find out what the real reality is
because when we go to comp they pay for
services and they get the real the real
compensation in the market in the area
right so don't compare yourself to
somebody in New York or LA right take it
for your region Thanks there's a
question from the audience or comment
[Music]
Thanks so so for the audio thanks Brian
what are some of the lessons as managers
that you've learned in terms of
retention and what are some of the
failures and successes you've had when
not when retaining employees the comment
was that many times employees leave jobs
because of them because of their
managers not because they're the team
members they love their team members but
they got a manager they just can't live
with sorry go ahead
there's this great Japanese proverb he
works for you you work for him and
that's just a way that I approach
management you know when you invite
someone onto your team you're inviting
them to be you know you're part of their
journey over their career so from a
motivation perspective you know I try to
stay very engaged I do one-on-ones
regularly with my direct reports but I
also do skip level meetings you know
every single month and those skip level
meetings I'm not going to micromanage
the the manager who has the direct
reporting relationship but I want to
know what their career goals are and
just kind of get the temperature of
their engagement I was horrible as a
manager in my first time out you know
and and I made it a point to focus on
those things that I wasn't doing and
start doing them and it's if you have
care for your team and you care about
you know that person within your
organization growing and having a chance
to contribute and always being
challenged you know that helps a lot and
you know we've got to work with HR to to
get their levels up because they're
under pressure to keep the levels down
but you know you watch your team members
grill out of their roles and it starts
to get a little bit easier you know
because now we're starting to get into
into different levels but it's very much
mindfulness about your team and having
some care about what their strengths are
and what their aspirations are and just
staying in tune and that's what I didn't
do when I started and when you interview
make sure that you're getting this
feedback from whoever you're
interviewing with know that that
boss that you're going to sign up with
because you're going to be with them for
a while make sure they're actually good
that's great thanks Jeff Chris I was
going to say having a two-way feedback
is the most important thing because I've
left bosses that I didn't and it was I
didn't like because it was the boss but
if you're open and honest one nice thing
you could do if you can't change the
compensation you can put them on a
particular project you can say what are
you most interested in all we can pair
you up with the telecom team to work on
this new UCC project or you're going to
spend twenty percent of your time doing
X giving them something to do that
they're really interested in helps them
stay motivated and then being honest to
say I'm stuck this is your salary I want
to grow you but I can't grow you in the
pocketbook let's grow you in other ways
and ask them how you want to grow and
and if you actually listen and do what
they have asked then your relationship
is that much stronger thanks Lyndee a
couple things we talked earlier about
you know you working and sharing your
knowledge so that you're not the only
one who holds a particular X and type of
expertise if you can't be replaced then
you also cannot be promoted so it's very
important to you know if you can work
yourself out of your current your
position and take on you know as many or
and come up with new things that you can
do and you know and suggest that you be
allowed to do them because that's how
you work yourself into another position
a lot of times you have to prove that
you're already doing the job in order to
get that job it's not that you can say
oh now I want to go you know do this
other completely different thing and
they say ok and they send you over there
you know you need to be able to prove
that you're doing it the one thing that
I've seen particularly from older
employees is the attitude of well I've
been here the longest therefore I
deserve the promotion and it's like no
you're not actually that good at your
job so know that that's that's a really
difficult conversation to have and it's
to be honest it's not one that I've I've
been very good at so far
but it's as mentioned that there are
different ways to grow in your in your
job but sometimes your managers hands
are tied
I would say the most valuable things
that a manager ever did for me
are one to tell me what was keeping me
up to date on what they were working on
what was going on on their level so I
could understand the lay of the land at
their position and also tell me what I
needed still needed to learn what what
their estimations of you know growth
areas for me were so you know one of
them said to me you need more experience
in budget management so he put me on
that so the those that there are many
different ways to grow in again you just
have to have a good discussion with your
manager but it may be that your manager
says I'm sorry my hands are tied and my
estimation you haven't proven that you
can do the job the other job that you
want but if the manager is a good one
they'll say well let me help you
try to find another place where you can
be successful at that if that's what you
really want to do thanks Wendy I'm so
we've got we've got just two minutes
left for the panel here so I want to
quickly go when you can start on last
words and or kind of the most successful
technical resources build their skills
wrap that together with saying bide
where normally is goodbye as I was
saying to somebody earlier another
important thing is don't be honest and
be transparent but don't sell yourself
short
I know a lot of people both women and
men who you know say oh I'm only a
junior in this or you know I'm just
learning this lay out your skills as
objectively as you can and let the
employer decide whether that's junior or
senior talk about what you're interested
in they may say well you know I can
bring you in as a junior but you know
you have senior you know capabilities in
these areas and you could probably grow
into this in a couple of months just
don't go in there saying you know
deciding it keeps dying on me just don't
don't decide for the employer
you can and can't do don't prejudge or
predetermine the outcome before you go
in for the interview just be really
honest on what you know cool Chris again
building technical or building business
skills and or you know last words sure
so I would say practice practice
practice whether you're talking to
people communication although technology
is really important
nothing happens without proper
communication in our game you can be the
technical wizard but if you can't
communicate why you want this done it's
never going to get done so practice your
communication whether you're talking to
the the clerk at the grocery store or
you're talking to the CEO have that
30-second conversation ready to go when
the CEO sees you in the elevator and
says hey I'm so-and-so what do you do
here have that prepared the last thing
you want to do is be stuff well my boss
tells me it's and you never know when
that chance we're gonna have it could be
in the parking lot it could be at the
grocery store so be prepared and just
keep talking cool just to build business
skills I would say consume business
writing that's done at a very high level
so Wall Street Journal if you if you
like that
side of the aisle The Economist or
Financial Times if you'd rather have a
different perspective but I mean that's
what the senior leaders in the
organization are reading and when you
read what they read you'll be able to
relate to them I like it and and I just
like to say thank you for letting us be
a part of this panel I mean the resume
is only 25% of the process you know the
rest is networking and you know for me
this was an interview right you got a
chance to interview us and we had a
chance to see from your engagement you
know and start that process
well thanks quickly Merton said quickly
I had to either hire we handed you the
mic and I have say quickly Oh only two
things I think really what's important
for you guys is I would say you know
know the business whatever organization
work in you have to know what's the
driver how you generating revenue all
the different things the company does
right because from a security
perspective or IT whatever don't treat
yourself
as a cost center right you need to be
part of the business me to engage and
find out what each business function is
doing and you start with your peers at
those levels right understand those
things and it helps I think from an
interview perspective know be confident
but be respectful right I would say
because you don't be in there
overconfident but I would say don't be
too humble or don't feel intimidated
right because um you're selling yourself
short right I mean you want to be equal
player so thanks Martin thank you all
too for attending Martin Martin Jeff
Chris Scott's getting Chris and Wendy
thank you guys for being on the panel
guys these guys are all hiring if it's
something they said is interesting catch
them in the hall as you go out to the
left here we will be doing a drawing for
a prize at the CBI booth CBI secure comm
if you get a chance stick around in here
for user behavior analytics I think is
with Dan Gregory after this and thinks
everybody appreciate thanks for time
[Applause]