I last talked today yet Justin Herman to
talk about thanks so much
I don't think all of you guys are coming
down one of the last talk of the day is
sometimes difficult to get that energy
and push through but I promise you that
we get through this we can all head to
the bar and have a good time so a little
bit about me I am Justin organizer of
East Side Cleveland I'm also for the
board members of Northeast Ohio
information security forum call soma
Cleveland locks port previously have
been a sysadmin network engineer sis
administrator help desk a lot of red
side as our blue side and I'm currently
working as a red teamer with a barge
bank and very much of a hobbyist this
whole talk includes a lot of gifts and
memes of Ron Swanson so hopefully you
all enjoy kind of break up the monotony
so this talk is really focused to the
hoots are really intended to go to is a
blue teamers people with limited
resources you're in a company that
doesn't have a lot of maturity maybe
their security model and you willingness
to learn though and the desire to make
something better for tomorrow obviously
all of you guys have come to conference
and not only come to the blue team talk
so you'll usually fill in to a lot of
those categories I know that when I was
in the position of small and
organization I didn't have a lot of
resources or money or time I felt a lot
more like Sisyphus here than Hercules
every day going in feeling like you get
one step forward or two steps forward
and then three steps back constantly
pushing the rock up the hill but this
talk is focused on ways that I found and
the methods that I used in order to step
myself from just that person in the
corner who runs a little bit of the
network or the servers to a trusted
resource for management
and making those big the small wins real
fast and bring them to market so the
first question is how do we win
fast and if you're in the military or in
a paramilitary you'll hear a lot smooth
is fast
but fast may not wait may not always be
smooth and that's a real concept is that
you need to practice and repetition so
the functions that you do and I'll have
an organized method that you're going to
handle certain issues and as you work
out that process it comes second nature
it becomes your common language and you
start to adopt it in all aspects of the
way you carry yourself so where we start
is a particular domains and in my mind
and where we started it was I wanted to
deal with myself first the first thing
that I can handle in control is of
course myself the next is my domain that
might my actual craft whether that be
the network side or in point control or
server administration or anything other
aspects of those particular domains next
to my Department of an IT team whether
it be the blue side and red side if
there was some personnel there or
management tying them in to my complete
department my company and then my
community as a whole and I want to work
through each one I'm going to talk about
ideas and concepts that we can kind of
bring to market and bring to bear that
we can improve upon so we're starting it
with course something you have most
control over which is yourself you need
to be able to create processes and those
processes need to be written and you
need to be able to follow those
processes throughout and you're going to
continue working on those you're going
to automate the crap out of everything
and that's the key thing you're going to
make good wins is by learning and
accepting that you need to automate and
create and work those processes
you're constantly to be able to learn
and you need to apply those lessons and
we rinse and repeat carrying it back
forward with creating processes and
movies they're there if you're willing
to do that to yourself and start looking
in different ways that you can apply
those particular steps you're going to
find that you have success and you're
going to find that you are able to move
that he'll move up that hill a little
bit faster move that rock up and feel a
lot more secure in your environment so
in written processes you need a document
I know everybody hates it
everybody hates to document it doesn't
come the second nature to a lot of us
but you do need to start to do it and
you just need a document what you do and
what you know we have a saying
Myron ization currently is that you
might get hit by the lottery bus and if
you were to take a sudden windfall or
get injured or just decide to walk out
you need to be able to have some sort of
idea that you could hand off to the
person they could pick back up and know
exactly what you're intending to do in
the future
what are your upcoming concerns how you
perform the actions that you perform on
a day to day process and basis I
encourage everybody to keep a pen and
paper with you at all times I don't know
if you guys know about they field notes
but everywhere I go I always carry one
jot down ideas and it may not always be
full complete sentences but it's just
something to always remind yourself I'm
a big encouragement of sending
confirmation emails if I get a response
we spoke about something over meeting or
in person or even over the phone I'll
shoot an email back and say hey this is
what we spoke about just want to confirm
that we're all on the same page we're
gonna go ahead and authorize the
purchase of X Y & Z or we're going to go
ahead so you're going to take the day
off or whatever the case is you need to
become the note taker in the room you
need to be the person who is aware of
your domain and you know yourself and
you need you accountable to that and of
course the ticketing system I know in
some organizations some little bit
stronger on that once you in on the
entire IT department they will have a
great acceptance of the ticketing
environment and other ones you know
that's what the help desk does they
write tickets we don't need to worry
about tickets even in the senior
positions and when you're working with
technology still need to write those
tickets write down what you did write
down your thoughts write double your
findings are because you're going to
forget it we work in such a fast-paced
environment and the technology
continually changes right past us they
you know you something you
might have learned or memorized or
thought that you would know perfectly a
month ago and now you can't remember
heads or tails of it I know it happens
to me and I'm sure it happens to all of
you so working beyond ourself and once
we've we've kind of worked on those
ideas we want to move on to our domain I
want to get our house in order and so
this is for you know our network admins
and our server admins and then pointed
mends and everyone else that's kind of
that blue team side and you don't have a
lot of support in your environment your
organization doesn't have a red team it
doesn't have a tiger team it doesn't
have a budget for a sim it doesn't have
budget for anything that you go and you
would wish for for pie-in-the-sky but
there's lots of things that you can do
either on a very very low budget with
you know desktop old desktop hardware
that might be around with automation
with scripting with functions that allow
you to keep your environment secure with
the limited amount of resources that you
have available so as a network
administrator you know you want to be
documenting out all of the ACLs and know
exactly what each one is doing and why
they were implemented and when do you
intend to go back and recheck and
reverse and look at those purposes do
they still hold should we still begin
maintaining all these particular rules
or can we simplify them can we condense
them down can we eliminate some because
particular products are no longer on the
market in our environment you know you
need to understand about why particular
VLANs are in place I've walked into
organizations that when I worked for an
MS SP and they couldn't tell you what
these particular VLANs were doing they
couldn't tell you why the a cells exists
or why these rules were there and there
was no documentation anywhere so instead
you're constantly looking around trying
to think well if I remove this I might
break XY and Z and this is not this
technical environment technology we
should not be like that we need to be
able to bring to bear the fact that you
know what is happening though to
communicate that with not only our
teammates ourselves and also people the
future down the line so the network
administrator also knowing about your
inventory understanding version control
and configuration management all of
these things are simple things that
don't require a dollars worth
of cost for you to purchase a new
product to go to deal with that these
things can be done through automation of
pulling out configurations and running a
back script to pull that out there
through SSH sessions or just Excel
documents and server administrators you
know understanding your application
stacks what's required for different
dependencies the different particularly
user groups and why they exist the lines
of business that a particular
application is using and and what the
purposes in the organization is very
important to be able to bring the
concept that you that you understand
what you're delivering to the end-users
and I mean it end point administrators
and that comes back to help part of the
help desk if you're there is
understanding your inventory how many
machines are out there but what
applications are commonly used you know
you may not have control to be able to
lock down every aspect every point of
control that may be in place but if you
understand at least what should be
whitelisted you can then have an idea to
move the ball forward in the future that
if new program comes forward and you
haven't heard of it before then now you
need to be able to research you need to
bring that to the rest of the team and
kind of work format so I was encouraged
people to you know identify the
low-hanging fruit before you go and ask
for budgets if you're able to to get
those low hanging fruit solve those
particular problems eliminate a certain
number of to pick them a metric and
reduce that and that metric could be you
know by your own design you know you
could say the number of infections and
Mosel to reduce that by only permitting
certain applications in Iran or limiting
local administrator access or you know
whatever particular metric you want to
leverage if you're able to actually
quantify that and then keep that and
record it as a win for yourself and
maybe not even announce that to
management just yet when you're coming
to the table but you're going to be
bringing an understanding of where you
were and where you are now and where you
might want to go in the future
it's going to allow you to be able to
show your impact and you can then people
log that information so one core thing
about that I think it's an amazing tool
that all of us can use that you know
from the lowliest low person to all the
way up to the senior and management is
actually to be able to automate you know
you have the power a lot of us to run
with PowerShell and Python bash and
Windows bash if you're into VB or you're
into any other programming languages it
really doesn't matter a lot of the
actions that you perform repetitively
throughout our day can be automated and
they should be automated you need to
take the time to address that if you
perform an action multiple times a week
you should be automating that because
then it removes the problem the
possibility of creating error in your
process you are able to think about it
systematically from start to finish what
needs to be executed in case you haven't
fully flushed out that process because
programmatically you're going to need to
have that in place and you can really
you know help yourself so we saw some
ideas for automating you know that I
would look into you know kind of
takeaways that you guys might be
interested in it you know finding stale
ad objects you want be able to you could
easily run that there PowerShell look
for a get ad request and look for users
that haven't logged in in a long period
of time they're right for disabling or
computer objects that haven't checked
into the main in over you know six
months are they really be in place
should they be disabled you know looking
at group memberships as someone joins
the domain admins this jump someone
joined the local admins group if someone
joined the helpdesk group and that
haven't had a new employee and joined
the company if that's the case you
should be throwing off red flags you
know maybe that's not even to a full
send maybe that's just you an email your
email address comes back and it sends
you alert says hey there's a new group
membership these there are there are
sample scripts that are available out
there and I've got a few on my github
repository but you know it's very simple
a few lines of PowerShell and you can be
able to have a lot of these problems
salty knows we're doing again scripting
out repetitive tasks for network alarm
ends us alerting you know service
interruption or a nominee detection or
if you see a huge spike on traffic you
know you may not have a lot of tools to
be able to dynamically control all that
environment but you can at least get
yourself an alert you can at least make
yourself aware and if that aware or
being aware of it may not even be until
the next day you're still ahead of the
game versus if you didn't have any
alerting at all configuration backups
again something very simple a lot of
organizations and mature organizations
have that but in immature organizations
they've just been running with you know
they call on the IT person they may get
something working once they have working
it's a-okay and that they don't think
about it ever again they're not saving
and and sharing that the config across
the environment of course endpoint
admin's comes back to configuration
automation knowing what your environment
should look like you know there's a lot
of tools that are out there that are
available to augment some of these
automation and that includes you know
local administrator controls loading the
local administrator password is either
using ships or laps one of them is a
available on microsoft technet one of
the other one is from trusted sec you
can set up user password change
reminders helping the end user remind
them if their pastures going to be
coming up do for expiration we not me
now think of that it's a security
control but as much as we can help the
end users understand why we're bringing
certain things lighting what's expected
of them you're going to have a lot less
groans and moans at all I didn't know
that I had to change our password it
it's locked out and you could leverage
that particular concept as a metric and
bring it to light to say hey you know we
were able to reduce the number of calls
in the environment because we put this
one little simple email that went out a
crown granularity you know looking at
breaking it part your own account you
know if you walked into an immature
environment you may find everyone's a
domain admin Oh
or everyone's a local administrator or
everyone from the IT department is the
domain admin or schema admins or
Enterprise admins and none of them need
to really be part of that and even in
you as the top administrator of an
environment don't need to be part of the
schema mental s you're making schema
changes you shouldn't be part of groups
that you don't need to be unless it's
directly proportional for your job at
the task that you're handling right then
so separating out your own account with
a low privilege Scout that you maybe
make your email with a next-level
account which which would handle you
know server controls next one up that
might handle domain controls and maybe
even break that out where you have an
intermediate which would live your local
administrator of certain machines there
is the standard technical implementation
guide that's available that is used by
the DoD they've excellent concepts and
ideas and gives you hints and ways that
you can even roll certain GPO settings
out that can seriously improve your your
configuration
I wouldn't recommend rolling them all
out all at once or not testing them an
environment because some of them are
fairly hard and can break some
historical applications cannot work them
there so you know immature organizations
also commonly forget about you know
having wsus or Windows Update servers
they simply rely on the users input to
update machines if you were to rule out
a wsus system you know they're going to
get faster updates and you could
programmatically have it happen at night
when they're not thinking about their
their updating process and said it just
continually works and you've got a
similar configuration between all of the
machines log management big big concern
I've stepped in too many organizations
and they don't have any sort of controls
that will permit you to to store or
record those even ad logs that's just
system you know sort of system and
configuration and security logs
it's simple to set up a gray log or a
log stash environment and that can be
ran on basic hardware if you're just
talking about a few dozen domain
controllers if you're just talking about
those particular logs and even if you
only store them for good 30 days and
then chuck the old ones it still gives
you a look-back period that you may not
have had if you are at a you know you
weren't aggregating those particular
logs together windows logs windows
forwarding for you know service logs are
completely available and then it's free
and built into the Windows server and
you can ship those logs back to an
independent Windows server if you if you
so desire another thing is by
aggregating all of those logs together
and bringing it to a particular
environment where you could look at into
single pane whether that be log stash or
gravano or whatever whatever flavor that
you want osm from there you can actually
gain some insight you could build alerts
off of those you see a lot of failed
attempts you now know you need to you
know figure out why that's occurring a
what end point that's that's happening
from and why users even the basics why
is the users account getting locked out
what machine is it coming from what part
of the network you know comes a lot of
hand handy to help end users out I would
highly recommend if you don't have one
already is to have a change log email
just create an email address box on your
own system and when you make a
configuration change just shoot an email
to it it's a great way that you can have
a store achill look back if you don't
have a formalized change request
environment setup and you're you're kind
of rolling this all on your own
you send a quick message allows you to
be able to look back and say okay why
did I why did I up this system to have
additional resources Oh and six months
ago I did do that and now I see I've got
to do it again three months from now and
again another three months you can see
the growth rates that are occurring a
particular environment another thing
that's really great of automation is
employee education we have an amazing
amount of technical skill that we carry
with us and that the end users
barely understand you know they
understand how to get their applications
that they need to work with they might
understand how to hop on the web and and
see you know Facebook YouTube or
whatever their social environment is but
we know a lot more on how to be safe
what you should be looking out for even
at your home when you're banking a lot
of organizations they have a way to send
an email to all the users or they have a
a mailing list or they've got a
newsletter offer to write a little
article there it doesn't take much you
can spend a little paragraph of a little
keeping it safe and you know send that
out and you're going to build trust and
when you start building trust you're
going to build influence so next fortune
you want to continue working on and I
think developing and building wins as it
is in your department I think very often
we gets very siloed and our concepts we
we only I only work on servers so I
don't really care of on the networking
team or I only work on servers so I
don't think about the end pointer I'm
only on in point why do I care about the
networking team or I'm only on this
similar tool efening I don't care about
any of those other guys we need to
collaborate we need to share ideas we
need to go to bounce off ideas off of
each other in organizations that are
smaller like this that may not have a
whole large team you don't have a lot of
resources and there's a lot of
experience in your own department you
need be able to share and uplift and
support them they may have security
initiatives or concepts that they'd love
to do but they don't have the resources
due or they need a little bit more oomph
or or a cheerleader to behind be their
cheerleader be on their team build
friendship within your department that
you know just because the networking
team got an upgrade and got their
purchased for whatever their fancy new
project is doesn't mean that your
project is any less it just means that
the organization identified that is
having a little bit more value at the
moment and the next step may be yours
but if you work together and I'm not
trying to snipe at each other and
thinking well he got he got some so I
now need to have mine or all right I
didn't get it last time or any aspect
like that
really just tears you and the rest of
the team down and that's not something
you want to do so I encourage you know
keeping a change log sharing that
chainsaw out with other members so they
kind of understand where you're coming
for coming from some of the week
Department emails or weekly talks if you
don't get a chance to and that can be
formalized or informal where you're just
you know circled around and and talk it
over a water-cooler the company is the
next step that I would thinking he
should work on and that is once you've
talked once you've assisted with these
these issues and you've kind of built a
little bit of trust you want to listen
to where the departments in your
organization and where they're having
problems at how does your business make
money what is it what does it do what
does sally-ann accounting what is her
pain point how could how could you maybe
help her in her issue she always yes he
does manual tasks every time and she
doesn't know anything about automation
she doesn't know anything about you know
creating templates she she just barely
knows on half that she needs to put
these particular boxes and it needs to
look like this before she sips that
ships that document out we have a lot of
skill and understanding of how
technology works we can leverage that
and build trust with her and help the
organization and at the same time do it
in a secure manner a manner that we can
you know stand behind and we feel safe
on when we can document that entire
process so you know employee education
is a strong one in building that trust
building that leverage but you know work
full automation and document creation
are very simple things to do with with
both Python and PowerShell and you can
pull those out you know other people see
what we do as magic and you know the
wizards that you know just whenever we
come by it just fixes itself it always
works for us and the cases that we've
built up years of knowledge and we can
leverage that that alter that they're
putting us on to build trust that we're
not aloof to them that we want them to
help we want to make sure
business can succeed we also want to do
it securely and we want to be able to
you know have great technologists
available but we need to do at the
proper rate that the organization can
handle it so listening and respecting
and providing technical with technical
technical solutions and help and educate
or core things that need to be done in
order for you to be able to succeed in
your environment they don't take much
you can you can build start building
trust you know next week you don't have
to have a formalized plan or but just be
open and be willing to understand where
people are coming from listen to them as
human beings we need to give back as a
community after we've kind of felt
comfortable with all of those other
pushing to organization you need to
share solutions and resources that you
found and it doesn't mean that you need
to share confidential information or
applications that have been built on
company time I'm not suggesting anything
like that but there are aspects where
you found a resource that was available
out in the web you could tweet it hey I
found this cool kind of article that no
one else kind of mentioned this might be
helpful for someone else or write over
love about it or extend a pod put it on
a podcast or give talks or you know put
a YouTube or you know the meetup groups
it doesn't really matter as you share
cool and interesting concepts we need to
be willing to step out of our boundary
and say hey I learned something kind of
new I that I didn't know and it's a bit
scary when you start talking about
standing up in front of your community
and and sharing things because you
believe that well everybody else must
know this every motive buddy must tell
everyone else must know exactly out of
programming Fortran or how to write DB
code I mean this is this easy stuff they
should all probably know it but the fact
is that many of us don't have concepts
and a lot of the technologies that you
may have expert expert expertise in we
need to be able to willing to share and
humble ourselves and help others
understand what we're kind
from you know no one I've never heard a
single person come up and say hey I saw
this cool thing and then someone else
feels you know slight them for it and if
I ever saw something like that you'd
they would definitely get an earful
because that's not the community that we
want to share we want to share growth
and help so those are building these
small wins and improving our environment
and building recording these metrics we
can start to leverage trust and
influence we became more than just that
guy who comes in and checks back out
stays in the corner doesn't talk to
anybody else we instead turn into an
ally a person that you can they can draw
from in their organization you can then
use that influence to you know make
changes and make recommendations you're
able to start moving mountains things
that you didn't think that would be able
to be trusted or systems in place that
oh we've always done that in the past we
don't change anything that's not what
we've always done it this way you can
start trying to understand why that's
the case
and then proposing new options and
because you've built trust in smaller
projects and and and coming up with
solutions you're actually able to make
those issues occur so the great thing is
once you get part of this influence and
Trust you start getting questions like
like this we hey we've got you know X
number of dollars left over on a budget
which we kind of spend it on or we want
to give you time off the to want to give
you some extra staff to fix the issue
quickly because we know you can do it
but we want you to be able to get back
to what you you really love to do or you
know what train Ian's conferences are
you interested in this year these are
the exact same questions word-for-word
that I've had as I work through this
type of process and going from stage to
stage and in my career you start
building trust and you build clout in
preparation for this talk there was a
great book that kind of got recommended
to me and I
felt it was kind of applicable and I
wanted use this I guess as a podium and
speaking board to let you guys know
about it and I would encourage everybody
to kind of read it it's a very short
book it's called the go Giver
and it speaks about five different laws
that are important to you to be able to
have success and I found a variable
because you know they say the value
compensation influence authenticity and
reciprocity and you know working through
each one of those gives you an ability
to give back to other people which in
you know information technology or
information security we are here to give
back we're here to support the business
we're here to bring value you know some
people might find us as not being we're
just a cost center we just suck money
well we say is no but the point is that
we should bring to them solutions that
allow them to be able to work faster and
easier and more securely so you know in
value your true worth is determined by
how much more you give then you take
your compensation your income is
determined by how many people you serve
and how well you serve them we have an
amazing opportunity because we can touch
almost everybody in the organization and
serve them well and if we're able to
solve all a lot of their problems you
know we're gonna have a lot more value
in compensation the influence you have
amazing amount of influence because you
control we most jobs today require
technology and you're directly tied out
as an administrator you have a direct
influence them you can make their lives
easier you can make it harder you can
make it so they have to change the
password you know 40 times in a six
month period or you could make it so
they have to change it you know twice
but maybe it's a longer character set
there's ways to be able to make things
easy for the end user but still maintain
security authenticity the most valuable
gift you have to offer is yourself be
personable be a person you can people
can accompany a stew I'll be willing to
ask questions you know be able to get
out of your comfort zone
and then reciprocity you know the key to
effective giving is to stay open to
receiving be open to suggestions from
other people take lessons and learn from
them it's a great way to kind of build
your build your skills and so yeah in
closing I did of a github account which
with a lot of these tools that I had
mentioned available the scripts are all
available on there it's you can find it
through my key base and other than that
if you guys have any other questions
just kind of wrapped up quickly anyone
all right that is really awesome mm-hmm
yeah that's that's an amazing you know
followed by using the mouse and those
automation macro buttons that are
available I really didn't think about
that as applicable to your job but
that's that's really great
there was a quote I'm not sure exactly
it was an efficiency expert in the
Industrial Revolution and he would be
assigned to a particular company and he
would ask you know show me the person
that gets their job done but always
seems like they got a whole lot of extra
time on their hands first on that that
is doesn't look like they're always busy
always has extra time to give that extra
coffee or whatnot but still does all the
jobs are necessary and I've always kind
of thought about that and that brings
back to the automation finding the
fastest way to get your job done the way
you're supposed to do it the you you've
written you understand from top to
bottom
you've scripted it or you've got it a
handle that you can knock those out so
yeah yeah predict oh that guy from the
name on stand up here alright thank you
guys so much for come out
[Applause]