I need the microphone so cute oh yeah
okay for future generation indeed cool
so I want to talk about prediction but
more importantly this talk is about how
to use data to make decisions and how to
use data in the correct ways to make
decisions most of the things I'm going
to talk about are really simple ways to
use data most of you will have this kind
of data available at home and so there
are a lot of take-home exercise the
reader here as well but I want to talk
about the types of data-driven analysis
that you could do using different
streams of security data give you some
examples of each one and then in the
last part of the talk we'll do some
hands-on playing with machine learning
and specifically with an application of
machine learning that I hope will make
it make sense to everybody in the room
so for a bit of background I work at
Kenna security we are a vulnerability
and threat intelligence platform so we
use threat intelligence data but a
specific subset of it applied to
vulnerability data to measure risk and
more importantly to drive
decision-making for our customers and
the way that we do that is we use a
curated set of data namely successful
exploitation to measure the probability
that a particular vulnerability is
actually where do we get that data so we
have two repositories the first is all
of our customer data which is about five
years of about 7 million assets and
approaching a billion of vulnerabilities
that are live and open
across different types of infrastructure
so when people do vulnerability scan
circle other than esses what have you I
have that large pool of data to draw on
the second which is a completely
different data set is a data set about
vulnerabilities themselves and how
they're used globally not necessarily
across our customer base but across
security MMS fees that intelligence
providers providers like reversing labs
I see sandstorm Center we have a kind of
a back door into the owesome product for
alien vault so we get two things there
the first is if an IDs signature is
triggered and at the exact same time of
vulnerability is open on a system that
we know that that exploit that was
trying to target that machine probably
worked so to us that's a successful
exploitation event and those events
while no compromise may occur no data
was exfiltrated are what we use to train
our models about whether owner abilities
are risky or not the second type of
exploitation data we get is from
reversing labs which is essentially a
piece of malware was found on a system
and we know that that piece of malware
must have gotten in using this
particular attack vector this particular
vulnerability and then we know
approximately when that happens as well
so that's also a successful exploitation
again maybe that malware did nothing
probably not but we know how it got in
there we use bad data to Train risk
about vulnerabilities so that's what I'm
going to be using stop me at any time if
it's not clear from which data sets
different portions are coming because
that's important and keep in mind that
the two data sets are completely
different one is our customers we know
about those we know about the machines
the other is data we're getting from
across the internet and so those two
aren't necessarily related this is less
the science of more of an art but in
making some statements and some judgment
calls based on that kind of data to get
some useful insight so let's jump in
there are three types of approaches that
are data-driven in this world the first
is a retrospective analysis to see what
has happened and we report on and we try
to look at trends in the past or try to
analyze and rationalize it the second is
the real-time processing real-time
analysis that tells you right now this
is happening this is how it relates to
your entire infrastructure
well infrastructure is already too
specific and security centered but I
mean the kind of you know how many steps
are
i phone reporting and then the third and
the holy grail of many of our security
friends are predictions I would argue
that there is nothing in security today
that is predictive at all no two will
predict the future of a vulnerability of
an exploit of the state of your system
or of the state of your security the
state of the art today the best that we
do is we have some real-time analysis
whether it's capturing firewall logs or
trying to reverse malware we're trying
to prevent vulnerabilities or measure
their risk all of those tools are at
best here in our real time analysis and
reporting so we're going to take a
particular problem one that I'm very
familiar with because it is my day job
and we're going to try to make some
steps towards prediction in this problem
so by no means is this a product that we
sell or we use this is kind of a
skunkworks project and we're going to
try to issue forecasts about
vulnerabilities that'll be the
prediction and I'll talk through how to
set up that problem
how we try to solve it where we are and
where we hope to go let's start with the
beginning the problem that we try to
solve is that there are too many
vulnerabilities and we want to derive
risk from vulnerability in a data-driven
manner manner
there's tons of vulnerabilities out
there not all of them are risky and to
measure risk is to figure out the source
of the greatest risk which is not that
easy of a problem itself and if there
are three ways to do it so there's the
retrospective manner that one was done
decades ago well about a decade ago by
vulnerability scanning vendors by the
national vulnerability database and
mitre when they publish CDSs what that
did was it looked at all the types of
vulnerabilities that had existed in the
past and it said we can classify them
into a couple buckets things with low
access complexity medium access
complexity low authentication or no
authentication required or somewhat
education required they found these
facets that describe the past data and
then they looked at all of the things
that are occurred in the past and
they're still looking at it they're
still publishing CVS F sub vectors which
is a whole bunch of data about
vulnerabilities as well as scores that
they've created based on that historical
framework so this is all really useful
information to have about
vulnerabilities this is how you learn
from retrospective analysis but this
does very little to tell you about what
besides what this tells you is
information about how to measure
vulnerabilities not - how to measure
whether they are risky whether they're
going to be used by attackers and
whether or not you should be remediating
those are worried about them so enter a
real-time analysis which is where we
take a look at how those vulnerabilities
are actually being used in the wild and
this is why I talked about those two
datasets in the first place here are a
couple of mashups of this two datasets
that we've done and published in a bunch
of papers this comes from whatever we
publish them there's a couple in the
Verizon DBA are that we submitted data
to as well so if you take a look at what
attackers are exploiting what those
successful exploitations are and you try
to pare that to the live in the wild
population that we happen to have a
sample of because we're a vendor you
start to learn a few things
so what this graph shows you is I'm
going to make my presenter note smaller
so I can see it better so what this
graph shows you is essentially for every
vulnerability that was to be exploited
in 2015 how many days did it take for
that exploitation took her and so when
you aggregate that what you get is a
cumulative distribution function that
tells you after ten days if a
vulnerability was to be hit in the first
year since its release then what's the
probability that it was hit after ten
days and you know you go up from the
bottom of the graph and you see that
that probability is about 15%
interestingly enough you know add 365
days because of what we've chosen to
report on which is all blown their
abilities that have been hit within 365
days
you see that that number goes to 1 and
at 0 it's not necessarily 0 because you
know there's some probability that there
was a negative day attacker zero-day
attack and we only know about the
vulnerability after we've captured
something about its exploitation but
more importantly this graph gives you an
estimation of how quick attackers are to
exploit a vulnerability when they do go
after it and so you know you could say
that there's an inflection point here
which is why there's that gray line
behind it that gray line measures the
change between the dots it doesn't
actually tell you anything about the
information itself but that inflection
point is really useful because it tells
you that
that's probably where you should tap
your benchmark that's the part of which
looking more days like so if you were to
set a benchmark over attackers are X
days fast if you look further than that
inflection point you wouldn't be adding
anything to that policy because there's
a small variation small change there so
if we were to set a policy we would set
it somewhere around the 40 to 60 day
mark that's what this inflection point
occurs I'm pointing not to the slide but
so at that inflection point it's
probably about 40 to 60 days sense of
vulnerability is released at that point
the probability that a vulnerability has
been exploited is around 90% so if
you're going to get hit you're going to
get hit in the first forty to sixty days
now keep in mind this is an
overestimation of how fast attackers or
how slow attackers are that is to say
within the first forty days there's a
nonzero probability at every step within
ten days there's a 30% chance to get
exploited within twenty days there's a
50% chance we'll get exploited so that's
the upper bound on how slow they are
chances are within that bucket you're
still getting hit but if we take that
upper bound that we compare it to how
quickly we're remediating
vulnerabilities something becomes very
apparent we are slower or mediating
vulnerabilities than attackers are at
exploiting them commoner mediation rates
that we see are somewhere between 120
and 150 days sometimes there's like a
goldmine rush like with heartbleed where
people start remediated within 15 days
but for the most part it's hovers around
the 80 to 120 mark as an average monthly
for all of our customers and what that
tells you is that that is also a lower
bound essentially that's only talking
about the vulnerabilities that do in
fact get remediated and for every one
that does there's hundreds that still
remain open so if you were to think
about this as a process some kind of
half-life evolution then about a hundred
days is a good lower bound on how
quickly vulnerabilities are being
remediated if that's the lower bound for
defenders and the upper bound on how
fast attackers are is 40 to 60 days then
there's that gap between how quickly
your immediates something and how
quickly they exploit something so why
does that gap matter it matters because
if
is true that they are exploiting
something faster than we are remediating
it then what we remediate matters a
great deal because if we're not
remediating the exact things they're
exploiting then they have open gates
they have ways to break in and they do
common logic tells you you should
remediating that comes out and patch
tuesday or everything you're eating the
news or every critical vulnerability you
heard about last week but that's just
not true
if you look at the vulnerabilities so
this is a different breakdown this is
not a breakdown of the live
vulnerabilities this is a breakdown of
just the definitional level
vulnerabilities just the cv ease
themselves if you look at all of the
vulnerabilities that were successfully
used in an exploitation attempt in 2015
then only about 72 of them were
published in 2015
the rest were published maybe years
maybe a decade beforehand and so what
that tells you is if you're chasing the
patch Tuesdays you're exposing yourself
to attacks across a wide variety of
publication dates of vulnerabilities
that might be ten years old you know in
2006 or 2007 there were over a hundred
distinctive ulnar abilities that were
used in successful expectations if your
policy is patch Tuesday you missed those
and a lot of people did they missed
JBoss when it came out in 2016 and they
got exploited on an offer and so if
recency is not a good standard and this
is a good asite to think about why
recency isn't a good standard it's
because attackers need time to develop
an exploit and weaponize it and so
sometimes they will find a really
appealing vulnerability to write an
exploit for where they found that
exploit already and we just learned
about that vulnerabilities publication
but sometimes you know theory this is
something old they take a look at the
national vulnerability database just
like we do and think well that's 2005 :
durability I think I could write an
exploit for that and I should test it
and nobody's going to remediate it if I
start exploiting people on that
vulnerability and that happens all the
time those are the things that we miss
and those those things we need to be
focusing on so what's a better way to
focus rather than patch Tuesday and
that's by looking at a factor that
actually correlates to attacker
incentives so this is also a strange
bastardized metric but this is
essentially looking at
if you were to look at our sample size
which is about a billion live open of
vulnerabilities across seven million
assets and you were to randomly throw a
dart at a particular definition and
remediate that vulnerability what's the
probability is that the portion of the
population that you have remediated was
a portion of the population that would
have been exploited so if you pick a
random CVS s10 vulnerability and throw a
dart at it that's I want to say 27 and
28,000 vulnerabilities right now if you
pick one of those then the chance that
your remediating a portion of the
population so scaled to the existence of
those vulnerabilities is about eleven
and a half percent so one in ten times
you'll be remediating a vulnerability
that actually poses risk to your Ganesha
'nor actually would have led to
compromise if you just look at a random
variability in the exploit database
which is about 22,000 vulnerabilities to
that proof of concept exploit code some
of which works some of which doesn't
then that probability quickly jumps up
to 17 and a half percent and the reason
it does that is because it is easier for
an attacker to write an exploit and use
that exploit successfully if a
proof-of-concept code has been derived
for it if you look at Metasploit then
the probability jumps up to about twenty
seven and a half percent and if you look
at something that was first an exploit
DB and then an Metasploit so the
intersection of the two that probability
quickly jumps up to 36 percent so this
is your real time data driven analysis
of that problem right how do we derive
risk from vulnerability we look at what
it is that attackers are doing we try to
measure their behavior and in real time
we try to predict or not predict we try
to describe which will owner abilities
pose risk to us we do that by looking at
the live exploitation traffic that I
have what you can also look do it by
looking at your Splunk instances and
seeing which signatures are triggered on
which vulnerabilities you can look at it
and then derive a heuristic like
Metasploit and exploit DB or the types
of vulnerabilities that we need to care
about so that's how good that exercise
is useful because it informs us about
kind of what we should be describing
with our data meaning that hackers
themselves rather than vulnerabilities
but that answers the question in one
particular way a subset of the question
asked earlier is I have 10 million
vulnerabilities today which one should I
remediate
and that requires data-driven analysis
and thinking but the answer to that
question is widely known by industry
it's you remediate old ones that are
stable and have weaponized exploits
because that's the biggest chance of
compromise because just about anybody
can compromise you on them
but the more interesting question the
one that's not yet answered is if a
vulnerability comes out today and I
think about this Dean came out today do
we have to scramble or not like do we
care about that vulnerability does
oppose a wrister organization and all we
know about it is perhaps some of the
cbss vector like authentication
complexity whether it's remote code
execution or not let Steve ESS score for
lucky and maybe some metadata about that
vulnerability so can we use something to
make predictions about it the answer is
yes it's just kind of complicated so now
we enter the main portion of the talk
everything I talked about previously is
nice insight and it's useful information
but it's important to understand that
all of that data that I've used above
vulnerabilities is data that's available
and known about vulnerabilities way
after they are released so we use things
like IDs signature scanners or malware
sandboxes to reverse malware to find out
whether or not that vulnerability is
being used we have to measure its volume
and velocity we have to think about
whether or not double mobility actually
exists some systems all of that data
only exists after the vulnerability has
been released we need to think about
just the period of time when the
vulnerability has been released that
exact second and so enter machine
learning specifically though we need to
figure out a way to use machine learning
well and accurately because throwing all
of this data into a data lake and
thinking about it a not very useful be
there's not a lot of data to throw in if
you're talking about trying to predict
something for which you don't have data
at the time so the most important part
of this talk is trying to figure out
what it is that we want to predict what
it is that we want to do with machine
learning and my answer is this when a
vulnerability comes out the biggest risk
factor as we saw in the real time
analysis is whether or not it has an
exploit
for it and so let's do that let's just
predict when it exploit vulnerabilities
released will it have an exploit written
for it or not that's a binary
classification problem with very stable
machine learning methods that work for
it and that's the problem that if we do
solve if we issue a forecast or
probability of how likely a
vulnerability is to have an exploit if
something that we can use because we
already know that having an exploit is
indicative of risk by looking at that
past data by analyzing past exploitation
specifically we use Amazon machine
learning to do so anybody can log in and
throw some data in there and try to
figure out how it works and to get a
little nerdy we use a 70 30% evaluation
split we use all of the vulnerabilities
in the national vulnerability database
for which we have complete data which is
eighty one thousand vulnerabilities the
specific type of linear of support
vector machine that's used in Amazon Web
Services for this is a l2 regularizer so
it's a way in which it size coefficients
to different variables and you use that
one when you are trying to predict to
things that are very different so ur
ability but is exploited in a
vulnerability that it isn't I assume are
very different than x why we use that
one also because we used l1 and it's
substantially worse each model uses one
gigabyte of memory and it does 100
passes over the data and then we measure
the ROC so essentially the area under
the curve to try to figure out whether
that model is good or not let's dive in
really quick and then I'll explain what
this all means if you just import the
base data about a vulnerability the cbss
base the CVA system portal or mode code
whether it's a remote code execution or
not availability integrity
confidentiality authentication access
complexity access vector and the
publication date that's the base data
that you can get about a vulnerability
the second is released then you get a
really terrible model that means nothing
that model you know 80% of them are
correct but the problem with this model
is that there are a ton of true
negatives there are not that many true
positives if you think about the whole
data set being 81,000 vulnerabilities
and also evaluating 30% of it and 12% of
the records are predicted as one with
you know only some of those being
correct
more importantly it's really hard to
figure out at which point you got to cut
the model at which point you should set
your threshold where it's a meaningful
point because both exploited data and
unexploited data both exploited and
exploited vulnerabilities are clustered
together in this model so there's not a
lot of separation what do I mean by that
a good machine learning model looks like
this essentially you want to minimize
the shaded areas because the shaded
areas are where your model is incorrect
at classifying vulnerabilities one way
or the other and then you want to
maximize the yellow areas and the gray
areas the yellow ones are where you are
correct about vulnerabilities being you
say that something is exploited and it
is in fact exploited and the gray ones
are the opposite you say it's not going
to get an exploit and it never does to
put it more simply you know that's a bad
charge that's a good trip so graphically
as I add things to these models as we
try to get a good one think about it
this way we want to introduce separation
so that it's really obvious for us
visually or for machine to determine
where the right decision point is on
which side of the equation to the
exploits Ryan which side of the equation
to the non exploit vulnerabilities lie
so as we try to go through this there's
also something really important to think
about if I wanted to solve this problem
in a graduate class I would try to get a
really high percentage of correct
classifications and I would try to get
that 79 up to 90 but the reality of
security doesn't work that way
we don't they're different values and
there are different business risks to
classifying something as true positive
or a false positive and I would argue
that in our scenario really the only
thing we care about is maximizing the
number of true positives in the model
and I think that because let's think
about how this model is used if this
model was used to drive remediation and
fire off tickets to Giro or ServiceNow
and then have developer scramble then we
want it to be the most accurate model in
the world but in reality this is just an
early warning system all we want is we
want the system to fire off alerts for
as many of the actual exploits that will
get exploits possible and then we'll
feed that into a larger decision-making
calculus about the priority of the
application it's on
priority of the server's of that
vulnerability might be on other
information that we know about it and
the times when we have false positives
those don't matter all that much because
we have other data that will come out
days later telling us whether or not we
were right or not so if we miss
something hopefully the other data we
collect in our other decision-making
processes like whether or not it'll end
up the Metasploit or not well tell us
about it at the time when we would have
known otherwise if we're classifying it
as correctly something that is actually
if we're incorrectly classifying it as
something that's being exploited not
that big of a deal because it's still a
vulnerability and you still probably
need to remediate it but it would be
nice if the model was accurate so what
I'm trying to say is the correct answer
to this problem
the most correct mathematical
representation isn't necessarily the one
that is most useful in a security
organization to a security organization
the most useful thing is being correct
about the most number of vulnerabilities
at day zero that are going to be
exploited because for every one that
you're not thinking is going to get
exploit it and you're letting that lag
occur of 30 to 60 days until it ends up
in Metasploit until you measure it you
might have already been exploited
everything else we have other methods
and other systems already in place for
dealing with wave events in a response
we have vulnerability management we have
other data coming in so the cost of
those other kind of bad things in the
model that are assumed to be equally as
bad is greatly reduced by other systems
all right so let's walk through four
other models right now on all of these
models view is we add more information
and that information makes it stretches
out our curves which is nice because you
can graphically see it but it also adds
information about what attackers are
doing or how they're behaving in
relation to those vulnerabilities that
allows us to make the decision and
allows us to get some separation the
model we'll get at the end is not
perfect but it's substantially better at
doing the one thing we needed to which
is getting more true positives in the
system so first at day zero you know
whether attach exists or that
vulnerability or not so I think
attackers think about that too I imagine
that an attacker when they see a new
vulnerability in the national
vulnerability database stops and thinks
well if the patch already exists and
they're already patching it in the patch
they release what am I going to spend
effort to weeks writing an exploit for
that just that I can try to attack
already patch systems whereas if the
patch doesn't exist at the time of
release of vulnerability two things
might be happening the first is they
might have already risen to exploit and
it's a zero-day vulnerability and that's
the way that we discover that the
vulnerability exists or they might think
there's an economic incentive for me to
write this exploit because if I use it I
know that the systems that it affects
are unpatched so when we add that the
model stays just as accurate but we get
a little bit more true positives and you
can see it starting to stretch out it
right you can see that while there's
still a humongous amount of overlap
there's a subset of our data and it's
very clearly on the exploitation side
the stuff that has no overlap at all but
it's really spiky and it's hard to cut
off and I don't really know how to do
that it's going pretty bad model so we
had more data this is an interesting one
and I think perhaps the most important
one that we could add it's the only one
that gives us this kind of very explicit
separation very explicit inflection
point of which we should be cutting it
off if we add which vendors and which
products in effects we learn a whole
bunch of information about the way that
attackers think first off we all know
that Adobe and Java exploits are more
effective and more of them get written
so that's already information we're
incorporating it release at release time
that helps us understand whether or not
it'll get exploded or not second off the
products themselves matter a whole deal
because if it affects one microsoft
product verses it affects every single
one of the Microsoft suite there's a
greater incentive to writing an exploit
for that there's also a greater chance
that it's in a shared library so it's
easier to port that exploit to other
things and lastly if there are multiple
vendors that the vulnerability effects
you know it's a library vulnerability or
at least one that gets reused and so the
incentive for writing some of an exploit
for that is much greater and it's also
more likely to be a remote code
execution of some kind when we add that
the model accuracy spikes up but also we
vote from a thousand seven hundred to
two thousand two hundred vulnerabilities
classified correctly as being exploited
without losing any sensitivity
essentially the same amount or true
negatives we have the
about the same amount of false positives
and our recall so essentially our
ability to correctly classify things
that are actually being exploited jumps
up dramatically but still we're only
talking about you know 30 percent of
81,000 we're trying to classify 22,000
vulnerabilities and we're only correctly
classifying 2200 them as exploits that
doesn't seem right that doesn't seem
like the number of vulnerabilities that
you have exploits written for them so
we're going to try some more things this
one is interesting if I add the
description of the vulnerability as it's
written by NVD after mitre writes the
description under BD does some other
descriptive writing that description is
essentially the analysts write-up of
what it is that the vulnerability is and
sometimes that's really boring it means
nothing but other times they'll say
things like the mechanism of
exploitation something like this is a
buffer overflow in a shared sea library
or this is a remote code execution in
RDP protocol things like that things
that describe the actual method by which
one would exploit that vulnerability a
really descriptive of the actual effort
it takes to write some exploit code the
ones that require you like Ram scrape or
like even heartbleed where you have to
keep continuously looking at multiple
things and then decipher them and have
your own system for doing that those are
really complicated exploits to write the
incentives for writing them might be
high but you need to pair that off with
how hard it is to write that we use
engrams here so we essentially look at
either one word two or three or four
word pairs to capture those kinds of
terms as factors so one such term is
remote code execution highly indicative
of an exploit being written for it
another one is buffer overflow another
one is in multiple libraries there are
all sorts of these things that analysts
keep using and reusing what's really
interesting about this one is that CVE
or the national vulnerability database
is about to allow user submissions of
the descriptions and so Adobe Microsoft
all of the kind of cans are going to be
writing their own descriptions of the
vulnerabilities so will either going to
get much better data or we're going to
get inconsistent descriptions of the
vulnerabilities so this model might work
worse
but something to monitor over time model
gets better we're now classifying 2900
of the 22,000 exploits that we trying to
make a decision on as correctly having
an exploit and the overall number of
correct jumps up to 84% and so the last
thing I'm going to add is something that
is maybe cheating maybe not we're adding
two things which describe how prevalent
is that vulnerability and how much
people currently care about that
vulnerability which i think is the core
of what attackers think about when they
think about weaponizing exploits so
vulnerability prevalence I'm cheating
because we have this large repository of
vulnerability scans and we can just look
across their customer base and say you
know which systems is this vulnerability
affected a zero how many what percentage
of the population is it affect great the
submissive owner ability that matters
not everybody has access to this but I
would argue that if you just do it for
your own infrastructure and take a look
at the products do you have installed on
a number of machines and the proportion
of the population that is affected you
get a pretty good representation or the
very least you get one that's tailored
to you and then the second thing we look
at and this was probably the most
interesting one is the number of
references in the national vulnerability
database at the time of publication so
when the vulnerability comes out
sometimes you'll get something like
Adobe advisory here's the CV here's one
length to the Adobe advisory other times
like if you take a look at heartbleed or
shell shock or if you take a look at
some things that are do not have names
that are important for owner abilities
you'll see that everybody's scrambling
to write about them there might be a
tech net article about it there might be
a rapid7 post about it there's might be
a Qualis halfway or vulnerabilities post
about it because it was the most
critical thing that they found that week
the more of those references there are
it doesn't even matter where they come
from the more of them they are the more
predictive power you get because that
means that people think the
vulnerability is easy to exploit people
think you should be scrambling and
there's consensus on that scrambling and
it comes from verified sources so
there's a couple of studies that have
been done in the past at the University
of Maryland about using social media to
do this kind of prediction and that's
really susceptible to attacks by
the people there's now a CVE bot that
nvd maintains that just tweets every
single CVE
so if you're using something like mining
Twitter four CVEs but at least hugely
affected by that but this these are the
verified ones this is how you know that
lots of people who actually care and
write about these things are writing
about these things so when we add that
data in we finally get some serious
results 3,300 true positive
vulnerabilities out of the twenty to
twenty one thousand that we're trying to
classify number of true negatives is
about the same as it was when the model
was only 79 percent accurate and most
importantly twenty percent of the
records are predicted as one twenty
percent of doctors are particulars
having exploits which is actually pretty
reflective of what you see if you just
look at any subset of it if you just
look at what percentage of all
vulnerabilities have exploits written
for them it's about twenty percent this
model is still not great right this
model isn't something that I would bet
my life on but it is something that I
would bet ten or twenty bucks on and
it's certainly something that about a
day of developer's time on if we can be
correct about predicting whether or not
a vulnerability will be exploited eighty
five percent of the time and by the way
this is all using only public data
available at the time the doubling
ability is released you could certainly
play around and get a little bit better
at it by getting some proprietary data
getting some better descriptions of the
vulnerabilities getting some more data
about the exploits themselves then this
model is a really good input to throw
into an overall vulnerability management
system that is if your current process
today looks like it's patch Tuesday
let's run maybe a better process is it's
patch Tuesday of the a vulnerabilities
release that have a patch do we really
need to apply it to these because if
this model is pretty sure that an
exploit is never going to get written
for this thing
maybe we hold off on that one or address
something where we already know and that
exploit exists so to summarise in more
simple terms that's a bad chart that's a
good chart we had a bad chart we have a
decent chart here has how are the
metrics changed so interesting laying
off our false positive rate actually
went up two percent here but there's a
reason for that and you know on paper
perhaps the first model is just as
accurate it looks better but that
increase in false positive is tempered
by the fact that our precision jumps by
a lot by something like 15% and that
precision
and is what is useful in a vulnerability
management program a couple of next
steps here there's clearly two things
happening here the first is that there
are some vulnerabilities that are
negative de vulnerabilities is what I
call them and there are positive de
vulnerabilities
the negative de vulnerability is this
same model it can't be making
predictions about them because negative
de vulnerabilities are things that are
found precisely because they are being
exploited so the vulnerability is only
related because it's exploitable in the
wild the second process is the one where
we can make accurate predictions the one
we just find a vulnerability and hope
for the best but nobody writes an
exploit for it that we can make some
good statements about what their
attackers will or won't write exploit
code for them so it's important to be
able to separate the two and again there
are words in those descriptions that can
indicate to us which ones we should and
shouldn't care about something like in
the found in the wild discovered in the
wild as reported by Microsoft whatever
system so if we can mind those out
that'd be cool
the second is that the world of exploits
that we use to put the training data and
the outcome data is pretty small we're
only using exploit DB and Metasploit in
reality there are tons of other exploit
kits that could give us richer data
about which ones are and aren't being
exploited you know your angular's and
neutrinos and all of those that maybe
are even a completely different model a
different stage but would tell us which
ones are those vulnerabilities people
are earning money on which is also a
huge bit of data that we could use to
figure out which ones create incentives
yep so I already talked about finding
better descriptions because the
descriptive text is powerful if there
are people that do the kind of breakdown
analysis of the exploitation of the
vulnerabilities themselves that go much
deeper than saying buffer overflow and
there are probably other indications of
the level of complexity of writing an
exploit in there I don't know I don't
write exploits but the meta data seems
to say yes and then it perhaps makes
sense to break it down by vendor because
the types that you know it's one thing
to say an Adobe Reader vulnerability
came out that vulnerability is going to
get hit it's another thing to be able to
say of the Adobe Reader vulnerabilities
this one is the most likely or the one
that's going to be fastest to exploit
all of them are going to get exploit at
some point though the last part is that
this is step one
and the conditional probability of
figuring out whether you've got to get
hit on the vulnerability or not so stuff
want to figure out whether someone's
going to write the exploit step two is
figure out whether that excellent will
be effective so once this model is
trained well enough gets up to you know
95 99 percent accuracy then the next
step is to take the outputs of this
model and run it through a negative that
says once the exploit exists is it going
to be successfully used in an
exploitation or a compromise and that's
the data that we use to do the real-time
analysis and the path and then if we can
do that and hopefully what we end up
with is with some degree of certainty at
wonderful everybody comes out we can
tell you whether or not a compromise
will occur based on that vulnerability
in the future and even if that degree of
certainty is 80% then we're talking
about you know deciding whether to pack
your umbrella to work or not versus just
hoping for the best I got to put my
money where my mouth is I first gave
this talk at RSA and when I ran that
model you can check when these
vulnerabilities came out and you can
check that they all came out around the
same time I ran them through the model
and I was like let's pick three that I'm
pretty sure about since then two of them
have had successful exploitations on
them one has not but I'm still holding
out hope because they didn't specify
timeframe so take a look at the the
timeline of these vulnerabilities it's
super interesting to see you know
obviously that reader vulnerability was
going to get hit we all knew that
without me running it through the model
but it's interesting to see how quickly
it was and why it was if you read the
description you can see just how easy it
would be to write an exploit for it and
how many effects like every version of
reader ever so of course somebody was
going to write something about it and
then the other one that got hit is that
Windows Server 2008 vulnerability it was
a shared font like some font was really
corrupt and allowed for something to
affect like everything that when that
Microsoft has ever produced so like it's
very clear to me that if I wanted to
steal some money from some you know
inject some branch aware somewhere it
would be awesome to create a malicious
font and then start spraying it across
the internet and that is exactly what
people did a couple months later
hopefully that chair for rolling gets
exploited or I can just replace the
prediction
and hope I'm right the next time this is
this is this is also indicative though
right like this is I'm kind of glad that
one of them didn't because this is
describing exactly where this is useful
and where this isn't as those
vulnerabilities came out like yes I was
going to be wrong one out of three times
or one out of five times or whatever but
it's still useful information and more
specific information and the typical
thing that we do whenever one everybody
just comes out which is either a wait
for the data about its criticality or B
make a decision based on another
heuristic that we've derived that's it
thank you questions comments concerns
mostly about this right right they have
an update changelog right they have a
change blog we don't we don't current we
don't currently parse that in this model
so there's definitely biasing the way of
using references this way because it's
you know the ones that end up being
exploited and people start writing about
like The Wall Street Journal will have
more references but it's also true that
hardly had more references when it came
out right the reality is people don't
care about loans that aren't media
published so those numbers are pretty
okay cv details is a really good place
to get de 0 state information because
you can walk back to the state there
they actually like highlight their
revisions as they happen
right the reality is is that very few
get updated you know like if you look at
it something like 2% of CVS I've ever
been updated after the fact and it's
either because somebody wrote an exploit
for it and started exploiting it or it's
because like they don't really accept
random blog post links kind of thing
because they have new ones to think of
it it's like three people right so the
other ones that get updated a lot is
when they were wrong about the CDSs core
so if somebody wrote a post or something
being like hey you know this thing
actually matters you guys miscategorized
this then they'll do an update it's a
pretty small portion of allure abilities
I suppose you are correct there's bias
because I'm guessing all of the ones to
get updated do you have exploits oh it's
a good measure to write whether or not
there was an update
ah yes for people that have of audiences
or really caters that are not okay so if
your see 40 to 50 days our name is not
updated for treating that why you know
if are their visibility fines is this
price
so this was work perspective right the
way that I looked at it was at the end
of 2015 I had a collected a bunch of
data from the correlation of IDs and
vulnerabilities by the way not our
customers were just like global start
stuff that told me here are all the
vulnerabilities that were ever
successfully exploited and then to build
that CDF function I looked at the
existence of vulnerabilities in our
system so you are absolutely correct
there is that delay right between
vulnerability to created IDs signature
written IDs signature installed somebody
installs it on their actual box and then
we get a trigger alert which means that
at best for most vulnerabilities we only
know about the successful exploitation
like two weeks after so you are correct
with the biases the other way
essentially yes you're right that people
don't update signatures which is why
they get hit but the way that I
performed this analysis isn't to say
this person got hit at this time let's
build the CDF it was I looked at these
things got hit in 2015 let's look at
what was open in 2015 and so me knowing
what got hit in 2015 is the thing that's
delayed meaning that in reality it's
probably like 20 to 30 days if you look
at you know if you remove the bias of
signature installation yeah that's a bad
way to collect exploitation data but
yeah so I'm very certain that this CDF
is wrong but I'm also very certain but
it's probably the upper bound so you
could only go faster I can't think of an
argument as to why will goes why
attackers would be slower yeah
on this with the reversing lab state yet
so we have access to their sandbox and
we can see when they reverse malware I
don't know anything about male reversal
so there's probably some kind of similar
bios but it might be that introducing
that kind of data would remove some of
those and speed this curve up and in
most I know a lot of it is automatic
nowadays but some of it isn't I don't
know cool well slides will be on the
internet will be tweeted from the
Twitter and ask any questions on the
Twitter thank you