Cheeta here we'll just go on alright so
I'm going to go over a little talk we've
put together I'd like to do technical
talks especially at the end of the day
everyone's been as everyone's had their
ear talked off death by PowerPoint just
this is a little bit more fun it'll feel
a little bit more granularity into some
of the things that are that are out
there that are new that are making
resurgence
today I'm be talking on an older tool
called evil grade evil grade has been
around for a long time and yes this this
deck is fueled by Red Bull and bourbon
so you will have some you will have some
interesting slides you'll I don't
remember creating all of it alright
we'll go over introduction of myself
kind of what is evil grades kind of go
over some of the attack methodology the
structures the attack the attack vectors
and how it can be used within the
environment and why it's now making a
resurgent and why you're seeing it being
used again and then we'll go over at the
end some of the preventative measures
you can do to help prevent this kind of
thing to being used against you it's a
little bit okay alright so start out my
name is Reed Brasco been working I work
for a CBI creative breakers incorporated
check out the booth at the front for the
CTF there's some great prizes and then
check out the recruiting booths at the
end for some additional stuff about the
key of CDI I come from a DoD background
I've got I come from the Marine Corps
worked with the MARSOC and a Yankee
white establishment
I hold a top-secret as two clearance
that I've used within some of the jobs
that I've done just recently last year
got my cissp been
volved in the IT field for about seven
seven years seven plus years but an
active red team pentester for about five
years and I've got to play in a lot of
different environment everything from
food processing and manufacturing ICS
SCADA environments to gaming as far as
casinos working on the casino floors
working the casino security is working
on the entire establishment the banking
I've been playing in from everything
from mobile banking to the actual
banking infrastructure and web
application pentesting and their actual
applications running there on your
phones and then DoD and military I've
gotten to play around in some DoD
infrastructure stateside as well as
international played Tiger team played
red team played blue teams I played
everything like that so I've got a nice
little smattering of splattering what
everyone called of different areas I've
got to play in currently working with
CBI I am a lot more the corporate
corporate guy on the red team that are
stepping into these corporate
environments around here that are saying
hey we don't want to be the next front
page here's our network or go at our
network tell us where we can fix it so
that's what I've been doing for the past
year or so what is evil grade like I
said before evil grade is a framework a
module framework that utilizes
weaknesses within update functionality
as well as update call-outs to help
compromised hosts this originally showed
up by a company called info bytes around
2008 so it's been around for a long time
and it's just now making a resurgence
with addition of plugins with a veil MSF
venom and shelter if some of you saw
Sean's talk earlier of that escalated
quickly this would be categorized more
of a Hail Mary in the environment this
is all else fails this is
let's throw everything the kitchen sink
in the keyboard at the at the
environment to try to gain that access
or that additional foothold into it one
good thing that made evil great made
evil grade so big when it first came out
was that it's all pre-made agents these
are you're not having to go in and
configure anything within the device
here these are coming cans straight from
info bytes with updates for when it
first came out was Windows winscp
FileZilla Windows updates so these are
all things that you can use to try to
man in the middle of the update process
it was a very easy to setup it came with
its own web server as well as DNS
servers if you do have to do I'll go
over a little bit later of the
methodology of it but he will do are
doing DNS relook or a DNS spoofing and
DNS man-in-the-middle so came with all
those you don't have to stand up
anything additional for it's all
pre-canned it's an open-source project
it's been continuously updated even as
far last time I checked it was I think
the last update of a module was added
about about a week and a half ago so
there it is continuously being updated
people are out there adding to it in its
multi-platform you don't--if isn't
saying art I can only go after Windows
32 I can only go after Macintosh I can
you can go after phones you can go up to
Mac you can go after Windows 32 64-bit
the only limitation is the payload with
that payload being delivered however you
package it and deliver it that is the
that is the only limitation so yeah I'm
flying through this this won't go full
going through the attack structure as
far as the methodology will be used kind
of where you can use it where you what
it can do what it can do and other
things big thing with evil grade is that
can be used externally as well as
internally externally you're looking at
things if you gain access to their DNS
I mean they've got bigger problems and
evil grade but if you can externally
gain access to internal DNS that's the
easiest way right off the bat to be able
to demand in the middle anything but DNS
cache spoofing there's countless tools
out there ether cap metalloids got a
module of the Bailiwick ii host dns chef
my favorite the paranoid penguin are all
just open source tools that are great
for a dns cache poisoning or spoofing
attack that can get you into the access
to the dns to add a record in there from
external fake access points is another
thing that this has been used with a lot
of paring things like DNS mask air base
fake IP evil twin standing up an access
point and basically just implementing a
whole list of the plugins and basically
spray-and-pray
hoping that something on their computer
the quick time the Apple though or the
iTunes the winscp something like that
calls out for the update when they're
accessed your fake fake access point and
you've got them that way internal it's a
little bit easier you've got access to
the internal network now once again
brute-forcing to gain access to dns
server are poisoning are causing
spoofing tools like subterfuge ARP spoof
Cain and Abel
ether cap are all things that can be
used and have been used to get that
foothold to the man-in-the-middle
attacks of of evil grade DNS caching and
poisoning same thing as the external and
then the DHCP spoofing so go over kind
of the basic normal update process the
app whatever app whatever calls out and
says hey I need an update and reaches
out to their their update server app
update F whatever that DNS server
pointed to the IP that that app goes
okay I need this is the late
update grabs that update and executes it
on the box very basic now the malicious
aspect you're stepping into that second
piece right when that DNS server cache
or Wynette that application pulls down
it says okay what's this point what's
this web directory or web web site
pointing at that's what a
man-in-the-middle attack with that DNS
spoofing DNS middle Manning is going to
take it in to take that DNS that IP
address and point it directly where you
want it to rather than where it was
going with that control now you can say
all right yeah this I'm on the update
update server here's the update you want
with my code now in it and it says okay
yeah that's fine here take that that
update downloads it executes it because
a lot of times older versions of these
applications we're not looking for
certificates we're not looking for
digital signatures or anything like that
it's reaching out and saying give me
that update all right you get you've got
the update give it to me I'll execute it
all right we're up and running
tech factors this is kind of where we
can get into some of the fun stuff this
is the scary part these are all of the
pre can modules that come with evil
grade these have been added over the
years and a lot of them a lot of the
bigger ones a newer ones LeNoble
as we okay as we know go the VMware the
Samsung are the reason why this is
making a comeback Dell just had a recent
one where they had a an update process
on one of their applications that was
not calling for digital signatures that
ended up in a vulnerability referred to
as Edel root that was utilized by evil
grade to push updates malicious updates
to corporations or companies that have
been compromised Matta C&C server on it
the ACE is the same way as has had a pre
canned Asus updater on laptops of those
laptops were connected to a malicious
environment they had
they did not call for a digital secure
digital certificate and were allowed to
be compromised Samsung same way the
Samsung was more on the the TV side or
you've seen some of the key Beek
exploits of being able to pull up the
webcam on a TV evil grade had a module
that when that TV called out over Wi-Fi
or land looking for updates for the
firmware it was not being digitally
signed it was not being checked and you
could man-in-the-middle that very easily
the Intel one was the most recent one
this was dealing with Intel driver
update a little Intel module on on
devices that said hey we're looking for
the latest update that is the latest
module that has been added and changed
and that was a recent use of we have
seen of evil grade oh there's a fun one
[Laughter]
I knew they're in here somewhere so as
we all know live demos don't work very
well so I decided to do screen captures
at the last minute you'll see some of
them that are blocked out because I was
doing it my boss does know I bought this
here but my boss boss is in here doing
some of it at work and some of it at
home so so we can start out the biggest
thing right off the bat it's not the
traditional aspects aren't going to work
you need to pair it with and that's why
it's making the comeback now pay lip
pair with a venom with a veil with a
shelter to Ock you skate that that
payload code in the back end because
anti viruses within pcs or anything like
that will still catch it so that's what
there's a rig the first thing is you're
seeing me create the actual payload and
listener ah with MSS venom just using a
traditional meterpreter session this is
evil grade evil grade open source pulled
down from github will look like when
loads up don't worry about that
just loading the modules this is a list
of all the modules what I put up there
on the screen you can probably can't
even read it but what I put up on the
screen a second ago is not a complete
list those are just some of the bigger
ones that you may know within the
environment this is the complete list
all of them for you as well as
additional document because it continues
to go on lower down on the page icon II
capture but once you basically choose
one of the modules to use like I use
this one easy one notepad plus plus so
many developers coders use notepad plus
plus it's been updated so I use that one
you simply tell it I want to configure
notepad plus plus show options very
similar to Metasploit of just show
options it will give you the what what
you have options to do within the
options
it says the agent the agent is actually
what you want it to do what you want it
to execute I simply told it that within
the root directory was the payload that
I use the notepad shell exe out bracket
bracket basically when this runs when it
runs I want you to run this pack at this
payload that I've got stored right here
next thing you need fun part now is the
DNS spoofing so using ether cap
basically the next one this is better so
you can see within the module within the
show options it'll tell you where what
the call out of the the application is
what you need to spoof the DNS too so I
simply say put in my ether cap DNS
man-in-the-middle anything reaching out
to that point it back in myself point it
back in my machine hosting up my V at
Maya my malicious payload with that
running now we go go into the ether cap
and basically start the DNS spoofing
aspect of ether cap to say alright any
traffic traversing this network
grab the arpit and uh okay
I hate this little clicker okay that was
a fun one we're starting it up and
telling you anything traversing that
Network grab it and point it back to me
when it hits that that directory we can
see it seeing different hosts within the
environment there was a few things
pre-canned within ether cap you saw
trying to man in the middle
Windows Update which was kind of funny
now I just start next thing is just
starting my interpreter listener on my
box sending out the payloads I've got
the listener started I've got the DNS
man in the middle started once that
machine opens up my Victim machine opens
up the actual notepad device you can see
a call-out and spoof happen here you can
see me start the web server grabbing
connections here and you can see on my
meterpreter i Metasploit you can see the
session being generated i was another
fun one I think that's it but um so some
of the additional options like I told
you about this being paired with the MSF
venom with the shelter any obfuscation
tools without they're within the
environment too ought to hide that
payload within is is key there's
everything's out there right now is
knows meterpreter sessions knows other
other Metasploit modules and stuff like
that so another great way is instead of
using a module use something like a net
cat have that push out and execute net
cat on the device or have it push out if
you don't know if it's running
PowerShell has a push out and also an
open PowerShell and call home over
PowerShell our shells trusted you see
that with Empire and things like that so
Empire is a great new tool because
everything's running PowerShell have
this if you can't get into it and not
know if it's running PowerShell have
this push PowerShell to it
updates as I said before they get help
updates over evil grade are continuously
being updated so it's always a great
thing to check prevention Wow I won't do
this waiting for this biggest thing from
this is insuring your update servers are
running over HTTPS a lot of these this
now a lot of these older applications
notepad plus plus some of the open open
windows and stuff like that our
notorious for running over HTTP and
that's where the the execution that's
where some of this man-in-the-middle it
becomes a lot more easily done running
this running the updates over over HTTP
using certificates for controls helps
prevent a lot of these demandin Middle's
from taking place and ensures that that
update cannot be pushed the dns cannot
you cannot man-in-the-middle it or
anything like that digital signatures
and use of public keys so the checksums
digital signatures to ensure that that
packet is where it or that update or
that package or anything is where it's
coming from is if paramount you don't
know where that's coming from and you
can't say that absolutely was not
interrupted or that was not manipulated
from the origination host you don't know
what's in it and then the last one as
always and user education continue
security where it is key you can throw
every piece of equipment at the
environment and if users continue to
click on things update things and not do
what's best practice it's not going to
make a difference okay that's any
questions yeah
it's always separate okay if it's
basically just because you're not you're
not pulling anything from the actual
legitimate update source you're
basically just saying it's reaching out
to here I'm not going to let it reach
out here once it reaches out to that
point I'm saying no it's over here and
it's just giving you my malicious
traffic any other question that that is
yes but we are seeing like that Intel
update was a newer version that was
running just continuously they weren't
they weren't following best practice of
insuring the over HTTP or digital
signatures on those updates
so it you saw updates from there I
believe the last time we saw it live for
a iTunes or Mac was 2000 was early 2016
they have moved to all secure updates
but it has worked with that the original
thing that this was meant for and
created for was to man in the middle of
Windows Update updates and it was damn
good at that but I have not seen that go
live within Windows updates or been used
in the wild and Windows updates in a
while
any other questions yes yes a lot of
times within networks things like X ARP
and no ARP and other things like that
then that will prevent or that will
notify and prevent our spoofing or
anything like that within the
environment is a huge prevention no I
haven't yeah yeah the new Symantec
products of Sept 14 are making my life a
living hell anything else all right I'll
give you some time back in your life
[Applause]
you