who lives in London and is anybody here
you stackoverflow John Smith has more
points on Stack Overflow than anyone
else he was the speaker in Southfield in
January when I went in it there so
they're still getting amazing speakers
they're still getting great attendance
they still have this mountain of stuff
to get away and it was um
Thai food was on the air that night it
was a minute it was awesome I could kind
of still see my thumb prints on it
but I didn't have to be there I didn't
have to be involved in that when I was
there I was like bringing other people
into volunteer getting them to have
ownership in it and I we had things like
before I joined a few of the leaders
would go out to the bar that would
support each other hey let's go to the
bar after meeting and when I became
president I got up to the podium
afterwards we're all going to the bar
we're not buying your drinks but come
and join us
here's the bar here's a map of how to
get there we'd have 50 people at the bar
afterwards we had more people just going
out for the socially that afterwards
then most user grips do it anywhere so
it was really just an amazing experience
to be involved in this community one of
the things we did we started doing other
things besides their monthly meeting we
had something we call a code slinger so
it's just a way to get together in and
write code together just a learning
experience
we met originally at a coffee shop in
Southfield I met this guy I met an
Oriole he showed up for one of the first
ones and he didn't introduce himself he
was like we got there and we looked over
in the corner after about 20 minutes I
can't looks like he's writing code I
wonder if he's here for us so we we
talked to him and I guess he was too shy
to say I'm here for the meeting but he
was writing code he's writing some
functional program when we'll learn F
sharp and he was doing was coming over
here one wanted to and we started
talking to him he became heavily
involved in the user group and then
later on went on to form his own user
groups he runs a couple of conferences
now he gave a he runs a conference
called the stage name a couple times
Detroit and everyday and a couple of
years ago was held here at Cobo and I
gave a keynote there and because of
Arnor he was running a tsp called
could you a team out there I was close
one of my first keno say I'd get it I
was really excited and who was in the
audience but this guy named any fair
said and invited me to give a keynote
here so that connection really led to a
couple days
it's a Wolfgang here who some of you
know there's one of the driving forces
behind this conferences and I have a
story about Wolfgang so he and I met
each other I'm going to say seven or
eight years ago maybe and it was not a
good start it really was not I just
started working for a consulting company
and on day one first day in the office I
met with a salesperson and she said
we've got this job for you it's with a
financial services company it's over
here you're going to show up tomorrow
and you're gonna be doing some
SharePoint development I said okay
that's fine I don't know that I I really
don't I've never really done any sharp
point development before but I'm happy
to learn I'm all about the learning I'd
love to learn stuff she said don't worry
about that I told them you're a
SharePoint expert this was day one of
this job and I'm not making this I
seriously thought about quitting the job
on day life seriously thought about this
I did not I thought well let's give it a
shot
day two I showed up to this company
Wolfgang was the manager there and I
tried to hide the fact that I didn't
know anybody added all the requirements
and then they had a server room you know
the loud fans but I said I'm gonna work
over here the server room I like hid in
the server room worked there for a few
days and then I said you know what I
dreaded I had to come back and ask for
more information because I didn't want
to expose my ignorance to to these folks
hmm I went back in for I think we had a
couple of weeks to deliver it I went
back to work to work remotely in our
office and I'd not there wasn't a waking
hour and I didn't work on this thing
because I wanted to at least get up to I
want to deliver it was only as an exceed
expectation like I certainly wanted to
meet expectation we delivered it we got
the SharePoint solution in place in at
work and I was like really proud of
myself that I totally pulled the wall
over these guys eyes they didn't know I
wasn't a SharePoint expert and and I got
to know Wolfgang later on he went to
another company and I worked for them
for a little bit and he runs a user
group I spoke there one time see Amit
conferences around the city I'm more of
a developer he's more of a security guy
so we can go to all the same conference
but there's some crossover and one day I
said hey and I'm really embarrassed
years ago we first met you didn't know
this but there were stuck it was really
awkward right first night he said is
that because you didn't know SharePoint
tight that's where I was so the story
has a happy ending I know now I'm
standing up here at his conference and
here's an awesome podcast by the way if
you check that out it's right there oh
this is bill bill spoke is still here
this year he knows so you've asked him
bill I have a good story about Bill -
this is how I first met bill I kind of
knew who he was through social media we
followed each other on Twitter I was at
I was consulting at a large automobile
manufacturer in Detroit I don't say his
name but it starts with a G and they was
doing something with with security I had
to do figure out how to do some security
that integrated Active Directory with
some Linux directory service using some
toolkit I know I was lost I was
struggling with it a lot and what do you
do when you're having trouble you whine
on social media that's what I did I said
hey does anybody know how to do this
stuff and build chimed in he said hey
I've had some experience with that and
we started in 140 characters having a
conversation over Twitter which wasn't
it's not a good way to talk about
security and so then we started didn't
he we started through it with the heat
evolved email and then two phone call
and so far he gave me his phone phone
number and we were talking on the phone
he said well it's too bad that we don't
live closer I think I could show you
this a lot easier and I said where do
you live Columbus Ohio and I was
downtown Detroit over
the Renaissance Center and I said what
are you doing tomorrow and he was he was
free so i trolled down to Columbus Ohio
we met in a Whole Foods and I bought him
a salad bar or something and he spent
hours with me showing me how to do this
claims-based authentication which I was
totally ignorant at just a almost random
connection on social media solve this
huge problem was having made me look
good to the customer from a virtual
stranger really really cool
this is me hi he lives in Romania and me
he and I we met in Boston one year and
we ended up doing a presentation
together a tech ed which is a big
conference big technical conference that
in the US that doesn't exist anymore but
who's big the word 20,000 people they're
not in our session but I got to know me
hi we became friends we went to tech ed
we did a session together one year and
then we were back at Tech head the next
year and I was having lunch with him in
Orlando Florida and he happened to
mention he said did you know that I run
a conference in Romania and I said no I
did not do that no that'sthat's awesome
he said yeah I'd like you to speak there
and I said oh wow that's great which
would you um would you help me pay for
my travel if I do he said I'll pay all
your travel I'm like done when tell me
win let's go and so the next year I was
in Transylvania North cluj-napoca large
tech hub city in northern Romania
Cressida it was amazing people from all
over the world were speaking there I met
a great group of speakers all because I
just in front of this one guy had no
idea was I do one other guy actually no
two guys at that time I knew two guys
from Romania Mihai and Tibby Tibby was
just moving away happened to live in
cluj-napoca the same city pick me up at
the airport which was lucky because
Lufthansa lost my luggage and I didn't
speak Romanian so he kind of saved my
life there but um Sydney was just moving
away from Romania to Sweden
and he ran a conference in Stockholm and
I didn't realize that until I started
talking to him hanging out with an after
the airport whining about my luggage and
next thing you know I'm speaking in a
conference in Sweden just because I've
made these connections he saw me speak
at this conference in Transylvania haisa
Denis guy's pretty good us let's have
him speak there great connection
Stockholm is a amazing place by far the
farthest north I've ever been in my life
and then I just threw the slide in last
night because I flew in Detroit
yesterday and I open up Facebook and I
see the some guy hanging out of the dive
bar on Randolph Street that I know and
so I showed up there and surprised them
and he's not even from here is from
Coldwater Michigan Southwest Michigan is
another guy there from Hattiesburg
Mississippi hanging out there all from
work together Quicken Loans down the
street and when I was there he posted
something on Facebook that I was there I
get a call from this guy rich on the
right here and he said hey you're still
in town let's go have coffee so I
actually met up with a couple people
even though I made no previous plans
while I was here which is really cool
all right so these are stories about my
journey and you may be wondering this
how is this relevant to me does this
have any effect on what I want to do the
reason I tell these stories is there is
a point there is something that you can
take away from my journey from where I
started 20 years ago first getting into
tech to now where I have my dream job
I'll tell you what it's not the point
the point is not that you can just make
connections and forget about technical
skills and forget about doing your job
right number one is still doing your job
right II of technical skill and I assume
everybody here is passionate about the
technology you wouldn't be coming out
here and giving up two days of your life
to learn this stuff if you weren't all
about that but I bet there's people in
the room that are not doing a good job
of connecting with other people you've
been here with this there are hundreds
of people here at this conference and
you maybe you came with a group and
you're not talking to anybody outside of
that group I think that's a mistake I
think there's a lot to be gained by
expanding your network it certainly was
for me because by
our selves we only we only know so much
but once we start to expand that Network
then we can expand the available
knowledge if I didn't know bill cent
then it would be really hard for me to
beef up my knowledge about token-based
authentication this was I was woefully
alert about that I'm still I'm still
kind of surprised I'm at a security
conference because my password is still
password so that way don't don't tell
anybody okay just just from the the
amount of knowledge that's now available
to me because I met this guy at this
conference I met that guy in fact I was
somebody says hey I really need somebody
that's an expert on you know content
management systems I think you know what
I know a guy named Chet he lives in
Memphis Tennessee I can call him or I
could put you in touch with him and it's
really expanding the great breadth of my
knowledge breadth and the depth of my
knowledge because I don't have to hold
all that in my head I have I have people
that I can draw on it helps me it helps
my customers as well and I've connected
these people it helps in terms of
knowledge it helps in terms of
opportunities I have this job and a
large part because I met people like
Josh and Jennifer and Brian who had this
job before me and I said this is an
awesome job how do I get there I connect
with those people I can connect other
people with other people as a network
becomes more and more interconnected
I've had plenty of minute mentors almost
everybody that I've shown a picture up
today I would consider a mentor even
those that are much younger than me
they've guided my career in a lot of
ways all because I went to conferences I
went to user groups and I just talked to
people I ask them these questions these
guys these guys have helped me out a lot
in fact almost everybody whose picture
I've shown so far I owe some debt to
they've done so much more for me than I
ever have done for them and I don't
worry about it I really don't I they
know it I know it what I try to do is I
pay it forward I tried
go to places like the user group that
created and I said let's you know let's
bring some awesome speakers and to teach
these guys and by doing that work
maybe I'm paying forward a little bit
what I got from those working ahead of
me and I worry I think about this a lot
I think about I don't keep a balance
sheet of everything little person but I
kind of keep a balance sheet of the
universe that I want to be paying
forward at least as much as I'm your
seed so where does relates to you is
what you can do in a similar way to
advance your career to advance your life
and maybe you're doing this already but
maybe you're not one of the huge
advantages of building this network and
engaging the developer community it's
just the idea that you can increase your
knowledge so you already know this come
to this event right now sit in these
sessions absorb what the speaker is
saying most of the talks are much more
technical than this one and you're
learning something that but how many of
you are learning something at lunch time
how many you were sitting with a
stranger at lunchtime and saying you
know what problems are you solving or
just here I have this problem does
anybody know how to solve it this is a
great opportunity for that even if
you're not at a conference just getting
on social media and sharing that stuff
is a huge baggage that finding experts
in your field increasing your knowledge
networking helps you do this jobs this
is a industry where every you know the
average person stays in a job about
three years and so people that are out
looking for new jobs there's sure a lot
it's sort of lot easier to find a job if
you're if you have a network of people
that know you it's it's true a lot
easier to find new people if you're in
the same situation you know there's
people leave or as your company expands
companies right now companies are
looking for people more than people are
looking for companies the man is such
that that's that's really the big
challenge that's a lot easier once
you've got out in network of people if
you're add bonus points if you're
actually standing in front of people and
talking I've been amazed I've been a
user groups where I remember when I was
looking for a job a few years ago I
stood up and I said hey just you know as
company got sold or I'm I'm on the
market and then I sat down and I was
surprised you know five people were
around there for the meeting just saying
hey so send me your resume what you
looking for it's just because I have
been a regular attendee there and then
don't knock the social erectus it's
enjoyable to meet new people I certainly
like that a lot this is not everybody
that's in software development is
extremely social but that's a muscle
that's a muscle that you can actually
exercise and if you're not great close
to face with other weather the Internet
is a big thing social media is an
amazing thing to keep connections going
until you see someone in the future and
I really enjoy that and that's the
reason even without making any plans I
ended up hanging out with some old
friends over the last 24 hours just
because I was in town and Facebook is a
thing reputation I trusted here because
it's kind of I'm really amazed by how
smart people think I am there's
something about standing in front of an
audience that creates the illusion that
you're an expert and that's not
necessarily true
but I it's sort of like writing a book
people were to write a book it gives
them credibility people will stand in
front of an audience and speak it gives
them credibility and it doesn't mean
that you're any smarter than the people
that are in the room they listen to you
maybe you know more about that one topic
than they do but there's something about
that that has quite a bit I've had that
many times certainly in my job searches
help certainly dealing with customers
it's helped it's when I was a consult I
was a consult for many years I realized
that a lot of people would listen to me
more closely if they see me speak at a
conference it just gave me that
credibility I don't know that word
helping others I think is a huge benefit
I this is like crack to me I just really
get off on on the idea that something
I'm doing is benefiting other people you
know when I teach a class and people get
it and I see that they understand
something present something I did I
absolutely love that this is one of my
favorite things to do and it's fun
interaction developing the community
I've made tons of great friends I can't
recommend that enough now it's not easy
for everybody is that there's
communities that you're already a part
of as communities that you haven't been
that maybe you're not as involved in and
I really haven't defined
the community can be anything from
family to your classmates - that's me
that's me right there in college your
neighborhood your coworkers
I'm really talking really about the
technical community here the developers
and the IT pros people that you can
share knowledge with that you share
something already share a passion of
something that you're that you're doing
not only for a living but kind of things
you're willing to give up a Thursday or
Friday to come and learn more about
interact about these are the conferences
like this one the code camps I think the
distinction is that the code cast tend
to be free and the conference's tend to
get pay for so maybe tomorrow we could
set about a code camp the b-sides thing
who's coming tomorrow
oh let's people awesome that's great
user groups like the one I used to run
in Southie oh like the one that Wolfgang
rallies to run your easy group Wow it's
big time outstanding user groups are
great way to get involved and I
encourage you guys to check out the user
groups in the area
either three that will just mentioned or
just go to the meetup comm you'll find
something there you can search on based
on quick on topics and geography you can
also use your favorite search engine
the only winos Bing but I think those
other ones out there they look for give
campsite Liam mentioned give camps
Gibson's are a terrific way to learn and
to interact with other people and to
help people get camps are these 48-hour
almost like a hackathon over a weekend
people lock themselves in a room over
the weekend and they build projects for
charities so build something that a
charity is of nonprofit needs and they
have fun doing it and they are doing
some good in the world and usually the
chance to learn some technology over
that weekend I've been to a bunch of
those are still the one that goes on
every year this is one Ann Arbor one leg
that goes on every year still and social
media also is a great way of connecting
with people I I can't keep up with it
anymore there's Facebook Instagram and
Twitter probably about all I can do now
this my company start someone's going to
use Yammer and like I don't have like 20
minutes a day I'm not on social media I
want to give that up so but so it's
great the one thing I love about social
media more than anything is in between a
lot of people I only see maybe once or
twice a year because I there they don't
live close by and I connect with them
through this conference the network of
conference speakers and keeping that
relationship alive during those times
get in between Facebook Twitter
Instagram but those are really good for
that you mastodons will be good for that
it's not easy not easy for everybody
there's some challenges in interacting
with the developers or the technical
community one of course is time you know
you've got your day job you've got your
family you've got your other activities
it's hard to squeeze in the monthly user
group meeting it's hard to take a walk
two or three days to come to a
conference like this it's a challenge if
it's a if you really want to do it you
can find the time go to every other
meeting show up you know every other
month and start to interact with these
people
these folks this is a big one in the
tech community a lot of people that
gravitate towards IT don't have awesome
social skills like you and I do it's
true that people get into dealing with
computers because computers don't talk
back they can go in a room and they can
just work quietly for a long period of
time and that's sort of a stereotype and
there's a lot of people that are like
that but social interaction is a muscle
it's something that can be exercised and
if you go to a an event like this and
you had lunch sit with one stranger and
strike up a conversation with them and
you're not used to that it'll be hard
but the next time you go it'll be a
little bit easier and the next time
it'll be a little bit easier if you
wanted to be one of those people who
stands up in front of a room and talks
to people for most of us that's
terrifying it was for me the first time
but the second time was a little less
terrifying and the third time a little
bit less and I got a little bit better
at at each time and expect that a year
from now I'll be better than I am today
it's a it's a muscle all these things
are muscles to get exercise so just
saying I'm shy I'm not good with mixing
with people I'm not good at public
speaking
that's a challenge there's not a
limitation this was a big one for me we
all want to appear smart we all want to
think want everyone to think that we
know what we're talking about
and so we're afraid to ask questions to
reveal our ignorance and that is a huge
mistake I wish I could go back in time
and tell my 25 year old self what an
idiot I was for taking this attitude ask
questions reveal your ignorance ah it's
this best way to learn come to these
things here I don't mind I go I go to
many many conferences around the dumbest
guy in the room I'm certainly the
dumbest guy in this room regarding
security and whatever I want to learn
you know it'll help me to learn by
saying that out loud by letting you guys
know don't assume that I know anything
about what you guys are experts at and I
bring that out because I know I'm not
alone I know a lot of people that are
that are trying to convince others that
they're worthy that they're that they're
experts that they belong as part of the
conversation the conversation includes a
lot of questions ask questions do not be
afraid what can you do look for your
local user groups you want to get
involved talk to them go up and show up
at them introduce yourself for the read
to the leaders of it go to a couple
meetings if you really want to get
involved volunteer they're always
looking for somebody to order the food
every month they're looking for somebody
to schedule the meeting every month make
sure the room is available somebody to
show up 10 minutes early to rearrange
the chairs in the room they're almost
always looking for speakers you want to
try speaking user groups are a great way
to start the user group Iran we
implement something called lightning
talks ten presentations before the
meeting anybody could do them you've
never given a talk before show up stand
in front for 10 minutes maybe it'll be
awesome and you'll love it you'll want
to do it again maybe you'll be awful
maybe so what it's 10 minutes it's not
like preparing a 75 minute presentation
people are people are really forgiving
about user group presentations and
they'll handle those little
ten so we already doing this ten
conferences code camps in the area but
if you're not doing this already when
you attend make an effort to find people
you don't know don't just show up with
folks that are that you work with and
stick with them look around connect with
your peers connect with like-minded
people get their email addresses follow
them on social media start expanding
that interaction find out what they're
good at what are their specialties so
that when you have a question you'll
have a group of people to talk to and to
answer your questions for you volunteer
I guess I got ahead of myself get
involved in these these groups these
meetups these conferences these
organizations give camps volunteer it's
hard to find the time it's great I'm
going to close with I actually wrote a
lot of these thoughts down a few years
ago on my blog that this is like an old
version of my blog but I anywhere else
still should still work go ahead and
read my thoughts there a lot of the
photos I showed here I took them myself
you can find those photos right here and
I'll make these slides available somehow
through the conference I'll give it to
the conference organizers and I had one
more slide well I wanted to limit slide
I must have hidden it by mistake I want
to before I go I want to give a shout
out to a close friend of mine this is
Jim and Jim is one of my mentors I had a
picture earlier in the slide and he is
his wife was was killed earlier this
year and a violent act and this
presentation is dedicated to him and his
family I will I hope that he will keep
them in your prayers my name is David
and I worked for Microsoft and I thank
you so much for your time
[Applause]