wait okay okay Oh boys even put their
heads oil is not to worry about that
come on Ceres is the safety we had the
roof it would not be okay he also saw
fire this place just doesn't have the of
the wood this detector is white red
results by they actually activate a
relative movement result and it is also
an unlocking ray they're usually big
needed so students would have fun Priya
appreciated hedges so I bet responded
[Laughter]
I'm a cop Death Valley area
which is different from the power to
power coil is this community good
prototype it helped either by stop
coming from the guy who blew the
L'Aquila
so on we protected by active especially
through my deck if you can't fight
because they are really dark dark blue
almost caramel cucumber and in a little
units of event as well yes said about
the kabocha traditional it the lady was
healthy during our check I'd actually
detach my powerful battery to my Apple
included in my own paper happening thank
you make it in the playwright memory
so we bourbon to the rising extreme the
healthy brain which we try to are the
building we depart ability it's really
touched by the stuff without coming
really really crazy
don't try pink pink my Lily can let Gary
hold on and is horrified look so so good
I even want to a sort of jumps up wide
we may know many many times well we
thought there were life of the neck so
if we plug in and they don't catch Byron
easy for you every month initially there
by the way it was going in and open
serum Jerry one and it works so the
reason maybe of an issue Ellen witless
witless the company ah we think we found
a role in the decision okay we like you
to get it welcome to constant together
this event we love to be alert in short
much secure development and all sort of
oh here we go there was an anomaly down
to get the peach sweet it was my way
residuals have peppers on cheetahs there
we didn't quite get to that but what we
did discover is actually kind of more
exciting in this this lets you verify it
in fighting over met one in remind with
alumina back wall what the sectional
analysis way
so last time we gave us hope we had fun