the question is are these red teams
capable of delivering physical pentest
clay what what do you think about that
do you think people are adequately
capable and qualified to deliver these
physical pen tests well certainly there
are some very talented pen testers out
there that have great physical security
skills but I guess in some respect I'd
like to see a little bit more cross
training and a little bit more
collaboration in you know some of the
red teaming I think that certainly a
recognition of you know the specialist
skills that every diverse member of a
team can bring it's certainly the case
that I took give an example from the
work that I do I will secure everything
and anything in terms of physical
security up to the server but once
you're inside that rack I'm quite
prepared to step back and acknowledge
that others have you know far more
suitable skills and expertise than I do
and I think that one of the things that
gets ignored sometimes in terms of
physical security testing is the the
civil legal implications now certainly
in some areas of Australia in some
jurisdictions security licensing
dictates that anyone doing physical
security advising or consulting holds a
security license and a master license
within that jurisdiction which may not
necessarily be I guess well known or you
know well appreciated by some you know
pen testers with a InfoSec background
well that's really the majority of
InfoSec people don't have these
qualifications I mean the when we look
at red said red teaming as a service I
don't think that InfoSec is is it all
have any any any of these qualifications
like is that is that a problem lot of it
is is that a problem with InfoSec is
that a problem with the the
certifications or the qualifications
look I think I've made a you know kind
of quite one known that you know
holistic security and and a balanced
approach is it's very much my view
within security
and to have a look at you know the need
for specialist skills in a variety of
areas it's certainly well defined them
as I said I'd like to see
InfoSec learning a lot more about
physical security and maybe even you
know some form of professional or you
know recognition or certification as
they do for our InfoSec security and
likewise I'd like to see a lot of
physical security specialists that
particularly in the areas of electronic
security that really should be exploring
you know what's required in terms of
information security these days given
the convergence between electronic and
physical devices what do you think about
this I mean when you teach locksmith
students do you do the crossover into
the red teaming world or do you teach
them primarily for client facing or
other purposes with training for the
apprentices we predominantly just focus
on whatever the tasks are the employers
seek is relevant to them it's built into
a set of training documents that we have
to abide by and it's very much based on
purely what they can sell in the
marketplace with our students I do try
to cover some of the holistic approaches
that we do cover some of the PSPs
documents but it's not in built into the
training unfortunately hopefully one day
we'll be do you see that there's a
market for for red teamers coming from
locksmithing apprenticeships it would be
a great marketing tool for us feel so
there was hang out of you're hanging out
of a helicopter you know by your ankles
picking open locks yeah why not
race Geo do you have any comments about
this is that is there some sort of
history background where we've seen sort
of a you know the general public
you know crossing over the fizzles of
security and sort of getting over into
that sort of the professional market not
necessarily with qualifications but but
being in the right market place at the
right time
um that's a I guess is a set of
questions that I was sort of more
thinking like if you think about what
the purpose of the Red Team answer you
have a company that's like contracted
with this team to piss out their
security sir and what they're getting at
the end of that is like a report that
says the things that they can improve on
right so I suppose if you I think like a
bunch of hackers probably like get past
get past the physical security side but
I would without more training I would
say I doubt their ability to give like
you know recommendations on how they
could specifically like improve their
Pacifica period that makes sense like
they might be absolutely kind of by
posit but maybe not be able to give more
like solid recommendations there's like
a little bit different photo so that
you're asking but kind of like I feel
relevance to that what do you think
levers do you think that the people in
Loch sport capable of performing rating
intestines what's your view of the the
general lock support community in terms
of delivering these services so so I of
the people in Loch sport who I look up
to and who I learned from and who
publicly share information which is how
I learned I would say that many of them
have either had a background at least in
some capacity and doing either
locksmithing or mechanical engineering
or perhaps a background in the military
at least the flexing overseas I think
that it's quite possible for people who
- self going to practice right in some
senses to figure out how to pick locks
and then develop that into a skill where
you can provide advice about physical
security mechanisms but because there's
also door locking systems and all this
other stuff involved there's quite a lot
to know to do it at least holistically
or partly holistically can you teach
someone on the digital side on how to at
least a tiny bit about physical security
any day of the week can the physical
security world learn about digital stuff
just as much
as for the current status I'm not quite
sure because I don't I don't doing red
sieving so I can't really speak on that
industry well to sort of to go sideways
a little bit what about the ethics of
red teaming I mean is there any betting
or background checks of the people
involved in in performing these these
these pen tests or red team exercises
there's obviously ethical concerns I
mean you know you're looking at you know
people's property and premises and what
life Erin what what what sort of what is
the process in terms of the the personal
checks on on people entering a locksmith
apprenticeship really depends on which
part of the market you working in sorry
about the arms by the way just thinking
on my feet really the vetting is done by
the employer some employers are very
very lacks in the you seem like a nice
enough guy kind of he can just rock in
and maybe break into people's houses
it's fine
compared to other places where they will
make you jump through a number of Hoops
you know public record checks and
fingerprint checks and all of the other
available things are having our national
police checks and things like that but
on the whole does the industry really do
any good bedding I remember guys this is
an interactive panel so if you've got
questions just put your hand up one will
we'll ask our panelists we have any uh
anyone want to wait up over here so
everyone knows I'm from the Australian
blocks walk guild I want to get your
guy's opinion on how you see the
hobbyist and Industry communities coming
together as one to try and bridge this
gap between the old guard and you guard
who think that what we do as a hobby
should be kept secret by those in the
industry
today he has the day off just it depends
if baby-steps is probably the the
optimum word is just that there are the
older generation of locksmiths are a lot
about the secret information that should
not be shared and yeah I do get what
were they were they going with that
because I mean most of what they learned
was through apprenticeship internet
didn't exist in those days so it was
basically the dark arts that you were
taught by other people and if you spent
the better part of a lifetime getting
dead that that skill perfected and then
some other guy just goes on YouTube and
figures out how to how to get these
secrets out yeah I can see that this is
people off but then again that's the new
world so so guide the other side to this
new way the world works I think that's
that's that's a way to go so not try to
piss them off too much it's helpful and
show them the other side I mean I'm not
from the locksmith sides basically
I'm a hacker that starts to figure out
how Audrey lives and that gives you a
different skillset we have a different
way of looking at executing mechanisms
and that's the way as with the the
questions before about your red teaming
and the ID and I think it's a difference
because if you are locksmith you'll
learn to operate that machine or that
piece of metal in a way that it's bent
and and a pen tester does that with
other metal bits let's put it like that
but the hacker mindset automatically
looks holistically I mean a hacker is is
geared to look at fail so so you're
looking at errors in implementations or
errors in whatever and you use it to
your advantage so I don't really care if
if a red teamer has a lock the lock lock
smith background or ex-military as long
as he has a open minds and a hacker
mindset then all the skills that you
actually need to get in can be obtained
either by hiring a new guy in your team
or whatever but to look at not just your
core knowledge but about your bit
broader than that that that's helpful
and the same goes for the older
generation locksmith go like oh these
new guys they look at stuff differently
maybe there will be helpful to add
wrinkles I absolutely agree with that
but as a client as a customer how can
you how do you know the good Packers
like that are capable what they do
they're experts in their field where
does the sake well word of mouth what it
them at least that's the way it works in
my neck of the woods yet which is not
fair that's the way it is um I have some
oh please I have something to add that
sir I think what you're going to get is
you're going to get some people you know
people have been doing this for their
whole lives in the way that they've
known how to do it like locksmiths and
so they might take it it's like part of
their identity so sometimes it can be
really
lunging for them to be confronted with
this other way of doing things so it can
be really difficult for some people to
you know be excited about these
alternative ways of like attacking locks
or even thinking differently about how
they could protect their locks so I
think that that would be something
that's you have to kind of be mindful of
when you're talking with people who have
perhaps you know done it like the old
way but kind of like adding in this
historical perspective right like and I
kind of mentioned this in my talk which
was you know being very secret about
locks was like you know really important
and it wasn't until you know you had the
end of like the era of perfect security
where these locksmiths started sharing
and publishing information about these
lock mechanisms and sharing that
information did improve improved locks
and you had people started to say like
actually learning how to pick locks is
really really valuable we're learning
how to protect against that but that
information was still shared within like
specific societies and it wasn't until
the internet came along where you know
anyone can access it that hobbyist came
about so hobbyists like it's like in a
way you know that's when it became kind
of like you're saying with like you
could just watch YouTube and learn a
whole bunch about it
so it's still like really new for some
people the fact that there are these
hobbyists out there that are picking
these locks and kind of like challenging
their worldviews and stuff like that so
you're differently going to get people
who are like resistant to it but I think
if you can kind of be empathetic in
their way and kind of like trying to
share you know being mindful of how you
share this information or how you kind
of approach these people and I think
maybe you could find unity a little bit
like smoother yeah and it's a different
skill set because as a as a professional
locksmith if you want to learn a new
skill of course you're going to you're
going to think about how can i market
this because I mean you put in an X
amount of hours and you want to get paid
in the end and as a hobby is you just
breaking shit because it's fun and
and I don't you bet that's true yes you
get to break shit because it's fun we
have to put it back together and we have
to get high on it totally else yeah if I
break it I might if I feel inclined to
naive you right put it in the fucker
bucket yeah everyone is like a fine
white paper upon it and used to write a
report that's yeah I mean I can spend
months on an interesting subject because
I think it's interesting yeah and a
locksmith will go like no because that's
that then his hourly rate would be
sky-high otherwise it's it's it's it's a
bad business decision to do that
I think bridging the gap coming back to
what Donna was saying I think events
like this are definitely going to help
change some of the cultural mindset
don't think everything's going to change
I represent and very much of an
old-school perspective on things I'm
glad to be here I think it's important
that we are here we're glad to have you
as though you haven't heard me talk yet
yeah we don't agree to run um it's
really really good these kind of events
are going to help going into a locksmith
shop and ballbusting the guy behind the
counter isn't really the best way to
approach it just be nice
tell them what you're interested in
share their interests and you'll be
surprised yeah I know Mick is somewhere
out there you know by having that common
interest in locks and breaking shit
because it's fun you know if you talk
locksmith hey I've got a bucket of
thermite at the back can we blow out and
say yeah we do that because that's good
fun
it's also no we don't call it how can we
just call it a few beers and blowing
shit up in your back so it look we're
not complete utter Psychopaths we did
learn the hard way and it can be painful
sometimes watching bosnian bill pick
something in like three minutes and then
a customer coming into the shop the next
day and saying my locks are all shit why
did you sell them to me you're the worst
person in the world hey man I'm just
trying to help you out you know what you
don't see is Bosnian bill spending 36
hours picking that lock so that he can
do it in three minutes and is it an
appropriate tactic attack vector this is
good because this is education so you
red teamers black hats white hearts gray
hats no hats
Balt hAER'S no hair innocence all those
beautiful wonderful people it's all
about education and I'm sure what was
that follicly follically the prize
challenged thank you it's really good I
would love to have a customer come into
my shop and have a ten minute
conversation to me about the perfect
lock or the best lock or and have an
understanding that it all fits together
in one beautiful mosaic did we call
security
unfortunately in Australia it's not
quite like that I think just add
something that Erin's been talking about
and something that both Aaron and Joss
have both touched on his commercial 'ti
I think this is where you know the Loch
sport community if they want to bridge
that gap certainly there's got to be
some work on the part of the locksmiths
for embracing you know new thinking and
new ways but then there also has to be I
guess an element of respect or mutual
respect coming from the Loch sport
community with regards to commercial 'ti
there are instances where we have LOX
borders going out and starting lockout
services and you know you've got
understand that when you start talking
about people's livelihoods you know it
starts cutting deep and and then you
know it gets emotional and people get
hurt feelings and you know
things get said and okay I'll get knock
your house that's what I'll do yeah and
if I find that you're doing that I just
want your help yeah and look to be
honest with you I'll be blunt with you
as a locksmith having operated my own
business in the past the amount of red
tape that we have to go through in terms
of licensing and the expense to see
someone come in and undercut you without
having any of those restrictions and
just because of you know the fact that
the regulatory authorities don't seem it
is a cost benefit to actually prosecute
the matter you know taking food out of
the mouths of your family and the other
thing is is that you know it it undoes
all the good work that the Loch sport
community does in terms of promoting
their ethical framework now you can't
hold yourself out as ethical people if
you've got you know members that are
discouraged from doing unethical acts
would you agree with that clip yeah I'm
just so really quickly in general
agreement yeah I think that the the
legal framework in Australia is too
complicated in to gray in general that's
just my general comment on the matter
I've helped people who would lock up I
will never take money for it and I'll
only do it for friends and family is it
because I'm I could potentially still
screw something up and I don't know
enough about the internal modest
mechanism and I don't I don't have the
ability to just go down and get a new
one and completely replace it within a
short period so I only touch stuff that
I feel comfortable with I don't
generally don't like the idea of
touching locks they're an operation for
something just because I like fucking
with things as well and just as a
general extra comment from an ethical
perspective I think it just i share the
the idea of having empathy with between
the two sides that Joss and grace have
talked about but I also think that in a
point that you might have been touching
on earlier was that I think there's a
need for honesty on both party sides too
right so I don't want to see a YouTube
video where someone claims to pick
something in a minute that's high
security without any without and without
a single mention that they've really had
to practice for it because I think
that's actually not very useful I want
to have some information it's actually
more destructive than it is anything
else
yeah it's not bringing
to the conversation yep same with like I
want to see a gutting if you take a high
if you claims it if you want to have
credit for taking a high-security lock
apart you know single take video
basically I want to see that the sidebar
pins are intact that you haven't rescued
with them yeah yeah what do you look
like
well the ethics of lock sports people
starting a opening services that what
what what you talk about does it happen
that often that's problematic not that
I've heard of in Melbourne but it
doesn't necessarily mean we've got more
issues than lock sport people we've got
yeah well hang on
is someone saying that they do it yeah
but in Europe there are locks locksmith
have way more problem with totally
unskilled people that have en we have
those two on line up they go to
enterprise I look handy men are a big
problem anywhere in the world I'm
actually saying there are people that
the Google issues that we have with not
with various Middle Eastern groups who
come here with very little or no
training setting up with a key machine
that they can buy from Israel they
they're an issue - and is that bigger
issue than locks bought by far is it a
big issue in this communication in this
discussion probably not so but it does
it really does hurt us and the one
person where locksmiths are very very
close-knit Bunch we know everybody in it
is I know in my particular position
where I teach I know probably about 150
odd locksmiths in Melbourne alone
probably know about 300 across Australia
and we all know each other
and if someone it's a butterfly flaps
its wings in Western Australia we feel
it here in Melbourne but we we totally
do
but surely to divide between locksmiths
and the lockable community isn't just
about like our services its immediate
seems to be that there is stamping on
the ground of locksmiths isn't is it
that they're they're not ethical or they
don't have background checks if I am
holding with a friend a locksmith system
oh yeah look this lock this I haven't
gone through the apprenticeship system
depending on how old they are
a lot of people learn at the old
fashioned way where it was just handed
down from words mouths I think it's a
cultural change it is happening you see
it ends like these as bringing those two
sides together I mean do you reckon you
see many locksmiths they recognise in
the audience yes I do
I do see a number of locksmiths hiding
around in there
I think it is good I think they'll look
everything it's very interested in a
chat room and just go oh my god these
guys are clucking destroying the world
fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck I hate
them I hate them I hate them and I hate
this guy and I hate that girl and I hate
that guy - that's that's really easy any
idiot can do that but to come here look
and see the fact that they're young
chui's we had what 21 22 people
impression you had six guys on stage so
it had some people in there doing area
packing which most locksmiths would just
go yeah I want to be there I want to do
that that's great in my opinion so say
to all locksmiths know about a lockable
community in general we don't actually
understand why the fridges do it well
they do a commercial thing we go you've
done that moving on to the next job we
don't want you guys to make our job
harder we don't want you to educate the
public by the way my dudes are purely my
own and no way reflect the views of my
employer what subsidiary company is
there any
and I do not give any experts position
for this severe to broke up to anyone
else we have any questions from the
audience
I've been banned apprenticeships ask me
about training ask me about why you
couldn't get the safe open off the back
knowing most of you up there right there
I'm knowing also how how hard it has
been for locs what people to communicate
with lock Smiths themselves how do you
see it moving forward bridging that gap
not just for events like this but in
everyday life as well assistance
education and training where locksmiths
through tapes or any other methods I
reached out to by Infotech people or
white hat my cap whatever you want to be
so that we can do some training we can
see what we we help you with and try to
make you better informed customers of
locksmithing services or physical
security services as I think the term
locksmith I think is kind of conjuring
up some guys sitting any shared building
locks I think the real world view of it
is is that we've become and what brought
around our understanding of security and
how it all fits together I will make a
parallel and say that in the info
section conferences there's a very
strong percentages of professional
government and various privateers I mean
it's you know it seems to me that that
the lock small community and the locks
making communities is about 20 years
behind the InfoSec world most definitely
if you come to a locksmithing conference
it's mostly the same bunch of people
drinking the same amount of beer if not
more talking about the same thing that
they did 3 5 10 15 20 years ago so bla
bla bla back in my day bla bla bla
yeah that's exactly right in exams like
you've been to a number of conferences
um his youngsters yeah they're coming to
taking my money
so yeah I think you're right I think
that integration between the two with
better training and maybe not giving
Infotech people a diploma or certificate
maybe just coming in for a five-day
thing might be the way that we actually
start breaching that gun but what do you
think about howdy how do you bridge that
that like how do you still do doing
white locks mix two concepts you invite
them to to your conference a couple of
our members are our locksmiths and in
the Netherlands and we do I mean we have
a couple of manufacturers will
definitely come to our conferences and
we like those and then some of them some
of these manufacturers hate us to death
and well loved to death but some cuddle
us today I'm sure it's a lot in April I
say it depends so yeah and we had a
couple of members who were clearly sport
pickers that started working for tiny
companies like a table and its
consultants and some of them full-time
so it it is boundaries to be crossed and
that leave doable I mean we are talking
about different skill sets about
different view of the world and there's
no one truth and people can learn from
each other
please let's that's what they do
honestly I think if we had something
like this at the master locksmiths
conference standing along later this
year where you can learn how to bypass
an alarm system and you could do some
software-defined radio stuff and a
little bit of impression or tamper
evidence seals I think you would have
the place absolutely jam-packed with
with lostness because they want to learn
new skills I just don't think they know
and I know I saw crikey b-sides cambra
well so be fantastic god god damnit
brain too many beers or too less
it'll come to me like villages there are
lots port villages the fantastic events
that they ran here last year platypus
Khan
I think if locksmiths saw that those
events and I could see a commercial
reality and the things that they're
learning there I think you'd find a lot
more of them just quietly sneaking in
and paying very quietly and just done
learning a lot I'll take a question in a
second both sisters follow along with
that there are commercial companies that
that three times today plus the
conference says things like you know
locks lock picking companies like
pigtails for example or what week in
Australia like how does how does the
industry see these companies I mean you
know focal you know what because you
know lot lots of really but you know we
have uh some Australian May companies
yeah but look I think our Arrington on
the point you've got the old garden the
new garden locksmithing
I know locksmiths that will refuse to
buy from some locks making tool supplies
because they sell openly to non
locksmiths personally you on the
pragmatist in the consumer I'll go where
I can get the cheapest price and the
best service but yeah that is widely
varied within the industry yeah let's
just say that there are some locksmiths
supply companies that don't particularly
like our people like a peek pal sparrows
etc etc it looks it's a commercial
reality for them but by the same token
of our key machine to super super cheap
order so yeah but that goes both ways
exactly a cup size wine I've spoken to
do official suppliers and in an non
recorded session said I don't care if
they if they the customers steal cars
with it as long as they do it with my
tools so yeah I mean come on ethics and
so yeah it goes definitely both ways
we'll just take a question over here
so total change of pace in in
cryptography we have a principle used to
sort of judge you know whether a are and
algorithm is good Kirchhoff's principle
which is like over 100 years old and
basically saying that
everything about a cryptosystem can be
public with the exception of the key and
if if that principle holds for
cryptosystem then it's a good crypto
system because you're not relying on any
secrecy apart from the key itself do you
feel that that's a good principle that
can be applied to physical locks and if
not why not
well a physical lock you can break open
so if you're gonna tell me you can buy a
lock but you can't open it then you
better make sure that I can't buying it
because I can open that thing and if
it's a purely mechanical lock I can
visually assess that there's only one
key that opens that and so that's that's
different in the Chris book quick crypto
system so if there's a back door in your
crypto system yeah I have to be able to
read codes in order to figure that out
not a lot of people can do that but if I
can explain to somebody the basic inner
workings of a lock I can see if there's
a back door or not so yeah same
principle applies but the by starting to
sell a lock
you're basically opening yourself up to
this is the same research as you're
saying so yeah of course you can look at
a lock and see how it works so the inner
workings are open Clampetts have you
ever come across a lock which is
advertised one thing but actually uh you
know it has interned in fact turned out
to be quite the contrary and bots as
well and become a cross block with their
advertising some security claim go to a
market in Turkey you buy lock done yeah
there's a there's an Australian supplier
who was selling something that at a high
price point and claimed to have security
pins in it and they did not have
security pins and then I just bought a
whole bunch of different ones from
different locksmiths across the country
just to make sure that the batch wasn't
affected and they all were missing the
security bin so I would like to hear
back from them and they seemed to
recently try to make contact so I don't
really name who they are because I had
one negative experience with one person
in that company I think like marketing
so I got my phone call originally and
basically told me to get fucked
and threatened to sue me if I were to
publish any details about this
everything was fine in the conversation
and then I basically went so like they
asked me so don't you want a refund and
like no I'm just going to tell you that
it doesn't have what you've advertised
in it and they're like okay so you don't
want a refund I'm like no I just
literally wanted to tell you and I'm
like and then they asked me are you
going to tell anyone else and I said
maybe and at that point immediately I
was asked if I had a license and when I
said I didn't they threatened to sue me
no I licensed as a locksmith or as a
traded accredited security professional
someone apparently is there a disclosure
policy on beneath like if you discovered
it or in a lot it certainly see InfoSec
this is you know 20 20 years old this
process what do you do if you found a
significant vulnerability that needs to
be addressed that maybe is a false
advertising and manufacture a problem if
it's false advertising then that's
different
yes like because then Daniel oh yeah
that's that that's different but if
purely hypothetical hello and if I find
a vulnerability in a lock that I think
is major I probably will do the right
thing and go through responsible
disclosure so talk to the supplier but
of course most locks today are not
software so updating them can be a
hassle to say the least
so it's it's always a challenge to do
that in and all the way and of course
suppliers starting with we're going to
see you that's not the best way to start
a conversation because that tends to
will rub the runway and then my cool
cooperative mode is also switched off so
I related back to a zero-day hack
basically if I could commercialize it
and I could use it to my advantage for a
little bit I'd probably keep it under my
hat for a little while and then I'd like
told the supplier if I feel like I
really want to but that's me wearing my
bad hat my good hat would be most
definitely if I think it's going to be a
massive security flaw that's going to
impact a lot of people
cause I pass it on if I could use it
commercially and I might use it
commercially to give myself an advantage
for a little while what about public
disclosure like what is the process how
do you know when to helpfully disclose
in a security system you don't know you
never know when it's in the general
public's interest that it's going to
impact them in such a way that they must
know the right thing if that's as I'm
sure the process is well you know well
disclosing it is going to affect the
security of customers so their their
premise is not to disclose it in general
I think that normally in software you go
like okay yes 30 days or 60 days to fix
this and never go in public and if you
if you ask a lock manufacturer long
should I wait before our released is
there probably set and mode any other
three and that's I mean that's it's just
different so so you have to find a
middle ground but you can't just roll
out patches for your locks that's
correct yeah it's like way more
expensive you know no and it also
depends on in which in which segment of
course consumers these lock resides
because I actually remember two years
ago now that uh there was a paint we're
going to be released at an academic
conference defeating a and immobilized
runner on a luxury car a supercar in
fact and the the manufacturer of that
that arm that security system made a
legal complaint and actually tried to
try to stop them from presenting their
work in an academic conference I think
the outcome was that they could do the
presentation at the conference but they
couldn't publish their paper I mean is
this the right just the go-to thing that
manufacturers do how do you stop that I
mean surely doesn't help the security
industry the security of people that
that is just zero disclosure on every
big vulnerability in a physical system
and if we're talking about actual super
super car those are also super super
expensive so yeah image wise that's
going to hurt them like health but if
it's we're talking a couple of cars with
customers who paid stupendous amount for
them I'm pretty sure you can sir
those and replace those locks if it's a
consumer-grade lock than every household
has those yeah it's got to be a problem
so it depends so yeah but that super
super car probably has super super
lawyers as well so yeah saying fuck'em
it can cost you so it is hard there and
any questions in the audience well it's
always I mean does the natural like the
silly thing to leave this on to is
almost like the Internet of Things the
Internet of Things lots of physical
devices all have terrible security I
mean I mean is the physical world of
locks like this that I just produced
something it's a pin tumbler lock is
that is that secure quite quite frankly
I think if you're using an inline pin
tumbler for a security application in
today's day and age for it's really at
your own peril there are better
solutions out there but people have just
bought into the marketing I mean you
look at it a consumer walks in to
Bunnings which is you know quite frankly
the largest retailer of locks in
Australia and what are they presented
with lots and lots of marketing height
from Lockwood and gainesborough the two
biggest suppliers in Australia they're
really not aware of the choices or the
other solutions out there and I think in
some ways yeah this is where testing you
know those boundaries and trying to
crack the old chestnut of you know
security through obscurity helps the
consumer in the end because I'll be
blunt you know people talking people
from lock sport community talk about you
know having been oppressed by you know
manufacturing companies I think Erin
will agree with me that when locksmiths
identify you know problems with locks
even if it's just with regards to
serviceability or general construction
quality they're quite often shot down as
well you know quite often the people
feeding them and fixing them are the
first ones to identify that there's an
issue with a lock you know I think a
perfect example was you know the mortise
lock from Lockwood with a hole in the
side of it that's not quite the one I
was thinking of it how yeah there's a
five shape star bit that goes inside a
lock and a break with repeated frequency
and those whole locks a whole ten years
of research and development went down
the tube with 5,000 locks being
manufactured and installed at massive
expense to the company well what about
home alarms if you go to Bunnings buy
the most expensive home alarm system and
you can do a replay attack with a
software-defined radio to disarm the
system is that what is that there's a
home alarm system from a hardware store
worth it's worth its money no friends of
your risk profile but normally the
answer would be to know well I'd be more
worried about the fact that they could
probably just knock out a couple of
bricks and walk through the side of my
house
that's how Australian building standards
up alarms there is only as good as the
other bits that go along with it you
know do I want my security sandwich with
just one life of dry bread or I want the
full the full Reuben it really just
depends
Australians are very very very non non
security thinking and what the she'll be
right mate attitude permeates all levels
of decision-making and the cost benefit
security risk triangle it's in full
effect and Victorian and sorry
Australian consumers are extremely price
conscious we'd much rather have a
big-screen TV to watch the pudding
whatever code it is that you like rather
than actually protect the shit that's in
our houses yeah don't take his TV I'm
pretty sure that's not just an
Australian thing yeah I know well look
the European model is that the
stronghold bottle I've got one door into
my apartment I put a half-decent lock on
it and I'll hope for the best defense
rate of this but yeah so yeah I'll take
a question over here I want to get your
opinion on this should Bunnings be
selling safes and lost and be part of
the security industry or they should be
stopped altogether because you can pick
up and drop burning safe and it's open
in seconds
what do you think they're not sighs but
they're marketers say they've been
marketed fireproof yet fireproof cashed
in exactly sorry paper tune and I think
that a lot of that comes down to you
know a standard legislation in
Australian our consumer protection laws
yeah it was once again this is you know
clipper starter their laws a gray in
week and the usually not enforce then
you've got massive massive companies
with massive massive profits and lots of
lawyers and unfortunately you know the
government has to behave is the model
litigant and behave ethically you know
as a big box company you can pretty much
do whatever the hell you want market
share I combined sixteen pallet loads of
your freshly imported lock or you don't
get stopped and guess what you do you
sell it to Bunnings but that's
unfortunately the cold hard reality of
the way the world works would it be
great I think it's going to have to be
consumer driven the change in security
perception it's going to have to be led
by lock sport and locksmiths and
security advisers to change that culture
and I think it's going to have to also
take part of the insurance company if
there's anyone here from insurance
companies they'll change it they did it
with transponder technology in Weston
sorry in West Germany in their cars
before that they had great high security
locks kind of that you could just drill
out you could drive the car over to East
Germany be part of our through Bulgaria
and before you know you'd be selling the
parts in America it will be led by
insurance companies if insurance
companies see that their premiums are
getting paid and that their payoff or
too high they'll change that's it I was
talking to a woman earlier Sally who is
a locksmith and we're kind of talking
about you know the choices that people
make around what locks they find or that
kind of thing and choose pretty much
like whatever helps you sleep at night
like
is kind of because if somebody wants to
get in they're gonna find a way to get
in right they're going to find a way of
bypassing it and if they have really
serious business they'll probably use
social engineering to do it you know
okay because that seems to be the
easiest way to like I treat panic
reciprocating school yeah so you know
we're kind of talking about like for
some people it's having a dog in your
backyard it's like so it's different for
different people but I think you know
having if I think the point about
insurance is a really good point because
that will be probably the way that
people are going to find out they'll try
and insure their things and the joints
company is going to be like well what's
your what are your looks like like
what's your security like and that's
probably going to be the thing that will
get people thinking about it probably in
a very frustrated way but like you know
that could be this probably I think a
good way to get people thinking more
about their home security and stuff
again we've got about five minutes left
so we might just start to wrap up the
panel if I could ask each of our
panelists for some final words maybe a
little bit about what we talked about or
something that you'd like to say purpose
what what what would you say to the
people here first off thank you for
coming
I a bunch of us is sadness like channel
went let's make this happen and I think
each of us in our own times has said or
thought to themselves over the last six
to eight months like this is not going
to fucking happen and no one's going to
bloody show up or it's just going to be
shit so thank you
secondly I think it just want to
reiterate the sort of point today I
personally feel I think these are two
two things that we could all do on both
sides of this sort of dichotomy which is
yet be more honest and share some
empathy to each other don't carry it
here you got like if you're a sports
picker don't carry your ego into a
locksmith store and confront the
locksmith like I try to be nice I
haven't found that nice was always
reciprocated but when I do it you know
it tends to you ten attempts to come
from both people just being friendly to
begin with
be honest
a bundle runner ability disclosure
airlocks in physical security I think is
a slightly different cup of tea to being
able to in theory roll out a patch now I
know without some IOT systems for
example you're not might not be able to
do that but I still think there's a
point where yeah you might it's not it's
not a black and white subject where you
kind of blankly go at this point I do
tell the public or this point I don't
never blue yeah I think the the only
thing otherwise I have to say is and
perhaps the topic that we might carry
across on over there that we could
always have conversations that later
which is that I think that's quite a
different market we have an isolation
here in Australia we've had a company
that locally produced pretty cool locks
that a lot of people overseas really
like Lockwood for example and I think
that there's a quite a large different
market and different so comparing things
in terms of what the availability
commercially what's available to
consumers it's quite different say
between Australia and what you have
available in Germany or the Netherlands
oh then even again in the United States
yeah and that's about it thank you for
coming okay well thanks for having me I
guess yeah I think bility of locks is
original thing because you well there is
the internet but then again sometimes
there isn't because if you live in the
US and you are you want let's say
protect you can fly in a project but
then you cannot fly in the hardware to
fit with your project and then if you
ask as a boy like can you ship that they
said no we can't because there's a
American supplier and there's one tiny
American supplier that doesn't stock
that stuff so in its it's it is weird so
sometimes you can't buy the stuff you
want to buy and that kind of frustrates
stuff so yeah and I'll be Pickers well I
don't want all the hardware I just want
to lock so I can play with so with
different source wise that's
like and we were discussing responsible
disclosure some companies started to
learn that it's easier to to be there
earlier so a couple of companies and I
will not name names
even after drinks notes no clarity and
that post R&D ship some boxes of lakhs
of brand new not on market lakhs to
sport pickers and just have a go at it
and we rip them apart and all these
things are supposed to be a bubble and I
didn't notice sorry and so they don't
get to market because we played with it
and of course that cost a shitload of
money but yeah if we don't play with it
and we start playing with it after
market that's gonna be a bundle of money
more so yeah so we started to learn and
and and and coexist in this shared space
maze which i think is one thing I'd like
to leave with something that's kind of
about general security and that is quite
a sensitive topic for people like it's
quite personal like what your state of
you know how secure you might be failing
or what your object is like and whatever
I think so you have to be careful when
talking to people about things because
you don't want to make assumptions this
people might take it personally or they
might not be able to learn from that
because you kind of want to educate the
people around you that you know right
because you know about this and you want
your friends and family to be safe so I
think it's good to talk about security
but being really empathetic and not like
oh boy your lock on your doors like I
could pick that like shoe ii said just
let me show you because you know that
person is not going to be sleeping for
the next month you know you know beer
like I guess my padding was would be you
know be sensitive and have these like
conversations and and let you know let
people have like a way out of those
conversations rather than just backing
to Thermidor corner about
my pal was shitty there's security as
you know so yeah just just baby sets and
just being really nice and like the way
to go I think thanks Fred I look like I
think that the way forward so you know
both security and the locks ports
communities is more stuff like this you
know I encourage I see a broad range of
people from you know multiple sectors of
the industry and the hot and the Hobby
here
and I just encourage everyone that's
here to continue doing what you're doing
and forge forward with you know doing it
because with persistence you know we'll
end up with a better product and a
better you know a better result all
around for everyone and just to hop on a
point you know
remember your security sandwich it's not
just about one thing don't get the
tunnel vision and just look at one
aspect as your perceived threat remember
to keep it general and keep your eyes
open because you know the next one
durability is only around the corner and
a side step to the side I'd like to
thank the panel actually for their time
today it's been great to actually have
this kind of higher end conversation for
once in a while it's it's a nice change
it's great to just actually talk about
things at a slightly different level
I think locksmiths will come around to
this level of thinking eventually it's
just going to take on it's going to take
patience
remember we're kind of actually techno
lights you guys start talking about like
RFID hacking we like the idea of it but
you're going to have to be gentle with
us okay I'll tell you how to break into
a safe no problems but I'll be gentle
with you and we'll take it easy I'd like
to think especially all of the staff
here at the comedy lounge I'm putting up
with the shenanigans that's been going
on Tony I would like to thank the
locksmiths that have come along with the
broad and open mind and not the big
pissing Ergo contest I'd like to thank
Silvio and the team from these sites for
their help and their assistance I would
like to also thank all the people with
orange lanyards without you guys
this wouldn't have been able to be
possible to the VIPs thank you very very
much for believing in this and making
this the event that it is
so far it's going to be bigger again
next year I heard that we can actually
have a robotic dinosaur that we can hack
I hope so
I've said it now has to happen I don't
know where we're going to get it from
you know beard punished with his amazing
key casting if you didn't say that that
was fantastic he missed out next year I
really want to get over to the
tamper-evident staff that looks
fantastic as well so please when you are
putting events together and you want to
market it to locksmiths make sure you
really include all of the real physical
security stuff I know it's easy to write
about all of the great talks and
presentations you're going to get on
InfoSec and non-physical security stuff
but if you want lock use to start coming
along get a bit of a focus on that I
also like to put out a big THANK YOU to
topaz where I know he's around somewhere
in Swords can I get you all please put
your hands together to topi he's done
amazing job is that not got the guy from
the side of MORTAL KOMBAT look just
perfect for that um yeah really I just
would like to thank everyone for coming
along making this such a great event
everyone that gave up so much time I
know yeah I did a tiny little bit but
it's been really really good and I would
love to see a lot more people here next
year and um yeah let's take one final
round of applause to our panel
[Applause]
what while we are down the neck
you