all right I'm ready to go so how's
everybody doing today
yeah alright so I'm really excited to be
here this is the first time that I'm
presenting at a besides charm conference
here in what's now my hometown I was
supposed to present many and during the
first one but I was unable to do this
from last-minute engagements but I'm
very excited to be here today and I'm
very thankful for the organizers and who
gave me an opportunity to come here and
talk to all of you today so thank you
are we good Adrian awesome
ha all right so my name is Jose
Fernandez and I came here to rock so the
name of my talk is burning furnace
exploring singing signals from Seoul
City I am on Twitter so if you get one
guys to get one follow me and please go
ahead so the agenda for today
I'm going to describe the research goals
or for this project I'm going to
illustrate some pest works that have
been done in the field of dignity I'm
going to highlight some of the signal
analysis that I did and the methodology
that I used to do it the multiple
avenues of approach that you can take
when you're doing security research into
the grand scheme of things what I call
case wants a lot of those avenues have
approached I focused on one of them
particularly and that's why I'm able to
talk to you all of you today and for the
research that I'm looking to do and I'm
you know part of this talk is a way from
to help me find other people who are
interested
and doing research because you know it's
no fun being John Rambo and you know
just doing everything yourself right
it's always you always get better
results when you integrate involve more
people and you know the opportunities
are there sometimes you know we just
don't know where to start so about me I
am an intersect researcher for the
purposes of this talk I consider myself
a mad researcher my scientists I focus
mostly on attack and defense mostly and
I'm a veteran I'm a PhD student and this
presentation League of Women right it's
my it's my own it's my own minions my
own research it doesn't involve many of
my employers past current right so took
care of that so all this started a year
ago I have access to solar city
equipment and I was at cotton pretty
interesting I mean how does this all
work like how does it communicate I
thought if these things had antennas
that there were devices that I had to
plug in you know in size network and I
was like huh how does all this work so I
spent countless hours during that year
just learning about
sdrs learning about Zig being on
reversing among other things but I had
to wait for the right time and before
doing any of the actual like hands-on
research and my hypothesis was someone
like me who had very little experience
exposure knowledge Zig me could go from
zero to now in front of all of you due
to the lab due to the vast amount of
work that has been done on ZigBee
research over the years and be able to
provide mutual contributions in this
field for the purposes of defense so I
finished an abstract it's like hey you
know I have a pretty good feeling that
you know this idea gets picked up you
know I'll be able to run it and be able
to present in a short in my point
so now I have an actual reason to do all
this work right so I thought about how
to attack this research and what what I
was going to do to understand all these
technologies and all the things that
make it work and that was a you know
long hours long days right
I'm sure all those already had 9 to 5
jobs and you know maybe more than one
right so I was able to devote a lot of
my free time in the percentages terabyte
hypothesis was is a large pool the
passwords exist in your fields how
feasible is it to replicate the findings
on systems are unreported right so in a
lot of these other researchers a lot of
the other research that you'll see it
mayn't focus on on certain things but
you know in this case I wanted to see
how SolarCity actually employed on their
communications
there was no existing public research on
either SolarCity
or fro dias which is the manufacturer of
my power inverter that this company is
starting to deploy that technically
analysis until today so I'm adding to
that that knowledge base right now by
just being here is descending now they'd
been research done to date Puri
secretary Spicer that's not true I don't
even believe that he said that but
nowadays maybe he did so these are you
know cut a lot of passwords done by
other individuals you know uhm let's
take a moment to give them a round of
applause for all the work that they've
done
there's so many projects that you know
it's one thing for you to do research
and then not tell anybody about it but
when you share it with everybody you
grow that body of knowledge but at the
same time you know you put yourself out
there right so in every subject extinct
but a lot of these individuals and many
many others right I couldn't just put
all of them in a slide but there's
definitely a lot of material out there
that if you're interested in this
technology you can just pretty much
search for it and run with it now here
comes the perfect timing in all ways so
the Digital Millennium Copyright Act of
all pieces of you know legislatures that
are out there now allows insel tech
researchers to conduct research on
consumer devices the research has to
actually start in 2017 so that may mean
fiscal year for the government but you
know I literally started around January
of 2017 doing the actual hands-on
aspects of my research so I spent about
a year thinking about how I was going to
approach this problem and how to best
approaches I contacted the vendor to the
starting to dispose of responsible
disclosure channel and I received
approval to present today so thank you
to them we into an agreement and to
limit some of the things that I've
already shared with them in terms of
findings while letting you know and
totally figure out how they're going to
permanently fix some of these issues so
in my case Solar City or throne is they
didn't have public like contact with
like they didn't have a bug bounty and
they didn't have any of that so at first
it was a little bit tough to figure out
you know how to actually do responsible
disclosure because sometimes you know if
you're doing research or a particular
vendor the information isn't out there
and you don't just want to call the you
know 800 number and say hey no mobility
since cousins like let's talk about it
because you know it opens you up right
so I used some you know I watch the news
I knew that Tesla had pretty much
acquired SolarCity and Tesla does have a
bug bounty program so I was able to use
that PC I contacted them it's like hey I
know you guys aren't SolarCity but since
you guys merge perhaps you know who I
could contact and they actually brokered
the communication so my initial
observations was SolarCity starting to
roll out the furnace equipment to the
solar customers when it comes to the
companies like this where it's like
smart metering and generate your own
power there's there's multiple vendors
out there but in this case Solar City
started rolling out some of the
erroneous equipment and you know the
device I would assume would have to
collect that metering information and
report it back somehow so this thing if
there's this power inverter which I'm
going to show later that is like
physically outside of your residential
place of work it communicates with an
Internet gateway that is inside your
residence and place of work right so
there is some form of communication from
something on the exterior to something
inside this particular vendor uses
equipment from Proteus and digi who's
heard of digi yeah they have a huge
ecosystem of products and in this case
even though I did the responsible
disclosure from Solar City you know they
ain't use their product so if you try to
approach all three or more at the same
time you know your mileage may vary in
terms of acceptance so the
communications flow between the devices
this is what the hard winter looks like
in this case
a erroneous primo model you can see
there on the bottom there electing their
butts there's an antenna there this
thing communicates to the Internet
gateway which is you know a small small
low device you know also has an antenna
right it looks it looks kind of
innocuous right let's kind of say Matt
talk to your land which talks to
something right because it's not really
clear at first just by looking at these
things how is this actually
communicating you know over the net so
the solar gateway needs three lights to
function properly and right in one day a
meteor power the other one is going to
be the network link on your on your land
the other one's going to be the ZigBee
link so three lights I'm sorry young Lou
three life so my initial thoughts on the
equipment were they if they gather that
consumption device of the energy that
you produce you know what what else are
they collecting so the company is
already you know disclosed that you know
they can actually fingerprint the
devices inside your house based on how
they draw power it's pretty interesting
so they can actually tell what model of
like large appliance you're using like a
washer dryer refrigerator they can
actually fingerprint those things based
on the consumption of it that's pretty
cool right
and then yeah for me yeah yeah I guess
I'm okay with that right now because you
know let's say you had a really old
dryer and they're able to fingerprint it
and all of a sudden you start getting
marketing mailers for like discounts for
your energy efficient wood right this is
a marketer's three
but at the same time what do you what if
all of you consider could be the
repercussions of once this technology
actually becomes very precise let's say
that there's certain devices out there
that they don't want people to own a new
powered end and they're able to
fingerprint that where does the sharing
of that information stop okay so there
are some concerns there but you know for
now my initial thoughts looking at this
thing there's like you know it looks
kind of flimsy it's like are these
things really secure right I keep
hearing about IOT and the IOT for me
means the Internet of threats and I keep
hearing about how all these other like
vendors and corporations that keep
getting it wrong so I was a little bit
suspicious of course I would want to
remind everybody here that you know
there's always when you're doing
Infotech research there's three things
that you need to consider you know this
vigil millennium copyright kind of like
thing that came out that's okay but you
never want to be the first person to
have to test that in a court of law so
you always have to consider the
difference between what you can what you
can do what you could do and what you
shouldn't do at all times if you see a
lot of the other presentations that you
know happen in and let's say like
conferences like that song stuff like
that sometimes they'll do the research
and you know it's pretty much violating
a lot of the title 18 laws especially in
a computer problem abuse act right and
sometimes they get lucky and you know
they don't get sued and okay okay
threats
sometimes a tox get pulled right because
they don't go through those proper
channels so always consider things that
you could do within the scope of
yourself and your own reality right
there's always many more things that you
can do and usually in some of those can
get you in trouble at the same time you
shouldn't be afraid to explore and just
open things up and figure out how they
work
and that is part of this community right
if we don't take screwdriver and a flat
head to things and figure out what's
actually there
we're doing a disservice to our
communities so everything's secured my
initial response to that answer is yes I
am going to continue doing this
presentation as I continue the process
of responsible disclosure and hopefully
that will always remain that way you
also have to consider don't give away
free pen test the companies when you're
not invited or you know just just don't
do all this work when nobody asks you to
and nobody wanted you to do so the work
either right so don't just do all this
work and then just give it away to them
for free
that's something else to consider never
value your time at zero there are
multiple avenues of approach to kind of
understanding how the vendor actually
ties all these devices and
communications together so there's the
communication between the power inverter
and the internet gateway the
communication of other power inverters
and Internet gateways and by that I mean
you know the ones that you may or may
not own the communication between the
internet gateway and the company the
communication of a web app that they
have in order for you to communicate
with the company and then you can see
now the March power you're producing and
things of that nature they have a mobile
app so that's a whole different Avenue
of approach
how does the mobile app communicate with
Ty intelligence and you know for me the
most interesting one was the
communication of the Gateway and its
internal components right so this
presentation is only going to focus on
the very first avenue of approach which
is the communication of the power
inverter and Ethernet big wave because
this time it would just being legal
please close some of the
that discover and I'm still looking to
put all that together also so you need
to give the the vendor of time to fix or
you doing under service and you're
opening yourself up for lawsuits and
other napkins so recently did you course
actually put out the internet of threats
security balance between economic cost
and benefits so perhaps the people in
the back to not see this very clearly
but so it's pretty much the cost of
scale ratio between you know here's some
at the bottom there's some communication
impacts your I shouldn't point things so
in there you have some cement in the
middle attacks that you can move there's
some software attacks that involved
apparently malware and social
engineering or up in the scale I would
argue that social engineering you know
it costs almost nothing right so it's
just my perspective though but over on
the right side we have invasive hardware
attacks and non invasive hardware tax so
in the non invasive channel aspect of
this they have side channel analysis
JTAG right so they know what people can
do to their devices are they're aware
but they put a cost kind of like risk
balance to all this because the things
at the very top were the invasive
hardware attacks they figure that those
things could be you know it could take a
lot of time and resources to actually
produce so you know then they know that
those things can happen but you know
they see the likelihood of trying to
make the preventative measures to defeat
since its kind of like you know right
now just the cost-benefit analysis it's
not just it's not worth it at this time
it's a business decision so you might be
asking yourself why are we talking about
first lady and why are we talking about
the first thing why did you know why is
how did you get permission to do this
it's because there's a physical security
problem with these devices right these
things are usually outside of somebody's
residence or building they have to be
accessible by you know not only the
power company that it's tied into but
you know is it like a fire or some other
type of emergency you know those those
first responders need to potentially
come in and have seen attorneys
equipment off so the physical security
problem in the way that it gets
integrated and deployed to customers
anyone can access this panel in fact you
can pretty much operate this thing
I'm just using the dashboard and you can
get some pretty cool but you can do some
pretty cool things with it and you can
also do some very damaging things from
it so I know what I notified the vendor
of a particular problem and you know I I
kind of expressed it you know this is
worth talking about because this is
already out there and it's been out
there for years and nobody's really
talked about this openly you might be
asking why not the second one why didn't
you try to figure out how the other
people's power inverters communicate
right so I did a poor man's war drive
with the Ziggy module and I had some
imbalance in it I had I had some a waste
in terms of a laptop that I was throwing
away but I took out so the wireless
antenna because you know when we said
you know different electrical components
and you know old hardware out you can
still scrap some things and then you
might use them in the future so I was
able to do that and then I was able to
amplify the the signal strength with my
poor little expertise device and you
know I tried but it was very difficult
because um I found that very few orders
around my area actually had the same
figuration that I had from my experience
I was told that hey you're one of the
first people to start getting this new
equipment with this type of particular
configuration sometimes they do the
configuration where uses wireless
Ethernet right those things are also
very interesting and they suffer from
the same the same physical security
program problem so SolarCity has a web
app where you can actually find other
solar consumers near your area that's
pretty cool right so I use that web app
and I started driving around it's like
okay I know where that Street is and
then you know I just use visual analysis
that's like you know just look at the
roofs you'll find the solar panel
difference that you don't have to get
too technical with this and I did some
some non basic scientific analysis by
that I mean if a device popped up on my
screen I wouldn't have tried to interact
with it further it would be the
equivalent of using something like a
Wi-Fi tumbler something like that oh you
can't be there so I kind of stopped
doing this too because for me it just
wasn't as interesting as other things um
but if you do want to help with this
initiative burning furnace at protonmail
comm it's going to be in the email that
we're going to be using so that way if
you are interested in assisting with
this research are just getting involved
that's going to be that or you know talk
to me after the talk ideally I'd like to
find somebody else who has the similar
solar equipment so that way we can
compare notes right and local would be
better because I'm pretty sure somebody
else besides me happens and they may or
may not live close by so we look at
their web app so although all those pins
on Google map those are other solar
customers that they have
when you click on the details of those
pins the information that it gives you
is how much power they've produced
that's pretty cool all right there's no
that they actually took some time to
make sure that you can't just like rip
this and you know finding GPS points and
stuff like that so they did take their
time to kind of reduce the exposure of
that customer information but it's still
pretty interesting right you getting
pretty much find people who are solar
friendly by endings so the easiest way
to start like most things that you know
you know was not taking a screwdriver to
it and look at the labels in this case I
had two devices I looked at the label
for moles outside and you can't really
see it so clearly there but there's an
FCC ID number there alright so then when
you do a search for that it's in 2.4 15
megahertz right nothing talks about
right yeah that is an empty empty
frequency no it's not it's unlicensed
though a lot of devices you know are
going to operate in this channel for me
I was just like okay so there's a lot of
things going on there let's find out
what's going on here so I started
speaking to some of my peers like hey
what's the best way to approach this
right and that was told just put a USRP
on it ok so that looks like this right
no it's not that easy it's bad advice so
then I was sold just throw where you
left or T at it let's see what that
looks like
now I said during signal now since I
purchased this the very small kind of
USB dongle from Texas Instruments it's a
GM 25:31 I think it cost a little bit
less than $50 and it's specifically
built to help analysts and researchers
find ZigBee communications I use
stationary analysis to identify the
communication between the devices and I
determined that you know there were
going to be other IOT things talking
also so I came up with the hypothesis
that you know if I remain at a
stationary position and just look at the
different channels over over long
periods I'll be able to determine which
is my device just by the amount of data
it's being transmitted I did this for 14
days and by that I mean in the morning I
would wake up select the channel run it
and when I'd come home and evening that
would stop it and I would look at the
look at the information that was
collected so in my case it was channel
20 the one where my the signe equipment
was communicating on I did the same
thing with killer B it took a minute to
ID the the the devices and the channels
that they were operating on another
three minutes to pcap on that channel
and it maybe took an hour to flash those
razor and USB sticks they have right
because just because you get used to
have to flash it in order to kind of
support packet injection and the other
cool features so looking at this I'm not
going to show you guys the peak abs
because it's too intense to be honest so
it was beginning every three seconds
sounds like three seconds you know yeah
odd number but looks like Y like three
is this really my stuff so I compared
the the MAC addresses on both levels I
match both of them it's like yep myself
and the packet sniffer from from Texas
Instruments called packet sniffer it has
an awesome GUI it's great eye candy but
you know I need pickup this thing
outputs to a dot PSD and it's not
Photoshop sounds like package sniffer
data it's like come on guys that also
means something else so they actually
have a wire shark converter so then you
can take those PSD files and convert
them into wires into pickup then you can
you know do more things with that
there's also these other like
third-party drivers where you can output
like a 500 file and then open that to
Wireshark but I found this to be lazy
considering I had collected tons and
tons and tons of the Cap'n's it's a good
way oh so I decided to take a peek at
the things that are outside right what's
in the device you know there's a
physical security Pro a program a
problem with it so let's open it open
what information can I pull from it and
I kept thinking you know I kept thinking
you know there's you quit you involved
and stuff like that you know I really
want to like offset you know I'll just
stop let me let me figure out what's
there first so this is a picture of the
center of the of the PCB board for the
power inverter and you get Nick the
backpack is huge and there are many caps
just like that one so all of those
things want to kill you so even if you
power off these things you still needed
this charge it and you need to be
extremely careful I mean I've seen this
thing work with 19 amps at any given
time yeah you know it takes what almost
let them want to kill you so be careful
right don't just go in there and try to
mess things up or you know just be very
careful when you do it so this is what
the daughter board looks like but when
they will so this thing has a dollar
board and yeah see I already see head
shaking right so um so so can somebody
saying with what's wrong with this
picture
any takers so one of the things that I
found pretty curious you know it's not
only the XE stuff but it's that
capacitors oh my god too much coffee so
you see that that cap there and going
through the antenna wire I was like oh
maybe this is a trap maybe you know this
is some form of like physical you know
maybe I need to be careful with this
like Indiana Jones but no so it turns
out that the that the way it
communicates from the outside inside its
using XP Pro right and that chip isn't
soldered in so you can literally just
pull it and put it on to the device
there on the right which is an XP
Explorer and some analysis on that I
load it in some program called X CTU who
has not heard of XC t you let me tell
you doing this ZigBee stuff and then
learning about X CTU I was kind of like
this exists
like whoever like all the people that
develop that I spent a lot of time
incorporating features that only like
engineers would care for right people
like us also so there's so many cool
features and that was very surprised
with what I found so when you load XE to
you you tell it hey I want to use this
ZigBee device so the device that I
pulled is the one on the right upside
the ones left it's working at the router
right now the one on the right is the
coordinator I'm not going to get into a
ziggity specific you know aspects of
communication all this but those things
are important so it's able to pick out
that other device that's inside a
building right whole thing is you can
double click on the on your device on
the left and you can actually reprogram
it on the fly you can read the config
and reprogram it very cool it has many
many other features which I will not
cover today
but little to say barrier to entry is
very low right so there you know I kind
of mentioned this thing beacons out
every three seconds there's my three
seconds the scan duration so every three
seconds was scanning so I was able to
answer my own question so I can read
this all the informations there great
well I was looking for that well-known
ZigBee Alliance key right because I
figured hey this is maybe maybe right
maybe just do the fault
you would find your answer here this is
part of the things that I've agreed with
the vendor not to directly talk about
today but it would be that easy for
anyone to open this whole little fig and
read on encryption specific information
that way it's all there
it is this was the part that blew my
mind you can actually remote into the
coordinator with with the thing that you
just pulled from the outside so yeah see
I can already see the looks on your
faces like what yeah and this is what
fiber should look like my vision if I
just videoed how easy it was it wouldn't
be school you're in the coordinator like
that I was really surprised I was like I
was not expecting that to work but it's
built into the the capabilities of the
describe actually it's supposed to be
machine rental right from my experience
in the past I thought these were only
using like dev kits I didn't actually
expect to find this in something you
know out in production but it was and
then we decide I'm seeing this the
actual way that devices ticket to
communicate not only the channels or the
pan ideas and other
other cool socks right so you can pull
even more relevant encryption aspects
from this remotely so you took something
from the outside you went in and you're
able to read that config and you can
also configure it too so you can change
it to whatever you want I thought that
was pretty neat so if you want to do
kind of like more sigelei analysis I
would always recommend that you know you
get something where you can attach an
antenna to it so you know you give it a
results you get you can see more things
now the cool thing is you can actually
use xct you to just look for other
devices right so you can program this
you can start mapping out different
things and you can probably remote drill
into those things - yeah no I thought
that was cool no yeah
would you agree right so I like getting
things that you know you're able to
connect antennas just for this very
purpose because you look at things like
the razor USB sticks there's no way to
connect an antenna to it unless you know
you get very creative and sometimes you
don't have to you can just use commodity
hardware it's already out there just uh
so in this case I started doing you know
poor man's signal replays and that that
video there on the left was me replaying
traffic just very very crudely but I'll
be honest it didn't work because I was a
victim of guy go a lot of it had to do
with the way I was replaying traffic and
what I was actually replaying so I
wanted to keep the three green lights at
all time and you know within half an
hour of just doing these weird replays
without you know manipulating dates or
you know counting for the different
aspects in this it dropped right but
there's always the potential that if you
spend time doing this you might get
results so but proposed that you know
this cure the the problem the spender
needs to stop using this pan ID that
seems to be used
you know through through other solar
companies they need to started changing
the pan ID or you know just mixing it up
right to not make it as easy to be able
to identify this thing um if you want
you can actually use X CTU and change
your encryption on that coordinator
first on the thing that's inside right
because when I looked at this device it
had 31 things that it would have to
unsolder
and I didn't want to do that so you know
I can barely on a good day solder mostly
so 31 things and then you have I didn't
want to do that so you can actually set
encryption however you want remotely
then you can do it on that power
inverter I think that you extracted from
the exterior
then you set it that way you know you've
you've done that it has limitations
because anybody can still pull these
things and they could pull you config so
maybe you know the vendors can get
creative and they can do things to their
the program this this small module or
loaded from another data sort I mean
there's different things that they could
do but you know it feasible I can't
really answer that you know definitely I
would say at least solder the damn thing
in make it hard right so some of the
future work or I looked at a lot of the
passive communication I said how this
thing talked out to the mothership how
does uber forward you know the metering
and all that stuff I was able to kind of
find similarities as to the end points
where it was actually talking out to
just take some time and consider the
things are on the right side you know
that there was no clear text default
passwords not have stuff they address
all that right so still interesting you
know communicate over the net hmm I
spent most of my time doing research on
the actual device itself
so looking at things that I could pull
from memory that's what these are you
know kind of like proofs of work that I
was able to pull that I felt were
relevant to show these are the kind of
things and you can extract from from
memory and there's always you know
better ways to do things also right so I
use very rudimentary process to be able
to do this but you know that I can
figure out you know what version of at
least Python that they're using with
this you can see some some of the
companies and software's that they
incorporate into this you can actually
see like C code like ads pretty cool so
there's definitely a lot of work to be
done that's why I'm here today I'm
looking for other people who kind of
want to assist with this help take it
further right call for allies now let's
work to solve cool problems together and
you know let's be ethical about it too
right nobody wants to go to jail
um I'm not really looking to get into
like any book binding programs because
it will usually tell you into an NDA and
then they limit what you can and can't
say mmm
frowny peroneus protonmail comm any
questions yes that's what that earlier I
kind of had somebody has this I'd like
to be able to talk to them so that way
we can sharing compare notes you know
just looking at the roofs is one thing
so then when you're looking at the side
of people's buildings and they're out in
the street and then oh hey what is this
character doing yeah yeah it's okay
I'm an info tech yeah that doesn't
trigger any alarms
so and that's an interesting point
because when you see all the mad metal
things usually they want you to install
things on the client device first this
is a small embedded thing you can't
really trick it into like hey no use
this from now on so you have to get a
little bit more creative if you want to
do those things it's definitely still an
avenue of approach though any other
questions comments that's it thank you
so much for being here and hope you
enjoy the rest of conference yeah right
now