hey can you guys hear me okay thumbs up
cool alright start from the back yes
awesome cool hi everyone my name is ben
actus you can follow me on twitter at
Ben raw this is a 20-minute dish in a
pressure cooker what could go wrong I'm
giving a 60-minute one in Austin besides
Austin's next week so thanks for coming
by the way this is gonna be a lot of fun
about me motivation how it should work
huh all the things wrong with it or part
of it and then I have a demo video
because I didn't want to bring the thing
on the flight so okay Who am I I started
miter in the area here phenomenal FFRDC
I did a bunch of mobile reversing there
I build a lot of network sensors there
is a really great website called open
security training that info if you want
to see me with hair teaching about
NetFlow analytics and hunting that's up
there too then I went to look out in San
Francisco which is absolute blast I got
the tear part Android and iOS malware
all day and most recently I'm at cynic
and for those that don't know syn/ack is
like combination bug bounty program volt
and scanner and what I do is I build all
the mobile attacking tools which you'll
see from the talk so what we do is I all
the tools that how do we act scale
reverse statically look for phones and
dynamically look for bones and I also
tear apart a lot of IOT devices before
they come to market to at night I'm a
troll on Twitter I do it on a side
business called cyber merchants of death
so if you want training in any of these
things come talk to me after the talk so
alright my work did fly me out here so
I'm going to do a quick pitch if you
like bug bounties if you like attacking
mobile apps web apps host go sign up
blog bounties we pay them only
difference is we do a kind of little
technical assessment so if you say you
know how to hack Web Apps before you let
you touch the customers web app
infrastructure and make sure you know
your stuff it's a smaller crowd and what
I like is the payouts are really fast
because it's only one group of people
vetting them and because that's it's a
smaller kind of competition circle so
please go check it out if you like this
stuff
especially students in the audience -
okay how did this come from who's heard
of the Internet of shit Twitter account
couple people so this really was the the
inspiration I saw this on Twitter and
I'm like this is funny and I don't know
you can see in the bottom but someone
made a funny little dad joke this
basically said is the next like IOT
botnet going to be a pot net and I like
that right yeah so I started looking at
it and this is literally five minute
findings like I'm not exaggerating this
so within five minutes I just started
wrapping around in the mobile app and I
saw they're sending things over HTTP and
I'm like that's weird what are they
downloading and they're downloading
these dot cooker files and don't worry
explain how all this stuff works and I'm
like huh what's the dot cooker file so I
unzipped it this is good file and it has
these like weird binary values I'm like
huh that's weird
it also stores all of them on world
readable world writable storage
directory on Android which could be bad
so anyway if suddenly bought some email
and I was like Patrick plaintext
communication
sends executable code source executable
code and a directory anyone can touch
pretty sure I gave a talk on this can I
buy it and like absolutely this will be
fun so like any good security researcher
person we send a disclosure letter so
here's my company letterhead
I talked illegal and I wrote a letter
and I was like hey dear insta pot you
have an application an IOT app you send
data in securely store data and securely
and we're pretty sure we can modify a
temperature heating and timing and
pressure remotely right
and they don't really have like a
security team so I sent it to like the
general helpdesk you oh it gets better
guys um so it's that there for twenty
days and also he says like if you don't
respond in sixty days we can go public
right so that there for twenty days and
then Nancy s closed it without saying
anything so I went to there like our
attorney and I was like what do I do and
he's like oh ping um again I'm like okay
so I opened it up and I was like you
still haven't patched it and like as a
week ago it's still not patched if you
want to play with this later
and Nancy closed it the next day without
saying anything so right here's a talk
regularly or use cases so it's pretty
simple the idea is you like unbox this
big pressure cooker you sync over
Bluetooth Low Energy then you launch
your little mobile app you select the
recipe right I like yes okay if anyone
couldn't sell you wait and then you eat
some yummy foods right and like the
products cool just they built it really
bad right no thank you
so weird things i reversed thousands of
apps no exaggeration I never found a
mandarin poem unused in the codebase
before sound like what does this mean so
I've 13 Google Translate and it's like
kind of sweet it's a little kind of emo
and depressing but it's like I thought
it was cute so no security volunteer I
just thought it was funny
other bad things yes this is what do you
think it is so they were so an Android
you had like a flash assets folder and
that's like images graphics things you
use sometimes right they have all these
XML key param happenings the actual
integer binary value you send over blue
and a Bluetooth low-energy
to control things like heating gear
elements this is probably bad and if
it's unclear yes they definitely
outsource to some Asian company to
actually do the code base
they also have the pressure state values
in there too
so we'll get into this why this is bad
later so my goal is I just want to be
able to break everything so looked at a
lot of code and we're going to dive into
that so first question is those like
binary files remember the cooker ak's if
files I unzip those and I understand how
to parse that so the plan was I have to
figure out how each binary weird hex
name file name corresponds to an actual
recipe file and then I had to map out
what those values mean so this is O&O
editor and you can see the really really
long file and a on the top and then it's
about in ten byte increments how big
these files are so you can see a weird
kind of pattern emerging each of these
is like a a five five five eight oh one
is each different step in a cooking
recipe and then there's various bytes
after that the correspond the different
instructions so the first thing we got
to do is figure out how each of these
weird file names corresponds to like
Ben's favorite pork and rice recipe
right so I pulled a bunch of files off
the phone and I noticed the current
running recipe is stored in like a
secure area the only thing to store
securely and I'm like well I don't
really don't want to go through a dozen
recipes so I pulled out this sequel Lite
database and it had a beautiful
one-to-one mapping of all the weird file
names to the actual custom recipes or
recipe human readable names
it also leaks it in logcat too so now I
can I know what the recipe file
corresponds to like the weird hex name
and I can actually start messing with
stuff now
so first things first I probably should
have read the manual because it would
have saved to me like two weeks of
reversing because turns out you can make
custom recipes and I didn't know that
and what's nice about the custom recipe
is they have things like heat for a
period or heat to a pressure and I was
literally in a four-hour car ride of my
girlfriend and I made every variation of
everything
little step and then I just distal the
files and it was super easy so this is
the only hardcore reversing part of this
at the top but basically how it works is
when you make a custom recipe it looks
for a string and it's a bunch of if
statements so if it sees something like
heat for a period it calls for the
appropriate method and that mess and
then there's methods for every single
instruction right and each of different
integer values and then it calls a build
command so this one build heap for a
period throws a 14 under that build
command method and that there takes a
hash map and convert that to a big giant
byte array that then gets thrown into
the Bluetooth Low Energy kind of
functions and I'll get into more on this
and the Austin talk so let's look at the
custom recipes first things first
heat percentage so offset 0d that's
what's actually doing the heating
percentage so you can see it goes for 8c
and then 10 there right and that's
basically when you want like little
pressure cooker to stay at a certain two
heating percentage so this doesn't
really do much right time modification
is a more fun one right so oh by the way
anytime you see the little evil baby
best ways you can mess with someone's
recipes remotely so you could easily
like take some of these pre-made ones
which we get into the attack layer on
and undercooked or overcooked food
because you know we're in the offset
that changed these instructions right so
like my friend Willy's in the audience
if Willy has his favorite chicken rice
recipe it cooks for 30 minutes I can
make that cook for like one minute or
like 100 minutes right so that's kind of
fun
LED settings I couldn't make it do any
cool emoticons or anything but it's just
like there at offset zero II so other
ones the whole key to a temperature was
cool so like my first thing is like I
want to make this thing blow up right
unfortunately the max value in the GUI
is 284 degrees Fahrenheit and it is the
max bite value I can put in there but
the lowest Beauty value is 86 degrees
Fahrenheit and that's only 39 in the
heck so you could do a lower value which
is pretty cool
so that's kind of interesting pressure
low versus high the only officially
supportive values in the app is 20 and
30 but they don't do kind of any error
checking so you could kind of throw
these weird values to change like weird
state method for future work to LED
settings so I talked a little about this
a few slides ago there's actually a
bunch of others in here and I'm still
kind of systematically mapping out like
unknown ones so there's like none hot up
down there's also like yogurt food a few
other weird ones right but there's a
bunch of bytes that I have to try for
every instruction sound options so you
if you want to play like obnoxious
Gameboy sounds here's what you change
and again you see it's weird it's like
20 40 60 and then four it's not music
it's like 16-bit sound files it's really
gross so you can do that too and the
rest are just static values so we know
how to control timing right we know how
to control temperature we know how to
control pressure and we know how to make
them not just sounds right let's do
something with us so my claim that kind
of prove this to you guys is I made a
custom recipe with no sound and we're
going to go to a known temperature and
then it's going to do other things that
it shouldn't be doing so I have a little
video here do we have an audio jack or
we're gonna wing it with the mic waiting
it okay we have an audio jack now don't
okay so we're gonna wing it
so I'm gonna hold the mic close to this
and hopefully you guys can hear it if
not I'll articulate it so hey everyone I
have access and here is yes the test
case of the la cote pressure cooker by
me the boldest test cases I want to show
you what the expected behavior of a
custom recipe that has not been modified
looks like so that way and I modified it
next step you can see it's clearly
deviated from the set instructions so
first things first I have the pressure
cooker synchronized over Bluetooth Low
Energy with a nexus 5 test phone right
here
it C says connectedness to pot
now what I've done is I went and made a
custom recipe that's really really
simple I'll show you right now what I'm
doing is I'm strong through all the
recipes I've had and I'm selecting this
a proof of concept three or apoc three
and pretty simple whole is is going to
heat to desired temperature I'm going to
stop so things start here and there's a
few so the kind of kick core ingredients
of this recipe is 286 degrees Fahrenheit
midnight at 86 degrees Fahrenheit is the
lowest threshold I can set the graphic
user interface and additionally since
waters family get room temperature and
then the cooker right now we can get to
that happier quickest so few things I
can also show you which is kind of
interesting here we can see the desired
temperature here so it's at 84 so we
should hit really really quick right now
it's sending this heat to 86 degrees
Fahrenheit command over Bluetooth Low
Energy if you can see it behind me to
see like a little moving iPad says on
there's a little rotating guy I symbol
for the moving circular object behind it
so oh that was a pretty simple it hit
black degrees
okay so then so that's what should
happen okay now I mess with stuff and
you see different things so again quick
things because it's only 20 minutes I
have to cut off a lot of the steps but
modify the files you could either do
this in downloading or because it's on a
shared directory and they change the
attributes and I just threw it on the
phone and we're going to click that same
recipe again
back I put a new cold water in there I
also trimmed my beard any more handsome
and it also pushed us out to refine the
modified lines so as you recall from my
longer beards video they can just sell
the only instruction that should happen
here is going to have roughly six screw
it and it's go stop it's not going to be
it's not going to make noise you have to
see any led change either here we are in
the phone I push the modify files at
this point and you can see connected in
stock so now let's go back to all of our
lovely recipes that out of my beautiful
well known across the world
proof-of-concept
recipe when many words for taste and you
can see at them you can see it on your
says introduction this is modified and
for a little script value so I inverted
here you can see that it says only heat
to 86 degrees Fahrenheit and we should
see if our temperature here so let's try
something it start and Louise the on
first off so I go back to my dashboard
and right now I'm waiting for this to
kind of update here so now I'm going to
update we can go through a few kind of
attack scenarios with this right so the
first thing is I can see it on and you
can see cool heating level step one a
three which is really really cool
because our Regional instruction was
only want that so now you can see three
steps are happening yeah heats a hundred
twenty five degrees Fahrenheit which is
not 86 degrees which we put so boom we
can actually control stuff here pretty
neat right now few things right so we
just kind of cheat a little using a
rooted device so I could easily figure
out what recipe I want to modify now if
you didn't really care you can modify
all turn it the actual recipe files
themselves are stored on that shared
directory
so you can do it there another trick you
can do is also modifying it transit
McDaniel because these files are sent
over point text HTTP it's just as if it
doesn't check in turn which we obviously
put so yeah so the good news is you
can't set it how to higher temperature
Sam what was intended right it still
maxed out at 284 degrees Fahrenheit
however you could do a lot of knock your
since you could put the lower values you
can cook to play doctor sounds you to
end early there's a lot things you can
do in that regard so yeah okay 122
degrees chips table at 125 which and
then your ear a couple beeps and that'll
be our very clear indication that this
isn't multi cool see offices behind food
trying to point out the facts right
there alright there's not in the
original instruction either and this one
should also I think wait for another
minute and that's going to make some
more detail on this body so yet clear
demonstration we're changing the glance
which is pretty cool I haven't been able
to get to explode but you could under
cook food you could change things so it
doesn't cook rinses yeah creamy kind of
fix is actually crazy for these guys all
they have to do though is you know top
star stuff an SD card and together the
rich piece anyway thanks for that so
what else I got here yeah like I said
man in the middle if your network
attacker you could mess with this a
bunch the other thing I was thinking on
the flight like I could make like a pot
or like ransomware or like I ruin your
food until you pay me money which could
happen right and then based on this I'm
really hesitant how they're keeping
track of State so I even I've just
scratched the surface I'm like offending
malicious ble input to this thing so
yeah there's a bunch of other things so
we have about a minute left so I'll take
questions and then for future work you
could totally make a Metasploit plugin
for this which would be really cool and
then I mentioned the fuzzing the actual
Bluetooth stack so thank you for your
time I have fun and yeah I'll leave it
up Thanks