welcome everyone welcome hi welcome to
the battle for oceans are you team GUI
are you team command-line I am team GUI
I'm Tracy Mei leaf also known as InfoSec
Sherpa my co-presenter in crime here's
Joe gray he is team command line and he
is c3 PJ all thank you so we want to
make this fun but real quick we just
wanted to kind of explain the purpose of
this talk we are not saying that one is
necessarily bad or better than the other
one way of doing thing we want to show
you different ways to retrieve OSINT so
my background is that I am a here we go
I have a library background so I know
how to find stuff so has a text
background he knows to find how to find
things another way so what we're going
to do is going to show you different
ways to find things and here's our our
credentials with each of our our spirit
animal is a Tigger
mine's a a cheetah apparently oh yeah so
this is going to be good so just real
quick little give you overview so we do
not have a ton of time I alone could
spend an hour talking about GUI ways to
retrieve stuff he would spend an hour
doing stuff so just going clockwise
we're going to do a little brief intro
which we're in the middle of now I'm
going to talk first about GUI stuff he's
going to talk about command line Joe is
going to continue the reins holding the
reins and do a live demo and then we're
going to have a Q&A but we also are
going to have a giveaway but you have to
be present to win so you have to say put
and watch our whole conversation so we
have some of the same stuff I came up
with what I thought was a very clever
way to give away the books that remains
to be seen will figure it out well I was
going to tell people move up this isn't
a Gallagher show if you don't know that
reference ask an old person or look it
up but she kind of helped sweeten things
up a little bit since you're all a bunch
of Smarties we have some Smarties and
we'll see how good my throwing arm is
and I'm also going to periodically throw
candy out because I don't want to see
the top to your head looking down at
your phone or showing you some cool
stuff but please wait until we're done
talking
about it because we worked really hard
on this so so you know heads up for
candy okay all right cool so and since
Jo and I are both talkers we are
meticulously timing our talks
so that we don't run into each other's
stuff that want to make this an hour and
45 minute long advance for system
security podcast yeah exactly we are and
that's all so that as a practicum Idul
is oh so quick quick comment so Joe and
I met for the first time yesterday we
worked on this distance we met each
other over Twitter we work on his
podcast together advanced persistent
security podcast and we worked on this
all remotely so if you are looking to
present at a con don't just wait to you
know meet someone in person it is 2017
if you meet me someone on the interwebs
you can work with them and do a project
so we're pretty excited about it and
hope you like it too
all right oh there we go okay okay
so let's start with Twitter so a couple
things you may not know you who knew
that you had two who knew that you did
not have to be logged in to Twitter to
search it anybody knew that okay cool
Smarties we've got some Smarties here
awesome so that's important to know so
there they have this advanced search
screen they like to hide it but it's
there that's the URL for it and there's
some cool ways of doing things so why do
you want to do this well Twitter has
something crazy like 300 million posts
daily or monthly or something like that
so they have a lot of content that's a
lot of low-hanging fruit to go after if
you're trying to find information so you
know go to social media people are
posting stuff all the time so what I'm
going to show you is you know you don't
just first to get a get the wall and
expect something to stick use the tools
that these search engines gave you now
keep in mind they were not built in
search engines so things are wonky so
here are some examples of how you can
pull information out do it if you leave
you're not eligible for the book
journaling
all right so let's start with an easy
advance Twitter search if you use the
phrase here to : Walmart that means all
tweets sent to Walmart with the keyword
defective and you tell it I only wanted
to filter out tweets with images so
you'll get a whole string the people who
took pictures of defective things at
Walmart why is this interesting well I
worked at law firms for 10 years don't
you think that would be interesting for
products liability standpoint that was
low hanging fruit to pull out if you're
trying to find out it's a customer or a
client had some issues with their
product go to social media are people
complaining about it chances are you're
going to see a chair that didn't fold
correctly I love this one the chair
didn't fold up they call the defective
so they just left it in the beach
parking lot alternatively with this if
you're ever doing a protection game you
need a name to pose as this is where
you're going to get your name so if
we're going to be the good guy cursing
of the phrases Chris could be the bad
guy you can complain and that'll be just
within your pre tag and I wanted to
highlight the the top and the latest in
case you weren't aware if you want to
search things that had the most retweets
the most likes the most things that were
interacted with or sponsored tweets
they'll show up is top if you want
straight-up chronological you click
latest it'll always default to tops and
make sure you're aware of that
so now let's get into fancy this is a
real search that worked as tested it as
of this morning I had to do some
research again for a for law firm and
this is well I knew that there was a gas
explosion in Manhattan
it was around those dates around March
20 you know end of March time ish so
these are all search tools that you use
in Twitter this is all done in the
bubble I did this in the in the bubble
so they have things you can do near now
this is dependent upon people having
their geo-tagging on on their phones now
I know smart people like us don't have
that enabled but a lot of people don't
so take advantage of that and you can
even do a mile radius and then the since
in the before or since and until we're
like before and after so I'm searching
tweets from that time period
and this is a whole string of photos
which to an insurance company or a law
firm this is gold because the next step
would be then some paralegal will reach
out to those people and maybe get a
statement or a journalist might you know
get a statement from someone may I use
your tweet rather you know being able to
find things on site so this is how you
can really narrow things down all right
next question how much our hands how
many people have heard of Twitter list
okay here I want you start throwing eye
candy make yourself useful okay all
right excellent keep those hands up if
you actually use them all right if you
somebody gets we have nerds wave nerds
and Smarties so maybe don't serve the
Nerds are kind of heavy be careful but
if somebody wants their nerd come as I
get nerd okay
come get it nerd uh-huh okay so okay so
why are our lists import okay all right
the candies over now I'm talking again
okay so why are Twitter lists important
so true story I was hired by a company
to do competitive intelligence and the
company said we want you to find out who
our biggest rivals customers are but we
don't want you to spend any money
because of course that's how you do
research but anyway because I am you
know enterprising and clever and all
that good stuff because I am the Sherpa
I start poking around the company's
social media and I notice that somebody
was dumb enough to have Twitter lists
called clients potential clients in
imitations of you know party invites
things like that they spelled it all out
for me so I couldn't believe my good
luck so quickly did some screencaps I
did save the URLs that I thought surely
somebody's going to wise up at some
point and make these private so that I
can't see them but I had proof of both
of them it was gold I couldn't believe
it I couldn't believe someone was that
stupid so right note make sure your
Twitter list or private if you don't or
don't call them something so obvious
like clients or customers so that's a
good way to do Osen is by looking at the
social media list now how you get to
list as you go to that's my profile and
you can go you know you click down on
your photo and you see lists there's two
different kinds and ones that your
scribe two and ones that you're a member
of and you can also create your own new
list I have it circled in red there now
I thought I discovered a loophole last
month but I checked it again last week
and it didn't work anymore but I'll just
tell you what I thought I found I was
all excited I thought I found a way to
bypass the privacy public saying because
if you are on a public list you get
notified that someone added you to a
list whenever I tweet about data
visualization I get this you've been
added to data visits experts I'm like
why why does one article make me an
expert but I initially set up a list
made them private added people and then
made it public initially at the end of
March it never sent any generation
notices like yes I found a loophole and
then somebody must have fixed it because
when I did that again a month later and
and changed it all of a sudden all these
notifications popped up and they were
all my own accounts so I wasn't like
sending that to people who didn't know I
added them but the reason why I'm
telling that story is Twitter changes
all the time they're always changing
functionality so don't expect that
something that works six months ago was
going to work again and especially let's
be very careful that you make lists
private if you don't want people to see
them because otherwise people will be
notified so now you're probably thinking
okay this is great Tracy well what if I
want to find a list to follow okay so
because Twitter loves to mess with us
they disabled the feature how you could
search for lists in their own Twitter
clients that's awesome right so you have
to go to the Google so this is these are
ways how you find lists you tell it you
know that you want the site Twitter you
want the in URL you want the word list
and then you want you know members if
you're looking members of a certain list
and I showed you three different options
then you want your qualifier so what you
want to have cyber in it you can use
with or without quotes you can use a
hash tag that will bring up lists that
have that word or that hash tag or
something in it describing it that's how
you can find a list of cyber people to
follow or things like that or if you
want to follow people you know with
Descon that's how you find it so you
have to go to Google to find Twitter
list so that's pretty interesting I
think so anyway so okay so who here is
not
on Facebook not give them people from
candy give them some candy not on
Facebook okay okay so good job for you I
wish I had your your strength okay okay
all right so so this is a two-parter
slide here all right last one okay pay
attention we have lots of candy just
come up and see us afterwards okay so
don't worry about the van without
windows it's just wine okay so this is a
two part slide one I found this article
in Business Insider's tech insider piece
and this is what I want to talk to you
about you know thinking creatively and
thinking outside the box as far as
resources
you know you might follow a lot of text
you know and security things and that's
great but if you're you know trying to
do awesome stuff you know think about
some of these other resources think
about all the business pages if you want
to be really on top of what changes
there are in social media follow the
accounts that these are engineering and
they're they're blogs and Twitter has
all kinds of like blog and help and
engineering and API Twitter accounts
specifically where do you think all the
news outlets get their information they
follow all those accounts so that's the
point one part the second part is I
blacked out stuff to protect the
innocent and the unwilling to
participate in this presentation you can
go into your Facebook account type in
photos like by in a name I do not follow
this person on Facebook but yet I can
still see photos that they liked because
the photos that they liked had the had a
public setting so it doesn't matter if
your individual setting is private if
you like a photo that's public it shows
up in this search string and I just did
this like this week so this still works
until Facebook figures out a way we'll
take questions at the end okay
so hey we all know about backdoors and
things and stuff blah blah blah so
there's a site called academia.edu if
you go to it it has all these ways to
log in log into here or log in here log
in here it's so st. they make it so hard
to see there's a row at the bottom that
has different subject areas like physics
and things like
that if you click on one of those you
get into the site without having to hug
in so be enterprising if you're trying
to find something there might be a way
to get into it now again remember I came
from the law firm environment so I would
not pull these are full of like academic
papers and things like that that people
post themselves but what I would do for
a site like this is I would get the
citation and then go pull it from a
reputable source because I would have to
make sure that things were admissible in
court if it got to that so I would just
poke around on this site find citations
take them to the actual journal that
they originally appeared in and pulled
it from there
so that's why there's a couple things
here just to show that there's you know
ways to get into things that look like
you have to require a sign in if you
want to be under the radar but also just
use it to take information elsewhere and
get it from more reputable source I
couldn't use things like striven and all
that stuff I had to get the actual like
from the source stuff all right what's
the scoop I love this site so Scoob sq
oh okay it used to be free I think they
want to charge me 100 bucks now it's
still pretty cheap but this site is good
for sort of social engineering sort of
things do you want to pretend that
you're from the law firm that a company
hired to do intellectual property do you
want to pretend that you're from the
auditor that does a company you know
books and things like that this site
scoop will all at once search SEC file
filings
patent and federal law cases all in one
fell swoop so my example here it's
really hard to see because it was a
small page but I just typed in cyber
security and I was able to see you know
SEC documents you know financial
documents patent lawsuits it's a good
way if you're trying to get background
information on the company or like said
if you want to verify like if you're
going to try to pretend to be an auditor
and you say you're from Deloitte and
that company doesn't use Deloitte you're
quiet so don't just rely on do on a
random google search that you're going
to get that information go to the actual
SEC filings because that's legit right
SEC is legit hashtag SEC is legit and
it's a whole supply
so the last site that I want to go over
is Storify show hands to know Storify
okay so some candy yet those of those
people so since we're so few I'm going
to put some words down the aisle
okay so Storify so okay actually well
this is a good example I did
so our lovely ca here did a great
Twitter chat story one time giving he
loves to dispense information and vice
and things like that and he does a
series of tweets where he tells a story
and the first one of the first times I
saw that you did it I was like kind of a
DM would you mind if I Storify your talk
so what I did he gave me he gave me
permission so I went into Storify and I
pulled all his tweets and I put them in
a pretty row like that and added some
graphics and some explanation and sent a
link out there so that when you could
read it it's not just a clever name you
read it like a story because all of them
are stacked on one top of each other you
manually pull them in there so it's a
great way to capture storytelling like
that and do things but it also is a good
search engine so I tried to it to me
that looks really small hopefully can
see that so you can search a variety of
social media platforms on Storify and
multiple information in what I like
about Storify is you can so I told it
that I wanted to search for tweets that
had the word malware in it but in
Baltimore so then this map popped up and
it was like we're in Baltimore would you
like me to search a one-mile radius or
25 mile radius and it gives you some
other options as well but you can do
this for Instagram and a whole Flickr
and all kinds of other sites and Twitter
so not only can you just pull that
information but then you can also just
make it look pretty because all you have
to do is drop and drag and put it over
there so again if you're dealing with
someone who is maybe you know a c-suite
or something who isn't very savvy don't
send them you know a CSV dump you know
or don't waste your time trying to make
a dump look pretty you know maybe you
can go in here and show some examples of
like hey I looked up our competition or
our company and I put them all in here
for you so it's a really nice way to
bring things together so before we move
on to Joe's
I just kind of wanted to say in summary
so you know get to know what Reese's
resources are out there there's probably
a hundred different social media
platforms that you don't know for
everyone that you know if you are doing
research in a specific country chances
are that country may have its own
homegrown social media platform you know
China has them Brazil has them you know
you might need if you're not finding
what you need you may need to expand
where you're looking I always make the
analogy of you know think of research
like a funnel you know funnels are not
just for beer bombs anymore it's you
know you need to really cast a wide net
and then narrow things down I think I
see a lot of people who like to go into
Google and just through a whole string
of search words and expect things to
come up yeah you might get some hits but
you know narrow it down though
incrementally another just I'm going to
close on this story about how to use
your search time wisely so at my first
law firm job came in first thing in the
morning and this associate was like I
was up from midnight to 3:00 a.m.
searching for the Labor Code of the
Cayman Islands can you help me and I was
like oh you poor thing
okay so I had it in two seconds because
I knew to go to Google and do site
search okay why because I didn't I did
this kind of research all the time I
knew that gov dot KY was the Cayman
Islands government site I knew that it
was probably a buried PDF so I
specifically told it to search PDF and I
knew that the use of Queen's English so
I used the key word is labor with you
popped up right away but I didn't want
to make him feel that bad because you
know you put all that money go into law
school and everything so I was like so I
got my coffee check my email did a
couple that let him hang for a little
bit and then I sent it to him and I was
a genius and blah blah blah never spend
more than fifteen minutes searching for
something you know that that concept
gets drilled into your head better if
you ever worked at a job where you have
to build time as a librarian or law firm
I just have to bill every six minutes I
use I have to keep track of my time
every six minutes so I have a very keen
sense of how much time I'm spending on
stuff because time is money
your your time is money too you know
that's keeping you away from playing a
game or playing with your kids or going
out you know with a girlfriend or spouse
or boyfriend or whomever so you know if
you are if you find 15 minutes and you
still can't find something stop take a
break evaluate what you're looking at
ask for help ask you on Twitter or ask
for other resources go to your library
you know libraries have lots of
databases that you can have access to
you know if you pay city taxes you know
you probably can use the Baltimore
public library or your local library you
know be be thoughtful with your searches
you know be mindful of that so that's
why I just wanna tell you to save you a
lot of aggravation step back take a
breath and it will all come together and
that is my GUI presentation thank you so
that it's a pretty good right everybody
learn a lot from it I'll admit it's it's
pretty hard to follow so let's go ahead
and get this party started
with a team command-line so we're going
to start this out with I'll take what
our API is for 500 Alex so we need to
understand it with the command line
we're actually interacting with the same
resources that trades the interacts with
we're just doing it in a different way
so with that we're typically doing it
with an API which is an application
programming interface if you don't know
a lot of times you might use an API to
talk to a library of some sort not her
kind of library like a code library
there are api's for operating systems
many times it choose to share
information or in this context gather
information and then you know sometimes
it'll be like hey we have this service
we distribute video for this if you want
to use it on your website here is how
you get an API key and you can use our
code that's what is ultimately for but
in the ocean sense why would you want to
use the command line over the GUI
anybody have any ideas Automation yet in
data formatting faster yes
to a degree yes it's behind you so all
these things are true you can actually
gather the data it's in a flat file
you're not having to compile it out of
the web browsers and all that stuff you
can put your regular expressions against
it and move on to the next thing use
that to refine it and just keep moving
there is a certain level of maintaining
anonymity from it especially if you're
using an API key that's not really tied
to an account that's active another
thing that you have to worry about when
you're using the GUI like when you're
scoping somebody out on Facebook for
example when you start scoping them out
you may actually show up in people they
may know you don't want that right if
you're being a creeper you don't want
them to know you're being a creeper so
with with an account that I use actually
I get all kinds of recommendations it's
like no that engagements over I'm not
working with that company anymore
alternatively if you have in that same
email address that it's side to if you
have their email address in it it will
recommend you there as well so keep that
in mind but the big thing that I always
want to think of whenever I'm thinking
about you know Oh sent this right here
basically sums it up roses are red
violets are blue you can't see me but I
can see you and that's ultimately what
you want out of go sin so with this I'm
going to hit you with some memes and
then I'm going to kick kind of into the
demo mode because that's where most of
my talk lies it's kind of hard to talk
about a command line a lot right so
we're trying to apply underneath the
radar and Buzz Lightyear he's telling us
there's radar traps everywhere so if
we're going to be under the radar we
have to be cognizant of the radar so in
that sense let me shift gears for a
moment and I'm going to show you some
some little surprises that I came up
with so
I'm not rolling let me see if I can zoom
by then when I move it over yeah yeah
[Music]
Oh No I've heard the sound on now
yeah hand out some candy there we go
that's what I was looking for problem
behind podium not in keyboard so it
always is let's see here what am I
looking for here appearance here we go
just got to change the font give me just
a moment here aha how's that absolutely
so within this directory basically I've
got a I've got a couple of scripts of
value here we're going to focus on charm
pie and I've also put it up on github if
you want to steal it I've sanitized some
stuff out of it so in that regard and
here it is on github we'll just kind of
break through it a little bit here
that is the legit URL for it if you want
it but in this charm dot PI script
basically what I've done is I've created
a separate file that contain my clear
API keys because I'm in no way shape or
form going to put that up here for
someone to take a picture of but anyway
within within the script what it's
actually doing it's right here is just
setting up the encoding so that I can
have a little fun with it later this is
the definition for your download tweets
URL and we're looking for the screen
name the number of tweets and we're
excluding replies
and I'll show you the fields that
actually go with that here in just a
moment but in a sense basically we're
looking for the response and it's from
requests which is another Python library
that actually comes into this of course
using JSON is going to return the tweet
and then we're actually going to use
this to format it and then print it low
down below so within the actual code
here you can see that I've loaded
'besides charm we're going to get 150
tweet and under exclude replies we are
excluding reply so this is true so
moving back to a little putty let's just
go ahead and and we'll just call that
tram done shall we so okay so look it's
every single time every single the last
hundred fifty tweets that has crossed
these ads charms Twitter feed so how do
we make meaningful use of this well I'm
glad you asked so I've put another
script that I put in here that is a
parking scripted runs a regular
expression I'll show it to you in a
moment
but we'll just call that parse dealt tag
then we'll just catch Alan okay so now
we've set this actually setup by date
time a little bit of context here who
did it
all of that fun stuff same thing all
around and with that within this as well
I've actually got a second regular
expression which I should probably go
ahead and show you the first one
actually just takes the entire tweet
while the second one actually just
determined - it's communicating with who
else is mentioned in that and we see
here
thank you there we go
only hole - little bit here so I'm not
mirroring the screens over here so bear
with me a moment so going back here so
in par stop hi it's very simple with it
it just you just open the charm text
file and here's the regular expression
that's going to get your date your time
your message and all that and then for
contact there's the second regular
expression it's going to print both of
them and yes sir well in this case I
purposely went a little bit more
challenging as opposed to using one of
the libraries that actually tie Python
directly into the API and with this one
I wanted to break it up into two
different scripts because one of them
was being a little bit more
temperamental than the other because I'm
by no means a Python developer I'm not
heavy in Python at all so this was
actually kind of a stretch to get this
portion down at a later time if I were
actually going to try to build something
out of it I would actually put the
regular expression within the single
script and actually have it interactive
where you could make decisions what
context you want to see so forth and so
on but for the sake of simplicity that's
why I put it into two scripts for this
but with it you know it's just running
those regular expressions and it's
running a find all across it and that's
what's dumping the data out from the
Osen point of view the reason that
that's actually somewhat valuable is
because if you're trying to get to
someone if you're if you're doing a paid
engagement and you're actually trying to
get to someone per se you're going to
need to know who their contacts are
because you might need to exploit them
to get there you may need to pose if you
were coming for me you might need to
pose as Tracy and say hey Joe there's a
talk there's a CFP open it up are you
interested
that'll probably get my ear so in that
sense you know knowing who people
communicate with that allows you to
enumerate their personal network and get
better information about them for more
effective intelligence be it for social
engineering or anything else you're
trying to do so within that scope kind
of that with a script portion there but
have no fear got a data split here and
[Music]
data void is an open source tool written
in Python and basically it just aims to
scrape data you need to get some API
keys it ties in very well
well it doesn't communicate with recon
in G but they are very similar in nature
and with them basically the keys to the
kingdom happened to lie within what you
have API keys for so in this sense this
one is more for going after like emails
and domains where recon in G has those
same capabilities but you can actually
go for a little bit more like things
like out have I been poned and profiles
elsewhere in geolocation information if
you have the correct API keys so with
this one we're just going to do the
username ascent one if I could spell
today and let's do ok so doesn't look
like it so much
look there too so they've got a
Pinterest so there we go so and you
can't really hate on Pinterest I did for
the longest and then I found out if you
post like somewhat relevant memes on
it'll it'll attract people to your
website so so that's probably why no
hate there but that's the kind of you
know this is the kind of information
that you could definitely make a
meaningful use of in your ascent you
know do is this because people typically
use the same username like Tony he's
probably da underscore 6 6 7 everywhere
we're close to it you want to put it to
the test here we have a tribute
what we got here
oh you've got a Pinterest - you do
what's that what's your user name
cigarette okay so your deviantART there
you go so you know from this this
actually allows you if you want to apply
this to like social engineering that's
actually and and I'll talk about this
more in the workshop tomorrow but you
know once you get an email address or a
user name this allows you to start
building a profile about someone and
oftentimes when you're dealing with
oesn't that's what you're trying to do
you're trying to build the profile so
that you can use something against them
in a perfect spearfishing engagement and
understanding that there's no such thing
as perfect but a near-perfect style
engagement and then of course we we have
tools like recon ng which I don't think
will go too heavily into recon ng but
it's something worth being cognizant of
because it is pretty much from the
command line I understand the font sucks
so I'm just going to go with showing the
modules so basically here's here's what
you have in terms of capability
discovery interesting files is always
one of my favorites when I'm running
Osen against a company why because well
you never know you might find something
out on the public internet that's not
supposed to be there and before I go
further with this there's a module in
recon ng that I found to be very
valuable as well and that
is there wikileaks module you can
actually search to see if the company
you are after is on WikiLeaks so and
then within here you have other
capabilities as well you can import as a
list or a CSV you can also do it export
CSV HTML but basically here you can see
that you've got like companies in the
contacts looking for github who is
contacts credentials there's have I been
poned Ashes org Mehta crawler that's a
really good one if you're looking for
metadata like academia.edu that she
mentioned I would use it a completely
different way I would go in and try to
scrape mated metadata out of people's
file so that I could gain information
about them yes absolutely
I mean I highly recommend running au
sent on yourself because you know in
some cases you can control what's out
there in other cases you can't and it's
important to know when you can when you
can't and you know something that
Michael basil talks about a lot of the
disinformation campaigns which I've not
really achieved that level of Oh st.
quirkiness I guess would be the proper
term yet but I'm definitely stocking up
on the aluminum foil to start going down
that rabbit hole at some point so
continuing down you know there's
tonalist which it doesn't really exist
anymore
you can enumerate other domains this is
very useful for like the brute suffix
because I just did a fishing engagement
this last week against an organization
it was a little bit too accurate and it
got shut down in about four hours but
not before I had almost twenty email
addresses and password combinations out
of a very small organization they could
have actually caught me before I even
started if they ran this because they
would have found where they have calm
for their email domain I used dot us so
and I'm a huge fan of dot life and Club
because they're 99 or 88 cents and a
dollar eighty eight on Namecheap huge
fan of those but you know you can just
keep going and going through
kanji there's I mean eaten we could talk
about this for hours on end it's very
robust there's a lot of good stuff with
it and it is from the command line you
do have to have API keys but it also
produces a really nice report if you
want to hand it over to management at
the end of everything so they can
understand where their organization lies
so it's a really good tool for that but
now I'm actually going to do something
out of the ordinary and in doing so
whenever I find my cursor I thought I
just saw it there it is so with this I'm
actually going to for a moment defect
from Team CLI city GUI has anybody seen
this before this is the Facebook live
map I come I come I I commonly refer to
this as the Oh cent pew pew map what you
see here a little bubble here seeing
these are everybody that's on Facebook
live right now publicly I think if you
look at my other tabs you might see the
direction I'm going to go with this so
let's look see what do we have here and
it's only got three people watching we
you need somebody that's got a lot like
quite a few watch let's see what's going
on right here on now I need to zoom in
some more yes
so with it being a bigger dot there's a
good chance that it's got more oh yeah
338 excellent so honestly I don't even
care what they're talking about
I'm just doing this for demonstration
purposes so here we have it here what
you need to know is right here is the
video ID what could possibly go wrong
anybody familiar with this place you're
ready for your skin to crawl if there's
a time that's going to do it it's going
to be right now because if you see what
the next tab is I think you know exactly
where it's going Oh what do we have here
lat are they doing like lat races in the
gym are they doing like the long jump in
the Olympics now actually I think this
is latitude longitude so let's just have
a look around over here I'm good the
laughs shall we
nothing ever goes wrong right
pew-pew Oh what what's going on here how
long do there you go
I don't hear their party my first yeah
so like with this one I actually ran it
once oh there's something in Baltimore
let's see let's see who it is what
they're up to
shall we with this you know honestly
true applicability for this before like
while the Facebook killer stuff was
going on I was like I really don't want
this dude to kill anybody but if he
would go live publicly one time I could
get him with this anybody could get him
with this but you know let's either here
to there man
so with us just know you know when I
first came across this we were I was in
Chattanooga Tennessee and we actually
looked at local videos and at the
University of Tennessee Chattanooga
dorms across the street from each other
you had one lady absolutely running
Trump into the mud and the other was
doing a makeup tutorial like okay oh
absolutely
right because because you can actually
get environmental data you can determine
hey are there other people walking
around in here or do they look like
they're in the bedroom or what kind of
ambient noises exist what's going on
with this right I've never tried it with
the VPN I want to try it but I'm also
ultra private with Facebook
um so I've not but I would think that
there's a good possibility that using a
VPN would actually circumvent that and
if I really wanted to be like really
creepy I would actually take a
screenshot from Google Maps like Street
View and actually post it as a comment
but I've not achieved that level of
creepy yet one night Joe one day right
and that could be the case if you have
location services enabled then there's
that opportunity alternatively you know
I have a VPN on my phone as well so I
dumped out another location so if I
since I don't use location services it
may try to triangulate off that IP
address as well so that's definitely
something worth putting putting to
practice sure well I know one VPN
service dumped out in Seattle and has
stuff in New York as well one service
ironically enough that's about all
that's going on in that area right now
let's see what she's up to is this a
makeup tutorial let me go ahead and so
we take the the ID here and I almost
guarantee you this is going to be
residential let's go ahead and reload
this just since we don't know how long
she's been on right okay
oh here we go again if this was the 80s
I'd be saying something about here I do
again on my own than anyway that is that
is a I'll show you as soon as it so here
we go again oh it is residential so
let's just have a look at the end of the
cul-de-sac and this is the time that you
break out the spider-man a screenshot
neat meme and just go neat screen shoot
it so when I first did this actually
there was a political pundit they were
they were all up on their soapbox and I
was like okay y'all run this and I ran
it and they were at the back of their
cold a house or I'm sorry Cole de sac at
their home in Greenville South Carolina
they had red siding they had a white
Mercedes SUV and a black top exactly so
from that scope that's about all there
is to me making your skin crawl it's
cause it's corrosive just enter it in
the browser okay and it just wears a you
just got to watch the screen over there
oh yeah I don't have her eating on so
just you don't even have to type in
Google because this Chrome just go
straight for what you're doing yes
Michael nozzles are after after this is
over are we not on the interwebs we were
all right well just talk through it
anyway so you know if you go to news
google.com
and it has the things across the top and
one of them is cool if you drop that
down you can limit by date when you
search for the news he's gonna try it
again I do a lot of research for
clients and I need things that were you
know date specific and things like that
so hmm gosh
yeah news that Google does so we can't
see it on here there we go okay so I
can't see I'm still if you give a way to
get so so yeah and I'm getting the wind
up court here I'm going to choke I think
so hard about that
nope no I don't think so no the Ord okay
let me up be like hey man you're gonna
come hang out the bullpen and close this
out in the eighth inning sorry I can't
I've actually concealed by month I you
know I think okay so I also do a lot of
foreign language searching but so if I
go to Austria's Google Google eighty
most countries have their own their own
Google homepage just do fiber is a good
word that crosses language parent here
so the setups the same so even though I
don't know German I can just kind of I
know that mom at is month so the cool
thing is no matter which Google News say
you go to much language it's all pretty
much set up the same way so again for me
I do a monthly project where I look up
fifteen different countries and I do
subject searches so I look at a handful
of languages and know I don't know them
all but I get to learn them I get to
learn where things are in Google in in
Google Austria for example and it's all
pretty much the same so it's kind of
cool if again if you're not finding
because I found the Twitter if you try
to search foreign languages and Twitter
in the English web painting of the site
if you go to like Twitter France you'll
get some different and even sometimes
better results so if you're not finding
what you need and you know that it's you
know in another language or Virginian of
the country go to that country straight
so that's going to
than you do okay so when we do the
giveaway and then we'll have questions
real quick so ensure we get to the
giveaway so a little moral astoria so
hopefully you've learned some stuff
round of applause you guys aren't
anything and so that's all right good
good so obviously as you know there's a
part of ocean where you just need to be
good right you need to know stuff you
need to be good but there's all parts of
ascent where sometimes it's better to be
lucky than good so we brought this this
type of giveaway together is where we
have two decks of cards here I have
joker representing zero up through nine
and we're going to talk draw two
different cards it's the last two digits
of your cellphone match you get one of
these looks and we're just going to ask
you a show at your phone number we're
not going to say at anyone or anything
but that was a least intrusive way and
the easiest way we could think to do
this yourself I'm going to call it out
so I'm shuffling these and Gent to hold
the books up and if we have ties or
whatever we'll figure it out fit
Sooey here we have the Seminole social
engineering by Christopher head naggy
and here we have mining the social web
so the whole API stuff right here sorts
where you're going to find it right so
because I don't want to disqualify
anyone Jim put this down I'll have him
choose the card and shuffle these all
right pick pick a card this play to hand
or anything just hold on to it first
hold on for it come see it yeah oh man
that's my phone number don't say yeah
all right take another card signal the
card any card
all right if your cell phone number ends
in 8 1 or 1 8 you have an eight and an
eight come on up show us your phone come
on up social phone that's that's a way
to people well that's perfect
so really we got we got like a few
situational slides to work through as
well so I don't always Facebook stalk
people but when I do you're welcome
so yes yes
I didn't put it up here but it's
github.com slash josephus jo c e ph us
that's like my only legit repo out there
right now everything else is just clones
yeah so just to reiterate plugging the
podcast she's on PVC sick regularly
she's periodically on event persistent
security sword and shield did the
giveaway my employer of course so thanks
for having us thanks for being a captive
audience if you're interested in working
for sword and shield
we're actually hiring if you think
you're qualified or you just want to
find out more about it talk to me after
we're done I'll tell you kind of what
we're looking for because it's kind of
vague HR told me what they were looking
for and it's like okay sure I let me try
to get the signal to noise with that
ideally they're looking for somebody in
Knoxville Tennessee are willing to
relocate there but if you're qualified
enough they'll they'll accept remote and
if you're looking to add a Sherpa to
your work force I am looking for a job
yes so yes so she is at info sixer
Sherpa and I am at C underscore 3p Jo
all right hope you guys had a great time
thank you so much for guy
we did it