okay we're going to get started my name
is Jeff Kossoff and I am a professor at
the United States Naval Academy cyber
science department and I'm presenting
with midshipman Dennis DB who is a first
class meaning he will be graduating next
month and we will be talking about the
Cyber Security Act of 2015 and the
related laws involving monitoring
information sharing and operating
defensive measures before we start a
full disclosure I'm a lawyer so as most
lawyers I have a list of disclaimers
that I have to present first everything
that we say only represents our own
personal views they don't represent the
views of the Naval Academy the
Department of Navy Department of Defense
possibly each other just our own
personal views also I am a lawyer as I
said so I will be providing you a lot of
information about laws and legal issues
but that does not substitute for legal
advice I understand there's a
presentation yesterday about Maryland
law which is great because you have to
always consider not just federal law
state law local laws the laws of all
other countries so this is just one
aspect to sort of look at one some legal
issues involving monitoring information
sharing defensive measures so with that
we just wanted before we started on the
substance of the cybersecurity Act we
wanted to talk a little bit about us why
we're doing this why you're having
people from the Naval Academy talk about
both public and private information
sharing I'm on the faculty of the Naval
Academy cyber science department which
was created a few years ago and we have
we basically have two approaches to
educating our Midshipmen about cyber
every Midshipmen is required to take two
classes in cyber security regardless of
their major so a history major or
mechanical engineering major they all
take two classes that gives them a broad
education on both the technical and
policy aspects of cyber we also have a
cyber operations major where Midshipmen
who are particularly interested in
divert take a wide range of classes on
both the technical side legal policy
social factors side to give them a
really wide-ranging do cyber so we're
really trying to take all approaches to
educate our Midshipmen I will put in a
very brief plug our department is
growing we have a few tenure-track
openings available so if anyone here has
a PhD in computer science or a related
field and would love to have one of the
coolest jobs I think at least in cyber
in this area
please come and speak with me because
it's a really great and cool opportunity
so a bit of my background I am a lawyer
as I said I before coming to the Naval
Academy I represented mainly large
companies both helping them plan for
information technology plans but also
more frequently after they had a data
breach helping with the mad scramble to
figure out what we can do and minimize
the chances of being sued now at the
Naval Academy I teach cyber security law
cyber security ethics and cyber security
policy and I write about similar issues
I recently wrote a book about the first
text book about cyber security law which
was published in February of this year
and is already becoming outdated because
there have been so many developments
like what we're going to talk about
today which I find really fun before I
was a lawyer I was a technology
journalist at the Oregonian covering
mainly technology policy so I have a
real interest in talking about these
issues and writing about them now let
Mitchum and Dede talk a little bit
everyone on Dennis TV so I am a mission
bent Academy I'm graduating next month
and then I'm going to go drive boats in
San Diego for a couple years I am NOT a
lawyer so I don't have a large
disclaimer anything I say is my opinion
only I folks thread team blue team shots
members of my security team who are here
right now the reason I got into the
policy side of things is I've been doing
the technical for long enough and I
wanted to figure out how it actually
worked and make sure that the policy
guys aren't making all the rules with
that
and I just will add Midshipmen jeebies
he's probably more modest than I am
about his accomplishments this pad in
addition to work beyond the successful
CDX team last fall he also was on a team
at the NYU cybersecurity Awareness Week
policy competition there were more than
90 participants mainly law school
participants and Dennis and his teammate
placed second nationally so I bagged a
little bit about that so anyway enough
with introductions what we're here to
talk about today is the Cyber Security
Act of 2015 this it was about a hundred
and thirty six pages so I'm not going to
post every single bit of it on the slide
but I just wanted to show you what it is
it was passed in late 2015 and if you
see on the top of it it says one seven
to eight that is not a typo it was paged
1728 of a bill that was well over 2,000
pages which was the budget that was
necessary to have the government running
this was something that had been debated
for a very long time and as we'll talk
about was fairly controversial for some
provisions related to information
sharing and like most legislation it
ends up getting passed when it's folded
into a much larger building needs to
pass at the last minute so ah this is
the bill and when I say that it had been
contentious the main issue that had
arisen for years and years had been that
the Department of Homeland Security
through us cert had been really
encouraging companies to share
information about cyber threats that
they'd been facing and successful ways
that they had been able to defend
against them now from a sort of social
point of view that sounds great you want
to have as much sharing so the
government knows what's happening that
could help companies respond to these
threats because the government care is
not just from an economic perspective
but from a national security perspective
as we saw for example at the Sony hack
so for years and years DHS had been
saying please share more information
with us and the companies had a pretty
valid reason of why they
want to do that and that is we don't
want to be sued we don't want to start
giving first we don't want to give the
Federal Trade Commission which we'll
talk about in a little bit information
about possible security vulnerabilities
that we should have noticed and also a
lot of the information about cyber
threats may very well contain personally
identifiable information and all other
sorts of private matter
that would be that the company could be
sued for if it provided it to the
government so the companies have been
saying we want immunity from being sued
for these sorts of things there was a
big spirited and pretty well informed
debate between the sort of electronic
civil rights groups corporate America
the federal government and that's what
that's really what had held up this this
law from passing there were a lot of
debates about exactly how to word it but
they actually eventually after years and
years came up with a final draft that
was a compromise and we'll talk about
how they compromise but it's basically
putting some privacy protections and
some requirements for removing
unnecessary personal information but
that so that's what the cybersecurity
Act basically the debate history was the
ultimate version of the cybersecurity
Act it's often talked about as the
information sharing bill which it is I
mean it does allow information sharing
it encourages information sharing but
there are two other provisions that are
not as commonly discussed and they
received actually very little coverage
in the media after this bill passed and
those were involving monitoring and
defensive measures so there are
provisions in there that we're going to
talk about that allow that at least
encourage and depending on how you
interpret it allow companies to take
certain steps to monitor their networks
for cybersecurity threats and take
defensive measures so it's the but to
understand sort of the scope of what
they allow and how it changed changes
the existing legal landscape we have to
first look at what laws currently at
apply and what restrictions there are so
like I said at the beginning of the
presentation this is just mainly at the
federal level almost all of the laws
that I'm talking about have state
analogues and frankly we just don't have
enough time to go over them but I want
to just at least talk about the
landscape as it existed when the
cybersecurity Act passed and then
discuss whether the cybersecurity act
actually changed anything and before I
do that I just also want to encourage
everyone if you have any questions along
the way please
questions comments please raise your
hand throughout I want this to be
interactive and again these are these
can be fairly complex subjects so the
main issue for monitoring often comes up
with the wiretap Act
so the wiretap Act prohibits the
interception of the content of wire oral
and electronic communications for cyber
this is mostly involving electronic
communications there's not a very clear
definition in the statute as to what
interception means but the way the
courts have interpreted it
they say that has to be contemporaneous
so it's basically data in transit being
intercepted can be prohibited prohibited
by the wiretap Act now the some courts
have gotten a little more expansive on
it there was a case a few years ago
where an IRS employee he was concerned
that his supervisor had been noticing
that he wasn't in the office all that
much because he wasn't an office all
that much so his solution rather than
talked to a supervisor was to set up an
auto forward rule on his outlook that
Auto forwarded all of the supervisors
received emails to his own personal
account I will just say as a lawyer I
highly recommend against doing this and
also just a matter of HR policy not a
great idea but he was charged with
violating the wiretap Act and his his
argument was this was not
contemporaneous because there was the
email had arrived in his supervisors
inbox before it was forward
and the judges unfortunately for him
said we're not going to buy that it was
close enough to contemporaneous that it
is a violation of the wiretap act the
wiretap act carries significant criminal
and civil penalties so it's very good
not to be in violation of it so um but
again it really does have to do with
data in transit there if data is stored
for a while there's another law we'll
talk about in a little bit but there are
some exceptions to the wiretap Act one
is consent so I'm sure many of your
employers when you log on there's some
banner that you don't read typically
that is consenting to allow your data to
be monitored you need very explicit
consent burying it in an employee
handbook more and more is not seen as
explicit consent bearing it in terms of
use for a service you really have to go
out of your way to make sure that the
that the persons providing consent
there's a wiretap order which is
basically like a warrant that a court
issued that requires demonstration of
probable cause of a crime providing the
communications to the intended recipient
obviously that's not going to violate
the wiretap Act the most common
exceptions to the wiretap Act is
rendition of service and this is really
especially for cybersecurity purposes so
if there's an act that is necessarily
incident to the rendition of service or
to the protection or rights of or
property that can be seen as an
exception to the wiretap Act in the
cybersecurity community it's always been
kind of a little unclear as to whether
that can be applied to just general
cybersecurity monitoring the and so
that's one thing that the cybersecurity
act may actually help clarify there's
also the trespasser exception and what
that basically says is that if you know
there's a trespasser on your network and
you can send to the government the
police the FBI getting onto your network
to monitor that active
that also can be an exception to the
wiretap Act briefly we I want to talk
about stored communications so wiretap
act again as data in transit or really
close to being in transit stored
Communications Act involves data that's
stored on a server now the caveat here
most of these computer laws these
computer crime laws were written in the
mid 80s and it shows um so there there's
one section that prohibits the
intentional access without authorization
of data that's an electronic storage
there's a very arcane definition of what
actually it means to be an electronic
storage but that's basically essentially
hacking into stored communications
section 702 then prohibits service
providers from disclosing communications
to third parties with a number of
exceptions I won't go through all of
them one of them involves consent so
again clicking on a banner saying that
you do agree to doing this they also
have something in a similar exception
for being incident to the rendition or
service of the provider and protecting
the property of the provider there's
also a court order issue I don't know if
any of you have heard about the 180-day
debate that's gone on but basically the
the bottom line is again this was
written in the 80s and there's a rule
that says that if email is unopened and
on a server for less than 180 days the
government needs to get a warrant to
access your stored communications if
it's older than 180 days or opened they
just need a subpoena or a court order
which is much lower standard Congress is
trying to address that and to meet
require warrant no matter how old the
information is and there are other
exceptions well Computer Fraud and Abuse
Act I'm hope that everyone knows about
what the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act
criminalizes it's it's seven different
types of activities committing espionage
so basically
bad acts involving classified
information hacking to obtain
information trespassing a federal
government computer doing something
fraudulent on a network causing damage
on a computer trafficking and passwords
or other access issues and just
threatening to hack which basically are
threatening to not provide information
back which is essentially like
ransomware so all of these involve acts
that are without authorization or an
excess of authorization and the courts
are really divided as to what that means
briefly I'll just say there's also
privacy and data security laws there is
a prohibition under the Federal Trade
Commission act of unfair and deceptive
trade practices basically meaning you
can't lie about your data security or
privacy practices and you also just
can't really be reckless with your
personally identifiable information what
companies worry about most are common
law claims of privacy and inadequate
data security under a variety of claims
that have existed for hundreds of years
like negligence breach of contract and
really I I'll state my bias here I'm not
really a fan of plaintiffs lawyers
because they will try to come up with
anything after a data breach or some
sort of accident a loss of personal
information to bring a lawsuit against
companies so it's something to be really
careful about they filed class-action
lawsuits that can cause damages and the
tens of millions of dollars we also have
industry specific laws that require data
security and privacy protections HIPAA
which covers health and health providers
the gramm-leach-bliley Act that covers
financial institutions a video Privacy
Protection Act which there's a long
history involving a Supreme Court
nominees video rental records being
disclosed but that covers video viewing
information the Securities and Exchange
Commission requires companies to
disclose certain cyber security
vulnerabilities and there's a California
law called Cal
which requires companies to post their
privacy practices so now we're going to
get that's the background what I want to
do now is talk about how the cyber
security act may change that landscape
and the caveat I have here is we're not
entirely sure as of this morning there's
not a single Court opinion that has
interpreted the cybersecurity Act it was
passed about a year and a half ago so
there may be some cases in the pipeline
but right now it's really all we have is
basically the text of the law
we don't have courts saying how to
approve it how how to implement it but
the monitoring provision again did not
get very much attention
partly because nobody knows what it
means so it starts off with
notwithstanding any other provision of
law does anyone have any guess as to
what that might mean not let's see good
so basically as long as there's not a
lot another law Barton yeah that's
that's definitely one one interpretation
yep
yes and that's uh that's how some
interpret it and there's a whole other
school of thought and court opinions
that say notwithstanding any other
provision law of law means that if the
cybersecurity act conflicts with the
wiretap Act that you would then ignore
the wiretap Act but the two
interpretations that you had say
otherwise the basically there's no
settled definition of why
notwithstanding any other provision of
law is in any statute because it
confuses every judge and every lawyer I
refer to it as one of the sort of terms
that's the full employment for lawyers
act because it justifies us billing
hundreds and hundreds of dollars an hour
to make our arguments about it so what
it could mean let's at least what
companies are trying to say is this
takes priority over other laws so if it
does then a company may for
cybersecurity purposes monitor and a
what it basically says they can monitor
their own systems they can monitor the
systems of the federal government or
another company if they get written
consent and they can monitor information
stored on all of those things so let's
just say that that notwithstanding is
the interpretation that companies would
like to go with so it's only for a
cybersecurity purpose so what the
statute defines cybersecurity purpose as
is the purpose of protecting an
information system or information that
is stored on processed by or transiting
an information system from a
cybersecurity threat or security
vulnerability excellent what are cyber
security threats or cyber security
vulnerabilities what the statute says
here is that a cyber security threat and
I won't read the whole thing but could
adversely impact the security
availability confidentiality or
integrity of an information system okay
so that's pretty broad it's not just
violating the terms of use but cyber
security threat seems to be something
that you can make an argument so many
different things constitute cyber
security threats it's not a small
discreet list it also applies
security vulnerabilities any attribute
of hardware/software process or
procedure that could enable or
facilitate the defeat of a security
control excellent we have this
incredibly broad cybersecurity purpose
so if you're monitoring for a
cybersecurity purpose you can monitor
your own networks or get the consent of
another company or government agency to
monitor their networks so I will turn it
over to midship and give you to talk a
bit more about what this might mean in
practice so in practice this might not
actually change all that much because a
lot of these companies have been doing
it internally and have just assumed that
they're never going to get sued so it's
going to internally it's going to be
logging as much as possible for the sock
capturing as much network traffic in
case you have to do Incident Response
logging all the metadata just see if
something you can easily search or one
of the big things that this might allow
you to do is some of the more
interesting things like say reading the
content of your employees emails
ordinarily that requires a pretty large
consent form you have to be able to
prove there's consent with this there's
a reasonable chance that as long as
you're monitoring strictly for it for
defensive purposes and you're only using
the information for defensive purposes
you're totally covered and don't even
have to prove that the employee
consented to the monitoring of their
communications the primary change is
that it eliminates the liability under
the existing statutes if we're
interpretating interpreting
notwithstanding the way that we are and
the way that it's likely to be pushed
another big thing for monitoring is the
ability for a third party to monitor
network previously that was a slightly
unsafe scenario because there's a chance
that you wind up sharing PII and wind up
becoming liable for this security breach
this act is made to make it slightly
more difficult for you get sued and will
act as an insulating factor actually
it's going to go to the defense measures
where things are a little bit more
interesting because it's authorizing a
lot of things because of the very broad
sweeps of what a cyber security purposes
so what this is saying is not
withstanding again a private entity may
operate the defense of measure for any
information system that they
own any information system that they
have received written consent to operate
on and and on any federal entities
systems as long as they have consent so
what kind of Defense note that doesn't
mean hack backs
sorry booze sorry Raytheon it's going it
the defensive action while in action
device procedure signature its
mitigating an owner suspect
cybersecurity threat or security
vulnerability but the key thing is that
it is a measure that does not destroy
render unusable or it provide
unauthorized access to which means that
it's very unlikely that you are going to
ever be able to make a successful case
for hacking back under the cyber
security act you're using the cyber
security act as your authorization so
what are examples there's all the boring
examples ids/ips or anything that's
doing intrusion detection intrusion
protection firewall rules but the things
that we've been doing forever some of
the more interesting things that are on
the cutting edge and some companies
might not have felt comfortable doing
one example is honey tokens and honey
files the idea of a honey token is an
embedded URL that's unique that allows a
organization to monitor access to a file
so just like a web bug every time this
resource gets loaded it's going to make
a hit in the log and record the IP that
came from maybe some more information so
you can hide these tokens and anything
from documents to webpages to inside
databases so you can actually put it
inside a sequel database so if that
database gets read it's going to make a
call to that and log that so using
internally to detect intrusions is
something that a lot of companies have
been starting to do but external is a
little sketchy because you're winding up
running having a call back from someone
else's domain and there's a very good
chance that under previous laws someone
could get upset when they see your word
document beaking back to them under the
cybersecurity Act of 2015 there's a very
good chance that you could embed a token
in a document send it out and it put it
on your network and if it gets taken by
an attacker once they bring it back to
their network and open it back it'll
make a request that IP will get logged
and you have a pretty
simple place to start your investigation
as well as being notified that you have
had a breach so that's not hacking back
in any way that is that there's
absolutely no access it is then making a
request and that is a very safe move now
and just a quick pitch for canary token
org it's a free service it's absolutely
incredible and will allow you to
download all the images you need to open
that up for your own organization so you
don't have to use their infrastructure
it can be all your own infrastructure
and you can start doing this so the more
exciting business what what if you took
that idea of having a document that was
stolen call back to you to the extremes
so you have to remember the defender
cannot adversely effect the attackers
network and the defender must not gain
authorize unauthorized access so there
is a very fine line between the CFAA and
the cybersecurity act there's a
reasonable chance and again this is
something that is going to have to get
worked through by the legal side but
there's a reasonable chance
under the current our current
interpretation of the cybersecurity Act
that mirroring the Honey file concept
you could put a piece of basically a
word macro malware inside of a document
so that no one gets stolen it gets
opened on the on the on the attackers
box and that piece of malware runs a
system profiler collects as much
information about the system as possible
sends it back to the defenders
organization and then deletes itself now
that's a bit of a stretch it's very it's
something that is going to have to get
worked through but there's a very
reasonable chance that we will start
seeing that in the next few years as
long as the code is proven to be
completely safe it's it's the effects
are localized there's no chance that's
spreading there's no chance of
authorized access continuing after the
initial profile such as something to
look out for and if you want to try and
argue that in a longer document
definitely a place to be another thing
that we're starting to see our
integrated defenses so this is hardware
manufacturers operating system
developers so seeing seeing things right
now like integrated anti-malware Windows
Defender is one of the best examples of
this
the ability for a company that makes
these systems to put put something on
not worry about monopoly laws not worry
about trust laws and be able to take act
action without the users consent on a
machine that they own or on an operating
system that they developed another
interesting possibility is for a
organization that makes perhaps Internet
of Things devices to have their own
access to a hat or to retain some sort
of access to it so that they are able to
reach back in and remove malware anytime
that's any time that they detect it
affecting their things whether or not
vendors actually implement that sort of
thing is up for up for them and so it's
unlikely to be seeing that in webcams
but Microsoft's already seeing it and I
expect to start seeing it across other
devices in the future so the third prong
of the cyber security act is the
information sharing provision and again
as I discussed earlier this is what's
gotten the most attention have gotten
the most controversy because there's
this concern that companies will be
sharing highly sensitive private
customer information with the government
with other companies so this final
negotiated version attempted to strike a
balance between those concerns so the
one really important point to remember
is that this is voluntary so it says
that if you're a company you and you
have cyber threat information or
defensive measures that have been
successful you're allowed to share the
them with the federal government and
other companies there's no duty to share
so even if you see the just a really
terrible threat and you're you've been
participating in this program before you
have no obligation to tell DHS to tell
other companies that's going to be a
business decision that you're going to
have to make also if you're receiving
information through this us-cert run
program you have no duty to warn anyone
based on that and
the cybersecurity act both a mis section
and also in other provisions that really
aren't part of this talk really further
centralized cybersecurity homeland
cybersecurity civilian defense to the
department of homeland security
including responsibility for
administering this information sharing
program and DHS has a lot of discretion
a lot of leeway in determining what are
adequate safeguards for these programs
so if you're going to participate in
this program and try to seek immunity
from any liability you need to make sure
that your part that you're complying
with DHS's guidelines and policies DHS
over the past year has released a number
of guidance documents that really help
companies figure out how to participate
in this so this is actually the
provision from the law it says that if
you're a non-federal entity basically if
you're a private company private
Association for a cybersecurity purpose
and protecting classified information
you can share receive any both with
other private companies or the federal
government a cyber threat indicators or
defensive measure okay so we talked
about defensive measures but what's a
cyber threat indicators so I apologize
for how small the sprint is that's
because this is actually from the
statute and they went that DHS went to
great lengths to make this as broad as
possible so basically because they want
as much information shared that
companies feel willing to give so it's
anomalous patterns of communications a
method of defeating a security control
or exploiting a security vulnerability
the actual security vulnerability
including any anomalous activity that
indicates the existence of a security
vulnerability a method of causing a user
with legitimate access to a system to
unwittingly enable the defeat of a
security control on malicious
command-and-control actual and potential
harm caused by an incident and any other
attribute of a cyber security threat if
the disclosure is
not otherwise permitted by law or any
combination thereof so this is basically
lawyers way of saying you can justify
pretty much anything being a cyber
threat indicator I want to go on record
in a brief on that but I mean that's
basically what the what Congress was
intending when they drafted this now
midshipman DB we'll talk about some
examples of cyber threat indicators so
while the lawyers made the threat the
definition for threat indicators as
broad as humanly possible in terms of
what's actually useful it winds up being
pretty narrow so it's going to be
anything that you're going to be trying
to put into your into intrusion
detection system anything you're putting
into your tuition protection system so
you could say an IP address is really
any sort of exploit discovered
vulnerabilities malware hashes malware
families domain names IPS and just
straight-up threat intelligence and
again of course of varying use but the
point of the legal side was to make it
so that you could share whatever was
whatever was being necessary on this on
the technical side there's it winds up
being a lot less than actually winds up
getting shared so just the mechanisms
that there have been many attempts at
creating different ways to share
information and finally one has really
taken hold and that's the stix cybox
taxi and that's really heavily backed by
the department homeland security and
us-cert that's really going a long way
towards making it so that intelligence
can get shared and in a usable manner
and be used in a timely fashion there
are definite concerns so there are
technical safeguards and that's
basically based off of the design of
these things there's there's no
mechanism for sharing of logs there's no
mechanism for sharing of documents as
well as legal safeguards so there's a
mandatory removal of personally
identifiable information if you know
that there is personally identifiable
information in there so that is a major
caveat there is a slight chance that you
could wind up sharing one of these
indicators that could have personally
identifiable information
but really the main takeaway from this
is it is very difficult to trample on
people's rights with sticks rules so
just going through it I mean XML
formatted the I chose the two examples
for sticks and cybox that have the most
information you can possibly put in
about an about a single person and this
is the default example for sharing
information about a threat organization
and this is one for all the information
that you can possibly put on a HTTPS
certificate so as great as the concerns
are that this does authorize the sharing
of documents and perhaps let's one
example I've been seeing thrown around
is the idea that a document could have a
piece of malware embedded in it they
share the document that has an hour in
it of course that there's that as a
valid use case and then the documents
filled with PII right now there's no
good mechanism to do that until magnin
is created to do that there's really not
too much for concern about it so we
wanted to talk a little bit about both
the immunity and the privacy protections
that the cyber security act provides
both for information sharing and for
monitoring because again that's really
one of the most controversial parts of
this law so because privacy was really
about most concerned there was a lot of
discussion about how do what do we do to
protect privacy so if it's for example a
bank that's had a cybersecurity attack
there there needs to be some way that
the bank doesn't necessarily provide
every customer bank record to DHS to
other companies because that's highly
sensitive personal information and most
privacy advocates would say there's no
good reason to do that so there are a
number of provisions in the law that
says both DHS develops its own
guidelines for protecting privacy but
also that companies before sharing any
of the cyber threat indicators with
anyone else they have to go through the
information and see if there and remove
any personal information that's not
directly related to the cybersecurity
threat again you could pay a lawyer who
charges hundreds of dollars an hour to
make an argument about why personal
information might somehow be directly
related to the cybersecurity threat I
think given the language in the statute
it's very hard I think but there are
also some privacy folks who say it's
actually much easier than you would
think to justify that and they're still
very concerned about large lists of
consumer names customers emails all that
sort of thing being provided under this
so I think right we have again we
haven't seen any major cases arising
from this yet I think eventually we
probably will and then we'll be able to
get further guidance from the courts and
from DHS as to what actually what
personal information actually is
directly related to threat so here's the
protection from liability this again
this was the big sticking point because
there were a number of concerns
particularly after the Snowden
revelations that telecommunications
companies and the government would just
use this as a way to share any sorts of
information between companies and the
government and be completely immune from
it if they just say that it's for a
price either security purpose the so the
immunity provision actually covers both
monitoring and information sharing so it
says that basically you can't sue a
company for monitoring an information
system and information conducted under
the cybersecurity Act so again for
cybersecurity purposes depending on how
broadly courts define cybersecurity
purposes that could be a huge deal or it
could be not any change at all if cyber
security purpose is defined really
broadly this could provide much more
flexibility for monitoring without
companies facing any litigation but
again that's just something that we're
going to have to find out with time as
Court Rule wanted the information
sharing immunity again it basically says
you can share the
cyber threat indicators or defensive
measures as long as you comply both with
the any requirements that DHS imposes
and also these privacy rules so
redacting any unnecessary personal
information cybersecurity Act also
protects companies from regulators one
concern that I've heard from companies
over the years is why on earth would we
want to give the federal government and
they frankly see the federal government
as one large entity why would we want to
give the federal government vast amounts
of information about why we were hacked
just for background I mentioned the FTC
the FTC will bring enforcement actions
against companies that have what they
would say they're deceptive or unfair
data security and typically in like 99%
of the cases you basically settle with
the FTC before they get to sue you the
good news is if it's a first-time
violation and you're not operating under
a previous consent decree you don't have
to pay any money the bad news is that
you do have to agree to what I tell my
clients is basically a 20-year root
canal by the FTC what they do is they
take they retain the ability to
basically oversee your entire data
security program require constant audits
it's incredibly costly and if you're
found in violation you can face vast
penalties so you don't want to have to
do that so companies say why would I
give this information to the federal
government if they're going to DHS just
passes it on to the FTC the FDC says hey
why did you not require your all your
employees to use anything other than
password as their password and that so
so that was the concern so to address
this the Congress said that basically if
companies provide any federal agency
information through the threat sharing
program they don't have this information
cannot be used directly or indirectly
against them in a regulatory proceeding
however the federal government can
basically use the information that
learns through this program to develop
future regulations so that
looking to see what sort of
cybersecurity threats are go our
companies facing they could develop
regulations along those lines the final
sort of immunity is for antitrust
violations so and under antitrust law
companies can't collude with competitors
so just a free legal tip if you're in a
if you're talking with the competitor
it's been fine to be friends with
competitors never ever talk about what
prices you're going to set if you do
that that's a violation of antitrust
laws they have criminal civil penalties
that are not very fun to face so the
concern that companies had here is if
I'm sharing information about a phishing
campaign for example with a competitor
is that going to be seen as an antitrust
violation so that's why Congress put in
this exception saying by participating
in the in this program you're not going
to be facing any antitrust liability so
in conclusion and something that I
wanted to get that we wanted to get your
thoughts on we in the past years since
this has really been active there's not
been a tremendous amount of
participation from the private sector
there's some and it's growing but there
have been about a hundred companies that
have participated overall that's not
very much or at least that was as of
this winter um so does anyone have any
thoughts about what needs to change
based on what you've heard of anyone in
the private sector would you participate
in this do you participate in it
yeah I think that's a great point I mean
maybe only allow companies to receive
information if they help out make it
communal rather than sort of take your
chances and if you want to be nice and
then participate has anyone else had any
experience with the program any any any
questions about it yep sure so it
depends on what the actual damage was
but if it's but typically it would
probably be a it would be definitely
those negligence breach of contract
breach of warranty lawsuits especially
if there was any physical damage from a
malfunctioning device something like
that the again the way that that works
is that typically the plaintiffs lawyers
will file a class-action lawsuit
whichever plaintiff actually gets it is
able to handle this multi district
litigation they basically hit the
jackpot because they get a percentage on
behalf of every affected consumer
regardless of whether the person is a
named plaintiff so I think that would be
the most likely the Federal Trade
Commission has indicated
that it's focusing more and more on
Internet of Things and security of
Internet of Things devices so I think
they're probably going to get more
active and finally enforcement actions
on that do you wanna technically all
right so are you talking about the witch
witch bot nunneries I just want to make
sure that I'm commenting on the correct
one
all the kill yo all the takedown okay
okay I thought you said operating the
botnet - okay
okay yeah this yeah so that actually
deals more that that was a very
successful FBI operation under the new
rule 41 which I'm sure many of you heard
about it was very controversial that
allows magistrate judges to issue these
net B's nationwide warrants for the
kilos botnet so that's that more is
under sort of the criminal enforcement
authority so but the legal authority
that allowed that was more of a change
to the warrants
so I totally agree and I hate to be I
gotta bring medical with it but I kind
of see it as like that things until you
reach a critical mass of people sharing
this information it's going to wind up
just being PMS 100 maybe 120 company to
this point and they're sharing not not
enough intelligence to even come close
to justifying the huge upfront cost of
setting up a full attack be system on
that way so it's public it's public
service for now right now there's no way
that somebody can look at and say this
is going to make us money but in the
future once you get enough people in the
ecosystem sharing information I think
that's what's really going to push you
over the edge so that one is not not the
true definition of a honey pile that one
is I know it's basically straight up ax
tool but that is one that I feel that if
you work through with the DHS and then
this is what we are trying to create
these are these specific actions that
are going to be taken by this tool and
call it something like a defense invent
a tool you would have to work it through
legal channels you would have to get
approval from them before you start
using it but there's a reasonable chance
that if you constrain the activity such
that there is absolutely no way that it
could be viewed as being used for access
you'd be able to pull that off legally
it's definitely close hit but DFA is
bees so honey file is just the idea of
you take honey token that unique URL
that when access pops up a lot for you
and honey file is just any file that you
embed that in so that can be something
as simple as a word document that has a
clear easier tables in there but any
file that when accessed is going to wind
up out of your network yeah kind of
companies that might not be able to so
if the competitor received the
vulnerability if it was something that
and hopefully they typically they will
be alerted to it as long as it doesn't
violate the equities process but yeah
but I frankly I think it increases the
chances because if you're facing a
lawsuit
in negligence inadequate data security
all sorts of causes of action you really
knowledge of a problem that you don't
fix if that goes to a jury that's really
going to hurt you so I think that's a
really good point the chances of an
organization having a full taxi set up
and not being able to catch enough
things to be covered legally as I'm not
a lawyer but the liability is usually
gross negligence something along the
lines of you really just didn't try okay
we're having the signal that our time is
up if you have any other questions
please ask us in person email us happy
to talk about this moron thank you so
much
[Applause]