all right good afternoon we're here for
the final session of the afternoon we
i'd like to introduce you to emma jones
she is a senior consultant with
crowdstrike and will be presenting today
on decoding the diversity discussion uh
please save your questions for the end
of the session there's mike's at the
middle in the front of the room uh if
you have questions at the end
and uh please remember to fill out your
feedback at the end of the day
through your app on your phone with that
please welcome emma
thank you
welcome to my talk today on decoding the
diversity discussion and i'm extra
grateful that you could make it along
for two main reasons the first because
there is a wonderful talk track running
through the whole week but specifically
right now at this time so a shout out to
my fellow crowdstrike consultants who
are also
speaking in the room next door but also
especially grateful that you're here
because it's the last session of the day
and i am acutely aware that i'm the one
person that stands between you and what
promises to be another wonderful evening
in dublin so no pressure right to make
sure that we are good to go right on
time
so on that note i will make a start
so essentially i look at the diversity
discussion in the same way that i think
i and many of us here used to look at
research into the cyber threat
so if we think it's fairly customary
fairly standard that we will all
be aware of threat briefs reports even
listen to podcasts on future predictions
on the cyber threat as well as look at
those specific blogs from incident
responders as they report on what's
happening on the front lines
now
thinking of that and remembering that
that's so custom for us um is so
important
because actually there's some parallels
between that situation
and how we reflect on thinking of the
importance of research into the cyber
threat
and actually i'm sure many of us have
thought
or read or consumed some of this
information and definitely had a moment
where we think
that's really interesting that's really
insightful but certainly from my
perspective there's been occasions where
i've wondered now what on earth do i do
with that information how do i pull out
those key salient points and take it
back to my everyday role in the incident
response community
and we know it's that reflective process
which has driven us and continues to
drive us
to focus on the importance of actionable
intelligence or operational intelligence
so consuming information that always
finishes up with something specific to
take away a measure or an action to make
sure you and i can protect ourselves and
defend against the adversary
now you're probably wondering emma what
on earth has that got to do with the
diversity discussion
well actually bear with me because i
think there's some similarities in both
of these situations
so let's break it down
diversity as a topic has been around a
really long time much like the value of
research into whatever threat it is that
we face
also recent years we've seen a huge
increase in the amount of narrative
associated with diversity often in the
context of real world events
much like ransomware and the evolution
of the cyber threat that's really got on
the agenda for all of us over the last
couple of years
and finally as incident response
professionals we're much more familiar
with the diversity topic and the value
in which diverse perspectives lead
directly to much better more enhanced
incident response efforts
and that familiarisation is similar when
we look at intelligence and research
because we know it's so important to
have intelligence-led activity so that
we can respond in the best way possible
so
let's think a little bit then about what
the differences are between those two
scenarios for me the main thing is that
the diversity discussion has not yet got
to the point where we focus on that
actionable item
there's so many amazing strategic
projects initiatives that happen in this
space and we see and read and hear about
all the time
but what's often missing is that nugget
of information that action that we all
need to take as individuals as teams and
of course across our organizations
so i'm here to hopefully take us that
little bit further in the conversation
to pull out some key items that mean
that we can be more intentional about
inclusion because when we decode that
diversity topic what really matters for
you and i is how we include and embrace
everybody that we interact with
but who am i to be here talking to you
about this
so by way of introduction my name is of
course emma jones and i'm a senior
consultant with crowdstrike i work with
organizations across the uk europe
middle east and africa on a whole range
of things associated with incident
response and readiness
but alongside that i'm incredibly
passionate about diversity and inclusion
i've been so fortunate to be involved in
a number of different projects both as a
volunteer and with the organizations
that i've worked with over the last 15
years and had some professional
portfolios alongside the day job
you can see here on the screen a little
bit about who i am what i'm interested
in and what keeps me busy in my spare
time and then some of the organizations
that i've had the pleasure of working
with and volunteering with over recent
times
now before we get into
the detail
i just want to give some context and
make sure that we can frame the
discussion in the best way possible
and essentially it's to remind ourselves
and everybody that we work with that we
all have diversity we are all different
we have different experiences different
skill sets
different perspectives all of which make
us unique individuals in the world that
we live in today
now often it's that concept it's that
fact it's that reminder that's missing
in some of the narrative that we have we
can forget about it or overlook that
actually embracing diversity is about
embracing absolutely everybody that we
encounter in this space
now what i'd like to do is go through
the incident response life cycle
talk through some typical actions that
we take or we're involved in as incident
responders
highlight how sometimes we can not be as
inclusive as maybe we would hope or like
and then share some actionable tips to
take away and either implement them or
make sure you continue to do them within
your teams
so first up phase one preparation one of
my favorites of course as a previous
role was as a proactive incident
response consultant
so i want to take up here the training
aspect
so as an industry we're fantastic at
recognizing we want to continually train
up skill everybody around us
particularly our incident response
personnel
but what sometimes happens is we talk
about training or skill sets in this
space in quite a divisive manner often
without realizing
so for example we will talk about people
who have soft skills we will talk about
people who are non-technical
and actually when you look at the
connotations of those words and those
phrases we think you know soft can
sometimes mean lesser than
none can imply that you don't have
something that doesn't necessarily
foster an environment where people feel
they have a skill set that contributes
to this response effort
so it's so important to think about the
terminology that we use so for example
core skills or actually calling out
those non-technical skills for what they
actually are someone could be an amazing
collaborator fantastic at written
communication let's make sure that we
mention it so that everyone knows that
we appreciate it isn't just about one
particular area and that we know
everyone brings something to the table
secondly ir plans those plans and
playbooks so important to us and many of
us continually evolve review them work
from them and they're fantastic
but in my experience so far i've seen
them evolve in such a way that they've
become quite long lengthy documents on
multiple different documents
and sometimes that doesn't account for
the way that we may process information
differently
so actually how can we start to account
for the different styles in which people
process that information listen or hear
what they need to do
so
supplementary materials are so so
important in this space
think about the use of checklists for
example any visual or diagrams flow
charts or mind maps and even think about
videos or short recordings which might
give people
more of an insight and more be more
receptive to what it is that they need
to do in that space
and then finally in this phase we have
tabletop exercises a firm favorite of
many of us and many of our organizations
and they're incredibly beneficial when
we have that usually you know that half
day opportunity to talk through what we
would do in a response regardless of
what our role may be in that space but
sometimes we have to stay take a step
back to remember that actually
those scenarios where you have quite a
large group of people um you know
they're quite intimidating they can
create anxiety they can make people feel
like they don't have confidence to speak
so they're quite conducive to only those
who are confident enough to speak up in
front of others
and whilst we still want to be able to
do tabletops is about thinking about how
we create a safe environment for every
participant so it's always good to set
the ground rules to begin with explain
that it's not an individual test or an
assessment
but also remind all participants not
just the facilitators
that it's everyone's job to bring in
other views and other perspectives
you've probably been in a scenario where
you think i would love to hear from that
person about what they would do or if
they've experienced it before so why not
bring them in could be verbally you
could be doing a virtual exercise and
ask them to type in the chat
just consider how we can bring other
people and we don't have that that echo
chamber effect where it's just one or
two individuals who are confident enough
to keep speaking up
so let's move to phase two
detection and analysis
so incident declaration so we know we're
going to get to a point where we need to
declare that incident categorise it
think about the prioritization we need
to give
and usually at that point your core
responders or your first responders they
are operating with all hands on deck so
to speak
they are working relentlessly tirelessly
often extended working hours weekends
evenings and actually
those individuals could suffer from
burnout they may be sacrificing things
at home or in their personal lives which
are particularly challenging or
problematic
and it's important i think to make sure
that all of us consider the well-being
and the welfare of our responders right
from the onset
we need to make sure that they get the
rest the balance so that we get the
optimum response from them because often
as we all know if it's a significant
incident we're going to be at it for a
number of days weeks months and it's
really really difficult to sustain that
response effort
so thinking about how you support from a
welfare and well-being perspective is
about making sure your organizations
don't just rely on the good will of
people to respond in that manner
so look at your policies or your
technologies that you might employ how
that makes sure that the response effort
is
you know supportive and effective in the
early stages look at how you split your
incident response teams or you seek
support from the wider organization
or other trusted third parties
also bring hr in so so important make
sure that you can signpost and support
and simply ask each other is okay
then that usually takes us on to having
to stand up your incident response teams
so we're talking significant incident
you've got your core team maybe you've
got an extended team executive team and
even an external incident response team
and the very nature of significant
incidents is that actually we're going
to come across people who maybe
we've never met before we've never had
the pleasure of interacting we haven't
had a chance to do a tabletop and some
of the teams or individuals can make
assumptions about those people that they
come across
often completely unintended because
we're in the heat of the moment so for
example i've seen teams make assumptions
about where somebody might work what
team they represent so automatically
thinking someone must be from comms they
must be from hr they must be from legal
and equally assumptions about where
somebody is located or what time zone
they might be in
and even to the point of making
assumptions about how to pronounce
someone's name
so the value of introductions is
incredibly important when it comes to
inclusion in this aspect
recognizing someone is an individual it
doesn't need to take an hour it can be
very brief but it gives you as a
responder or as a manager an insight
right from the beginning about who
somebody is
when you need to interact with them
because actually you have clarity on
their role in the incident response
but also they feel part of something
you're collaborative from the get go and
you've recognized each individual
contribution
finally we have out of bands
communication
so many organizations will have systems
in place where you can text or
communicate with your entire
organization in a crisis
but many organizations i've worked with
over recent years have not always
considered the need for those
out-of-bands platforms where you can
collaborate and communicate as an
incident response team
and in those circumstances what happens
from an inclusion perspective
is
individuals are running around trying to
get personal phone numbers and details
for the rest of the team particularly if
you're remote dispersed around the world
and trying to bring them all together
and put them all into this one chat or
this one platform to collaborate
and what can inadvertently happen as a
result of that is people feel left out
from the initial response because maybe
uri had a personal relationship with
people because we've worked together in
the same city in the same team for a
long time so we brought them all
together but then two three four hours
later we then to get everybody else's
details and actually someone could feel
like they weren't important or they
don't have the same part to play
so it's really vital even from a
preparation perspective to think about
setting up those platforms test them
make sure everybody is included and
whilst that will help make the incident
much more effective and run smoothly it
will make sure that everybody is working
together and feeling like they are part
of that response from the beginning and
you'll get much more out of those
individuals they will feel much more
comfortable and of course there's great
business benefit
moving on to the third phase arguably
the the largest and one that has the
most actions
containment eradication and recovery
initial containment of course is one of
those huge topics particularly when
we're thinking significant incident or
ransomware
and often there's decisions or
conversations happening about measures
such as severing the internet connection
and of course that has huge business
impact not just for those core
responders but the wider operation of
the organization
and the very nature of that discussion
it could be brand new to somebody who
needs to be aware of that business
impact and then take some subsequent
action
so they're likely to have questions want
to seek some clarity want to understand
what the impact of that containment
measure may be
but often that's quite difficult to do
you know to ask questions about a topic
that you're not so familiar with that in
a you know a
time of huge pressure
and stress
heightened heightened situation where
you need to act so so quickly
and naturally then people will go to
seek advice or ask those questions to
people that they feel are like them
because they feel like there's an
affinity and it's safe to do that
and whilst that's so important and
that's great because you are able to
have a relationship to understand the
information that you need
it excludes the voices of others within
the incident response team
so it's incredibly important to think
about those containment strategies bring
everyone together in that non
incident environment to talk about the
measures their experiences someone you
know in the wider team may have been in
an organization previously dealt with
ransomware and able to share um some
sanitized information with someone
asking questions and that puts
everything in context so it's about
making sure that we're not only
proactive but everyone has an
opportunity to contribute to that
incident response effort
secondly tour deployment we're probably
going to need to roll out some tools and
technologies in our organizations to
either gain visibility or to collect
forensic data for example
now what i still hear fairly often in
the community is the term white listing
or black listing
and of course there's a huge push to
make sure that we have inclusive
terminology and quite rightly so because
of the connotations that are associated
with some of those phrases that exist
out there
so making sure that as a team as
management as people involved in
incident response that we keep up to
date with what's happening in the
diversity and inclusion community you
might have people in your team who are
advocates or who are part of your
employee resource group so make sure
that you're feeding into those and they
are being able to share updates like
this and you can have some approaches
and best practice employed throughout
your incident response effort
and finally briefings we're all likely
to need to contribute to a briefing or
even write one ourselves on a fairly
regular basis
but we all have a tendency sometimes to
assume some knowledge about cyber
but actually many people reading those
briefings might not be from our industry
it might be new to them but they're
probably going to be making some pretty
big decisions about the way the
organization responds
so it's so so important at this point to
remember not to assume that knowledge
make sure that we write our briefings
without acronyms or we explain the
acronyms that we add reference points so
people can take some time to just get
some additional context
or even appoint a technical subject
matter expert who can be that point of
contact for the rest of the organization
to openly and
comfortably and safely ask some of those
questions to seek clarity right from the
beginning so that they can make their
decisions properly understanding the
impact of the incident that you were
dealing with
and finally the final phase post
incident activity now i'm laughing to
myself because that's often the nice to
do not the need to do we've always got
competing priorities but of course we
know the absolute value in this part of
the life cycle
lessons learned many organizations will
want to understand what went wrong
and that tends to drive the approach to
lessons learned
and we want to know what went wrong
really quickly so that we can start to
do something about it and quite rightly
so
but sometimes that drive to find out
what what didn't go well
can mean that we we overlook that a
lessons learned initiative or project
can be really triggering for those who
are part of the response
they probably worried about whether
they'd done something wrong whether the
company was going to be able to exist
after the crisis what it meant for their
job how it meant from their work level
or level of effort perspective
so we have to remember that welfare
well-being making sure you can sign post
support during lessons learned is so
vital
but equally as is gaining additional
insights people are often worried about
providing information about what went
wrong so you need to consider
alternative ways about how to do that
not just a a form or a survey online but
give an option for anonymous mission
hold one to one so it's more personal
people respond better in that scenario
even consider group lessons learns our
group debriefing there's so many other
ways we can gain that insight but also
give that reassurance that some of our
incident responders may need
that then always tends to lead on to
improvements you come out with a whole
list of recommendations or things that
need to be changed from small specific
items all the way through to maybe
overhauling your security program
and again that's quite a focus on what
didn't go well
and sometimes to make sure that we are
inclusive and have a holistic approach
when it comes to response
think about the successes what went well
because naturally you will then be able
to recognize reward
pay attention to the good work that your
responders did
and not only then will you have a suite
of improvements that you can start to
implement you're going to have some
successes that you can make sure
embedded in the response effort because
we all know there may well have been
some successes that actually were
unintentional but we want to make sure
we do it again and actually indirect
consequence of that and that holistic
view from an improvement and success
perspective
is that actually your staff may start to
buy in to those improvements and may
even hold the hand up or express an
interest in leading a particular action
and of course then that means they are
part of something that they belong and
that they are vested in both the
reactive and proactive work in this
space
and then finally we have digital
technologies
so many of the tips or suggestions
are very much focused on people and
process
but actually they can be implemented or
you can even instigate some of this work
from an inclusion perspective by using
the technology that you have so let's
take communication platform as an
example you may well be able to
turn on some of the features that allow
people to input their time zones to put
some pronouns to put their work in
preferred hours to even explain how to
spell the name
little things like that very simple but
incredibly significant in recognizing
everyone that's around
it's also good to get used to transcript
functions or even think about how you
have colour contrasts in your power
points or how you run the accessibility
function when you finish composing your
great content
there's so much out there from a
technology perspective and so much
commitment to being inclusive by design
we probably haven't taken note of
everything that's available to us so
there's lots there in that space
now there's plenty that has been covered
but as a recap and if there was one
slide actually that you could photograph
or take away it would be this one
because certainly couldn't put all the
content in one and actually this is
about making sure that we acknowledge
everybody that we build belonging that
we are consciously considerate of those
around us and that we delve deeper into
the topic into the technologies into the
processes
it's really important that we recognize
that being simple with our approach can
have huge significant impact on how
people feel how they feel that sense of
belonging and allow themselves to be
part of that incident response effort
now we talked right at the start about
the direct benefit of threat
intelligence or intelligence-led
activity when it comes to incident
response
and actually what i hope this talk can
do
is start to generate that thinking about
how inclusive practices and being
intentional about our inclusive
behaviors can of course have that direct
positive impact on incident response
because if we can communicate
effectively right from the beginning we
can collaborate better people feel part
of something and then our decisions they
are sound decisions where people have
sought clarity in a really comfortable
way
now we know of course it makes business
sense uh for diversity and inclusion
we're quite good in this space
understanding why we need to do it but
what i hope this talk has done has
mentioned what you can do some specific
key actions or takeaways in that space
but then often people wonder well how do
you do it how do we make sure we can
think about this
all the time in all our interactions no
matter how big how small
how can we implement this all the time
well it's about assuming less and asking
more
i think if we take that that mantra it's
stripped back it's simple
but every time we approach something an
interaction a situation an action a
process a task whatever it may be if we
take a moment to just sense check
see if we are assuming something in this
situation and ask more seek some clarity
get that information from those around
you and then by that point we will move
into much more intentional inclusive
behaviors
so i will pause there and ask if anyone
has any questions
i'm also very eager to go and enjoy the
evening so no obligation
great presentation thanks for that
a quick question so i as a person i have
blind spots
when someone points out a blind spot i
don't know if i react the right way
and so from a diversity point of view is
there any advice that you've seen or
you've ran into
on how to give yourself time to consider
what's being said without being
offensive and then come back with the
right response and i don't mean like
thank you that was nice i'll talk to you
tomorrow i mean like if there's some
some formula you can follow for the
first minute or two to get you that that
space to get into the right mindset yeah
definitely great question
and so we often overlook the importance
of listening
so taking that time to hear what
somebody is saying
but before you can get to that point i
would say that you have to build trust
with those around you often people won't
come out to talk about something that
they've experienced or that they want to
explain to you because they don't have
trust so you're in a good position so
far if you've been able to build that up
so being conscious about that and
explaining that you do want to hear
about it and that you listen and
understand what they're saying and you
don't have to always give a response you
can take it on board and it depends how
the conversation might go they may want
to
explain certain things you you may be
able to consider going forward so
there's lots of different ways but i
would say the number one approach would
be just just to listen and really hear
and ask questions because they want to
talk about it if they if they've brought
it to your attention
and nourish that opportunity because it
takes a lot for people to you know to to
approach or to highlight something so
recognize that
and they will be more than receptive to
continuing the conversation and that's
certainly what i've seen so far
love the presentation emma thank you
in some cases in incident response we
may have some
very aggressive
folk members of management
and more
timid technical folks that report to
them
how do you draw the
nuggets of information you know that
they have uh the technical folks to uh
bear on the problem when you have those
overbearing managers how do you make
them feel like they're heard
or can be heard and can weigh in on the
problem yeah great question thanks um so
it's definitely about reading the room
and so i went to a great talk last night
and someone talked about how we should
be the chameleon and recognize what's
happening in any given environment and i
think if you're able to pick up on those
challenges or imbalances it's about
finding a variety of ways to get
people's input and contributions so it
may be that you recognize a particular
approach where you have everybody
together is is not working well so then
you might have to adapt your style or
your way of communicating and
interacting to bring people into a
different forum or introduce someone to
ones and a lot of that will then build
the trust and you will be able to
represent others
if that's the best approach when when
doing so but creating safe environments
is certainly is something to consider as
well so often we have to really set the
tone for a conversation even if it's in
a really pressurized environment or if
something happens that
you know is inappropriate it's also
about being able to acknowledge that not
to just stand by and let something
happen
but finding different ways of of having
certain conversations or closing certain
aspects down and bringing other people
in um is definitely sort of some of the
advice or where i've seen it happen
really well so far
in the beginning you talked about the
implicit bias that people have for soft
skills and non-technical skills
when you start bringing a team together
how do you
set the stage for saying how folks as
part of the introduction how different
parts of the organization whether it's
in the technical hr
legal or
communications field
set that
where everyone has that kind of a
feeling of being a part of it without
embarrassing someone definitely so it
all comes back to that prepare or that
proactive interaction and we
when we're in that heightened state and
you're trying to work together and
understand who does what and we can
often overlook all the things we need to
be more conscious of
so if you've got environments where you
can bring people together
you know in a safer space in a quieter
space and give everyone an opportunity
to talk about who they are as an
individual start at that point and then
let them explain to other people about
what their specific role is within an
incident and by doing that and bringing
everybody together there's an option
then for you know for those who who are
on the other side of the response to
actually hear and listen what somebody
else's role may be and a lot of that is
supplemented by you know the formalities
and what exists in the incident response
plans for example and having roles
responsibilities and accountabilities
but it's about bringing the humans and
the people into that aspect too
thank you thanks
okay
i think we shall pause there i just want
to say a huge thank you for coming to
listen and hopefully something you can
take away with you and you'll see there
on the bottom of the screen one of my
favorite quotes from a philosopher
called simonville and they say that
attention is the rarest and purest form
of generosity thank you
[Applause]
thank you