[Music]
so welcome uh to this presentation which
will be given by olaf hartung and he's a
defensive specialist and security
researcher at falconforce
the presentation is idr internals from a
defender's perspective and olof will
tell
more about that
just to remind about the rules this is
tlp white session
please switch off your mobile phones so
that we don't get any
uh unpleasant noises during the
presentation
and after the session please do fill in
the evaluation on the mobile app to show
how do you
like the presentation thank you very
much and olaf welcome
thank you
i just set my own timer
so good morning everyone thanks for
making it up um
just a brief introduction to add to it
so um my name is oliverton as mentioned
before
i work at falconforce and one of the
things that we do and i don't want to
make this into a sales talk but we
primarily focus on a lot of detection
engineering a lot of research
and a lot of offensive work and that's
also why we started digging into edrs
because that's what everybody uses or
should use
just to figure out what it's capable of
and how we can
make it useful for us as a as a defender
but also for an attacker perspective
to understand how can we bypass it and
detect that again
so i have a broad background in all
kinds of threat hunting ir and these
kind of things you can read
i went to art school so i never studied
computer science and
nor should you but it would help
i'm father two boys and of course i like
warm hugs for the people that have seen
frozen i really like disney for that
so what can you expect from this talk so
i'll generally talk about defender for
endpoint
from microsoft um i mean also an mvp i'm
not a commercial vehicle because it will
be a critical talk
but this applies to every edr
technically right so there might be
differences and all kinds of things but
the whole the whole way they work are
generally the same
so i started looking at what kind of
telemetry does it bring you what can you
do with it
where does it come from which is also
very important also from an attacker
perspective because you might have a
separate set of telemetry that you want
to augment to it just to make sure that
you have it
um it's configured so we also want to
show a little over know a little bit
what what it's actually doing how it's
getting its information and then i have
a wrap up and if i go too fast i have
backup slides for some additional fun
so first of all what what can you do
with it right so it's a it's a sort of
all-in-one trying to be solution
xdr whatever
it doesn't really matter
it has a couple of components and the
most important ones are av
attack service reduction which is sort
of part of the operating system as well
so it ties into each other but it
doesn't necessarily have to be bought
you have exploit guard the application
control there's of course the edr
component that is cloud-based
um there is there is some incident
response capability where you can live
connect to a host do some memory dumps
some small analysis things get some
artifacts
it does do some vulnerability management
or scanning
there's a network sensor it has dop
capabilities you can even scan networks
these kind of things so it's being
expanded constantly
just use whatever you like so the av
component of course is embedded already
in the operating system that just
ingests the alerts into the edr product
of course it's very signature based
as every edr mostly does
it does do also some cloud-based
analysis of the samples that it can
upload if you allow it to
and if you want to be a little bit more
into what the capabilities of the
signature database are there's a great
research project from camille moogie
probably butchering his name sorry he
works for the france french ansi
and he basically found a way to do to
decrypt the whole database
so a couple of things that you should be
aware of of course you can exclude stuff
from av like like
sometimes should be useful
but this is also something that
attackers will at least try immediately
when they hit the box so definitely make
sure you monitor that
and there are some couple of quirks
where you can also exclude a process for
instance but it won't exclude that
process it will exclude the child of
that process so if you want to
have a certain tree that you don't want
to see being caught then you should
address that accordingly and
if you exclude something then it's only
excluded for the av which is kind of
nice because then still the edr and all
the other components will apply to it so
if you want to exclude it there you have
to make multiple exclusions
um and if you really want to see how it
works there's a couple of tools so you
have defender check which is a tool uh
that i sometimes use if i want to see
why it triggered on something
so
it didn't used to be but now it's also
detected by the av because they think
it's a malicious tool so you can use
defender check to check on the fender
check to check on the fender sort of
weird weird deep dive but basically what
you can see is is
the bit that the av engine triggered on
and then if you're a malware developer
you could change a bit of that code
usually it's a bit of string or comment
and you might be able to bypass the av
that way it's just to understand a
little bit
also if you have a legitimate tool why
it triggered and you might be able to
talk to the
developers
other component is the attack service
reduction one
and this is built in as i mentioned just
into windows 10 and up
and it's a super powerful feature so
there's like 16 rules for office child
child processes and so on
which you should enable always
but you can you can configure them in
blocking or audit mode so in the
beginning definitely don't block
because you might break stuff and people
will be mad
but
um the ones that you do think
should be blocked you can at least start
enabling because it's a really powerful
way of making it harder for an attacker
without too much hassle so the graph
that you see here is built by by
palantir a us company and they basically
had a sort of generic
guidance into which ones should be safe
for most companies
and the rest you might want to
investigate
still you want to also investigate the
safe ones because you never know if it
is different for you and it's relatively
easy to enable it's just a couple of
gpos that you can push
or register keys via intune or whatever
you're using so it's relatively safe and
again this is also something that is
slightly rule based so this is an extra
extract also from that same research
from camille
where they have all kinds of lua scripts
that run
in the engine for the
for the asr rules and i
highlighted a couple where you can just
see some are are quite bad in a way
because they they just look at two
folders in a whole path so if you know
this as an attacker you can just create
those two folders drop your malware and
it will bypass this rule
it's still a little bit of fiddly but
this is a way to bypass it and microsoft
is working on addressing this to also
look a little bit more
in a broader sense
than only past command lines and file
names
but there's something to be aware of
right as a defender another one is the
defender application control which is an
extremely powerful feature
where you can basically
kill everything anything on a box that
you don't want there
and you can do that on all the
attributes that are listed there so it's
again very powerful there's a lot of
great research by matt graber on this
something that you might want to look
into it's like application whitelisting
it's complicated i have to grant that
but
if you just have a
there's a couple of lists even with
malicious drivers and some stuff that
you probably don't want on your systems
just start with that
and maybe
use it only in audit mode again so that
at least you have telemetry when you
know something that you probably think
is suspicious will will be executed
and this also goes for driver loads and
all kinds of other telemetry so if you
only rely on your native event logs and
your edr you might wanna augment it with
this
and then of course the edr telemetry is
there right so this is probably the gist
of of where an edr becomes powerful
and in the defender for endpoint case it
relies primarily on the sense service
which is an a service that runs on your
windows box and it gathers all kinds of
events and ships it off to the cloud
where it gets analyzed and then if they
find something they push it back and
block it
and all of those events
are basically stored in a
advanced hunting table as they call it
which is basically a log analytics
workspace on azure
that you can query with the gusto
language
and a couple of things to note is
basically the most important one is
which the events that are logged
and visible is controlled uh by
microsoft and they they control that
configuration you can't say hey i'm
interested in the registry key and i
don't see it yet
too bad yeah you can ask them right so
you can you can open a ticket request it
with a reason and it's relatively likely
that they'll do it but they don't do it
tomorrow might take a couple of months
depending on the backlog
so this is something to take into
account and then another one that is
very important so some of those events
are
sampled
or at least filtered
and the reason that they do that and
well you can see which ones they are but
the reason probably why the primary
reasons is one you pay a fixed amount
per month for that service so they have
to sort of constrain their resource use
which is probably the primary one
the second one is a lot of people don't
even use the telemetry so it's also a
ways to store it i think that's that's
both their reasons to do it um and then
of course there's some bandwidth
restrictions that they want to keep it
contained in a way but
um generally it's it's okay so for
instance the network connections are are
heavily
rate limited so you usually get the
first scene event
of that day with a lot of fields
so it's relatively it's relatively okay
but you can't see beaconing or that kind
of stuff
so be aware of that because
if you want to build a detection rule
that looks for beaconing behavior
this is probably not your data source
um and it heavily relies on the event
racing for windows as well so i'll dig
into that a little bit
and longer
even generate their own
native etw events which you might have a
look at as well if you start looking
for for special events
so
as i mentioned so you pay per per device
or per user a little bit depends if it's
a server or a workstation
and they they keep the data in the cloud
for you for 30 days
um and the marketing says 180 days but
that's basically the timeline so they
also make a sort of very condensed
version of your already condensed uh
telemetry and you can create that for
180 days but you can't query it with the
query language you have to use this
search box or the portal which isn't a
very nice experience and
if you want it longer you have to
basically get it from the api extract it
store it somewhere else there's plenty
of ways to do it there's all kinds of
azure solutions but you can also get it
to splunk or whatever you're using
locally
which would be a good idea because 30
days is nice but if you have an incident
you generally want to look at look at
least longer
um and on average i think i think this
slide is a little bit out there but it's
like 20 to 25 megabytes per device per
day so it's
yeah it's not it's not a lot but it's
also not very little um and depending on
how active you want to be with that data
it's probably too little for you if you
want to get a lot of it but
it's it's storable
and then
it's structured in a way that it's it's
like a database right so there's tables
and then within the tables there there
is a schema with all kinds of fields
um and basically what you can do you can
query the the interface itself
tell it to get the schema and you get
all the fields listed
but that doesn't go
to the depth that you want it because
what they do for the at least for the
device events
is they have a sort of catch-all bucket
where the action type
is basically filled with with the whole
list and way more i think there's 185
different action types in there now and
they go from those asr events exploit
guards
usb devices plugged in
but also
for instance uh elsa's dumping
is also in there and then there's all
kinds of additional fields
tied to that event which gives you all
kinds of very nice json information
which you can actually use in the
detection but keeping track of that is
relatively difficult because they
constantly onboard new information for
you
but you're not necessarily notified of
that so one of the things that you can
do there's there's this schema reference
guide in the portal where you can browse
through it and see what is there
but nobody wants to scroll and then
remember everything so
what you can also do is just
open the hacker tab with f12
and then basically get that
through the api so you can get the api
call that they do
and basically build a very simple script
where you can download it and do a diff
and then you can build a slack bot for
instance that tells you every time they
added some new data components which is
kind of nice because you want to be on
top of what you can use
out of the box they generate all kinds
of alerts and this is nice but you never
know what they do so what we try to do
and i deliberately share an old slide
because i don't want to help anybody on
the offensive side
and since this is broadcasters i don't
know who's watching but basically what
we do is try tracking across all of our
clients and our friends
anonymously what
type of alerts are triggered plus we do
a lot of research ourselves so we
constantly trigger all kinds of
out-of-the-box alerts and this can help
us at least understand okay where is it
strong where is it weaker so where do we
need to do stuff ourselves build
detections or get an additional product
that's basically a thing and it will
never be completely blue right everybody
that works with with the attack
framework knows
that there's no there's no holy grail
there
and we can also start mapping the data
potential so basically we can look at
what type of data components does it
actually log
and what would that theoretically
be able to visualize for us and then of
course it's theoretically because not
every attack will be visible that way
and
not
all data will be in there since it is
configured and
sampled so
it's it's at least the direction so we
can understand do we even have the
potential of data for it
and basically what you what we did is
map it basically to every uh mitre
data component with the the table and
the entries in there that we want to
utilize
and this gives us a huge potential in
theory again but we can cover well 299
techniques which is quite a lot out of
the 550
ish that they have
and we can even start visualizing it so
this is a custom bloodhound version that
we that we used
where we can see okay if we want to only
use the registry for instance as a
data source what kind of techniques
could we be covering here
and then we can see which event types on
the on the provider side which is
defender for endpoint can we actually
utilize this is a nice visual way of
seeing okay what can i actually do with
my data
but also what is important is so where
does the telemetry come from on the
operating system there's all kinds of
ways that it can be acquired so we
started looking a little bit into this
and the easiest tool i could find to do
this was mimikatz because it's just so
convenient in there but basically we can
see all the the kernel callback channels
that were there
and see if this is here so welcome
um but
the the cool thing here is if we can see
basically what what it does does is it
tells the kernel the driver tells the
colonel hey if an incident like this or
an event like this happens i want to get
a
an event from it so we can see that we
see a wd filter that says and mss
the wd filter is the windows defender
agent so that's the av component
and the msec flt is basically the edr
component so they both get their own
individual data stream and they might
also look at different information there
so
they if you want to kill it or if
somebody wants to kill it they have to
kill both which is kind of nice
but you did you don't necessarily know
what they do when you see some system on
in between as well
for the people that use that so
a lot of the stuff is the same so they
get the same telemetry at least from the
kernel
with one diff difference though
on the process side you can see a
pre-operation and a post operation which
technically means the pre-operation is
whenever it happens so process creation
event
and the post operation is a process
termination event so as you can see
sysmon does both and the defender
product doesn't do that so
not necessarily bad
unless you want to monitor for it or see
how long a process lived
which could be cool in an ir
investigation right
but yeah that's something the edr won't
help you with
and then the event tracing for windows
bit it's basically the mechanism on the
kernel side which generates all the raw
telemetry it's a fire hose so don't just
ingest everything
and it's basically built in three layers
so you have providers you have consumers
which basically consume what the
provider gives you and they have a
tracing session which is sort of
a consumption based thing from a
provider but it works in a slightly
different way
and basically
what it does and what the defender
product does is it creates its own
providers as well where it basically
looks at itself and these are
sort of aggregation providers so what it
does is it looks at a lot of other etw
events gets it into its own
stream and then hooks on that and ships
that to the uh to the portal
and
there were there were like i don't know
how many as an eight or nine so i i was
very interested in what's in there right
because i want to know what is actually
what what is being logged what it's
looking at to understand a little bit
more what i can actually do with it
so what it does is it stores it first
locally so it's it makes a
subscription to the event tracing for
windows providers
gets that information stores it in the
sqlite database and that gets flushed
every time it uploads it so there's a
sort of local store and forward system
to not lose any of the telemetry if the
internet goes down or whatever on that
machine
and it's kind of funny that they use a
sort of very old
code name for that database which is
called asimov which is i think a halo
reference
but it's also
now
the whole asimov project
was renamed it to the direct track
service which we'll come back to in a
second so keep in mind that name
and basically this is where it stores it
so it's not very important for the rest
it's it's
assigned and it's protected so it's very
hard to tamper with that from an
attacker perspective so that's
relatively safe
so then i was interested in what what
kind of telemetry is being being
generated right or being captured
and
one of the very nice tools to to start
looking at those event racing things is
um is c lighter it's a it's a relatively
simple tool where you can just say okay
i want to subscribe to these providers
and you can log it to either the screen
or to a json file or even to the event
log itself so you can create your own
custom feeds if you want to
and as the the the creator mentions it's
not as stable i found it very stable but
if you want to do with a skill maybe tw
or even velociraptor might be a better
way to to start hooking those
so once i started building those traces
i saw you get a very nice structured
data output per event this is from the
cyber security feed
or cyber defense feed
and one of the things i noticed was this
this events blob which looked like a
base 64 string so i figured okay let's
just decode it that's probably possible
and then i got this as an output and
probably you can't read it
but but this looks probably quite
familiar to a lot of people which is
even in the same structure with all the
ugly tabs and so on as a normal event
log events from the powershell
provider
so that was kind of interesting and then
there was some some base some some
basically some some blobs and binary
code around it so it turns out that this
uh that's bond it's an open source
project by microsoft where they use
some serialization with a schema
to make it more efficient to upload it
and just compress the data a little bit
i couldn't find the schemas in the in
the source code of
of the defender
client but i also didn't really need it
because i was more after the the
telemetry generation so i
i might dig into that later
um
but my next question was basically so
hey that powershell information is kind
of interesting where does it get it so i
started looking at
all of the providers the etw providers
and their subscriptions on the operating
system and one of the tools to use is
the telemetry sourcer which is another
open source tool really nice
and you can basically see the
on the left side you can see all of the
providers and the subscriptions or the
sessions next to it
and the powershell one only had one
session basically so only the event log
was actually capturing that powershell
information and i rented a system so i
should be able to see everything
um so then my sort of assumption would
be a
mde just uses the event log right
because i can't see a session there
so i started looking a little bit more
on the underlying side and there the
dire track thing comes back which is the
diagnostics tracing service from windows
which captures a lot of information
and apparently also microsoft uses that
as a vehicle to get to some of those
event logs
and the interesting bit was that
the service itself is not protected so
it's just there and every local admin
can basically kill stop
and pause it
and if you do that some of the telemetry
doesn't go into the defender portal
anymore so you you can partially blind
it you still will have all your brass
creation all the other ones that it gets
from the kernel directly but some of the
event tracing for windows traces will be
sort of suspended for that for that time
so
i don't know why it used to be a
protected service for quite a long time
and then for some reason
in one of the patches
it suddenly got unprotected
so that's something i still have to
validate with microsoft but it's
interesting to know so if somebody stops
at surface that might also be a trigger
for you to have a look at
so going to the configuration a little
bit so like every product you have to
tell it what to do and as i mentioned
before microsoft maintains this
it's stored on the box
it might be a nice cdf to to find it
and and
decode it
because i'm not going to tell you where
it is for
all kinds of reasons i don't want people
just just to be able because you can
basically see everything it's tracing
which is great for every offensive
person or ransomware person as well
but it will be a nice exercise to do so
um
it is signed so you can't
add stuff to it or remove stuff from it
it's just a source that the process can
can
access
and we so far we didn't manage to
actually
bypass that signing so that that's it
it's quite secure but it is it's
readable and on a mac linux box it's
super easy because that's stored in just
the json blob in plain text
as a file so
those are easy but the ones on the
windows box is slightly more complicated
but some examples there so so they
configure all the etw events and the
registry keys the file passes monitoring
and so on all kinds of exclusions the
filters that they apply to it
which process names are white listed
a lot of stuff and then the the very
important one is the capping so they do
a global cap and a local cap so the
global cap is basically i only want 5
000 powershell events for that day
and then the local gap might be i only
want one powershell event today that was
spawned by this process and this command
line and some some of the other ones so
it's basically trimmed down a little bit
then they also do a lot of dynamic data
collection so they have all kinds of
powershell scripts that they run to see
which
which wi-fi connections you have stored
on your box or which services are
running all kinds of dynamic data
collection
then the config of the agent itself so
how often should it upload what are the
quotas
if if there's a low latency connection
or a high latency connection it also
trims down the volume of the data that
it will upload so it will be a little
bit dynamic from that perspective and
that config is huge it's like probably
over 75k lines by now so it grows over
time
and we also monitor that to see what
they're actually including excluding
these kind of things
we can see all the etw providers and the
events within it that it's uh it's
grabbing there's like 500 registry paths
that it's monitoring
and and all those data collection once
it's like 60 scripts it's quite a lot
so this is just a random snippet of it
as a very lengthy list as i mentioned
before so this is an interesting one the
threat intelligence provider which is a
windows native etw event that is only
accessible to
[Music]
basically approved
what is it the elam drive so the early
load malware analysis driver it's
slightly different but you get drift so
microsoft allows you to to get access to
that or not so mostly most av and edr
vendors have it and what's in there is
like process suspension events process
resume
um some some virtual allocations so a
set of api calls that it can monitor
the powershell commands we actually seen
that one right in this in the example
before and i saw security w which which
kind of looked funny to me because it
the name is very different but yeah it
says secure so it must be interesting so
i started looking at that and what what
i did first i looked up the provider
guide so everything has a global unique
id
and with log man which is a native
windows tool you can just query it and
see what it's actually called so
it turns out it's just a security lock
so from there i started looking at hey
what's actually in that security log
which events is it tailing so for
instance it checks the 4624 which most
people would know as the logon success
and then we can also see a couple of
things so we can see the events or the
fields that it's making that that local
cap on right so there's a cap of one
if a specific user with a specific
domain name with a specific sid and a
specific logon type from a specific ip
has a specific target logon id so that
that whole set of things would be one
event per day so if i use a different ip
with the same other variables it will be
a new event and there's a thousand in
total that would get logged
and then there's a bunch of field
configurations so basically all the
fields that would get shipped to the
portal
um
so then i was interested okay it tells
the security event log which events is
actually looking for and it's quite a
lengthy list as you can see
you don't have to go through it all but
basically what i then did so i know from
security log is that sometimes you need
to enable some of those events right
because
out of the box
it's pretty bad so there's a couple of
things that you can do
i have to speed up i know this so if i'm
going too fast just wave
but basically what you can do with the
audio policies is you can set nothing
and then it doesn't audit
you can say it's only on the successful
field and on both
so for most of those events that we just
saw we can actually know
what setting does it require to get logs
so i started mapping that and then i
started looking at
what is on a default out-of-the-box
windows box so from that whole list and
most of them are grayed out that are
actually fine but all the white ones
remain as
out of the box not logged but required
by the edr or at least preferred by the
edr and there's some some interesting
ones in there like service creation
um
scheduled tasks which are probably two
of the most used attack factors
so there it's blind to that by default
but fortunately
the defender team was also aware of this
so they enable a bunch of those
but they still don't enable all of them
and there's a couple of reasons because
as you can see you see the firewall one
and you see uh
default credentials which isn't that
noisy but especially the firewall one
most people would know that that's like
a fire hose so you might not want to
have that enabled on all your servers
that are also shipping to splunk or
sentinel or something else and then get
flooded by all kinds of data because you
enabled edr so this is the reason why
they don't enable that sadly they also
don't document that they don't enable
that
which you have to sort of find out now
or by yourself so that that's kind of
shitty sorry for my language but um that
that's yeah that's not good so at least
have a check
in your environment and that's also
something to know so they enable
they enable a couple of them right
serves creation for instance you
probably have that in your gpo already
but if you have something else in your
gpo and they enable it the gpo will just
override that and then it's gone again
so
be aware what you actually have set in
your your gpos
and
to help you out i build a very bad
powershell script but it basically gets
all the gpos sees where there's an audit
event
and if it isn't enabled it will tell you
or if it's not in the right setting so i
have a have a check there so i have to
almost wrap up there we go
um so just to conclude really try to
understand if you use a tool how it
works
where it's strong where it's bad because
then you can actually
address that
and try to reassess this because tools
like these evolve over time they
constantly get improved or sometimes
worsened
so you can then augment it with an
additional tool just to improve your
telemetry and make the full use of it
and with that i think we have time for
questions
absolutely so there is a microphone in
front
please
do ask
question we have a couple of minutes
left
i think it was very good to see uh
some
insights and ticks and trips that
you can
give us so that people
can be aware of these details
yeah one of the things i'm working on
now if there's no questions i'll just
talk on
probably
a few more minutes
one of the things i started doing
because one of the the most annoying
features is that they most of the time
they they restrict the amount of
telemetry but for the dll loads it's
completely random there's really no
logic behind it so you just get events
maybe or not
so what i started doing now is starting
an open source project with a defender
application control policy that is in
order only mode for the dlls that i
actually care about
so that at least that dilemma sheet gets
generated and that will also show up in
the portal so it's just a sort of cheap
hack to get rid of some of that other
limitations
sir
there is a question down there
yes yes it's working thank you thank you
for this presentation presentation i was
just wondering is there a documentation
from microsoft on this i'm not a client
for microsoft
no no that's sadly on the at least on
the blind spots with the security audit
settings there's no documentation so
the only thing i i couldn't find it at
least and i googled and i searched on
the microsoft website i haven't seen it
there used to be something only around
the firewall events but the rest is just
it's not there exactly no i have the
same issues with my own provider
yeah it's a shame right because if they
if they want to have that telemetry it
makes the product better so you would
figure they would at least tell you to
enable it to make the product their
older product
perceived as a better product so
and as you say you would better
understand how the product is working
and how yeah
where it cannot work uh and where you
have to put specific things around
exactly that they don't publish their
own configuration like the one that i
reversed i can imagine because that's
helping attackers but this is just
enabling your your whole work fleet of
at least generating the right telemetry
which that should be that should be
documented period
thank you welcome thank you
thank you for the question and let's
thank allah for the very insightful
presentation thank you
so we have 10 minutes to either change
the room or stay here and
stretch a little bit and then in 10
minutes we'll start the next
presentation