[Music]
hello everyone thank you to be here
today
i want to remember that the current
session will be tlpy tp white sorry this
session name is follow the dynamite
commemorating team tnt clouds attacks
and to speak about it let me to
introduce
nicole fishbein and joaquin kennedy
thank you guys
um thank you everyone and
we just want to kind of give you guys a
a walk through of the sort of the
activity of a threat actor called team
tnt
um
come on there we go my name is joy kim
kennedy and i'm a security researcher
for inteser
um i kind of consider myself as a
assembly reader i spend most of my days
sort of looking at suspicious binaries
and things like that
when i don't do that i also hunt for
gophers usually malicious gold binaries
i have
a open source project for
binary analysis of go binaries
that is hosted on github
hi my name is nicole fishbein i'm a
security researcher at integer and
previous to that i was in the embedded r
d department in the idf
so today we're going to present you team
tnt and
i will present the chronological order
of their
saga which is kind of a shakespearean
strategy story because it started pretty
well for them
with targeting ready servers
then they moved to the cloud nine
targeting different cloud
infrastructures
and they got really famous they have a
very active twitter
account
and then they had to deal with the cost
of fame when copycats started to show up
and right until the
end
so who are team tnt
uh it's a group it's a threat actor that
targets cloud infrastructures to mine
cryptocurrency
uh basically crypto jacking crypto
jacking means mine cryptocurrency on
someone's else's computer
and crypto jacking is the most popular
threat to to the cloud and team tnt is
the most active threat actor that we can
attribute attacks to
so we will start right from the
beginning
okay
so the beginning
so this kind of era kind of starts in
around like winter 2020.
um
they started to target redis servers
and
what is kind of unique with this kind of
start was the um
the use of pn scan which is something we
usually see
crypto mining threat actors do they
download it on an infected machine and
they scan for others and then just sort
of spread as a worm around it
but the interesting thing with this
actor was not the sort of use of a
massive shell script instead everything
is broken out in a lot of shell scripts
files
in addition to that they also utilize
some binary tools
one of them that's very like that they
liked a lot is
movie track is like tsunami
it kind of was
downloaded as this whois.irc
um it's a irc bot that is designed for
denial service
and hence sort of like where the tsunami
comes from because it's one of the key
words that you can send to the bot which
is basically to flood everything
the other use is a
linux backdoor called rat hole
relatively simple and provides just
shell access with encryption
and in addition to that they also had a
binary that sort of operated as a
watchdog that made sure that everything
was running
and
to do some lateral movement they utilize
a post exploitation tool called punk p
which uh i think is all the way back to
like packet storm and stuff like that
but nowadays you can also find it on uh
github
the interesting a bit here is that
even from like the beginning uh they
started to sort of
exfiltrate credentials uh and trying to
sort of spread within the network um
there were some interesting ways of
doing this where they would go through
bash history and
steal keys or whatever
now the sort of the
initial name of where like team tnt come
from is the first use of sort of the
registration of their domain name which
they registered as you can see here in
february
now
on this sort of server where they hosted
so they hosted all of their tooling on
this server
we could sort of manage to get get some
stuff that was sort of dated uh
relatively early um here's for example
is something that was uploaded or added
to the server four days after the
registration of the domain name
so it's like one of the earliest tools
that was out there
this is kind of the nightmare of shell
script
that you have just to show how things
are sort of connected
it starts with the shell script in the
big sort of in the middle called
load slash setup dot sh that's sort of a
folder name because it has a couple of
other loader
it will download all of these other
tools and stuff like that uh which
sets up to sort of the spreader
functionality um the mining part
um
and
some other stuff like just to grab
credentials
the one thing that's very interesting
with this group is from the beginning
they slapped on like a
copyright header on their shell script
so
here we have you know like
it's describing what it is so this is
you know the
for example we see the top one there is
the
shell scripted
focused on on compromising redis and
it's their private module uh with uh a
copyright of hildegard which is the
handler for a handle name for the team
tnt operator
we also have the apoorman's ssh
keylogger
and things like that
um
also throughout sort of the um the shell
scripts although the comments were in
german so it's kind of like the first
sort of hint that maybe this is actually
a german threat actor
now
they're also utilizing some really
interesting like homemade kind of
tricks to kind of
do stuff here for example is a shell
script that is installed who's designed
to hide files um and as you can see what
it's doing
it is a it creates sort of like a
bind mount or like i know if with a new
fs mount on like a bsd where
it's sort of linking a folder
um and it does it over the um
where in the procf
uh file system where sort of like the
process information would be
uh so it turns to hide itself by doing
that
now
unfortunately unlike most linux
distribution nowadays
um this mount tab is just a link that
it's sort of manipulating with that
points to the proc fs so it's not a file
that exists on disk
and also if you run some of the commands
to list sort of mounted folders and
things like that
and
the tools is not using those files at
all they kind of just provided there for
shell access
so
it was a nice attempt but i don't think
it worked that well on the actual
infected machines
the
credential stealing method so this is a
the poor man's ssh logger um just uses
s-trace and looking for specific
syscalls and just logging it and then
having sort of a cron job that runs
and
sort of
uploading the logs they
in a hope that like someone logged in
and authenticated to another machine and
sort of grabbing those credentials
so the tsunami botnet so this is
from the beginning we saw this one and
this is the one that they've used all
the way till the end
um it was used sort of as a
secondary access once they've sort of
got control over a machine
and we can see how it's
it's a
like a newer version oh sorry it's a
old version of uh chitin or sigistar tux
these are two like uh
incarnation of sort of like this this
malware that you can find source code on
github there's plenty of like
repositories with it
this one that they're using doesn't have
the new functionality so it's taken from
one of the original sort of
source code
and as i said it has the ddos
functionality but it also provides a
shell access
and the way they it it ran on there when
they infected it it will change its name
to sort of masquerading as a kernel
thread
the the rat hole as i said it's just an
open source back door
uh it uses blowfish for the encryption
and
the interesting bit is like the key that
they had was um team tnt
so they started kind of putting their
mark on their stuff
now
those were kind of the artifacts that we
could get from where they started to
utilize sort of like the team tnt
but luckily um this rat hole binary was
actually uploaded to virustotal a couple
of months earlier
and so here here you have sort of like
the posting of it when it was first
uploaded
and sort of utilizing where this one was
shared from we could actually pull back
and find other activity that's that
they've had done before
and the interesting bit here is in the
screenshot down the other user with a
username called hilda and then
the password if you crack it is uh hilda
is a guard so
this is a name that you will see it was
both in sort of like the copyright
and you'll see sort of even like in all
of the activities that they have
all right so spring 2020 that's when we
saw the major shift
to targeting docker and not only redis
but also in spring 2020 the first
documentation of team tnt's activity was
published by trend micro
so that's when other vendors started to
track them
thank
you so spring 2020 uh that one that
that's when the first documentation of
team tnt was published by trent micro
and that's where the major shift to
targeting docker uh environments
made by team tnt
but they still continue to use open
source tools and scripts to deliver the
threat and carry on the malicious
activity
to target any an exposed docker instance
they first would scan the network using
maskin and zigreb to open source tools
once they would find the dock and expose
docker instance they would create
a legitimate image
of alpine and set it to execute to
download a certain script that will
download all the other scripts that will
execute
that data
and similar to what we saw before we
have one script that we'll call another
one and then each script has its own
dedicated
task could be installing persistence
evaded detection and executing the next
components of the attack
and an interesting thing that we were
able to find is when we looked into the
different scripts we found a url
and then we analyzed what other scripts
communicate or using this url
so we found another script on virustotal
and the interesting thing
is that it didn't target docker it
targeted redis but it was uploaded in
spring 2020.
so it means that team tnt didn't
entirely shift their focus from redis to
docker rather they expanded their
victim range
and another interesting thing is that
this script still has two detections on
virustotal
and spring 2020 is when
coveted pandemic spread and affected
each and every one of us
many threat actors still using the
pandemic to deliver threats and phishing
attacks
but team tnt started to use covenanting
keywords and buzzwords in their scripts
and urls for no obvious reason
maybe they decided just to go with the
flow with other threat actors
thank you
so the summer
i'd say the kind of they
they moved the way sort of from the
reddest part and docker became sort of
their bread and butter
now there was some minor changes to it
um
here is one of the setup scripts that he
they utilized
um where he first tries to fetch a
what appears to be a jpeg but it's just
a shell script
and
the sort of the new part here was like
if that failed they just base64 encoded
the shell script uh as an alternative um
so if they because of the uh
the or bar
in in the uh in the double or
if the first command fails it will do
the other one so
even if their server goes down it would
still sort of spread through it
the
other kind of shift we saw here was that
the actual started to go more hardcore
with regards to root kits so here is
sort of a script that downloads the
amorphon this is a open source kernel
level root kit and it would download and
compile it on the machine and load the
kernel module to hide the mining that
was going on
the credential
harvesting expanded and
here you have a sort of a
list of all the different kind of files
where it was going through so
um
it would go through and look for all of
the uh known hosts for ssh all the user
accounts and and ssh keys and things
like that and then it just would loop
through and just try to what would work
um
and sort of just to spread within sort
of like its network
fall 2020 was the time of different
changes and updates in team tnt
the first thing that our research team
was able to find is that they use a tool
called wifscop which is an open source
tool to control and monitor your
containers
and once it's stalled it's relatively
easy to install and once installed it
creates a dashboard that you can access
through the browser
so you have all the files all the
resources all the processes that run on
the container and a really nice shell to
execute commands and it's open in the
browser and it can be set to
to have access from outside of your
network so anyone can access it
so once tmtnt found an exposed docker
instance they would install wifscope and
basically they had a full backdoor
without running or sorry without
developing a backdoor and by using a
legitimate tool so they evaded detection
then once again they expanded the
credential stealing capabilities using
once again open source tools
mimi penguin is similar to mimikots but
only for linux so it dumps all the
processes looks for passwords
and mimi pi does the same but it also
supports extraction of passwords from
http and browser communication
as reported by eset
team dnd started to use izuri so izuri
is a crypter or
or a packer written in goaling and it's
open sourced
and it takes the the payload encrypts it
with aes
and that's how they were able to evade
detection of standard tools
their social media account on twitter
is very active during this time period
and they tweet a lot about their
activity about different things
and that's how we were able to find more
information and better understand this
threat doctor
we took all the tweets and started to
analyze them so
we wanted to understand
what are the active hours of the fred
group maybe to understand where they're
located
and as you can see they're more active
during the late afternoon and evening
however they're active the whole day
and that's how we once again we think
that they're in germany
because of all the tweets that are in
german or talk about german news and
related topics
another very interesting thing is that
they openly talk about their activity
they're not hiding it
and they're not thinking of themselves
of
the bad guys or threat actors
and they're very responsive
with co the researchers and with the
community which is
really rare
so here for example uh they replied to a
research that we posted about one of
their campaigns
and they refer to this
mount trick that we covered a few slides
before
so the
winter so during the win
one of sort of the reports that came out
about the group
from lacework
they
got onto one of the irc servers that
they used to control the tsunami bots
and reported that about 200 affected
bots at
sort of like activity kind of around
that
now
of those 200 it was 90 of them from
unique ip addresses
so
we've already seen that they are very
heavy on like the lateral movement so it
kind of suggests that they are actually
effective in managing the moves within
the network um also the threat act is
also reported of a couple of vendors
that they keep sort of trolling into
their network and it's he kind of found
annoy that he just kept getting in and
stuck in their networks
in general from sort of like the the ip
addresses most of it was just cloud
based cloud providers
majority of them were based in asia but
not just like asian companies and just
their endpoints
so you have the vendors up there indian
in general who was there
additionally to this now they all also
added a secondary kind of method for
their rootkit functionality
so they started to download this lib
process hider it's a open source tool uh
kind of followed with the same theme as
they've always been doing
um
utilizing a different method
to achieve sort of a user land based
root kit which makes it a little bit
more portable
it hooks like it loads itself into
processes using
the linker uh so you can sort of
manipulate the the world around or like
the infected machine and sort of stay
hidden
the other shift that happened here was
that they moved away from docker and
started to directly target kubernetes
um
we also saw more use like pretty much
all of their binaries at this point were
using the same packer to sort of stay
hidden
one thing that
we were surprised to kind of find was
when
we're sort of looking at some of the
files that sort of been or like
connections that
virustotal had recorded for like their
uh
infrastructure
we noticed these urls um
and some of these files are detected as
windows files or pa files
so
it could be that they were sort of
moving on to targeting windows servers
uh and
one of those files was it's just a
compile auto-it script that is called
like a they call it a sniffer and it's
pretty much what it is it will actually
just install a
win pcap and then perform packet
capturing and look for specific
credentials and stuff like that on the
wire
and the other one is a
miner for that is specifically compiled
for uh cuda so like the nvidia graphics
card
additionally to that this drop miner
also will drop a
a windows driver
um
[Music]
it's this driver um
allows for root sort of like ring zero
access
and it it's actually part of the miner
itself
to
set up a couple of uh cpu registers to
improve performance
and
so it's part of the legitimate run miner
but probably not recommended if you to
have it on your machine because a user
lane can reach into
to ring zero and do any manipulation
for the sort of like this
via this driver there's no sort of
protection in that
so next they continued to extend their
credential staying capabilities uh as
reported by trend micro so they uh moved
from targeting only aws or ssh looking
for
crypto wallets ids
github api keys and so on
and on top of that
they use the aws cli tool which is a
legitimate tool that provides lots of
information about the instances the
um the framework the volumes the network
connection that's only a small part of a
huge script full with commands of aws
cli that team tnt executed on a
compromised
environment
and
a report was released saying that 50
000 ip's from china
were compromised by team tnt
and that's where they
replied and said that's not us and the
numbers are not quite right and you
should check your facts
and then another researcher
connected some scripts to one of tim
tnt's campaigns once again they replied
saying that's not us and someone else is
using our old scripts or our techniques
so
it seems like some sort of a copycat
someone else is using team tnt's scripts
and techniques
because another report that attributed
some more
attacks and campaigns to team tnt was
published and once again they responded
so we learned that first of all someone
is trying to use team tnt's artifacts
to spread more mueller
and team tnt refused to take the false
the false connection
so
it's kind of idea with like the copycat
obviously didn't
go well with them and so they kind of
decided to come up with a way of like
how can we make sure that
security
researchers and things like and people
like us actually would know that this is
team tnt
so they put this in this information out
saying that they would
start sort of tagging the stuff which
include like a link where you can get
the most recent version of the shell
scripts that we using
and they also did that so they added
this to the headers for all of their
shell scripts
tells you what it sort of what it is
and the name of it and the aversion
number and also sort of like the
the date when it was created
this was
kind of part of a new kind of campaign
that they called during the summer
called chimera
and
you have sort of they put up this new
website and you can see kind of like the
where they were targeting which
different instances uh so we have both
docker kubernetes and
weave scope um
and they were trying to kind of create
like a live dashboard to say like how
many how many machines have we managed
to compromise and how many hash what's
our hash rate
um
but
clearly like this overwhelming of like
copycat cats
and kind of overwhelmed them and then
eventually towards like the fall
the activity dropped
and then
like in november they post sort of put
this information this announcement out
where they sort of said that they were
done
and they put a
this url here it just is a link to a
i think it was a zip file or a web
directory where they have all their
tooling including source code
so
unfortunately what that leads to today
is that you see a lot of like team tnt
stuff
but it's all coming from like this stash
so there's a lot of like threat actor
just sort of utilizing this
their um
twitter handle has kind of gone quiet in
terms of the
crypto mining part they still tweet
especially around like german
policies and politics and stuff like
that
but they kind of have tried to moved
away from
the crypto jacking part
so
just sort of just to conclude sort of
the the conversation here um
so in general we would say like the
crypto jacking is like one of the majors
or threat to linux environments
there's actually a lot of threat actors
out there doing it um
the barrier to entry is relatively
low for them they utilize this all the
same exploits
and sort of to protect against this is
relatively easy it's just make sure
you're
you use no like solid credentials so you
know no weak passwords
uh patch your stuff uh and don't ex like
expose stuff that shouldn't be exposed
um what team tnt utilized a lot was
the
misconfiguration of docker
servers that had the api
listening
on the internet which allowed anyone to
send whatever command you wanted to the
the back end and spin up whatever images
you wanted
now in during this time team tnt was
sort of like one of those uh predominant
actor they sort of resulted in the most
compromised
machines
and their focus was
most of the time around docker and
kubernetes
and
the
interesting bit
is that compared to all of the other
sort of crypto
jacking actors that we've seen out there
they had a very
strong like public presence
where they
would tell threat researchers if they
were wrong
uh and also as
we saw some of these tweets they would
share
like how successful they were um which
is
quite of an interesting uh
sort of scenario
so
that leaves us with it
so thank you akin thank you
nicole some question
for
okay there we have one
from me
thank you for the talk great talk it's
very interesting um
i'm curious about something because we
are following another group
which is basically using tor web
gateways and accessing hpc
infrastructures
exactly same techniques the tools are
even i think the same scripts are the
same i don't see the german part
and for what we know this seems chinese
because the first connection they do to
their backend infrastructures is from
china
and when we look at the translations we
were wondering if it's not chinese using
automatic translations
or something like that
did you
try with the dataset that you have to
automatically translate all the text to
see which one makes sense
to see if the original translation is
not coming from another language
um good question no we actually didn't
do that
most of the stuff we were looking at we
looked at the
historical part and we just was
following along as they were changing
the scripts
when sort of like that copy cat stuff
came on board
because we looked at so many of the
scripts we could see that this was a
hodgepodge of like it's not theirs it
doesn't follow along with what they were
doing yes it's like it was pulling the
stuff from
their old server
uh which i think was a compromised
web server
but there was so much other stuff going
on that just it was such a drastic
change
it's like we saw like
they
used this technique and then you would
see this completely different thing and
then back to that normal again and it
made no sense those jumps
and also when we looked back further it
was the same thing as they were saying
that those are old scripts
and they match pretty well with the
older stuff too there too so it kind of
made sense um
the
some of the paths too was very similar
to like another
um
krypto miner i think some vendors are
tracking it as system d minor or
something like that
so they were the one that sort of picked
up
but yeah
thank you for question we have another
one
yeah
comment to the to the previous question
and when when you show the tweets as a
native german speaker uh you know they
read all great grammatically until at
some point and then i was like what
grammar is wrong here now
are they smoking potter or something i
don't know what yeah but so maybe that
there is an indication that there is
something there anyway my question is or
my comment is that um when you run
docker by default on ubuntu at least
debian as well you totally evade
ufw or ip tables
so maybe that is something a really
quick trick for
lots of linux systems to actually
not have that by default because
many system admins might not even be
aware that it's actually docker opens
that
and they configured the ip tables
properly but
then docker goes just next to it
yeah did you encounter that in your
research also
i think
it's not part of the the research
per se
do you want to talk yeah i know you did
some research on this part
the initial configuration of docker when
it's installed it actually doesn't
expose these ports
and
i just saw different guides that
guide people to expose these ports
because then it will be easier to access
the containers
so that's how i think most of the
misconfiguration happen
thank you there is no more questions so
thank you again to joahin and nicole
big applause for them
thank you guys thank you