[Music]
okay it's time and i will start the
session start the talk
so uh
i am yusuke masoka a research principal
with fujitsu system integration
laboratories
and i'm sharing this talk
um and
first a few
housekeeping notes um so this stock is
tlb white
and please mute your phone
and
q and a will be at the end of the talk
and that there are stun standing mics uh
over there
and over there
yeah and
so um
and uh so the
speaker is uh
first uh
kwelsky
sorry
i hope i did a decent thing and pewter
makes things happen
as the shadow server foundation ceo and
also coding is large-scale data
collection
analysis projects and shadow servers she
said relationships
he has a strong seasoned background
working at nask in poland for 14 years
at the third polska
team
he was the head of the third posca team
from
2010 to 2016
where he expanded the
sensor project malware analysis and
malware disruption capability
pure
interests include a threat intelligence
incident response honeypot technologies
he is a member and ex-director of the
honeypot project
as well as a botnet and malwa networks
which he likes to disrupt
and then
here's a dave
d costa yes
dave decosta is the internet spelunker
for the shadow server foundation and has
been involved in the internet security
for over 20 years
when he's not scanning the internet he
can find him doing things not online
so
the title is
internet spelunking
ipv6 scanning and device fingerprint
printing
so the stage is yours okay um hello
everyone
uh it's great to be back giving talks in
person again um the talk is about
internet spelunking so essentially our
scanning and how we uncover new strange
objects uh exposed on the internet
the talk will be given by two of us uh
uh together with my my colleague uh dave
decoster
um a very quick intro shadow server is a
non-profit uh working to make the
internet a more secure for all which is
kind of like an ever never-ending task
it's an american and dutch non-profit
foundation
we've been around for for for
15 years and we our mission is
essentially to
share information with internet
defenders at no cost to mitigate
vulnerable vulnerabilities detect
malicious activity encounter emerging
threats we do this for free we don't
sell anything
we are funded exclusively through
sponsorships grants and donations
and if you are able to support us in any
way we would very much appreciate it if
you like if of course you you like our
work we are about to launch a shadow
server alliance uh of a group of
like-minded organizations
uh as a way to ensuring our future um
stability from the financial perspective
as well so we've been around for a long
time and we are probably the world's
largest provider of free cyber threat
intelligence
we collect a lot of data sets um this is
data sets scanning we scan the internet
and that's really the subject of the
talk but we also sinkhole disrupt a lot
of um
botnet malware or other
uh uh malicious uh cyber crime and some
sometimes state
uh activities with and we disrupt and
take over um
the command control infrastructure
either through
a court order working together with law
enforcement or with industry
we also run vast honeypot sensor
networks
uh in thousands of locations worldwide
uh we run a big malware repository
that's comparable to to any antivirus
vendor with 1.7 billion unique malware
samples by hash and then all in all we
have 12 petabytes of storage
of various types of information that we
collect
and what we do with all of this is that
we share this for free
with the community so if if you're a
national c-cert you get the data that we
see every day for your country if you're
internet service provider you get data
for your network network every day if
you're a corporation or an sme or
university and you signed up with us you
can get our data there for free
um every single day so if you haven't
subscribed to our services please do and
there is no no catch here you really get
data for free and
we hope you do something good with it we
also use the data to support law
enforcement operations like we work
together with the fbi europol
and many other national national
agencies and long-term multi-year cyber
crime analysis and take down
operations
so the focus today is about our scanning
dave will really talk about how we
actually do the scanning and
also uh how we how we got into ipv6
scanning and then at the end i'll just
to wrap up i'll take over and talk a bit
also about how we actually fingerprint
devices
um remotely thanks to all of this um
scanning
so thank you
so on average day we report 149 million
ipa addresses
that are these are unique ip addresses
that we find in our
in our data sets from the from the
scanning so
uh it's not a small number
so to get that number we do
approximately well 107 billion udp
probes 225 billion tcps uh sins and we
perform 407 million full handshakes and
those numbers are probably small but
close enough
so first the ground rules of how we do
our scanning
we make sure that our scans will not
compromise harm or degrade system
performance we always we will always
always always use the smallest most
minimal packet size possible to get our
results two reasons first of all we
don't want to make a mess of your
firewall and second of all it's more
economical for us to send small packets
and we will test we will never ever ever
ever take a packet or a probe and just
fire it across the internet blindly
we'll always make sure that it's tested
is tested in a uh in a private
environment in a live environment
it will always be tested and before we
even do a full scan we'll do what we
call one shard which is one two fiftieth
of the uh of the internet
and on top of that we will only scan
what is necessary for uh to get the
information that we need to let someone
remediate their system
well so
we also also look for specific ports
used for our criminal criminal
infrastructures which law enforcement
finds useful and our scans will never
ever ever break the u.s laws
that is your red line that we will not
cross
so
how did we get here
no deed goes and punished
we can all thank christian rashford for
publishing a very actually very good
paper um
but the problem is is that this opened
the door for people actually made it
easy for people to realize how to do
reflective ddos scanning
so we started with one of the protocols
out of i think there are 14 on the list
uh we sort of dns because people were
already doing it it was easy for us to
do and the miscreates were already
abusing it
and also allowed us to double check our
work
the first scan that we did it uh was
very bad code it took up 91 hours to
complete we found 16.9 million um dns
servers on port udp 53 and we found one
let's say 12 and a quarter million of
them to be openly recursive and
vulnerable for abuse
uh scan currently takes four hours and
we're down to six million total
responses and we have one point eight
million recursive resolvers that's now
that was a that was reduction of 10
million ips
great it worked
um so after we discovered that you know
this this wasn't just a terrible idea
with uh with a here hold my beer we
could do this uh we got more hardware
more bandwidth we wrote new tools so
that's how we got down to four hours and
we proceeded to implement scans on the
rest of the targets
and everything was great and then
somebody came along and discovered that
um
poodle
it was a very bad thing and we said we
were asked can you scan for uh do tcp
scans we said sure we can do tcp scans
discover that doing adp scans is a whole
lot easier um udp you know you spray
attack packet out there and you're good
to go and you don't really do much you
decode a pack you decode the packet and
life is happy
since it's tcp you have to do a sin scan
then you have to do a follow-up scan
afterwards and you also have to decode
the https
that's expensive compute wise
but it took us a bit but we were able to
do it
and november 2014 we sent out our first
report uh with
15.5 million ips that were vulnerable to
downgrade attack
nowadays we're down to 2.3 million it's
still big but it's getting better
but you know
we really couldn't let it just sit
because it's only 11 protocols and had a
very large pile of hardware so well we
added a few more scans
we are currently at 103 uh scans on ipv4
and we're at 10 on ipv6
and yes i realized that oh actually you
can read that
so
to choose our next targets
we
don't just throw it no actually though
sometimes we do we don't usually throw a
dart on a dartboard but
it's usually trying to be topical about
it if it's something that's interesting
uh so it's like one in the days before
netis with the uh net of spot and that
stuff and the amplification attacks
there who chose to do that
or things like
sinful knock where you wind up with the
uh with the nation's z implant or uh
benign certainty on isa kmp we started
looking for things like that
and we also look for legacy protocols
that shouldn't be exposed things like
you know telnet rsh things that just
don't have encryption
and also for current things that
shouldn't be exposed um you know
say mongodb kubernetes mysql uh redis
or the other reason actually it's
probably one of the biggest reasons
that's actually scanned for something is
someone actually asked us someone sent
us an email and said hey
do you know how many of these are out
there and usually we're a curious bunch
of folks so
we look
and sometimes you find good things
usually we find a lot of bad things
but for some fun facts
with daily repeats we have sent
209 trillion udp probes i updated this
this morning so it's probably pretty
close
221 trillion tcp sins
500 as we performed 508 full protocol
connections that means https uh just a
full full handshake there mongodb
anything anything along those lines and
we have sent
287 billion
services for
remediation apologize advance for the
noise
because well i'm sure i'm at everybody's
firewall if you've seen me that's me if
you're not then someone just look at you
for a little harder
so to get all this done we have a very
large rack of gear we are currently
scanning from 37 servers there's so
they're pancake a combination of pancake
boxes and
and blade servers we have two 10 gigabit
lines that get very rather heavily
abused
and we have five uh ipv4 say five slash
twenty six and one slash twenty four on
ipv4 and we perform scanning from one
one slash 64 ipv6 block
and these are probably the dirtiest
sliders on the net
uh the nodes are assigned 15 ipv4
addresses and 33 ipv6 addresses so that
we can bounce around a bit and we say
bounce strong within constraints
and at least make sure that we don't
that we don't trigger too many ids's
because we hit everything from one ip
the methodology that we use for scanning
the tcp scans are scanned differently
than udp scans our tcp scans are broken
into shards
the shard is one two fiftieths of the
internet and we randomly do a random
seed using zmapp
and uh we use the entire i'll say all uh
all 37 nodes to actually scan from
and those are performed using the using
pretty much open source software our udp
scans are monolithic which makes life
interesting
they are each each scan is run from a
from a single node and is performed
using custom software
oops
for our udp scans our custom software is
something named railgun mainly because
you know you throw one packet in there
and we send it out really fast so it's
designed to say this is designed to send
a single packet randomly really fast to
all 3.4 billion packets and tries to
randomize them as fast as possible is
tuned for doing small small payloads it
can do large payloads but it gets very
cranky
it will send packets using all 15 ipv
ipv4 addresses that we have available on
the box
but the only downside is is that it has
very few safety measures if you want to
shoot yourself on the foot it will take
your foot off
uh usually we can scan for the internet
in about four hours for for any given
packet uh something like isa kmp usually
takes about six just because of the
packet size
and it's also highly dependent on the
number of things that actually respond
to us or if somebody decides to detox us
in the middle of a scan then things take
much longer
the tcp scans are done by commodity
tools we do our we do our assignment
jobs using condor which is commonly used
in a in research environments
so we use that to farm up the jobs as
needed to boxes that are idle the actual
scannings are performed by z-map because
it does it does its job quite well very
quickly and we use z-grab or z-grab 2
for the for the back end for most of the
things
and we have a few other tools for doing
uh for doing custom scans just because
things get strange
or they require multi steps
uh each service takes between 10 minutes
and three hours depending if that's uh
the time is highly dependent depending
on the complexity of the scan things
that don't require uh cryptography like
telnet um sometimes
ftp but those take and human times takes
eight minutes eight minutes and end from
38 boxes and if on machine time it takes
3 hours and 57 minutes which isn't too
bad
but things with cryptography
the longest scan that we actually have
is https um that is much slower it
requires 2 hours and 29 minutes in human
time which equates to
full to uh say a full two work weeks so
82 hours of machine height
but the reason that https is so slow is
because that it is a uh it is a
combination of a straight up https scan
a uh scan for
say ssl v3
tls version 1.3
we're looking for uh this for export
ciphers using that's what's called the
freak scan
and we're also looking for excel looking
for exchange servers and it's also a
portion of the kubernetes scans that we
do
which is why it's so long
and then after after things are run the
data is all parsed we check for protocol
specificity we send any check to make
sure that nobody's throwing bad data at
us however if somebody decides to spoof
data at us and sends it at
that
in ways that are actually protocol uh
compliant that causes issues sometimes
but we have solutions for that too
everything is normalized and it shipped
off for the data center to get turned
into reports
so
we have frameworks for dealing with
pretty much for ipv scans ipv4 scans
that make it pretty easy for us to spin
things up
everything was going swimmingly until
one day
goes
we have a we want to scan ipv6
and my first response i think
was actually and i quote are you nuts
he says no no no we have an idea
an idea he did have
so after a bunch of research um ipv6 is
like just like ipv4 there's a lot more
of it but not quite it's a little quirky
um you can't really set it from end to
end so we use uh we use queries and
curated lists where we source them from
ssl ssl certificates hitlist and other
places and we are currently scanning
about 814 million ipv4 ipv6 addresses
that we have determined are fully
actually currently in use
if we would want to actually blindly
scan the ipv6 space um it's highly
unfeasible since ipv6 space is 3.48
times 10 to 38 unique addresses it's
time to scan it would be roughly 2 times
10 to 250 years
way longer than i have patience for
so we use curated lists we're using uh
we're using passive dns records from
some of our partners that share data
with us
and we're using the ipv6 hit list from
the uh from the ipv6 hit list.github.io
certificate transparency seams sinkholes
and other partners and if you have more
data we'd love it
the
differences are that v4 v6 um you have
to use a different tool because one
created by the technical university
yeah
they have a zmap version that does ipv6
it does a great job
z graph and z grab 2 have native ipv6
support which is awesome
but there are other tools out there
yeah they don't exist
it has the uh we suffer the same problem
that every other security vendor has um
where the tooling for uh for instant
responders and defenders just doesn't
exist in ipv6 spaces uh so that's why i
feel if you uh if you have to receive a
report you'll notice that the ipv6 data
does not contain things like uh like the
tls version 1.3 uh scans because
while i can do it i do not have a tool
to do it fast yet
um the other problem problem is that
ipv6 scanning is much slower we have to
do much more general timings than ipv4
we can't just slam pack us out and
hopefully get stuff back
ipv4 we've tested that the
when we're using zmap the
potential packet loss begins at about
half a million packets but we use ipv6
the potential packet loss begins at
about 100 000 packets the reason for
this is just surely the packet size um
the default the minimum packet size you
can actually have an ipv6 is
1280 bytes if you remember correctly
which is uh substantially larger than
ipv4 so the processing time to actually
send it route it get it back and do
something with it is just causing that
just causes much more overhead
likewise if we're using uh confusing
concurrent senders to actually you know
actually us like splay our splayer scans
and actually do things multiple times at
once ipv4 we can do about 30 we can test
about 35 000 ips a single time ipv6 once
again we have the same problem with the
packet overhead where we start losing
data at about 15 at about 1500
the average number of ips that we could
actually process we can process
roughly a quarter million ips a second
with ipv4 but once again we've we see
that our speeds are dropped by about
probably a fifth let's say we're talking
to about a fifth to about 58 000 ips per
second
it's doable but
it's
annoying
and the other interesting thing is that
even though they're using different
protocol stacks ipv4 and ipv6 scans do
not like running auth running at the
same time on the same network interface
your machine will hate you trust me
uh to get around this we have uh we're
actually running routing those on
separate ip addresses and separate vlan
spaces that that route back into the
same network
our current ipv6 scans we're doing ssl
smtp telnet ssh http a couple ports
mysql ftp and postgres
and the responses
are sizeable
the biggest uh the biggest surprise
actually was http and uh
http being so large that one in eight
ips that we actually scan responds with
http
and when we look at the packet header
that the uh the page that we get back a
lot of them actually appear to be just
default pages so the best that we can
figure out is that
people are firewalling themselves from
ipv4 and they don't realize they have
ipv6 services running
mysql is so large there's one there's
one vendor that has a uh
that has a that has mysql up here
apparently uh enabled on every every vps
that they have we're not sure why we've
contacted them and
haven't gotten any answers back
but some other interesting information
observations that we can make from the
ipv6 scans is that with ssl
the things that ipv6 have
much better security on them there's
very very very very few things that
actually have uh the really old ciphers
so
it's not common that when we run a when
we're in scans for uh for poodle for
poodle that we actually come back and
don't see a single one usually we see
one maybe two maybe three per day but
that's it
um on ftp we're actually see greater say
greater adoption of encryption
finally
and my sql the other interesting thing
that we find that with the the one thing
that we find is that 42 percent of the
hosts um that have mysql running
they actually have some variety of acl
or block list
but on four but only four percent of the
same hosts on ipv6 actually have block
lists
as we look we'll get our population
scans we have
with the bulk of the in use we'll say
what's called in use ipv6 is we don't
really know exactly how much there has
actually assigned versus usage but our
best guess is that i say the the bulk of
the ipv6 usage is actually done perform
in the united states followed by denmark
germany and then the netherlands
however if we looked at the things that
are that we consider exposed or
vulnerable leaders still the united
states
not a surprise
but then we switched to netherlands
germany and singapore
but
i'll leave it at
the ipv6 scans we have currently are
small and we would like to make them
like do more if anybody has data they
would like to share it share with us so
we can actually scan the ipv6 space
more we would love to uh we'd love to
have it
and now
peter will tell us what he actually does
with all that data that we actually
collect
yeah thank you so yeah the lesson here i
guess from the ipv6 is if you think you
run ipv6 and nobody will find you
because it's not possible to scan then
i'm sorry they're wrong if we can find
them then the bad actors can also do so
so all the data that we collect from
from all the scans
uh we actually set on another mission to
try to identify
all the devices that are out there
accessible on the internet and by
devices i mean essentially anything that
is not a a desktop server a web server
we don't we don't focus on that we want
to focus on let's say let's call it iot
but a very light wide definition of iot
where we can get firewalls and
and home routers and all that stuff as
well and the idea is basically that
since we are running these 100 scans and
we have a lot of
um patterns that we can collect right
banners
uh strings um
this kind of information we can actually
match all these responses or try to
match all these responses and see if we
can identify
uh the make and model of a device that
is out there on on the internet and we
try to classify them by type what type
of device is it a router or a nas or an
ip camera or or something else right uh
we try to classify by vendor
model version and assign it to a sector
like is it a consumer device or is it an
industrial device or just just an
enterprise one
so we implemented a scan rule engine so
think of kind of like some kind of like
a snort for all responses coming in
and it basically classifies all the
scanned data from from dave here as he
submitted submits it to the shadow
server back-end api and we plan to have
like tens of thousands of these roles
but because we have limited uh
processing power human processing power
which actually needs to we need humans
to code the rules we have currently
around 1 200 only but it does give a
pretty good overview already of what is
out there in in various places so we
classify currently devices from from 173
vendors and that is basically up to 30
million
devices daily and we started sharing out
um this this information daily also with
the community um the idea being that you
know you should know really what the
devices are in your in your
constituency if you're a c-cert so that
you can respond adequately to any
threats or vulnerabilities uh that are
found in these devices so you can have
like immediate access to to to this
knowledge coming from us without having
to design a whole new scan all of a
sudden for confluence or or fortinet
firewalls or or or whatever right so we
have actually a gui for this graphic
interface where we can actually code um
code the rules and observe their usage
um
over time
um that makes it pretty easy to to add
new data set new rules either by
uploading essentially bulk
rules or just coding them
coding them manually and we typically
focus on various ssl
certificate attributes um the common
names their organization names there as
well we can we scan http so we can just
look at html body content and search for
search for patterns http server names
cookies snmp sys desk system uh fields
are very good ftp telnet ssh banners are
also are also good at help and
classifying devices and actually many
many more and there's more going to be
coming in as we try to enrich our scans
uh to collect more of the information
that we need such as like following
redirects where you can actually
follow an initial redirect and and
obtain more information
that is relevant uh to to a particular
device where essentially a login screen
quite often there's a redirect to a
login screen for instance so we're
currently missing that but but
essentially well we plan to add it and
i'll enrich our
our our data um as well so the rules are
really really simple it's just a
question it's just a boolean expression
uh where we try to specify various
fields
and then um and then make a statement uh
uh we just maybe basically assign values
to various fields based uh based on this
um boolean boolean expression so for
example uh if we want to identify
irobot roomba vacuum cleaners and there
are actually 400 of these worldwide um
exposed on the internet imagine that
we can actually look at the issuer
common name which starts with
the roomba string issue organization
name is irobot right and we assigned
that this is an iot
tag a device type is a home appliance we
that's the level of granularity that we
do but it's a vacuum cleaner right
device vendor irobot device model roomba
device sector consumer and we build
rules like this sometimes you need
multiple rules for certain devices
um sometimes you just need one rule uh
to catch to catch everything that's
exposed so
essentially it's a kind of like a
never-ending task where you just add
pile on the rules as new devices appear
or new scans up here which give us
new insight so if you're interested in
roomba vacuum cleaners around 400 out
there
around around the world there used to be
700 a year back so it's dropped a bit so
something must have must have changed
but we didn't really look into that in a
lot of detail philips philips huey
devices you know the smart lightning
systems
on on the internet there's actually 5
300 of those smart lightning systems
stuff people use in their homes
um uh exposed on on the internet thanks
to to well that's what we learned from
our scans most
uh most in the us but also quite a bit
in
in in scandinavia um as well i guess
it's dark quite a lot of times so it's
good there um
we also looked at uh many of the
industrial control system devices like
plc's they all they also have classic
internet protocols enabled right so web
servers enabled or snmp enabled this
kind of thing so for instance we're able
to identify 500 devices just based on
their
non-native so this is not based on on
the s7
protocol but simply on on other
protocols that are exposed out there we
actually also started industrial control
system scanning
that enables us to identify many more of
these types of devices but this is just
a stat for for the classic um
hdp or snmp essentially internet
protocols but s7 300 um 500 devices um
exposed
uh outside mostly germany
um united states and and japan as as you
can see here um microtic is is a device
that is the favorite of of uh
of many of us as as many of them are are
typically
um uh are there their favorite targets
of of many of many actors that use them
then for subsequent attacks whether it's
like ddos or or for tunneling to hide
hide their activities behind behind
various proxies so we are currently
introducing more and more scans so also
microtic dedicated scans
and we find every day
over three million uh essentially
exposed micronic devices um with uh most
of these many of these actually being
in in places like brazil
um especially but well also the united
states countries in europe um and and
and asia so that kind of gives us also
an insight into we started also looking
at at um at honeypot data and trying to
match what devices are actually
attacking the honeypot as well so that
we can get a quick overview of of of the
hacking activity going on at ever at
um various points um in in time 14 at
firewalls for instance uh fortinet is
is the most prominent firewall that we
actually detect in in our scans there
are 1.4 million devices
um so basically you know if if you know
where these devices are when there's a
vulnerability in a firewall or vpn
service which is usually pretty critical
of course uh we provide you the data for
your constituency
that basically provides you like pretty
good situational awareness of um
who is uh who is in danger where and uh
well the interesting thing about all of
this is
that you know we can change our way of
thinking about not just the internet as
in open ports or services but
essentially as in devices right and
different countries different networks
have different profiles and devices
based on whoever um they ended up
purchasing from so
uh think of a country's cyber security
as being determined essentially by the
effectiveness of a sales office of a
vendor in a given country and also to
look at some of the vendors like and see
if the amount of devices that they
they've that we can see um actually
correlates even with the location of
sales offices so we had like a u.s
county
breakdown of certain vendors and you can
find that quite often the amount of
devices that are present
in the counties are there's an office of
a vendor there so so this is how you
know the cyber security posture of a
country or your network is can actually
be
um be decided which is which is which is
interesting
in itself so most of the devices we
currently identify by country uh most
are in in in the united states um not
surprisingly canada interestingly brazil
there's a lot of stuff exposed in canada
but probably shouldn't be exposed
um the top vendor we detect is cisco
then huawei microtic is is third then we
have saturn com modems um
fortinet firewalls asus routers
um et cetera et cetera so there'll be
more and more stuff added here over over
time
um the stuff we are doing here is
actually an eu project and if you want
to see more results from from this
project from us and from other other
partners you can visit various.eu
to get more data and
including
data sets that you could actually use uh
for for for for for other work um like
the statistics that i'm presenting
i'm presenting here
um a lot of our work is going to be also
made public it's not just shared
operationally with uh but we're actually
going to release a new dashboard
um which which you can visit you can get
a preview here it's with a password now
but it will be public um shortly so feel
free to take a photo uh
password username alliance
the username is alliance the password is
safe for internet with a capital s and a
capital i
um
the it does contain uh information about
a lot of our other uh data sets uh it's
this is just the first iteration we'll
have some more stuff there uh we don't
have the device information there yet
but we do have the scans including ipv6
scans so you can get basically a live
view of your country and even a region
um within within a country it's not down
to the as level because we don't really
want to make that public but
but you can at least get to the regional
um regional level
finally if you would like to receive
this data for your constituency
everything that we talked about here
you can do that by visiting our website
um going to subscribe to reports in the
top right corner it's free really free
you just have to provide some basic
information about your network
contact us through your
through your domain uh work domain
basically um
and and provide us some information that
we can use to verify um whether you
really are the owner of
of of the network that that you say you
are so really easy
uh to to check out
and that's it um we have a lot of slides
as usual uh as an any single server
presentation but i hope it was a pretty
good overview
of of the scanning ipv4 ipv6 and
and the device fingerprinting that we
have introduced so thank you very much
[Applause]
hello sir carter from edison
so asking related to
the
i would say the equipment database that
you have collected
this means that you have now a
capability to
[Music]
flash scan
the network the in the whole internet
for example if you find a new
exchange vulnerability
and you want to identify
which versions are out there so you can
do that basically in within
half an hour
maybe
well we could considering that you have
the all the data i mean you don't have
to scan the whole net you just need to
bring on all the ip addresses you know
where there has been exchange server or
yeah so so at a given point in time
every day we do know where all the
certain servers are right like exchange
or or or others right so that makes it
easier to scan obviously with a hit list
uh the scanning is not necessarily
perfect because it's not dedicated just
to being uh an exchange and in this case
in your example we actually do have an
exchange scan but let's say a fortinet
scan which i used used before we don't
have a dedicated fortnite scan right so
we know there are fortinets there but we
don't necessarily know the version right
because they are not dedicated so we
will need to do a subsequent scan to
more more a deeper scan to try to
identify the version that is that is
true however dave can scan the internet
very very quickly so
i would say
if needed we probably could spin up a
scan if we since we know the population
if if we know what the um
if we know what page we're looking for
to scrape the information probably could
do it probably
uh probably an hour to uh with a little
bit of dev time but it wouldn't be
wouldn't be too terribly bad to do
with the death time right yeah it'd take
a little bit of dev time but it's not
it's probably not terrible so so do you
touch your
normal dedicated scans you anyway anyway
record the version numbers
if it's available if it's available yes
we do
carlos from the portuguese academic
season
well first thank you for the
presentation the data you send daily on
a daily basis and i got a bit concerned
about the slides where you have shown
that
you have said
no
laws of u.s are being broken
so
you are not saying
no laws of u.s and eu are being broken
so should we
worry about this
um
we just say we say no laws in the u.s
being broken because that is where we s
that's where the scanning cluster is
hosted uh we take great pains to not
break any law when possible um i
shouldn't even say what possible i just
don't want to break the law there's
there's there's no point in doing that
if we are breaking the law then that
this scan is not worth running yeah so
just to be clear none of the scans
involve exploitation of any kind right
so they are mostly hello scans or if we
can find a way to grab a version without
actually or determining if something is
vulnerable without actually exploiting
it that's what we do there are certain
scans which we could do but we never do
because they would actually
involve like reading a bit of memory uh
from a device for example or essentially
breaching
essentially
exploiting a vulnerability right so this
is this is what we never do right um as
dave said we scan from the us so we are
focused on on not breaking us laws but
to our knowledge we are also not
breaking any any other european laws
either and we certainly wouldn't want to
break any um that that is that is for
sure right so we have never had a
problem with it actually the other
detail i i was boring also is it seems
that you are doing the scans only from
one location with two
10 gig
links
so if it's kind of easy
to attack this location because it's
just one location so you uh do you have
any plans to
in some way
have diverse locations so the
the resilience
goes
improves it would be interesting to do
um
but
i mean it's definitely possible to do
but the problem is that uh it requires
money and a lot of it because the uh the
the scanning cluster requires a lot of
uh a lot of metal to actually run
yeah so i mean if somebody would like to
fund it then definitely
that's that's that's a fantastic option
um we do experience ddos attacks but
it's never really
been that it's hampered our operations
uh we do have other types of attacks
like uh
udp poisoning where for the udp scans
that we reach out that we send out uh
someone spoofs responses
and then we end up reporting false
positives so that's something that does
happen but that will happen regardless
of location right so yeah
that's
i think
but i'm just curious uh have you
considered using asics to offload the
cpus for either ipv6 scanning something
else maybe an asic online network or
something
no
we haven't to be honest
we've just done everything basically
just on metal and it's worked so far but
it probably would be not be a bad idea
to look down that route
well
if you've done if you've been doing this
for eight years then you could have
probably gotten a bit of value out of
other board asics or programmable basics
yeah
thanks yeah thank you
okay
let us thank the speakers again
you thank you and
please remember uh view the survey in
your mobile app
and uh
that's it for today thank you
[Applause]