[Music]
hello everyone
today meeting is a tlp wife and i want
to remember you that the q i session
will be at the end of the meeting
and one microphone is on the right side
one is on the left
and
the session name is it's just a jump to
the left of boom and
let me help with our welcome to lindsey
kate and scott small from recorded
future
[Applause]
all right hi everybody thank you so much
for coming to our talk today it's just a
jump to the left boom prioritizing
detection implementation with
intelligence and attack
so i'm lindsey k senior director of
operational outcomes record future so i
run the technical arm of our threat
intelligence team and i'm a malware
analyst and reverse engineer
and i'm scott small i recently
transitioned to a new role as a senior
analyst at a major u.s retailer but
prior to that i was a consultant
supporting mostly enterprise level
clients on both strategic and technical
applications of intelligence and to kind
of summarize our talk i'm happy to
report that mitre attack remains alive
and well in the cyber threat intel space
in even just a few years as a consultant
i saw a pretty steadily growing interest
in using attack for cyber threat
intelligence applications but also to
inform intelligence driven adversary
emulation and purple teaming
real quick standard disclaimer here the
content that i'll cover today doesn't
necessarily reflect the views of my
employer
and let's get into it so i'm a little
biased but in my view mitre attack
remains the best lens for generating
intelligence around and analyzing
adversary behaviors or tactics
techniques and procedures
however as interest in mitre attack has
continued to grow so too has the size of
the knowledge base itself so there are
now nearly 600 discrete techniques and
sub techniques in the enterprise matrix
and countless more implementations
and we'll circle back to this point
later but i recently took a survey of
publicly available detection rule
repositories and i found more than 9 000
of these detection rules and these are
just the open source ones there's plenty
more in private commercial repositories
as well as over 2100 offensive security
test scripts
so based on this alone the need for
prioritizing which controls to focus on
strengthening is clear and i've even
seen more awareness that intelligence
ideally should inform that
prioritization
what we'll do today is give more detail
about how this looks in theory we'll
walk through a case study showing
practical applications of miter attack
for cti
and finally we'll give a quick look at
an open source tool i had the chance to
release this spring that's designed to
help speed up this intelligence informed
control strengthening process
but first some quick context on why
we're framing up this whole discussion
around intelligence as opposed to
something like detection engineering or
threat hunting ultimately i really see
intelligence teams as being central to a
strong security program they really
serve as an important bridge in three
key ways
number one
intelligence teams bridge between the
external and internal
most intelligence teams maintain good
awareness of the external threat
landscape yes but also the internal
operating environment what technology
and processes are in place right now and
what transformations might be taking
place
number two intelligence teams bridge
understanding of both the strategic and
tactical levels of the threat space
what adversaries are most likely to
impact my specific organization and how
are they most likely to go about doing
that this area is really where minor
attack is most impactful
and then finally number three a little
bit of a combination of the other two
intelligence teams are perfectly
situated to bridge between the offensive
and defensive disciplines of security
by knowing what ttps are most likely to
impact the organization and what
technology is at risk but what controls
can mitigate those threats intelligence
teams have unique and valuable
perspective that can and should inform
control validation and strengthening
so before i hand it to lindsay i want to
cover key sources that i recommend for
surfacing intelligence around adversary
behaviors including in some cases
information that's already mapped to
moderate attack
these include three types of sources
that you might already be using open
closed and technical sources
closed sources will include your own
internal telemetry sure but this can
also include cases like when initial
access brokers have gained a foothold
into organizations and are reselling
that access on the dark web or cases
like lindsay will cover where actors are
sharing new tools and ttps on
underground forums
next most of you are probably familiar
with government agency and vendor
reporting which increasingly aligns with
mitre attack but one of the less
commonly used sources of open source ttp
intelligence is actually social media
there are many cases where security
researchers are publishing content that
either contain direct references to
techniques or even in some cases
explicit mentions of attack t code
identifiers themselves and you can
search these platforms for that type of
content
and finally some of you may be utilizing
technical sources that automatically map
to miter attack things like malware
sandboxes or network security controls
a really important note here is that
certain of these intelligence sources
will inherently be looking at threats
that have already been observed in the
wild whereas other ones really kind of
enable us to start strengthening
controls in a more proactive manner
so it's going to be a perfect segue into
lindsey's content where she's going to
cover her team's process for surfacing
and creating detections around these
truly emerging and novel threats
awesome thank you scott
so one of the things i hear a lot about
from clients is that they're really
concerned about ransomware but one of
the things i want to underscore is that
by the time the ransomware is dropped
detecting it is often a little bit too
late so let's go over what the anatomy
of a ransomware attack is and some of
those initial stages so first initial
access really just kind of how a threat
actor gains initial access to a target
organization
then after they gain access what they'll
want to do is find other systems to move
to potentially find other data of
interest
escalate their privileges or establish a
persistence mechanism in case they lose
access to that organization
then many ransomware threat actors
though not all of them will often
exfiltrate data so they can further
extort the victims into paying the
ransom and then only then is the
ransomware actually dropped
so you can see a bunch of different
tools that are used in this kind of the
stages right before the ransomware is
dropped to give you some idea so not
every one of these tools and ttps is
used in every ransomware attack but you
can see a bunch of different examples of
these types of tools
but what i really want to underscore is
that if we're trying to detect the
ransomware attack before the
ransomware's dropped there's a lot of
opportunity for detections especially at
this second stage
so insert group has a tools and ttps
team that looks for these emerging
threats and new tools that scott
mentioned that are released on open and
closed sources technical sources dark
web as well
but one of the things that we want to
ensure that we do as the technical team
is make sure that the intelligence that
we're putting out is something that our
clients can definitely understand so
maybe not everybody understands all the
specific nuances of you know different
types of malicious tools but being able
to use attack really provides that
lingua franca to allow the technical
team to convey what these tools do how
they work and then
allow our clients to make decisions on
whether or not they want to implement
these detections
so we'll produce two different types of
products
to convey this intelligence so first a
ttp note so this effectively functions
as a lead so here's the tool that we saw
it was published then by this threat
actor approximately this is what it does
providing a high level overview so be
aware of this not necessarily something
we've seen used in the wild just yet
we also have insect validated ttps so
these are often reserved for these very
high potential tools or things that we
started to see used in the wild so
different samples are released and what
we do is we provide
all that context but we also provide
actionable intelligence in the form of a
yara sigma or snort rule that clients
can take and then implement their own
environment if they choose to
importantly both of these things are
mapped to attack to really allow clients
to quickly understand what this does and
then is this something they're concerned
about so let's look at a specific
success story that the team had over the
last year
so in august 2021 we saw a threat actor
release a steeler called jester steeler
on the dark web and we put out a note
in case you're not super familiar with
steelers what these are are they
effectively take victim credentials and
they'll
exfiltrate them to the threat actor so
they can use these to continue to
escalate their attack or potentially
even sell some of these credentials on
the dark web to other fed actors
then in january 2022 we actually saw a
user on social media share a sample of
this steeler on malware bazaar so now
it's suggested to us that this was being
used in the wild and this is suddenly
kind of escalated in importance to our
clients so what we did
was we put together an insect validated
ttp and a signal so now our clients not
only have an understanding of what this
malware is but they also have a way to
detect it in their own environment if
they choose to
so you can see the
signal rule here and then you can see
some of the attack t codes that were
relevant to it so this allows customers
to quickly understand like what does
this rule look for is this something
that i'm interested in and should i
implement this as part of my defensive
strategy
so with that i'm going to hand it back
over to scott
oh sorry um
so it was actually really validating
then to see this about a month later so
another vendor actually identified
jester steeler as a priority threat so
this was awesome because it definitely
validated that our process is working
and also told us that we were able to
give our clients a way to detect the um
the malware about a month ahead so our
clients were able to have this rule and
then suddenly jester steeler was being
recognized externally as another type of
priority threat
now hand over scott
cool thank you
okay so
in the real world where i most often
started to see organizations utilizing
intelligence and miter attack
specifically to inform control
validation was as part of a threat or
risk profiling process
so i've gone ahead and highlighted just
a few of the key most common components
that ideally should inform a good threat
model or risk profile i'm not going to
talk through all these in detail
whatsoever but i'll just start to kind
of highlight a couple so
in working again mostly with
intelligence teams we're seeing more of
this awareness that intel should be
feeding actual control validation and
strengthening and we're seeing
organizations doing a pretty good job of
understanding again those external
threats and getting a better handle on
which ones maybe were prioritized which
ones are targeting their industry as a
whole or maybe even their most immediate
industry peers
in working with the intelligence team
specifically where we often start to see
organizations struggle is to actually
take that next step and start to
understand what is our own internal kind
of control environment look like and
there are certainly frameworks like the
detect framework that exists that allow
organizations to you know more uh
structurally map kind of those
detections what we started to do as
support for intelligence teams was we
wanted to kind of hand more of that
information directly to
our client organizations and this
ultimately kind of i won't talk through
the full process that led to this
massive spreadsheet lots of ones and
zeros in it just trying to kind of map
out the publicly available security
tools and how they map to the attack
framework what this all ultimately kind
of culminated in i was able to
kind of open source this this spring
this is a very much kind of a live and
active project you can go check it out
right now but i'm very actively working
on some kind of enhancements through the
rest of the year and i've added some new
things which i'll have a chance to cover
here today
basically a web app that allows you to
search based primarily on mitre attack t
codes what are the relevant control
mappings to those as well as which kind
of threat vectors might exist
so this is known as the control
validation compass i'm really excited
about this because this directly derived
from work that we're doing out there in
the field supporting our clients and
just able to share this back out with
the community
but what is it specifically it's open
source tool pointing cyber security
teams to over 9 000 publicly accessible
technical as well as policy controls and
those over two uh 2100 offensive
security test scripts all aligned with
the over 500 minor attack techniques and
sub techniques
uh so again this is live you can go
check it out right now i've just got
some screenshots to make it a little bit
bit easier i'm going to just walk
through some of the key features i hope
you'll go check it out
after our talk today so this is kind of
the landing page just to kind of get you
started there's some advanced features
that i'll highlight here as well but
what kind of just getting your feet wet
getting started with this what this
looks like is just go ahead and plug in
a search for a miter attack t code or
its plain text name and you will
immediately return
these mappings to all of these security
technologies again the ones that are
openly sharing you know what their kind
of mappings look like and so we've got a
lot of the proprietary security tools in
here as well as these kind of
third-party like libraries or
repositories so i think the one that
most folks might be familiar with is the
sm sigma rules repository um there's
things like miter attack produces the
cyber analytics repository as well a
little bit broader more generic kind of
signature format
and then the things that i get really
excited about which is the open sourcing
of kind of the the red teaming content
those scripts that allow you to go
simulate or in some cases kind of chain
together and actually emulate adversary
behavior as it's been observed out in
the wild a lot of this has actually
increasingly becoming openly available
as well and we've got these mappings
available in the tool right now so this
is what it looked like when i first
released this in march i've already
added some improvements based on
community feedback just again with the
idea being trying to make this much
easier for folks in the field to
actually operationalize what i've added
now is you can click into some of those
links and i know it's it's really small
on the the page here but
what this is pointing you back to are
links back to the actual repositories
themselves directly to for example the
detection rules so you can go
automatically search for a t code and
then find within the splunk security
content repository or the elastic search
repository which detection rules they
have available that map specifically to
miter attack techniques a really good
quick and easy way of kind of drilling
down into the specific content that you
might be able to utilize
one really exciting thing about this as
well is i know obviously lots of
organizations most likely aren't going
to be using you know multiple of those
tools at once both splunk and elastic uh
there's increasingly opportunities to
kind of convert rules into various
languages so you can that's the entire
purpose of the sigma repository it's
it's a kind of a genericized language
that would allow you to translate it
into uh uh
eql spl uh what have you so you can kind
of convert these do these conversions uh
back and forth amongst different
languages it just gives you more
potential content as you're going about
doing
research into detections
really what i see is the most exciting
kind of opportunity potential for this
tool is kind of this what i call the
threat alignment tab this allows you to
start plugging in some of those
components that would be specifically
relevant to your operating environment
so you have all sorts of toggle options
on the left under controls here where
you can specifically choose which of
those security tools exists within your
technology stack right now so you can
pinpoint exactly which tools you're
using if you're using any of those
third-party libraries as well you can go
ahead and toggle those on or off
if you're not doing any sort of kind of
iterative offensive security testing
right now you can just deselect all
those and just focus on the detection
side
for the moment but especially for those
most mature teams that are performing
you know pretty rapid control feedback
processes you can go in and say i'm
using the atomic red team framework or
i'm using prelude operator
as as kind of my c2 framework all of
this stuff being publicly available and
ideally you can come in here with this
being open source if you've got your own
internally developed content as well
it should be pretty easy to kind of line
everything up and you can start adding
in your own data as well the final piece
of this that i find most exciting is on
the right hand side the threat
intelligence window
this allows you to drop in
basically threat intelligence and start
to kind of line that directly up with
those controls that you might have in
place within your own environment what
that looks like in practice is it uses a
json you just simply copy and paste the
json into the tool itself
what this is kind of derived from is the
miter attack navigator this is a
visualization tool that they've released
and allows you to create these nice heat
maps and kind of visualize which
techniques
are being used by adversaries or
specific malware if you download the
json from a navigator that map that
you've created yourself you copy and
paste it in here you click that purple
button at the bottom and you immediately
get outputted with the entire list of
the detection rules and the offensive
security tests as they specifically line
up with kind of this profile that you've
built for your own organization
and just by the way no data is
transferred with this either it just
performs a quick lookup all within the
tool itself i know lots of organizations
are sensitive about you know they'll
create their own heat maps maybe based
on internal data so nothing is being
kind of transferred or stored anywhere
within this too which is kind of that
was very intentional building it that
way
so just talking through a very quick
kind of case study with applying
something like the control validation
compass to kind of uh these very real
active threats that we've been talking
about here today so what you're seeing
here is a screenshot of that malware
bazaar repository result that lindsey
had mentioned for jester steeler itself
this is just showing you a quick
screenshot you can go look up this hash
and malware bazaar and land on the exact
same page that i have what you can do
with that if you click into some of
these tabs is you can see the specific
miter attack techniques and sub
techniques observed and associated with
this specific sample of jester steeler
and i've got those highlighted this is
directly a screenshot from that miter
attack navigator visualization tool
what you can also do with this though uh
is keeping in mind you know again all
this open source information so this is
coming from one of those technical
sources when i talked through the the
various source buckets earlier we can
also pull in a lot of this information
from just purely openly available
sources as well so now what you're
seeing again i know it's pretty small
here but you're seeing kind of a
combined miter attack heat map for a
total of eight different steel or
malware the entire purpose of creating a
visual like this is to start to see
where there's clustering or
concentrations of certain miter attack
techniques and that's what you're seeing
visualize with like the brightest red
colors that's where we're seeing the
most overlap the way that i created this
i have these all saved on my own
personal github if you want to go grab
those yourself but i pulled this
directly from the miter attack database
itself you can directly within the
attack navigator tool or just from the
website itself you can kind of load up
all of the techniques in this heat map
view associate associated with certain
types of malware for example so i just
did a quick search for steeler there's
probably a lot more refinement that you
can do around this but i mean this took
a total of like five minutes to put
something like this together so compiled
all of those they had seven in mitre's
database overlaid the gesture steeler
example as well and that's what gave us
this kind of final heat map
just to highlight again kind of our
constant emphasis on you know
multivariate sourcing some of the types
of sources that were feeding into the
data that you're seeing on the screen
right now
were reports from the u.s csa
organization as well as security vendor
reporting
again just emphasizing that it's not
theory what i was talking through you
truly can pull in attack map data from a
wide disparity of sources
the final step with all this this is
what we used to kind of walk through a
lot of clients getting up to this point
and that is you know a great visual to
be able to show off leadership show
where there's concentrations and
techniques where you may want to focus
in a little bit further what do you
actually do with that data
what i did in this case is i just
downloaded the combined json for the
heat map and i threw it into that little
window on the control validation compass
this is now directly
populating
kind of concentrations and mappings of
the technical and policy controls as
well as offensive security tests that
you could run all directly in alignment
with these techniques and you actually
have a few different sorting options
with this as well the way that it
default outputs in this view is actually
from low to high
meaning it's going to highlight the
techniques that appeared in your threat
profile for which there are fewer kind
of out-of-the-box detections and tests
the takeaway what you can do with that
is ideally and i see this in practice
ideally teams will go and create their
own custom detections or tests to try to
emulate those and see what that looks
like in their own environment were they
able to detect it often cases you may
not be able to if there could be a good
reason why there's not an out of the box
detection for something like that it's
going to take a little bit more time and
effort to create something like that but
that's the entire reason you go through
this process because you're finding kind
of a higher priority technique based
upon your unique risk model
so i think that brings us to our end we
ended up wrapping quite fast so more
than enough time for lots of questions
here thank you so much for the time and
[Applause]
attention so thank you lindsay thank you
scott uh it's really interesting the
case study when intelligence drive
detection uh
detection rule that we were about i work
in intelligence as intelligence player
for us it's important to make reports
for treat hunting for a team and
at the end of this or their activity
it's important to
implement new detection rules cover the
uncovered part and so on
there is some question from the
sides
and the microphone is on the right side
so um really really interesting uh tool
thank you very much for releasing it and
and yeah
i'll look into that i have a question
about like detection so um one of the
things that we that we see is like with
a sock then afterwards working on the
detections
they sometimes get overloaded by the the
false positives right
so um
is there some way that you thought about
like also indicating which
detections you you highlight at the end
um
to give them sort of a precision value
sensitivity and precision basically yeah
so the statistical concepts that would
be really interesting yeah that's that's
a really great question and point and
thanks for the the feedback on the tool
too um so
man there's a lot to impact there uh i
would say like right now out of the box
i'm not familiar with anyone that is
really doing exactly that one thing just
for everyone's awareness the kind of
structure of a lot of these detections
are built with lots of opportunity and
like fields for metadata so if you
yourself were able to you know pinpoint
that based on if you run some tests in
your environment you can certainly plug
that in and the takeaway with that is
you know over time you build a larger
library and you can start to kind of
sort and filter based on your own
results i'm not aware actually i
i do think uh for a few of these
repositories they do highlight you know
potential for false positives but it's
definitely not super common and that's
why i didn't kind of include any like
fields like that in what i had because
this is probably just like one or two um
i'm also aware of like a few commercial
vendors that are their entire purpose is
to kind of uh create uh these very uh
high level simulations so they can start
to see like they're lining up the atomic
red team with the sigma rules and almost
like consistently running them against
each other to see what the output is
there as well so um
yeah it's a it's a tough one um not
seeing a ton like right now at this
moment but i know lots of organizations
are definitely like aware of that the
false positive challenge is very real um
i personally think that it is something
that organizations do kind of have to
deal with i don't personally like to see
people just excluding a rule if it's
generating a lot of false positives
because
there's probably a good reason for that
and you can hopefully do a little bit of
tuning to bring that down yeah so so
maybe like uh if it's possible to to
have like a feedback cycle from sock
saying yes uh that rule hit
it was you know sensitive enough to to
get the the the actual attack
but the precision was very low so
therefore it got too much other stuff
you know something like that it would be
really a recommendation for the further
100 that is the way to go ideally yes
and and in reality uh you know typically
it's kind of the more mature programs
that are doing this but i personally
believe and have seen once you start
getting into this it does become easier
over time in reality kind of the the
real scenario is you're going to be
performing potentially multiple retests
of those techniques that you had already
tested it's it's almost uncommon where
the first time you put in one of these
detections it's just works perfectly
from there that's the nature of how
challenging it is but oftentimes if you
do one two maybe three retests you can
bring that false positive rate down and
i do think like tracking all that is
absolutely the way to go yeah that's
great
finally comments too to just bring this
to a cycle to you know the the model
here is uh solving it basically together
right do you see it do you see like a
chance that this feedback cycle
uh for sensitivity and precision uh
could be shared amongst teams here is
that common enough or that in your
experience
the log detection is so different that
it's hard to compare
i wish it could get to be that point but
in the in the short term i don't i'd
love to hear your feedback i i don't
think in the short term it's going to be
possible i see too much variance in
organizations just internal telemetry
data sources all of that dude were you
agreeing with that or
yeah
you're going to tell us
sorry well it's it's kind of now my job
too
in in the new role but yeah
it's uh i would love to see that happen
i'm sure
folks will introduce frameworks for it
and that would be very welcome but it's
end of the day
gonna be almost organization specific
did you have any more equipment
okay question from my friend marco hi
thanks uh thanks for the talk um
definitely check the tool out uh just
simple question you wanted to ask if you
offer apis and you're gonna offer those
in the future so to allow basically good
integration with local tool chains and
so on
oh was that for the the tool that we
talked about at the end um so i would
say all of the information is available
in one format or another within like the
underlying the github repository for it
there's json data that has like just the
counts of the mappings
all of those when you get down to these
specific detection rules and the links
it's not in a very easily ingested
format right now there's very good
feedback that i'll take back this exists
in markdown right now so it's all there
and available and it is parsable because
that's how it's generated it's not in uh
json down to this level i've considered
maybe like sticks as well but
that would be appreciated yes because i
mean in the end we're gonna have
different environments so i i work for
siemens for examples of different
customers completely different
environments and then you have to check
this for all the environments and i
cannot go there like clicking totally i
want to to automate the whole thing so
that would be great thank
you
thank you marco there is no more
question
i think not so thank you to lindsay and
scott to be there big applause for them
please
there will be 5 15 minutes
break until the next session thank you