[Music]
okay
it's time and let us start the session
uh i'm yusuke masoka we
research a principle with fujitsu system
integration laboratories and i'm say i'm
going to share the session
first
some of the
housekeeping notes so the talk is tlp
white
and please mute your fonts
okay
it's time and let us start the session
uh
system integration laboratories and i'm
saying i'm i don't know why
don't do it
okay so uh and how far oh so qa session
uh after the uh talk
uh the microphone and there are
standing microphones
over there and over there
uh and uh
is
okay and uh talk
i lost
no worries
[Laughter]
[Music]
this
is should i take it from here
[Laughter]
i never walk alone inspirations from a
glowing wasp project and the speaker is
christian fellini thank you thank you
thank you for an intro rio
so my name is christian ferlini i'm a
swiss historian and security engineer
and we're going to talk about
my or our open source web application
firewall project
called os crs or the os
mod security
coral set we're a rules project about
regular expressions to detect malicious
hdb traffic if you came here for the
regular expressions then i have to
disappoint you a bit because this is a
bit different
this is a talk
about
this xkcd cartoon you've probably seen
it before it is about the infrastructure
on the internet that ultimately
rests
on a single person maintaining a crucial
library
somewhere maybe in nebraska and when i
joined this project
together with some friends we want to
make sure from day one we're not
the lone nut
in nebraska maintaining this for the
rest of the internet
and what i'm going to talk to you about
is the history of our projects and how
we came along and the decisions we've
made so if you're an open source
maintainer it can be an inspiration for
you
what you could do
to
have a similar nicely working project a
growing a flourishing project
meet people to join you and if your user
opens or soft and integrated perhaps it
can help you to share our perspective to
see the struggles we're having the pain
we're undergoing to maintain
upstream for you
good
so
what is this this as i said is a web
application security project it's 15
years old there was a israeli company
breach that acquired the engine mod
security and open source software and
they quickly realized they could not
expect their customers to write these
regular expressions themselves it was
much too complicated so there was a real
business need to develop a set of rules
core rules so to say they could ship
together with their open source engine
that was the birth of our project 15
years ago and it was made open source
from the beginning but it had a
corporate roof
over it two or three years afterwards
the israeli company was acquired by the
much larger american company and the guy
running the show back in the day ryan
burnett
decided this was the perfect moment to
take the open source rule set and move
it out from the corporate roof
under the roof of the ovus foundation
always like first is an american
foundation and always has over two or
three hundred chapters around the globe
and dozens of dozens of projects you
probably know always from the os top ten
there is over sap and os crs is another
flagship project so legally we became
independent however in reality it was
still mostly a one-man show driven by
that american company
maintaining it
so he was still working there
even though it was formally independent
the project died down in the following
years and 2015
ryan burnett quit and his successor
asked me
and a friend to revive the project
but before we get there
i need to be closer to the clicker yeah
so before we got there ryan burnett also
started an experiment he had an idea of
an experimental feature that is called
animally scoring that is not quite
obvious when a web application file
usually detects something you would
block immediately but what he would do
with separating the sensor from the
blocking decision this may a sound very
obvious and b
what does it really give you it gives
you a lot of flexibility namely doing
the integration
so without going too much into technic
technicalities
it is here to explain you he had this
idea and he was not
seen clearly but this was going it was
an experiment but it proved promising
and over the years we grew with
experience around this and when we took
over the project years later we made
this an essential features because we by
then we had understood how important
this was very often that is not clear
from beginning so this takes time to
develop
good so eventually he moved away the
project died down his successor asked me
and a friend from the netherlands back
into the project you guys want to revive
this and say yeah that that would be
interesting it's a promising project it
has a lot of potential unfortunately it
died down but let's give this a shot
and we immediately developed the vision
if we start over from scratch or revive
is bring this back to life we need to
have a common goal the three of us need
to have a goal but we want to go
and we defined usability documentation
and the power of the rule set as the
core essential we want to provide or
improve usability like every so much
software the use case is good but the
ride for the user is very rocky and you
back in the day you could
install mod security crs on top and your
web application would immediately stop
working everything was blocked
everything was on deny you would have to
work a lot until it was running again
and that ruined the whole customer
experience of course so we wanted to
improve that and we achieved this
relatively quickly with a much better
usability but it's still our
number one priority to tune away false
positive full false positive is that
what makes the experience of a web
application fall
web application fireball
very bad very often of course
documentation was lacking so we had to
improve that we're still improving
documentation as we move along and then
we wanted to make a powerful rule set of
course well everybody would expect a web
application fireball to be powerful and
detect all the malicious traffic out
there but actually that's not how the
incentives really work namely in the
commercial market
so we defined this as a core goal and
we're still hunting after this of course
it's always a rat race with the
attackers improving the rule set
improving as we move forward
good disentanglement uh
when we revived the project the guy came
sanders from the corp american company
he quit his job as well and instead of
handing over the os project to his
successor at his job he took it with him
so he moved away and he took the project
because legally it was an always
foundation project and of course the
american company they still treated this
as their own as if they owned it and
they had to be explained no no you're no
longer owning it actually it has been
given to over six eight years ago and
now we're running on our own website we
run our own project we welcome on our
own developers and you probably have to
live with that and they hated it of
course
that was not in the minds but we thought
it was time to walk in our own shoes to
do our own thing now and but that moment
that freedom really allowed us to bring
in new people into our project i'm not
saying that every open source project
has to be free of corporate interest not
at all but if you want to attract
third-party developers and that american
company definitely did not provide
enough developer power for us
you need to be at a certain distance
from commercial interest or people will
volunteer to work
for
a commercial company for free and that's
not cutting it nobody's interested to
really do this so we became an
alternative for people for security
engineers to their day job in their day
job they had business need there was
schedule there was road map and all
stuff and people talking to them and in
their spare time they could use their
own skills the same skill to work as a
volunteers on a very welcoming project
but they were allowed to experiment to
do the things they wanted to do at their
day job but couldn't so we became
attractive as an alternative for the
very same
people good
next one we made a first release we did
release notes we did a blog post we
explained everything on the mailing list
but then we also invested
quite a bit of time actually into this
release poster so we had a professional
graphical designer designed this as a
movie poster with the hope to make it
known a bit to go a bit viral to put it
up on slashdot back in the day slashdot
was a thing and we actually hit slashdot
with that and it was a lot of fun and a
lot of our user is still having this
poster in their office
so that's cool and from the beginning
this to say we try to make this fun add
a bit of twist make it attractive make a
stand out of it
from the competition
next one
this is a market scene from kiev in
ukraine i don't know if the market still
exists i certainly hope so
i have to photo here because of the
apple and oranges
there are a lot of very similar looking
apple and oranges here
in this market this could be github
this could be a market like github where
a lot a lot of projects very interesting
nice good-looking projects are
struggling for developers as you will
see there are relative few customers
here
it's a developer market there is a
scarcity of developers volunteering to
spend their time
developing regular expressions you find
a relatively few people willing to do
this in their spare time because it's
very boring so it is a struggle to get
these smart people to volunteer for your
project it's definitely a competition
and the developers have choice if they
have spare time to to volunteer to give
to a project there are many many
projects interested in them so it is a
real competition and the developers are
our most valuable assets that we have
diversity
from the beginning once we took over the
project we did the first release we did
the movie poster we attracted more
developers we've started to grow we're
up to 12 14 active developers now
comparison to a single man show on the
corporate roof
we have very diverse backgrounds we have
a female cso in our in our project we
have two guys running an isp
we have a cto from a larger isp we have
several security engineers we have
people working the public sector using
our stuff and i'm a consultant and
teacher on web application firewall and
whenever we have a new problem if a
bypass hits us a security researcher
shares information with us we have very
diverse approach to that different
perspectives and this adds to our
resilience because our team is so
diverse we come up with different
potential solutions very often
complementary solution so this is really
good
in contrast to the corporate setup where
people are recruited by hr and they're
much more alike
in a typical corporate team we're open
and it's possible for us to be much more
diverse admittedly we're too much
european too much western we have a
problem with unicode and utf-8
internationalization our engine is
limited in this regard and on top we are
limited in this regard and our knowledge
about this our experience with that is
limited in this regard meaning we're
letting
asian users down to quite a far extent
having
asian people join a project would be
beneficial so this is a weak spot for us
despite the diversity that we actually
have
knowledge we have an experience of over
a hundred years of operation with mod
security production very few
organizations in the world have over a
hundred years of experience running a
baffin production
so we bring together a unique experience
and unique backpack of pain running this
in production because mod security can
be extremely painful but it can also be
very satisfactory when you know you've
set this up in a clean way customers are
no longer affected by false positive and
you get a good night of sleep because
you know you have a decent first line of
defense
in place
by now
all the big cdns all the cloud providers
have a crs offering so they have all
integrated our stuff and we're kind of
the dominant player in the market we're
the only open source offering and the
commercial ones in user base are much
smaller than whatobut crs
is so we are kind of the go-to place for
the open source buff in the world
you have to formalize when you do a
security project any project perhaps
to a certain extent
you want to make sure you're not
forgetting something you need to have
certain procedures in case namely in
times of a release i mean a release
procedure you have to think about all
the steps that you need to do and sign
the release binary in the end but then
all this formalization these processes
is also killing innovation bureaucracy
is the enemy of innovation and
innovation is what developers attracts
to our project so the more we formalize
the more we take the breath away from
the developers so we have to strike a
balance in here we have to maintain
decent procedures without boring people
and this is relatively difficult to do
in a corporate setting you say look
you're paid to do this work and i'll do
this
we go
you volunteer to do this work here now
do it and then people won't rough
because that's not what they want to do
so we try to formalize but only just as
much as little as necessary to get the
stuff the job done we try to organize
this as a roundtable of people on eye
level talking about technical
discussions a lot of technical
discussions obviously and that allows
for innovation people bringing in your
ideas we handle a lot we are chat we
have an agenda when we meet in chat but
outside of that agenda is like dots that
we're covering it's completely free and
people bring in their ideas and by the
way i want to try this out be my guest
this is a green field develop anything
you want and show it to us and then we
discuss it but we make it into mainline
or not
we have a luxury of perfection
if you're in a corporate setting and you
tell your boss look we've developed this
twice already and then we refactor it
twice but i honestly think we need to
return to the same piece of code and we
need to write it from scratch again at a
given moment your boss will say hey hold
on
this is good enough this is at least a
minimal viable product let's ship it and
be done with it this is not how we can
operate we have the luxury of
polishing something as much as we want
if somebody from our develops
tells us and say hey look we need to
redo this because it's still not the way
it should be this is not beautiful
enough this is not really a static it's
still a bit of a hack i don't like they
have a bad feeling about this then yes
let's let's do this
we can allow our develops to do this
because we don't really have
business constraints we want to ship we
want to do releases we want to do
releases and times there are additional
incentives actually so too many releases
are not good for our customers
but we
compared to a commercial outfit we have
a lot of luxury that we can work on the
same code base again and again and it
comes down to a lot to aesthetics to
have a clean code base because a clean
and beautiful copays is inviting for
people to review it if people are able
to review it we get security researchers
to look at our rules if security
researchers are able to look at our
rules they will report their findings
and we can then improve so this is all a
very positive cycle the refactoring and
the polishing helps us to improve and of
course finding vulnerabilities as we
move along
clicker is a bit yeah we have leadership
so we are the three of us running this
project with 12 14 people
talking to
all the cloud providers by now i made to
contact the aws today so far and never
succeeded but here at the conference
this works so we're talking to azure aws
cloudflare akamai verizon media now
edgecast
and so on and we're trying to run this
project it's all a hobby project how can
we run this project one thing
that i had to realize
i wrote the mod security handbook i
thought i had a certain idea how this
works but the longer this goes the more
i feel i'm the newbie here in the house
because the new developers were
attracting they're so smart and
brilliant in their domain that i i move
back and go hey you guys are so good i'm
just a moderator here and i think it's a
natural role
in a
open source development because as the
leader you cannot be a perfectionist
the moment
you try to be a perfectionist in open
source project
and you drive your volunteers to
perfectionism
you drive them away
because if they are not interested in
the quality level you expect from them
you end up doing everything yourself you
you you try to drive them there and then
eventually they throw up and they walk
out the door and you have to do it
everything yourself and you end up in
nebraska we don't want to go there it
has to be the other way around
we need to be the liberal moderators
inviting the developers
to be perfectionists themselves they
tell us when a pull request is ready and
polished enough now to merge they
amongst themselves they review each
other and drive to perfection and we can
try kind of be a liberal if you guys
tell me this is good enough then we're
fine with it this is good this allows
for an atmosphere where a newbie comes
in and knows if i'm talking to to the
big
leader in this project these are nice
people they were liberal they were open
they tried to help me
they tried to somebody to coach me to
get my pull request to perfection
so this is working
if we are liberal leaders
swag many open source projects have
their web shop somewhere they try to
sell hoodies and t-shirts and stickers
that's not working
honestly it works for very few projects
swag is cheap it's distracting your
developers somebody has to do the web
shop somebody has to maintain it
somebody's come up with photos whatever
we gave up on that completely if
somebody wants to do logo uh t-shirts we
have all the logos on github print your
own t-shirts sell them if you want we
don't care it's distracting it's ireland
for the project what is much more
interesting is sponsorship sponsorship
is interesting because it's plannable
you can't have a good day and it's some
serious money namely if you're in
position to talk to big vendors the big
integrators they make money for stuff so
they kind of want to know to talk to us
you just need to find the right people
it's a sales process but once you have
found the right people they're
interested in the conversation because
very often the the big integrators
they're not running the stuff themselves
they're selling it they don't have a
hundred years of experience running our
stuff if they have serious questions
they want to talk to us so we're
entering in a very positive partnership
situation and we're interested in their
experience of course we're interested in
their feedback what we should do because
we again are not necessarily talking to
the end users so a sponsorship
relationship can be very beneficial
apparently need to have the parameters
right
but in our situation this works really
nicely we took this into our hand a year
or two ago and now we attracted a
hundred thousand dollars in sponsorship
money annually and you can get things
done with uh the amount of money giving
you one example we're running a
developer and duty program that means if
you hit our project on twitter stack
overflow slack mating list
or github with an issue with a question
an entry level question we have a
developer who's on duty to respond to
you and we kind of try to do this within
24 hours so we have first level support
in place for free sponsored by a sponsor
and that way we can pay our developers a
bit of money you get 200 for being the
developer duty per week and for some of
our developers that is substantial money
it's actually attractive and it's good
and it's nice for an open source project
to provide
guaranteed support only possible thanks
to sponsors
retention
developers
life continues
they get kids they change their job they
change their focus they wander off
it's the same problem in an enterprise
when you lose a developer an import a
key employee you lose so much knowledge
and experience it walks out the door and
it's very hard to keep them back and
it's even harder for us because
there is very little we can offer them
outside of pain sweat and probably blood
and a lot of time spent on boring and
regular expressions
so we need to make sure that we can
retain them and they feel at ease they
feel good volunteering the time they
feel good donating the time to our
project without getting too much back
one thing that helps us is setting up
personal ties physical meetings get to
know each other spending time outside
get up together to retain them in the
project because again developers are so
valuable
for our project
quality assurance i told you about the
aesthetics of code that we really have
in mind that we want to have
so we want to have reviews we want to be
auditable in a sense people should be
accessible the code base and then we
also remove a lot of stuff
we have a very good position that we our
copa is relatively small it's just a
couple of regular expressions a few
hundred of regular expressions and we
try to remove them make it even smaller
so it's easier to review of course but
it's also reducing the attack surface
overall
and this allows researchers again to
review our code so this
all comes together in helping us
maintain or raise the level of quality
of our software that we deliver i think
that's really important and it came out
in recent years that we need procedures
how to do this without making it feel
like a procedure of course
fun so
we tried to meet outside github we did a
one week developer retreat in the swiss
alps last year where we would meet with
11 people for a whole week developing
something together work on the project
together and have a few adventures go
hiking and stuff like that to build up
these personal thai friendships have
something doing together we run a signal
channel and the only thing we do on
signal is making jokes about pineapple
pizza i think
and this is extreme it's only for fun
purposes but it creates cohesion within
the project there's all these sorts of
insider jokes that makes sets up an
insider group and it's so much fun
people to be part of it so we're outside
the daily constraints in your commercial
company we're a safe space where you can
meet your friends without a boss looking
over your shoulders and you can do funny
or idiotic things as much as you want
and nobody cares as long as it's fun for
everybody
trans
transparency
we're an open source project
transparency in our dna and we want to
be as open as accessible as possible
i've come to see the last few years
uh
one or two years actually there is
always a drive to be no longer
transparent to take discussions behind
the curtain
and it's all it's important to always
know let's push this out this should be
in public just keep the really really
secret confidential things the dirty
laundry don't wash in public for example
keep that behind the curtain but the
rest our chat archives are published
everybody should be able to understand
why we're doing something at times it's
hard to understand but if you have the
archive how we discussed about it that's
actually useful so we want to be as open
and accessible
and inviting for newcomers as possible
because again we want to attract people
to donate their time
to our project
we try
to do a lot of our decisions all of our
decisions if possible we are consensus
we're not driving by hard time against
schedules
so we are all on equal level at least
the technical level we're all equals and
we've discussed things
and we've learned that very often
the timing isn't right for a decision
it's better to let it rest for a couple
of weeks until we take a decision and
then once it sets then people start to
realize understand each other's
arguments and then we're able to settle
a discourse in a very friendly way i
think we have never really forced a hard
decision that could rip the project
apart because if you end up with two
factions in your project
i mean the worst thing would be to have
somebody fork over a tiny technical
detail that would be idiotic it's better
to let it dress and revisit and as us
i've also learned personally the
solution that we finally agreed on was
much better than my initial idea just
because we let it rest for a couple of
weeks a month at times it takes half a
year until we have a solution to
something that we're not quite happy
with but we don't really know how to
improve it so we slowly approach it with
analysis and reports and then talk again
again again until we have a joint view
of this and all this together the course
of 15 years
is coming together in something which i
think is very beautiful it's a
flourishing project it's a blossoming
come on clicker it's a blossoming
project that is for me very beautiful to
work within and i think it looks very
beautiful from outside it's a group of
friends coming together as developers to
do what they really love to do with all
their passion writing very strong
security rules into a beautiful code
base
that they share for free on the internet
and naturally a community outside that
uses our stuff that loves our stuff on
their web applications to secure them
for the better and the better security
of the internet thank you very much
i think we have exactly five minutes for
question that was perfect timing wasn't
it
so questions
did i stun you
if there's uh
no questions i i have one yes please so
i had a difficulty of uh
and you mentioned that sponsorship is
important but uh kind of a pricing uh
their contribution
might be a little bit difficult uh
how
i mean how do you so they do they do it
on their own motivation usually but uh
you provide some uh kind of
uh money to them uh so uh how how do you
kind of balance them
with developers or with the sponsors
uh
with developers so
some get paid some no they're usually
not paid okay but that's a very good
question so we're a volunteer driven
project
and we want to be a volunteer driven
project and then suddenly money comes
into the game and once money is on the
table it gets really risky i think this
is really dangerous for the project to
accept money
and you want to share the money within
the project but you don't want to get
into a situation where people envy each
other over the money they're getting so
so far the policy has been we're
financing fringe activities around
support questions
on twitter in their spare time yeah we
finance that we do you coach a google
summer of code student
in your spare time next year project we
pay you for the coaching more than
google is paying you we do uh
we do an animal developer retreat in
switzerland we pay the trip we pay the
hotel we pay the food we pay all the
activities of course but you provide a
better regular expression in a rule set
you do this for free
and so far that has been the rule
however with the success of our
sponsorship project now
and the large amount of work that we
need to do we might have to revise this
one approach could be
and this is very new now is to think
about when we have security findings and
we run a bug bounty project this spring
a big integrator spent several hundred
thousand dollars
paying to security researchers to report
findings to us so the researchers got a
lot of money somebody paid that and we
get to have to work for free
and we're now in a situation that we're
overwhelmed with these bypasses these
are special patterns working around the
rule set
and
it's very unthankful to improve these
regular expressions but we could try to
divide this work a bit and do part of
this work
pay for somebody
that that could be an approach but it
would be
a revision of this rule where we say hey
the the core center of our work is is
still volunteer driven
but this might have to change i'm trying
to talk to all the developers how do you
feel about this look there is a security
researcher and looking at the numbers he
apparently bought a new car from what he
got from this buck bounty how do you
feel about this because for you it's a
spare time you could buy a new house
with that money
and most of our developers um
are easier about this than i am i think
hey money on the table makes everything
complicated and to say hey
it's beneficial for a project i still
enjoy the project anyway and it's not my
money so i don't care
so they feel quite at ease but i'm very
sensitive about money in the game it's
just something if we want to grow
and pursue the ideas we have with the
project then money is kind of
necessary we couldn't meet without
somebody paying the trip
yeah thank you very much very
interesting
uh
so uh no other question
then uh please join us join me uh
thanking a christian
thank you
thank you um
[Applause]
please uh remember to view the survey in
your mobile app and the next talk is in
10 minutes from
4 50. thank you
thank you