foreign
[Music]
I can hear me too so I guess welcome to
the session uh don't all cluster
together down front
um we've got some exciting uh what you
call content uh material uh Adventures
ahead of us this afternoon I'm not gonna
waste
this gentleman's time or all of yours
I'm trade early I'm your session chair
if there are any issues throw something
at my head or text me on slack or
something
um Joseph Carson you can read about him
in the program as I did but I asked him
what are some interesting things about
you that people maybe don't know and he
started talking about you know hobbies
and whatnot and then he happened to
mention that
as it says in the first sentence of your
bio 25 years over 25 years experience
but it was Brian honen
whose fault it was that God demented to
this back in 2001 the year of Our Lord
so
um you're going to take us on a bit of a
walk through of ransomware from uh the
other side of the Looking Glass
well let's have a warm Round of Applause
and one last thing sorry I'm it's been
years since I've done this before the
round of applause there's like a
kilogram of Belgian praline chocolates
down here I believe that good speakers
deserve good questions good questions
will be rewarded by me with Belgian
pralines just bear that in mind
throughout the rest of the day and with
that warm Round of Applause for Joseph
thank you
so
it's a pleasure to be here this is my
first time at first and my first time
speaking at first so I'm so excited to
be here sharing my experience and
knowledge with you and the majority of
this session I'm actually going to be
attempting to do a live demonstration
walkthrough I had two choices when I was
actually selected to speak here today I
could throw slides at you and walk you
through it that way but I think it's
always better seeing it in the actual
kind of the demonstration itself to give
you the real understanding about what
it's like from attackers perspective
when they're actually targeting an
organization and the steps and
techniques they do to go through I've
been privileged because not many
organizations I've been in the industry
quite a long time and not many
organizations give you the permission to
tell their story
to share their experience
to take you through the Journey to what
happened to their business
and I've been fortunate enough to be
allowed and permitted in order to share
that experience to give the knowledge to
you and hopefully that organizations
will learn from this and actually
prevent them from becoming a victim in
the future to provide the world a chance
we're all here superheroes fighting a a
major crime and I think it's important
that we actually have to share knowledge
together and work together and that's
what they permitted me to do so I'm
going to take you through a ransomware
insta response
and this particular incident is related
to the crylock version of ransomware so
some of you might be familiar with it
for me I like to take incidents that
I've experienced in the past that taught
me something new that I learned from
them that I think that others should
also learn from that as well now crylock
was a updated variant of ransomer which
the previous versions was known as cry
Echo and crackle went up to version 1.6
and it was around until about kind of
mid 2018 maybe early 2019 and then it
disappeared and was around the time that
they actually found weaknesses in the
encryption capability and ultimately a
key was disclosed to previous victims
then it disappeared for a while
then it resurfaced around mid-2020 and
in mid-2020 it was interesting because
it was one of the first it wasn't
necessarily ransomware as a service it
was actually ransomware with an
affiliate program so think about
ransomware creators that have a Channel
program that for those who want to do
cyber crime they can become you know
Partners or Affiliates of that uh
ransomware Creator and then basically go
and distribute it and get runs from our
rewards and they provide rewards back to
the creators of the ransomer so for me
it was an interesting time
um and that this was something that uh
was very catastrophic to the business so
the first thing is that this
organization promotes organizations you
tend to find out that you're a victim
from the outside before you even know
yourself and what I mean by that
sometimes you'll hear from law
enforcement sometimes you'll hear from
third parties customers Partners even
your employees sometimes you might hear
from security researchers and they'll
share a particular interesting story
about this incident as well from my
experience from being a security
researcher you sometimes might hear from
social media you might hear from Twitter
feeds the attackers might be shaming and
you know blaming you and notifying your
customers that you're a victim as well
this particular attacker they actually
notified the security team directly
early Sunday morning they decided to
send messages emails to the security
team notifying that or their
organization have become a victim of a
ransomware attack the attacker still had
persistent access they still were
actually at that time of notifying the
security team they were still actually
extracting large amounts and gigabytes
of data from the organization so they'll
actually still do basically escort
trading data from the organization now I
always like to share a bit of
interesting piece of this is that when I
was actually doing the instant response
in digital forensics of this particular
case that it's common that you sometimes
find other evidence of other victims the
attackers were not so sophisticated they
did a lot of copy paste and they
actually copy pasted some of the scripts
and some of the logs and evidence from
other crimes and actually reused it in
this particular incident so as I was
investigating the logs I did find
another victim of the ransomer and I
thought as a good security researcher
what should I do I should notify the
victim so I notified them fund the
contact details this is quite a large
organization
so I sent them information saying I'm
investigating another incident here and
I find evidence of your IP addresses
server names usernames passwords that
were actually discovered in this
particular case
and
that basically a few days later I get a
response back saying you're wrong
there's we don't have we have no
knowledge of urban summer instruments
and we're not a victim
I was curious I was going but I'm
looking at the data so I decided that
okay I sent back maybe this is a good
opportunity maybe they haven't actually
deployed the ransomware yet maybe it
gives you a chance to go and investigate
maybe they're preparing maybe this is a
good time actually you have a chance to
actually protect your organization
silence after that and about a couple of
months after closing up and doing the
investigation it came to time where I
actually had to take all of my archives
and all the logs and all of the evidence
passed it along to the organization who
was the victim and they were going to
pass it over to law enforcement uh for
evidence Gathering and so forth and I
thought other due diligence I should
notify this victim again that claimed
they weren't a victim to let them know
that I'm handing over evidence that has
actually traces of their data within it
immediately afterwards I Got a
notification saying yes we were a victim
we don't want anyone to know about it
they actually paid the ransom to recover
so it's always interesting when you're
doing digital forensics instant response
sometimes you do find evidence of other
types of victims and other crimes
another interesting thing was when I was
doing the evidence gathering this also
that I did find uh crypto mining
software that had been running in the
environment for two years
up until that point so crypto mining
which was installed well before the
attackers had access so it was likely
being installed by an employee who
decided to mine the organization's
systems for cryptocurrency so it's
always interesting what other things you
find now in this of course when the
organization was notified that they had
become a victim of ransomware it was on
a weekend
and fortunately enough all of their
employees majority of their employees
who had laptops had taken them home on
Friday so they were not directly
connected to the corporate Network at
the time but unfortunately the servers
which were all connected had all quickly
become victims of the ransomer itself so
the organization triggered a rinse
response and one of the lessons they
learned in this particular incident was
that having a plan is one thing
actually practicing it is another thing
and too many organizations they've spent
the last ever since not Petra and want
to cry they went through this
inter-response planning process and
they've got these plans in place and
then they've left them for about a year
on their SharePoint on their file
systems and then when it comes time to
trigger it what happens to it it's
encrypted they don't have access to it
they have an old copy that might be a
year old so a lot of cases organizations
they might have plans in place but I
think we need to get the point we need
to be practicing they need to simulate
they need to understand that instant
response is no longer just an I.T or a
security team's accountability
responsibility that actually is a
business impact we need to make sure
that when they're doing simulations they
actually work with the business they
work with other departments because in
this sense response it was the first
time they decided to talk with the
finance team it was the first time they
started talking with HR team the first
time they started talking with the seals
in other parts of the business to
understand what they need to be doing to
get the business back operating again
now unfortunately they came the decision
that within an hour or two of this
incident they had to decide because the
attackers still had persistent access
they still had access to the network
and the decision was made I can only
make recommendations I was sometimes I
would like to observe the attacker and
understand more about their techniques
unfortunately at the time when the
investigation started the attackers had
actually deleted lots of the log files
so the logs And archiving and events was
very very difficult there was much left
at that stage so I'd like to observe but
the attackers were still extracting
large portions of data so the decision
was made to basically shut down the
environment they decided to cut off the
systems shut them down cut the internet
off in order to make sure they were able
to control the incident and contain it
some things were able to go back to
operational Standalone that were
isolated and the important question was
you know how do we make sure the
attackers can't get back in where do we
find patient zero what systems were used
for the staging environment
in this less at this point in time there
was a big decision about how do you get
back to operation what's the path
now a lot of things happen in between
about understanding the skill
understanding about how many systems are
impacted and we got the point well let's
restore from a backup well unfortunately
like most organizations the backup was
on the same network with the same
credentials and what happens to that
backup it is also encrypted
so you're faced with a situation where
all your production systems all your
backup systems are not encrypted
and they face a hard choice at that
point in time it was the business had
gone the business had basically
evaporated within hours
and this is a large business Hunter's
employees multi-millions of years in
revenue and they're faced with the
choice of what how do we get this
business back so they actually started
looking into paying the ransom and we
always hear I mean I'm a security
researcher practitioner ethical hacker
and we always hear about well the
recommendation is not to pay the ransom
and I that's the recommendation we
shouldn't be forcing organizations at
that decision because ultimately I can
only provide my input ultimately it's a
business decision into whether they pay
the ransom it's a business decision what
choice they face sometimes organizations
pass that decision over to cyber
insurance companies now as part of the
policy so you have to make sure you
understand what's in the policy because
some cyber insurance company policies
say that decision to pay the ransom is
now part of insurance decision because
it comes into financial decision
fortunate enough this organization
we find a system that had been migrated
one year ago that was GDP decommissioned
that had not been completely erased and
decommissioned
that was a one-year-old server that was
migrated that actually was used as the
basis of rebuilding this environment
so what we were facing was was no longer
that the entire business has gone what
the business now faced was one year's
worth of their business data had gone
and it meant that we used that migrate
server as the basis we actually migrated
it and used that as Baseline we hired a
bunch of data analysts in order to go
through and sift through evidence to get
data look through receipts paper
inventory all the asset information and
start recreating that businesses one
year's worth of lost data it took almost
about two to two and a half months to do
that
but they actually avoided paying their
Ransom and actually this method was
actually much cheaper it still costs a
lot of money hundreds of thousands of
euros but it was actually much cheaper
than paying the multi-million of Euro
Ransom that was being demanded and of
course if you don't pay that rents
within two days
it increases 50 percent
so what I was tasked with in this
particular incident was not only helping
coordinate and deal with basically the
uh doing Dynamic and static analysis of
the actual Renaissance itself and also
helping to coordinate the team and
making sure they're able to get the
right images collected and so forth that
I was tasked with understanding the
techniques of the attacker my job was to
put the attacker's hat on and understand
how they got in what they did what steps
they took what scripts they run and as
an investigator we're dealing with a
ransomware case one thing they're great
at is destroying evidence
when you're looking at a ransomware that
but a lot of the times the logs are
emptied they're cleared the events are
deleted the actually uh systems logs are
also encrypted so you're dealing with
sometimes I call it like almost like
having been giving a 10 000 piece jigsaw
puzzle I'm looking at that puzzle and
I've only got 300 pieces remaining
and I know I need to put that jigsaw
puzzle together and tell the
organization what the big picture was
it's almost it's a difficult job to do
it's very challenging to be able to
actually get into understanding about
the entire attack path so I was given
understand what access do they have the
domain controllers
what systems that they have access to
what data how many applications was it
limited to on-premise and Cloud
what was the length of time of this
attack
what types of tools did they use did
they leave any hidden back doors that
allowed them to come back at a later
stage what data did they take and how
did they extract out of the organization
what was the timeline of events and what
evidence was remaining in order to
actually conclude a very consensus of uh
detailed investigation now what was
really difficult was for finding the
stage of machines at that point in time
so what I did was with having very
little evidence remaining I used things
like plaso and log to timeline I got a
lot of the event logs that was remaining
and what I did was at that point in
order to try and find the path to the
staging machines what I did was I
actually looked at the timestamp of the
cleared event logs and I was able to
actually create a pyramid into looking
at these with systems and timestamps to
finding the first machine that that
cleared event log had happened on and
that was able to then finding back to
actually ultimately patient zero now
when I got to Patient Zero was the next
stage where I was able to then start
building the footprints and
understanding the attacker's footprint
so who's ready for a demo I hope my
machine is so let's see if I can make
this work let's hope the demo gods are
with me today
yeah we'll see
um I like putting myself on these
challenging situations so I'm going to
cut it short because I don't have a lot
of time to go into as much detail as
possible there's a lot of different ways
that the attackers could have gained
access but we know that seven months
prior to the Hands-On keyboard so seven
months prior to the attack itself there
was a successful log on from a known uh
bad reputation IP address that was
coming from an exit tour node so we know
that seven months prior was a successful
logon how they got those credentials
could have been fight fishing could have
been via things like responder not bias
and Gathering hashes maybe a machine was
compromised at some point maybe somebody
entered the credentials into a phishing
website there's multiple ways of doing
it but the way that we think that was
the most likely was through RDP Brute
Force why do we believe that one is that
the the system that was patient zero was
an interesting system it was a database
Windows machine that was owned and
responsible by an accountant and that
accountant was in a different country
and during the start of the pandemic
that accountant needed to have access
they could no longer travel to the
location so what they did was Roland
calling it
they called the hosting provider
directly
and they demanded that RDP access to the
server was made in the available so it
they have Security in place they have
antivirus they've got vpns they've got
multi-factor authentication everything
but because the accountant has a bit of
power they decided to call the hosting
provider and hosting provider decided
well this is the person who pays the
bills
um we should do what they say so they
made RDP access publicly available on
this particular system this system was
also vulnerable to Eternal blue uh and
what happened was that we didn't find
any evidence that that vulnerability
been exploited because it usually is a
very unstable exploit and sometimes you
do see a lot of noise in the event logs
we didn't see evidence of it even though
it was vulnerable to it but the most
likely path was through RDP Brute Force
so we're simply using and the IP
addresses and everything the passwords
anything that was related to the victim
I have anonymized and simplified so what
you see in the demo is not the actual
passwords that was used in the victim
I've simplified them but they were
crackable because they were human
created passwords so simply using
something like crowbar what you see here
is krillbar basically targeting using
RDP it's targeting particular server
we've already enumerated and done
reconnaissance to get the username and
we've basically created a word list of
potential passwords that this person has
created we're only going to get previous
password disclosures we're looking at
basically their social media footprint
to create word lists and then create a
very intelligent very large password
word list and I'll be running this I've
selected one thread you can select
multiple threads but simply you can see
here after a period of time I've got a
successful login so that's what we
believe happened that seven months prior
and then nothing happened for three
months
three months later there was another
successful logon
two weeks prior to the Hands-On keyboard
another successful logon all of those
three successful logons come from three
separate different countries exit nodes
so basically very likely that the
initial access was obtained by an access
broker somebody who specialized in
gaining access to this infrastructure
it's very likely they then sold it in
the dark web to another actor who
basically had also became an affiliate
of crylock ransomware creators and also
purchased the credentials and were able
to then use that to gain access Next
Step the attacker did was basically do
an RDP to this target system so now with
those credentials that they've purchased
and knowing that this machine is
publicly available probably using things
like showdown in order to gain access
they log in now they've got a foothold
in the infrastructure so let me take you
through basically the steps that
actually attackers did now unfortunately
what employees do to make their life
easier I am not kidding you on the
desktop there was a file exactly like
this called important stuff exactly
named important stuff and when you open
that file they actually accountant had
actually put all the credentials off the
database and the financial systems in
the cloud
um on here making it easy for basically
them to see and start looking at
numerating further another thing that
was unfortunately on the system was what
do browsers love what is the browser's
love apart from cookies
they love passwords when you go to a
website the browser says hey you know so
you don't have to remember this in the
future we will save it for you isn't
that really cool but unfortunately what
the browsers not have by default
securely enabled so simply the attacker
can I go click on passwords and
ultimately for this victim they also use
this machine to browse other things that
they may have not been able to do from
their own machine because it was managed
or restricted browser and they would you
know some cases installed another
browser to bypass that but browsers love
passwords
and they want to store them and enforce
it by default
the attacker when they gain access to
the system now they can actually move to
that employee's cloud email to their
file system to other things that simply
is only protected with a password so
this is some of the things the attackers
did
the next stage the attacker did was then
starting to understand more about the
user that they're on the system
and the next step was just simply going
that user okay who else is on the
machine I can see different
administrators they can then do local
group and see what type of privileges I
have and unfortunately
this user was a local administrator
so now the attacker has the ability to
make configuration changes to this
machine they have the ability to change
the state
now most organizations Unfortunately
they think that it's a local Minister
yeah
it can only do damage to this machine it
can't harm our infrastructure it's just
local it's administrator they can
actually do bad means to this machine
but nowhere else that's a false sense of
security just because it's called local
doesn't mean that it can't actually
expand and be able to elevate and gain
other privileges
it's only two steps from having local
Minister rights to getting up to full
domain and this attacker knew those
steps very easily so what they'd end up
doing
okay now they know the local
administrator so on their attack machine
they set up a web server and the web
server had a series of different uh
downloads the and of course this was
available from the cloud
and what they'll simply then do is go to
this IP
and
we'll be mainly available is this
structure sorry for those in the back uh
let me see if I can zoom in here for you
or zoom out a little bit too much okay
so what they've done was a b c d e f and
so forth and then they have the scan and
then hit zap
now a was the first file LED download
it's the first thing that they'll
download and what a was basically some
enumeration scanning on the system the
places that they actually placed these
downloads was in a couple of locations
one was on the C drive and it was
actually in a folder called Intel and in
here there was enumeration scripts all
the locations were in user profiles
things like videos pictures and so forth
now in the enumeration here you'll see
that the first thing that a was simply
automation
a was simply just the automation of this
system and in the automation they had
things like disable security so knowing
that I'm now a local minister in the
system one of the things they can now do
is basically just to show you the script
itself
this would actually go and disable any
of the security that was on the system
itself
and the sessions lasted somewhere
between four minutes most sessions were
four minutes long others were eight
minutes no longer and the purpose of
them being this long was that in Windows
Defender has a auto healing as a protect
the service so when it's off for a
certain amount of time it will actually
restart but those sessions were shorter
than that window so they could actually
stay hidden they could actually do the
malicious activity within that state
so this would be the ability to disable
the security the next thing they would
end up doing is then running the
downloader and the downloader then would
actually go off to that site again and
then download B C D and from that within
c b c and d was the malicious scripts
and malicious Tools in order for the
further numeration because knowledge
security is disabled in the system it's
not going to detect anything that they
download and execute from that point
um the first couple of sessions they
didn't do any back doors but later they
decided to add some users so about a
week into the attack they went and added
the user and added that user to the
actually administrator and remote
desktop users we believe the purpose was
that they were afraid of losing access
and were afraid of the user may be
changing their password and therefore
limiting that access so they created a
back door another backdoor that they
also used which is still ironic today
that has still been used is sticky keys
so sticky keys is the ability to
actually go and change in the utility
Helper and molgun screen that when you
click in it it will actually open up a
full command prompt and have full NTS
system Authority access so you can go if
you ever lose access this is your quick
access to go and create another user and
regain access to the machine so another
interesting technique that was used in
order to create great persistence so
once they had went through and did all
of these basically it also run fine
passwords to see if there's passwords
kept in the registry in the file system
and at that point in time they would end
up going and downloading the B file
which contained memicats so mimikats now
they have the ability to go and check
and see is there any passwords and clear
texts so remember four minutes
disabling security
downloading the Malaysia's files and now
basically making configuration changes
the system the first thing and these
this is the exact same scripts that was
used in the attack so first thing is of
course the windows 12 sp1 there was a
change made that
passwords are not stored in clear text
but with a simple registry change as a
local administrator user you can reverse
that change and unfortunately this
change will be persistent
um that now with this change anyone who
logs in after adding this to the
registry they will actually be able to
then detect the passwords and clear text
post this point in time
so
once they've done that they will also
then maybe run a thumbscred and this
basically you'll see here this is the
exact script this dumps guys and also
the reason why they've got some of those
color coordination in the top there is
that they can also pass parameters from
another tool as well but you can see
here simply the protect the processor I
also they wanted to make it look pretty
by changing the color to something that
was something that they you know and
they also changed the title as well but
they will actually run the right version
of mimikats for this particular system
now once they had basically get the dump
and they realized that of course at that
first time they do this there's no real
passwords other than the credential I'm
logged in as so they will come back to
the numeration once they've made that
change they go back from the Automation
and they run a clean script the clean
script will remove all of those files
memicats all of the changes and also
delete the last couple of minutes in the
log files so from a end user or system
administrator perspective when you look
at this it just looks at this machine
rebooted or was offline for four minutes
and if you look at your AV dashboards
you'll see that there's a communication
missed for maybe a few minutes and most
people will just ignore that most assist
administrators will just decide that it
was a blip maybe a network failure maybe
something happened
every four minutes it looks like
everything's back online now it looks
okay but the attackers made some little
modifications so now what they've been
able to do is they've done further
enumeration and unfortunately for this
organization this was an accountant's
machine that was running Financial
database that actually for that
accountant to make financial statements
for the organization now within that the
IT team we're actually taking a backup
of that database
and they had a script running they had
PS exact running in the background open
up a connection copy the database down
to a local system to back that database
up and fortunately the credentials of
that PS exec script were a domain
administrator
now the series was the attacker only
needed to wait a period of time now
what's also interesting in this
particular case as well the attackers
also had downloaded gmr and I was
confused I was going why are they using
gmr because we use it as Defenders we
use it in order to detect root kits in
order to detect things like filter
drivers and mini-filter drivers that's
communicating with the kernel to
understand about you know what maybe
there's back doors in place the
attackers are using it for to find out
what AV and anti-malware software is
running in the background that they may
not see in the system trade they might
not see on the interface they're running
it to see what tools we're using in
order to evade detection after doing a
numeration in the system the attackers
had enough knowledge crylock was not the
only variant that ransomware they had to
disposed basically to use they had five
other versions of ransomware that they
could have chosen from they chose
crylock because of the security controls
and everything that was in place in
these systems they knew would not be
detected they needed to execute
successfully whether the defense has
been able to stop it
when I actually ran the first time when
I got a hold of this particular version
I ran in virus total I ran it in Joe's
sandbox I actually did Dynamic analysis
and virus total only three antivirus
vendors detected it three
at that time of running it
so this organization did have defense in
place and just unfortunately the
attackers are looking at ways in order
to get and move around it so a few days
later backup script runs attackers come
back in
they go in again they run the disabled
security they check their back doors
they come back in they run memicats
they dump the credentials opening up and
after running this quite a few times
it's only a matter of time before that
backup script that runs
you can see eventually at some point
you'll see here
even though I've basically been able to
get that's not the right one
here
domain administrator account coming from
PS exact that their team is using
themselves
in order to do systems management for
this environment to take backups so now
the attacker has knowledge of the
credentials for domain controller they
move to the next stage and fortunately
at that point in time
you're talking about hours before you
become a ransomware victim it's hours at
that stage once they have the access
so the next thing they'll do is they'll
go when they run a scanner now the
scanner was used in this particular case
was net scanner from self-perfect it's
great for using it for system
administrators for small business in
order to manage the environment
and ultimately here they were able to
scan the environment and unfortunately
for most organizations what do they do
what what do they name their servers the
backup server Erp system SQL we name it
so that we can easily understand what
it's doing in the business and
unfortunately for the attackers it's
almost like giving them it basically if
you know a complete footprint of the
environment itself
okay scanning's not working but I'll
find a reason uh to figure out but one
of the things was interesting and this
was here is where they set up the
automation this is the program so it's
integration in the scanner so when it
picks up the servers in the environment
they can simply right click and run
these this was the first evidence that
the actually attackers for Russian
speaking
from Russian origin and now it's not to
say there were Russian citizens or
Russian Nationals it just means that
here it was actually an acrylic language
which meant that basically they were
Russian speaking there's some
indications of attribution which I can't
disclose but were that potentially came
from but this was the first indication
that we find evidence of attribution in
this location from the acrylic language
been used in this particular tool the
next stage of course was to run some of
those scripts to create basically
download staging machines and staging
files onto other machines ultimately
then do an RDP
and it was moments after
logging into the main controller a few
about two hours after doing this point
was when the ransomware was deployed and
took out the entire business
so these are the steps and techniques
that attackers have used and that's what
we're here sometimes to kind of reverse
that and look at the evidence look at
the how they get it got in what evidence
was remaining so some of the areas once
they have the access and they go through
they can simply now go back and do
things like PS exec from Impact it you
can go and basically know you've got
credentials I can simply use a command
line just like the backup script does
and now I've got access to the victim
staging machines
I can also use evil win or M with the
past the heist method and go and simply
Target the domain controller now if even
um the you know I don't have the
password itself I just have the hash I
can simply log in and now I've got full
access to the main controller
as that user
all the techniques the attackers are
using
so going through this what things can we
do to reduce the risks how can we start
reducing these types of attacks from
happening and it's about it's all
working together it's all of us using
our knowledge and finding ways in order
to make my job is always to make the
attacker's job more difficult to force
them to create more noise to force them
to take more risks in the business and
giving the Defenders a chance at seeing
those ripples in the water seeing those
techniques being used in order to
prevent the attack from happening or to
stop it in mid attack but we what things
we can do from these lessons good cyber
education and knowledge and awareness
for the team not just for the I.T team
and security team but also across the
business
make security usable
make it so people want to use it
and also the backup itself the
organization learned a very important
lesson that the backup itself was a
protection against data corruption or
Hardware failure but not tailored to
ransomware
and organizations need to revise review
their backups and make sure that they
actually have a backup and plan in place
that actually considers ransomware types
of attacks
practice the prince of least privilege
make sure that basically the credentials
of user they're not being local
administrator user they're not over
privileged users you're not using domain
accounts domain administer accounts and
backup scripts that you've got scripts
to prevent lateral moves that after that
you rotate the credentials so even I was
able to obtain the hash I can't reuse
that hash to move around the network
using privilege access management Tools
in order to rotate credentials make sure
they're not human created credentials
controlling applications
a lot of the applications used here were
used for basically you know attackers
were pretty much living off the land
living off what they were able to find
but making sure when things are running
for example on a Sunday morning or
Saturday night being able to detect the
difference between that being run by a
malicious attacker and something that's
run on a Tuesday afternoon by an
authorized employee being able to
determine the difference control
applications make sure you actually have
a behavior and understanding about when
they run and maybe out of hours you have
additional security controls in place
and just make sure that do the basics of
patch management and updating security
ultimately
my last statement is understanding
hacker techniques
is the best way to defend if you know
the techniques they use we can put the
right controls in place to make it more
difficult for them
but we need to translate that into the
business
we can't go to the business and say we
need to put these in place to stop
attackers
we need to translate into business
basically return on investment in order
to get the budget in order for us to do
the things that make attack ourselves
more difficult at that point of time I
think my time's up and I would like to
thank you for being an awesome audience
and taking time and listening to me
today if I have some time for one or two
questions I'll be happy to answer
[Applause]
questions
yes don't forget there's some chocolates
here I think that uh you will you're
willing to uh
so while we have managed to
oh I can see you now we have managed to
stay away from ransomware attacks
virtually 100 of our supplier incidents
we deal with involve ransomware
and we ran into a unique situation
recently I was just going to run a
passage and see if you've heard of it
where
um the supplier was refusing to pay the
ransom
so the ransomware attacker fired off
random emails to some of our employees
saying we have your data on this
companies systems they're refusing to
pay the ransom if you don't twist their
arm and force them to pay that Ransom
were going to leak your data have you
run into those situations absolutely
I've seen lots of cases similar to that
in various different ways sometimes it's
their customers not so much their
employees sometimes they'll do uh
threaten to leak the data on the public
internet that much you might you know
cause the organization some harm with
regulatory needs and so forth like gdpr
um and privacy act so so yes I have seen
we're seeing ransomer you know even if
you look at the lapsis group their
technique was not so much sexually
locking the systems but it was more
about stealing data and threatening to
disclose that data so yes attackers have
different ways of gaining financial gain
and some of them might take multiple
steps whether being threatening and you
know employees to disclose the data so
yes that's there's multiple extortion
techniques that's been used it's not
just destruction of data and systems
it's also threatening disclosure and
other brand damage and financial damage
that they can do absolutely
all right uh we have time for one more
question
hello yeah hi George kutepas from
certain U thank you for the brilliant
talk
um we we seem to associate ransomware
attackers with a higher degree of
automation usually a fishing email the
victim just clicks on some links or runs
something that is attached to that email
and we go from that in your case we see
the attackers doing some serious let's
say Hands-On effort and some very deep
research of the victim was this a
special case of a threat actor or was it
a special case of a victim which would
uh satisfy the need for a higher degree
of effort due to the expected profit
what's your take on that so thank you so
excellent question thank you for for
asking the question uh from this
particular you know these attackers made
lots of mistakes the when you in
retrospect when you look at the evidence
remaining that I went through they were
not quiet most attackers that are more
sophisticated prefer to stay stealthy
they made lots of mistakes they made
lots of uh areas so from my view these
were script kitties borderline you know
kind of with a bit more skills so they
were not very events and going into the
path where what rather than actually
doing phishing emails themselves most
criminal gangs are now starting to just
go and buy the access directly so they
don't have to do that stem their special
access Brokers out there were rather
than me having to do multiple types of
Specialties and you know fishing and
then creating ransomware and then doing
Hands-On keyboard and gaining uh and
then also even doing the communication
in this particular case it was actually
another group that was actually dealing
with the communication because the
attacker native language was not English
so you're dealing with a series of
almost like a supply chain of criminal
activity
um so yes more attackers are starting to
rather than try to be specialist in
everything they would specialize in one
thing and do that really well and rather
than doing fishing they'll just buy the
credentials of an access broker this
particular organization actually had
done all the right things they had all
the right things in place unfortunately
it was that one employee had a bit of
power and was able to do Shadow I.T like
most organizations Shadow I.T is a is a
very dangerous thing and can
circumstance security quite extensively
and that's unfortunately was the case
here it was Shadow I.T that ultimately
created a backdoor into the organization
which the attackers are you know very
skilled they're looking for so this was
not this is not sophisticated this is a
common thing that I've seen about 80
percent of it I see in most cases I
worked on it's just the entry point and
the ransomware variant tends to be the
the slight differences
so thank you so much for the great
question uh thanks for Joseph Carson our
speaker thank you very much it's been a
pleasure
and I'm here for the rest of the today
and tomorrow so if you have questions uh
feel free to come up in directly and
always you know make sure you provide
feedback to the organizers uh because
I'd love to this not be my first and
only conference I'd like it to be my the
first of many uh could I ask our next
speaker to come up here uh uh
and uh
we've got a great lineup ahead but we'll
get started here in about oh let's say
six or seven minutes
and if you asked a question please come
forward if you want to grab some
pralines
so is there