[Music]
okay let's get started
uh i just want to double check this is a
place for the first session of the
auditorium
first session on friday morning and the
last session track of the
conference before the ending keynote
and there is no ttp
by
dr
martin iron
if you are expecting that this is the
right place if not look for your right
place to go
i am seeing adachi anti dessert and i'm
going to be a session chair
the uh this morning at this auditorium
and composed of two
presentations
and let me give you a quick reminder the
first
the this
presentation
will be tlp white
and the q and a question the answers
will be the end of
the session
and there are
two three four i don't know
there are microphones there so if you
have any questions
just move into the right front of the
microphone and wait for the instruction
second
the please please please fill out the
session survey the after
session serving the mobile app
the after this presentation
your input is variable
third
turn off
or silence your devices
to respect
presenter and of course the rest of the
audience
now
this is my great pleasure to introduce
the uh
dr martin iron today's presenter
who is a research researcher at the
pneumonic
he has he has more than 20 years of work
experiencing id security
i.t operations
and information security research roles
in addition to his positions
at mnemonic
he is a member of the europol ec3
advisory group on internet security
please help me welcome dr martin sage is
yours thank you
[Applause]
do not try
and detect the ttp
that's impossible
instead only try to realize the truth
there is no ttp
ttps
don't
exist
they are abstractions
constructs
that help us
understand
you cannot detect a ttp
you can only detect things that exist
furthermore
there is no such thing as a ttp
it's either a tactic
a technique
or a procedure
to make this useful we need to be able
to tell the difference
we need to understand
what they are
and my opinion is that we
currently don't
know thyself
originally from the oracle of delphi
popularized
by the oracle in the matrix
to know yourself
also means to know your limitations
to know what you don't know
if we think that we know
then we stop searching
we stop asking questions
we do not progress
the only true wisdom
is in knowing you know nothing
this quote is attributed to socrates the
ancient greek philosopher
socrates was a master of annoying people
he would start talking to an expert
he would ask the expert for definitions
of key terms
and then he would keep asking questions
until the expert contradicted himself
thus being annoyed
but socrates goal
was to highlight
what we don't know
and that is my goal today to highlight
what we don't know and i'll start with a
story about myself
i started as a junior threat analyst
back in 2014
one of the first things that i noticed
was people using the term ttps
it seemed important so i tried to
understand what it
was i quickly figured out that
it's an abbreviation for tactics
techniques and procedures
but i didn't understand what each of
those meant
so i started to annoy people
whenever i heard someone say ttp
i would ask them could you give me an
example of a tactic
an example of a technique
and an example of a procedure
i never got any examples
until
a fellow threat analyst
pointed me in the direction of ryan
stillians ryan stillians published two
blog posts in 2014
one
on the detection maturity level model
and one on ttps
what he did was basically to take david
bianco's pyramid of pain
and then expand the ttp at the top
into tactics techniques and procedures
and he argued
that it's useful to view them separately
but in my opinion
the way ryan stillians defined tactics
techniques
and procedures
didn't make any sense
so i kept searching
then
in 2018
the big breakthrough happened
i don't have any fancy sound or lighting
effect so i'm going to need your help
try to imagine a choir of angels singing
a pillar of light descending from the
heavens and in the middle of that pillar
mitre attack
adversarial tactics techniques
and common knowledge
this was exactly what i had been looking
for
the knowledge base of my dreams the
framework that i would want to spend the
rest of my life with
so i immediately started using it
but over time
i had this nagging feeling of
missing pieces
of things not being quite right
and i saw
attack being used in ways that didn't
make any sense to me
and now i'm finally able to articulate
why
but before i tell you why
i would last i'd like to ask you a
couple of questions with raise of hands
how many of you have used mitre attack
in any way
that's most of you
thank you
how many of you have read the attack
design and philosophy paper
one
okay
good but still
fewer than those who use the fact if you
use attack in any way i strongly
recommend that you read it
it's really good and it clears up a lot
of the misconceptions and
misunderstandings about attack
now i went with the matrix as a theme
so we need a red pill and a blue pill
the blue pill
represents my impression of what people
in the security community think about
attack how they understand attack
this is based on discuss discussions
with customers vendors and peers on a
lot of reading
the red pill
represents
my understanding of what
how things really are
and this is based on my own experiences
with attack
the attack design and philosophy paper
discussions with peers
and also
a lot of reading so in short
the red pill is me and my understanding
and the blue pill
is my understanding of others
so which one do we pick
well why not do both
the structure of this talk is as follows
for each of tactics techniques and
procedures
i will first present the blue pill
then i will present the red pill
and finally
i will tell a short story with some
examples to illustrate
and now i'm going to test if the clicker
works from over here but let's start
with
tactics
mitre attack enumerates tactics
resource development initial access
execution persistence privilege
escalation defense evasion credential
access i couldn't put the rest of them
in there because the font would be too
small
but
yeah
it's all there
this is a solved problem
those are not tactics
they're tactical objectives
and or kill chain faces
do we even know what a tactic is in the
cybersecurity domain
we might never know because we think we
know
but where did ttps come from
originally
the military
what are military tactics
well some examples of military offensive
tactics include ambush
charge
skirmish siege
encirclement
they describe something that you do
not the objective
but more importantly
they describe how you deploy your forces
let's look at an example
ambush
is a military tactic
it describes reconnaissance to find
suitable terrain
it describes preparation of the
battlefield
traps and obstructions
it describes compositions of teams and
roles
like rifle squads machine gunners
anti-tank teams security teams assault
elements
it describes deployment and positioning
of those teams
it describes actions on objective once
the enemy convoy enters the kill zone
you block off the front you block off
the back you fire until you achieve the
intended effect
and then you fall back
to the rally point
now how does this translate to the cyber
security domain
i don't know
but i see some parallels
terrain and battlefield
correspond to
the attacker infrastructure and the
infrastructure under attack
in our world
the teams and roles have equivalents as
well
one example
the team tasked with achieving initial
access
if it's in-house with a threat actor we
call that the breach team
if it's outsourced we call it an initial
access broker
there are other roles as well
malware developers
infrastructure maintainers
social engineers money mules and so
forth and so on
a tactic is not a point event
a chain of events
or a playbook
this playbook is related to the tactical
objectives in mitre attack so we
shouldn't throw those away
we should just stop calling them tactics
maybe we can call them objectives
we do research on
adversary roles and teams
adversary playbooks but we lack a
standard structured way to record and
share this knowledge
which brings me to my first story for
today
with this nice little storytelling
picture
i remember reading an incident report
many years ago but i can't for the life
of me find that report again which
annoys me but that's life
but i think it was about the 2013
lockheed martin bridge
one thing really stood out to me in that
report
the attackers
were described as stealthy
they took great care
to avoid detection and to cover their
tracks
but once they realized
that they had been detected
they switched to a smash and grab tactic
they try to collect and exfiltrate
as much information as they could as
quickly as possible stealth be down
other examples include attackers that
switch to destructive tactics or
scorched earth
if they realize that they have been
detected
or attackers that suddenly drop
ransomware
when they understand that they have been
detected
so first off
to me
these sound a lot like tactics smash and
grab scorched earth
and second
wouldn't this information be useful to
an incident responder
if you know
that the attacker will cause destruction
when they realize that they have been
detected
would that affect your decision making
as an incident responder
because it sure would affect mine
so wouldn't it be useful
to collect and enumerate tactics like
this in some kind of
knowledge base
like in mitre attack
i think so
and i think we should do that
moving on to
[Music]
techniques
attack techniques describe
how
an adversary achieves something how it's
done
their behavior
techniques are useful for attribution
we can detect techniques
techniques can be used to make these
nice heat maps of detection coverage
actually some of the techniques in
attack describe what an adversary gets
not their behavior
but what they get
like valid accounts
my experience is that techniques are way
too general to have any usefulness
whatsoever in attribution there's too
much overlap
it doesn't work
and you don't detect the technique
you detect an implementation or a
procedure
in fact you don't even detect the
procedure you detect the traces
that it leaves behind
i mentioned the design and philosophy
paper and about heat maps
this is a quote the techniques within
attack may have many procedures for how
an adversary could implement them and
because
adversaries are always changing it's
difficult to know what all these
procedures are in advance
that makes discussing coverage of a
technique tough
especially when some ways of detecting
behavior rely on individual procedures
and some may span multiple procedures or
even an entire technique
and furthermore
anyone mapping to attack
should be able to explain the procedures
i cover
which brings me to my second show of
hands how many of you have seen
technologies or products that
map to mitra attack
comma
all of you have right
and then the follow-up
how many of you have seen
technologies or products mapping to
attack that explain the procedures they
cover
a couple of you
why is that so
well if you tell someone to do something
but you don't give them the means to do
so
what's going to happen
they're not going to do it
we're probably not going to do it
and i think that's the problem attack
doesn't really provide the means
to map the procedures
so a short story about our use of attack
we made the mistake of trying to use
attack for automation
an automation requires machine readable
information
a description field with human readable
text is the bane of automation not just
because it's difficult for a computer to
interpret
but also because people will stuff all
the important information into that
human
readable description field
because it's easy
instead of figuring out where in this
big complex structure you should put
your information you have this nice
description field you can put everything
in there so but we did automation anyway
so we developed an open source tool
called adversary emulation planner
this tool takes a set of techniques
and gives you a set of ordered attack
stages with all the techniques that are
possible to use at each stage
and to achieve this we
semantically model technique
dependencies
every technique requires something
and it provides something
this is the reason why you're using the
technique
because of what it provides
and what it provides can be required by
another technique and so on
so for every technique and sub technique
in attack
we describe what it requires
and what it provides
and that made it easy to build a tool
that generates the attack stages
this works when
techniques describe how an adversary
achieves something their behavior
but it breaks down when techniques
describe what an adversary achieves or
what the technique provides
it doesn't fit so we basically had to
ignore those techniques
so if you come to attack with an
automation first
mindset
chances are that you will be
disappointed
design decisions that work for manual
processes
do not work well for automation
then over to the final part on my
completely illegible slide
sorry about that
procedures
attack describes the procedures used by
adversaries
so the thing on the right that you
probably can't read
that's from one of the techniques in
attack and it's a long list of procedure
examples
connected to threat actors or
software
have a look at the right hand side here
this is the attack object model
do you see procedures there
no
what you saw in the previous slide
was
procedure examples
human readable description fields
and most of them are of the form
adversary x uses software y
to achieve this
procedures are useful for attribution
in my experience you can observe two
different adversaries
using the same technique but their
procedures are different
by looking at the details
like command line parameters you're able
to distinguish them
you can't detect procedures either but
they contain a lot more detail than
techniques and those details are helpful
when you develop detection analytics
so why are we not enumerating procedures
why do techniques have ids
but procedures don't
and this time the story is about you
you handle an incident
during this incident you observe a third
actor using mimikats for os credential
dumping
you see that this information is
actually not in microattack
and since you are an upstanding citizen
you want to report istimiter for
inclusion in attack to help others
you now have two choices you can either
report that the adversary group uses os
credential dumping
or
you can report that the adversary group
uses mimikats
but not both
the problem with the second approach
is that this links the adversary group
to mimikatz but not to always credential
dumping
mimikats implements nine different
techniques
in mitre attack
so your observation was the use
of a single technique but someone else
looking this up in attack have no way of
telling
whether the adversary used mimikatz for
one technique
or for nine techniques
this is information loss and information
loss is
bad why are there two different ways to
report techniques or technique usage
in attack
well i can give my opinion because
procedures are not part of the object
model
this has been a huge headache for us
working on threat intelligence
automation
in my opinion the correct way to record
this information is as follows
the adversary group used mimikats
to execute a procedure
this procedure implements os credential
dumping the technique
the adversary group and the software are
linked to the procedure and not to the
technique
here's a picture of the road ahead
it's long
we can't see the end of it but it seems
to have a pretty clear direction
now
the road ahead also known as my personal
wishlist
i think that's maybe a more accurate
description this is what i would do
first off
i would remove all of these what you get
techniques from attack
they actually hurt automation
if you cannot describe
the behavior
what the how an adversary does something
then it shouldn't be called a technique
it's something else
and the second thing is
we should enumerate procedures and we
should try to figure out how
to represent them in a machine-readable
way
and the same goes for tactics we should
start enumerating them
and we should stop calling the tactical
objectives tactics
because
that makes us think that we understand
what tactics are
and even further ahead
if we are able to describe procedures in
a machine-readable way we should start
looking at ways to transform
this into detection analytics
and the closest i've seen there for a
domain specific language is stick's
patterning
which could be a target for such a
transformation
now in the introduction
i showed a quote from socrates the greek
philosopher
the master of annoying people
if you add a c to that you get socrates
the innovation project
a lot of the ideas presented here
originated from or
matured in the socrates project
socrates develops a
security automation and decision support
platform for security operation centers
and incident response team so if you're
interested
in research on automation
have a look at the webpage there's a lot
of information there
but to wrap up
if you remember only one thing from this
presentation
then you need to step up and do better
because i needed to remember three
things
we don't know what tactics are
we don't know what procedures are
and we need to do something about that
thank you
[Applause]
thank you very thank you very much dr
martin
now it's time for question
so again there are two microphones i can
see up front so if you have any
questions
just show up in front of microphone yeah
my question is what
maitre thinks about your personal wish
list
they mostly ignored me so far
i think three or four years ago i tried
pushing uh pushing them to get
procedures included in attack but the
answer was people are already
complaining about how the complexity and
all of too much information so they
didn't want to go there but then two
years later they implemented some
techniques
so i don't know
i'll keep complaining
and if someone feels personally offended
then
good i think
i mean
someone has to ask questions
and i might be wrong these are my
personal opinions i'm happy to be proven
wrong
thank you for the good talks thank you
i'm in the cyber threat intelligence
i would like to know how can we
enable tactics and procedures
where we don't know about them
yeah we first need to agree on what they
are and as i said the closest i've come
is to me like things like smash and grab
sounds a lot like a tactic to me
it sounds similar to what tactics are in
the military domain
how to enable them
well you start identifying them you read
reports you see descriptions of
adversary tactics there
so i don't know if low and slow is a
tactic i don't know if yeah
does it mean that we can reflect it into
some numbering or some skills oh yeah to
what enumerate means it means assigning
an identifier like in my tree for every
technique you have a t and a number an
id
that's what i mean by enumeration okay
and ideally this would be part of attack
itself
thank you very much yeah
any more questions
or are you still
it's too early in the
morning every is there everybody working
waking up
i woke up at least i know you're working
and you woke up you woke up very many
people inspired please inspired me thank
you very much
so
if you have
again any questions
oh one more oh yeah yes please
i'm gonna just run off to the airport
after the presentation so you need to be
good at rugby tackles if you want to
stop there
but you have my uh not anymore
the pdf will be published my contact
information is in there feel free to
contact me
thank you
all right so he's in rush so
[Applause]
thank you
and have a safe trip
all right we are now in the break 10
minutes break and the
we will start at 10 15 on time
you