so
i'd like to welcome you all i see you
are there there are still people
entering the room but let's get started
we have an hour and 20 minutes that's
not too long time for this interesting
topic
my name is henrik larsen i'm the head of
dk cert from denmark and i'm the chair
of this session and i'm very happy to
welcome uh on the scene
chad normington from canada
john miller us
caesar and
don stickford from
holland from elsinore that should be a
town in my country but
it's his company name
and
they are
giving you an update on the improved
[Music]
tlp protocol the traffic light protocol
and so that's why we're all dressed in
colors up here
they are the
the tlp sick the special interest group
or members of that at least or
and they have
prepared this new
protocol for first which has just been
approved the tlp version 2.0 i have just
learned it's called
so uh take the scene done and oh is it
tom
will stop we'll start
all right good afternoon everyone
um
so
if you uh hope you all enjoyed your
lunch you can now start to take a nap
um now so i was just going to start with
a little bit of a how we got here story
about the traffic light protocol how
it's invented um where it sort of comes
from what the impetus was behind its
creation
and uh and the
road that led us to where we are today
um
so all the way back in 1999
uh in the united kingdom they
established the national infrastructure
security coordination center or nicey as
it's pronounced
and this was to part of this was to
establish ways for infrastructure
sectors to uh to share in sensitive
information amongst themselves about
risks that they face
about um you know about mitigation
safeguards countermeasures and that sort
of thing
um not just for cyber security but for a
number of different types of risks uh if
you remember like in 1999 cyber security
was barely even a word
um so the world has of course changed a
lot since then but
um
during the very early 2000s obviously as
you can see they started to establish
what uh in the uk are called information
exchanges in the united states we call
them ice acts or information sharing and
analysis centers um we also there's also
a number of things called information
sharing analysis organizations all of
these exist to sort of do similar things
which is to share information generally
between different private sector
institutions that otherwise would uh
would probably not share sensitive
information with one another especially
about uh
anything that could be used for
competitive purposes but
the point being that this sort of like
risk stuff that affects an entire sector
or affects an entire um sort of sub
sector or even a group like we have one
in the u.s for faith-based organizations
for example or one for real estate
um so all of these different types of
things needed a better way to
mark information that was not classified
in any sense because that's not what
these people were dealing with but there
was sensitive enough to merit sort of
you know like some kind of control
scheme
and
they uh and they created they came up
with traffic light what you know the
very very original version of traffic
light protocol
which is sort of very informal
was not a classification scheme which
tlp is still not a classification scheme
just to be clear right up front
and the original one had five colors i
just wanted to include that for trivia
and
this was inspired it was inspired by
caveat markings for sharing classified
material as anybody in the room ever
heard of or con for example
okay a couple of people know what an
oricon is that stands for originator
controlled and is sort of like the
original inspiration for example tlp red
which means you have to ask me
permission before you can share this any
further with anybody
um
so during the 2000s uh tlp sort of
spread
throughout especially uh like uh i think
to
ian bryant told me all this history he
basically said you know he started
spreading throughout you know
at first northern europe
um
and uh
and made its way into other things and
made its way into like recommendations
from the task force for sea certs in in
europe and started to slowly but
gradually or slowly and gradually why
did i that's redundant anyway sorry
apologies um slowly make its way through
the world
and then um
and then this is how i get involved
specifically
i think it was
here's the scenario as i recall it
we were sharing all of our stuff from us
cert
as unclassified for official use only
which is a government marking which we
use for things that should stay within
the government and we would do this by
default and really without thinking very
hard about it at all
and so we would share things
unclassified for official use only and
then we'd send them off to places like
the treasury department
with the expectation
unspoken in some cases that the treasury
department would then share it with the
financial sector in the u.s that was the
desired end state
it turns out all of these things got to
the treasury department because of
internal policies there they said oh it
says for official use only that means it
stays within the government we can't
share it outside of the government and
then the financial sector would get wind
of this and be like we never got any of
your indicators of compromise that you
just shared
and we're like why do you mean we gave
them the treasury department we told
them to send them to you and they were
like yeah we can't see any because you
put fou on there you put for official
use only
um so we got yelled at a little bit
and the suggestion was why can't you
just use top like all of our partners
from you know other parts of the world
um especially again in europe
and uh and we're like oh yeah tlp we see
that sometimes from our international
partners they send stuff to us with tlp
markings on it and we kind of know what
it means we kind of know what it means
and we try to adhere to it um but yeah
we don't really use it on a day-to-day
basis and then
because i'm the guy at sizza that i was
the guy at us certain now i'm the guy
that says it who deals with random stuff
that nobody else you know really wants
to touch they were just sort of like hey
this tlp thing figure out how to
implement it you know you're the guy now
and i became the action officer for
implementing traffic light protocol uh
at us cert and what's the first thing i
did
i wrote a new version of tlp just for
myself
um so i tried to adhere to everything it
said but of course i wanted to like oh i
think i can phrase this better in you
know like special cool american english
so boom boom boom boom boom knocked out
a new version of tlp
with some slight tweaks to things threw
it up on the uscert.gov website and it
stayed there and then all the private
sector partners that we were sharing
with throughout all of the ice acts in
america started to uh to use that
and then we got immediately got into
some disagreements with other partners
you know like hey your tlp is not 100
compatible with mine
and then i also started to notice i was
like hey wait a minute
now new zealand has their own version of
tlp now these partners have their own
version of tlp this is proliferating and
this is going to be a real problem if we
don't try to do something um soon
and
uh so in 2015
we established the tlp sig
and
which everybody in this room should join
obviously if you're not already a member
first tlp was established and uh
basically because i thought first was
the obvious home
for a standard version of this and i
thought it was the best way to ensure
broadest adoption of a standard version
uh throughout all of the member teams
and their partner organizations that we
work with in infrastructure throughout
the world
so
you now you know me
you probably know don
we uh
we pushed out tlp 1.0
in 2016
um
after the uh shortly after the
conference in
yeah 2015 yes seoul 2016 was seoul and
um yeah and then we were off to the
races and everything was great
for almost 15 minutes
all right and i'm going to hand that off
to you sir
and they lived happily ever after
well let's see
so um
well i think we were kind of quiet for a
few years
so the group was still there but there
wasn't much activity every now and then
somebody had some
ideas but we really started working on a
new round of consultation in
in 2019
and yesterday
i had a look at the current membership
of the sick it's over 50 people
and
very well very good is that they really
come from from all over the world which
also illustrates the fact that tlp has
this has had this major take-up in so
many places
i could even mention a few countries you
have coded top in part of their national
law
so
even that exists
and in our group is also non-first
members so what did we what did we do in
this consultation well first of all the
starting point was this is now a
standard basically and the standard
needs stability so could we have come up
with something entirely new well of
course but
we wouldn't have become very popular i
think
so we were talking about content
improvements we're talking about uh some
changes in regards changing times we
will come to that
language
and certainly also
because that was a critique in 2016 and
that was justified in 16 basically we
came up with a new version and that was
mostly that and now we want to come up
with more supporting materials
we worked for
some
almost two years and came up with a new
draft that we sent out to the world
quite widely
many fora were included in a very wide
distribution and we got
a big number of responses back
a lot of them were focusing on the same
kind of issues
but that was a great help and we
actually changed our
draft in a few key places due to all the
comments that came in so this last
consultation round was absolutely very
very useful
and after that we discussed it again in
the
in the special interest group of course
the zig
and went for approval by the first board
which
we received
and um well here are the the main
changes
so we clarified the standard text on
in a lot of places it's very funny
because i actually contributed to the
to the dutch my own language to the
dutch translation of the tlp v1 and only
when i started translating it into my
own language i sort of started noting
that there were obscurities unclarities
in the text which i never noticed before
because i was always reading the english
text again and again
so with that in mind and people other
people had similar experiences of course
we really tried
to get more unified languages so we
removed all the literature in there we
removed all the synonyms and other nice
things we even removed things where we
could have probably a three hour debate
on that with with some of you but for
instance um
my english is mostly british english and
i would say to whom
but most of the people on the planet say
to who so it's this kind of
simplifications that we
for some people improvement that we
inserted into the uh text because the
target audience is really people
worldwide and not people who are very
very proficient at uh at english so we
wanted to keep it as straight and simple
as possible language wise
we added definitions for community
organization and clients and we used
those definitions in the
top
texts so for instance if you may wonder
why does have this awful kind of
great green t-shirt well i would
normally never wear this but thanks to a
good idea of tom we were you know we
were wearing top colors
and i i got stuck with green
anyway green
is the color that in the description uh
corresponds with the idea of a community
and and so we we did our best to map the
the terms used in those definitions onto
the various
definitions we added the colors table
which now also has rgb cmyk and hex
colors and some improvements to
accessibility which was i think mostly
the top red was improved color-wise if i
yes because it was a little hard to read
under certain circumstances
and then we come to the more
major changes this is absolutely a major
change
we changed uh top y to tlp clear
now we're really sorry but
uh the text you'll be clear should still
be on there but that's obviously not the
case
yeah this of course is um in line with
all the discussions that we've had in
regard also blacklisting whitelisting
and i do not need to
reiterate that and we decided as a group
that we want to move away from the top
white and move away from all the
discussions associated with that at
first we went for in the consultation
that went out last november for top
public
but lots of people said that's not a
caller
which is correct and then our good
friend scott mcintyre who i think these
days is in australia came up with the
good idea to
label it top clear and everybody who was
involved in that discussion at that
stage
uh who was not against this change
agreed with that so to be clear
it is
and then finally another important
change we had one of the ongoing
discussions we had
since 2015 actually
was on tlp amber
there were people who said we need to
reintroduce top yellow or something like
that we need to make things more
complicated
we actually sticked with the tlpmer and
we also stick with dlpm topmer in the
meaning it got in version 1
for obvious reasons to avoid confusion
and well i'll read that one out you can
read it here yourself
limited disclosure recipients can only
spread this on a need to know
basis within their organization and its
clients so that was the meaning already
in quite a few of the original versions
of top and it was also the meaning that
we coded in tlp version 1 in 2016 but we
added
to and hopefully a lot of those
discussions that we've had the past few
years top amber plus strict without
spaces
which restricts the sharing to the
organization only because this was the
one
that was apparent in some older glp
versions in some parts of the world i
think mostly north america
and by adding that one i think
we made it easier or at least
standardized the possibility to restrict
it to the organization
only
and that's basically the changes that we
did by the way we'll come to discussion
later of course but first i would like
to give the floor to
to ted
to talk a little about about use cases
that we're working on
thanks don
um i got involved i think it was career
um
probably when tom got the wrong day for
the tlp sig meeting and i'm like where
are you and and he's like it's tomorrow
and like we're all waiting for you
um
and then tom proceeded to say well at
least everyone's good on tlp green and
i said i'm not and that got into all
sorts of arguments but
one of my favorite things over the last
few years is coming with use cases and
and saying well under these
circumstances
what would you do under these
circumstances what would you do we have
not perfected this by any stretch of the
imagination i've been working on
different versions and trying to make it
more readable more usable etc but we're
still trying to work on these to to make
it
clear and to illustrate to people
what's a good practice
one of the
one of the things we got a lot of
feedback on was about sharing with
service providers
i've got this report i just got
i've outsourced
this activity it's affecting this
particular technical thing that we use
but we've outsourced that
or i've brought in cyber defense
services because i've got an incident um
can i share with these people
now tlp clear is obvious yeah yeah you
can share with everybody you can post it
on the internet i i really don't care
tlp green
in general it's yes
and one of the things we can get into
and i've gotten into with tom is the
whole definition within t.o.p green is
it says with a defined community and if
you define a specific community
and this is this is an argument for
later on but it's an argument that that
probably will come up for version 2.1
is what are these whole notions of
community definitions and community
interactions if i go and say
i want to share this with
a broad audience but not too broad an
audience can i go and say i want this
just with the automotive sector
in north america
um
is that different than tlp amber where i
send it to people in the automotive
sector but they don't know who they can
share with
so in general if there's no restrictions
on it on the tlb green
yeah you can go ahead and share with
your service providers not a problem
tlp amber and tlpm restrict no
it says within your organization and
your clients and as tom said there are
definitions as to what our clients what
is an organization
so
an organization is not necessarily
somebody you've outsourced and brought
people into
if you need that
always talk
have a chat to the people who are
providing you the information and say
can i get either instructions in line so
in the document in whatever you're
receiving that gives me instructions it
says
yeah it's tlp amber
but you can
share this with outsized organizations
or maybe outsized organizations within
this
country or whatever definition you think
is you're comfortable with
um
maybe you can get ad hoc you can go back
to them and say hey can i share this
they'll respond and say yes go ahead or
get a standing agreement if you've got a
relationship with the organization
that's providing you with this
information you can get something that
says yeah anything we send to you that's
tlp amber
you can share with your you know
outsourced this
and
uh we'll tell you otherwise
that's
regardless if you do not have clarity
talk between the the creator and the
recipient
have that conversation
um
tlp amber
to tlpm restrict that's one of the
things we haven't
put in the um in the definition but it's
something to keep in mind is that if
you're giving someone permission to
share a tlp amber document
with
a service provider have them change it
to tlpm restrict when they do it
i'd like to see it by default in the
definition but we haven't got that far
yet
the reason is
that it could easily become tlp amber
green and we had a couple of people
raise that issue
i've outsourced i've brought in
a particular commercial incident
response company to help me out and then
said okay i'll give them my tlp amber
document
well
now tlb amber for them says i can give
this all my clients
they give it to all their clients
one of their clients has says oh well
this applies some other some other stuff
that i've outsourced this activity to
say it has to do with your your um
cash points i've outsourced my cash
points i'll give it to the company that
provides the cash points well now they
out you know can provide that document
to all the the clients that they have
and
some of those have instant response
teams and it can just go around the
world like that so we highly recommend
that if you're sharing it with a service
provider or if you're allowing someone
to share with a service provider change
tlpm or tlb restrict
but it's not it's not in the definition
you have to do that so again the onus is
on the people providing the information
to make sure the recipients understand
your intentions
so anyways that avoids the yoyoing back
and forth
so that's service providers another
use case and i've got a bunch of use
cases that we're working on but just
bring
another one that
is
particular interest to me because i work
in a national c-cert
and we deal a lot with incident
notifications
and one of the things that i've i've
recognized is that we go and always say
well tlp amber on all notifications when
they go out because this should only go
to the end recipient
the problem is the information that's in
there
you may be less restrictive about how it
gets shared out
and
you may go and say well the identity of
the organization is in there so we need
to make sure it's tlp amber but once
that goes to the organization at the end
um
it's their right to go and talk about
things that happen to them so
what we're suggesting is notices go out
at tlp again this is not in the code
this is just a suggestion
notices go out at tpm restrict
but you add
the following information can only be
provided to the end recipient or
necessary intermediaries that allows you
to go to send other national c-certs to
send to telcos isps anybody who's in the
way in order to get to the end recipient
so you give that special instruction
that says it's tlpm restrict
with that caveat until it gets the end
recipient then the information inside
has its own tlp
now it may still be tlp strict if you
don't put anything else it's till tlp
strict the recipient gets it
if it's
amber strict they can't share it with
anyone else
it's only in their organization
but quite often the only reason that
we're putting restrictions on that is
because of the identity or details that
are specific to the end recipient
so what i propose is that you if if you
don't really care as a producer of the
information about what tlp it is you put
that information at tlp white
the end recipient can then go and say
well
there's no way we're going to share this
with anyone so we're just going to keep
it in-house they don't have to share
that information
it's the end recipient's choice of what
to do with it
if they want to share the tlp green with
people great amber with people or just
keep it in-house that's fine
or tlp white they can publish the stuff
on the internet if they want to go
public with it
but if you have sensitive information
that you have shared
with an end recipient with a victim of
of of an incident
you need to go and express that to the
end recipient you say
this information is tlp green or tlp
amber because we don't want you to share
this information any further
you may want to go public with it but
there's information sensitive to us the
producers the creators of this
information that can't be shared
elsewhere and so you need to make sure
that information is is defined
in the core of the message that's
received and so separating those two
elements
so i said those are those are a couple
of examples of use cases that that we
use
and one other thing we're working on is
a cheat sheet because quite often people
like well can i share with this can i
share with these people
we've put together this this little
cheat sheet that goes and says what can
i do with the information
and
there's some key questions of the ones
that people are always asking
and it says given the tlp
if it's got an x no you can't do it
it's got a check mark yes you can do it
if it's got a question mark
it really means no you can't do it but
this is something that people want
a lot so you should probably have a
discussion between the the creator the
originator and the recipient
to say are we going to have an agreement
back and forth about how we do this
especially we do this regularly
and then there's the little arrow there
and this is something that we may debate
afterwards
um
depends on the definition well we've got
a definition of an organization but if
an organization is a huge conglomerate
you may want to think about saying if
you give it to a parent company that you
don't want to go down to some of the
recipients i'm thinking you know you go
to uh was it um
hitachi i think or whatever is a huge
huge presence with all sorts of you know
minerals and transport and things like
that if you give it to it transport
element you really want it transport
focused
well do you want it to go to the parent
or the conglomerate and then now down to
all the other sub companies
um
it's not enforced in the standard
something i'd highly recommend depending
on the the shape of the organization
and
i think that's
the next steps
see if this works it does thank you
so next steps
by the way you see the callers right
well tom would you like to explain your
callers
right so this is obviously uh
uh this is obviously tlp amber the way
we all know it today
um and uh the pants are tlp and restrict
sorry trousers the trousers are tlp am
restricted is there a difference between
pants and trousers yes uh yeah okay
and language discussions again let's not
go in there no not yeah it's yeah
so we would like to publish the this has
been agreed with the first word
v2 standard after the conference and
they will become valid at the time of
publication but obviously people will
need time to
to adapt their
their their
protocols their own texts
and sometimes and we have had extensive
discussions about that
it
means that software needs to be changed
firmware needs to be changed because in
some cases
the tlp is coded quite deeply
and
the board we've agreed on the transition
period until the 1st of january of
we will also ask the translators because
there's a few language other language
sources in english on the website to
update their language version because
this translating effort is a voluntary
effort
by by first members and we will ask them
if they want to provide uh updates and
of course we will do communication not
just inside first but in the widest
possible way ap cert uh tc cert
oh yes
et cetera yeah you name it all the four
hours we can find them many more
we will communicate this
no
and then hope that there will be a big
pickup just like was the case in 2016.
now the new version i think is pretty
backwards compatible
the exception obviously of top clear
and that will take time to adapt to
obviously
and the addition of the opm was strict
but still vmware was already there and
does not change and as people were
already doing dlpm strict but then using
their own words like keep it in your own
organization only
this is now basically codified so i
think that changes
should be quite an easy one
we will also make some training
materials available
and some training material inserts it's
not highly complicated of course what
we're talking about but it's important
that that word gets out there and
continue to work on what dad has been
talking about the use cases
and the cheat sheet and to have as much
as possible available in a very short
time
what did i forget
okay no i don't
um yeah and the six months is hopefully
going to give people enough time to
change some of the bad practices that
are going on i'm not going to name names
um
but some people that go around using tlp
red as tlp amber because they didn't
trust tlp amber um
we found a few cases that it's like okay
well we're just going to send out
copyright and we're like can i talk
about this to people in my organization
yeah yeah sure go ahead it's like
why aren't you selling it to amber it's
like well because we don't want you to
send it to anyone else it's like we'll
just go and put a label on it saying
don't send it to anyone else but so
hopefully
in the six months people can change some
of the habits as well
and that's the key is to make sure
you're actually following
following the standard
my organization has definitely never
sent anything out that said tlp amber on
it and then immediately followed by a
caveat that basically rendered it tlp
red
that never happened
oh i have a goal that's not on here
i'm going to double the size of the sig
and get more people helping with the
work
so come to our meeting on friday
and uh and join in the fun
i promise we're funnier in real life
and that will of course then be mostly
focusing on the
on the use cases and
the communication the the training
materials etc
and i'm interested in knowing is there a
current iso that
outlines
tlp and do they match up
that's a great question
so iso
apparently has tlp in it
um i have not used my library card at my
agency to go download a copy and like
see exactly where it is
but um but apparently it's in there
and it matches like a 2012 or a 2015
rendition of traffic light protocol and
it will be and uh we're going to have a
friend of ours make sure there's an
update applied
he's a member of he's actually i think
it's it's going to be probably be in
brian who's a member of the sig okay um
which do you see
changing
are
are agreed upon
first agreed upon tlp or the iso or
there's got to be a marriage there
somewhere otherwise
people are going to be doing different
things anyway
i think we uh
the i think
ours stays the way we've written it with
the sig and the iso will be updated to
reflect the changes we've made that
would be great that would be great and
let me know if you need some help with
that i'd be happy to sit on that group
working group
thank you
thank you very much
thank you laurie and
by that we've opened the floor for
alexander
is
approaching the mic
thanks a lot for the work and
i will go first for the positive points
i mean you need a lot of challenges that
are quite positive i'm really glad of
the tlp restrict it's a lot of
clarifications for for many of us and so
on
i'm glad to with various changes that
you do and so
on the negative aspect on the tlp clear
i still don't get why you change it but
okay
would you keep tlp white mentioned in
the final document to mention as being
compatible with clp clear or would you
completely remove tlp white from the
official document
and my second question is what is the
relationship with the tlp sig and the
information exchange policy seek which
was defining
sharing policies tools for
materials and so on so i'm just
wondering about those two
and if you are still willing to change
any document or changes into the
official document you plan to publish
or would you keep it like this and
people have to deal with the
mess with tlp-wide changes can i take
the first part of the question you the
second part tom i think he has three
questions oh okay then the second i'll
take i'll take as many as you want me to
okay
so the first part was
[Music]
we will have only to be clear in the new
version but we will keep the top v1 of
course on the first website for for for
reference purposes
second part and it's the second part was
um
uh let's see and you said you didn't
understand why we changed it and the
answer is racism and then the um
the uh the second part yeah go ahead and
remind me
uh
think the information exchange oh the
relationship with iep
um
well just like we've done today i think
we're just going to make sure that the
iep sig meetings are always in you know
like at the same time as tlp sig
meetings so you can't no i'm kidding um
so
uh iep references tlp and it references
the first.org tlp so i suspect the way i
would like to see it go is that iep
which they're hashing out right now what
they're going to do next for iep in
another room um and i hope to hear about
that and hear positive things i would
expect iep to reference tlp 2.0
going forward then there's a collateral
question to it how do you represent in
tlp the versions
should we prefix versions too for
example in tlp if some people want still
to use the older versions i mean
backward compatibility and stuff like
that
right now we don't
if we say tlp double points
amber it's still the old one
um which version is it is it version
1.1.2
should we prefix clp2 double point for
the specifications i'm just wondering
about machine readable things
or do you specify the version there
well um
taking the example of iep
so iep points to the url that just says
first.org
tlp
going forward after this conference
that url is going to take you to 2.0
so
anything machine readable and so also i
think a lot of this relies on the on the
what i consider to be a fact that a
great deal of what is shared under tlp
is very time sensitive information so
there's not like you know like a whole
bunch of like really old stale stuff
under tlp that that it um
is of great concern
uh i'm willing to be absolutely
corrected on that
um
and uh so if machine readable
if it needs to be machine readable
the machine will follow the url the url
will present tlp 2.0 and that way
anybody who is actually trying to
interpret the uh the the stuff that the
machine's thrown around
is going to be reading the up-to-date
version okay does that help it does that
help at all answer the question
partially yes thank you if there needs
to be if we need to hash out more to do
with how we mark the specific version
that something is being shared under
rather than just simply referencing the
url which is going to be the most up to
date
then um
then i'm more than uh
more than happy to welcome anybody to
join the sig and help us help us get
that squared away something else a cheat
sheet is really great
just one thing for tlp red
defense for your organizations it could
help if you don't do anything or you
know what to not do so you tlp can be
useful there
in
i think it's really crucial
i think it's really crucial to confine
tlp to the scope of how to share things
and not to get too much into how to act
on things absolutely yeah
yeah because that's covered by iep but
just out on the the tlp red um
i talked earlier about making sure you
have a discussion between recipient and
sender and usually the onus is on on the
the person providing the information
out to make sure that the recipient
understands it with tlp red we say it's
only the people in the conversation that
can understand that if you're sharing
tlp red and we've got to make sure that
this is in the use cases that if you're
sharing tv red with someone who has a
legal obligation
to provide that information to other
people in the organization that you
understand that you go and ask them and
says if i provide you this information
do you have a legal obligation or policy
obligation to provide this to other
people either in your organization or
elsewhere and then make sure that you're
fully informed about that before you
make that choice to share the
information so it's really the onus is
on the producer of information
as far as backward compatibility i mean
that was one of the things we really
made sure
was in there was the backward
compatibility so that if you're looking
at something that says tlpm but it
really doesn't matter if it's version
one or version two it's tlp amber um if
it says tlp clear tlp white you know
which version you're dealing with if it
says tlp amp restrict it's either
somebody who's decided they're going to
stick that in version one as their own
edition or it's version two but it all
means the same we did have an earlier
try where we're going to try to
make tlp amber the strict one and have a
one that was less strict and we realized
that that's not more backward
compatibility so
from a person to person i don't think
there's too much of a problem for
backward compatibility on on the right
interpretation of it yeah exactly
okay thank you
okay uh anders if you could wait a
moment i think it's patrick first
hello patrick green um
i'm going to mention something that i'm
sure you've been fighting with before
but i've been working with
national level sharing communities
and connected cheering communities
and at that point
tlp amber gets really quite messy
because these are
more than peer lesson organization
and i'm sure you've wrestled with this a
number of times but it's on
two it might even get even more messy
than on one um they've caused me
no end of problem but um
i'm sure you're aware of that i just
thought i'd bring it up as a thing
can i speak to that just because one of
one of the things we did was put a
definition because i work for a national
cesar and
one of this is definitions i think are
the one difference
the lack of definitions in version one
version two
there was an intent in version one not
necessarily in version two but if you
take a look at the if you haven't looked
at the actual um final uh
tlp that we sent out
we've said for clients that for national
c-certs it includes your constituents
we have not defined constituents
so
one of my concerns is that for us
constituents are people who are
especially on board
have done some sort of
we've tested to make sure they
understand tlp et cetera for another
national cesar they might not understand
those kind of things their idea of
constituents might be the inside of the
country but tlp amber by default if
you're a national c-cert gives you the
right to distribute that to your
constituents
yeah i'm not working for a national
season this is um so if you imagine
third sector sharing community where
everyone is vetted into the third sector
that is then greater than peer
but less than organization and then they
can also share to another sharing
community
at
green
but they can't do it at amber which is
fine that works but amber to amber and
it's automated as well so you can't you
can't necessarily get
the upfront agreement from the
originator
and it just gets
really quite messy
because of the
definitions
this
this is one of the things that i had in
that discussion with tom years ago about
tlp green was the notion that if you
said
if i go and call something tlb amber in
your example and share it with a
certain subset of people if anyone is on
that say email
they know who else was on the email if i
didn't bcc it so you know you can talk
to those people about it
but if i sent it out individually you
don't know who else got that information
you don't know who else you can talk to
about that information
in theory
if you said if you use a defined
community for tlp green and say
let's say tlp green this can go to the
banking sector in the european union
and maybe the rationale for european
union is because it's it fits the data
compliance laws
um
if i send this out it means oh i can
talk to anybody that's in that sector
you know who you can talk to
so
i personally like the idea of a tlp
green where you
define a sector and that sector could be
well not necessarily a sector you define
a community
it could be defined by sector could be
defined by nationality it could be
defined by
whatever
and then you know that it's safe to
share it within that definition but
that's
that's not encoded in there but it it's
sort of one of the things i interpret by
reading tlp green to a defined community
we just define by general
in general when we see tlb green if
there's nothing else we just say it's
the cyber community that's what we've
always assumed one of the risks doing
that though is you share tlp green
somebody doesn't read all those little
caveats and they're like oh it's still
bigger i'll just share it with somebody
else so all that can be done in iep
you can put all that stuff into iep you
can't do it easily here i mean this is
much more human readable so i would
assume from a human perspective read the
caveat from a machine perspective use
iep
oh perhaps i'll catch you afterwards and
ever go through it with you rather than
take up the
stand join the sig yeah
you're
welcome okay andras
so first of all thanks for all the work
that you're doing on this especially
with the clarifications i think it's
especially solving the dlp amber issues
are going to be really handy
i'm still worried about tlp clear
especially about
use cases where you have for example
data guard
in networks
that are hard coded looking for tlp
white to let data pass
the problem is very often these tools
have been written by someone ages ago
and they're in place
so suddenly we'll see a drop of data
flowing basically data that could be
absolutely vital to protect
organizations so that's my biggest fear
of tlp clear and perhaps uh as a first
step something for the sick to consider
would be
a campaign or or or actually
perhaps outsourcing
this task
of uh
of running automated scripts updating
all
code repositories that have uh tlp white
hard-coded so to put effort into
actually changing the existing tools
that are at least available publicly
so that we we don't run into these
issues and this drops in data flows but
if i understand well uh both you and tom
already have an idea about that would
you like to
mention it
well i mean i don't know exactly how
serious the conversation was as most
things with me kind of go
um but we were
you brought up the the month of code
and uh and how many pull requests could
you generate if you went and looked for
everything what had had tlp white hard
coded into it and then just did a pr for
everything so that it had uh so that it
changed the tlp clear right and that you
you you know like that somebody's gonna
get a free t-shirt and a deal
um
well but i think i really like your idea
of like doing some kind of campaign to
make sure to raise awareness of this
particular issue especially within that
time frame that we've art that we've
worked with to on with the board to
agree upon
so that uh
so that the word gets out to as many uh
developers as possible
i think the issue that you raise about
the data cards that the data guards that
are looking for this for um
for dlp purposes or something like that
is a is a really important one so thank
you
thanks thank you
yes
hello
i was triggered by the third
mention about use cases so i'm thinking
about
two scenarios one scenario is that i
have a document and it says still be
read
and is it clarified somewhere in the
documents
what is my expectation because tlp red
means what i i can do about it but
instantly i think in my head probably
it's not known
but for example don
tells me something tlp red
but maybe it's out there public on
internet
right so
when we think about reverse case that
was presented
so
if i get a document which says dlp white
or clear
my instant feeling that it's public
but if i have to because it's about me
for example right and then i choose to
share it
but then i can introduce some confusion
but actually if it's still py it doesn't
mean that it's public
it i am deciding what to do with it
and there's a mental
thing which can introduce
miscommunication because now i can be
scared or somebody else who doesn't
understand the difference between
instructions to me versus availability
of information
uh for example my manager you know he
sees dlp white and says oh it's a public
document or tlp clear
so
do you plan to clarify this aspect on
especially for this use case what you
have mentioned thank you
i was just i was just going to suggest
while while you were um bringing this up
i had the idea like maybe it would be
handy in the in this particular use case
the victim notification thing which is
the one you're talking about correct
or that scenario
um
maybe it would be useful to create some
some generic language or a template
language so that it could be like a
basic caveat that would explain why
you've kind of got the
tlp amber envelope that contains that
tlp white information
and how the how the recipient can behave
with it because again we want to keep we
do want to keep tlp scoped to only
talking about sharing
um but
it is um
it is useful i think in some of the ins
it will be useful in some of these use
cases to have more in-depth explanations
of what the recipients can do yeah in in
the use cases some of the use cases i've
put together so far i've put try to put
an example text and i think this is a
really good one that probably
it's not part of the standard
but
as an example that you give in a use
case to go and say in this in condition
maybe just the wording
the following
text
can be shared at
this if you so choose
and then maybe have an end so we can
work on again join the tlpg we're going
to work on these kind of things in the
next you know few months to try to give
this guidance but
and i encourage everyone here if you've
got use cases
send it to the tlp sick even if you
don't want to join the sake send your
use cases send your questions to us we
we need those because i've got my own
examples where i have problems and
you know i want to solve them and each
person has their own unique situation
so the more we get these these kind of
examples of real world problems that
you're having the more we can actually
go and say
ah what's the best wording that we can
use what are some good generic
words that we can use and then we'll get
translators to translate them in
different languages as well because
something that while tlp is english only
the instructions and all that you want
to make sure that people understand it
so having extra extra language
translations of those would be good but
i think it's an excellent point and we
should definitely be giving that type of
guidance in the use cases
i think you meant to say like the the
markings themselves are primarily in
english
yes yeah not the top itself is yeah
ethiopia yeah and one more remark which
you reminded me of villius which is
really important you may not be able to
read it but i'll read it out just to be
sure is that what stayed the same and i
think we even put a little bit more
emphasis on it that tlp is a simple
standard right it's it's four colors
basically and it's a limited set of
words
and sometimes we try to solve too many
problems with just a few words which
doesn't work so that's why there are a
few things in bold there at the middle
of the page which are extremely
important first of all the source is
responsible for ensuring that recipients
of top labeled information understand
and can follow top sharing guidance so
that one that one remains the source
must actually know what they do when
they spread the information
yes it is harder to apply when it's
automated exchanges i know but this
stays very important
number g the source is at liberty to
specify additional sharing restrictions
that's still the case these must be
adhered to by these must be adhered to
by recipients
an age if a recipient needs to share
information more widely
than indicated by the top label it came
with they must obtain explicit
permission permission from the source so
these very important remarks uh
stay valid and it stays a human work so
sometimes tlp just doesn't quite fit and
we need to be creative in using it
and yeah as i said earlier explicit
permission come in three ways one is you
can actually put it in the information
saying you can do the following extra
things that are beyond the standard
number two is you go back to the to the
sender and ask for permission or number
three is you get a standing agreement
between you and the sender to go and use
this exception and then the onus is on
the sender to make sure that anything
that goes outside of that agreement is
is identified
okay
any other questions i'm sure you have
comments or questions or suggestions
that you can come up with
feel free we have a
a lot of time left 25 minutes
minutes okay thank you my name is
duchess i'm from national assert of the
republic of serbia thank you for this
information i have one question uh
related to tlp red
so it should the information classified
as tlp red should be
exchanged
verbally or in person
so
is there any way that we use for example
pgp with email to share with some person
information that is classified as dlp
red
is this
a kind of question that is
stupid question or
i just wanted to say uh to to ask myself
what is the way that we could
by mail exchange dlp red information is
this possible
at any kind of encryption
and so on thank you uh
it's not a stupid question at all no
such thing
um
so the the
the wording i believe is should
and that's just a piece of advice
um my gen my more my other version of
the advice is basically if you find
yourself opening something in a
microsoft office product and you start
typing the letters tlp red you might be
doing something wrong
but
um
it does happen all the time and there's
lots of use cases for it and sometimes
people share tlp red without any
encryption at all i've seen
i am
i've not only seen i am a member of
multiple slack channels in some trust
communities where the whole slack
channel is marked dlp red and people are
just typing away about whatever the news
of the day is
um so you can share tlp red um in a
variety of media and different types of
channels
um
digitally etc it's just um
it's considered like so there is no must
be shared in person or you know like or
sort of manually so as you as you put it
but uh
but it's advisable to be sort of
sensitive about how you do share tlp red
and i would say does that help
let's say you as the recipient shouldn't
feel guilty that somebody's gone and
sent you an email that your system can
look at i mean the onus is again on the
sender not on you as the recipient so as
you as a sender
if you're
hopefully if you're sending tlp
information you know that
the sysadmins and anybody in between is
going to be able to read that
information and if you're comfortable
with that and you want to call it tlp
red well that's on you your tlp red is
anybody that can is part of the
conversation and maybe the system is a
part of that conversation um if you want
it to really be
encrypted and send a pgp to someone so
they open it
again realizing that person is going to
open it on a computer and sysadmins and
others are going to be able to get
access to that information
if you're comfortable with the fact that
the sysadmins on the other end are going
to be able to look at that
then yeah go ahead
you should until quantum computing we
should
realize this asymmetric encryption yes
yeah yes so it's it's so i'm aware i'm
ensure that my recipient has
his private key uh and he's only can
access this i'm i'm i'm sure that with
encryption there is no way that someone
in transit can read that information so
i'm free to send to share dlp read
information
to only that recipient is this okay this
uh yeah end-to-end encryption is great
okay you should always use best effort
okay great thank you thank you very much
alexander i know that yeah based on
based on his feedback i'm i'm not
struggling with still period
which is quite interesting um
there's the program for first
and this talk from inteser
i think it's tomorrow which is still
period
but
it's here of individual individual
recipients there so that means a crowd
of conference of people it's fine so
it's been
in uh meetings with many people it's
fine to use it as a kind of
classification scheme but in this case
it's only for individual recipients so
i'm lost now
what did you say like the the talk that
smart tlp read yes
well i would assume
that the source of that information the
presenters
is intending for everybody in the room
to keep the contents of that talk to
themselves
okay
yeah
so we
as you know we don't rule that and we
don't want to rule that so probably my
personal choice would be different i
think it is this is my personal comment
right yeah sure
i think i would not share anything
with a very big audience on the tlp red
because it seems a little unlikely to me
but i assume that the indeed like tom
said the source of
or the speaker tomorrow wants to limit
it as much as possible
uh but in general i think that the music
you'll be read
if you are wise and this is again my
personal comment it is indeed good to
know who you are actually sharing it
with exactly that's why i think that the
word individual recipients is still
supported so it's more like close
meeting with like a small number of
people yes okay make sense okay thanks
amen if
you need free speaker registration and
all you've got is tlp red information
do what you got to do
i mean things that i consider is
legitimate tlp rate that i've seen
before someone coming in talking about a
specific incident and they may go and
actually tell me the name of the
organization that was affected and it's
like i don't want anybody else in your
organization to know this but i'm
telling you
because if you see something similar
maybe i'm talking to somebody in another
national season and i'm like
this is the company that got impacted
they've got offices or they've got
something in your country
i want you to keep an eye out if you
happen to see anything then you'll know
it's related you can talk to me and then
we can start this conversation or
something but if you don't see anything
i don't want anyone else in your
organization knowing this i mean those
are that's the kind of example that i
would typically use for tlp red is is
i've got somebody i trust and i know
they're not going to go and share this
information but that information might
be useful a bit i've also seen it happen
sometimes when i get tip-offs from from
police about a takedown and they'll go
and tell us and it's like
they'll tell me so that i make sure that
i can tell my bosses later on that yeah
i was informed about this um but they
don't want me talking about this broadly
because again that there are
consequences but they just want to give
me a heads up
because
you know they don't want to look like
they're not sharing but
it's sensitive
another example is i use tlp red often
when i give trainings just to tell a
story an inside story where i would
rather not see people use it outside the
room
and still it's sensible to you to share
it because it's just an interesting
piece of information so there you can
also use top red
yes
welcome
tom you're
probably double this a lot at you a
certain system but is it possible that
you could see the use of multiple tlps
and a single one where it's like
something's tlp amber but if you want
people to
use actionable
stuff to share with the people who are
going to be doing the grunt work you can
make it plp green
um
as you're asking this i'm imagining
something more like uh like what we call
paragraph markings
in uh in certain communities where we
say like this you know
this pair like for example like this
part of the message is tlp and restrict
and this part of the message is tlp
green
yeah
yeah because that is actually like that
is another one of the use cases in
progress
to get clear language on how to use
um
multiple tlps in the same
uh in the same context
and it kind of sounds interestingly
enough you just heard don admit that he
does that on a regular basis when he
gives a training he will have the
training probably is tlp green
for the most part and then it contains
tidbits that are tlp red
so it's already something that some
people are doing in fact i think there's
some sharing organizations that do this
um
but uh but it is something that's not
codified or
um or clearly explained in the standard
and probably in some sort of appendix or
the use case document that we're talking
about
um we want to include something like
that for sure
yeah in in
the work we do typically in the
classified environment use either
paragraph markings or tear lines
so again paragraph markings is like this
paragraph is this this paragraph is
you're very explicit sometimes the
tearline is
yeah this part below is tlp clear this
part is is tlp green tlp amber
in one of the use cases that i was
working on for um incident notification
i had an example where let's say it's
it's a company in thailand discovers
that there's uh
they've been compromised and one of the
beacons is going to a hospital in
germany well they may send a tlp amber
strict notification to
tycert
and then
in that you would have a paragraph that
would be tlp amber strict saying
please do not um
identify that it's our company that's
affected and then tlp clear
here's the beacon information
so as far as they're concerned they
don't care if they get published online
once it goes to the recipient this is
what i was talking about end recipients
right to do what they want at a minimum
level says this can be shared at tlb
clear and it's the beacon information
that goes forward and so tyser would
only share the tlp clear stuff because
the rest was tlm restrict they said okay
i'm going to pass this to sir bund
and surfbond only gets the clear stuff
and they can send that off to the
hospital so yeah you can you can have
tear lines paragraph markings yeah the
ic tear line classification the little
genesis of my question
and training everybody who works for all
of your organizations on how to do all
of these things we're talking about will
only take 10 minutes i promise
yeah well one x-ray mark when you do the
embedding
be very careful i recently saw an
example of somebody sending out the top
green email
fine
and then hidden in in there somewhere
was a top red passage
you can do that but remember that you as
a source is responsible for how this is
being used chance is of course very big
that people will just forward it without
having read everything and
maybe the top rat was not meant to be
forwarded so when you do embedding be
very clear about what you're
communicating and how you're
communicating it we can't put this in
the standard but this is just
common sense
so you're saying the subject line was
tlp green and then inside of the email
body of the email there was that hurts
me yeah the message should always be the
most sensitive level of tlp regardless
of the content and then you can if you
want to have bits and pieces you can
pull out that's fine but yeah
but again that's that's on the sender as
the recipient you know you get it and
you're like oh my god they shouldn't
have sent that and
it's not your fault it's it's the center
it's always the sender has to make sure
that
their information is going to be well
understood by the people receiving it
any other questions or remarks
suggestions
doesn't seem so but
maybe the gentleman in the panel has a
closing remarks
anything you want to add i'm just going
to suggest that don needs to get himself
some converse
for real for real dude
i mean worry about my nikes it's okay
they're all nike products
yeah
i just also put up what you probably
already saw at the table because it's
not spectacular but uh quite nice that
we now have all these color codings here
or also
which is just a little progress but
but worth the effort
um
thank you all for coming i hope that we
did at least uh i hope it's not clear as
mud
now that we've tried to explain what
we're doing what the changes are what
the reasoning and the rationale uh
behind the changes um
is and uh
and i'm really looking forward to
working with um as many of you who want
to join the sig as uh
as you want to and um
and you can come to our session on
friday how late
it's friday uh at 10 a.m
friday 10 a.m and as you're meeting your
fellow colleagues make sure
yeah as you're drinking this week make
sure you talk tlp with all your
colleagues and share
the new tlp with them and tell them to
send in use cases and join the
tlp working sig and uh and remember if
anybody says uh starts a sentence with
tlp white correct them immediately
oh yeah just shut them down right now
we can find out
do we have it
make me get out the app hang on
oh the sig itself
the work we do in the sig is
oh oh oh okay
i've been trying to make jokes up this
this is a tough crowd
um
let's see
uh when are we on friday
we are 10 o'clock
wicklow room 2 which i think is the
floor above this one
wicklow
anyway it's wicklow room two friday at
10 a.m
please come
um
this draft document is that available
anywhere
um well he was said draft at the top
that's why i said draft yeah
um
so it will be made available right after
the conference
okay yeah so you have a publication date
it's just if i'm communicating with
people i want to be able to say from
this date this is going to be published
and at the moment as it's not available
anywhere on the site or in the email
list or anywhere it's a bit difficult to
talk about it because i can't have any i
don't have any sporting documents we'll
know that on friday this mostly
currently this week of course is very
complicated especially for everybody
who's involved in first on the on the
admin side
but we'll know on friday when when it
can go online i hope somewhere next week
i'll go uh i'll go find dave and try to
peg something you know thank you for the
question good question
yes
anything else on the
edge of this
panel discussion no no one
no no none of you thanks again for
coming everybody thank you thank you
very much
help me
thank you