uh it's time and let us start the
session
i'm i am ryusuke masoka research
principal of
fujitsu system integration laboratories
and i'm sharing this session
first this talk is
tlb white
and
please mute your phone
and q and a will happen at after the
talk
and i use
standing microphones over there
and there
so uh speaker today is first queen
norton
uh she's a writer who likes to hang out
in the dead and alice and the love
neighborhoods of the internet where bad
things can happen to defenseless little
pockets
she started studying uh hackers in 1995
after a wasted use of usenet and bbsing
her writing uh tends toward science and
technology and her projects tend toward
uh towards um
supporting a journalist and activist she
has covered a sci-tech copyright law
robotics and a body a
body modification
and a digital politics and culture a
culture and medicine but no matter how
many times she tries to leave she always
come back to hackers
okay so much for queen
and
now rafael
rafael vino
is a security researcher at the computer
incident response center luxembourg
circle
you know it
since 2012 raphael wants to increase the
i.t consciousness of the human beings
populating the
internet in order to make it safer for
everyone that's important his day job is
a mixture of forensic and maori analysis
with a lot of python on top of it
to glue all the pieces together
he loves sharing and thinks everyone
should contribute to open source
projects
okay
so uh
uh
so
the title of the talk is watching our
web pages in action with
luki lu
right okay so floyd's yours
thank you thank you
uh so uh this is rafael from circle and
i am quinn from the internet um
uh and uh but we're really here to
introduce you to lookie lou
a piece of software we've been
developing for some years now
so
we all know the web is a terrible place
but
how terrible is it really
uh so
we
we created a tool to figure that out to
look closely at what happens when web
pages load the term looky loo is kind of
an american vernacular term
used for either a person who walks into
a store looks at touches and picks up
everything but doesn't buy anything
or for the people who gawk at traffic
accidents while they slowly file by and
uh looking we'll show you both of those
aspects um uh of lookingly doing this
for the web
but let's start in a nice place on the
web
don't worry there's plenty of train
wrecks coming later
this is a nice clean website which is
also full of interesting content which
may interest you it's the eff or
electronic frontier foundation it's the
internet's first and original digital
rights organization
they have to be really well behaved in
terms of compliance privacy tracking and
so on since that's kind of their thing
um
we're all pretty sure this website isn't
doing anything too dodgy
so that's what happened when you open
eff.org in your browser and it's loading
a bunch of content and this is the
looky-loo view yes that's a look at the
view of the of the website um so what
happened when you open a page is like
you load the url and that url is going
to load some extra content
so from the left to the right here you
have content loaded by each of those of
those two apps
so yeah times move left to right and
there is no cookie set in that in this
capture
so
those inc i could show you the content
that we look at specifically when um
when we open websites and those ones are
like well-behaved node of the first page
of eff and you can see it loads uh six
javascripts uh three css files and 20
images
and those content like those before the
css are loading um a few more images on
web phones it's just pretty normal stuff
here
so what is lookie loo in general that
thing you just saw a little tiny snap of
well it's a forensic tool
it's for mainly for the investigation of
websites showing website contents but
also kind of capturing and just giving
you an interface to see websites in
motion
we're indexing all the headers resources
and everything that a center received
mapping that onto a tree the tree you
just saw and displaying what type of
data each element is along with links
there's links inside there
to the elements content
and hashes for that content this is this
will be important later
the more you use your particular
instance of lickiloo the more valuable
it will be
so look hello is not uh developer tools
of your browser it has some other lap
and you will have some of the resources
that you see in lukilu that are also in
in developer tools but it's really first
and foremost a forensic tool so it can
find things in a capture that are hard
to find anywhere else
as well as its context and we are
hashing and correlating all the
resources between websites
so we are capturing it away from your
browser meaning that the capture is down
in a dedicated browser this is not the
one that you use on a daily basis so you
don't end up like leaking any of your
own information or potentially being
compromised or anything like that
and it also gives you a way to configure
the browser you're going to use to do
that capture
and we are saving everything that we
like we capture during that let's you
get during that capture so it can be
studied studied and analyzed later on
and another really interesting thing is
that it gives you a blurry version of
the screenshot you can also unblur it
obviously but that blurry version of the
screenshot of the page can be really
useful useful
when you realize that you really wished
you didn't see it so that's really
important like basically you have a way
to not not see every screenshot that you
capture on that indicator that was a
pretty early feature request and we
suddenly realized it was a very good
idea
um
so why did we build wikiloo
like most good stories it starts with a
room full of lawyers
so back in 2015 we were brought in by
some friends to have kind of an
educational informational session with a
bunch of media and journalism lawyers in
new york and um we were kind of there to
scold them about serving malvertising uh
and they were kind of there to find out
how to not serve malvertising
that was one it was not the only focus
but it was definitely one of the things
that we were all talking about that day
so
my field i'm a journalist normally my
field has a lot of problems these these
days our traditional business practices
have evaporated and everyone's just
scrambling to survive which means that
journalism is a big old target for
both above board and below board
exploitation
um
and
these law these
media and journalism lawyers were really
worried about being hacked and being
taken advantage of
because it was happening
a lot
um in this time range especially i
suspect it's still happening i just
don't think it makes the news that much
also because we're um we're little we're
a little nattering sewing circle we just
love reporting on each other getting
hacked and then reporting back when the
other one got hacked
so
i guess that got i don't know that the
advertising getting away but the
reporting got less fun over time
so uh
when when they said these lawyers and uh
and essentially the people they were
working with kept saying to us
how do we know what's on our site
and we looked at each other in a room
full of people like this and we looked
at each other and we said we realized we
didn't have a tool to give them and um
we looked back at the lawyers and said
we'll get back to you now initially our
thought was okay there'll be something
out there and we can send it to people
and they can
integrate it into their um
into their infrastructure and their
processes
there is nothing there was nothing out
there that actually allowed people to
see their own websites or other websites
in motion
so
we built it
and let's go back to the eff example
again clean
simple and safe
and we're running this page through a
browser a headless browser we're mapping
all the connections to the content on a
phylogenic tree that's the format you're
looking at here which shows time left to
right and resources as they are accessed
and placed on the page
there's always a relationship we always
try to preserve that relationship
there's always a time flow and that's
what a phylogenetic tree specifically
gives you phylogenetic trees are used to
map evolution for life on earth
the web is complicated and terrible but
we're betting it's not more complicated
than seven several billion years of of
the evolution of life
we hope
uh the eff site we use it because it's
very simple but it's a real exception
most things are not like the fsf site
most large websites are are
agglomerations of cruft and crud and
content and code that's never very well
maintained um and never as maintained as
the website admins thought it was going
to be or at least hoped it was going to
be so
at the other end of the spectrum from
the eff is fox news which is an absolute
mess
and not the way you think i mean mess
oh no oh no
so that's how it looks like when you
open the the fox news website in lukiloo
so like it's not even out of the tree
you have on the on the image here like
it's just way bigger than that but we
couldn't just fit it like tiny lines you
could see nothing if we put the whole
tree up there so yeah like that and
that's the front page that's just like
you load the front page and that's what
happened uh you're getting from europe
12 months of content um just like by
waiting for long enough if you load it
from outside of europe like us it's
going to be way bigger than that we
guess it's somehow related to the fact
that try to do some gdpr compliance we
don't know but anyway it's just like it
can go really crazy
um
and it's it's content it's also crap
mostly crap and they're just not that's
not editorial it's a lot of ad networks
tracking widgets
all kind of
probably broken things that i mean i
haven't noticed yet
and like all those complex websites um
they are like badly managed software
project
full of craftsman camps it's just a lot
of things going on that
who knows what's what's happening
and before you think you're picking on
fox news for the fun of it this website
has the distinctions that's on the to be
the most uh constantly crushing
looky-loo basically it was just like too
big on just making all kinds of stuff so
we had to rewrite part of the code in
order to make it
just
support those kind of big websites so
it's just not the content it's also like
everything that is happening on that
specific page fox news is a great way to
test an application like this
so what is lookie lube good for um
here's a an overly busy slide on that
beyond oh damn
that page is a mess the web is a mess
let's actually kind of drill down and
look at some more security focused use
cases for lickeyloop
we can get past this busy slide um it'll
be somewhere online if you want it and
get to examples and explanations
so
here
here is trustwallet the most trusted and
secure cryptocurrency wallet
conveniently named trust wallet so that
you know it's trustworthy
of course
it is not trust wallet it is a fishing
wallet it's a fishing site intended for
a trust wallet customers
so this is how the phishing site is
loading and you get to see the
infrastructure and even the stuff
they're kind of using trickery most of
which is redirects at this point
to hide this is also where capturing
hashing and building the data page of
elements really comes into its own
so that's another example of fishing
websites here um so looks trust is a
two-factor logging system for luxembourg
government on banking
and again that's just like a fishing
page and as you can see here you end up
with a few redirects
and when we look
at css on this page
we see that
the same css like the same blob that is
used on the switching website
is also visible and it's also used on
other captures in that case we have that
css yeah i was just gonna say just to
make it a little bit more clear what's
happening here is we're kind of drilling
down we're essentially clicking through
the nodes on the page we're not
demonstrating that we're just putting it
in slides but so you know how we got to
this particular thing um we're going
from the node to the content to the to a
list of the things that was there yeah
and what happened here is that we have
like that css resource that is loaded on
that page and we can see that we have
that same css document
also loaded in other captures
and that's where it gets really
interesting to have
a lot of captures in your in your local
instances that you can find um like
similar phishing pages
that have been seen by other people in
your organization
so that's just like the reason we hash
all those resources and unstore them
locally on the instance of the look
hello instance it has the nice effect of
um
when you see something that isn't lux
that isn't lex trust you know that has a
css you know it's um
it's not supposed to be there
because looky loo captures everything in
time sequence and maps it out we catch
infrastructural bad actors that are
using techniques to obscure what they're
doing like this is a case of a targeted
phishing attack which very quickly
redirects to google when it detects that
it's not actually at the target it wants
to be at
so normally when that happens you lose
the middle layers like you know
something happened and now you're on
google
but but looky loo lets you actually
expose everything that happened before
the redirect to google
so lookieloo accidentally turns out to
be great for finding gdpr violations and
oh boy
so many
so it's there's no good news none
um for instance uh the mirror newspaper
in britain i know they're not
technically in the eu anymore but
they're still they haven't scrapped gdpr
yet and it was just the first thing we
found
this is all over believe me we founded
uh french
news websites were terrible
um
and uh so what we see here uh on the
mirror's website under looky loo and
again it's one of these huge ones so
we're just exciting a little bit of it
is uh before actually any consent can
even be given before you even click
agree add services from google and
doubleclick are in an iframe they're
setting and reading cookies
and there's more evidence down the line
of stats and tracking
ips
there's a lot going on in this tree
journalism companies are some of the
worst regular offenders we've found on
privacy tracking and gdpr and that's
because our only business model left is
selling you you to social media
companies who are slowly dismantling our
industry
anyway moving on
so uh let's go a bit into like how look
hill is built on what kind of tools um
are used so
in order to do the capture
we now use playwright which is an
amazing tool by developed by microsoft
that is mostly used to um just test
websites basically to just like make
sure that the website is responding
properly uh to to anything that is just
like just like contigration for websites
um
we just switched to playwright from
another tool that was called splash that
was not really maintained anymore but
playwright is basically a full
headless browser that you can configure
the way you want and it is great to just
to use in in lokido
the other tool we are using is called
ete toolkit which is a python library
developed by biologists to represent
phylogenetic trees
so that's again like a bunch of tools
that are linked together and as i said
like just you put glue between all those
tools and then you have something that
is usable
um so yeah that's what we did for for
like the back end and for the front end
we're using a d3.js which is a
javascript library that we use to like
actually represent the tree itself on
the page on flask which is a web
python web server with
jinja which is like the templating
system so just like all those tools like
jammed together with some glue and
then you have lukilu
okay let's talk take a look at some
specific features and the interface of
lookiloo when you start a capture on the
first page of lookieloo you have some
choices to make
including your browser user agent and
configuration of
your
capture
so browser configuration
obviously browser agent changes the
contents of websites
uh so we let you configure that
but there's one limitation here which is
that we can't change how our website
responds or how our web browser is
responding to website probing of browser
capabilities so if the site that you're
you're
uh
accessing is um is using probing more
than user agent you're that's that's
kind of gonna that's gonna show or not
show as
the case may be
uh so there are a few modules that will
make playwright harder to detect um like
play white styles and stuff like that i
didn't implement them yet but there is
something that we can do about that to
make it harder to detect right now it's
still seen as a headless browser so
some
some people trying on some websites
trying to like poke what figure out what
is browsing them
we'll
we'll just detect it and block you but
we are looking at implementing it
in the near future
uh configuring um the initial settings
of the browser we have
the standards http headers refers
cookies proxies
uh obviously geolocation will change
what kind of
mess you get from fox news um but also
cookies allow for you to do scans with
the logged in state which is pretty
vital for for a lot of applications
um
so yo dog i heard you like captures um
[Music]
now you can do more captures from your
captures in this case for instance like
if you've got a bunch of urls from there
you can click to kind of do further
captures on those urls in this case uh
it would be useful for say you've got
phishing that's been blocked by bitly
but you want to investigate that so you
have the url and you can re re-run that
and we keep the state in case you need
cookies and referrers etc
so look hilo as we said it's like a tool
you can install in-house
it's really useful to allow your users
to like notify you about
something that they want you to
investigate so
this is extra special yes so in that
case uh you can just basically click on
the on the web interface enter an email
address and some details and it's going
to submit a notification to
the
admin of the platform
you also have the ability to
connect third party tools so in the
public instance we have virustotal on
urlscan.io that are
automatically there so we can just like
look
at the results from those two
services
um if you install lukilu in in your own
organization on yourself you need to get
your own api keys um but sorry wikilea
doesn't come with virustotal yeah
but yeah it's just like an extra few
features that you can have that are
quite handy
um yeah
so let's go back on like when you when
you investigate specific nodes
when you click on a node you can it's
going to open a pop-up and that pop-up
has a lot of information about all the
requests that have been made um to load
the page
so when you have when one of the
resources downloaded is an image you can
hover over that the icon and you will
see the specific image
pretty handy you can download each
individual resources so if you want if
you have like a specific entry like a
css or some javascript or something that
turns out to be potentially malicious
you can just click on it download it and
investigate it manually so you don't
have to like
try to scramble to figure out where this
specific resource comes from you can
just download it it's fairly
straightforward
[Music]
in the other integrations uh we have
obviously a misp
integration so you can search
like from a from a capture on a miss
instance
um yeah yeah so and when you have hits
so any urls or ips or resources it's
going to be to show you uh like the
event in mist you can click on it and
open the mis the missed event and that's
just like a handy way so again on the
mis
integration requires you to have your
own miss instance like it's not you
cannot access that you can't use ours
yeah like you cannot access
like circle missed instance in that case
yeah
and you can
trigger so you can like
do a search request against mist but you
can also push a capture on a miss
instance so you can configure it and if
you are used to misp you see like the
info field and then the tags and so on
and when you click it's going to publish
to like submit the mis
event on honors instance
okay
we have an apa in case you're afraid of
your mouse and love looking at code
so you can basically do all those
actions like all the actions you you had
on on the web interface you can do it
over the api so just like the python
module but it's just like a simple rest
api you can just
use it as it is
and you can submit to misspen everything
like that
okay so we have this is fairly new we
have a wikiloo browser extension which
will allow you to submit the page that
you're on logged in or not to an
instance that you've configured
i hope that you can see the problem here
because please please never use this on
a public instance or an instance that
you don't control or
can completely expect what's going to
happen
your login cookie will thank you
your i your your credentials will thank
you for not putting this into the public
but it is it is convenient and powerful
if you have your own instance and your
own kind of more closed ecosystem so
yeah that's a close-up on the on the
browser plugin so you can see you can
like select what you want to send to the
capture uh so again like if you have if
you're like on facebook you're logged in
on facebook and you submit that to look
your instance it's going to also push
along all your cookie jars containing
your login cookies for facebook do not
configure that plugin on uh to connect
to a public nuclear instance very bad
using a cyber cafe
yeah so yeah just
be careful about that it is it lukitu
will let you shoot yourself in the foot
just
know that
i mean
it's harder to shoot yourself in your
foot if you don't use the browser
plug-in but we gave you the power
uh so what's next for lookie-loo uh we
are um
uh revamping the we've had some user
testing we're gonna be revamping the uh
ui uh i got sidetracked on that project
for roughly two years
anyway um
one of the other features that we are
going to add soon is a passive ssl
supporting passive ssl so basically we
will get like all the ssl certificates
and hashes and so on and throw them in a
passive ssl system that we have at
circle um just to again do look up
against that passive ssl instance and
submit new
new indicators
the other one that we are going to
implement soon is
like integrating it with pandora pandora
is another tool that we develop
that is used for analyzing specific
files and the idea will be to select a
file from the capture send to pandora
and then you will have
just details on like what what that
specific file is doing
okay and um
long more of a stretch goal at this
point but we want to create kind of a
modality to it a modes for different
investigative uses whether we're talking
about security which is most of the
focus right now people who are trying to
do research on the web people who are
trying to learn how the web works or
teach how the web works um and of course
the legal applications that were
somewhat the beginning of the genesis of
of lookie lou
but that's in the long term again i
still have to redo the ui
um so who is lookie lou for i mean
obviously security people you guys
uh but also i hope in the long run for
the lawyers who inspired it um
i think it could be a great tool for
journalists
uh who are looking at malfeasance and
bad things on the internet
website admins and we have had some some
feedback from people who are using this
on their own website to try and figure
out what the heck is happening um and
then ultimately educators and students i
think would be a great application for
this and already has been yeah yeah i've
been using it uh in a class in i was
giving uh last semester to just like
teach students how the web work and show
them that it's a lot more complicated
and messy than the message that they
thought initially and heck that we
thought initially yeah yeah i mean we
learned a lot by developing that tool
it's just yeah
and uh where do you get it yeah so we
have a public instance uh at circle so
look in the circle i'll tell you
you can just like use it submit your own
your own urls it has an api yeah it has
an api and everything
if you use this one know that the data
is all stated at circle so please do not
submit like
login cookies or anything like that that
would just be very annoying to like
clean up afterward
and it's open source obviously so it's
all accessible on github you have
installed guides on just explanations
and like what you can do with it and how
to configure it on only on github
yeah
and that's us uh so now we throw it over
to you guys for your questions yes
[Music]
thank you thank you very much for your
talk i
i found uh clicking a gdrp
uh
link uh consent to it means something
but now i know it's it's nothing okay uh
so question time uh
there are two standing mics
and
okay
go ahead
just a couple of questions one is on the
javascript engine are you
running a full javascript engine to
detect everything
to detect set timeout based
redirects or set timeout based
pull-in
what about things like service workers
and
cash where you can use cash to basically
proxy requests behind the scenes
and the session storages local storages
also where you can do
corruption of content yeah so it's going
to it's basically running in a full
browser like it's really using google
chrome headless like this complete
browser so it has access to all of that
um we are still like working on getting
the play right setting in line right now
it's it's going to it has cookies it has
local storage um
we allow a bunch of permissions to the
browser so it can do like a website can
do almost everything including like
geolocation and so on
we need to look more in how we can
handle timeouts
right now we have um like basically
levoit has really great support for that
you can like wait for a specific amount
of time before you close the capture um
we don't have at this point a way to
like make sure that all the timeouts are
over but it's possible with playwright
to implement something to basically make
sure that all the timeouts are still
have been have been triggered it's not
there yet but by default we wait
five seconds after the last network
interaction
so it will catch a lot of the cases it
should not necessarily catch all of them
but it's still possible to like bypass
uh look you know like figuring out like
just
not necessarily run everything but
for most of the use cases including like
malicious websites like phishing and so
on it it worked most of the time
and when that whenever use case that is
like not working properly we always try
to like implement it and fix and find a
solution for that so if you have like
times where it's like not working as you
expect it to work let us know yeah like
github open issue send us an email like
happy to implement uh walk around
yeah so specifically though with the
service workers where you can a lot of
the malware today uses
service worker to hide url request is
not even visible if you use the
developer tools
yeah have you looked at that yet or no
so
it's basically what we use uh from
playwright is ha output so the http
archive output so if it's in there we
will have it if it's not we won't
um but i should definitely look at like
i think it's going to be there i think
the hi has like a lot of that content uh
but yeah like we need to look at it like
we need to see if there is like stuff
that we are actually missing um
yeah
yeah please
i have i have two small questions one is
uh
is it working only with the website
which is live now or can i use it to
submit the whole web page when i we i
have for example i may need to analyze
the website which was uh which was
live on in the past but not alive now so
i can get it from a let's say wayback
machine or it i have the full package
can i submit it and get analyzes this
the first question the second one is
does it give me the
full overview what the website has or
does it also help me to understand some
malicious
uh
part particles it has for example if
there is a stored xss for example on the
website can i get this result from it or
i am
am i expected to get the
files and analyze by myself
so you will you're expected to analyze
it by yourself like you don't have like
we that's the kind of stuff we can add
and like we can probably figure out like
if there is a way to detect that there
isn't stored xss
i mean obviously if something's already
in say you know virus total and you have
that it will flag it we've also flagged
um safe scripts yeah um which is kind of
the reverse of that but still somewhat
helpful uh so we've got things that are
marked safe
from
uh yeah for like a
cdn gs so all the libraries that are
known on cdngs as legitimate will be
flagged on the site like on the capture
as legitimate i mean again like
legitimate is not the right word
basically as at least
a known javascript
from a library that is
existing and has been published
uh so that's like one of them
uh aren't
uh yeah on the first question i think it
was the uh just basically we need the
har file uh yeah so for yeah for like
the first question like when you have
like um like if you if you have a con
page content
you cannot just submit that to lukitu
like
that would be interesting the thing is
right now what it does is really takes a
url load it in the browser and generate
http archive blob
it's using the har file to do that so
i mean you'd have to pick at it a little
bit but it would be entirely possible to
feed it a stream of those but that's the
format that's that it's expecting
so yeah if you have
uh like if you have cap like if you like
capture websites and you get the hr
outputs or the http archive output
somehow you can load it into lokido it's
not like easy to do right now but that's
something we could do in the future just
like using that and then generating a
tree out of it certainly if that's if
that's a more common use case we can
implement that yeah
okay uh last question
hey regarding the artifacts uh from the
capture and you
mentioned they are being saved locally
on the machine
it is just a csv or some other like a
json or is it a structure so it's start
in http archive blob so it's like in
json and so basically you have like h
air file has like it's a json document
that contains all the requests and all
the artifacts are stored in base64
encoded in the json itself so it's a
really it can be a really big json
document that contains everything
thank you
okay uh let us thank the speakers again
[Applause]
so please provide the
take your time to
do the survey in your mobile app
as much as possible and the next talk
will start in 10 minutes thank you
thanks for not scaring me