thank you very much okay we'll dive
right in so you've all have seen the the
book that I published two years ago when
I first started writing that book I was
right it's a business book it's about
conquering the Chinese market okay and I
did anticipate that I would spend a
great deal of time investigating fraud
as well as other crimes and my
investigation led me to different
countries and at one point it led me to
a pub in England where I was meeting
with an undercover investigator and this
is a man who was nearing retirement and
he'd spent his entire career
investigating counterfeits in China so
he was the guy to go to so I and I had
just come back from China where I had I
seen already quite a lot on the topic I
talked to a lot of people a lot of
Chinese wine growers as well as people
dealing imported wines so I knew this
was a big topic very complicated so I
asked him after we talked I wanted him
also find out how he did his undercover
investigation some of the tricks of the
trade and I said so you know what do you
do would it what do we do and he said
you make it as complicated as difficult
as possible for them to copy your
product so they move on to the next
person I thought okay so there was no
rounding up the counterfeiters or you
know and putting them in jail or having
them stopped the idea was just to get
them to move along now this is a big big
topic fake was a huge topic so think of
this as just a primer this is just a
short course and I'm gonna try and hit
the main topics okay so hopefully by the
end of this you'll have an idea what the
what the big ideas are what some of the
methods are being used okay and maybe
I'm thinking because this is your this
is your business you might have some
ideas okay okay what are weaving by
shape wine this is anybody your work in
the wine business or have contacts with
the wine
business okay what do we think of when
we think of fake life okay well that I
mean that's that's it right there
so either have refilled bottles the real
bottles memory filled with something
else you have a very like Alice had a
very poor quality fake that wouldn't
wouldn't fool anybody who's a real
consumer or someone in the wine trade if
high quality fakes are very difficult to
figure out you have wine makers use
their own brand and they put a wine that
does not correspond with the label in
the bottle and then we're going to touch
on the IP war on brand squatting okay so
here's here's here's a photo I pulled up
that this is the Chinese authorities had
done this right now this is not just in
China this happens to be from there
someone had collected used bottles real
authentic bottle so they're gonna refill
this is an old scam it's been going on
as long as there has been bottled wine
okay very low-tech
very easy you could start with a long
bottle and you're a business okay and
just so happens as if they knew you guys
were coming I was giving this talk this
week an ex-con and they pollo stick who
lived in Lorene was just sentenced to
got an 18-month suspended prison
sentence for selling fake patrece on
eBay and if I keep gone legit and this
was for then he was running low on
retirement funds I guess so he started
and he's a real wine lover so he filled
it with really good wine
he chose something and that was his
thing he wasn't putting bad wine in
there he was putting some actually some
classified growth in the bottle but they
caught him so they're suspicious
customers eventually alerted the Chateau
and the police and he slipped up because
of the length of a cork and
way them one of the labels was fixed
okay but the average consumer probably
wouldn't have figured out those were
fakes and he made about a hundred
thousand euros in 18 months of which
nineteen thousand was left for me when
they caught him okay sloppy fakes these
are really if you know anything about
why these are easy - easy easy to notice
look at Nissan Montpellier okay that
should be a nice hot glue tape
well my Conti is is a is a is a red wine
it's not a white wine I mean is there's
so many mistakes on there yeah if you
don't read if you presume what if your
your your you have a language of does
not use alphabet what if you don't read
French you know
I'm not sure my mother who's a very
intelligent woman would know that's a
fake okay sup there but there but for
the wine trays they're easy to figure
out châtelet the feet okay these are all
what this means for the wine trade is it
you're still in the early stages of
counterfeiting because this assumes a
gullible market and the counterfeiters
haven't really got very good at it okay
then we have high quality things the
poster child for this is Rudy this is
somebody who had a great deal of
sophistication he knew a lot about wine
and he was buddies with all the big
collectors he was finally caught out
because he tried to sell vintages a
famous one that didn't exist okay and it
happened to be that the wine maker you
they look at the option sizes you there
ones are going up for sale he's like
wait a minute we didn't we didn't bottle
those messages so he interceded okay and
Rudy has a 10-year prison sentence as
well as hefty hefty fines so this is the
one that I run into the most and this is
I always hear it's just still grape
juice okay how many people I interviewed
who've been convicted of this crime who
told me the same thing again a very old
scam this
of winemaker a wine producer who has
real brands real labels real bottles
they own and instead of saying pudding
for instance coke de Rome in it they're
buying some bulk wine from somewhere
put it in there a table wine okay so
these can be in the millions of bottles
here's some recent cases this guy was
just this summer this is still an
alleged fraud but I've spoken to the
prosecutors and the investigation will
go on for a while because it's so
complex and so much money involved but
he's out on a 1.2 million dollar bail
right now and he is the head of this is
a multi-million dollar company a big big
company this in different countries okay
and he risked it all for you know a
couple million bottles of feet wine um
this guy's local he's from a big wine
family very wealthy he owes 20 chateaus
and he's gonna do two years in prison
for 1.1 million bottles and what he was
doing was buying up cheap table wine
from desperate wine growers in the north
of the Bordeaux region guys who who'd
you know they usually have second jobs
they could barely they can't make a
living at wine so if somebody comes
along says I'll give you cash for it of
course they're gonna be tempted okay he
he took that cheap wine and put it in
his own his very prestigious appellation
sentimental okay
now this I love this one 18 million
bottles of fake Pinot Noir most of us
all to gallo and constellation okay I
get these guys that the profit was seven
million euros and look what their fines
were it's like a slap on the wrist
they're still in business you got all
the big wine trade shows are there so
this is all to say that China did not
invent fake wine okay boom Bordeaux what
China has done
is its horse the wine trade the up its
game in a way that I think is really
significant but first I want you to
understand what we're doing in China why
it's so important okay this is this is a
Bordeaux grower who's there presenting
her wines in the south of China it was
one of my best to get a trip there I was
watching so it's worth today it's worth
2.4 billion dollars but 2020 they
expected to be with 21 billion that's a
big big market currently they estimate
38 million imported wine drinkers 47
percent of whom bialon and us can be
important later on the French have 40
percent of imported wine market and
Bordeaux dominates that you have the
lion's share to see if it's for those
number one volume and value market today
and I put in Hong Kong because it's
important to understand because we won't
really get into today but one one issue
is the smuggling between Hong Kong and
Mainland China and that is because 2008
they dropped the import duties on wine
so all the expensive one goes through
Hong Kong okay so like 10 million
bottles but it's worth almost the same
amount as the mainland trade and that's
because it's not because Hong Kong is
drinking so much wine it's just it's a
platform for mostly illegally getting it
into me not China okay let's see here oh
this is the other reason internet
internet is the way to move beyond the
first tier cities okay the you know
Shanghai Beijing they're saturated if
you want to if you wanted to get into
the Chinese market today with wine
you've got to move beyond there and the
Internet is obviously a way to do it you
guys all know Tamar this is this is not
new for you right okay
one thing they've done this this is the
second edition of their global wine and
spirits festival I think maybe you know
that they have a 1111
eleven festival is huge okay you
shopping best well they have a wine one
now since on September night and then
they just had the second year the second
addition of it I don't have the figures
yet I'm writing a story about it but
they haven't released the data but last
year in five minutes they sold more than
the entire country of Italy sold in five
days this is a big big event and reason
the other reason this is so important is
because of the social nature of
e-commerce in China it's a way for the
wine growers to reach consumers to
interact with them they they can its
brand building and education because
it's where the Chinese consumers go to
learn about one okay but now the
downside we have one this is from a wine
fair okay this is out in the open this
is typical you see this all the time so
this should be Chateau Latour it's shut
child a tour and just because I guess
they thought it made them look better
they also put the base shovel symbol
down here in 2015 there was a Foreign
Trade Commission released a report that
was originally suppressed that found
that confirmed where the experts have
been saying already that counterfeiting
had reached an industrial level it was
very specialized there was a great deal
of expertise fakes we're getting better
and better and better so bottling lines
and and this is on this this is the
figure that caused people to get really
upset is that they believe that for
every bottle of authentic French wine
there's at least one bottle of fake in
the market okay this serious serious
problem
one thing that's happened is that and
this happens to Chinese
my producers as well their distributor
partner can sometimes be the counterfeit
earth so for instance I was meeting with
a Chinese wine producer in middle of
China and he was explained to me how
this is an example he sells a hundred
cases to a sub distributor who then
sells 300 because he's counterfeited
another 200 okay the same thing was
happening to the French selling wine to
China they had no idea no idea they
thought they'd signed a deal with the
distributor they didn't understand that
they were that distributor was trading
around and counterfeiting their wine
so let's would real shake up in the
market and people are trying to find
better safer relationships and in it and
that's happening there's many many very
reliable distributors brands squatting
does everybody know what brands squat
eNOS okay okay that's been a big big
issue for Bordeaux okay if everyone
knows what it is that I'm just going to
talk about one of the more famous cases
first of what happened was the internet
was a big part that was everybody
suddenly was getting on the internet
this is this is a decade ago but because
every wine grower even though they're
not selling the wine themselves are
using an intermediary it felt like they
needed to have this presence on the
internet to reach customers
okay well the brand squatters use that
as their hunting ground so people didn't
realize even before there I was going to
China
someone was was registering their brand
okay this guy right here is really Huard
remarkable ok mr. Lee he is the owner at
pennant Panetti wine and in 2000 he
managed to register his CV which is the
Mandarin transliteration for Castel
Castel is when it fast his biggest wine
producers okay huge and they're in
many many countries because there was
the assumption that a French name might
be difficult for a Chinese person to
pronounce or to understand them to read
they always have Mandarin
transliteration of their name okay sushi
on the back label well this guy was very
clever so he he registered the Mandarin
transliterations years of lawsuits yeah
he he held the the name brand for it
he wanted to ransom of million euros
Castel said forget it
you know who is this two-bit traitor you
know holding us hostage you know we're
Castell
years of lawsuits they lost each time
they lost and they were ordered to pay
five million of the largest IP
settlements in China and it was read
this year they managed to get it reduced
but it's still a still a big a big fine
they did he did the same thing to
pencils and then food although big oh
sorry Peck shouldn't same kind of regard
State Treasury wanted states they won
just earlier this year
okay alibaba's B Bayside everybody knows
it is it's a real problem for the wine
business it's where you go if you want
to buy empty bottles fake bottles fake
wine it's a it's a real problem
apparently recently I know this summer
they've said that they have a new system
in place and I've heard from Italian
wine makers that they have had good
results with with Alibaba pulling down
the sights of counterfeiters but I've
also heard from other regions that
Alibaba was not very responsive so I
won't put it up there so the way forward
make it complicated menus Bordeaux is an
example because they've really been the
leaders in dealing with this issue
there's a lot of low tech options that
they use so they work with customs and
bring customs officials here to train
them
they go to China and and train them as
well
they have investigators and recover
investigators so since 2010
they've taken 3100 samples in 27 cities
and all over the country and they had
1600 suspicious suspicious bottles so
it's pretty that's pretty good that's
pretty good and the it's the wine some
wine council that's doing this this is
called the CI baby and it's that really
their job I mean they've had they've
they've been given this job but it's not
what they were doing before they didn't
have any didn't have a lot of experience
in it because they've never had to deal
with such a big big problem but it's
given ideas since 2004 they've launched
240 lawsuits in 28 countries and I wrote
down Naga Valley there because poor Napa
Valley has not had such good luck
now the valley if you drive through
penglai in eastern on the eastern coast
of China in a wine growing region there
the scene is big science on the freeway
napa valley and it's all you know it's
registered napa valley can't do anything
about it
it's they've tried they've tried to
reason with the local government and
it's not they're not gonna get anywhere
that same local government in the in
here leaders of this of this battle met
with a representative bordeaux wine
council and could understand why they
couldn't call penglai the bordeaux of
china they could understand why they
couldn't use the word bordeaux in their
in their own publicity in their own
region they did not have notion of a
geographic indication that was the
biggest thing okay so one of the most
important things that that wine trade
has done or now is done is it got their
geographic indication recognized in
China okay so now they have a legal
means pursuing counterfeiters or misuse
of the Bordeaux half
legends okay so here we are there's
there's Chinese customs destroying figs
so here these are the high tech options
that they're using and it's a
combination of all of these things I
don't think I'm sure you probably all
know these things I don't need to
explain it too much to be all nah okay
we're gonna go move we will go to bubble
tags actually to go to all of them just
I want to touch quickly on labels some
growers are using our special paper like
when when stocks are printed on it's
just a Samedi when you print currency so
they've special paper printed us special
printers that is very very difficult to
it's impossible to fake actually they're
doing all kinds of different things with
printing that hidden Holograms they have
the one letter on the name the wine name
will be slightly different for different
vintages or different wines from your
state they try anything they can to make
it as complicated
on the bottle itself you'll find
engraving nobody said like a number on
it and if you've really got the money
you can have a special mold made for
just for your bottles with the name
right in the glass okay but that's
that's you only see that at the very
very high end part of the market it's
very expensive
okay so these QR codes is sort of the
ground level you might say that's where
everything kind of starts and this is
more of a supply chain is it's a supply
chain security measure but it does not
authenticate the bottle okay let's see
so this is okay gs1 which is guys you
know just wanted to see how they for me
unfortunately of course you do well they
are I'm not promoting any of these these
companies these are one
to where you do a lot that with the wine
trade and that's why I mentioned it but
at least you can see how the the QR code
works it's obviously it's on the bottle
it's on the box it's on the pallet but
again it doesn't it doesn't mean that
what's in that bottle is authentic why
it just is track and trace okay yeah
okay the bubble tags these are what's
interesting
so these bubble the bubble formation so
it's like a little constellation is
random and unique each time okay at
first when they first came out everyone
thought they were ugly and put them at
the bottom of the bottle and then they
started wisen up and realizing that in
fact if you put it between the capsule
right between the caps on the bottle it
also becomes a tamper proof label right
if it's broken
you know the bottles been opened so
proof tag proof tag and attr are kind of
the big players in that in terms of the
wine business they all work within
different industries and you can see how
they've got the QR code too and it's
what we see more and more is each little
label uses multiple technologies okay a
good example is the crew blue schhwaff
it's important because it represents 30
million bottles of wine a year okay all
of their wines have to have this code
they have to have it and it started
originally not for it wasn't meant as a
security measure it was a way to
internally control the volume of wine
that each producer was labeling couche
law okay because they're there every
year they're allowed to they submit a
sample as for a certain volume of wine
and it's accorded it earns the label
cuckoo schwa okay
so they can't have thought they only
have a thousand thousand files like 1000
labels in mm but in turn in fact it's
ended up becoming really important
really really important really are this
looks like so it becomes a tamper-proof
label as well because once it's once
it's broken you know the models been
opened and it connects with the
smartphone's weight and so they also put
also gives them direct contact not not
direct comment there's a contact with
the consumer excuse where you scan it it
takes you right to their website where
you can put in the little code to see if
it's a real bottle right but it also -
right there you get to learn all about
the chateaus to learn all about the
wines so it's it's really important I
think to understand that the wine
business is also using this for
marketing so this is shuttle Margo this
is what they do as you can see there
little label you can see the little
little code and the edge number okay so
obviously each number is obviously the
alphanumeric code is unique to that ball
okay and as in most cases very few
people have all of the information at
the company it's all held privately
within the company and there's just not
even a handful of people who have access
to information
it's that closely guarded and in fact
when I talk to producers about working
with customs and sharing information
with customs customs organizations they
kind of laugh like no I don't think so I
think we'll keep that information very
very private this is one of the this is
what AT&T is doing with champagne and I
I think it's kind of interesting because
they you can see that they're using
different technology I'm going to go to
this holographic zappy which i think is
is pretty cool
so on one level you're dealing with
agents in the field okay you're doing
its supply chain management okay
security you're dealing the QR code
you're it's your marketing right as well
as as well as track and trace and the
holographic stamp is for forensic
expertise let's see that there it is
this is something new that they're doing
I think we'll see a lot more of this
kind of thing and basically they just
keep improving on the technology test
escribió send it to you I work with them
they have they work a lot with the the
wine business castel is one of their big
customers for though Bordeaux superior
so here's what castile is doing in China
so that same company that is dealing
with the brown squatter they this is
what this is their answer to China so
you scan it you put in your code you're
also giving them information obviously
opens up this its marketing
possibilities but it can also then it it
works with a smartphone but they decide
against an app because they felt like it
they could potentially lose customers
but it works with WeChat and China
because we Chad has a QR scanner in it
so people can actually use WeChat they
scan it it links directly to the
security site for castel they can take a
photo and send them send the photo of
the dodgy bottle to castile and it's
linked to Google Maps so if they get in
reports of enough suspicious bottles in
one area they sent in an investigator so
it's really been really really important
I think evolution and how they're using
this technology to track down Thanks so
obviously on these in these these tags
on these labels you can see some of the
technology you can't in the rest of it
you can't see they don't it's not all
obvious there's a need code in the
shimmer it's not a static hologram
that's something they started doing it
the consumer doesn't see everything but
they can't connect with it and they can
get the marketing information they can
get all kinds of it about the wine if it
interests them and this is appear the
things they do like these labels one
from competition by competition and
they're doing special ones that can't be
faked although again every time they say
they can't be faked the counterfeiters
usually figure out a way to start doing
something very similar so it's
constantly constantly evolving marketing
applications ok the NFC chip behind the
wine label that's been important
important evolution it's still very
costly so they're relatively few bottles
are going to be equipped with it but it
is interesting it is what's new and
including the capsule seal with these
little antennas and if you see if you've
broken the seal the antenna is it's able
to notify you that the bottle has been
opened ok which I think that's pretty
cool but again I imagine fairly
expensive but I think that's I think
that's pretty interesting here this is
the NFC this is a good example of it
that's being used in the in the wine
business and here's where they're
checking to see whether the capsule has
been whether it's been broken and then
we basically refilled is what they're
protecting against and that's it did I
do it in 30 minutes ok do you have
questions
yes yes it depends the NFC is because
you need this the smartphone is really
more for consumers but yeah people look
for retailers sales staff anyway anyone
along the supply chain could use it I'm
told that the RFID is used more for
professionals it needs a reader so
that's so it's not really meant for
somebody for consumers but the NFC is
definite but in general it depends what
country you're in but obviously in China
or the states most sales staff has got a
smartphone I assume at some level you
can put all the QR codes and other codes
on you have to you're absolutely right
none of it works if the consumers and
the buyers to retailers aren't don't
know what's going on they don't know
what it is obviously Bordeaux has a
really really active wine school that
trains hundreds proxy thousands of a
year in China alone professionals wine
trade professionals as well as consumers
they have advertising campaigns all over
the world but in certain markets they
have priority China's a big priority so
that's how they do it but they also
these literally out are on the ground
going and needy people talking to
people that all the big trade shows
constantly communicating about how to
authenticate a wines I think you were
saying it was there we love we're here
to say about somebody doing it hundred
thousand bottles of cheap - a little bit
less cheap versus a very high-end bottle
and look what is it well the first year
always worried about our health and
hygiene issues you're always worried
about someone putting something bad okay
luckily that happens very rarely in
Europe okay or the states it happens
more that happens actually more in the
hard liquor business okay in the wine
business not too often in China however
or another other difficult markets not
just China you can find all kinds of
things in there colorants nasty things
and that's usually when the Chinese
actually stepped in because they're very
very care something they're careful
about health and hygiene but they do
take that very very seriously as a crime
so you're much more likely to get
Chinese officials cracking down on
counterfeit ER if that counterfeiter is
putting bad things into the ball that's
what everybody always worries about the
most after that I think that it's it's
the it's actually the the volume the
valley encounter fairs because they're
attacking when they attack Bordeaux for
instance right or it could be a burgundy
or champagne whatever it is cognac
they're attacking the whole region right
and they're not only they effectively
taking a sail away from you but they're
if the consumer drinks that right and
it's it's bad
is that consumer gonna buy that your
product again a real product now so it's
really bad for for business is bad for
our reputation is bad for our brand and
Bordeaux is a 3.7 billion your business
okay it's between 600 and 700 million
bottles a year it's a big business with
lots of little growers about so
thousand growers 300 merchants it's kind
of peculiar business but it's supports a
lot of people and someone know someone
do still work there you know it's funny
when the first wine crime stories I
covers when I was a reporter for the
French News Service AFP and it was the
18 million bottles of faint Pinot Noir
and I arrived I told my editors like I
think I put her head down there's this
case going to trial I really think I
should be there and like okay fine so I
went down there and they're all these
French reporters around my in the
country grout when I was doing they're
like why is this American coming here to
cover the story me it's just just like
fake wine story what's the big deal and
of course it turned out to be this huge
story went all over the world it was
just an enormous story
but there is there is this sort of like
wink wink nod nod attitude a little bit
about I find that's just my personal
opinion it's not seriously here lies the
case signals it will be to be over
I mean how do we deal with all the
people creating all this case so you get
six URLs and say then you basically Gy
we label everything those same six label
life can be through every nursery in
China that one said here's your own
unique age every single bottle is unique
every label is valid if you look it up
on the table it says yet new wallpaper
thing even though it's gonna fit that
have another scoping game come here how
does this vary it there is the actual
art cases of where the counterfeiters
are created websites I'm sure the same I
know like this investigator that he
talked to me about going into label fact
label factories where their girl label
printers and they're right there
printing you know not just for wine but
for clothing the making labels of cats
what they do but they are printing the
the fakes as well for the fakes as well
as the legitimate factories it's right
there the same business so you're right
noticed an enormous problem I think that
I think is what Alan said actually it's
communication we have to just keep
communicating but the problem is on
places like you know tap out is if they
don't take down those sites when they're
identified and of course they just pop
up again under another name
right I mean it's it's relentless I
don't know if the wine industry these do
have sort of cyber detectives out there
working on this all the time
just they don't have to taste the wine
right part of the problem there is that
from a business culture perspective you
can't do trust but verify where China's
concerned it has to be all verify
because it's culturally acceptable to
substitute and screw and you know it's
perfectly buying for a factory running
off labels too as soon as the guy from
the legit customer leaves run off a
couple thousand extra for their other
customers well in the counter pairs
aren't just attacking international
brands they attack Chinese brands and a
lot of these Chinese brands are owned by
the government you know the the
counterfeiters attack them as well well
they get into trouble if there's a
health and hygiene issue yeah not too
much recently apparently they're
starting to crack down a little bit more
but no I mean there's so many stories
that the you know the running like a
bottling line on an abandoned chicken
farm or something and not a lot happens
to them no hungry you know it's pretty
me have to give another three years they
become equally silly as we are forget
around sort of wanting brands for the
sake of the brand rather than product no
I think that that's actually I think
that that's a really good point when
when China opened up just to give you an
example there was only a few thousand
bottles of Bordeaux going into to China
look what it is today okay it was just
it was just a huge rocks and and at that
time that the average annual income I
think was one hundred eighty seven
dollars yeah I mean there was no market
Noma had nothing absolutely nothing and
it's gonna take a little while but I
think that that's gonna really push the
Chinese government is it now they're
exporting wine okay
they want their wine protected here and
they want China
wanted to be something to be proud of
okay they want to stand for something
that means we're gonna have to be sure
that when we buy Chinese wine that it is
what it says on the label is what's in
the bottle right so I think that that's
what's going to raise the standards
[Music]
factory where they make the religious
stuff how do you determine you thinking
about you mean in France when it's
manufactured
[Music]
sambata that way okay in France its
heavily heavily regulated they have
these registers in everything you comes
in and out of that cellar any kind of
product is goes into these register and
they're audited regularly okay and
they're very these inspectors are really
good at following the trail how much
wine came in at one con and how much
we're not looking at false looking for
false paperwork they're very very good
so France is actually pretty good but
because of their ridiculous comedy
system and and paperwork they're
actually pretty good their countries
were that doesn't exist which yeah I'm
sure that there's a lot of creative
blending which was legal not that long
ago I mean we forget that but it was I
mean it why isn't uncommon in the in
their early 20th century to take wines
from warmer climates like North Africa
and blend it with French wines okay yeah
did make it a little fruity er okay that
wasn't illegal that wasn't illegal that
was common just ours our notion of
origin has changed
and it's become very very important to
protect our geographic indications I was
leaving one last thing a friend of my as
a historian I did put it up here because
because he hasn't published yet I just
didn't want to I didn't feel comfortable
posting it but he sent me my emails told
me what I was talking about he's his
great wine historian and he sent me a
recipe for a first group from the 1700s
and all the things that went into it
different wines to create this perfect
the perfect the it was a first grade
Bordeaux first growth but and this was a
very very respectable wine merchant so I
mean we are our notions of what fake
wine is has changed a lot okay yeah
questions I think we're
[Applause]