hello everyone I've met most of you
already so my name is Adria fortescu
I'm a pre sales consultant for Cody's
future and a cyber security professional
for 10 years now
and today I'm going to talk about
enabling anticipation by enhancing your
visibility over the cyber landscape so
it's basically understanding how you can
anticipate what's going to happen to
your business what are the capabilities
of threats against your business by
obtaining or disability over the
landscape that what happens in donetsk
so first of all I will start with some
conceptual ideas the concept behind the
use cases that I would use a bit later
on
so we over here cyber security
specialists right and our duty is to
solve security problems right
unfortunately and I've had this t-shirt
on the honest with you I haven't brought
it with me we usually are told to be
solving problems that the company
doesn't know about with methods that
nobody understands which I totally
disagree because we should never be
acting on tests and solving cyber
security problems is about defining and
achieving objectives on different levels
that are related to the business right
so it should be on a strategical level
like for example I need to identify the
threats that might impact or could
impact my business it might be on a
technical level enforce an aggressive
risk-based I don't know who nobility
patching system and also an operational
level like ensure that the users are not
leaking credentials or if they did what
happened with those and so on
so understanding all of these and
understanding that basically we need to
solve troubles that are related to the
business we transform this into being
the cyber security specialist that
actually solves problems that you as a
business knew about because it started
from there right and with the methods
that you should be understanding we
should be able as security specialists
or Italy all of these two different
departments in the business right
because all of the problems are actually
their problems we need to solve
okay so what are the actual usual mix of
things that end up helping us solving
problems in security and we all know
that it's a lot of mix of people
processes and technologies and you all
know the saying that if you think
technology will be solving your security
problems even on technology Lenovo
security right so it's a mix of all of
these we need people we need
technologies and we processes to run
those technologies properly when it
processes that are matching the business
the way the business runs right and all
of this and I think you can all agree
with me start getting enhancements once
they get visibility and for example
technology and antimatter if you take it
it gives it more effective if it gets
visibility on the system to be able to
understand what's happening on the
system and it also gets visibility on
the threats it has more signatures so
it's more powerful right it's enhanced
the same with the scene if you're
bringing logs from different places and
you have visibility you get to enhance
your your systems it's the same for
processes no process will ever be
efficient if it doesn't have visibility
in the things that is actually managing
as a process right and the same with
people of course we need basically have
good decisions and every day we are
making a lot of decisions I think is
like 13,000 decisions that we're making
every day and all of those are enhanced
I mean decisions like from taking one
step right and all of these are being
enhanced once we get visibility but what
is actually visibility about and
visibility is about getting access to
data information because that's what
brings visibility and all of these three
like people processes and technology
have advantages and disadvantages and
the fact that they are working together
that's the reason why they end up being
the thing that actually helps us solving
problems because for example technology
can be faster than humans right
but there are some humans that are not
replaceable because they know so much
about the business the technology cannot
replace them right also processes there
are a lot of processes
and a lot of methodologies that are
being developed to slow security
problems but the thing is there is no
one that fits everything so we need
people that understand the business in
order to define the proper processes and
to choose the right methodologies that
are suited for the business right so
unless we have a mix of these three we
will never be able to solve efficiently
problems and to enhance all of these of
course we need to bring date on top of
it but data also have advantages and
disadvantages it is available internally
externally there is a lot of data right
storage is very cheap so we can store it
once we prep it but it has the
disadvantage that is hard to collect
right because it's a lot of it so it's
quite hard to collect and also it's hard
to organize or to understand because as
I think most of you have worked with a
scheme before right you need to
interpret those logs you need to
normalize them you need to bring them at
the same level in order for the
technology or for the processor for the
people to understand that but data has
another advantage the fact that if it's
put back through the entire process if
the data goes back through people
processes and the technologies its beam
transport transformed into intelligence
and it's being transformed into the
insights and those are actually the ones
that end up improving each one of them
so you end up solving problems and
solving security problems with an
intelligence approach on top of that and
that's actually the reason why we end up
being on top of these lists and
transforming security from just the
basic approach or maybe the compliance
security because we were talking about
compliance and just checking the boxes
that doesn't solve problems okay all of
us tend to be as high as possible on
this graphic right so maybe we end up
being proactive but the best thing is to
be predictive to understand what are the
threats that have the capability
of impacting our business right and how
can we actually put all these things
together what is actually the potential
of a threat to impact my business and
this is a graph that actually defines
what is a threat for the business it's a
mix of the capability the opportunity
and the hostile intent the thing is that
my presentation today will not be
focusing on apts will not be focusing on
nation-states because it's hard to
identify the host time in that right
it's hard to find when somebody has a
hostile intent until you end up looking
at the big picture but I will talk about
the usual cybercrime the one that is
most prevalent in our landscape right
because it's very rare that we end up
being attacked by an APD but it's very
often that we get a text from everybody
else right so usually the hostile intent
is always over there if you have a
business that has some data that means
that once the deepa gets licked out the
attacker might be having some advantages
like making money out of it so all the
time the fact they can make money on
your business that's always a hostile
intent they want to make money right as
that cyber crime so we need to focus on
those other two we need to focus on the
capabilities that these threats have and
actually the opportunities that these
threats have against my business against
my infrastructure and we will see that
so first of all let's talk about
capabilities which kind of capabilities
should by should I be looking at which
kind of capabilities should I be getting
visibility more and I might be trying to
get capability of a specific relevant
actor because we all know we should
start with what already happened to me
so if somebody at some point interacted
attacked me definitely I should be
looking into the current capabilities of
that particular threat actor but the the
problem is here is that we should
actually look at the capability of any
threat act and to give you an example
imagine just a simple vulnerability
right the exploit is being popped
vulnerabilities being disclosed and
that's a capability that is available to
everybody any threat actor that wants to
make money and already has that
capability will be using it it all gets
back to the opportunity does he have an
opportunity to interact with your
business to attack you right so then if
it goes back to what is an actual
opportunity of a threat an opportunity
of a threat is basically whatever
defines you and I would I I wouldn't go
up to threat modeling I don't know how
many of you have ever done an exercise
of threat modeling but that's actually
measuring the opportunity that the
certain threat has against you okay
is what is your threat surface what are
the places that an attacker can actually
interact with you what is what are your
assets and what are your technologies
and we were talking over lunch the fact
that there were so many breaches in
which X filtration was done through
systems that were not even on the
inventory not even benched not even on
the inventory they didn't know about the
system it was a computer somewhere for
guts in a basement that nobody knew
about nobody was monitoring right and
that's an opportunity for the attacker
also we might be talking about specific
partners right maybe specific suppliers
because you have a weak chain in your
supply a weak link in your supply chain
that might be used and that might be an
opportunity for an attacker to email
okay and he can go even to operational
spaces specifics everybody's trying to
get banks and trying to exfiltrate money
and all that which is late they were
through Swift the reason why they're
matching managing to attack different
banks and to extract money is because
both all of them have some specific
operational aspects using that software
which can be exploitable right so
everything that goes into this area of
opportunity is everything that defines
you as
company is you'll be thinking if you're
defending yourself right I will be
caring about the people that I'm
interacting with the way I am the things
that I'm doing everyday in the way can
do that right so I need to understand
that I need to pay attention as a
business to everything that might be
considered an opportunity for the other
right so once I get visibility and I get
data about the attackers capabilities
and I understand what might be their
opportunities against me then I
understand the real potential of that
particular track and when I understand
the potential of that threat I need to
adapt because otherwise while the intent
is always over there to make money I
will be having the real threat targeting
so there is a saying that I love and
it's really directly connected to this
adapting stuff the fact that if the rate
of change on the outsides exceeds the
rate of change on the inside of your
company then the end is near and this is
by Jack Walsh a former G CEO so if I'm
not able to match the rate of change of
the threats that are on the outside most
definitely that will be in the end of my
business I need to understand them I
need to understand their capabilities I
need to understand their cup up is
against the opportunities that I might
be presenting to them right so I can
adapt I can adapt my infrastructure I
can adapt the way I'm doing things or I
can adapt I don't know even my controls
right it's not just about checking boxes
and compliance it's about checking the
boxes against the threats that are
actually relevant for me right so that
being let's say the conceptual part of
my presentation the fact that visibility
allows you to understand better the
capabilities and the opportunities and
the intent of a certain threat you might
be able to define if that threat is
really relevant for you and to
anticipate what you do in to adapt so I
will be applying that to
three use eases right and starting with
the most simple things direct mentions
related to the threat service and the
easiest and the most simple thing
related to the threat surface are leaked
potentials right and as you've seen in
earlier in the presentations even the
highest level a PT's they are running
spearfishing they are running fishing to
get some credentials and why are
potentials so important is because they
are turning an external threat into an
internal one right so they are jumping
it's the letter over the fence the
letter over the wall right and you've
heard what happens whenever it's an
internal threat nobody cares about it
nobody looks at it and usually
monitoring on internal system is not at
the highest level as it's on the
parameter right so what you're seeing
right now is actually distribution of
the last two months of leaked
credentials documents containing liquid
n shows on paste sites underground
forums and dark web and special access
and it's just two months every dot is
another document with leak credentials
right so as you can see out there there
are a lot of liquid oceans so once you
get visibility on these things that they
are out there right and you get access
to this data you can understand if
you're providing an opportunity for
somebody because your credentials are in
those lists so you can identify the
capabilities that they might be having
and the opportunity they might be having
but also this can also enhance your
defenses because I don't know I've
haven't heard about this and I actually
am building this on my own I have a big
database of no no passwords and hashes
that I shouldn't be using just because I
have visibility to the data if the
attackers in there are a lot of DDoS
tools or brute force tools against
systems of bodies that are actually
using these open available credentials
so once in my company I get visibility
on that why not close the opportunity of
the attackers that are using that as a
capability right by making sure that my
internal passwords and hashes are not
mentioned so once I get visibility in
that landscape I can start influencing
and adapting so I can minimize their
capabilities and of course be able to
cover the opportunities that they may be
have and this is just an example of the
things related to the tread surface
because it's a login
other things might be for example this
one it's a list of emails with a clear
title may list for spend by this
protector so immediately understand the
intent if I'm on that list
oh that straight actor has an intent
against me right and more than that
because I have the data about the name I
can start investigating a lot of
capabilities so I can see if against my
oh my do opportunities that I'm
presenting that's a real threat right
also I need to understand that threat
surface means everything that defines me
getting back to the opportunities file
it can be anything like domains it can
be IPS it can be systems with operating
systems and ports opens everything that
is a port open the world is an
opportunity for an attacker to target
right so out of this first use case is
understanding and getting visibility on
that that is related directly to my
threat surface and understanding their
capabilities I can start at that and I
can start closing the opportunities for
the attackers just by looking over data
that is related to my threat surface the
second use case is risk based
vulnerability patching program would be
would be visibility and having access to
data that is available right be
enhancing my approach in that and I
would say yes first of all this is just
a simple timeline of all over
vulnerability and exploit against the
vulnerability yeah so we have the disk
our
three of the vulnerability which might
happen somewhere in the underground
right and we might be having an exploit
of that it's I noted as an exploit of
Technology because there is no CV there
is no definition of the vulnerability in
that moment is just an exploit against
the technology also we have the
disclosure time and then then we have
the actual exploit of the vulnerability
after the disclosure and of course then
scanner is being built model being
builds vulnerability being added to this
exploit kits and so on so it would be
wonderful if I would be able to perform
some mitigation actions because I have
visibility at this point right if I know
how they are exploiting the technology
and I know that I'm using that
technology so it's an opportunity for
them I can start adapting maybe my I
don't know my infrastructure the way
things are communicating so I can close
that opportunity or of course if the
vulnerability has always already been
disclosed I can start by getting
visibility to prioritize things right
which one is actually being exploited in
the wild so I know which one to touch
first like because I can close their
capability right so the idea is that
once I get visibility and this is
actually a timeline of the SMB
vulnerability that started eternal blue
and then wanna cry okay
so this is what on the lower part you're
seeing events about the disclosure on
the higher part of the screen you're
seeing events against the technology and
we have and basically this is time zero
this is the moment when the
vulnerability was disclosed right so
everything that happened before the
pattern of how how visible it is but we
have smb3 connect zero they PLC we have
the exploit of zero day vulnerability in
SMB protocol is published so available
data visibility available right load
library of of library over SMB
determined or his version the SMB all of
that our capabilities of actors against
this technology if I have this
technology which also is an opportunity
that's a potential threat so if I
understand and I have this ability over
this I can easily start adapting right
and also the same thing happens on the
right side of the timeline right because
I have I have here the vulnerability
being disclosed and I have the moment
when the exploit was actually published
which was eternal blue after that things
started getting crazy right so if I have
the vulnerability I also have the
patching if I have this visibility I can
start understanding that this is really
important and I should be patching that
with a priority because otherwise I
might be getting hit right so couple of
examples of what happens afterwards
people started publishing on github for
example PLC's everything you see is
Python scripts PLC's on how to run
eternal blue how to exploit Windows 10
how to exploit Windows 2012 different
PLC's
so that's the clear capability and of
course after that it started fire less
ransomware uux to a pentia wanna cry and
a lot of others ending up with people
running services of delivering malware
based on that vulnerability so it's an
entire ecosystem and I think Alan will
be talking a bit more about the
ecosystem behind that afterwards but the
idea is that once you get visibility as
soon as possible on this exploitation
timeline you can understand how to adapt
or how to prioritize your pension right
and the last example that I had was I'm
always getting this question should I be
given what happens to others it hadn't
happened to me is visibility over what
happens to others relevant to me is it
increasing my chances of solving
security problems and the answer is
definitely yes and I'll show you why so
this is an example of
Tector called the dark overlords I don't
know how many of you have heard of it of
him oh it's a team actually it's
supposed to be a team initially was
thought it's just one guy but seems to
be more than one and the time line on
the top shows things that he published
the time line above shows things that
were published about him and his actions
right so if we're looking on that we can
see that I don't know mid-2016
this guy was into breaching health care
companies in us like very heavily
breaching them in publishing and selling
databases of patients personal
identification information and more than
that he was also disclosing the way he
was doing that so we have things like
from a severely misconfigured network
using readily available plaintext
usernames and passwords and that's two
cases and that's actually three cases
and also RDP without any kind of like
default credentials like admin admin so
it's not very high level of course he
used some zero days as well so he's
quite big in the business but the idea
is that sometimes the opportunity that
is presented to the threat actor is
something that cannot be missed and it
ends up being like that so he did a lot
of things in the healthcare and of
course if you were a healthcare company
you would care about that because it
happened to others but at some point
after sometime late 2016 this guy
started reaching others with probably
the same capabilities just because the
intent was the same making some money
and it was presented with a new
opportunity making more money because
there are more money into the finance
industry right
so he started hacking finance industry
and the first one was Westport Capital
Bank and what I want to emphasize here
is that this Bank had a lot of customers
the problem
is that all of those customers were
immediately offended so they needed to
adapt if they wouldn't know about that
and believe me there are some like
Pegram reputation investigations that
were holded by that bank and different
other very powerful documents that were
hauled by that bank that was breached
unless you are you're you get visibility
over this you don't know how to adapt
yeah
and further on this guy started
attacking media companies so if you
understand that he is like actually
switching depending on the opportunity
and the intent is all always over there
just wants to make money you should be
knowing about this guy and it actually
happens that first of all he hacked
Larson studios which was a cub
post-production company which was a
partner I was our supplier for companies
like ABC or Netflix so after some time
because he breached one of their
suppliers let's say of services and they
didn't adapt it on that they ended up
some month later like in the mid 2017
being extorted because this guy wanted
to lick some things that he's told from
the previous bridge right and you know
what happened they leaked some some some
movies and but the idea is that once you
get visibility and you get access to
data that is available right you can
understand things that might be
happening to you right because you
understand the opportunities that you're
presenting and the opportunities
sometimes are presented through the
partners and through the customers that
you have through the entire supply chain
what even is just an opportunity that
manifested itself somewhere to in some
other company that was never in your
landscape but the fact that you might be
affected by the same thing
makes it important for you so if it
happened it might be happening to you
because you have the same opportunity
presented against the attack so that
being told oh I remember I have another
one this is quite funny the reason why I
put it here is because it's so so
obvious so this is a both bank duty this
is early March let's a needle March and
this is early April end of March one
bank suffering SMS fishing camps this
was like announced the campaign was
public people reported it on Twitter
this is like fishing over SMS right not
more than two weeks afterwards customers
from another Bank from UK one of them
actually got lost 23 K from the same
scheme so if this bank would just have
had disability over this particular
event that happened like two weeks
before that he would actually started a
campaign and they could have added it in
order for that not to be happening to
their customers right so it is important
to get visibility and just as a
conclusion to this I think that while we
have a pyramid of pain we should also be
having a pyramid of interest and that
pyramid of interest should be covering
everything from your threat surface your
technologies your assets subsidiaries
partners peers and you should be
interested about what happening in the
global landscape because you don't know
maybe somebody has a capability against
your opportunities that are your
presenting that transforms something
that is a global threat into a threat
that might be impacting you and for that
of course you need data and you need
let's say relevant data and you need
means in order to get it and to make it
understandable so you need the broad
visibility you need relevance in time
because you need to find out about those
things as early as possible
the equation chain as soon as they
happens to others and of course we need
to understand that we need to have a mix
of technologies humans and processes
with data on top of it in order to make
things happen and to be able to solve
those security problems that we were
talking about at the beginning
so thank you very much that was all for
me so if you have any questions I'll be
more than pleased as now if not thank
you very much for your time
[Applause]