you can't hear me be sure to a gesture
or yell or something so I can make sure
to try speak louder obviously it's not
gonna really help if you can't actually
hear what I'm saying well good morning
everybody
hope you're not too hungover my name is
Phoenix Snoke and the talk that I'm
doing today is called don't panic it's a
beginner's guide to hardware hacking the
way I tried to set this up is that if
you have very little to no experience
you should be able to follow the
instructions I'm providing and get a
result as a result of that I made it
very slide heavy so they're going to be
written parts there maybe you'd like
copy of the slides I'm gonna include my
contact info at the beginning and end of
this talk so that you can get them no
pressure Rob and anyhow I'm apparently
supposed to give a bio or talk about
myself so that you know who I am which
seems little narcissistic but uh I've
spoken here twice previously with my
lovely talented wife this is the first
time that I've spoken by myself so you
know be gentle anyhow we've also spoken
at derbycon
sky con and some few b-sides up and down
the countryside I've got a two-year-old
and I make questionable life choices
other than that I'm very very normal I'm
going to include my email on here I
don't really do social media so that's
just the easiest way to get a hold of me
if you have any questions or comments or
like one copy of the slides or anything
feel free send them to me again since I
have a two-year-old I don't always have
as much free time as I would like to
think I do but I do make a point of
checking things and if you know I'll
make a point of getting back to you so
here we go pop quiz based on stock
photos what is the appropriate way to
hold a soldering iron safely yes if this
is any sort of indication you should
never take any sort of safety guidance
based on stock photos I was kind of
surprised I couldn't find one of
somebody picking their nose with one but
yeah their safety stuff is apparently
not a consideration and fake fake
photography that is what it is there's
my contact information it's Phoenix and
insecure devices comm and so about how
this talk is organized first parts going
to be why you should think this is
interesting I'm gonna spoiler it so you
don't leave the room
hardware vulnerabilities are really
really cool the other thing about it is
that there aren't a lot of ways to
really mitigate against them in the
first place however if a device goes out
with hardware vulnerabilities that
vulnerability will be there for the
lifetime of the device they aren't going
to send a technician to your house with
a pair of scissors to cut off a uart
port or something like that it's there
additionally we're going to talk about J
UART which is going to be a majority of
this talk sent this geared towards a
beginner level we're going to talk about
J tag I'm gonna try to briefly touch
upon SPI and i2c if we have time both of
them are really outside the scope of
this SPI is really really cool but it's
not really anything I would consider a
basic or beginner level techniques and
ITC really doesn't have a lot of info
SEC specific uses although it's really
cool too but it's more like if you're
trying to make your own devices to do
things and I do have a video
demonstration of actually breaching a
device that I'm gonna do a show here I
apologize in advance I had to do it into
two parts because I'm not very good
about editing videos which is not what
I'm talking about so I hope that's
alright so here's the AR T this device
was a baby monitor that we used for IOT
testing years ago reason I included it
is because it's a nice large beautiful
picture and because the helpful Factory
in China silk-screened the port which
made it very easy to locate
additionally there's some visual
indicators to tell me kind of which pin
is which I've got a better picture that
I'm gonna use it a little bit there but
we're going to just tell you you know
tell you what they are and how we mess
with this first thing about UART is it's
not a protocol so people will confuse
this one a lot of people will call them
either rs-232 S or rs-422 S 232 s are
your old serial ports that I'm sure
you're all familiar with they're not
really wrong per se but they're not
really right either a UART is simply a
physical circuit it's only there to get
information from point A to point B
there can be it but like in terms of the
people are calling them that it would be
like calling any sort of copper cabling
in a Comcast modem there is a copper
wire component of it however that is not
the device in and of itself
there's going to be three to six pins
usually we're going to only need three
the rest of it we can ignore now on
these security is not any sort of
consideration and this is the part where
we're all supposed to act surprised but
if you look at any sort of industries
writings about this about securing them
they'll actually be talking about
securing it so that they make sure the
signal goes from point A to point B so
you actually if you look at any industry
stuff about securing it
they'll they're talking about changing
baud rates or turning parity on on or
off
they there's nothing about actually
securing the signal it's just from
getting it where it's supposed to go the
other thing about this that I really
like to emphasize is that when you
locate the power or VCC pretend it is a
dangerous snake and you know how we'll
say that you should be you know it's
afraid of you as you are a bit know you
should be more afraid of this I don't
want you to break anything or you know
shock yourself and get it send me hate
mail so the part we care about is how do
we break it what we're going to want to
do is we're going to want to connect
these pins to a device that was a USB to
TTL cable there are a variety of flavors
of these I would recommend against
getting a PL 2303 the company itself
please don't sue me they seem like they
do a fine enough job but there are a lot
of counterfeit versions of this device
on the market and so you could buy one
and it just wouldn't work out of the box
for something that you're just starting
out on you wouldn't necessarily know the
tool wasn't working additionally in
order to try to make this accessible I
was trying to come up with the lowest
cost way to do everything and telling
you to buy something doesn't work really
kind of goes against that purpose the
one I would recommend is some flavor of
FTDI that's the name of the company it's
future technology something but they
have a series of these they're 23 I'm
sorry
23 two blanks there's gonna have like a
RQ and s they have a six wire and four
wire versions the six wire versions can
do a few more things if your start
getting into our way knows the price of
them are about the same as the four wire
version so I would just recommend
getting that sense you even do more
things with the tool and it's the same
price additionally there's going to be a
dip switch on them a lot of them will
have a different three or five
you're going to make sure you have it on
the correct voltage a lot of logic is
almost always going to be on 3.3 you can
in theory build your own with Arduino
most Arduinos are set at 5 volts though
so you might have to do some sort of
level shifting anyway it you can a lot
of this is trivial if you have access to
an oscilloscope or a logic probe you
really don't need to do any of this
however if you can read an oscilloscope
already you probably already know
everything they say in this talk because
you know how to do Hardware work
additionally you're just going to use a
multimeter that's what I use the tech
probes on these if you're going to ug
JTAG enumeration obviously gets a little
more advanced but we're just messing
with you arrow keys right now can you
all hear me okay I feel like I'm alright
awesome now there are visual indicators
that you can use to help narrow down
where you're looking grounds will
sometimes show if you shine a bright
light on Durham I'll show you in the
next picture but they're usually be a
pad that will basically be a cross on it
you can look for it like a large chunk
of solder or a metal pad that they'll
actually have under it additionally the
traces the lines that go out from the
ports the wide ones are going to be your
power the thinner ones are usually going
to be your transmit and receive have a
beautiful example here this is actually
the device I used for the video demo off
to the left there those are the JTAG
pins but the ones that we're concerned
about are on the right there I can tell
you from looking at them which ones are
which the two with the thin lines
they're off to the right
those are your transmit and receives the
one with the pad is the grep is going to
be your power here I'm going to stand in
front of this sorry I don't have a laser
pointer or anything that's going to be
your power there's the cross pattern I
was talking about that's your ground
there's your transmit and receive
visually you aren't going to be able to
tell your transmitted and receives a
part but that's not that big a deal in
the scheme of things we have other ways
to do that so in order to find the uart
port or to verify that you have found it
successfully you want to take your
multimeter and you want to change it to
your a continuity setting continuity is
going to be one of those two symbols
what
happen is when you successfully meet
make continuity the device will be if
you want to know what I'm talking about
you can take the probes and touch them
together it's the same thing this does
not work at the devices powered on at
all so what you're going to want to do
it doesn't matter what order you use the
probes on you're going to touch the
ground and then touch it to another
grounded point if there's an intent on
the device they usually attach a ground
to that but there's going to be like a
large a large piece of solder usually or
a pad of some sort again when you hit
the when you hear the beep you've won
now in terms of the power when you start
to device up and probe the pin it's
going to go to 3 3 5 volts whatever the
the power setting is and it's gonna stay
there once you've identified it again
you know remember the white races if
we're looking for it but once you've
identified it just just ignore it we
don't need a fright thing we're going to
do and it it is one of the few things
that can damage your equipment so that's
why I'm trying to you know stress that
this is something we just don't want to
mess with so for finding the transmit
during the boot sequence is the easiest
way to do that what you'll do is you'll
probe the pin it should start around the
same level as the device itself but
it'll drop off a little bit and it'll
remain very active it's going to go up
and down a lot you can look for the thin
traces to try to narrow down where
you're looking for the receive in a lot
of cases we can just simply say that's
the one that you know we've narrowed it
we've found all the others that's the
one that's left over you know
congratulations again you can look for
that thin trace if you're trying to
visually you know narrow down where to
search for usually though it'll start at
about the same voltage has the device
itself but then it'll drop dramatically
there are exceptions to this if you have
a device like a router or something like
that that is constantly trying to
receive it is going to be very very hard
to tell you're receiving your transmit
apart because they're both very active
and they're both high level the good
thing though is that you can guess you
can hook it up to your USB to TTL you
run everything you'll usually get a
result it'll be a bunch of a garbage
it's going to be just random ASCII
characters you can swap it out at that
point then it works correctly the but
it's not going to harm anything if you
Pro if you plug them in backwards it's
not going to harm anything the one thing
we really want to remember is that you
know you're transmitting your devices
your talk your receive as you're
listening the you have a transmit and
receive on your computer that you're
attaching this to you want to make sure
to reverse the lines you don't want to
attach talk to talk and listen to listen
they won't be able to communicate
correctly now there are some other UART
pens there's our CTS DTR they don't
factor into anything that we're gonna do
so we don't really care about them
additionally they're gonna depending
what how sincere your multimeter is
they're gonna probably read fairly close
to zero most of the time anyway so I
mean they'll they'll stand out as being
weird simply because there'll be a lack
of activity on them and they won't set
off any sort continuity but in general
most of the things I find are either
gonna have three or four pens
three will be the the bare minimums MIT
or receiving a ground but sometimes the
power ones there too so when you want to
use a terminal program I use many come
all the time because that's just what
I'm used to be working with you can use
screen or other ones it doesn't really
matter you're going to want to set up
odd eleven five twenty is usually a good
first guess most devices then last
several years are set for that so I mean
it's it's extremely common so it's it's
not a bad guest because you're gonna be
out right more often than not
additionally you can write scripts there
if you do anything with like PI serial
or anything like that you can write
scripts to go through and check at each
level so you can see that you're
actually getting good information if
you're wrong a lot of times you'll get
it's just going to be random strings of
ASCII characters whereas once you
actually set it correctly you'll start
seeing you know press Enter you know
you'll you'll get text that's that's
human readable again we remember that we
want to put those wires in the correct
place that we're going to want to swap
you know transmit to receive and vice
versa now for troubleshooting
oh my goodness that's too small to
really say sorry if you get a lot of
output that it's going to be like a
diamond symbol with a inverse question
mark on it a lot of times that indicates
that the ground is not grounded that you
that you've soldered there so I would
double check that you can check the pin
the end of the pin that you've soldered
and check that for continuity it still
works
again you would want to make sure the
device is powered off same thing with
your transmits and receives maybe you
saw it or something
sometimes the pins are already attached
but you usually are gonna have to attach
them yourself but if you want to make
sure that the pins are done correctly
you can test the end of the pin that
works just like the just like the port
itself but I would check that I would
check through your transmit and receive
yeah swap them out see if that see if
that works then you can check your bod
rate very very rarely I've seen again
specifically with the question mark
error some devices will want you to
enable Hardware flow control which I
made a note of that because it's not
really that common in you don't mess
around with a lot of this you wouldn't
necessarily be able to figure it out it
and you know I don't want to frustrate
people so I'm going to show my demo
video here again I apologize for it you
should stop I apologize for it being a
little badly done but again I don't
really do videos I'm not John Waters but
this is me attaching the device itself I
[Music]
went ahead and I actually attached the
pins because I filmed it and it just
ended up being about two minutes of the
back of my hand I figured nobody wanted
to see that so there's our pins that
we've set I'm testing and with the
multimeter
you'll hear it beep here in a second as
you can tell I've said before continuity
there I'm checking the other ones for
continuity just for the sake and
completely completeness on this spoiler
alert they don't feet because they're
not the ground anyhow I'm thinkin oh
I'll plug in the device and show how I'm
trying to find the transmit and receive
the problem with this it's a router so
it's constantly trying to receive
information so I did end up happening a
guest for the transmit and receive on it
I happen to guess right on this I was
just going off the one that went lowest
but yes here check the ground to the
active cables when the device is powered
I had no idea that wouldn't actually
stop there sorry guys say three one the
device itself runs at three three so but
you got our you got your a boot sequence
where it's going up and down from where
it's transmitting information and that's
how we verified that you've done that
correctly you can just put pins on there
I usually like to run wires to it
because it just makes it easier now the
other video I have of this I did it's a
screen from inside Callie this is on the
other end once I did that I attached
those wires to a USB to TTL cable and
this is how you know the terminal work
on the other end because I think you'll
find this really interesting
oh that says Oh fine
I think about as big as I can make it if
you really want to see this I can send
you a copy of it just shoot me an email
but um
basically this is me going into mini-com
then plugging the device in so that it
powers up at this point it's going to
start going through the boot sequence we
have human readable information here or
it would be human readable if it was
large enough where you'd actually see it
I'm sorry but we're gonna let it do its
thing here sometimes you want to
interrupt them but for the first time I
would just let it run all the way
through you might be pleasantly
surprised what you end up getting you'll
also get information sometimes it'll
tell you information about like I in the
case we're out or sometimes they'll
actually get network information based
on the boot up sequence hit enter to
continue okay I hit enter busy box which
is I busy box is a Linux package for
you'll see it a lot in IOT and embedded
devices if you look that I do echo user
I'm Roo I got shell on the device I
didn't do any any heart Ivy didn't do
any thought we're hacking whatsoever I
just went through the hardware
I now have complete control on the
device overall the process took me
including the soldering in about ten
minutes
that's why soldering and opening up the
case and taking it apart so you can see
why this is a really good thing to know
how to do the other thing I want to say
about this is if you want to if you want
to get a device just for the purposes of
messing with it I would go for a router
there is a very large community of
people that do custom firmwares on
routers so you can find a lot of
hardware information because of that the
thing is a lot of them are doing
over-the-air updates but there are
occasionally people that do JTAG stuff
for with them and so dependent what it
is if you're wanting again a JTAG depend
look up their forums of these and
they'll actually tell you we're all
dependent simon's are at everything you
don't have to actually do any work other
than confirming that what ran to people
on the internet it's telling you is
correct I mean I wouldn't just assume it
oh that doesn't say pal
on the Internet everybody's telling the
truth now about the rest of this here
we're going to go and touch up on JTAG
here now JTAG Mikey IRT is not a
protocol in and of itself is named after
a trade group called the joint test
action group they're not superheroes
they're not going to come to your house
and beat you up if you're doing bad
things
Jay tags are a lot more cool than UART s
however they are a lot more work and you
can't just use a multimeter to find the
appropriate ports you're gonna have to
actually use advice to do it they're
really really awesome things about Jay
tags is that you can do stuff like you
can write to the memory you can expect
the memory you can dump the info to ID
up I mean I'm sure you know you all are
starting to see where this has the you
know capabilities of doing some really
really awesome things additionally
though since you can do awesome things
you're going to want to be very careful
about what you do
surprisingly enough all these really
awesome security braking features
weren't meant to be there initially they
were stapled on after the fact because I
guess a vendor decided that they wanted
to have you know easily exploit a cross
cross-organizational remote
administration capabilities but you can
if you're going to want to do something
like dumper dumping firmware or
modifying firmware JTAG or SP eyes are
usually the way you're going to want to
go on that so how do we break it yes
unfortunately it's a bit more complex
than UART stuff I would recommend though
if you want to start out start out with
you a artis again like if you follow
those instructions you should be able to
get a result depending the device you
can get shell and get out you've won so
on this though you're going to FTDI or a
dongle program or jumper wires to
Raspberry Pi bus pirates would be that
what I would recommend if somebody said
hey I don't know what I need to get I
would say a bus pirate bus pirates new
communications with a lot of devices
they'll also do SPI and i2c if you start
messing with that there are expensive
tools
that will do things like dump firmware
significantly faster like shakarez and
some other specialized hardware they
start getting a lot more expensive
though bus pirates are usually around
like 35 bucks
now if the chips are not running at 3-3
you might have to do some level you know
some level shifting there the really
really awesome thing is if they have
both connectors like the picture I
showed you you can connect to both at
the same time and so if you're doing
something this is really useful because
a lot of devices if you're doing really
weird JTAG stuff you can set the devices
to you'll make the device reset if you
have a you are a plug-in and you can
watch the monitor and see what's going
on while you're doing doing the work in
real time so you can see if you're
tripping resets on the device or
anything like that
additionally since you can set
breakpoints
you can you know see what you're doing
it's it the you've got instant feedback
it's awesome in terms of identifying
which de-tag pin is which there are card
to like devices they're basically they
look look very similar to like some of
your raspberry pi type stuff but there's
a JTAG Noom which will go through an
arduino and then jtagulator again if
you're using an arduino to connect to
this stuff you want to make sure that
it's the same level as the device since
a lot of our tomatoes are 5 and a lot of
your logical circuits are 3-3 honestly
though the easiest way is in a lot of
cases you can find documentation if you
look around that will tell you what the
what the ports are unfortunately since
JTAG is not a standard i sometimes
there'll be 12 ports sometimes they'll
be 20 it's it's really random and it's
it's just different vendors do different
things different vendors do different
things based on the devices I was going
to do JTAG enumeration on that modem for
this just in case we had enough time but
the JTAG on that heart they actually
managed to mitigate hardware attacks on
the JTAG they did that by not including
any of the chips to make the JTAG work
which is a really weird design choice
based on that manufacturer i'm not
really sure why they put a port there in
the first place it's a dead port the
it should connect to is not on the board
if you surface-mount the appropriate
chips on there though it works so they
put a working channel but no actual
hardware for it to connect to which is
strange I don't know why they bothered
in the first place I'm assuming that
they must reuse the boards for like
maybe other other products and that they
the other products have the chips
because it just seems weird since it
would cost more to put a candle on there
and you know the channels it's not
connected to anywhere it's bizarre now
in SP eyes SP eyes can also do a lot of
really really awesome stuff it starts it
starts getting outside of the scope of
what you don't want to talk to you for
inter a talk you can use a bus pirate to
communicate with SP eyes additionally
instead of soldering they make a thing
called an SOI see pin it's a looks like
an alligator clamp and you basically
just stick it on the parts finding the
proper ports on SBI chips is really
really easy because if you look at the
chip there's usually the manufacturer
name and the number on it and then you
can look for datasheet like that so like
the router in question i use for the
demo this is the datasheet for that
there's going to be a dot on a lot of
them when it's just a chip you know tell
you which which ones pin one but it
tells us what all the pins are since
that's from the manufacturer itself it's
probably accurate but again it's also
showing they have a similar thing a JTAG
where it's not really a standardized
process so i mean has you could tell
those are all versions of the same chip
now i2c is the first thing out of all
this that actually is a honest good
protocol everything else is sort of a
de-facto one the cool thing about i2c is
that you have multiple devices speak on
the same bus and you can have multiple
identical devices speak on the same bus
this doesn't really have a lot of
security considerations the only that
can really think of is that you can
actually transmit through i2c like off
the board itself it's extremely slow
though and you can use bus pirates so
that to communicate with these they do
also make
usb2 I to see adapters so you can find
the port on the board and just solder an
adapter and then remove it when you're
done so anyhow I've gone 25 minutes
exactly here so I'm really glad that I
had time to share all this with you
here's my contact information again
unfortunately I don't really have any
time for questions but I'll hang out in
the hall for a few minutes if you have
anything you want to ask me and again I
do try to be Quito reachable so I really
appreciate everyone showing up this
morning I know it probably wasn't easy
based on last night so thank you very
much everybody
[Applause]