I can move a few things along by talking
about this now while we do this
basically I do end up doing a review of
modulo math because a lot when I've
talked to people about it saying you
know this is the basis of cryptography
and they're kind of like yeah I remember
anything that I think you do it in like
the sixth grade where you have remainder
like you do like 27 divided by 6 is for
remainders 3 and at the time I remember
doing that and I think it was about the
sixth grade and I was like why would
this ever be useful for anything and and
I went to Boston University to get my
master's in computer science and I went
oh my entire cryptography course was an
intensely deep study of modulo because
that's what all the cryptographic
algorithms are based on they're based on
the fact that if you say 27 27 mod six
which is basically 27 divided by 6 that
whatever the remainder is from that the
remainder is 3 but then if you say 33
mod 6 you also get remainder 3 so if
somebody says I have a number guess my
number if you do mod 6 you'll get 3 you
can't know for sure what its gonna be
because it could be any number of
numbers right number 3 so imagine that
you have these huge huge numbers with
hundreds of digits is it gonna open
let's get a lot of pitches in it pretty
pictures so if you have these huge
numbers and oh there is PowerPoint yes
and then you know all you know is what
the remainder is at the end of doing
some operation with these numbers it's
impossible to know what the starting
number was and that's the basis of
diffie-hellman RSA and also elliptic
curve cryptography so I just saved about
thinking very hard thank you here it
comes
it has a unicorn in it my presentation I
thought it'd be nice to have a unicorn
on Sunday morning oh it's go be serious
the magical this is actually the title
of my presentation is the magical world
of elliptic curve cryptography but I
didn't want to do that in the submission
to no laconic because I was afraid
they'd think I was like crazy or that it
would be all about like you know the
relationship between My Little Pony and
cryptography thank you yes so excuse me
to flip the slides I just tap thank you
okay all right so here we are my name is
Michelle Bousquet
a little bit about me um this is some
things about me I am from New Orleans
which means I have a lot of wigs and
hats and tutus and I also do some
theater and I like to put on an orange
wig sometimes and pretend to be a
Russian hacker and videotape things and
anyway I'll give you my website at the
end if you wanna have a look at that
anyway um when I got my master's in
computer science as I was saying for bu
I had to take a cryptography course and
it was pretty intense but I really did
enjoy it because I'm a math geek but
then when I was trying to explain the
joys of cryptography to other people I
found that they didn't get it so
I wanted to come up with a simple
explanation of elliptic curve
cryptography so that if you're an
engineer or you're even just someone
who's involved in the industry and one
of your customers says to you well what
is that actually you can have a sort of
intelligent answer to give them without
having to spend 17 weeks deeply immersed
in math in a cryptography a graduate
level cryptography course so just a
really basic thing cryptography and
computing is used to transmit sensitive
information probably I don't think
there's anybody here that doesn't know
this but basically on any kind of device
that's going to transmit information
particularly wirelessly you want to be
able to encrypt it before sending it off
this is a big part of app programming
for example now when something goes
through the air that hacker can see it
so of course you want it to be safely
encrypted before it gets sent back and
forth so modulo map I touched on this a
little bit so we can buzz through this
if I say 27 divided by 7 is 3 remainder
6 the math way to express that is 27
months 7 equals 6 that's 3 we don't care
about ok about the 3 all we care about
is the remainder and you can see that if
you go with sequential numbers you will
get your remainder moving sequentially
and also that if you're using mod 7 the
only possible answers are 0 through 6
right the answer could never be 7
because it's 0 so this also works with
negative numbers if you need to do a
modulo with it but it's a little bit
different basically if you end up with a
negative number you keep adding 7 until
you get something between 0 and 6
basically with any kind of mod 7 every
the answer has to be between 0 and 6 so
it's kind of like having this box that
all it has in it is 0 through 6 and you
can take infinity any number up through
infinity positive or negative and it
ends up getting stuffed into this box
your answer will be 0 through 6
okay this that's that's our little
modulo refresher for those of you who
for whom the sixth grade is not a recent
memory okay so let's take a look at the
way that this is more like the way this
is used in cryptography now here I still
got relatively small numbers but we're
gonna do this with some bigger numbers
just to kind of make the point so
suppose I take they want to do this math
problem 385 to the 57th power mod 293
you could probably get out your
calculator and get an answer it's gonna
be 89 because that's a forward
calculation no problem
but suppose you try to go the other way
you don't know what the power is and you
want to go this way and you know what
the answer is at the other end well how
do you figure out what X is well this is
what misters Diffie and Hellman figured
out back at me 70s is that there's no
formula for this the only way to get it
is brute force so this is the one of the
cornerstones of the original encryption
formulas so the way that diffie-hellman
works and various other key exchanges at
a very basic level and you probably
learn this at some point but again this
is a refresher is that meaning we want
to exchange some information securely so
we need to have the same cryptographic
key or at least corresponding ones if
you were going to do public and private
or something like that so both of us
need to at our ends figure out our
secure key without passing any
information between us that would expose
that would expose what happen there it's
like a magnetic field that suddenly
appeared in my midst or something
because we need to be able to generate
this key without passing information
back and forth because if I generate a
key and send it to you the hacker could
see that you know there's you have to
there had to be a way to do that and
this is again
Diffie and Hellman figured out so what
we do is we have a formula and we have
some starting numbers and those are in
the middle the hacker knows what those
are they're actually known they're
published everybody is using the same
ones but I have a secret number and you
have a secret number and we don't tell
anybody what that is and we have the
starting numbers that we've exchanged we
know what those are
so we each do a modulo formula on it and
we get a result so for example I take
385 and I put it to the power of my
secret number and do mod 293 and get to
20 so the hacker knows the 385 and the
293 but he doesn't know my X and you do
the same on your side so then we pass
our remainders over and the hacker can't
figure out what that XS because there's
no because unless they use brute force
then I take your result and my secret
number and I do another formula with
them and you can look up exactly the
formula with this but the Diffie and
Hellman found that I can take my secret
number get a result send it to you and
take your secret or your result and Miss
do something with it with my secret
number and at the very end we won't end
up with exactly the same key and it's
actually really cool the first time I
saw this I was like oh my god that's so
cool and I took you know I did like some
threes and sevens and fives very low
numbers to try it out because it is
really interesting and very cool of
course if your numbers are very low like
this it's easy to brute-force it but the
the numbers that we're using here have
hundreds of digits and it's it'd be very
difficult to brute-force
so the hacker knows what the numbers are
that got passed back and forth but the
only way they could figure out the keys
different for it so this is just in you
know how you would brute-force a key
this is a very small table but some
hackers do make tables look-up tables
for known numbers known prime because
usually using prime numbers and some
devices sometimes they're very lazy and
they use like the same prime number that
everybody else is using and a hacker
might have a table of that but you can
see where the tables would get really
really huge so it's impractical for a
hacker to have tables like this plus if
you are having a secure connection going
on the really good ones anyway they will
refresh themselves after an hour or two
or so half an hour or some period of
time so new keys will get exchanged and
by the time they figured out your key
you already got a different key so
ideally that's the way it works and it
keeps everything secure so all this is
going on every time you go on to your
phone and buy something on Amazon all
this is going on in the background so
RSA is is this standard that's still
safe to use it's difficult I don't think
it's all by itself isn't used anymore
RSA has a little more complicated math
going on but it's the same principle and
it is safe to use but every few years
NIST and other organizations start
recommending that the keys are tous is
getting too small if you want your
devices to be secure five years from now
you need to bump up from 1024 size key
to 2048 if you want it to be safe past
the year you know 2030 you're gonna need
to bump it up again so the keys keep
getting longer and longer and longer and
when they do that it takes more and more
power and more time to generate the keys
and to do the exchange and stuff like
that maybe it's only measuring in
milliseconds but we also at the same
time we're getting less patient you know
I've got her day I went on two ways
which I use for directions and I hid
ways and I had to wait three and a half
seconds and I was like what like what
what so then I went to Google Maps and
Google Maps only took like two and a
quarter seconds we're inpatient and also
battery power when you are you have a
device how frustrating it is it way is
another thing is it just chews up
battery power it's frustrating so before
I get into what ECC is elliptic curve
cryptography it is a completely it's not
completely different
method but it's still the same idea of
exchanging information where you and I
can generate the same key without
revealing anything to a hacker but it
uses a different kind of math and just
an idea here these are the different key
sizes for RSA and for ECC and for a
hacker to brute force one of these keys
look at the difference in the sizes you
can have a 138 bit key that takes the
same amount of it that does the same job
of a 1024 and smaller keys are faster to
compute use less power especially if
you're doing a little out of computing
this is a big gonna make a big
difference and if you look also as RSA
the size of the RSA key doubles the ECC
size key size does not double it only it
big they get larger at a lower rate so
as we're going into these bigger and
bigger keys the divide is going to be
even bigger okay so let's see how does
this work it's fancy math there's a lot
online about this and if you want to get
him deeper into the math after seeing
this great but at least this will give
you a foundation if you like me came to
a certain understanding and said ok
that's all I need to know about that
then that's good too
all right so these are elliptic curves
remember in math class the teacher would
give you a formula and you had a drug
Raph so this is the type of formula that
they follow something squared equals
something cubed plus something times
something plus something right so these
curves these are their formulas and
they're really easy to draw you just
pick you know start off with x equals
zero and you know you get five on that
one the one on the Left and then you put
in one two three fourths so you can draw
your curve these are really pretty
looking ones that are easy to see and
the numbers are very small the the
constants are very small we got threes
and fives there's some pretty intense
formulas for these but they all follow
that
we're gonna just look at a really really
simple one today to get the concept of
what how these are useful in
cryptography so we're gonna look at this
one and this is my disclaimer if you use
description you are an idiot but it's
really good for your illustrator
purposes so we're only interested in
integer pairs we're not interested in
any fractions or decimals or anything
and this is true for for ECC also so we
have some pairs here and notice that we
have the negative ones we have 1 3 + 1 -
3 4 + 4 9 and so on so at some point the
graph goes nearly vertical with any
elliptic curve go back a little bit take
a look at those see how it at some point
they go nearly vertical and you're not
going to find any more integer pairs so
you need to just stick to the ones that
you have that are within that okay so
here we have this curve and we're going
to perform modulo mapping on a graph but
you've never done that before so the
concept here is remember we have that
box that only contains 0 through 6 and
all the numbers would get shoved in the
box we're gonna shove everything into
that part of the graph the 7 by 7 so all
of the points the XY points are going to
be numbers 0 through 6
so you basically take the integer points
and going back a bit here we have this
negative point C 1 + -3 minus 3 is not
within our seven by seven but remember
for negative numbers you keep adding
seven so that's going to end up being
one for you got it the negative 3 you
add 7 to it it's 4 and now it's in the 7
by 7 modulo box so when we do that we
shove everything in there and we end up
with this in our little 7 by 7 box
everything all of the X's and Y's are
between zero and six so these are our
points oops no no too far here all right
so what we're gonna do is look at these
two points four two and six six these
are two of the points we ended up with
and we're gonna draw a line between them
and then we're going to extend that line
off outside of our box and then because
it's outside the box we can map it back
into the modulo space so we map it back
into the modulo space and there is a
line it's coming through here now of
course this programs that do this for
you obviously you're not going to sit
there with a piece of graph paper every
time somebody tries to you know buy
something from New Ager or something
yeah it's a joke god you guys man coffee
and then it loops around you know you go
back out and then loop it back around
until you hit one of the other points on
the curve you follow how that works
drew a line between two of the points
kept mapping it back into the modulo
space I see some frowny faces okay let's
go back a little bit we're taking all of
these points and mapping them into our
mod space our six by six mod seven space
so every point every line everything
that happens we're just going to keep
you know mod setting on every point that
we get to shove it back in there okay
that makes sense okay so we get this
line push it back in there and we end up
landing on one of the other points on
the graph so what we say because we
finally landed on another integer point
we say that for two plus six six equals
one for in elliptic curve math all right
so you start off with two points and you
do this thing and then you end up with
one and there's a formula for this you
can Wikipedia it it's it's
I mean I knew this was gonna be Sunday
morning I didn't want to hit you with
that but this is the basic idea is that
you're the the addition the operator the
addition operator means that okay so the
cool thing about this wait for it you
can't figure out you can't go backwards
except with brute force and that's the
magic of elliptic curves is that going
forward very easy figuring out what X is
in this situation really really hard
what you would need is a table just like
you would need for modulo math if you
wanted to figure out what that was if
you have a complex enough elliptic curve
and there's like a dozen or so of them
that are recommended for use for
cryptography this is not one of them
telling you again
so it's the same type of thing I have a
starting point and you have a starting
point and we both have a point that
we're going to add and the addition by
the way is commutative you can switch
them back and forth so I could it
doesn't matter which way you add them
you could say you know a plus B or B
plus a either way so I have a point and
you have a point and then it as a secret
point that we have and then we have a
point that's known that we're going to
add to it and a curve that we're going
to use so that we know our formula that
we're going to use and we both calculate
and we get our result and we send them
to each other and the hacker can see the
result but he can't brute force what our
secret one is then we do more math on
the results that we got from each other
and we end up with the same key so in
this way this parallels all of the key
exchange concepts that we've used all
along it just takes advantage of the
fact that with elliptic curves when you
have this thing about the two points
adding two points together to get a
result that it has the same quality of
it it's you can't go backwards without
brute force and it has the advantage of
the keys that the keys are much smaller
and the calculation goes faster so
remember we talked about brute forcing
keys when you're using modulo the
original type of modulo math this is a
really simple table for how you would
hack easy see you would need a table
where this is the addition of you know
the points across the top and the points
down the left and then you have a where
the two of them meet like everybody see
what I mean and some of them go to
infinity so you don't use those a good
algorithm won't let you use those but
the tables are there's a mirror image
aspect to it of it where if you add you
know if you look across adding it one
way and adding it another way you're
gonna get the same answer but this is
just 25 by 25 points now imagine if
there were hundreds and hundreds and
yeah the hacker had to calculate
calculate so it's less hackable so so is
everybody with me so far there's some
witness yeah okay good yes so that's
pretty much all I was gonna say about
how it works and that's you know this
gives you something that you're at a
meeting in some ways just we use UCC or
RSA you could say well you know she was
buzz word from my presentation and Salo
smarter no no more you know okay so now
we're gonna talk a little bit about more
about how it's used and why you need it
so this is from MIT from February 2018
they came up with this chip that uses
ECC and it says reduces power
consumption of public key encryption by
ninety nine point seventy five percent
and increases speed five hundred fold
and they actually already had an ECC
chip that they
developed but they they actually put the
the calculation stuff on the chip it's
hardware based now instead of software
based so this was kind of cool
now I try to find information on exactly
which types of devices use ECC but as
you can imagine a lot of companies are
not too eager to discuss in detail what
they're doing with their encryption but
I did manage to find some different
situations where it's used to use them
thermostats the sensors for all the
autonomous vehicles that are being
tested ECC is obviously very desirable
because it uses less power it's faster
it's very safe you know it's one thing
to have your network hacked it's another
to have your car hacked if someone hacks
your network probably you're not going
to hit a pedestrian you know as opposed
to the danger it's the physical dangers
of it and a lot of you know home
security systems will use it and most of
the mobile devices have it available to
apps if you're developing a mobile app
you've had the option using ECC for your
app as long as you build it in so that's
basically why you would want to use it
it's more efficient use with less power
better safety with smaller keys and
that's all I have to say about that
today and my next slide talks about me
as I mentioned I sometimes put on an
orange wig and talk about security if
you want to come to my website and visit
me I also have a password quiz to find
out how much you know about passwords
and what are good passwords it's very
simple and also my email address to
complain when you don't do get a good
score on the quiz so any questions about
ECC I think like that are you guys all a
year to get to the prizes it's gonna be
drawings of prizes coming up
yeah we good we really oh yes
what's that why no wig today this is my
first time presenting at NOLA con and I
was a little worried they wouldn't take
me seriously if I showed up in an orange
wig and started talking in a Russian
accent about you know steal your
Pittsburgh you know now that I've been
here and you know next year could be a
little bit different I might just submit
with the picture of me and the orange
wig and do a whole thing like that but
yeah this is Scott Lana
did a lot more fun than me which really
does any other questions this the
question is why would somebody still
continue to use RSA probably there's
more support for it it's more
established it's the easy way out a lot
of PC based stuff still uses RSA because
it's you know your piece is plugged in
if the power consumption isn't as much
of an issue so the question was from a
theoretical standpoint would you always
want to choose ECC I would and I know
that everything that I've read is like
recommending it and pushing it but it's
you know you got people who've been
doing this job for 10 20 years and
everything is very familiar and they
don't want to have to move into
something else which they have to
support and be responsible for so it's
you know it's gonna take either take
some time or take some pushback from the
industry where where there has to be
some serious RSA fail or something
before it's going to be but it is being
used more and more and I mean one of the
things is that consumers don't
understand the difference so for example
there was some recent thing
we're not so recent but the Belkin home
security devices turned out to be easily
hackable and they were all using RSA so
I when I would buy a home security
device I would want to know what was
using ECC but you know my family other
family members we wanted an InfoSec
don't care all right any other questions
yes I do not have an opinion on which
elliptical curve to trust the most
huh I know that NIST recommends like 15
different ones and I don't I don't
having a practical experience with it to
really answer that question but I would
you know easy enough to find which ones
and also following the advice of my
cryptography professor where he said
don't ever try to write your own
cryptographic function just because it's
just always a bad idea there's other
people who devoted their life to this
and they have teams of people testing
stuff so there is all there's already
modules out there that have been found
to be safe and secure and everything and
you would just end up you know if with
any language there's going to be a you
know some functions somewhere some
module that you can include that it's
going to include all that and you just
have to get it into your code and
working so that's great question though
I'd have I should find that out for the
next time I can present my favorite
elliptic curve and I could draw a little
hearts and rainbows on it all right
anything else anybody any questions who
wants to win things in the drawing oh
come on that's an easy question all
right thank you very much
[Applause]