[Music]
hey good afternoon good morning good
evening wherever it is that you might be
listening uh this is a talk about road
deployment in the dns core
where i'm coming from with this my
name's ed lewis by the way i work for
icann i've had a long experience working
for registries
i've worked in all sorts of tlds out
there i've worked on dns protocol
development
and so on i've seen this i've seen a lot
of things get built and rolled out in
the past
now one of the interesting things about
this process is to look at
how operators adopt new technology
in the past there was assumption that
technology should just be adopted
because they are good things
however i've learned that a lot of times
if you look at how operators
treat a new technology it tells you a
lot about whether the technology really
is ready to go
uh or where what other improvements are
needed for it
so you know is it new technology ready
for operations it's not really yes or no
it's it's a sliding scale
and i'm going to look at one case of
this
now the talking we're going to look at
the adoption of route origin
attestations
which are part of the routing public key
infrastructure
these are used to protect routing the
routing system which many people are
probably
really familiar with from other talks
i'm looking at only the routes that are
leading towards
servers that are part of what we call
the dns core
and so from here i'm going to talk about
two things initially what is the dns
core
and what a row is the first because it's
a
small concept that i've been working
with by myself
the latter because i want to make sure
that you that
you see that i understand what i'm
talking about or maybe i've got the
wrong thing i just want to make sure
about that
so first the dns core it's this green
area on the on the slide which is the
top of the dns name space
it starts with the root zone it starts
with the tlds the top level domains
that we are familiar with that have the
names of everything in the internet
below them uh there's also
the address and routing parameters area
that has the reverse maps for
ipv4 under inadder and ipv6 under ip6
and there's some other structures that
are inside of here that i collect
together to be
to create what i call the dns core
outside of that is
everything else that really uses the
internet out there you're probably more
familiar with what's outside the core
than what's inside the core
now i'll i want to take one side step
here and say that in my talk
i'm going to talk about tlds and i'm
using the word tld in my talk sometimes
not exactly the correct way tlds we
generally think of the cctlds the the
jurisdictional based
or country code is what cc stands for
tld's out there
the generic the commercial tlds out
there i also throw in the reverse map
as part of that because they kind of
behave the same way
when it comes to the dns protocol itself
the protocol doesn't differentiate
between forward map and reverse map
and i like to keep these these all
together and i you know having worked
for an rar
having worked for forward domain name
registries in the past
it's the same technology we really need
the two to all work together
uh there's not really a divide except
that there is a divide in the mission
that they cover
so the uh the core what you know the
upper reach of the core i'll give you
some caveats about that because this
might
play into how you evaluate what i'm
saying here uh the space up above
tends to be pretty stable in the
membership uh tlds do come and go but
not not many a day every once in a while
they they they come and go
in the last couple years a few have been
pulled out
not a great amount but some the
operators of the in this area too have
the dns as their primary mission
the reason why they exist or in business
is because of the dns
so they kind of have to really give it
uh that's their top priority uh
operations or operational-wise and the
protocol the us protocol surprisingly is
that it's simplest in the in the core
it's not a very complicated area now
outside the core there are higher
traffic zones there are higher value
zones there's greater functionality
and there are zones that are really well
engineered i mean
it's the core is not special in certain
ways but it's an area that's good for
studying
uh quickly but the roas because i want
to
get on to the rest of the talk aroa is a
route origin which is the ip prefix
and the last hop asn that i get
information about
and the attestation signs that the the
combination of prefix
and orig and the origin asn are approved
by
whoever it is the ip prefix is
is is allocated to
so the question let's go back the
question is what is row is signing
happening in the dns core how much of it
is out there
that's a relatively new technology it's
how far we've gone along
if it's low deployment it's been a hard
sell if it's high it's been
it's probably solving an immediate need
now beyond just a simple number
evaluation i won't look at a patterns of
this
to see where it is you know if it's not
full you know what's going on how is it
being
deployed out there and i want to point
out too that
in as part of any kind of a security of
this kind
there's signing in validation and i'm
not talking about the validation end of
this i'm just talking about the signing
is the
are these uh statements available
my method is is pretty simple it i look
i create a census of the dns core i look
at everything that's in there
the zones that are there the zones use
name servers the name servers use
addresses
addresses have route originations
related to them
i get the latter mapping from team
comrie's ip to asm mapping service
that's my source for routing information
and whether or not there's a roa or not
a roa i get that from
a list published by the ripe ncc
uh which just has a list of everything
that's been validated i had
my percentages are yes divided by yes
plus no
pretty simple calculation so
after a lot of this work uh putting
stuff together
i came up i come up with this uh pie
chart which is
uh current as of 24th of january and it
shows that
just a bit more than one in four routes
leading to the dns core
are covered by arowa and to give you
some more uh
orientation to what my calculations are
coming from
i have some numbers on on the right hand
side of the screen
the number of zones is 3000 or so that
includes all the tlds plus their
substructures
uh there are about 1774 tlds and again
that that's counting the
1500 or so forward map tlds plus
reverse map zones in there and so on a
few others
there are only 4 300 name servers
involved because there's a lot of
sharing
though for all those zones all those
tlds they only use 4 300 name servers
and there's only about 7 000 addresses
meaning that many name servers are
sharing the same address
and below that route origins there there
are much fewer only about 2 000 total
there's a lot of
sharing of a co-mingling of services you
go down the stack so to speak here
now looking i have about five months of
data
in this particular uh measurement system
i built
and i was able to go back to see that on
the left hand side you see a chart which
shows a pretty steady growth from
uh from the from august of 2020 to
now on the right hand side there's
another chart
which is actually the same chart uh the
difference is the scale
and one is showing that from 22 to 25
it's going up but from zero to 100 it's
kind of flat
and so it's going up but it's taking
some time to get there
and we're gonna see at this rate if i
just took that line out and be nine or
ten more years till we get to full
deployment
now one number is not enough here um i
will look at some other categories that
are out there
uh ipv4 versus ipv6 is one of the
categories that we usually look at
routing information and then we'll look
into the dns core that we have the
cctles the gtlds reverse map
as individuals and maybe there's some
other way to divide this up
what i'm looking for here is what are
the decision points
in the architecture where you might want
to address
what needs to be done to the protocol so
v4 versus v6
um they're pretty similar uh it used to
be that ipv4 or v6 would be different
because of the
the experience we had with these two
protocols and largely it's not
much of a difference anymore it's just
like a three percent difference between
the two
uh between 24 and a half percent and 28
7.5 rather but in doing this chart um
i was wondering why the numbers were
just off a little bit because i look at
my accounts and they're different
and being that when i'm writing my
software and you know i'm not that good
at it
sometimes i make mistakes but in this
case here
what stands out is the number of tlds
there are 1774 tlds counted for v4
but just 19 less for v6 and i went back
and i
trolled through some data out there and
i found out that's true that there are
about 19
of the ipv 19 tlds out there that still
don't have ipv6 servers out there which
is
uh surprising to me um but not part of
what i was studying here but i just
thought that was interesting
so if i look at now the zones by what
where we categorize them at some level
gtlds have a very small sliver
of roa deployed out there very small
number
of routes are covered thirteen percent
cctld is about one-third are
and the reverse map they're two-thirds
and the reverse map uh
we're talking about the the places run
by the rars who have been promoting uh
the roa technology quite a bit so it's
not surprising to see
kind of a much higher uh adoption it
with reverse map than in other places
so uh looking at this i mean there's a
couple of things that were surprising to
me because i do know
a lot about how the tlds all work
together uh there
there are a lot of cctlds and gtlds that
are run
off the same platform so they should be
together and now we expect numbers to be
closer
but still there's quite a bit of
difference out there in the reverse map
there's there is actually one
organization that's gtld cctl is in
reverse map all together but only one
but we have all these different
configurations we have different
agreements out there
uh trying to find out where things are
decided regarding the deployment of
routing technology and who needs to be
who needs to be pleased to roll this out
or can have where the concerns have come
from
are kind of all over the place so
taking a look at what i have understood
to be the way things are put together
we have the stack up on top registries
have a policy you know who's allowed to
list their names in my
dot whatever tld out there and that's
the registry administration takes care
of that stuff and there's a front end to
a database
the registry database is something run
by an organization um
and it produces whatever mapping
whatever they want to do with the
registry out there they have the we call
the who is data comes out of that the
rdap data comes out of that
but we have the dns is part of is one of
the products the dns and dns sect comes
out of that
then we come down to dns server hosting
now that kind of stuff generally is done
by
a dns operator the largest one out there
holds the largest one in terms of number
of tlds is around 250 and i call those
dns houses
are there a couple clumps of these out
there and i don't have details much in
the slides to keep this
in time for for the talk now below that
uh there's server hosting that's another
layer people who
run servers for other people and there
are up to 600 tlds in
one of these what i call a s houses an
as house might be the
might be the wrong name uh but it's it's
basically a collection of the
atom system origins that seem to share
uh
that that have dns servers in them now
uh it's kind of surprising that the
largest one of these is much bigger than
largest dns
operator out there because there's some
co-mingling some research
some sharing of these services
it in some cases you actually do have
organizations that run
all three of these layers in other cases
you have organizations that only run the
top layer and they contract the bottom
two
out to other people and it's all mix of
these different things out there
but it's interesting to start to divide
things into this so
i spent some time uh deriving things
called dns houses and
dns house is data driven uh so i run a
program and it will go off and do this
by itself
it looks at two things it looks at
what's in the dns there's something
called the r name field of the of the
soa resource record the r name is
supposedly
uh the responsible identity of
who's running the dns who's created the
zone file now it's not guaranteed to be
accurate but turns out to be pretty
accurate in the dns core
the operators there have taken time to
put in a reasonable value there that can
tie things together
and also there's a technical contact
field in a registry for the root zone
uh managed through the inf functions web
you can get it through their website or
actually online uh and i can use those
two things together and
and weave a little uh web of connections
and
create buckets of who who's coming who's
cooperating
a bunch of tld or who's who's running a
bunch of tlds out there
now in doing this uh there are very few
there are very few
large houses uh for which large meaning
they have over 100 tlds out there
there's
a couple of them out there and there are
many single houses it's a typical long
tail we have many that only do one or
two tlds
now typically the large houses are the
commercial places the commercial
operators that have done
tlds in bulk the single houses tend to
be the cctlds that are running their own
systems for whatever reason they have
for whatever purpose they have
so i created i took my dns houses and i
bucketed
up all of the route information i have
in dns core
and i made this plot and this plot shows
on the bottom from zero to 100 percent
how far they've someone has rolled out
row i mean that if they're 100
column every route advertisement has a
row covering it
uh zero percent on the left-hand side
they haven't started
doing anything about it now the height
of the dot is how many tlds they run and
you put this out there and you see
pretty much nothing there's not a lot of
organizations a lot of dots basically
everything's down low
a lot of small bit players in the bottom
the big players stay
either zero 100 percent and there's not
a lot in the middle in fact
over the months that i've been
generating this chart there's a dot
right in the middle
i don't know if i can actually uh use my
marker here but right here
right here if you see that um
oops yes maybe you can't see it right in
the middle of this about a hundred
tlds up and 50 that dot just appeared
one time and i haven't figured out who
it is
uh so i don't think it has much there's
not a lot of statistical things to say
about that
so the as house a little more
complicated i've had to do some more
playing with network names
uh bgp prefixes imagine the parsing of
the network name that comes from the
team country listing from the rers
and some other debatable parsing rules
and one up that i create pools of as
numbers that may be running together
and one thing that's important here is
zone could be multiple as houses
and i do this chart here which again
doesn't seem to have a lot to it but
actually it seems to be a little bit
more organized
and i've used some colors here on
purpose here the green dots which are
all on the left side of the screen
are the large commercial operators
that's a subjective
application of that term by me these are
the ones that i've known for running
tlds for a very long time and they all
are staying low on the scale of adoption
one has got a little bit of the ways up
there but not very far
the red dots there you can see four of
them easily and there's actually a fifth
one that's visible if you look hard down
the bottom
those are the five rars and they are all
at 100 percent
now the you noticed earlier i had a pie
chart which showed
only two thirds of their routes are
covered the difference here is that's
two thirds of the routes to their
servers that they're running
further for their zones if you look at
just the routes to the
as numbers that they have allocated back
to themselves for their own business
they've done all of the road coverage
already sometimes they have some
some other they go to other sources for
uh
uh ho server hosting that haven't
covered their uh
their routes now the orange dot is a
special uh
one-off it's not it's not a special one
it's a special unique
organization which has no tlds they
don't run any dna they don't run
a registry but they uh they offer
services to many many many tlds and
they're significant in their size for
that
but also they're trying to push
sometimes the technology further
now this next chart is a blow up of the
lowest part of this this
only the small the the 50 tld uh
players or less and you see the other
red dot that's there is that last rar
that wasn't too visible before
and there's a slight organization from
low to high as you go left to right but
nothing much i would really uh
make a conclusion about so uh
overall judgment um overall statements
ro's are sparse
there's not a lot of data here a large
non-rr hosters as houses have low
deployment
but the large r hosters that are that
are the large hosters that are not rer's
i'm sorry the large rar hosters do have
high deployment so
the last two bolts there kind of show a
contrast in uh who's
rolled it out uh there's an inherent
risk of adding security to an
in-operation system
uh this is just a background slide to
why a slow adoption may
actually be uh going on here that we
don't try
to uh put if you were to put security
into a system that's very critical and
the securities of itself
has a an issue there will be chaos so we
look for communications for this
now i've had experience with dns sec dns
sec is also similar because it was a
up post operational application of
security to an operating system out
there that if it broke it it would be
really bad
adoption of dnsk has taken a very long
time in over the
two decades since it started being
rolled out it's only pretty much
respectable or visible and
depending on how you look at this uh
it's actually been a good thing it's
been slow given some of the early
hiccups that happened
uh currently though dnsx sees a
different adoption pattern
within the dns core itself in the dns
core dns core the large operators have
fully deployed it
and what remains to be deployed are in
the single cctld operator is kind of
a little bit different from what i see
with the roas
for who knows what reason so good
questions here uh
uh is it ready for deployment i'm going
to duck the question um
i don't want to speak on behalf of
operators explain why it hasn't been
rolled out if deployment ought to
progress
what needs to be done again i'm going to
duck that question because an operator
would be the best source for that
information
and so in wrap-up uh the this the work
that i've done here
it's merely checking the temperature of
the room uh is 25 acceptable for now
maybe maybe not are there possible
improvements for this to go forward and
is it a business case issue i've always
heard about the dns business case not
being made
um i think that it's probably very hard
to make that
now relying on my experience of dns sect
from 1990 since 1998 rather
slow adoption has advantages we've used
to have lots of bumps with dns second
because the pioneers were the only ones
involved in either the signing or the
validation
only the pioneers were they were willing
to smooth
over what we saw uh there are gaps that
still exist in dns sex some
still still need to be filled as we go
forward and
the other part of this too is that the
value proposition
may change over time if there was a time
when dnsec was not solving an immediate
problem
uh but that changed when people's uh
attitudes about that happen
so i hope i'm gonna end here and hope
that there may be some discussion or
questions about so maybe other people
will be interested in looking at
the topic down the road thanks
[Music]
we'll continue next with q a
edward what are ican's next stepped
steps with rpki other than research
when will we see a raw covering
the l root ip blocks
okay uh what is our what is there
besides research is that life
now i i really uh well what part of
icann's mission is to
basically coordinate communicate what's
going on out there so research
and observations are important to us and
uh
you know at some point it'd be good to
have a dashboard for this so you know
we're thinking about
what we can do to do some of these over
these studies over a longer
period of time but in terms of anything
else it's kind of beyond me
to uh really give a plan for what we
want to do in in terms of
the rpki and roha deployments out there
and in terms of the operational
questions
um that's actually not in my area of the
organization i'm going to deduct that
as a non-operator i can assure you that
the operators we have
are well aware of the technology
and they're doing their evaluations
they've tested it and
they are just evaluating whether or not
they want to when or when
or if to roll this out at some point
so i'll leave that
okay thanks uh another question that
came up is um
you're aware of uh detailed studies of
the implications
or or rpki of rpki on robustness
of the dns core can you comment on that
well it's there's a general uh a general
cat you know a general situation here
whenever you add
a security mechanism to an already
running system
you're you're changing things you're
making it a little bit more brittle at
times and we did it with dns sec
um in everything everything system when
we add on security later we're risking
the
original system's uh health
and so you want to go slowly with this
uh
and it's without being specific with
really detailed answers would take an
hour to explain
uh basically whenever you add on
security to something you want to make
sure
the security system itself doesn't cause
a failure
down the road you want to protect and
not destroy the system
it's it's running on
okay um
do you um we are unfortunately out of
time
um any uh final thoughts about uh
observations anything you would like to
share with the nano community
now just well just quickly uh i noticed
that susan fourney gave a statistic last
night or at the end of the session
yesterday where
uh she mentioned 25 was the adoption
there so i think that the measurements
have some uh
basis in reality they're spread further
than this
uh but in general i just want yeah i
want to take this as a
measure of you know it's not the
operators are slow to adopt something
but uppers may be reluctant to adopt
something we need to figure that out
before we decide there's business cases
promotion is needed or whether or not we
need to go further with developing the
system to make it
make sure that it is truly adding
insecurity and not
risking some of the performance we have
today
okay well edward thanks for joining us
you