[Music]
hey everyone
my name is mannan venkatesan um i work
in a network architecture in
comcast primarily focusing on the
backbone and the original ip networks
um i want to i want to thank the
committee to
give me this opportunity to share our
backbone evolution we had over the last
few years
we wanted to go over some of the
challenges we faced
um how we address them and some of the
learnings we had
um in in our backbone um
deployments so thank you for the
opportunity
um so before i start going into the
details
i wanted to share this slide most of you
would know this
already i just wanted to give you an
overview of
backbone core networks their
capabilities and their functions um
typically the backbone networks are the
big mega routers supporting hundreds of
thousands of ports
carrying multi-terabits of traffic
critical traffic
um interconnecting all the routers and
sites
regional networks external peers
external
providers um provide them connectivity
between
between those networks it connects to
the the routers we use in backbones
typically they are scale out or scale
up hardware scale out meaning
we expand the router across multiple
racks
multi-chassis is an example a few
vendors came out with a multi-chassis
design
multi-chassis one of the example for
scale out option
and scale up means we would upgrade the
hardware
um at regular intervals a few
once in a few years or we would replace
the whole box with a new
denser box that's a scale of options
um these these are all critical uh
backbone
uh core routers supporting millions of
customers
um so we
they play this they support all the
traffic flows all the services
that we provide to our customers um
though i am showing you a single router
design in this slide
i have seen other designs where
folks would use two routers in a
backbone location
connect them back to back and provide
the port denser
density they would need the support and
i also have seen
three or more routers connected in a
ring fashion or a star topology fashions
fashioned to support the density they
would need
to support their growth um so moving on
to the next slide um
so um i wanted to start with some of the
challenges we were facing
with the with the core uh router
platforms um
i have listed a few of these challenges
here in the slide but i would go through
them in detail in the following slides
and they're starting from the port
capacity we need to
deploy um to support the traffic growth
um some of the bandwidth and features of
asic chipsets we have to deploy um cost
of the software and the hardware and
blast radius that's a failure zone
and maintenance window followed by the
environmental constraints
we have just to deploy them uh in in
both
comcast footprint or our internal
footprint as well as our co-location
facilities
so um in the first challenge i would
like to start here is the is the port
growth we need to support uh we all know
you know the traffic internet traffic
exploded
uh last last decade um the red
graph the red line shows the internet
traffic
volume we have to support in our
backbone in your background shoot
um it's it's it's exploded in last
uh ten years or so so
the the sports you would need to support
the traffic
uh is also proportioned to the traffic
volume
so we have to make sure we stay on top
of the
port capacity we support on this core
routers
that's the the blue line you see
if i go back to my start of my career
with comcast we were
you know we were using one gig uh
ports those days then we moved on to the
10 gig ports then we were doing multi 10
gig
links then we moved on to 100 gig and we
survived with the multi-hundred gig
ports
for a few years now we are looking into
uh 400 gig
links so that's the step function you
would see with the blue line it's based
on driven by the port capacity output
port
speed uh and the platform capacity to
support those ports
so depending on which way which year to
look at
um if you if you look at the end of the
end of your platform life cycle you're
always running behind
with with the demand so you always like
at the beginning of the platform life
cycle you know we have enough course to
support to
meet our demands but you have to stay on
top but when you come
closer to the end of the life cycle we
got to make sure we
we have enough ports on the box or we
bring in a new platform or new hardware
to support the demand
so that's always a challenge that we
have been facing
and the next uh challenge is the failure
zone or the blast areas we will say if
we lose
one router in a core location we impact
millions of millions of customers
if it is a hard failure then the packet
on the wire is lost
then during the convergence we may
impact some flows
but if there's a partial failure if the
box is starting to misbehave and start
blackholing traffic
you will impact millions of millions of
we will impact millions of customers
with those failures so it creates a
snowball effect
impacting the regional networks core
links
as well as our inter-provider links our
peers um
all the traffic between this route
between this network we connect you
um so if we lose one of the router in
our in our core location
at the same time if you lose another
failure if you have another failure in a
connected network
this could lead into a disaster
situation
for example if you lose site one uh all
our
all of our providers would would start
sending
traffic through site two three and four
but
during the same time if we had another
failure in their network or in our
network
we would have a a much better impact
to our customers so one of the goal here
is to reduce this plus radius
the next one is the economics and
features
we have seen over the years
the more of the more bandwidth we
support in a box
the features uh supported is kind of
taking an
impact um the port cost
um it's it's higher to support complex
features compared to basic ip routing
features and then it is really difficult
to
mix different port profiles different
profiles
uh different uh profiles of the
different
requirements in a single chassis um so
as i
show in this uh graph if you have three
or four
different profiles we end up supporting
uh ports
that would support all all pro all
features in the box
so we would end up probably paying more
money for for the box then
um then if you have to support the basic
ip routing features
though the backbone is a pure pe
function but this applies to our
edge uh role also so if you have a big
box supporting your pu to pe rolls
you will end up seeing the same problem
there too
the other thing we have seen the cost
per port cost of a multi chassis
router is a lot more expensive compared
to the fixed us
fixed our modular chassis routers so we
got to account for this economics as
well as the features
um as we start deploying these big boxes
in our network
um 10th and operational challenges uh we
we could come up with the cool
technology or we could come up with this
uh brilliant architecture but it it
they are not good enough to deploy
unless we
we made them uh unless we we make them
supportable in our network
or any network so we got to make sure we
put our operational hat on
we have to make sure whatever we are
rolling out in a network
they are supported by our operations
team
over the years the number of uh hours we
get for maintenance has been going down
now we have hit we have started rolling
out many critical
services um the more and more services
we roll out
the number of hours we can get for
support um get to do like a
configuration changes quota bridges is
going down
we have to make sure we align with all
our uh
internal teams and external teams on
notification before we start taking down
a box for maintenance
um so this this kind of puts us in a in
a spot where it takes a long time to do
a code upgrades or bau
or business or social arguments we need
to do no network to support the capacity
growth
and the last challenge is the
environmental demands um
so we do deploy these core routers in a
call office
collocation facilities that we don't own
um
so some of the constraints there is
always space power and cooling
though we have new big routers coming
into the network into the network
i know they're like 200 terabits of
capacity routers
um the power per gig is going down
with the new a6 but because we have more
ports
on a single rack the power needed per
rack is going up so some of the
new routers we are looking into they
need like 50 to 60 kilowatts per rack
and the cooling is directly proportioned
to the
power we use and the port count we turn
up on the router
and so and also there are some space
constraints
in this facilities where if you turn up
a big
high density next-gen routers we would
have to make sure we have enough space
around the rack
for the for the proper cooling purpose
so we end up losing more space
um with this new deployments these new
big routers
so that takes me to the the proposal
or the solution we we came up with or we
went with um
we decided to go with um
a spine and leaf class architecture
in our core locations this is not a new
architecture
it's been there for a long time it's
been
deployed and proven successful in in
data centers um so we have we are
adapting
that architecture for our core um
backbone locations um so it does address
all these concerns we talked earlier
we can pick and choose different
platforms based on the
roles we can we have flexibility to
scale
up as well as scale uh out we can do
both horizontal and vertical
uh uh scaling and we would able
we are able to seamlessly integrate this
new architecture into the existing
network
so we would turn the existing core
router as one of the leaf
into this spine enemy of architecture
and so that we don't disrupt the
existing traffic flows or the demands
by taking a big router and breaking them
into
smaller routers we break the blast
radius now so
now with one router failure we are not
impacting
the traffic flows going through that
site anymore
um moving this architecture
allows us to change the focus from a
platform towards an architecture
so before we were always looking for a
bigger and bigger and bigger platforms
and aligning our deployments to the
platform
rollouts now we have this architecture
now we have more options to
pick different platforms for a different
roles so
now we can focus on the architecture
rather than the platform
uh we have built with n plus one
redundancy so that means we can take
um the routers offline to do maintenance
during the daytime during the nighttime
um
we don't have that maintenance window
constraint anymore
we have uh we have done hitless
maintenance during the day
time now um this allows this
architecture
allows us to drain traffic on one spine
so for example if you have four spine or
eight spine so you take one of the
spines out drain traffic
uh of the spine move the traffic over on
the rest of the spine nodes
and do the maintenance and bring them
back up um without impacting the traffic
flows
through the site so our downstream
customers as well as our upstream um
providers don't see uh this maintenance
being done
in their network
but you guys might be wondering so
spinal leaf is there forever i mean
more than 10-15 years and it's proven in
data center what is new here
um the what we have found out is that
um deploying spine and leaf in a core
location has its own challenges
the requirements slas support
uh requirements uh design requirements
are
slightly different than um than the data
center network
for example in a core network we have to
support a you know
ip table full internet table we have 1.2
million
uh prefixes uh you know about 800 uh
internet prefix then you have internal
prefixes so we have more than a million
prefix we need to support
and when you bring up the bgp full mesh
there are you know you you
you go from um two million packs to 20
million parts or 30 million packs
i'll go through more details about
routing later in the slide but there are
there are constraints there are um
limitations
there are issues that we have to tackle
to make this architecture work in core
backbone
now with going from a single router to
30 node or 20 node in a site you
multiply by number of sites
you ex and the number of nodes you get
to support in igp domain is
is going up drastically that means we
have to keep an eye out on the igp dom
igp protocol also
make sure they are good with their scale
numbers
um the other um constraint is the ecmp
paths before we had one path east or
west
now it's finally if we have n number of
paths in number of hcmp valves we could
have
if you have four spines here there are
four ecmp pads it could be eight that
could be sixteen
so you gotta make sure that the routers
be picked they can do proper ecb
traffic load sharing and the traffic
profiles are different
you know we don't control that the the
traffic
profiles that uh we support the transit
um and like data center you know you may
have your own applications you have an
opportunity to change the traffic
profile if you need to
with your own data center app but in a
core location we have no control about
the traffic profile so we got to make
sure we pick the right platform
we have to make sure we have the right
tools to monitor
the traffic load sharing among the ecb
parts
and we also need to rework the bgp
design before it was simple
you know in a backbone network you know
you may have like
a small number of routers maybe 20 30
routers or maybe 40 routers
it's easy to do bgp full mesh among all
four
um among all core routers now you go
from the 20 or 30 or 40 routers 100
on to hundreds of routers so we have to
rethink on on
the bgpd design as well
and then the other uh constraints we
will
another thing we were trying to solve is
the convergence so
now we have high number of bgp paths
and because of the bgp design ecmp
you got to make sure the bgp convergence
is in
is in within the slav support um so we
have to work with our vendors to make
sure
that the features and knobs some other
trick we used a network with the bgp
to allow the better convergence to meet
the slas
and and the last one as i was saying
earlier we got to make sure our support
organization
our operational team is on board with
this
class architecture they have all the
tools and dashboards and
um and the toolkits to support this
network
so we have to think through to make sure
how we support this network how we were
supporting single node design versus
a multi uh class cluster
in our core backbone and one other thing
i missed in a in a data center you know
all the links are
jumpers you know there are like three
meter jumpers
pretty much you know once you plug them
in they don't go bad unless the update
goes bad but here in core locations
some of the links are over you know
kilometer for the long-haul fibers they
could be like you know across the
country
there could be multi uh maybe 100
kilometers 200 kilometers even more than
a thousand kilometers store so depending
on
where the locations are so we got to
watch out for those um
the fiber failures how does it impact um
the class design how does it impact the
scales we support
um in the class designs
this slide shows a quick
preview of a typical core
deployment we did um um
so we we started with spine routers we
call them cs nodes
we started with four cs nodes but we
have enough we have an option to
go beyond four uh depending on the
growth
and then we have uh the local piece
remote piece over the long fibers and
the crs are the leaf nodes connecting to
the spines
and we also have the regional area
network um
that supports our customers that
directly connects to our customers
as a leaf node to this uh cs
and we also have two router reflector
i'll cover more in the bgp design but we
have we installed two router factor
servers
and we took the router fracture function
off of the routers and moved them onto
this
x86 um rr routers
um so in the igp design
um it's a the way we have our backbone
network it's it's on its own idp domain
and we have a separate igb domain for
backbone compared to the ranging area
network so that helped
us a little bit here so
we did increase the number of nodes in
the backbone now with this class
architecture
but we are within the limit of the igp
uh scale numbers but we are closely
watching
because as you add more nodes more links
your igp database is going to grow big
and we got to make sure we don't impact
the convergence
by increasing the database size so we're
closing
watching the igp database
numbers we're also looking at just few
options
to reduce igp database in future if
needed and there are a few itf drafts
out there on how we can do
uh optimization to igp isis for example
in particular to reduce the database
size so we are closely watching those
traps
so if we need to do any optimization in
future we have a few
few options on the table to tackle
bgp design is a little bit complex than
igp
so we before we had full mesh vgp design
and now we are going we went away from
it and we did a
two layer bgp design we have router
reflector servers
uh in a mesh and then all the routers
in the site would be the route reflected
client for the servers
um so uh this is
uh this is a two layer design that we
that we are rolling out with this class
architecture
uh we have to do a lot of quite a few
features and enhancements and
enhancements
uh to get the convergence number we were
looking for
um and also we had to turn up uh certain
features
um to make sure the load sharing works
fine
so now we have a lot of ecmp paths we
have to turn on
bgp add path feature um otherwise the
router effect is going to pick one
path out of the um
all possible uh bgp patch and send down
to the
downstream clients that means we are not
going to use all
ecmp paths so we have to make sure
we enable a bgp ad path feature on
on the router effector servers so that
the router reflected clients
the pes and cs nodes and crs have full
view of the topology so that they can do
um packet flow load sharing across all
the pads
all the ecmp pads we have also rolled
out a bgp
pick feature with vgp pick
feature what it does in addition to the
best path
it also um pick a second
backup path and install the backup path
in the fib
so that if the primary path goes away we
already have a backup path in the
hardware
you don't have to wait for the bgp
convergence and so you
you swing to the backup path immediately
so we enable bgp pick to get the better
convergence
and also we need to enable um bgp pick
multipath
because now we have a ecmp
we have four nodes or eight nodes
depending on number of spine nodes we
have
we have a lot more paths so we have to
make sure the bgp
installs the ecmps of primary patch if
there are four ecmp paths
we installed four bgp uh primary paths
then a
second our backup path which is not part
of this acmp group so we are enabled
that
bgp fake multipath feature for that
and we're also working with the vendors
to get additional features and
enhancements
to optimize our convergence
so when we turn on bgpr path
the number of uh bgp path explodes
now now you have a lot of ecmp paths a
lot of bgp speakers
so then the number of uh bgp path
explodes to reduce the path
the more bgp path you have it takes long
time to compute
and run through the algorithm and pick
the right
best path in during failure scenarios so
it impacts the convergence numbers so to
reduce the bgp patch
uh we we are rolling out the anycast bgp
next top
so what it is is that we would pick an
ip that is configured to say any cast
among all the cs nodes
within the site and that way um
the rrs and the pes and the remote crs
local seals crs and remote crs would see
one vgp pad with the next up uh anycast
so we were able to reduce the pgp path
by using any cast
vgp next half
but when we enable any cast there's one
corner case where we could impact a
traffic
um we have to make sure if there is a
link flap if there is a bgp
flat um the anycast address is not used
for that path until the entire bgp table
is converged
you know it takes this good amount of
time to download
um 1.5 million paths and run through the
bgp algorithm to put the right path so
it
takes some time during that time during
the convergence time we don't want to
send any traffic through the
path um so how we address that we are
we are trying to we are tying bgp state
are the triggers
to the anycast advertisement so if if
there is a link flap on cs1
we have to make sure the cs1 is not
being used as an active path
we would wait for the incomplete
convergence of bgp before we inject
any test into the igp domain um so we
are using
any advertisement with triggers
and bgp state the other option we were
we were we have deployed is
advertised bgp paths
with different policies only the local
nodes need to know the full topology of
of
the local cluster so we are advertising
the full view
onto the local nodes local clients but
the remote clusters remote rrs are the
remote clusters they don't need to know
every path
inside the local local class cluster so
what we're doing there we are
advertising only the best and backup
path
to the remote peers and advertise full
view or full paths to the local clients
that way we have a
better control on how many paths we
advertise to the remote
rrs we are still actively
working with our vendors to find other
ways to reduce the bgp paths
um so we can keep optimizing as we go
along
um provisioning and support automation
and operations automation is it's really
it's a critical uh component here we got
to make sure we have automation
to support this class deployments and
there are four categories
we need automation to launch devices
we need automation to roll out
configuration
into the devices we need automation to
do cable validations there's a lot of
cabling now
and we also need automation to do code
upgrades
so we have uh we have made a lot of good
progress with automation
but we still need to work through a few
things as well um
when it comes to operations uh we
realized that we probably need more than
snmp
we need to start collecting data
from the routers in a different
perspective because now we are
monitoring
a whole cluster that could be 50 nodes
inside the cluster but we need to find a
way to
get data from all those routers and
correlate them and show them as a single
cluster
so we started looking into telemetry
data streaming
we were able to successfully get data to
those routers
we are pushing those telemetry streams
into
into a collector and that goes into a
database and we are
we are starting to use the data data
sets that we collect using telemetry
data
data streams um
before the change here before if there
is a fabric problem in a big multi
chassis or big box we would just make a
phone call to our vendors
and have them to figure out the problem
and fix but with the class
architecture now we get exposed to the
fabric problems and we it's on us to
troubleshoot monitor troubleshoot and
fix all the fabric the fabric issues
between the spine and leaf modes so it's
a little
bit complex than how we were operating
before with a single
chassis design
so a little more on this and the support
here uh we need to make sure
we have all the tool sets um available
to our operations team to monitor this
class cluster and we have to make sure
we group all the routers in the
in a cluster and show them as a single
unit
um so that we can find the health of the
cluster
um and this is it's critical because
if if the cluster is not um if we lose
one of the spine we got to make sure we
notify that to our operations
that cluster isn't in a in a failure uh
uh situation we can have one more
failure in that clusters
um so we got to make sure how we monitor
these class components and we got to
build the
dashboards and tools and to show the
entire group of routers
as a single srg
so we started thinking how do we monitor
this class so we were able to come up
with
five pillars um starting from the
hardware
software routing protocols links
and and traffic um i'll go more details
about each pillar in following slides
so in a hardware if you look at any of
this new um
asics coming out there are a lot of
components and components inside the
hardware
a6 um there are resources there are
memory cables
sliced for different applications for
example pecan
lem lpm fec and there are port buffers
we use
inside the the chipset
and there are qos buffers we need to
monitor
um so there's a lot of hardware
components we need to monitor
to make sure the hardware is working
fine um
to the level we expected we are expected
to them to behave
um so we are we are looking into
some of the telemetry data streams to
monitor um
these components and to give us
visibility to the
hardware uh health
uh likewise the software we are looking
ways to monitor
the smooth upgrades the smooth running
in the box the signature
check of the software and also the bugs
um and this under all other software
process
processes
then it comes to the routing protocol
now now we have
a you know a group of spine a bunch of
fleas we have isis
lldp running on those fabric links so we
have to monitor to make sure
we track all the link failures node
failures
um um all the protocol states
um and also we need to start monitoring
we had to monitor the bgp sessions their
states
the prefixes received advertised between
the bgp session
between between the bgp peers and also
start looking into the router
uh trend to see how stable the route
the network is so we have to watch all
those uh
routing details um the churn and
the isis database and bgp table
of all the flaps going on so i get to
monitor them
um so that gives the visibility to the
routing protocols
then the links so we
we have to monitor as i said before you
know we didn't have to worry about the
fabric
links inside a box now with the spine
and lift we have to monitor those fabric
links
and we are to check the redundancy for
those fabrics if
one of the spine goes out we have to
monitor we have to monitor and notify
the team to make sure you know they get
fixed
and also there are a lot of optics here
now involved we have to monitor the
receive and transmit power of the optics
uh the health of the optics um
and see any any trend that we can pick
up for any issues
and the last pillar is the traffic so as
i was talking about ecmp paths now
uh you have to make sure that the
traffic is load shared among all the
among all ecmp pads properly we got to
make sure that
the packets and bits coming into the
cluster are being
routed out of the cluster without any
drops internally
we have to monitor the drops
interface drops now zero drops ttl drops
no
no route drops cures drops and hardware
drops so we got to monitor all these
drops
to understand what's going on inside the
cluster
uh one thing we found in the lab testing
was that
during the convergence when when you
have multi-level bgp sessions
if there is a failure then the bgp has
to advertise the failure to the remote
to the router effector servers and they
would have to pass on that
failure to the remote rrs and to their
local uh
clients that takes a little bit of a
little bit of time the convergence
so during this convergence the only way
to figure out if there are any problem
with the the traffic is looking into the
micro loops if there is a micro loop
happening
inside the network the ttl uh drop count
would go
high so we we started looking into this
ttl numbers to understand the
convergence
and start figuring out uh different
options to bring down the convergence
number or the recovery time
and so that um the conver so that
we impact the impact of our customer is
reduced so the ttl drop
um the no route drop the qrs drops are
critical
data points for us to look into the
health of the class
the next slide shows some of the graphs
that we started building again we are
very early into this telemetry streaming
uh project the first thing we needed to
do
was to find out all the data points we
want to collect from the routers
there are hundreds of thousands of data
points that router can stream out today
but we have to pick and choose what we
are interested in
we don't want to just dump everything
out of the router then figuring out
you know too much data to process
so based on the pillar i was talking
about earlier
we are uh we are we are we have
identified those sensor points we have
configured the sensor points on the
routers
now we have those streamings coming out
of the routers at every
30 seconds to 60 seconds we can go down
to even
10 seconds but that's too too much i
think i thought
so we starting we are starting with 30
seconds and some routers for some
sensors
some center points but other ones we are
starting with 60 second
intervals so we are we have turned up
a collector it's an open source
collector from cisco big money
um that takes all these teams and we are
processing them put them
populating at the influx db database and
i was able to create some of the graphs
here
that i show and now you can see the isis
adjacency within the cluster there are
four spines
and you can see the total um isis count
um aggregated for the cluster and you
can see the traffic
load sharing among all the leaf nodes
um and also per leaf node view you can
see the traffic split across
all four nodes and then on the right
side you have the bgp routes received
we have the fabric bandwidth being um
monitored
by lltp data and also we have the qos
drops
graph that shows you know if there is
any drop going on with qos we would get
them here instantly
so these are the some sample graphs we
are building but there are a lot of work
to be done here
so now we have the data in the database
now we need to find
find a way to build the tools and
dashboards that can send right triggers
to our operations team to react for any
failures
um just want to give you that preview
here with the slides
the graphs um so that
uh takes us to the last slide um we have
the
next gen core cluster uh spinal leaf
architecture deployed
broadly in our comcast platform uh it's
it's been there uh
serving a customer's carrying production
big uh for a for a while now
um we were able to upgrade code on these
boxes
uh during the day time um we were able
to manage the traffic utilization
because now we don't have a single uh
router failure
impacting multiple paths anymore we the
blast rate is as small as we were able
to manage the
traffic utilization properly some of the
lessons learned
automation is the key
need better process and tools for
operations
and there's a lot of cabling work to be
done so
we have to make sure we have all the
tool set in place to
um to track those cables to fix if there
are any issues with the cable in on day
one
so we use telemetry data set for that um
again the design is built to last longer
so
one of the learning is that you get all
your physical work done on day one so
you don't want to go back
and change physical cabling later
in the in the later in the time so
if you can get the physical work done
it's easy to deploy
more leaf nodes if needed and expand the
class class cluster
to support the demands that brings me to
the last slide i just wanted to thank
you
for the opportunity to share our
our evolution of backbone getting
comcast
i i thank uh augie and and tony tauber
and other folks who helped me this is my
first
nana presentation they helped me
to navigate the process and make me
comfortable to present this
thank you
[Music]
we have a few questions and if you have
any more please put them in the q a
channel now and i will relate them as we
get to them
uh so the first question is from dan
magorian who is asking
how could inbox and between box speeds
be similar when
same ship port to port is much faster
oh if i understood the question is he
asking if if he's asking
did we see any change in uh the speed of
processing
is in in different um boxes
i think he's asking more about how you
can get enough
bandwidth between boxes um in a
multi-node deployment versus a single
dropbox type of device
uh with with morse spines
uh we were able to with more notes we
were able to get more
more ports serving the you know the
service ports we call
uh we were able to expand the spines um
as we
um as we need to increase the bandwidth
we can expand the spine and and grow
horizontally to
support the additional ports yes we have
we have to spend
we have to use the force to interconnect
the spine and leaf
but i think if you scale enough and
vertically can support the service ports
okay matt p tech is asking
you say dashboards and tools should
monitor the entire group of
routers in the clusters as a single srlg
but you created an n plus one spine so
that you could fail
individual spines out without causing
impact if the whole cluster is in a
single slrg
when you have a spine failure do you
fail everything out or ignore it because
you have
n plus one redundancy internally to the
cluster
uh we don't actually so if there is one
spine failure we don't drain traffic
but we all we all we do need to mark or
tag
that group as a as a different state uh
it's not green anymore
it has it has one spine failed so we
have to mark and tag it differently so
that our operations team
keep an eye on the cluster to bring the
spine back up
and also will stop them to make any
changes to the cluster
to avoid any uh impact
thank you chris summers is asking uh
what streaming telemetry are you trying
gnmi
config and do you find consistent
multiple vendors support
no so open conflict we use wherever we
can but again it doesn't give us every
uh data points that we want to monitor
uh
so we are dipping into the and models
vendor specific
end models uh there are
we find a little inconsistent between
the vendors
it's you know but we have to pick and
choose the right models
from a vendor-specific uh perspective um
until we get the open config coverage
for all the data points
that you would need to see let's see
michael doherty is asking
are you integrating any rpki or prefix
validation into your redesign either on
the ingress or egress
so there's no change in rpk deployments
approach
we are we are still keeping how we've
been deploying rpki and
age so there's no change um with this
deployment and how we've been handling
apk development
okay shredder hegde is asking
what is the impact of bringing costs
into our network
on traffic engineering paths do you have
te deployed on
in the core and any thoughts about
placing pe pass in the class
we do not we don't have te support yet
but it's something we're actually
looking into
this part of the network experience is
doing pure ip routing
um now we have the topology set
we are looking to uh see how we could
use
sr um to solve some of the
key requirements that would come up in
future
let's see brian holloway is asking you
mentioned keeping an eye on your
l2 isis database are you considering
l1 l2 l1 or
did you have something else in mind it's
one of the options on the table that
we're looking into so if needed we can
we can break it into big l two domain
into l1 and l2
and manage the database that way it's
one of the options we are
we are considering okay and we're almost
out of time but we have time for a
couple more questions so i'll get as
many as i can here
let's see uh would you please
give more details on how you are
monitoring qos drop
so one of the vendor blocks that we are
have deployed
there is a data point sensor uh
telemetry sensor uh
uh data point uh sensor path available
to us so we are watching all the cue
drops
um for for all the queues
um all the qos queues we have in our
network
by looking at those cube drops we have
an idea what's going on is it
the queue drop related to a convergence
is it
something else going on in the network
so we are using the data point
to monitor the queues
cheers okay ronan dobbins asks can you
talk about the design and scale of your
telemetry export collection network
infrastructure for all the various forms
of
telemetry you're doing uh it's still
really early so we are learning right
now so we are streaming
uh about 100 to 200 rounds now about 100
plus routers
sending telemetry streams to a collector
uh
all uh data points are stream data
every uh 30 seconds some data points of
30 seconds are the data points of 60
seconds
so it is a lot of data we are uh
keeping like seven days from right hour
five to seven days retention so we
do drop those uh data points after seven
days after we process them
uh so but it's a only early stage and we
are still trying to understand
the scale we need to deploy to support
the telemetry to retain
the data longer time longer period okay
and one last
last question from blake willis any more
details on how you any cast bgp next
hops in the core please
sure so if you have um
if you have like eight um paths to an
ebtp session
an external network you would learn um
like all the pgp prefixes from the from
that bgp pair
and you would have eight different next
stop and with the add path enable
now you're going to send eight paths um
times number of prefix you would get
from the customer from the
as external ais um so this
multiplies you know if you have more and
more spines more and more external
appears
uh more prefixes coming in um
the number of bgp path explodes so what
we are doing instead we are
using an anycast virtual anycast ip per
cluster
and we are setting that anycast as a
next stop bgp next up so now we go from
my eight paths
to one path with any cast which we next
start
so that way we were able to control the
bgp paths in our core network with this
class deployments
all right thank you um we're out of time
for questions but uh if
any of you have anything else uh please
continue in the chat or
contact him offline