[Music]
so welcome ladies and gentlemen friends
and colleagues
this is our rir panel
for an analog 81 virtual a a panel that
we
probably might not have been easily been
able to do any other way
we have people literally from all over
the world at all different
times of day or night or morning to talk
about
irr tech and we have
all of the irrs represented here is a
list of those folks at the top
uh in alphabetical order by rr i'm going
to let them each do their own brief
introduction this is
their contact information uh which i'm
sure they'll welcome
a uh email if you'd like to have a quick
follow-up with them but they may point
you
to a more general alias if it's more irr
operationally related
if you do contact them i hope you'll at
least offer them some kudos for doing
this
very generous of their their time to do
so my name is john kristoff there's my
contact information down below if you
need to reach out to me
i work at depaul university i also am a
phd candidate student at university of
illinois chicago
i run a project called dataplan.org and
some other stuff
and that's all i'm really going to say
about me because it's not about me it's
about the irr so let's
let's talk to our friends at the irrs
so let me go over i'm going to just kind
of go in the order that my windows
are displaying each one of you
and i'll just ask each of you to just
briefly do your own little introduction
say your names
which are you represent and then if you
would
possibly uh maybe tell us one thing
unique about the ira that you represent
maybe something that uh
is distinct maybe something interesting
maybe something good maybe something bad
uh maybe something new uh whatever you
can think of off the top of your head
would be happy to hear it so i'll start
with you carlos
you're first in my window okay
thank you john um thank you for the
introduction and thank you for the
opportunity of doing this panel
and thank you for being a part of nano
which is
a conference an event and community i've
looked up to
for many years actually my name is
carlos martinez i
i'm based in montevideo uruguay i'm the
chief technology officer for
lucknick landing is the area responsible
for
uh latin america and parts of the
caribbean uh we share
the caribbean in a strange way to say
something
uh with uh my friends from irene
um something unique about lucknick
well i i think there are a couple of
things that i
think make lagning a bit different
lagning is one of the
younger rirs
began operations in 2002 it actually was
actually incorporated as an organization
uh in 2002 it's rather young
and the other thing that i think makes
us a bit different is that we
conduct business in three different
languages which
always presents interesting
sets of challenges when trying to breach
parts of our community we have a
significant part of our community
which speaks portuguese our brazilian
brazilian membership
we have obviously spanish community
and all we also have some english
speaking countries in our
region like belize and trinidad and
tobago for example
so i think that makes uh different in a
way
uh in in a way interesting
because uh actually have had the
opportunity of
visiting places and meeting folk that
otherwise
i would never probably been there like
that for example the
the netherlands netherland islands in
the caribbean which is
quite interesting that's very good
next in my window george if if you would
introduce yourself please
hi everyone um i'm george michelson i'm
the product manager at ap nick 4
registry
and that covers off on core registry
product
maintenance of the record keeping but
also services like who is the internet
routing registry
rpki rdap um
we also we have quite an interesting
structure here in ap nick we're a
federal structure with national
registries and so i'm in charge of the
technical liaison function for those
guys as well
and we also do back end tier 2 support
for the frontline service delivery
as you can tell i'm a british australian
i've been here about 34 years and 20 of
them
i spent working in the rir system so
ap nick we were the second regional
internet registry to come into existence
after the ripe ncc
we've got about 56 economies in our
membership
we have this more complex structure than
a lot of nano members might be used to
with aaron and
ripe and afronic because we have that
pre-existing national structure
four of them in fact were founders of ap
nick
that's jp nick k nick t w nick and c and
nick and three have formed since
18 that came into being that's vienna
nick id nick in indonesia and erin in
india
we've got about um somewhere around 20
000 participating asset holders internet
number resource holders in our
region and it's pretty much 50 50
between
direct membership and the members of the
national internet registry
something that people might not realize
about the asian footprint is that we
have a much more complex structure now
we've been checking industry subtypes
and classic isp telco mobile
it's actually only about 30 35
of our overall membership a lot more
direct ownership of addresses is now in
fintech
or in the data center that's probably
amazon the content holders those guys
government related service people who
have no
core routing knowledge maybe holding
asset and relying on other people to do
the routing for them
and that's made for a bit of a change in
how we think about service delivery
because we're not dealing with people
all the time who are in the classic
nog community we're dealing with people
who have to have one of these
weirdo internet numbery things but they
don't actually know what to do with it
and it means we've kind of shifted some
of our service focus a bit
anyway that's enough about me that's
fascinating
thank you very much next in my my window
going
uh clockwise for me would be uh you
felipe
so my name is felipe i'm the chief
operations officer
at the ipcc i'm responsible for
registry operations which includes all
the management of
internet thermal resources and also
software development activities which
include things like
rpki who is routing registry
and all the internal software as well
like the lr portal
rage to software and so on
uh the rypncc is the original internet
registry for
europe middle east parts of central asia
and russia which makes us quite
a diverse rer
with many different cultures
participating
which brings its uh own challenges
from the point of view of the
geopolitical challenges
uh and so on um we are
the oldest uh rar i think were founded
in
1992 and
uh we have uh at around uh 20
000 members and a little bit more than
23 000
uh lar accounts i think that's
it for me thank you
mark if you would uh sure
so i'm mark hosters i'm the cto of erin
um
and basically i'm responsible for all of
engineering operations within
within there so whether it's development
or operations
or even i.t support within our
organization that
is under my umbrella so uh sort of
a little bit of stuff about me is um
in 1991 i worked for this place called
the dod neck
and in 1992 i remember this guy named
daniel carenberg from this organization
named ripe
come over and say hey i want to start
actually
pulling data from you guys because i
want to run a registry in
dealing with with europe and i was like
oh this sounds really cool okay let
let's see what we could do and a little
bit later there's this guy named
david conrad who did the same thing for
ap nick
so so it was uh i basically i've been on
the ground floor of this since 1991
i helped put aaron together in my spare
time
uh after hours while i was working for
rare sign i would come over and help set
up aaron
and now here i find myself actually
working for air
so it's a great place to be so thank you
thank you mark last but not least hello
amrish
uh thank you john um so yeah thank you
for the opportunity giving um
to afronic today um actually it's my
first time participating to nano
and i'm i've always been on the
on the mailing list um but now uh it's
good to be
uh live basically uh so afric
uh as you know is the youngest rio we
established business i think in 2005
uh and uh obviously we got
help from uh our friends the all other
rios to to set up our operations and
we are quite thankful for that as well
um uh
what else from our predictors we
might be one of the lost rios to still
have rpv4
uh i think just over two million
uh addresses remaining uh which we think
will be depleted soon um
right now we are in a phase called
a soft landing phase phase two actually
of the soft landing phase where we are
only
allocating very small pieces of ipv4
um i myself work in the research
department so i'm
leading data analytics projects and also
doing research
on many different aspects of the
internet from rpki to
uh performance to security uh
yeah that's about it thank you john okay
thank you amish i wonder if uh by
mentioning
you have ipv4 you'll see an influx of
some new potential
members and customers coming towards you
let's see
but i i want to remind you and the
audience here that
what i think we'll find too as we
broadcast this those who are watching
this know that this isn't live
um that there'll be people from not only
the north american region the the
typical man out of attendee but
but we've seen an additional influx of
people from all over the world so it'll
be good
for them to not only see their own uh
irs represented but
those who they they want to interact
with as well
okay so i'm going to start firing off a
few questions i'll try to get in a few
i'll try to make it equitable to get
around to everybody
you feel the interrupt or bring
something up if
if you want to add something of course
i'll target one person in
particular but we'll try to go around
robin more or less
in some worldly fashion we
probably have about maybe 20 or so
minutes
i don't want to monopolize the time and
trespass on the time when i hope will be
some good follow-up questions by the
live q a when this
when this does get broadcast on the day
of the
conference so let me start with you
george you'll be the lucky contestant
number one
um it's one of the things that people
maybe know a little bit less about is
how
of you i assume you all know each other
reasonably well or
the colleagues of each other reason be
well
and you have ways i assume of working
together and cooperating and one of
those ways i think
is through the nro what is the nro
so the nro is the
collective entity that was formed by the
individual
rirs to give some coherence and cohesion
to provision of service and application
of policy under a regional structure
we are all independent bodies all the
rirs are independent and we're really
quite fiercely independent we respect
our local members priorities and
preferences
i've had the luxury of going to other
rir meetings
boy they are feisty in ways you wouldn't
expect there's kind of local issues but
there is of course that global
address policy context and there's
global alignment issues
facing things like the istar ietf
icann you know interactions across that
space it's useful to have a converged
body
and we did a lightweight
construction here rather than making a
heavyweight body that sat on top of us
and had its own infrastructure and had
its own costs it's a
really small secretariat function it's
pretty much one or two people a general
manager
um herman who operates from ap nick's
territory he actually worked in lac nick
for years and years he's been involved
in more than one region
and we have a communications specialist
who works in us i think from memory that
also may now come from the lac region
but it has been someone from the ripe
region and we kind of carve up delivery
of functions between us
so for a while a converged statistics
and delegation report was being made in
ap
nick there were some issues in the
software control process and reflections
of how that worked for different
registries
that job moved to the ripe region and
they've done a huge reinvestment
implementing the design and the delivery
of a converged statistics report for the
nro
so things like that happen and we
operate working groups by function we
have an engineering coordination group
it's the one we all talk
in we meet at um ietf meetings typically
and we have an
annual offside where we coordinate a
worksheet
and that's helped us deliver things like
rdap
the new json format for the same data
and who is and to deliver convergence in
our services across things like rpki
and also to converge the delivery of how
we communicate key messages in address
management out to the wider community
but we have a communications working
group and the registry services working
group
they've been looking at a thing called
ithi
which is internet health measurement
something an initiative that i can
started
and we've taken that on board and are
now looking into our data services
to reflect the same kind of thing so
it's a lightweight
small coordinating body and we just seem
to make it work it's really pretty
effective
okay that seemed like a pretty complete
answer but if anyone else has anything
to add feel free to
chime in hey marish
let me ask you a question there was a
interesting report that came out of
your irr recently this who is uh audit
what was this all about what can you
tell us about that why was it and why
was it interesting noteworthy
yeah indeed um uh so
uh recently so afrenic published a
report called the who is
accuracy report uh it's basically an
audit that
uh afferent carried out um so the audit
started a couple
of months ago when there was some um
alleged fraud uh of ibf e4 so ipv4
were misappropriated and basically
um somewhere in 2019
basically the fbi conducted the supreme
court of mauritius where afrinic is
based to
to start um an invis an investigation
based on um some complaints that they
receive um from from researchers
uh in the us so this is where affinic
started the
uh a full full on audit and actually
discovered that
uh there was uh indeed misappropriation
of
actually before uh agrispace and
unfortunately this was done
uh by a former uh afrinic employee
who actually had host master rights so
that person was able to access the
database
um
in an unauthorized fashion um
unfortunately
um yes so
this ip audit enable us to
understand which ip address space
were allocated to organizations
without having a proper we call it a
registration service agreement with
afrinic and without having
any trail of tickets being open
and so on and so forth and we have also
seen that
a lot of the uh space
that were misappropriated were actually
doomed space so they were not even
appearing on the routing table
so they were either in the african pool
in the available athletic pool or they
were
legacy space um so legacy space as you
know
space that have been allocated to
organizations
prior to the establishment of the arrio
system
and some of them are used some of them
on the queues uh
so um they were part of the
space that were actually uh misused
so the the report um is to create some
transparency around
uh the events what what happened and
what are the
the next steps in terms of strengthening
access to
to the database and um improving the
process
uh so that such things do not happen
again
yeah i hope people who haven't checked
it out check it out i think it was
something very valuable and i think the
community
owes you a bit of gratitude for
producing that i think it was very
interesting
carlos except for america i suppose who
still has some ipv4 addresses
i think there was a time years ago when
uh that that
run out was imminent uh for most of us
that some people questioned what are the
irs going to do they're not going to
have any more addresses to deal out
there what's their job going to be
so now that the the v4 exhaustion is
pretty much complete
is has your work changed are you doing
less can you
can you just sit back and relax now
what's happening
what's changed about the role now that
you don't have before addresses
that's that's a very interesting
question right right now i would say
i i cannot say that our work has changed
or actually gone down in any way i think
we are working more than ever
uh although it's true that it's too
early in the
usa run out process to actually
to actually tell because we are still
seeing some
allocations uh we have this waiting list
uh we
are still doing some might be before
locations out of
uh recovered space revoked space and um
and some um allocations that were being
analyzed before
the actual uh run out people are
requesting more ipv6 which is
interesting
i just uh i was really early today i was
reading a report by
uh jeff houston from ipedic
which details the registry operations
for all their irs
in 2020 and actually i was
very surprised to see that lagning was
the rail that assigned
most had the most richest three
allocations performed on ipv6 not
necessarily the biggest space
but the individual registry operations
uh lagne was the
railroad that made the most allocations
of ipv6 in 2020
which was rather you know
surprising in an interesting way um
we are seeing a lot of demand for our
other type of services for example rpki
rpki has
usage has been growing a lot
during the past two years and it's right
now this actually demanding
a lot of engineering effort from my team
we have an interesting historical
anomaly in lagnik we didn't operate
a routing registry for historical
reasons i'm not exactly sure i tried to
research why
it was that way but lagning was the only
rir that didn't operate the routine
registry and a couple of years ago we
decided to do something about that
and we are now operating a
simplified i would say routine registry
that basically feeds
or creators synthetizes our psl objects
out of rpki information and that has
that has seen a lot of uptake in usage
and
um again we are facing another another
challenge that we
which is um providing these services
across the region because we also have
some
nirs and we have the challenge of
integrating
uh these services across not only our
own membership but the membership of the
nis which
presents its own set of challenges uh we
recently
for example um a year and a few months
ago
we started providing um in coordination
with nick brazil
rpki services for uh for the
membership in brazil um
and we've been working with our friends
in mexico for providing rpka in mexico
as well
and right now for the last
year and a half i would say we've been
finally able to provide our pka service
throughout the region and uh
yeah i i have the feeling that we are
working more than ever
eventually i i think i believe things
will
probably settle down at some point but
uh
probably not in the in the next few
years i'm not so sure that's true but
i'm glad you're busy
can i come in there john of course so
i think carlos is hiding his his light
under the bushel because he's actually
been doing a huge amount of work doing
development work as well he's got an
activity that's about network security
that lachnik does
building capacity inside his community
to have better resilience against the
attacks they're doing amazing work there
he's been funding development of code in
rpki that's become really significant in
our footprint
and it's kind of it's not a competition
but it kind of is a competition between
us for instance aaron did heaps
and heaps of work specifying api
bindings for service delivery for
members using rest and json
we've been looking at that and we're
thinking wow how can we leverage things
from that
ripe ncc they did all the groundwork
developing
rpsl-based systems and their engine of
running that whois service and routing
registry
we got hold of that and operate a fork
of that code i think afronick are using
parts of that code as well so we all
kind of
leverage tech off each other like carlos
our actual transactional work with
holders of addresses
just hasn't gone away and it's kind of
two-faced there's the part which is we
have a huge
legacy of holders that have basically
not kept data up to date
it might not be entirely the same in
aaron but they have the
lrsa and they have all of that pre-aaron
registry state
we've got a similar story in fact aaron
did an amazing job of helping all of us
the second comers get
that data and incorporate it a lot of
that data is very old
and so there's a kind of job there
keeping those records up to date
the other thing is no isp wants to
terminate the abuse phone calls when
someone says what is that ip doing on my
house and they're all building customer
more specific records about who's really
using
the the information we don't have a
mechanism like swip
so or our who is so there's a whole
bunch of transactional work in ap
nick keeping on top of how do i document
the real users of the resource
who are live in the network it's more
than just bgp
and that's a lot of help desk work and a
lot of human interaction work
so yeah we still all have jobs well i'm
glad you said that
and i i was a leading question i i know
that you guys are more than
busy this is an opportunity for you to
tell everyone else how much your actual
work you're doing i knew rpki was one of
those things and i'm glad you brought
that up
that was actually maybe one of my
questions i'll ask you felipe is
what are the the things that's come up
from time to time i think in a few of
the different regions
um and there's a couple on a few of the
different mailing lists
is the um is the
because each irr is it is a trust anchor
and uh you know act independently as a
as a trust anchoring
and the processes behind how you run ap
care i think people are still trying to
um better understand maybe maybe you're
trying to also better implement
so tell us a little bit about maybe um
the process
of um how you how you may do
testing verification um
and and maybe something about how uh
roads get pushed out what's that what do
those processes look like
maybe from going back a little ways and
where are we headed
what how are the how are the irs moving
in in that direction to
really improve the rpki
yeah it's a very good question and i'm
taking a hook from uh what carlos said
before
since a couple of years ago we have been
experienced a
very huge growth in rpi
uh usage within our region
so i did some homework for the sessions
i got some numbers
so just to get some ideas it took us
eight years to go from zero uh to ten
thousand arrows
so from 2011 until june
2019 and then took one and a half years
to double that amount
and we can see that over the last two
years that you can see this
huge exponential growth
and because of that experience more
pressure
to operate trust anchor not only in
terms of
availability uh resiliency and so on
but also in terms of integrity like the
integrity of the trust anchor
and the integrity of our processes
so since uh mostly beginning of last
year when we got
some funding secured from our
board uh we have been working uh harder
in terms of increasing the the
resiliency
and the security of our trust anchor uh
so we're running a project that is
calling uh rpk residency
and one of the things that we are doing
is uh defining
an audit framework uh for rpki
we're partnering partnering with a third
party
which is called a brief standards
institution
and together with them we're defining a
sock 2
type 2 audit report and the idea with
that
is that you can have relevant controls
uh for how to audit uh our internal
processes
uh sorry in the middle of this process
today like tailoring made
this kind of report and then later
this year we're going to hire another
company
that is going to actually uh audit us
that's one of the initiatives that we
had last year we have
many others in place another challenge
that we have in terms more
of infrastructure we run most of our
user infrastructure
in our data centers in amsterdam but
if you really want to be highly
available we want to leverage data
centers
all across the world so we're looking
into deploying uh
our infrastructure to the cloud so
looking mostly into aws
and how we can leverage on their
multi-region
infrastructure so in case of one of the
regions
is unavailable we can fail over to a
different region
but you also don't want to be fully
dependent on
a single cloud provider so we also want
to be able
to keep running the infrastructure in
our own data centers
so in case there is an unavailability
from the cloud provider we can also fail
over
uh to our own infrastructure and uh keep
running
from there does it fit just maybe a
question for all of you
perhaps um hopefully they maybe they'll
direct it to you since you just answered
do we first see the trust anchors in
particular
getting to a point where where the root
system for the dns is massively
scaled through things like anycast do we
anticipate something like that for trust
anchors
one day perhaps not so much for
mode but maybe even for for resiliency
from
security threats like a service attack
is that where we're headed you think
uh i'll sort of uh sort of chime in here
and yeah yes our repositories are things
that need to be highly scaled up
as we grow and and we're seeing growth
all of us are seeing growth on the
number of fetches that
are going across our infrastructures and
making sure that we're ahead of the
curve
and and uh someday we will be as
massively scalable
um maybe not to the extent that uh the
root servers are
um quite but it would be in a different
way
um but that is something that we are
looking
to do and are in the process of doing
actually
so i feel phillip a has actually been
working on
on stuff um growing things through
aws we've been working through google so
it just gives you sort of an idea
of the the sort of the the big
differences that we have but yet we're
all working on similar sort of ideas and
concepts
very good let's continue mark
you're you've been brought up in the
context of rdap what's the state of who
is in rdap
uh so uh who is is um
when you look at directory services in
general
um there's been lots of forays in this
space so who is has been a protocol
that's been around for
forever and basically you ask a queer
and you get back
response a very simple protocol and so
people have been using this for years
and
and one of the things that you don't get
out of it is like hey
where's this ip address 193 something
rather
where is that coming from and it's like
oh yeah that's in the right region how
do you know that
um and so one of the things that was
very early in the
process was this thing called a referral
who is saying well
we might not have the data but kind of
like similar mem
mirroring dns let's go ahead and show
you
where a better place to go to get that
information that didn't quite work out
as well as it
um it did but the latest foray in this
is actually using
basically a web version of of
of that sort of similar framework using
json
actually saying hey if i have the data
i'll give it to you if i don't have the
data i'll send a redirect so you can get
the data from a closer place
uh so that is work that's been underway
in the itf it's actually going through
the standards process now so there's
lots
lots of good forward progress on that
front not only from
the registries but also the domain
registries
so they're also very much involved in
this
so it brings on lots of new uh uh things
that actually people can
uh sort of leverage internationalization
being one
and another one being uh dealing with
pro
better ideas of privacy because right
now
anyone can see the data and who is and
there's no sort of security access
associated with it with art app you can
actually create those sort of access
controls if you wish
uh so so there's a lot more potential
there than we have
with our traditional whois service okay
again there's probably a couple of
follow-up questions to this go ahead
george
mark is kind of hiding his slide under
the bushel because a lot of the heavy
lifting
in that standards work got done by aaron
tech staffers they've taken a strong
lead in doing that core protocol
development work
i think it was a massive benefit to the
wider community
and we've all taken on board this idea
of converging
how we do things for various reasons who
is kind of fractured a bit and these
structural elements
of how we returned answers in who is
they just didn't
really quite line up we had different
language in our region to talk about
things
so if you're on the consumer side trying
to read and pass who is you're facing
that barrier they do it a bit different
in lac nick
aaron is not exactly like right coming
to our dap
we've got this golden opportunity to
come to some agreement
how do we tell you this is the asset
holder of the internet address
what's the structural element here in
json machine passable
it's really a golden moment for
improving that kind of service delivery
and those guys they did a lot of work to
get this right
so the other thing is for reasons that i
still don't understand
aaron they terminate like 50 or 60
of all the queries in rdap and then they
have to say oh
no that's not with us you've got to go
over here so even though there's a
global steerage file right up in the top
aaron is still having to do a lot of the
traffic management to get the queries to
us
it's just weird yeah yeah so so we
share numbers from time to time and what
george is saying
the numbers that we see are are quite
high
so it's uh we see 1800 queries per
second
across our directory services
constellation uh
just gives you an idea of of the scale
that we're dealing with
um and it's more than just one site we
have a three sites right now
um and in each site those aren't udp
query
dns queries those are no those are tcp
queries and yeah
and and actually the queries themselves
are quite complicated
it's not it's not a hash sort of
response that can go back off of queries
and it's it's it's of course https it's
encrypted http
complex json it's it's rather heavy it's
not a simple udp packet
so it looks easy from the user side and
we're all going to be very grateful from
a tool building perspective this you
mentioned or someone
mentioned this idea of privacy are
is there a risk that that that goes too
far there's a lot of complaints about
who is privacy because of gdpr
are are we gonna end up in the same
position with
address and asn uh direct information
where
you know where it's redacted for reasons
that are
unhelpful for various kinds of analysis
investigation
is is that a real risk that was its
potential
for that to be a risk i think we'd be
wrong to say oh no no
that couldn't happen because we face
legal pressures i mean ripe in
particular with gdpr but also aaron
they've got ccpa the californian
obligations
we can be told in the regime the
political
economic environment we work in by an
authority
you have to change so there is the risk
but the thing is one of the standards in
rdap is the idea of using
federated authentication oauth
and if we go with that model and adopt
that framework people who
need to know law enforcement legal
track and trace isps who need to do
technical
contact they can identify and it could
be they identify in aaron
and their token is usable inside
aphronic or in ripe or in ap nic or
laknik
we can do that kind of federated
authentication
model and uncover the data that if
you're just a casual user
we kind of have obligations to hide so
we do
we know there's the potential for a loss
of public view of this data
but we're thinking ahead about ways we
could maybe handle that
respectfully because privacy is a pretty
big deal some of the people who hold the
dresses
they're actually individuals they're not
legal entities
if you go into who is you don't see
corpco
in portland oregon sending you packets
you see
randy bush because he holds the assets
as an individual
and that's a pretty massive breach of
privacy so
we have to be careful about this you
know
thank you george let me we're we're kind
of coming close to the end of our time
here so let me ask uh one question for
the group and then
uh maybe one more kind of closing
question
i think it's quite clear and obvious
that you all are working on
some really cool stuff some of the
future stuff like the rpk and some of
the changes are adapted
i think it's kind of fascinating and you
and you do things maybe necessarily not
strictly
irr related than some cases i know but
particularly does all kinds of stuff for
instance
what kind of opportunities might someone
[Music]
be appealed to working with
your irr either full-time do you
i don't know how big you are and how
much hiring you do um but what sort of
uh technical opportunities might there
be this is your pitch to make
for someone to maybe come apply to if
you have open positions or maybe
internships
we have a lot of young people who are
tuning into nana who wouldn't normally
go who would probably be very interested
in
in helping do work for probably pretty
free to help their
way through college anything going on in
that space i may uh john
um so afraid has a what we call
a research collaboration program where
we
we get in interns on board and uh
for for three to six months and they can
work
on various subjects such as
you know any engineering type of work or
also
in my department on research subjects
we also do collaborations with the
academic bodies
so for example uh we we send out
um some collaboration requests to
to universities uh here on the continent
requesting support on let's say we want
to do we want to run internet
measurement
um activities let's say in congo dlc
then we will
reach out to the different universities
there too to host
for example ripe atlas anchors or probes
and then we would um do the analysis and
publish a report
at the country level so this type of
research work
we like to collaborate with the students
and uh
yeah we have this program that we can
take them on board
that's great if i may as well do some
sales pitch we're actually hiding at the
moment
because i have an opening for a devops
engineer uh in rpki
so if you want to help us to do all this
cloud deployments
uh feel free to apply and also a soft
engineer
and uh one of the things that we're
planning uh to build that's
quite excited about in the rpk island
is a publication as a service because
now with more and more people
uh running a no no hosted rtki
with krill there is a need
for resilient uh repositories and
instead of they're running their own
repository
they could publish the repositories uh
within the the right pcc
it's not uh it's on our roadmap
something that we really want to build
uh but yeah it's not uh it's not ready
yet
right maybe there'll be another opening
yeah yes
hopefully there is people from latin
america
watching this talk uh we are going to
have two positions open in my team
uh one software developer and one
systems administrator
and uh it can be quite challenging and
quite fun working for lightning we are
we are i would say a small team
so the bad thing is you get a lot of
work to do the good thing about that is
you get to see and touch
a lot of different technologies during
your
things at lagnik
and it's definitely a very nice place to
work at
uh i'm biased of course but i highly
recommend it
mark you look like you want to say
something yeah actually i just want to
say that one of the things that's
happening at aaron is that we realize
that we need to give more focus to the
community on some of our services that
we have
and so we just hired a product manager
a senior project manager who's going to
be taking care of
routing security both rpki and irr
services
so you'll you'll be seeing a lot more of
of
people from aaron um in the future
not just me but others um so so that you
can uh
so that people can see that we're hard
at work trying to improve
things um at aaron we have had in the
past we've had interns
uh work at aaron i'm not sure how well
it's going to work this summer
with us being in the sort of coveted
environment
and frankly our office we're all working
remotely um
and that's going to be a little bit
challenging in the meantime but
we're working through it okay very good
george do you have a one last thing
we've got a community trainer
position open so if you're um
technically adept and good at the
communications and if you've got a
language in use in the asian footprint
we would love to hear from you
we've done interns um works out pretty
well australia is a nice place to be but
as mark said this isn't exactly the
right year for
global travel we have some remote
workers
it can work but the time zone shifts
between
places that people are likely to be can
be quite a substantial barrier
for us i don't know that we're in a big
growth phase at the moment but i suspect
there'll be technical positions coming
up
and as a 20-year person in the rir i can
say
it's a great place to work so i
definitely support
people in your community in nanhog have
a look at our job boards because it's a
really nice place to be
public interest work it's good stuff
excellent
okay let's let's end this way i'll kind
of go in the reverse order this time to
close
i'll start with you american what i'd
like for each of you to maybe
make your last pitch what is it that a
network operator who
maybe from that or any other region who
maybe wants to
operate in your region what is it they
need to know what what
should they know about afernic and voice
first of each one of you so
what should they know about um
so yeah um so we
obviously will welcome anyone uh wishing
to operate businesses
uh in africa so um you actually need to
be
incorporated in africa to actually
become a member of afrinic
and uh we have a dedicated team called
the member services team that can
help you through the process of getting
resources
and and uh yeah getting started with you
with your business and we welcome anyone
from
whether you are a
an lio or or whether you are an end user
for example a bank or a university so
um so we still as i said we still have
ipv4 address space
so that you can get going with your
v4 setup but we also would encourage you
to add up ipv6
and we have a dedicated team of
trainers as well and we are also doing
something
uh rather new called deployations where
uh if you're interested as an isp or as
a network
we would work with you and help hold you
to actually
deploy ipv6 or deploy rpki
on your end to make your services better
very good mark the community
watching may be most familiar with your
irr
so you can introduce your arrest the
world or perhaps
there may be something you want to tell
this community
uh a special message like here's here's
what you guys aren't doing and ought to
do or here's what you
are utilizing that you ought to this is
your opportunity to make that pitch to
yeah
uh thank you john so i i guess i'll just
say that aaron's a membership
uh based organization uh where isps um
is our our members all the way
down to individuals as george said that
uh people
like randy bush who's no longer in our
region but was once in our region
um have or we're members or our members
and each of those members have a say and
actually people in the community have a
say
so for example one of the things that we
have is we have a
uh suggestion process so if you see
something that we
need to be doing differently or better
we have a suggestion process that you
can go ahead
and submit and we actually earnestly
look at those and
um and and work on them on these
suggestions so
so this isn't this sort of big registry
in the cloud
or registry out there that uh you know
everyone has to deal with but it's kind
of painful we try to we're
making we're trying to be as customer
friendly as we can and trying to
uh try to achieve or uh
keep on going with what the community
wants us to do
thank you mark and felipe what uh what
the network operators need to know about
the writer um yeah i think one thing
it's interesting because they all have a
technical background network operators
software engineers
and they tend to not give much attention
to the more boring parts
of the relationship with an rar which is
keeping the information up to date
giving all the necessary documents
and so on uh and we do face a lot of
challenges
uh because of that so records are left
not up to date and i'm talking about
companies changing name we're going
through mergers and acquisitions and so
on
and then we finding that out many years
afterwards
and then you have to go back and do all
the paper trail
and then that can be uh quite
challenging uh to do
so i know that network operators
they tend not to care much about this
but they'll say
please please let us know when there is
a change
uh especially the legal structure of
your company so you can
speed up things it's much easier uh to
update
uh your account if you the change is
fresh so it's much easier to get
all the paperwork uh and the necessary
signatures
thank you flipping george any uh final
remarks the things that you want people
to know in closing about the yeah
we're we're operating in the australian
time zone
aest it's gmt plus 10 and we do a
12 hour 9 to 9 window for being online
so we'll talk to you online
skype email phone voip if you're outside
those hours you may incur a time penalty
with us we've got a really nice new
member center if you just head to the ap
nick webb and hunt
new member center there's a lot of
guidance on how to do process in our web
forms or within our systems
got free training opportunities free
conference registrations for new members
if i wanted people to take away one
message
keeping your records up to date as
felipe said it's really important these
assets are valuable
and these assets have enormous impact on
the global internet operation
you need to secure your retained
management
of these resources keep your information
up to date
do rpki if you don't make a public
declaration of your origination in bgp
you're at risk and we're here to help
you and we want you
to be in this system and to be as secure
as you possibly can
please come in to us and talk to us if
you're having problems getting this
stuff turned on
thank you george carlos
i would like to echo the yeah i would
like to make the comments of
my colleagues here i think we share the
same
interesting being as customer friendly
as possible we
certainly encourage new members to keep
their documentation and their
information updated in our member portal
[Music]
and i would really like to invite
everyone who wants to do business in the
latin american region to
be part of uh which i consider is a very
lively community with a lot of
discussion
and a community where people are used to
help each other you can call us you can
email us we consume
skype whatever i actually
worked members through rawa creation
myself
actually helping them discover their own
drugs in policies because they were very
confused about their own
policies and uh is that
is that our way to of looking at things
and we are happy to do that
all right well thank you very much
everyone and i'll close this out we're
going to
hopefully see you all for a little bit
of q a i think i saved some of the
hardball questions for
the audience to ask you so i wouldn't
get in trouble myself directly but
i'll maybe uh help seed some of those if
i don't see any pop up in the window
so thank you again we'll see you soon in
the virtual
uh or the uh the virtual nano with a
live q a
thank you everybody thanks john thank
you everybody
thank you very much
[Music]
that was absolutely awesome thank you
gentlemen
we don't have that much time for live q
a
so i've picked one out of the
pile and i'm going to ask that we
round robin through it and i believe
that carlos is the first one to my right
the question is is anything being done
to enforce
accurate information of contacts such as
useful
or working abuse addresses the comment
was personally i encountered bad
information
when attempting to report malicious
behaviors
thank you alex uh yeah definitely um
that is
i would say two two things that uh we
are wonking on
and answering the question for lagnik
specifically
uh there is a policy that was uh
approved and ratified
early 2020 if i remember correctly
that has to do with validating points of
contact
particularly i will use contacts and the
idea is to
actually ensure that those email
addresses email inboxes are actually
monitored uh the implementation of
such a policy ended up being quite
complex
and i hope uh that it will be
implemented
um i mean we have a release date around
march
may and uh which it should be
i mean to start growing the validation
upon that point of time
uh the other things that we've done in
the past is that we
created a dedicated incident response
capability within lagnik and we have a
scissors
and the system can receive your
incident reports and i can actually help
you
track some specific contact within the
organization and
if you are dealing with a particularly
serious incident so feel free to contact
them
thank you can we move to george who's
the next one over
hi so like carlos we have
a mandatory incident response contact
policy we actually did work back in 2010
to make this mandatory for all resource
holders
and we had a reaffirmation of this in
2019 with the validation process that
requires six monthly review
but the the lived experience for
everyone is that some of these people
are simply non-responsive
so we do have a reporting mechanism
in our website if you're experiencing
non-responsive abuse contacts and you've
reached out to the isp
we have a process that we can go through
but
there is also quite a large amount of
acid held in our
region that is before strong policy
compliance came into being
and there are people who have full use
of their resources but who simply are
not
going to update their contact
information
and we don't have policies that allow us
to reclaim because of non-contact
ability like this it's not actually our
functional role in region to do that
but for most of the cases yeah we have a
process and we're happy to work with you
to keep this information up to date
excellent thank you can we pass now down
to felipe
going clockwise
uh yeah similarly to uh laknik we also
have a
abuse validation policy it was
approved i believe a bit more than one
year ago
and we have been doing the the
validation
since early last year and the process uh
semi-automated so we do part part of it
using a software solution and we also do
a follow-up
manually uh using the the host masters
uh on our initiative we want to extend
that
to all sorts of contacts so to do a
similar validation
uh to all kinds of contacts in the
in the right stream uh we didn't decide
yet exactly how but that's planned
to be done this year
thank you very much can we move now to
mark
sure so we've had puck validation for a
long
period of time um over 10 years and so
we've been using that uh it's had
a pretty good success there's been a
number of people who have been
uncontactable much like what george has
been talking about um
but for the most part it's worked quite
well so we've been
working with keeping our data up to date
based on our poc validation
uh that's done on an annual basis
thank you mark uh ambrish can you finish
up the round robin and then we'll move
on to our next uh
presentation which is closing thank you
alex
uh yes indeed so maintaining uh
updated information in you know with
different databases
is absolutely um important and uh
we have quick process for the members
contact update where periodically we
will
contact the members and make sure all
the
information in the database is actually
accurate
um uh in the past we have also had
uh abuse abuse contact uh policies
um and unfortunately they haven't been
really uh i would say effective
and efficient because currently they are
not mandatory
i know we have
a new abuse contact policy
that has been uh circulated um
in our policy discussions uh at the
moment which is still under discussion
um uh unfortunately it hasn't reached
consensus yet but hopefully
um it will because it's i believe it's
an important piece of work
um so yeah thank you
thank you very much henry uh gentlemen
i'd like to thank you and thank you on
behalf
of john kristoff who as i said was
pulled away by family emergency and
couldn't be here