[Music]
so
hello everyone i would like to talk a
little bit about security and design
let's begin right here which is that
oftentimes
in the networking world we're told that
we need to build security in from
day one we need to design the network in
a way that it is secure
but what does security in from day one
actually mean like how do we actually do
this
isn't doing security just a matter of
putting firewalls in the right places or
whatever the case might happen to be
uh packet filters or whatever in the
right places
well there are three thoughts that you
can push back on this this kind of
mentality with
and think about doing security from day
one or building security into the design
the first is to build simple now of
course i'm a huge advocate of
getting rid of complexity where you can
so this is not going to be a big
surprise coming from me
the second is building places for policy
so
intentionally setting aside places in
the network where
you can put policy in place and then
build measurable
really build in the telemetry that you
might need for security from day one
think about where you would measure
and why you would measure so here's a
quote from bruce schneier
which is about complexity and security
he says the internet and all the systems
we built today are getting more complex
at a rate that is faster than we are
capable of matching
and that is absolutely true security in
reality is actually improving
so what bruce schneier is saying here is
that we are getting better at security
but the target is constantly shifting so
we're getting better at hitting the
target but the target's getting narrower
smaller
and moving around on us as complexity
grows we are losing
ground so complexity then therefore
is the enemy of security but why let's
talk about why that might happen to be
let's begin here with that thought which
is that
what we can think about in the
networking world for complexity is we
can think about a three-way trade-off
state
optimization and surfaces if you've ever
heard me present on complexity or
any other topic i tend to bring these
things in a lot this three-way trade-off
so when i look when i talk about
surfaces though a lot of people don't
totally understand what i'm saying when
i talk about a surface
so interaction surfaces have two ways of
being measured or to be thought about
the first is is the breadth of the
interaction surface
so the two systems that interact over a
broad interaction surface
interact in a lot of different places as
you can see there's a lot of arrows
that run between these two the second
thing is
is that there is a depth of interaction
surfaces so
the deeper the system
the two systems interact in terms of
using state from the other system
in order to do something locally within
the system the deeper that interaction
surface is
so this illustration shows you two two
different systems
that are interacting with one another
through a single international
interaction surface
but they are deeply doing so they're not
very broad there's not a lot of places
but they're very deep
so up here we have two systems that are
not only broadly interacting but they're
also
deeply interacting now what we want to
get to is we want to get to a system
that is only interacting very narrowly
and as
shallowly as possible with as much
shallow interaction as possible
why because the broader and deeper the
interaction surfaces the tighter the
binding between the two systems
if you have two systems that are tightly
bound what you've done is you've enabled
cross-system attacks
in ways that you may not expect expect
another thing is the more there are
these interaction surfaces in here
these places where these two systems
interact you get a larger and richer
attack surface so broader interaction
surfaces give you a larger
attack surface and deeper interaction
surfaces give you
a richer attack surface so what you
really want to get to as a rule of thumb
is to have these two systems to be
hermetically sealed where they're not
able to
interact with one and of course that's
irrational or that's not possible in the
networking world because otherwise you
wouldn't have the two systems there in
the first place
now if we talk about the way a
particular system is designed from the
outside and the inside from the outside
it looks like
an opaque box the system just looks like
something that
i can push inputs into and i get outputs
out of
or push inputs into up here or down here
and i get them out on the top
so i can think of those outputs as being
sort of a reshaping of the system
or my exterior view of that system so
it's an opaque box that i can push on
and make things go in a certain way now
what happens however
is that while i might expect if i push
here on the system i get a nice
even parallel push on the outside so i
get the data out that i'm expecting
in real life what i have is a lot of
unintended consequences
if i push over here i actually get
something that's coming out in a
different place than i expected this is
an
unintended consequence this is a
mismatch between the way the system
works and the way you think it works
so the more complex this system is the
more likely you are to have this
situation
where there's a mismatch between what
you think it does and what it actually
does
so this is something what we would call
this technical debt
actually this is a form of technical
debt in our systems
that we think it works one way and it
actually works a different way
and one way you solve the technical debt
problem in
coding is you refactor the system so
that you match your expectations
to the actual operation of that system
so every unintended consequence that i
get into is an attack surface
if i can attack a device or a system
by pushing on it in a particular place
by feeding it data
and having the result be something you
don't expect as an
administrator or an operator then i've
actually opened an attack surface in
your network
so one thing i can do is i can simplify
these systems
to reduce the unintended consequences
which means in two directions first of
all
that i actually understand how the
system works so i'm expecting
this sideways output from the input and
the second
is to control the output to be more
parallel to what i think i'm actually
should be getting
so another point that you get into with
good interaction surfaces
is that policy containment is very very
key
to so to security i want to contain my
policy
within a module or at or to an
interaction surface
the reason i want to do this is the more
i have my policy encapsulated within
this system or this system or the more i
have it encapsulated
along this interaction surface the
easier it is for me to understand
and pin down what that policy is doing
there's something here called the
subsidiarity principle as well
this is kind of an extended version of
the subsidiary principle
instead of the social part of it which
usually is
the subsidiary principle says that what
i want to do is i want to pull
my decision making to the closest point
that has the information about making
that decision you would normally apply
this to government
to governance to social structures
things like that
within a network what this might mean is
it might mean
i want to say that this module has the
information required to make a policy
decision
i want to make that policy decision in
this module
rather than in a separate module through
an interaction surface
so this is just a way of trying to
simplify things as much as possible
so let's talk about places for measuring
measurement requires context
so we need to know when we're measuring
something what normal looks like this is
where people miss it a lot of times
when they're troubleshooting or dealing
with security is they think
i can just measure this and i don't
really need to know what normal looks
like
but it often happens if you don't know
what normal looks like you don't know
why it's broken
or why it's why it's insecure what the
attacker is doing
you just kind of guess based on
background knowledge or rules of thumb
or something like that
so you need to be able to measure what
normal looks like
and then you need to know why normal
works looks that way
or rather how this system works in
internally so having these clear
interaction surfaces
with shallow and narrow interaction
surfaces or interactions between these
systems
allows me to better understand what i
should be measuring
the more places i need to measure and
the more these measurements are deep
measurements
the less able i am to do effective
telemetry to understand exactly what's
going on
and what i'm trading off in having those
types of things
so we normally reduce complexity via
modularization
you've probably heard me say this a
thousand times but there's this concept
of the wasp waste
and what i have here is i have a typical
wasp or a bee
and this particular bee or wasp has a
lot of complexity down here there's a
stinger and there's
a stomach and all these other things and
then a lot of complexity here there's a
lot of muscle structure to support those
wings and the legs
and digestive systems and stuff like
that so these are separated by
this little wasp waste and this wasp
waste is a containment mechanism
so i can do the same thing in my network
i actually control complexity
by inserting these interaction surfaces
and modularizing what i'm doing
what's interesting is this
modularization point also gives us
places
to insert policy in places to measure
things
so my modularization that i'm already
doing to reduce complexity
and again complexity is the enemy of
security
is also helping me in security so let's
think about how this might work in a
data center fabric let's say
so let's think about in a data center
fabric what we normally think about
in terms of modularization might be my
pods
or something like this and i might think
in a normal hierarchical network
or in a normal network design i'm
thinking about having
three layers and i might have my access
layer or
two layers i might have my access
distribution and then my core or i might
have three
two layers which are like just my access
or aggregation
and core or something like this and what
i'm doing is i'm doing aggregation route
aggregation
probably in my second or third layer or
along the lines between these layers
in order to reduce complexity and to
modularize the network
in a data center this bottom layer
fabric is often
a single flat failure domain now i might
be running bgp or a link state protocol
or whatever on that
fabric but it's largely going to be as
an underlay
it's going to be a single failure domain
so what i need to do in a data center
environment
is rather than modularizing horizontally
i modularize
vertically so my underlay is one failure
domain
and then i may have a a network overlay
and say this might be evpn
sitting here and it's going to be my
second module
and then i may have an application
overlay that sits on top of this maybe
running sxt
or whatever the case might happen to be
kafka or whatever it is
kubernetes or whatever that is going to
give me my third layer so what i'm doing
is i'm modularizing in order to simplify
but what this also does is this allows
me to break these up not
into failure domains but that also
breaks them up
into security domains what i want to do
is i want to think about this
underlay fabric as being a single
security domain
and my overlay to be a separate security
domain and then my app overlay
to be a separate security domain
separately again so
for instance if i design my
underlay such that the underlay cannot
be attacked
by any host or device that's attached to
these type of rack switches
somehow i force it to bypass the
underlay and only talk to the
network overlay that increases my
security
on this underlay fabric so that is the
type of thing that i can do
so what i want to do is for instance i
want to use this modularization
to increase security by allowing hosts
and other applications
and applications running on the host to
only talk to one particular
part of the network or one particular
module
so now for instance if i look at this
and i think
i'm going to have these two hosts and
they're going to be attached to top of
rack switches
what happens if someone owns or roots
this host and can then talk to the
underlay
in a way that can cause the entire
fabric to fail
that would be a very very very bad thing
so what we can do here is if i want to
run routing
on this host then what i do is i only
run the overlay
if i only run the overlay routing
protocol or the overlay control plane
on this host then it would only have
access to what it would have access to
its particular vlan
or its particular verf or whatever you
want to call it
it's ethernet segment it's es or
whatever you want to call it in
different control planes
and that's pretty much it well it would
have access to the other hosts that are
also the other processes that are on
that same es or that same vlan
but that's all it would have it wouldn't
have access to
a lot of the other stuff that's out
there like the control plane for the
underlay
it wouldn't be able to ddos this router
because it does
while it has this physical connection it
doesn't have access to the right ports
and stuff
to get that so the way that you
deal with your routing on the control
plane directly
impacts the security of your data center
fabric
so here is a point where my design
and the way i have designed the network
from a modularization point of view
is actually directly impacting my
security
of the network so it's very important to
think about it in these terms
another thing that's interesting to
think about here is if i have a single
control plane
in both the underlay and the overlay and
the host can talk to that control plane
and take that control plane down in the
overlay it can in theory
impact the underlay once again if i've
not thought through
my modularization correctly and both of
these
planes are running the same routing
protocol then i end up in a position
where attacking
this routing protocol also attacks this
routing protocol
so i've actually merged the two failure
domains and i've also merged the two
security domains now of course this is
all going to depend on your
implementation
and how you've done things in your
design so again
this is something to think about when
you're doing design
is whether or not you want to have these
things combined
or not and how you spread them out and
how you divide them
from a modularization perspective now
another example
is let's say i'm running is to is
in this network and that's my underlay
and let's say i'm running bgp to run
evpn in my overlay
so that is my two protocols so i've done
total separation
and the host let's say for some reason
can still talk to this router or this
type of rack switch
using is well you might think well
there's not a lot it can do it can
inject routes things like this
but let's say that i'm very very
concerned about
the speed of convergence in this network
so i tighten my isis timers down way way
down
and i try to get it to converge and say
50 milliseconds or 100 milliseconds
or whatever it is so i tighten up
everything and i use
and i use exponential back off
for my timers so that i can
force spf to run very very quickly the
first time there's a change in the
network
and then it runs more slowly over time
as more changes take place
well if you think about it if this host
has access to is
and i have tightly tuned timers what
this host can do
without even knowing what routes to
inject or what to do to bring the fabric
down
it can simply slow down the convergence
of the fabric by constantly
injecting new lsps in the network
at the pace required to cause spf to run
more slowly
across all of these devices so what
that's going to do is when there's a
real change in the network
say this d2 to d1 link fails
these routers or these intermediate
systems will converge much more slowly
because they'll be running against their
higher end of the top end
of the exponential back off in the
network so again this is a situation
where
even if you split things up correctly
you've not thought through
all of the attack surfaces in your
design so what you might want to do in
this situation
is to make sure this interface is a
passive interface
another point to make about this is this
is another example of the state
optimization surface trade-off
right what i've done is is i have
tightly modified the convergence speed
or tightly managed the convergence
speeder optimized
the convergence speed in this fabric to
make it as fast as possible
but in doing so what i've done is i've
made myself
extremely sensitive to the rate of the
state
that's in this fabric so if somebody
comes along and starts shoving state
into this fabric
really really fast it actually reduces
my optimization
by working against what i've optimized
for so this is again one of those
situations where you have to think
through
does my design really really require
this
super fast convergence or am i okay
slowing the convergence down
in order to manage that attack surface
so we can think through
how to use modularization and how to use
network design to build security in even
before we get to the point of thinking
about firewalls staple packet filters
packet filters of various kinds whatever
it happens to be
i can actually think through my network
and think through where i'm creating
attack surfaces
where i'm doing interaction surfaces
between modules whether those modules
are truly separated
or what i'm actually doing with those
things in order to think through the
security ramifications of my
design before i deploy it before i even
get to
packet filters so again to optimize you
either increase state or create new
surfaces
and as i'm creating new surfaces or
removing state i always
almost always leads to less optimization
so reducing complexity one one last
point about this is that
reducing complexity locally almost
always
increases complexity globally so as i've
decreased my complexity
in each individual device or in each
individual system
i'm actually increasing overall
complexity globally
so i need to think through what i'm
optimizing locally and globally
and think through where i'm increasing
complexity and go back to
security or complexity is the enemy of
security and i need to think about
how i'm going to balance those things
and make the network secure
so that is it so i'll leave this open
for questions
and this is just some other places you
can find me if you're interested in some
of my other work
it's my blog my podcast and my other
podcast
that you might want to listen to thanks
for listening and i hope this has been
helpful in just connecting for you
mentally
the concept of security against the
concept of design
and giving you some pointers in how to
think about design in a more secure way
this was uh russ white presenting on
security and design
russ white is well known in our
community rus is an infrastructure
architect to join for networks
and was just talking to us from raleigh
north carolina
this is russ's seventh present present
time presenting at nanook
russ first presented a talk called
trade-offs in network complexity
at nanox 60 in 2014 in atlanta
uh welcome back to nanograss and we're
certainly happy to have you
back today we're going to continue next
with a q a
first there was a comment made about
uh a false sense of zoning especially in
a world where we tunnel everything
anything through anything please comment
so yeah so i was going to answer this in
the chat window
but job i know what you're saying but i
think
the other way of looking at this is that
when we tunnel we actually are creating
vertical domains in a sense and that's
what we want to do is we want to think
about
how to make those vertical domains are
those vertically stacked domains into
separate failure and security domains
so yeah it is difficult to think in
terms of
zoning as far as the wasp waste goes and
everything from a
hierarchical perspective or a
topological method any longer but to try
to replace that a bit with the vertical
stacked ways of doing things so
i hope that was helpful oh
good thanks joe
very good uh the next question that came
up was um
about uh a use case where we would be
doing an igp
isis uh traffic inbound from a host
sport
yeah so i i've actually seen this in
real life which is why i put it in the
slides
people who run either a single overlay
with a single underlay
ip plane ip underlay with no overlay or
they are actually running an overlay
anyway and then they are running
is is or something else to the host to
run in the v router so that
so that evpn knows how to reach the
correct next tops in the right way
i consider that really dangerous i think
you should always make sure that
your um you should always make sure
that your fabric is protected
as far as the control plane the underlay
fabric should be construct
protected as far as the control plane
goes from anything going on
in the overlay or on the host even on
the v router
and i think that's just good value
domain separation and
good hygiene in network design so that's
kind of
okay thank you um
another question is what other general
rules to enhance security
of the underlay would you recommend so
one thing to think about
is to encrypt your traffic across your
own data center fabric
the problem with doing this is going to
be key distribution
and just the difficulty of configuring
and managing an encryption system
on top of a data center fabric that
is just very difficult to
mess with or figure out how to do that
so
you know i've talked to some of the
internal i've talked to security folks
who say you should be running maxsec
on your data center fabric well yeah
okay but max it's very very difficult to
deploy and it's very hard to think about
how you would do that
so that is one of the general rules you
can think about
is how to just consider running some
sort of encryption on your data center
fabric
to prevent insider attacks another one
is just
the whole concept of automation
repeatability
making sure that you don't keep open
ports treating devices
as part of the attack surface those i
think are general things that you can
think about as well that might be
useful
thank you russ what are your thoughts on
bgp
and the new external systematic
dependencies introduced by the
likes of rpki
oh so i had a data center fabric i don't
know that i would think about
pushing rpki into my data center fabric
it's more of an external thing as far as
external dependencies go well
i i really have this thing about bgp and
data center underlays that i actually
don't like bgp as the underlay
for a data center fabric because of some
of the things we're doing to bgp and
some of the external
externalities and stuff that go with it
so i'm not
entirely certain that answers the
question but maybe
uh if they want to continue and
let me see if i can see it okay
um what about um
what other material can the
nano community reference
to further learn about the um
design and insecurity concept that you
just covered
yeah so i think probably the only place
i've written about this in any way would
be
to think about is in network
problems and solutions and computer
networks i don't tend to spend a lot of
time talking about security although i
intend to spend more time in the
security realm
um in the coming years i saw a couple
other questions i don't know if you want
to do those a year how much time we have
yeah we have a minute left but go ahead
yeah if you want to comment so blake
said something about
abstractions are always leaky yes that
is the rule
of leaky abstractions and yes it's
absolutely true
that all extractions are leaking and
because they do
yet they are leaky you can end up in a
situation with something like a ddos
attack and an upper layer can impact
even a well isolated lower layer but of
course the more
isolation you have the less likely that
is to happen
so that's why you need to think about um
reducing the depth and the breadth of
the interaction surfaces
um and then blake asks also how can one
maintain
loose coupling between layers in
conjunction with differentiating between
volumetric attacks and production
traffic
yeah so the same sort of thing just
thinking about your
just thinking about the interaction
surface between your layers as an attack
surface and i do like the idea by the
way of
pulling out fibers halfway i think
that's i think that's a really good idea
let's go one final comment on complexity
is the enemy of security
final thoughts yeah oh that's absolutely
true
um this goes back to the first corollary
of keith's law
and that how important it is to reduce
complexity as much as possible in a
network to
make it where you can get your head
around things and understand what the
side effects will be when you do
something
okay well very good uh russ we uh thank
you very much for joining us uh the
network community appreciates
your time and um
[Music]