[Music]
hello everyone
my name is louis xing i am an assistant
professor at the indiana university of
bloomington
it's my great honor to speak at black
hatch this is joint work with my
colleague
professor georginio and our phd student
honolulu so today we are going to talk
about the design platform and
security challenges in the commercial
mini programs
on both android and ios
so we are talking about a new mobile
computing paradigm today
it's called every app or sometimes
called mini program paradigm
it's quickly gaining huge popularity in
the past a few years
in this paradigm the mobile app called
the host app
such as snapchat recharge facebook
they support a new feature delete other
small apps
wrong in them so those small
two small apps also called mini programs
or
sub-apps they draw in the host app
they significantly enrich the
functionality of the whole step
so here is an example
this is a sub-app called item tickets
it is running in the snapchat app
so with this sub-app so the group of
users in snapchat they can
chat while purchasing movie tickets
together
instead of leaving snapchat and buy
tickets
individually so with sub-apps
for example with amazon sub-apps you can
also place
amd orders inside a host app you can
also use the tesla
sub-app to check a nearby charging
station for your tesla without
leaving a host app sub-apps have been
released by
major app vendors and service providers
such as amazon tesla google
stockbox microsoft such a mini program
paradigm
or fpf paradigm allows the whole step
vendor to build a ecosystem around the
hostel vendor around the whole step
so this paradigm has become very popular
in the past a few years
after first introduced by vchat in 2017
so in this research we studied 11 cool
steps that
are providing the app feature
i mean hosting mini apps
to the those footsteps
in total have more than 2 billion
downloads examples of the whole steps
include wechat tick tock
facebook also refund more and more apps
have started to support mini
apps such as ipod imessage and the
snapchat
so to date there are more than one
many suburbs or mini mini apps into the
in the wild they are provided and
released by the
sub-app stores provided by the hosted
vendors
similar to google play and apple app
store
so how do they work how does this uh fpf
paradigm work
so here
we see a typical fpf technical
architecture
which we learn through reverse
engineering so
in this architecture there is the whole
step the operating system
in the tab sub-apps draw on top of the
whole step
the hoof tab acts like an operating
system
to the sub-apps the whole steps provide
a sub-app runtime to run servers
the host-type provides a sub-app api so
stop app
card card.api to access the resources
to access the surface and
the host have a call corresponding
system api to
get the resources for the sub-apps
if a sub-app api
accesses sensitive resources then the
whole step requires a permission check
for the sub-app to call that api so
those permissions are called server
permissions they are similar or they are
like the android permissions
to restrict system api
[Music]
in terms of the security model in the
fdm paradigm
first sub-app api are restricted by
web server permissions good permission
must
be granted by the user to the sub-apps
so this is similar to how android and
os apps request permissions second
the sub-apps are isolated from each
other
by the hoofstab third
the whole step usually has a sub-app
store that reads sub-apps
they check the malicious sub-app or
detect
those with the privacy violations
this new fdmf paradigm introduced new
security challenges
first it is fundamentally difficult for
the whole staff to properly manage
subjects
in particular the host tab cannot
read the mechanism through which the os
manages mobile apps
for example android use the traditional
linux user id
to isolate mobile apps on android
android assigned a linux uid to each
app so the app each app and the
resources are isolated
naturally by the linux kernel however
such a mechanism cannot be easily
replicated to the
whole step to isolate the servers
also the hoof needs to securely manage
system resources delegated to the
sub-apps
through permission policies such as
similar to the android permission policy
or ios entitlements
however we found that the operating
system level security policies
are opaque scattered and never organized
for the host vendor to reuse it's harder
for the hoof type vendor to construct a
sound
security policies that are compliant
with the operating system
to regulate system resources also given
the host limited
capabilities and resources it's hard for
them to manage the
suburb ui model and life cycle which
reveal detail of these attacks in this
talk
another challenge is the lack of
standards
we found that the different host apps
today have
provided heterogeneous sub-app apis and
security policies even for accessing the
same kind of resources
in the absence of a standard
the server app api and policies can
easily go wrong
unnecessarily convoluted and which can
be hard
to verify and protect so next i will
hand over the
talk to hora who will continue and
introduce the new vulnerability that
we found on the most popular epic system
in the wild
hi there yeah thanks for the
introduction
and all right i'm going to talk about
the
four design pitfalls we discovered
during our study
so namely the four pitfalls are
system resource exposure the new overlay
hazard a sub-window deception and the
setback
level select lifecycle hijacking
the first one i'm going to talk about
the system restore exposure
ideally in app in app architecture
software permissions
required for setup api are supposed to
be consistent
with the permissions required by the
operating system
when using the relevant system apis
label app
for example recording audios need to use
the microphone
which can be accessed by the host app
using
using the corresponding android or os
apis
the host app wraps the api and provides
a new unified
server api since the operating system
requires permission to use this oreo
recording ada apis
the sub-app apis should also be
protected via sub-app permission
in the example record audio permission
on android
and microphone usage entitlement on ios
are required by the o-ring systems
so the satellite permission scope.report
is also required by the hoster
however for the host as a third party
it's very challenging to construct some
separate api permission policies in our
study
we found inconsistent permission
requirements between server
api and system api which lead to system
resource exposure
an example is the unprotected wechat
sub-app api that can perform wi-fi scan
web scan can be accessed by wifi manager
api on android
and any hospital helper api on ls
a host up recharge roughly
2 and provide a server api
wx.get wi-fi list
wi-fi scan are protected through an
entitlement
hospital helper on ls and a dangerous
level permission
access fine location on android however
the sub-app api provided by wechat is
not protected by any sub-bad permission
as a result the satellite api exposed
the wifi scan capability
to the sub-app leaking out user location
we named such unprotected server api
as escaped server api note that
a high-profile host app for example
wechat
is typically granted the location
permission and many other
dangerous permissions due to its rich
functionalities
for example the camera and microphone as
a result
the adversary gains unauthorized access
to system resources through the escape
satellite api in addition to the example
we show here
we found many other escape sub apis
in popular ibm systems affecting diverse
sensitive system resources across ios
and android
so looking into the root cause of this
escape subat apis we
found two possibilities first is the
unclear operating system level security
policy
and the second is the cross-platform
discrepancy
of permission requirement between
android and allies
so for the first root cause the
operating system level security policies
are opaque
again we take the ufs scan as an example
ls protect web scan with an entitlement
named hospital helper
to get this entitlement developer must
file a dedicated
written request justifying that the app
will now have any malicious intention to
get this system permission apple reviews
the requests internally
and possibly access the risk of location
leakage
from the app however the intelligent and
its public information
failed to show that wi-fi scan can
cause location leakage such an opaque
operating system level policy make it
non-trivial
to construct several level policies that
are compliant
in addition we found the open system
level policies are scattered and
disorganized
state-of-the-art approaches leverage a
program
analysis-based best effort search in the
android code space
to construct the android api permission
mappings the results suffer from
surprising low coverage
for example they own they will they are
only able to find
required dangerous permission for about
half of the android apis
the other root cause is the
cross-platform discrepancy
since server api is designed to be
cross-platform
the effort to build server api
permission policies
that are comply with all operating
systems
has been complicated by the
inconsistency between android and lis
is in terms of the resource protection
consider bluetooth scan as an example
android api bluetooth le scanner and ios
api
cv central manager provided the host app
with success to the bluetooth scan
results
whose app reacted to aps and provide a
sub 5
api ws again bluetooth devices
android protects x api with generous
level permission
access file location in contrast
ls does not require any permissions or
entitlements
on its api in this case what should the
self api permission be for the host
that can be that should be required for
the setup api
the answer is host apps you already do
not require any
on the koreabook on the bluetooth
server api we found that the fbi dealer
tend to leave the related server api
unprotected
for example the server apis for
bluetooth scan are not protected in
multiple whole steps
actually the difference in policy level
protection
could result from an additional security
guard
put in place by the opening systems
which
is unaware to the fpf designer
in the bluetooth scan example
combining the signal strength and the
device id return value
in the full scan result can review the
user's geolocation on android
the id and the signal stress are
returned
so the so at the android require
permission
on the only android api ios
however one of the device id
is authenticated so the ls
result can now be elaborate to reveal
the user skill location
and so the app does not product this api
in total we tested 11 host apps
including apps like wechat and tiktok
we found 39 escape separate apis in
six of them this 39
escape sub api covers five different
system resources
including wi-fi bluetooth microphone
camera
and ipcon the third weakness we found
but the second weakness we found is a
new overlay
holder that exists in access control
management of the ibm system
this attack is a new type of ui
redressing tab
for the checking attack before we go
into details of this attack
let's quickly go over the basics of the
click checking on android
on android the permission grinding
window features a protection
against quickjacking gaps that is when
the permission grounding window is
covered
by any other windows the user clicks
will be rejected
to stop any potential attacks
so the defense of this attack is that
the android will
will remove the overlays created by
third party apps
and android designed a specific
permission for this purpose
that is hide non-system overlay windows
however this permission is usually not
available to host apps
the permission is designed only to be
available
to system apps for us that are
pre-installed by the device vendors
this leaves an opportunity for us to
explore
recall that the host app are usually
very powerful
holding a lot of permissions and
delegate them to the sub-apps through
setup apis
so the server apis are protected by
satellite permissions and the select
permissions granting window
are not protected against click checking
attacks
so previous two channel tests only
target the android permission graphing
window
and in this case we will target the
information gradient window of these
setup permissions
so first user install the malicious
android app
which can draw overlays over the host
apps
then it can launch a colluding setup
which does not need to be installed
before by the user in many host apps
the coding server will invoke the
sensitive server
apis accessing the sensitive resources
of the users
when you set up a permission grinding
window of the wholesale
pop-up the malicious android can draw
overlay and allow the user to grant this
setup permission
to the loading setup the
coordination of the malicious android
app and the coding setup
can be through the clipboard or
websocket
and any other technologies
in total we tested 10 host apps that
are available on android all 10 whole
steps are vulnerable to our attack
leveraging this attack the malicious
android app can get access to the system
resources like
camera microphone that are considered
well protected before
the third weakness we found is the side
window deception flow
as a background we first introduced the
fpf ui model
the sub-app is displayed in a full
screen window
of the host app taking over the screen
used by the hosa
in the screenshot on the right areas
color in
green are controlled by the setup it is
possible
that a malaysia setup may fake the ui of
the wholesale
sensitive ui of the whole set for
example the
mobile wallet ui of wechat and alipay
are also displayed in the area
controlled by the server
so in this case the server can fake
local uis
once explored the server can
the server can steal users mobile wallet
passwords
which can be used for making payments
we constructed a test sub-app that
contains such phishing uis
and submitted it to the wechat select
store and passed their writing process
a similar ui tool can attack the web app
on chrome
or as known as the progressive web app
and the app click
on safari when using a web app for the
progressive web app
the web app will be open in full screen
without any ui
of the browsers including the address
bar
that can tell you the current domain you
are browsing
users can freely navigate to other web
pages
outside of the domain of the current web
app
in this case the browser will display a
banner on the top of the screen
showing the origin of the web page as a
defense
in the screenshot on the right if we do
a single sound
using facebook you know in another web
app
then the browser will display a banner
that is showing the facebook's url
on top of the screen however
the web app can imitate such banner when
user is not even visiting the facebook
page
in this case the user would believe that
she or he
is on the facebook website and gave all
their
facebook credentials to the web app
so the problem is has been acknowledged
by the
chrome and apple team
so current phishing anti-fishing
techniques
that works only on app level which focus
on identify the app of the foreground
window
in our attack the foreground window is
always the whole step
since from the percep perspective of the
operating system
the satellite is running within the
wholesale and treaty
as a whole by the operating system
so they will now be able to tell the
difference between a server and hosa
so they are not able to detect that kind
of attack
the first attack we discard discover is
the 7th
left cycle hijacking which is the
weakness in the lifecycle management
of these sub-apps
[Music]
to give cell lab user a native outlet
experience the whole set
creates attacks for the sub-apps in the
android recent screens
in which user can quickly access as they
opened before
the screenshot on the right is an
example of the task
we check created for layer stub app
to implement the recent screen feature
each host up need to predefine a number
of
activities that will be used to
accommodate
this sub-app since the number of
predefined activities is limited
the number of the sub-apps user can see
in the
recent screen is also limited to limited
the limit is different for different
wholesale
for example for wechat is file and for
chrome is
it when the limit is reached a mandatory
recycling process
starts the newly launched setup will
replace the
oldies-wise task in the recent screen
silently which means the user will not
know the first sub-app he or she used
that is no longer exist in the recent
screen
so a malicious android app can imitate
the
disappeared sub-app's task by inserting
a new text
of its own in the recent screen which is
also known as a test
hijacking attack there are two questions
to answer before we can
insert the fake task first is
what is the disappear setup the second
is
when shall we insert
we found that there is a set channel
that we can use to observe the sub-app
launch operation in real time so we have
answers for the two questions each time
a sub-app is launched
the hosa will add in some files in the
external storage
that is accessible by the malicious
annual apps
usually these files are for caching
purpose
we can reliably identify the sub-app
being launched
through those files and cut the number
of
launched setup so far to find the
correct time
to insert the fake task
the consequence of this attack can be
various and serious
depending on the targeting setup for
example if we target
a health setup the health information of
the victim user
will be elite and we can also get the
bank credentials
or travel histories of the user if we
task
we target the banking setup or traveling
set up they are using
to understand the scope and magnitude of
all four attacks
we presented we analyzed eleven most
popular commercial
fpf ecosystem on both ios and android
including wechat tiktok chrome etc
all of them suffered some or all of the
aforementioned
attacks we mentioned of information
attacks
so to summarize doesn't mean as
mainstream and vendors
participate in the fbi paradigm by
releasing sabbath
supports their apps can no longer
benefit from the protection
offered by the of modern operating
systems
which have been hardened after years of
open security research
in this talk we presented the challenges
in building a secure
self-ecosystem on top of the operating
system
including the lack of security standard
and practice in building an fdf
ecosystem
the security gap between the underlying
operating system
and the limited app level capabilities
of the wholesale
also the lack of operating system level
support
and thank you for your listening