[Music]
good morning good afternoon and good
evening
no matter what timezone you're joining
us from it is my great pleasure
to talk to you today about our briefing
on
effective vulnerability discovery with
machine learning
i'm a sankhya and this is joint work
with my colleague mingy
from veracore in this talk
we will talk about vulnerability
discovery we will see
how finding vulnerabilities in your
application goes beyond the code that
you have written yourself
if you look at any modern software
application it is composed of
a number of third-party components and
libraries
the increase in the number of libraries
means that your application today has a
much
wider surface of attack in this
presentation we will discuss
about ways in which we can curate and
track these vulnerabilities
at scale this is a brief
bio about us i am a sankhya i'm the
director of engineering
at sca which is the software composition
analysis
product group at varaco i'm joined in my
talk
with ming who is a senior research
engineer also working
at the sca product group at veracore
our agenda for today has three points
first we will talk about the problem of
vulnerability curation in the context of
software composition analysis
then we'll discuss about our machine
learning approach which is used to
identify these vulnerabilities
and at the end we'll talk about what it
means to be effective at doing
vulnerability discovery at scale
so what are some of the difficulties in
tracking down these
uh vulnerabilities um if you look at
the number of libraries and components
that are used have they have exploded in
the past few years
today uh developers have a choice of you
know downloading
millions of libraries uh from
third-party repositories
uh it becomes very difficult to keep
track of
vulnerabilities that exist in these
third-party libraries so we need a way
in order to curate
and collect the vulnerabilities that are
found and rely on some sort of a
vulnerability database
when we analyze these libraries and
applications
how do we curate these vulnerabilities
right so we process data
from a variety of internet sources
including
the nvd or the national vulnerability
database
we track the upstream software artifact
repositories of
all um open source libraries so these
include things like
their bug reporting systems like jira
bugzilla github issues
or their source control repositories um
like get
bitbucket etc we do that because we
realize
that even if there is a vulnerability
that eventually gets assigned a cve
there is a high likelihood that there
are clues or hints about that
vulnerability
which are available in the upstream
software artifacts of these repositories
where you could actually track them much
much earlier before they eventually
reach
the nvd and in case of open source
libraries many of the
vulnerabilities and security issues
still do not get assigned with a
cbe now
when we started this process we were
doing things manually
and we realized that it is extremely
difficult
and the reason for that is we have to
support millions of
libraries we actively track thousands of
git repositories and in order to
manually do this means that somebody
needs to sit in and take a look at
every single commit message or a bug
report that is filed
and then make a judgment whether to see
whether it's related to a vulnerability
or not
right and once you know that it's
related to one ability you still have to
do further investigation to figure out
what versions are affected what is the
fix and how do you
address that vulnerability so we need a
solution that can scale
with the increase in the number of
libraries and third party components
um so it's quite natural to think about
using machine learning in this context
because if you look at it from a
perspective of machine learning this is
like a
classification problem so you have some
particular data source whether it is a
bug report or a commit or
mail advisory and you want to figure out
whether this is
related to a vulnerability or not so you
have like a binary classification
problem
right so when you look at it from a
machine learning perspective you'll
realize that
the data set that you're dealing with is
highly imbalanced so
the chance that a given commit out of
all possible commits is related to
vulnerability is actually very very low
right so when we looked at our own data
we realized that
depending on the data source uh even
after doing some pre-processing or
removing you know some obvious things
or filtering obvious candidates we ended
up having a data set which is highly
imbalanced
so in some cases it could only less than
six percent of the
uh data set was related to a
vulnerability right
and as we continue to expand on the
different sources or we continue to add
more uh
libraries to our system the size of the
label data set keeps increasing
but the unlabeled data set is always
there
so imagine you start using the system
and then you start predicting
what items are related to vulnerability
eventually you will have a
system where you're always doing
positive class predictions and over a
period of time
your label data set will only consist of
positively predicted data because you're
not really verifying or validating
the things that are predicted to be not
a vulnerability right so that's the
whole point so you want to scale
so you end up having a data set which is
uh labeled
it's highly imbalanced and the labels
are mostly related to the positive
predicted data set right
so due to these two problems we really
needed a solution that can balance
and scale the system despite having
these two issues
at this point i would hand over to my
colleague ming who would go over
about and talk more about our approach
towards vulnerability
curation which is based on machine
learning over to you ming
thanks asankia as noted previously
we wish to develop a process to hunt for
vulnerabilities at scale
so we iterated on our machine learning
approach that is able to keep up with
our requirements and skill
the following section is a condensed
summary of the machine learning approach
we presented at the mining software
repositories
2020. in this new approach
we incorporated more data sources and
supported more programming languages
on top of that after having the system
run over a period of time
our data has become highly imbalanced
the highest imbalance from our most
affected source went from about six
percent
to about three percent what this means
is that
if we looked at 100 items we would not
utilize the other 97 of them
this became an issue as it can cause the
machine learning model to be overly
biased
depending on the machine learning
parameters we desired
to solve the issue of data imbalance we
introduced self-training
into our machine learning approach the
self-training approach allows the
machine learning
to utilize the unlabeled data for
training
this is particularly useful for data
sources that display
a huge imbalance of labeled data
proportion
such as for commits as asankyo mentioned
earlier
in a machine learning system we will
want to be
only one to be able to only focus on the
data that matters
and so the majority of the data we
process
comes from the data that were predicted
to be vulnerable
however as a machine learning model is
usually
imperfect there will be type 2 errors
where they provide
false negative predictions together with
the false negative predictions
we also have a portion of data which
have never passed through the initial
filter
these two types of data makes up the
unlabeled data which
will be utilized for the self-training
approach
through our evaluation we find that the
new model is generally performed
no worse than the old model and in most
cases
we did see an improvement of performance
from the new models with self training
from this study we also made a couple of
observations
self training generally increases the
data set
which the model is trained on and the
increase
of performance diminishes as
if we test it on models which originally
have a high recovery
overall we have deemed the study to be a
successful one and
throughout the rest of the talk when we
talk about discovering vulnerabilities
it
is generally from processing data that
we have put through
our machine learning model
so up until this point you have heard
about vulnerability
creation and how machine learning has
been utilized
to help us discover and curate
vulnerabilities
however it's time to take a step back
and wonder why
all these are necessary why are we
even doing this and to think about what
we are trying to achieve
to understand about the complexity of
this issue
moments ago you have heard about how we
have implemented a machine learning
solution that enabled us to process data
at scale
with the main goal of finding
vulnerability related data
from the entire stack of general data
it is shown to be efficient at finding
vulnerability related data
however it it does not automatically
translate to data
we are interested in so what exactly are
we looking for
and why at this point you may even be
asking me hey ming
isn't there a ton of databases and
central authorities we could use to help
identify these vulnerabilities
well before i get to that first allow me
to provide some context and motivation
behind why we are so
interested in discovering
vulnerabilities firsthand
to help understand some of the
motivation we will learn about the
nature
of modern software composition
before moving on to the topic of
dependencies
and finally to highlight some
inefficiencies
in particular the central authorities
as we will see in the next few slides
the problem of securing today's
software is not as simple as we would
like it
let's relook at how we typically think
of securing our code
first we start off with ensuring that
developers adhere to safe coding
practices
then we run static analysis to further
ensure our first party code
will be relatively free from well-known
vulnerabilities
such as sql injection or directory
traversal
we might even run dynamic analysis to
check
if we might have missed out from
detecting some subtle blocks
or to reach code that static analysis
would not be able to fully understand
to double down on finding exploitable
vulnerabilities at runtime
we can also conduct penetration tests
and if we have done everything up to
this point our code is
relatively secure what else could go
wrong well an
often overlooked point is the trend of
external dependencies
when you use external dependencies you
are subject to both
the good and the bad part of it the
threat ranges from regular code flaws to
malicious threats that tries to hide
itself through pre-installed
post-in-source scripts or even through
social engineering attempts
such as like typo sporting
the threat of external dependencies is
not just about what kind of threats are
out there
it is also about how it is increasing
our attack surface
without us knowing about it just in the
picture
on the right of this page describes a
regular expression denial of service
issue
found in url rejects
if you take a closer look on the fifth
row where it says path the url rejects
package
is actually not directly being used by
this application
but it is found in the sixth layer of
dependency
hopefully by highlighting this example
you would have a better picture on
how the issues can go unattended and how
it can actually go
dangerous
now that we have discussed about the
potential of a dependency causing harm
let's look at the nature
of modern software composition
most software built today are almost
always built with a ton of third-party
dependencies
very few of us would write our own
framework or even a http request client
from scratch
just to implement a feature that may
take a few hours or
a few days to write
to give a quick overview of modern
software composition
i used some key information from vera
code's latest volume
of the state of software security report
depending on the programming language
used and the type of application
a real world application would typically
include tens
to a hundreds or even over a thousand
third-party libraries
when you have such a large amount of
third-party libraries being used
most of the code in the application
would most probably
not consist consist of your own code
but would instead mostly consist of code
that others have written
these code may not be audited by anyone
and it would also be too expensive to
run static scans on the
applications if your application is
pulling in hundreds to a thousand
over third party libraries
the top 10 used libraries in javascript
is included
in over 80 of javascript applications
well one way to look at this is if any
of these top 10 libraries
was vulnerable it could cause
most of the javascript applications to
be vulnerable
in fact we found that at least two of
these libraries in the top 10 list
have had known vulnerabilities at some
point
in a study of all applications scanned
over a year
of over 70 of applications tested
has at least one external library flaw
and of which over 40 of these external
library libraries were not
directly requested by the developer
again all this just shows how widespread
the issue could get
when developers use third-party
libraries in the application
how about relying on central authorities
when it comes to the topic of central
authorities well we agree that central
authorities provides
validated vulnerability information
the issue arises when they are overly
relied on
to provide the source of truth of
vulnerabilities
so the issue of central authorities
include the time taken for
vulnerabilities to be published
the inaccuracy of the data where
information could suggest that
all versions before a certain version is
affected
but it's usually not true as the
vulnerability may
be introduced only at a certain version
imposition of the data where information
could suggest
imprecise software component
an example would be like if spring boot
was
vulnerable or stated to be vulnerable it
is
usually only a specific component within
spring boot
the inaccuracy and imprecision of this
data generally causes
it not to be directly actionable
furthermore there are flaws which are
not found on
central authorities the percentage of
such flaws varies be
programming language and the overall
average
was found to be at 15 percent
with respect to understanding what your
application is
one vulnerable to one of the gaps would
be to only rely on central authorities
when we look at how software is built
into this landscape
to develop the intuition of discovering
vulnerabilities in
party libraries we will need to also
understand the challenges with finding
such vulnerabilities
two main challenges arises resources are
limited
and new libraries or library updates are
usually
many and frequent
therefore we find that as a starting
place we wouldn't recommend to
directly look for vulnerabilities in
third party libraries
after all we don't really know what we
can expect to find and
would not know where to look from
for the remainder of this talk i will
not go into the details of
collecting the precise information
of vulnerabilities instead we shall
focus on the vulnerabilities themselves
and how we can discover vulnerabilities
so instead of the traditional way of
securing code such as using static
scans we could use we could look for
sources where the developers and
contributors
will interact data sources
such as github jira and mailing list
are very rich in information to know the
good and the bad about
a particular library
and to test our intuition we have
formulated a process to help us gather
these data
however doing so also results in an
infeasible large
dataset in a hundred thousands range per
week
for this reason we implemented the
machine learning approach
that reduces this amount to thousands
per week
to talk about the results of this
implementation i will be sharing some
data examples in the next few slides
first we have a case of denial service
found in the axios package
the issue here is where axial streams
will not be destroyed
if it exceeds the value of max content
length
and having lots of them would lead to
high cpu usage
thus causing the denial of service
normally this wouldn't be such a huge
issue
however axios is downloaded over 13
million
times a week and is depended on by at
least 44 000 others
this example highlights the potential
for issues to be
highly widespread
next we have an issue of denial service
through regular expressions
found in the trim package this example
also highlights on the potential for
issues to be highly widespread the
package is downloaded over 3.4 million
times weekly
and is used in over 371 thousand
repositories
if it look closer in the picture we can
see that the issue was still being left
open
and was at least 7 days old when the
screenshot was taken
for such a widely used library the time
to react to such issue may result in a
more severe penalty
cross-site scripting has been
consistently one of opp's
top 10 vulnerabilities here we see a
particular case of
x found in xxl job used by over 2000
repositories
this issue isn't going to reach as many
end users
as the previous two examples but it
should not be left alone as well
the omni-off package is vulnerable to
crossset requests for the ray
and it is rated as a high severity issue
by nvd
omnioff is a library that provides
flexible multi-provider
authentication for web applications and
it is typically used in ruby on rails
applications while the issue is only
present in
specific conditions it is written as a
high severity issue
as it can allow an account to
authenticate as
another account a ruby on real
application
could likely use the omni-off library
for authentication
in the unsafe manner and have this form
baked right into the application in this
specific example we can see that
a warning has been added to the readme
and it was not addressed directly in the
library
a possible reason might be due to the
flexibility attribute of the library
here's an attempt at security by
obscurity in zen cli
through a one word description patch
the issue was caused by a weak regular
expression that could not properly
sanitize file paths
these are some of the data points where
we think that the machine learning
approach
shows its efficiency at discovering
vulnerabilities at scale
without the need to run any form of
static or dynamic
analysis
an issue of arbitrary code execution was
found where
eval was used for json passing
in this example it would be fairly easy
to write a code password to find such
issues
but a larger issue would be the
consideration to run all those at scale
to run it on every external library used
and every version that was used is used
or will be used in the future
finally we also find several transitive
issues
through the data and there are many more
and we can go
on for a day at this point you would
probably have a better understanding of
the risks
so i will be sharing some of our key
observations from processing these data
from the examples we have noted that
third party dependencies are vulnerable
to the same
type of code flaws and faces the same
issues of fixing
transitive issues by keeping frequently
up to speed on the data that matters we
are able to discover
and act on these issues earlier
now you might be wondering apart from
malicious quote
introduced by social engineering attack
how serious can this get
well to emphasize on the issue at hand
we have seen new classes of highly
critical vulnerabilities uncovered from
time to time
and affects existing code which may be
widely used
into this application this serialization
issue
such as those injection data buying
arbitrary file or write true unzip
functions
the issue of prototype pollution these
have all been observed to be widespread
when they were first discovered and
as the number of libraries are expected
to increase with time
it is also much more probable that newly
discovered flaws can affect even more
applications
so to really be somewhat be safe
we have to know what we are using
whether they have known vulnerabilities
and to actively keep up with this
as a new flaw may be discovered at any
point of time in the future
now that we have a sort of baseline on
what information is out there
we can also think about taking the
approach a step forward by discovering
similar vulnerabilities in other
libraries
while this is still an ongoing work in
progress
the general concept is to be able to
automatically sync up
potential libraries that may be
vulnerable to an existing vulnerability
type
further for each pattern we could come
up with a key signature to automatically
create a proof of concept
and to test if an application or
third-party library will produce
positive results it is like
running a targeted dynamic analytics
scan
and it may not be possible to
automatically create
a proof of concept for all known types
of vulnerabilities
[Music]
to conclude this talk we have three
points to make
so we have to continuously be on the
lookout for issues
in our dependencies the number of
dependencies
increases over time and so does new
types of vulnerabilities
code that may look secure today may
actually be
insecure in the future the machine
learning approach is not
self-sufficient and can still be
improved upon
and that what we have discussed today
does not cover
all actual prevailing vulnerabilities
so at the very least we should try to be
on par
with already disclosed known
vulnerabilities
while we continue to discover more
vulnerabilities through different
methods
i hope we have brought across the idea
of
how we can discover vulnerabilities
quicker
for faster response to learn from what
is out there and to develop an
intuition to finding similar
vulnerabilities that are out there
thank you