[Music]
hello everyone
my name is jason and i'm the director of
the strategic threat advisory group at
crowdstrike
today we're going to talk about north
korea's rapid ascent to becoming a
global cyber superpower
so like i said i lead something at
crowdstrike called the strategic threat
advisory group
and basically what our team does is we
help our customers operationalize their
threat intelligence capabilities
prior to crowdstrike i used to work for
a big four consulting firm where i built
threat intelligence programs for fortune
500 companies and government agencies
prior to that i was in the army for
approximately seven years where i held
assignments at places like the nsa
and united states cyber command and now
over to my colleague josh burgess
hey everybody so josh burgess i lead the
technical science chief director team
sounds like an arbitrary long title but
i'm the person helps people action
intelligence from a technical
perspective
integrate automate it and build it into
your workflow i've been at crowdcheck
about
three years um running this program part
of that
working as a lead technical officer at a
major credit card processor was there at
about four years prior to that
u.s intelligence community doing that
for about 10 years um
in private military what i've learned
along the years is
it's not necessarily about how much
money you spend sure you could dump
millions and millions of millions of
dollars in infosec program or millions
of dollars into an intelligence program
but it really won't make you better the
idea is to learn
from history learn from the tax and the
techniques that we've seen
build that into your intelligence
program and help you get to the point
where
you're predictive instead of reactive
awesome thanks josh so here's the agenda
that we're going to be reviewing today
we're going to start off with an
executive summary that reviews over all
the patterns that we've observed from
north korea
and then we're going to talk about their
evolution throughout their cyber journey
across a three-phase process phase one
is where they focus on military-focused
targeting
phase two is much more so about currency
generation operations
and phase three more about dual focused
operations finally we'll conclude by
giving a few predictions
about where we think north korea might
evolve to in the future
so let's go ahead and start off with the
executive summary and
probably the best way for us to
characterize north korea's path to
becoming a global cyber superpower is
across
these three phases of their evolutionary
process in the first phase
we're looking at the the kim il you know
the kim jong-il
dynasty kind of regime during that time
frame and during that time frame they
were very much so focused on
power projection really going after
military targets
also during that time frame they were
demonstrating the beginnings of their
nuclear program
and so again in this phase they're
really focused on kind of really
projecting power
and really pushing back some of the
regional adversaries to include the
united states
south korea and japan in the next phase
we're going to talk about currency
generation operations
and this basically came as a result of a
lot of the sanctions that were put on
north korea
as a result of their nuclear program so
in order to bypass
some of the financial hardships caused
by these sanctions we observed north
korea engage in a variety of different
types of currency generation operations
to include fraudulent attacks ransomware
attacks against the swift banking
systems
and more and then lastly we're going to
talk about dual focused operations which
is where we see them as currently being
and this is basically where they have a
dual focus priority the first one being
really still going after these economic
targets and still some of the currency
generation targets
but also really expanding their global
targeting apparatus
to go after more international
organizations such as the un
and other similar type organizations
so before we dive into talking about the
phased approach that we saw in north
korea leverage
let's do a brief history and review so
with the first
few kind of attacks that we're observing
here what you'll notice is that for
these four that i'm showing here
it's really much more so about lashing
out and
in large part i would i would argue that
a lot of the attacks they did early on
their days were fairly
ineffective they engage in a lot of
different ddos attacks
they attempt to use wipers on several
different occasions however they weren't
able to really do any serious damage in
the beginning of their military
targeting phase
and then as they kind of progress
throughout this phase what you'll notice
is that the attacks become much more
targeted
as well as more focused so here's what i
mean by that
whereas in the first phase you see a lot
of ddos attacks and a lot of lashing out
in this subsequent phase you see a lot
more focus for example the exfiltration
of 200 gigabytes of data from the south
korean ministry of defense
which you know again that's a that's a
major victory for the north korean
cyber capability you also see them hold
at risk the korea hydro and nuclear
power plant
you see them continue to go after
critical infrastructure by going after
the seals the
seattle subway system and then of course
culminating in november 2014 with
you know a very significant attack
against sony pictures
in the next phase of operations we see
north korea focus much more on currency
generation
and that's what this these blue uh you
know these blue little snippets here
really mean right
and this is where they're focused much
more on engaging in attacks that allow
them to generate currency
such as atm cash out schemes fraudulent
attacks
the use of the wannacry capability as a
sort of ransomware
as well as stealing approximately 60
million dollars
from taiwan far eastern international
bank
and then the last phase of their
operations what you see them now do is
really engage in sort of this
dual focused type of activity where
they're not only focused on still the
currency generation operations as
indicated over here where i'm circling
my mouse
with the you know the stealing of seven
million dollars from the cryptocurrency
dragon x
cryptocurrency exchange but also attacks
against critical infrastructure
such as the one i'm illustrating here in
october 2017
as well as attacks against international
targets such as the one they were
illustrating over here in august 2020
so again we're looking at sort of this
evolutionary phased approach
where they start off with
military-focused targeting then evolve
towards currency generation operations
and then lastly leading them to where
they're at now with as where they sort
of
dual focus in their operational stature
so now let's talk about the individual
phases and we're going to start off with
phase one which is military focused
targeting
and again with from a military focused
targeting perspective
here's some of the big areas that we saw
them focus on the first one being around
the use of personas
so josh is going to describe this in his
slide but basically what we saw north
korea do early on
is use various personas in order to
avoid blame
or avoid taking too much credit for some
of these malicious attacks
like i said in the overview slide we saw
them engage in a lot of different
operations
against both south korea as well as the
united states
particularly ineffective operations
especially in the early days
and then lastly i would characterize
this phase as being really much so about
how
very much so about power projection so
the ability to project power
to push back regional adversaries to
demonstrate to the world
that they are this you know extremely
powerful regime with all sorts of
capabilities
and this is very common for different
types of countries who are trying to
engage in deterrence
in order to basically get the
international community to kind of go
more their way
so now over to josh where he'll talk
about some of the personas and some of
the more nuanced aspects of this phase
of the north korean operations
thanks jason so a couple of different
phases like when you look at the initial
campaigns all the way from 2009 2011
independence day 10 days of rain
really no misdirection they didn't point
to hey we're this group or that group
or a fake activist group they just smash
stuffed and they tagged it but they
didn't tag it as north korea
dark soul was the first time that they
actually misdirected
the eagle is it who is team there's some
references to roman foot soldiers that
they messed up and i'll show you what
that looks like in a second
in operation high anonymous because you
know what anonymous is still big in 2013
let's go ahead and ride that train if we
still can
and they utilize that as their big
persona guardians of peace the sony hack
now guardians of peace was interesting
because again
fake this persona but they utilize a lot
of the same artistry and same imagery
from the previous campaigns like dark
soul and high anonymous so i guess
the uh the artists there really weren't
feeling too original
with the latest campaign the last one
that we saw with some real big
misdirection
was who am i and that who my campaign
was launched against the korean hydro
nuclear program
or nuclear plant excuse me and they bent
what like
as a traditional definition of a
hacktivist they didn't just go in and do
something for ideology
they went and did something for ideology
but they also had an e-crime slant and
espionage slant so
it's a little interesting and that's
really where the um where the personas
kind of stopped after that
so let's talk about military targeting
of south korea this is where they were
first all kicked off 4 july 2009
dozer dozer is a multi-pronged malware
approach
the first thing dozer does is ddos
attacks and the first one is leveraged
that was u.s targets
on the fourth of july then you know we
saw on the 7th of july
going against 7th or 9th of july going
against korean targets
this these targets going after gov
mill.com
banking sites um ddos you know
fairly effective not particularly great
and then
came the wiper component on the 10th day
the wiper command goes in
and smashes stuff 10 days away the next
evolution 2011.
cordos create a botnet and be our wiper
now this one was a little more tailored
a little more customized this is when
they first started building obfuscation
encrypting their malware
the other thing they did was interesting
they look for files very specific to
south
korean systems files like dot hwp or
hangout word processor
or files like g well or azp or some of
the other south korean tools
again though a lot of the mostly ddos
attacks with a little bit of white brown
tail dark soul
this is when they really started making
web um the steedy and who is wipers
used against atm systems um
servers workstations multiple big huge
south korean banks were hit pretty hard
tens of thousands of systems
were wiped this malware worked on
windows as well as linux environments it
really wasn't specific to one
platform or the other the other thing
that's interesting about this malware
is you know the references to histidi
and principles they kind of messed up
those references those are basically
um forms of old roman soldiers they kind
of mix
mix and match the definitions mix and
match how they were used
really didn't read their textbooks quite
right operation high anonymous
you know again why not ride the
anonymous train that's big back then
core high malware used against mostly
south korean government well as needed
targets
things interesting about this campaign
is a lot of the malware that we saw
that we took apart the amount
the malware specifically had
the credentials hard coded into it so
they knew what they were breaking into
before they broke into it once they got
into systems
wipers perform change administrator
passwords from
whatever they already knew it was to
hide on 2013
and cause impact the last big one
kimonsky
kamonski targeted korean hydro nuclear
plant
and this malware did extensive recon
help ahead of the you know actual
infection the reason this is a big deal
and it ties all three together it goes
you know the e-crime side when they
broke in they demanded
millions of dollars millions of dollars
in order to
disable you know in order to re-enable
systems they also demanded that
you shall um shut down three reactors
as a part of our demands not sure where
that demand came from but they also had
an espionage piece
so the kamatsuki malware was designed to
steal information about nuclear power
generation because if you've looked at a
map of north and south korea north korea
is really dark at night
south korea not so dark so they're
trying to you know
push through military targeting but also
kind of straddle all three lines along
with their attacks
last one power projections the sony
attack um retribution for the interview
the james franco and seth rogen movie
that basically
uh made fun of the um kim jong-un and
later led to his assassin you know
assassination
they got in and this was an all hands on
deck they utilized malware from multiple
different subgroups
to get in and really smash things around
one of the best tools was bramble
um and then core high for smb spring
these
tools were used like years and years and
years prior to the attacks
so get in spread around utilize
smb ports to move and move loudly
then utilize tools like mac truck which
was used in swift targeting nest egg
also in swift targeting and the atm
attacks
get in steal information they stole
employee information from every sony
entertainment employee under the sun
they also stole all the future movies
before they were even released
posted them all out again it goes back
to that projecting power
you shall not mess with us we don't take
kindly
to your slights and our leader um and
that's how they
did those attacks
[Music]
so the first movie first movie i'm sure
you guys first demonstration i'm gonna
show you guys is dozer
dozer was the original destructive piece
of malware
that we saw from north korea let's go
ahead and roll it
so this is the first of three different
malware samples we're going to
demonstrate for you guys
this is the og of the dprk destructive
malware
what we're going to walk through is my
doom
now dozer was the first real campaign
they did the first real malware family
my doom is the destructive side
the reason we're doing my doom is
because my doom operates really well on
windows 7 and windows xp where dozer
really only works on windows xp
to do what we really wanted to do so
since windows xp license keys are nearly
impossible to get a hold of at this
point which is a funny story because my
wife just threw away
the last of my old witness copies a
couple weeks ago but
since we don't have a copy of windows xp
we're gonna run this on seven it's gonna
work just fine
now as i detonate this couple things to
think about again this is the original
stuff
not particularly quiet arp requests are
going to go crazy with this thing trying
to move all over the network as much as
it can
the other thing that's interesting about
this is despite the fact
that it's the early campaigns there is a
couple anti-virtualization
tricks and techniques that they use in
there this is an obfuscated version of
vm
so it works just fine but there is a
little bit obfuscation to do
the other thing they do is the mutex
that the malware creates is ahn
underscore v3 pro so kind of a nod to
south korean um
antivirus you know when they launch the
campaign the other thing that's
interesting about this
is when they go through and they execute
a lot of 10 files are dropped
unpacked dll comes down more tim files
loud beacon out back to
um a a get request that's really obvious
the get request is slash china slash dns
the uh
the 200 you know marking is google.com
exclamation point which is interesting
but you know again not particularly well
written but it does its job so we're
going to go and execute this and you're
going to see what it does so we're going
to give this next pupil name
go run
quick comb through all the files are now
locked
we don't need to do any more as you can
see can't do anything with it it's a
gzip file
the gzip file's encrypted the only thing
that remains is a beautiful picture of
this nice man
right here on my desktop that's the only
thing that lasted from the encryption
process so
that was the first thing we're going to
show you guys there's a couple more
coming your way
awesome good stuff josh so in this next
phase we're going to talk about the
transition from the military targeting
phase
much more towards a currency generation
type targeting aperture
and really what we're looking at here
and the reason that this happened
is because as a consequence of a lot of
north korea's actions
during the you know kind of the the 2008
to 2014 time frame
north korea well the international
community imposed a variety of different
sanctions
on north korea so the way we saw north
korea respond
was by engaging in cyber operations that
allowed them to generate currency
the first of those was against the
targeting against the swift banking
systems
where they were able to basically engage
in a global fraud
against several different banks
throughout the world the next was an atm
jackpotting technique
where uh during some of the subsequent
slides josh is actually going to
describe
how they how they used fast cash to
engage in banking entities throughout
asia and africa
and then lastly we saw north korea
actually also engage in ransomware
operations
via wannacry where they use ransomware
in order to fulfill some of their
objectives
and again to make uh to make money in
order to fund the regime's illicit
activities
and now over to josh thank you jason so
swift targeting where it all started um
actually the first yeah incident that we
saw was the bangladesh bank targeting um
they actually made quite a bit of money
well into nine figure
kind of um revenue from that now the way
this initial attack happened was
you get into systems and they had deep
knowledge deep deep knowledge of these
targets um
well ahead of time so get in modify the
swift you know swift
transactions delete the records behind
you
and then you know some additional steps
and additional steps especially in the
beginning was super interesting because
they actually had programs designed to
steal
information as it went from the system
process the transaction to the printer
they don't want anybody to have any
record of these attacks
later on the vietnam attack which is the
next one that we tracked they modified
the foxit reader
to to obfuscate and change the message
as it went out
it kind of shows you that that deep
knowledge this wasn't like
uh e-crime attack it was a spray and
prey trying to hit whoever they could
they knew what they were targeting over
the years they made over two billion
dollars in these campaigns
um the the other piece that goes along
with this you know because this is north
korea
is the white papers the wipers were part
of a highly modular framework going back
to the two-pence power framework
that was deployed in the end to
mess up forensic evidence or mess up you
know tracking of actually what happened
and hopefully they get to keep their
money sometimes they did
and then sometimes they did
the next one i want to talk to you guys
about is atm jackpot
operation fast cache again starts with
two pins framework get a beach head
there
deploy modular framework once the module
framework was in
again highly targeted really capable
stuff this wasn't like a spray and prey
attack
they actually targeted the aix operating
system which is owned by ibm
now if they you know a lot of these
banks that they had the current version
of it they didn't use legacy software
that was end of life
by years a lot of these attacks wouldn't
have been a possibility so they targeted
vulnerabilities
in these older um these older operating
systems so
when the matter got in the first target
swiss the swiss application servers
intercept the cash withdrawal and delete
the record of it in the tail end
they also built that as they went
through this a very
um high level of social engineering in
one case they went after a
major chilean bank when they hit the
chilean bank
um i guess they didn't get in the way
one two or they wanted to get in a
different way they actually
recruited an individual from a linkedin
post
found an individual that worked there
that was network administrator sent him
a fake job interview
actually held a job interview over skype
in spanish
um a job interview went really well hey
you got the job just download this
executable to help you fill out the
application
executables the back door as a result of
these attacks and
much of them like that we've seen over
30 countries be involved in ap and
jackpot
again you want to show like the amount
of time resources in one case we
actually saw
10 000 fraudulent cash withdrawals these
cash withdrawals were spread across 20
different countries
all over the world all these different
cash withdrawals all happened
within five hours high level
sophistication high level of capability
it's definitely uh shows that you know
they're broke they need to make money
they need to get their fun you know
their finances up to where it needs to
be
the last one this is the dawn of the
ransomware
wannacry wannacry actually started back
in february
um of 2017. february 2017
um malware was pretty well written had
some obfuscation
had a little bit of you know
misdirection in there um
antoine house wasn't particularly
difficult then we saw two more in march
start introducing things like tours of
back in start building an encryption
then we saw more in april april again
kind of the next evolution we saw smb
spreaders be put in there
but in may that's when you know
it went that's when it went nuclear
that's when we saw um
all the effects that happened from it we
still don't know the initial infection
maker we think the core dll framework
because in some cases
um some of the initial victims had
dusted over on their network so earlier
targets the reason that the may one was
such a huge deal
obviously is they incorporated an
internal blue into their attacks the smb
you know vulnerability thank you shadow
brokers for releasing that to the world
and that you know caused a huge impact
200 000 systems were infected
all over the world now the interesting
thing about that is 200 000 systems
that's a lot of systems right
but they only demand about 300 to 500 in
bitcoin depending on the flavor you got
thousand systems plus three hundred
dollars should have made a lot more
money than a hundred thirty nine
thousand dollars in revenue
but it really did so you know that was
the there was a genesis
of their ransomware campaigns now we'll
go ahead and show you guys
the next video and what i'm going to
show you is the early the february
evolution of wannacry
and where it really came from
so what we're going to show you now is
this second piece of now that we plan on
demonstrating
today what we're going to go through is
the original version of wannacry the
wannacry that was first um discovered
on february 9th not the ransomware
campaign that we all know and hate that
happened on friday thank you kim jong-un
on may 12th so we're going to walk
through the malware and see what it does
a lot of similarities with the other
stuff um aes 128 encrypted
file structure and file extensions are
pretty much the same the biggest
difference between the two
is really kind of around the propagation
method
the reason the propagation method's
different because the earlier version
was found on february 9th the shadow
broker the release of the smb
vulnerability the smb worm that we all
also hate wasn't you know really the
release until march so kind of a little
before that
so we're going to kind of walk through
the malware and see what it does
the other thing i want to kind of
highlight is what's interesting about
this malware commonality between the
recent wannacry
is in this case along with the previous
case
when you kind of take apart the malware
and you look at when it was constructed
constructed or compiled it's utc plus
nine
the reason this is interesting is utc
plus nine is south korean time
not north korean time north koreans in
made their own time zone how north korea
them their own time zone
utc plus eight and a half so this sample
doesn't fall along with the right time
zone the reason for that likely
is they're rocking pie rated software
who would have thought they weren't
paying their bills
so let's watch this thing execute what
it does
here it goes puts everything with wry
extension encrypts the files
pops up with a pretty ransom note that
all your files have been safely
encrypted
and now your computer is unusable
all the data is largely encrypted and
gone so
that is the second sample hang with us
in a few minutes we're to
show you the third great thanks josh
and that takes us to our third and final
phase where we assess north korea to
currently be at
whereas we're kind of see them right now
it's sort of in this dual focused
type operational stature and when we say
dual focus what we're really talking
about here is sort of a combination
of that traditional military focus but
also focused on
economic operations as well things to
not only enhance their national
economic priority areas such as
agriculture power generation
and similar types of critical
infrastructure but also still continuing
along the vein
of currency generation operations
however one of the things that we see
with these new currency generation
operations is now the targeting of
non-traditional targets such as several
cryptocurrency exchanges
especially those located in the east
asia region you know within south korea
as well as japan like i said we also saw
a lot more focus
during this phase on economic growth
targeting and you know one way to think
of this is sort of like they took a
page out of china's playbook whereas you
know whereas china engages in a lot of
economic espionage in support of their
own economy
we're now seeing north korea do the same
and like i said
it appears to be focused on the sectors
and particularly critical infrastructure
sectors
where they need a lot of help so things
like agriculture
things like you know power generation
you know you heard josh say earlier
that if you were to take a satellite
image of both north korea and south
korea
at night you would see all the lights on
in south korea and then you would see
barely anything in north korea
so in response now you see north korea
focused on espionage operations
to try to basically empower that aspect
of their economy
and then lastly beyond the economic
growth targeting operations and then
beyond the expanded criminal operations
now we're seeing them targeting
government-related entities but going
much further beyond the traditional
government entities and when i say
traditional i mean kind of like the
traditional adversaries
so like the united states south korea
japan
and now we're seeing north korea think a
little bit bigger right so now they're
going after
international organizations such as the
united nations uh recently we even saw
them go after
the israeli defense industrial base and
what that really indicates is an
increased amount of confidence
on the behalf of the north korean regime
and at this point they really do believe
that yes
they've succeeded in the past they've
been able to kind of get to the point to
where they're at now
and now they're really taking it to the
next level so now for this final section
i'll pass that over to josh to talk
about some of the more specific use
cases
joshua muted thanks
yeah always going to slip maybe at some
point
so so economic growth targeting one of
the biggest areas we've seen them focus
in on is energy production but not just
energy in the form of nuclear
uh oil and gas you know coal multiple
different
groups so in 2017 we saw a target in
north america pretty heavily
a lot of different organizations got hit
one of the biggest one was in houston
texas and goes to oil and gas
not everything is nuclear now these
these campaigns they all built
in malware that was designed to steal
stuff it had destructive back ends of it
but it was more designed to steal than
anything else
especially in the most recent you know
oil and gas campaign
it it was designed to go through pilfer
the information out
throw the wiper on the end and then you
know make a
make it seem like they could actually
control power fortunately
in every case that we've seen um from
then until
even the most recent 2019 attack
everything was designed
to be more business focused disabled
business not
ics sca systems 2018 we saw the us
really stopped
getting targeted europe and asia kind of
took up in its place
as a result the biggest most notable
attack though is the 2019 targeting
a major indian power plant this indian
power plant supplies power for most
of southern india so a huge deal when it
hit the maori utilized that was d-track
the reason is cinching is because
d-track's been used multiple times in
the past
detroit atm stole information from
indian
atm systems detract you know in the
early 2010s was utilized against korean
banks
you know again we're using the malware
over and over again if they broke don't
fix it let's just keep you know
operating the same way we were the other
thing that's interesting about this
attack is
india is a major trading partner with
north korea so i'm not really sure what
they were thinking of this one
kind of you know something to watch to
see where the effects come
fall out from that
last one and jason was mentioned this
earlier crypto target
these crypto targeting operations
involve a high amount of social
engineering
you know in some cases you know
targeting individuals via linkedin
recruiting them fake job applications
like we've seen before but in some cases
they actually create legitimacy or
what looks like legitimate fund
companies jht trading
um silas trade pro they actually created
these organizations created these fake
companies with you know
shells and whole back stories in order
to
be more appear more legitimate the other
thing that's interesting about what
they've done
is collaboration with known russian
e-crime groups groups
like trickbot and ta505 trickbot for
those that don't know
it is a malware as a service you have to
be a highly vetted criminal to get
access to the malware but it's still
malware as a service the trickbot got
the initial foothold network
foothold was established um connect is
different systems get full access
then that access was sold to lazarus
toolsets
which did later monetary um scraping and
data collection often
the last one is the new evolution of the
ransomware vhd
vhd we believe was deployed via
vulnerable vpn gateways
once the vpn gateways were exploited the
matanet malware
moved around and gathered information
this magnet malware
is highly versatile highly modular it
works on windows works on macs works on
unix there's multiple different
operating systems shows that they're
maturing their operations
and they're confident in where they're
going the next slide i want to show you
guys though this one's super interesting
because this is kaminsky north korean
apt
going after russia not just going after
russia
writ large but going after russian
aerospace and defense
i'm not sure what they're thinking
because most of their armament most of
their arms and their military equipment
comes from russia so i'm not really sure
what they think of this one
but it's definitely something
interesting to watch so what happened
you know
we saw or you know there were
phishing emails were observed targeting
these aerospace and defense contractors
these these phishing emails look a lot
like what target u.s
and europeans european defense
industrial base fake job application
because code is a thing what's up why
not use cobit as well so
utilize the um the fake job location of
the
covet operations then drop the malware
and then you know move around the system
to try to build for data it also goes
back to the reconnaissance effort so
we've seen them as they mature
it's not just get in there smash and
grab and kind of feel your way around
there's a lot of scanning that was
observed from april to september
against russian systems as well as yes
you know u.s and eu systems
that correlates along with these attacks
so highly you know high's fist hit
great social engineering around it not
sure what to think of going after russia
but you know something worth watching
so the last piece we're going to show
you guys is another version
of ransomware from north korea again
this isn't highly widespread like
wannacry this is more
targeted and more moving into the big
game big hunting operations
so this is the third and final piece of
destructive north korean malware we're
going to be showing you guys
this one's a little bit different unlike
wannacry which is strictly revenue
generating this is more of a smokescreen
this is designed to lock systems down
and it's a wiper not ransomware
it's designed to lock systems down and
distract incident responders from what's
really going on in this case stealing
millions and millions and millions of
dollars from the taiwanese far east bank
so the malware is going to execute um it
comes along as a package i shouldn't say
that first it comes along as a package
and this comes along with the whole two
pins framework
hermes is just a piece of it it's an
instructor piece i would demo the whole
package but
two pins not quite as cool to look at so
this power is going to go through and
do what all ransomware does first thing
gets on or almost all
first thing gets on the system it'll
check for language artifacts it's
designed um it has code in there to look
for ukrainian
belarusian russian however it only
really checks
and stops the process if it finds
belarusian ukrainian
not russian which is a little
interesting then it'll do all the normal
things yes admin
delete shadow copy so for backups code
through every drive letter
use the windows crypto api to come with
the key pair crypt things over as256
and then do all the normal smash things
that we uh we all know and love at this
point from ransomware
so nothing really new or novel or
interesting about this ransomware the
biggest thing that makes this you know
something to look at is again it's not
really designed to give
garner ransom this is only designed to
distract
instant responders away from what's
really happening on the system
so we'll watch it execute give a few
seconds
and then everything becomes unusable
deletes itself
and one two three everything's gone and
then there's your pretty ransom note
you don't pay me money you never get
your data back blah blah blah
blah all the meanwhile everything
is encrypted nothing works
so thanks everybody hopefully you
enjoyed
all right awesome thanks josh and now
we'll finish off with the conclusion
where we're going to make a
you know a few uh possible assessments
of the direction that north korea might
go in the future
so the first one that we have up all the
way to the left is around the potential
use of advanced ransomware operations
so as josh and i demonstrated throughout
this brief we've seen north korea use
ransomware for a variety of different
reasons in the past
whether it be for the currency
generation elements of the ransomware or
for the potential destructive elements
of the ransomware attack
what we think north korea could
potentially consider in the future is
the addition of
two new ransomware techniques that we've
observed over the last year and a half
two years or so
and those are one data extortion and two
ransomwares of service
with data extortion basically what the
threat actor does is in addition to
engaging in the ransomware attack
they are now stealing valuable personal
data during the course of the attack
and then after locking down the systems
what they do in addition to sending the
ransom node
is they also extort the victim with
additional information such as
pii or intellectual property or other
sensitive data
and they basically threaten the victim
and say that if they don't pay up
they'll
essentially release that data on a daily
site so that is one possible option
another possible option is we could
potentially look at and see north korea
engage in you know business models such
as ransomware as a service
where they can potentially outsource
large portions of their ransom
operations
to third-party affiliates thereby
allowing them to increase the volume of
their attacks
and therefore also likely the amount of
profit that they get from the attacks
the second prediction or assessment that
we have is that they will likely
continue to take a page out of china's
playbook and we can see them really
investing in this area
so you know we've said throughout this
brief that obviously you know
north korea's economy is struggling it's
struggling in a variety of different
ways
for a variety of different reasons
whether it be because of having you know
being ran by a dictatorship or some of
the you know some of the conditions that
have been imposed upon them because of
the international sanctions
we do see a lot of you know struggling
within north korea and one thing that we
could potentially see
the kim jong-un dynasty our regime do is
go after
you know continuing to go after these
economic targets and we've seen north
korea issue five-year plans
very similar to what china does and
whenever china has issued these
five-year plans
what we have observed trying to do
immediately after the plans is engage in
espionage in support of those particular
objectives
so it is very possible that we will
likely or potentially observe north
korea do the same thing and then our
last prediction
is around the uh the notion of cyber
brinksmanship
so brinksmanship is basically a term
used in
deterrence strategy where two sides are
going against each other
and they basically want to see who's
gonna kind of call chicken first who's
going to kind of chicken out first
and that's sort of basically what we see
them doing we see them bringing
their regional and international
adversaries all the way to the very edge
and then potentially using capabilities
such as cyber
or nuclear capabilities to achieve those
deterrent effects
uh we do believe that they're likely to
evolve more towards the cyber side of
the house
as opposed to using continuing to use
nuclear the nuclear option as their sold
to turn capability
and one of the reasons that we think
they're going to use cyber more is
essentially it's just
safer for them the more they play around
with using nuclear weapons as a
deterrent capability
the more they re the more they kind of
uh you know the higher the chances that
one of their adversaries like the united
states might engage in a preemptive
attack
and obviously north korea does not want
that if north korea were to go engage in
kinetic conflict with the united states
north korea would lose and not only
would they lose uh their you know the
regime would potentially also be
replaced and they want to avoid that at
all cost
so given that logic it is very likely
that they will
instead kind of go the cyber route which
still allows them to project power
still allows them to kind of take swipes
at their adversaries but does so in a
much
safer way for them that not only has a
lower risk of
kinetic retaliation but also a lower
risk of having
the kim you know the kim dynasty being
replaced
so that is all we have thank you for
watching our black hat
talk and please enjoy the rest of the
presentations at black hat
thank you