[Music]
hello everyone
welcome to my presentation today my
topic is related to
the apple bluetooth subsystem the title
is
attacking io bluetooth spamming hci and
vendor-specific commands
my name is wong from dd research america
i can be reached through this email
address
in the first part of the presentation we
will focus on the design
and implementation of bluetooth hci on
different platforms
the first question we may have is what
is hci
of the bluetooth system basically
people define the operating system side
as the host
and the firmware assigned as the
controller
then the software interface between the
host and the controller is called
hci from the hardware perspective
the physical connection can be for
example the uart interface
the following is a more detailed diagram
the blue part
here is the hcs stack
which includes components such as
demands and the drivers
the red part is the hci firmware
or we can call it the controller the
yellow arrow is
hci which is a bridge connecting the two
parts
for daemons hci provides a
unifying command method access bluetooth
hardware features
next question we may have is how many
commands does hci
bluetooth hss part the answer is a lot
and they are divided into many groups it
is worth mentioning that
there is a group dedicated to
vendor-specific commands
or we can call it vsc for short
if we search for vsc on the internet
we can quickly find documents similar to
the following
this document is from texas instruments
but i have to point out that
holding a small number of bluetooth
vendor-specific commands are documented
for most of them we cannot find
references at all another thing is that
the meaning of vses on different
hardware
may be different even if their op codes
are the same
for example for the command whose op
code
is fc0a
they have completely different meaning
on the
ti and broadcom platform
and let's take an example to learn the
hci command of bluetooth
in the link control group the number one
command is
inquiry we can find its definition
in the latest version of the bluetooth
official menu
according to the menu inquiry must
include
lab inquiry length
and the number of responses
the menu also defines the cracked
value range for input for example for
inquiry lens input should be
from 1 to 30 in hex
if you submit an incorrect input it will
theoretically be rejected by hci
or controller
with the basic concept of inquiry
command
let's take a look at how each operating
system implemented
i chose three different operating
systems
lightweight bluetooth linux kernel and
macos kernel lightweight bluetooth is
representatively implementation of
bluetooth
protocol stack and we often see such
lightweight implementations in iot
devices
or iot environments lice
731 to 738
of the code are the construction of the
inquiry command we can see that
this this code is constructing
lab inquiry lens and the number of
responses almost a bite by byte
personally i don't like this kind of
handmade code very much
they are not easy to maintain and
sometimes not easy to
understand
when it comes to the linux kernel it
becomes clear
almost all commands are defined as data
structures
which can be found in the header file
the third example is our protagonist
today
the mac os io bluetooth family kernel
extension
when i first located the function io
bluetooth hci inquiry i saw some
strange strings with the
deepening of reverse engineering i found
a large number of such strings
which appear in almost every bluetooth
hcl handler
curiosity draw me to summarize these
strings
and i found that they could actually be
regarded as indicators to
guide the functions pack data list and
unpack the list the indicator for
bluetooth hci inquiry is hbtb
h means two bytes and b means one byte
they represent the op code and
body size of the hci request
tbb corresponds to lap
lab inquiry length and number of
responses in the menu
so we can easily deduce that t means
three bytes
now we can summarize three different
operating systems
the implementation of iot related hci
represented by lwbt is the
simplest and the design of
mac os io bluetooth family is the most
complicated i think apple can patent
their hci requests to construction
process maybe
second complex design
often means more attack surface and
please also keep in mind
if the design and the implementation are
too simple
it usually doesn't mean security we will
discuss it
later on
in the next part we will try our best
to dive into io bluetooth family to be
honest
when i started this research project i
didn't expect that i could find the
security problems
of bluetooth at first i just want to
learn
about the bluetooth subsystem of mac os
for this i read the documentation
write a lot of source code and
even reverse engineered the bluetooth
kernel extensions
however if we in turn to take the
previous work as a starting point
and continue this research seriously
where should we start
for me i think i still need some more
tours
for example sniffer i need sniffer i
need fuzzer
i need the code coverage masters for
close the source driver
and the kernel address sanitizer
then we need to do attack surface
assessment
after reverse engineering i found that
there are at least
two attack surfaces that we must
consider
simple dispatch wl is responsible for
managing the data floor from daemons
to the hci while the function
process event data wl is in charge of
the
state machine from the controller
back to the host
and three years ago in order to learn
mac os
i wrote a kernel extension which
integrated file operate file operation
monitoring
dynamic library and the network traffic
manager access control policy filtering
kernel extension firewall and other
features
the project called chemo also includes
a kernel inline hook engine which can
hook
almost any kernel function you want the
source code of the project can be found
on github
in the last year i practiced the mac os
ipc communication monitoring based on
this project
it can filter x pc ipc communication
between
processes and here is a link to
blackhead usa arsenal and in order to
learn more about the architecture and
the
attack surface of mac os bluetooth
subsystem i wrote several sniffers
based on chemo
this screenshot is one of them it can
intercept all hci requests sent to the
controller
because k-monk has pre and post callback
capabilities
i can parse out the input parameters
core processor like bluetooth d
and other useful information in the pre
callback handler
and i can also print or modify
the return data of the target function
in the post
callback handler by
analysing the log we can find some
interesting details
of the bluetooth operation on mac os
platform first of all
every specific operation is
accompanied by crate and the delete
operation
this is very similar to the file
file open and close handle operations
on windows platform between
create and delete is a specific
hci request
and i have a demo of the sniffer project
please let me play the video
let me first clean all kimon locks
then i will turn on air job
it will trigger sharing the and the
bluetooth
these operations
okay yeah
then we can say a large number of
bluetooth
hci requests
let's take the first group the first
group as an example first there is a
create operation and then
is a row command row window specific
command
from process bluetooth
d and then is a
delete operation so compared with other
hci sniffers
on based sniffer can capture and display
the details of this car sequences
okay
and in order to deepen our understanding
of the hci commands
we need to do some more practice
next i'd like to refer an article
called hanking i o bluetooth which will
be mentioned
trials in today's presentation
this article explains how to write a
user mode program to communicate with
the
bluetooth daemon and driver and finally
meet the requirements such as modifying
the
local name as shown on the left
here the author
wants to change the bluetooth local name
to
cda
with the knowledge learned by using
keymount based sniver
this requirement is is easy to us
to achieve we only need to
implement the calling process from
one crit hci crate
and then read local name change log name
and
then delete so we can have a
command line tool like the one on the
right
in the next step we need to deepen our
understanding
of vendor-specific commands render
specific commands on mac os
can be divided into two types
the first is the building vs
reverse engineering shows that
these commands have corresponding
handlers
and indicators
but more vendor-specific commands come
in the form of raw data for example
as shown in the screenshot
of hci sniffer
it's your command in the in the format
of document
at this year's blackhead usa arsenal
i shared some tools that uses the
raw vendor-specific commands they can
communicate
directly with the controller among
them some commands are very variable
they can even read and write ramp
data of the firmware
and here is a link
okay so our next goal is fuzzing
because we have sniffers we can quickly
convert them to
passive buzzer that is that is because
we can do bit flipping
of input parameter easily and we have
implement some tools that can
send for example raw
when a specific command to controller
which can also be
transformed into active fuzzers
in practice in practice i found that
combining
the two fuzzing method often has better
results
and by the way since we have chemo in
hand we can use the
inline hook based method
to perform basic code coverage analysis
against closed source drivers
let's see how my further works on mac os
bixer let me play
the video
[Music]
as a target machine when i made this
video
the operating system was the latest
macos mixer
let me draw my browser and yeah after a
few seconds the
system crashed
it's already crashed
[Music]
okay
yeah through all kinds of efforts we
have gone
a long way compared with simply
reading documents and codes we already
have our own
sniffers and the fuzzer
we even implement several
implements simple code coverage tool and
the kernel address sanitizer for
close the source driver they are not
perfect
but as we will see in the next
capture they do perform well
the next capture is mainly about
vulnerability case study
i will share with you some details of
the latest macos
bluetooth kernel vulnerabilities and
what i have learned
from them
since hci is open to low privileged
processes the infosec community has
always been
concerned about the security impact of
this
interface in recent years
binary auditing and fuzzing against
drivers such as io bluetooth family have
never stopped
we can also approve this from the output
of
error pro hexary the routing
io business hci user client
valid parameters has expanded from
300 lies of code on macos highest sierra
to more than 3000 lies on macos catalina
so that means hunt vulnerability is not
that easy
however with the help of fuzzer's
k-mount-based code coverage method and
the kernel address sanitizer
solution i did the
i did find some security problems in the
latest mac os and i so far i reported
the
23 vulnerabilities to apple
um and their types include
uninitialized memory derivatives kernel
information disclosure
heap data autobahn access arbitrary
memory access double free use of the
free cost by
risk condition and one more thing
security update turning turning number
two can be bypassed
here is the cv id and the patch
information
the first vulnerability i want to share
with you is related to
autobahn's reading of kernel hip data
i have i have give i have given two
cases for
this type the cv id is
3907 and 3908
in the kernel address sanitizer's panic
lock
we can see that for vulnerability 20 20
39 7 our actual input lens is only one
byte
and the wonderful function will read
about 200
bytes out of bonds to hci request
and here we can see
a lot of database tag
they are all created by my kernel
address sanitizer
and the call stack is
is this
[Music]
hci request method
a similar situation also exists in
function
hci write start link key
this handle this handler mistakenly
trust the user input
and the situation is the same
so in summary this type of vulnerability
is
straightforward and easy to fix the
wonderbolt handler
lack the necessary verification for
user mode input parameters and
with kernel address analyzers help
such vulnerabilities are easy to hunt
we have several more cases
[Music]
the second vulnerabilities cv id is
turning 10
39 12. it was fixed
in june this year
this is an autobahn access vulnerability
and i listed list listed separately
because
as far as i know this is the third time
this function
has been found vulnerable the first time
the vulnerability was disclosed
in 2014
that means six years ago and
in the in the link below is a poc for
the vulnerability
and then in 2015
a vulnerability named 20
2015 3787
showed that the function was once again
found to be vulnerable
the call stack triggered by the
vulnerability is shown
in the figure below
and five years later when i was auditing
this function
i found that it still lacks
if effective boundary checking
when the input is malicious magical
number
the handler will auto bond access and
the
panic
in fact vulnerabilities are found
repeatedly for some
complex functions another interesting
case is 2020
9834 it's a wi-fi vulnerability
i discovered this year this wonderful
function
was attacked 30 years ago
so for such complex functions
it is better to have complete test
cases to ensure that all branch
can be covered
case number three the 79 cv id
for of the third vulnerability is
20 20 99 29
which is fixed in september this year
the reason i noticed this one
variability is because i found that
the indicator of function hci enhanced
except a synchronized connection request
has changed
on the high sierra platform the
indicator is
this one but on macos catalina
the indicator of the function has
changed to
well to to this this string contains
several percentage characters
and i have no idea about the percentage
character
so this change has brought me many
questions
for example um we will need to introduce
compatibility issues and
what is the main meaning of the
percentage character
and whether are there other new
characters introduced
um i have no idea that at a time after
reverse
engineering i found that percentage
means that the pack and unpack
routine need to read five bytes
of the data from the input address
but the problem is that the address can
be controlled by
user mode
so the following panic log is the
result of setting input address to
that coffee that beef
there are many interesting use uses
for this feature such as
building a more efficient low hammer
based on this vulnerability
and we can have a try
next i searched for for
apple sdks this is another case
where i found useful information from
the sdk
in the bluetooth header file the
indicator
input that can be accepted by the
pack and unpack function is defined in
detail
a percentage is actually the
shift key of the number five
which represents the reverse
processing of the data input by the user
so all the questions about indicators
have answers here
[Music]
as a conclusion i want to
print out the change
of indicator actually means that
the function of the controller
has changed and the new features
or changes always mean new attack
surfaces
um so which are worthy
of our exploration
and by the way uh reverse engineering
plus apple sdk usually means a better
life
the first vulnerability is related to
vendor-specific command let's start with
lwbt
i found many interesting comments
when reading the lwbt source code
the comments show that the ulcer
does not seem to be very clear about
how to handle the bluetooth event state
machine
and how to write
exception exception handling correctly
it should be said that this situation
is not uncommon
it's remind me that bluetooth event
handling functions
are worth of attention
on the mac os platform the name of this
function
is process even the data wl
and for which i wrote fuzzer
and the sniffer specifically for it
and this with the further research
i noticed a raw command
with opcode fce9
which is not actually documented
this command will cause the kernel event
handler
to crash and this is the screenshot
at the time
so this case reminds me that
undocumented commands and
non-standard hci implementations
can lead to domino
effect
case number five the fifth case
is is an uninitialized
memory dereference vulnerability which
is also the
first bluetooth vulnerability i found
the process of discovering this
vulnerability is very interesting
it took me less than 20 minutes
to find it and 20 minutes ago i just
decided to
open the edit pro to reverse
bluetooth kernel extension so this
vulnerability give me
a great confidence um
i i can fund this vulnerability not
because i'm lucky
now because i'm good at kernel reverse
engineering but because i have made
similar mistakes a few years ago
the pattern of this vulnerability is
like this
say if someone writes a lot
conditions in an if statement
so what what situation need to be
covered in the
else branch to me for for this case i
don't know i prefer to
rewrite this code
and let's simplify the problem the
this this question um
if there are only two conditions
uh like condition a is true and
condition b
is also true we need to discuss
three cases uh in the else branch
which is uh a is not true but b is true
and a is
true b is not true and a and b
they are both not true so
if we ignore these corner cases they are
likely
to lead potential problems
so now let's look at the
wonder real vulnerability of the mac os
kernel
the if branch here has two conditions
the number one is the number one
condition is
the kernel must allocate
a heap block successfully and
number two is the the user input
buffer is not empty okay
according to our previous analysis
the else branch should cover all
uh three corner cases um
but what about the the actual situation
yeah we can see here the else branch has
nothing
this means that attacker can bypass
or skip the initialization process of
the
function validate parameters by holding
providing the
input lens and this uninitialized buffer
are then parsed to all hci handlers
so um this vulnerability has been hidden
in plant side for a long time and
some traditional fuzzing methods are
difficult to find this type of
vulnerability and one more thing
is i i
agree with linux coding style do one
thing and
do that well
okay the last one the last case
um also represents a class of
vulnerability
that took two patch days to fix
the story can start with the call stack
in the article
hanking i o bluetooth when i first saw
the call stack
the odin words i could say was wow
with the deepening deepening of the
research
i found that it contained a lot of
useful information
in this english cod stack in short
after entering hci the entry is
simple this here simple dispatch wl
and the exit is i o bluetooth hci
request to start
after request to start the request
will be inserted into
a queue and then send to the controller
through the uart interface my question
is
how to protect the data structure in a
multiple thread development
the answer is the command command gate
mechanism
which holds the lock when entering the
command gate
and release the lock when the command
sleep is caught
so please note that we cannot hold the
lock during sleep
otherwise it means deadlock
then a new problem comes after
command sleep the request is not
completed by
the bluetooth controller so again
how to ensure the bluetooth related data
structure are safe
in this window
unfortunately the mac os bluetooth
kernel developers
didn't consider this situation
and this design issue is very similar to
the
windows wings 32k user mode callback
issue and due to the the
limited time i could not discuss it here
um here is a link i
i i have
explored this kind of vulnerability
several years ago
and it's very interesting
so here is the panning log of this
vulnerability
it's a user after three or double free
issue
so as a previous one vulnerability
like 20 20 99 28
have been hidden in plant side for a
long time and the factor
all os bluetooth hci handlers
um yeah so and
and again this kind of vulnerability is
very
uh it's hard to find by traditional
fuzzer okay the last part
take takeaways
the first one from the perspective of
vulnerability research
i want to say with the with this
research as a startup starting point i
believe we can do more
and from the perspective of engineering
i would say with the help of kmon
project
i believe we can do better
okay thank you thank you very much thank
you for your time
bye