[Music]
hi everyone
my name is timur yunusoff and today i
have my co-speaker
alexis tennikov and our presentation
today
is post world should you be afraid of
hands-on payment devices
and today we are going to talk about two
major point of sale vendors
and vulnerabilities that we found in
their devices
and for us that was quite a journey
absolutely new world
new creatures new habitants with its own
rules and that's why today
we are trying to do this maybe a little
bit childish metaphor
of pokemons and we call this world the
boss world so what the post world
consists of
what the rules are what creatures do
they have and how secure these creatures
are
that's what we are going to answer today
on top of everything we have
pci scc or payment card industry
security standard council and whose main
job is to maintain pci dss
or data security standard so you see
this is kind of the
book of the book of main rules of this
world
in terms of security then we have
mastercard and visa two major current
brands we have verifone and ingenica
major point of sale vendors today we are
going to talk about
only two of them and we have issues and
acquiring banks who are doing payments
responsible for cars
issuing and for receiving payments
then we have merchants essentially shops
and we have customers
and we also have hackers so hackers can
act as rock merchants or customers and
this is basically how we jumped
into this research ourselves you see
over the last four years we
had a few banks and service providers
who were particularly interested in
how much security is in their devices
devices that they use and their
customers use
if you look at the payment process
hackers can act
as external entities against
point-of-sale terminals
if they are customers but if they are
rock merchants
they try to compromise the devices and
they try
can try to insert data
in card stream fraud and commit
fraud on much higher scale you see
[Music]
so if you talk about security
requirements
of pci we have a few documents and each
of these documents have
uh dozens of pages with spreadsheets
with
requirements questionaries we have ptas
pin transaction security document and we
have pin entry device security
requirements
but i will try to save you time and
explain your rules
in a few lines so the main role of pci
do not store send or process sensitive
data
customer card holder or card data
without encryption
so these data include pin codes track to
data
or cv codes from the back side of your
cart
then if device uh if someone is trying
to open the device
these should be detected so device
should be tamper-proof
and once this is detected you should act
so
terminal should turn on even if it's off
and delete sensitive data which includes
encryption keys and
payment apps and we'll talk about this a
little bit later
and also terminal needs to indicate that
the device has been compromised
so it basically should be turned into a
brick
now let's talk about hackers so we had
a few researches about point of social
security in the past
so within the last 10 years guys from
the university of cambridge
made the research about hacking point of
sale devices
then within the last five years we have
sr labs and carstenol
who have presented vulnerabilities about
major
european uh point of sale vendor and
we ourselves within the last three years
made a research about mobile point of
sale
and security in these devices
so now we are going to talk about the
terminals what is inside what
vulnerabilities they have
how to attack and how to weaponize them
and finally
we sort of know the requirements of this
world already but we still
don't understand the rules of how this
world operates
and i would like to pass the microphone
to alexi
hi there thanks timur the first step in
order to make your own evil and
weaponized creature is understanding in
its weaknesses and internals
basically every terminal hides from your
bunch of legacy code
technologies and strange approaches and
it's great to understand world
technologies takes starting from
hardware
in this talk we don't have enough time
to describe point-of-sale hardware in
details
but we have already published this
information on defcon payload village
more details you will find on the
village youtube channel
i'd recommend to you to pay attention to
this channel because it also contain
other useful information and now we are
going to shed light on software
components
it's time to weaponize your post
terminal
we should keep in mind that we are going
to break into secured well protected and
certified devices
when the vendor goes to pci
certification he should satisfy pci
rules
and fill a form like previously
discussed one
suddenly this successful certification
itself don't guarantee that devices
completely unhackable
the first creature to weaponize is
ingenico pin pad
let it be slowpoke our findings affect
the wall product line of such
terminals there is basically no
difference
is it portable or counter top they all
built using the same hardware
and uses the same telem 2 operating
system
this is just an example of this series
but i sure this kind of terminals
is well known for all of you it is
expectable
that all the communications to the bank
servers are encrypted
but there is an alternative way to get
into it
the maintenance tools and special modes
the main software for server section is
called llt
it is usually used for application and
operation system
locks collection firmware upload and
operating system and application updates
to connect a pin pad to lte software you
should boot the device
with special key combination what does
this mod hide
first of all it uses very strange way to
establish connection
to the device the terminal itself is
recognized as a virtual com port when
usb cable is connected
llt software brings up pvp connection
over this
virtual com port when this connection is
established the pin pad initiates
connection to pc6000 tcp port
and weighs a response from lt software
usually the llt software sends the
command to pinpad to open
ftp server in order to get access to
some part of device file system
the interesting thing here is the code
credentials for every step
also no one has an ability to change
these passwords
because they are part of operating
system binaries
the protocol on 6000 tcp port used to
open
ftp server is called ntpt3
it is completely insecure with
absolutely no authentication
and other integrity control mechanisms
by exploiting this vulnerability and
having direct connection to terminals
usb and attacker gain access to internal
ftp servers it also has some
undocumented comments
lt is allowed to read only file system
the directories host and swap one
vulnerability allows
reading any files whose absolute path is
less
than 17 characters long
it allows an attacker to obtain
cryptographic keys
and manipulate traffic between point of
sale and
acquire also some extra functions
of this protocol are buggy too
the third intestines finding in this
chain is trace protocol
with no authentication and encryption
trace mode is intended to monitor
performance of banking application
during
development for post debugging and
assist developer feedback capabilities
by using this protocol and having direct
connection to the terminals
interfaces for example usb an attacker
gain access to terminal operating system
and application internals via trace
command line interface
anyone has access to this command line
interface just using the config file
magic
and the trace 2 from software
development kit
example of trace tool output is the
following
this command line interface has help
commands in order to get description for
every available comment
but a research wouldn't be complete
without bunch of non-declared comments
as you may see it exposes to attack or
additional function
to get hardware and software status and
some additional debug capabilities
as a result this sim debug mode allows
full control of the pin pad
the exposed commands allow to allocate
and de-allocate memory
display the contents of all files
of the terminal internal file system
including encryption keys
and to suspend resume and terminate
processes and threads
the example attraction error is
classical
allocate a memory for malicious code
then
write malicious code to allocated memory
suspend and modify a non-important task
in order to point to our
code and then just resume suspended task
finally we have code execution on
any italian-based angelica terminals
is it a good result for such research
definitely yes is it a good news for
their customers
probably no but anyway
we have another creatures in our
research
the next question is well known very
foreign terminals this is an example of
their vx series terminal vx-520
let's figure out what can we do with
this creature
the entire vx product line uses works
vx5 operating system
it is proprietary one as in previous
example
executables for varex operating system
has dot out extension with their own
binary format
and should be signed in order to be
executed on the pin pad
the default password for this type of
pin pair discussed many many times but
no one changes it
you can find the same password even in
ancient
zone xl pin pads from 18th of previous
century
to enter the service mode you have to
press f2 and
f4 keys during the boot of pinpat
and enter the password this mod allows
to modify
internal variables and obtain technical
information about
the exact pinpad model and extra install
updates
example of such variable is go variable
it should contain an executable file
name for autorun when terminal
it turn is turned on
the vx5 base terminal has a file system
divided to multiple drives
some of them mentioned in documentation
but some of them
are used internally by the vendor and
are contained
run drive some partition on non-flash
drive
drives related to boot block and
additional file systems
the drives mentioned below the list are
marked as reserved and
written by varex operating system during
production
this is very interesting thing because
we haven't found any useful information
related to these drives
in any sources in the recent reason
we paid attention to them and found some
gifts from developers
we all know that all executable files
should have their digital signatures
but the drive t is another case its
contents
can be modified and all the binaries
you can find there are trusted by
operating system by default
you can modify the configuration file on
file system menu
in order to execute any of dot out files
from drivet
the most interesting of findings on the
internal and
undocumented file system is the shell
binary
probably once upon time this was used
for recovery and debugging
but now it's just legacy piece of
executable code
to execute it we should modify go and r
variable as you can see on the slide
the results of this modification is the
following instead of merchant
application the pin parts cited the kind
of shell
it is accessible via serial port and
maintenance cable
it has an ability to run signed binaries
list and dump contents
of the file system upload new files
to the pin pad and some other comments
it is very useful but we still don't
have an ability to run our
unsigned code as a result we can upload
any files execute
signed binaries modifier configuration
of the device
but we are still limited by digital
signature checks
in this case we already have extended
user input
from the merchant application to some
internal commands
once the merged application is limited
to the encrypted tms server interaction
and whereas from bank to bank let's
focus to vendor specific issues
we need to look what can we do with some
shell commands
when we try to file the user input for
some comments
we've got a crash we passed too many
symbols
to shell command and we got classic
buffer overflow
also useful scene is in this crash
is output on the display we can see
crash addresses
and some register contents as you may be
noticed
13 in hex in the least significant bit
of cpsr register
means that we got a crash in supervisor
mode
it equals to the crash in vx5 operating
system kernel
the investigation of this crash points
as to buffer overflow inverse operating
system
system call as you can you can see on
the cd code
there is a classical memory copy mistake
on the stack
additionally it is needed to be said
that
there is no measures turned on in order
to prevent code execution
finally we have got a code execution on
any verifix
device because they all have the same
code base
but another interesting thing is the
case in the boot chain
every vendor reinvented their own boot
order
in the case of pin pad devices sometimes
the boot order chain
is very long it also has a lot of legacy
because almost all of these
operating systems developed before
traditional secure boot approach became
a mainstream
after reset a zero stage bootloader
should be started
usually it is located inside mcu in form
of
mask rom it loads the next step
bootloader from flash memory
and checks its cryptographic signature
using the key stored
in otp rom and any other secure memory
every next bootloader also should check
the cryptographic signature of
every loaded piece of code etc etc
finally when operating system loads an
application it also should check
its signature
now you see the works operating system
terminal
boot log output internally it is called
sbi as you may see it can work with usb
sticks
and in this case it loads works
operating system kernel
please look at the operating system
kernel output
here you can see the broadcom cpu model
that
was previously operated to internal
verify name
this bootloader is located at the start
of non-flash memory
the purpose of interaction with usb
flash is factor
restore if usb stick is recognized it
goes to look for science script file
that executes a sequence of actions to
burn you
operating system kernel for example
another interesting ability of this
script is to put the bootloader to low
level command line interface
however we don't have any examples of
science scripts
when we had a look into bootloader we
found
some protocol handler if you dive deeper
we faced with the
same protocol as used in usual
maintenance for terminal loading
the utility for this protocol is called
ddl
and can be found in the internet
and finally there is another classic
memory copy related black was found
the weak logic is contained in the
update format parser
and allowed us to write any memory
regions without any restrictions
the most fast way to exploit this
vulnerability is to call restricted part
of bootloader
as we have mentioned before there is
very useful command line interface
parser
and now we are able to call it
as you can see this command line
interface prompt called without
valid signal script file this mod allows
us to access the wall file system
to dump and burn in regions of flash
memory
to load any code into memory and pass
execution to it
as a result this pin pad can be
exploited
using the physical connection before
operating system is loaded
the last case is linux based mx series
verifone
this is one of most recent pin pad model
and it is also pci certified it has
advanced permission settings like
supervisor user and maintenance mods
also the road user isn't allowed to get
access to different files on the pin pad
file system during to role based access
control settings
we have already seen the research
related to these models at different 25
three years ago the mx series of
verifone pin pads
already were hacked but in some reasons
we have seen exactly the same problems
on our projects with the latest
firmwares
the exploitation chain is default
password for system mode
command injection in maintenance mode
privilege escalation based on vendor
service
and finally write condition in role
based access control configuration
this presentation describes all the
steps how to get into this model but
this is not the end of a story
about mx series
in the bootlock we see the same chip
what already known as
9 bcm5892 surprisingly faced with the
same bootloader as
in where x5 pin pads but in this case
it loads not the proprietary kernel
model
it loads you boot finally it has
literally the same
code and can be exploited in the same
way before operating system is loaded
that's almost all about technical parts
of terminal weaponizing
and i am going to pass our virtual floor
to tmur
now when we are finally familiar with
vulnerabilities of possible species
we can try to establish the rules of
this world
so rule number one i guess is that if
pci console does not require any
specific security measures
they will never be applied in the real
world for example pci does not say
that you need to delete firmware and
vendors delete
only applications on the main operating
system it's also probably quite time
consuming to delete quite a large
chunk of firmware with a tiny small
battery
next is keys should be deleted yeah
but pci does not specify how exactly
uh vendors should delete their keys so
in most of the cases
vendors just put a special mark on the
files in file system saying that
files add files are deleted and not
delete them
in a very secure way so
rule number two is probably that
over the years all vendors are doing
uh sort of security through obscurity
approach of their devices of security of
their devices
so they were using proprietary operating
systems for long long time they were
using special proprietary protocols
and outputs formats of files formats of
physical outputs you can see that there
are a lot of special modes skill switch
combinations which allow
to get access to special secret comments
and probably security through obscurity
is not the best
approach security wise
next let's see at the difference what
you can
and what you can't do in different
models of
point of sales so because ingenica has a
dedicated
chip for the cryptography which we could
not get access to
it actually should seem very secure
even though you can compromise the main
uh
part of the reader however it's not so
you still
are able to send arbitrary packets that
make sense we'll come to this just in a
minute finally
and we still can clone cards including
pin codes and track 2 data
and cv which is quite strange and i will
explain this
just in a minute the only one difference
is that you can clone terminals
themselves
because keys for terminals will be
stored on the dedicated chip
and the problem is in jennica is that
your malicious code will be rewritten
after each reboot so you won't you will
have to
in fact device after each reboot
let's talk about cloning cards cloning
pins
how you we all would have presumed that
pin entry process works for example so
the customer enters pin
on the pin path and information goes
there from there to a dedicated chip for
the encryption
and already encrypted goes to the main
operating system and the main part main
chip
where it goes in the transaction stream
over the network
however in fact it's not the case the
algorithm how most of the vendors do
this procedure
is that pinpat customer enters pin
on on the pin pad and it goes straight
to the main operating system to the main
app
where to get access to you need to have
maximum privileges
root access or work with the
[Music]
kernel kernel rights
and only after that from the main app it
goes
to the specific chip by
api for encryption gets back already
encrypted and then
goes in the transaction stream so
you can see flow here right if you'll be
able to
run special malware special software
which will allow
to scrape the memory of the main app
and still the spin codes still track to
date
before it will go to be encrypted
that's it hackers can get access to
pin codes to track 2 data and it's quite
bad
shall we say so now let's talk
how to clone the terminals yeah
only one vendor allows to clone the
terminals
and to do that you need to steal quite a
fistful amount of different keys
you need to steal the keys for
encrypting network communication you
need to steal the key
for pin encryption you need to steal a
key for
signing message authentication codes and
you need to steal
a few additional keys like the key for
storage encryption and the key for
integrity control for the operating
system
but once you've done it you get a fully
functional clone
of the original point of sale and that
allows you for example to make
transactions
pretending to be a part of the big
merchant
and carry out transaction stream fraud
or carry out for example money movements
and refunds
which is quite nasty at the end
so and finally let's talk about
weaponizing terminals and making
payments attack
so when we begin this project that was
the one of the original goals where
customers said
is it possible these infected terminals
to carry out some actual fraud for the
banks
and we have done this uh and shown these
to our customers
and we actually even done a
a bit of site research so once you get
access to the transaction forward
to the transaction stream it's really
easy
to send arbitrary packets and try
to confirm fraudulent transactions and
it's much easier as if that would be
just a regular customer with stolen
cards and
these fraudulent transactions will be
accepted in the end
so as you may know uh european banks now
adopt adopting new payment rules
called uh psd2 or payment
service directive across the board
and we've shown how it's possible to
bypass
pin requirements pin checking process
and reset
cumulative limits for contactless
transactions
so in normal circumstances this attack
would have required specialist equipment
for a few thousand
grand and
[Music]
what we have done instead we just
tweaked
a couple of bits of information
in the transaction stream with
modified terminals and we were able to
save us a lot of time
and a lot of resources and we have done
these attacks and fraudulent
transactions
were accepted using these attacks
so i'm not gonna spoil you can read
about this
uh in a white paper this research uh
now is about something completely
different
so for engenica we arranged 10 different
cves
and as you can see they were informed in
that's why we call this pokemon a
slowpok
yeah as you can see it took two years
for vendor
to get back to us and to confirm
that vulnerabilities were fixed the
problem is that
we still don't even know how badly or
how
really good they were fixed because we
never received
any update we never received any
software
or firmware or the hardware with the
updates
very fun on the other side is quite good
and acting
quite proactively so we inform them in
they get back to us reasonably quickly
and once all
vulnerabilities were fixed uh they even
send us
updated devices to confirm from our site
that all
vulnerabilities were effectively uh
mitigated
[Music]
so we still have a few open questions
yeah one of that is that we still don't
know how good
very ingenica fixed their
vulnerabilities we never received
any updates from them and these
vulnerabilities still can present
in the modern versions of their point of
sales
uh we also don't know the difference
between
end-of-life devices and new devices
newer devices that
both vendors supply because
at the end of the day bad security is a
bad security
and if you do mistakes and if your
developers do mistakes
that means that they probably will be
found in the whole range
of your products
and then i would like to say thanks to
all researchers and reverse engineers
who were participating in this project
and thanks to all of you guys this
project would not be done without here
it's really nice job and if you have any
questions
uh you can let us know and we're already
publishing
our research our white paper today so
links are available
on our twitter pages so go ahead and
read and thanks so much for listening
us