i'm really happy to have uh steve
scooped thomas back on stage
uh first time was
in
paso scott in oslo in december 2012 so
almost 10 years ago
uh a pretty uh fun experience and a good
talk back then uh he's also been with
pascal several times before
and uh about steve i can say for you
know for certain that
i understand maybe two percent of the
stuff he's talking about because i
basically suck at math and crypto
but i can also say that if you have
anything that is using crypto that you
intend to put online
if you haven't hired steve to look into
it first to look for vulnerabilities
you're doing it wrong because he is
incredibly good at finding
vulnerabilities and now
it's steve and
via script a cash hard password hash so
go ahead
okay
uh just for clarification that's crypto
as in cryptography
okay so uh bscrypt
uh it's a new password hashing algorithm
and kdf
so uh password hashing and password kdfs
follow on a fall under this umbrella of
key stretching so
key stretching can be used for other
things like
so if you have a small key
you know you have something with like 30
bits of entropy
and you want 40 bits of strength you can
stretch for 10 extra bits
you can use that for like um
uh fingerprints so you can have a
shorter fingerprint but it's harder to
make a collision or whatever
but we're only going to be talking about
uh password
uh
key stretching in relationship to
passwords so uh
key stretching um so
uh the first thing that people came up
with was uh computationally hard so what
this is is you just hash your password
then you hash that and over and over and
over and
memory hard you just use the
resource of memory and you hash stuff
and you know
uh
whatnot here are some algorithms so
pvk df2 uh you may have heard of maybe
not and you know uh there's argon 2 s
crypt uh balloon hashing which doesn't
actually have like an official
uh spec or anything like that uh yes
crypt
um
so
computationally hard uh there's two
sub sections one that i explained before
where you hash the password then you
hash that then you hash it again it's a
very sequential operation
i realized that i should probably
uh so it's like kind of a new algorithm
people are kind of afraid of it
but pbk df2 has this foot gun where
um
so if you ask for so pbktdf2 sha256
uh that's 32 bytes of so sha-256 is 32
bytes uh if you ask for 32 bytes
from pbk df2 uh you run through all the
iterations but if you ask for any more
it will do all the integrations again
but with like a different counter at the
top
so all those are done
in parallel if you ask for a large
amount of output so
i just
this is the entire algorithm
uh you just
ask for a large amount and then you xor
each of the blocks together and then you
do that uh this should
you know uh nist should um
like fast track this into pbkdf3 or you
know uh something so that we can get
something that's better than pbkdf2 df2
at the end you'll see a benchmark
between this and other algorithms and
yeah
[Music]
so this brings us to cash art this is
relatively new
basically uh
the difference between memory hard and
cash hard memory hard uh reads like
sequential blocks
of memory so you'll read like a kilobyte
from memory randomly and then do
something with it and then you know
what not uh cash hard you want to
do small
fast uh random
uh
lookups so you're looking up
uh eight bytes versus a kilobyte
and doing
a quick operation
so
decrypt
this is minimally catch art
it was kind of accidentally cache hard
because it used this
encryption algorithm called blowfish
which had uh 4k of s boxes and
we didn't know that you know
cash hard was a good thing until gpus
came out and
uh you know
people were noticing that you know the
speed to
generate one of these hashes from a
defender
versus how slow they are for a gpu
attacker you know it was way better than
other things so
uh bs grip that's what we're basically
going to be talking about uh then uh
puffer fish two uh pufferfish was uh
submitted to the password hashing
competition and then uh i forgot exactly
when it changed i think was in the
tweaking round uh or something like that
but we'll also be comparing uh that
uh yes script
and argon 2 ds
those are memory hard algorithms that
have
this extra thing where they do some
cachard operations um
you probably haven't heard of argon 2ds
if you've heard of argon 2 because this
was actually uh created after the
password fashion competition ended
uh i i even keep forgetting about it
uh so we're basically just gonna be
talking about bs grip and puffer fish
too
so
uh how to do a password hashing uh
how to do key stretching well
so what you want to do is hash all the
inputs then do some sort of work
with that
uh so you generate the seed then you do
some amount of work
you generate this value called work and
then you just put it in a kdf and
stretch it for whatever length uh you
know if it's a password hash you
probably want to have that be a fixed
width of like 32 bytes
and if it's kdf you know go
whatever
[Music]
so
um
uh bcrypt they didn't do that first step
uh where you hatch all the inputs so
what ended up happening is
um
there's bugs with null characters where
uh
you know it
so a lot of the implementations are in c
they expect c strings but if you give it
you know utf-16 then you have no
password part
um
then uh there were
bugs where um
the uh with uh unicode characters and
like utf-8 where the sign got extended
and
cleared out parts of the password um but
basically this uh right here is blowfish
encryption
uh so the block right there that's done
like 16 times s uh zero through three
those are s boxes
and so pufferfish made these changes to
uh
uh blowfish
uh also blowfish is 32-bit uh you know
all the variables are 32-bit and these
are 64-bit so that you can have a larger
larger masks so you can have
larger s boxes also the uh mask allowed
for scaling the s boxes to
um you know
nice binary numbers of sizes so like
64k
128k stuff like that um so in
uh april 2019 before bs script was
called bs corrupt i figure it was called
but um i was like oh
i don't really like how pufferfish was
not using some of those bits to do
lookups on so i was like i'll do
eight bit lookups and then just have
uh so this right here is uh 64k
of s boxes
uh 16. did i say 64. whatever uh 16k of
xboxes um and when you wanted to do 32
or uh some weird thing like 48 or you
know
something multiple of 16 you just do
eight more s boxes and then you just do
a for loop around this to do multiple
iterations
um so
what i didn't know was that
cpus were going to have weird sizes for
cash like uh you know 48k or 1.25
meg
uh so
um i tweeted out this uh
benchmark in uh sonya team uh and
so two different cpus one has only two
layers of cache one has three uh you can
probably guess
but um
so the
what i noticed was uh the pink line that
one little duh it it came uh that was at
quote six uh 256k uh which is the cash
size the l2 cache size for
uh one core
on that and i noticed a jump and i was
like oh
that's weird um
so i realized
that it was the p boxes because i think
i actually was using multiple p boxes uh
permutation
uh s box is a substitution box it's like
a
cryptographic term whatever uh anyway so
i removed those because we're not using
this for encryption and that's like
where the key bits were and stuff
so um
because the only part about this being
cash hard are these
s boxes so uh removing those um it then
uh you know
got rid of that little bump before uh
when you
are at that limit
um later uh
i was like you know what uh i should
switch to accumulators because the only
thing that
matters is that you're alternating xor
and add
um so you just do lookups and then xor
or add into the accumulators like this
uh
but there are some issues with them like
if it's zero and then you if your
accumulator is zero which is one into uh
two to the 64. so very rare so it
doesn't really matter
but if you add a value
and then
you xor the same value it'll be zero
um basically i was thinking of having
just like one s box that i you know
scaled
uh because you could actually do that
with an accumulator but you could it's
possible to read the same variable
twice
so
if you did that with you know a non-zero
value then the least significant bit
stays the same
which is also not really a big deal
so i was looking at different sizes for
masks you know how many look-ups i could
do and like what the limits were and
whatnot
and
so
uh
then uh i had like a aha moment
so i have two s boxes that are
overlapping
and you can shift them over to get those
weird cache sizes so now i can hit like
any size you really wanted with within a
eight byte boundary
granted the way that i did things uh
it makes it nice for like 128 byte
boundaries and then
i really like how easy it is to read
the settings and know what they mean so
i just made it uh
kilobyte boundaries so
the m parameter
if you see 256 that's 256k and whatnot
so it makes it uh nice and
easy to
understand
so
um
the largest size that i could do with
these overlapping uh
s boxes where
a special case where they're you know
totally separate for the largest size
would be these values
and
um you know
so obviously 4k that's kind of bad um
and 64-bit masks you know
that that's kind of excessive so
i i got rid of those
and
then i was looking and i'm like well a
megabyte that's kind of low so
and then um
depending on whether you wanted to push
out into
l3 cache some gp some cpus have
more than 32 megs now
so
i guess this one wins
[Music]
so
this is the main operation uh basically
uh all right so green and blue you can
basically consider those like uh l one
uh well l zero through l three and then
r zero through r
three
uh anyway so the reason why i do four of
these in parallel is uh password
crackers for decrypt what they did was
they interlayed two um
password uh you know
they interleaved two um
uh
decrypt hashes with two different
passwords and you got like a slight
speed bump because it was hiding latency
a little bit better so uh i wanted to do
that but now these operations are
just parallel so
i do a block of that then i rotate them
and then i rotate them again and again
so it's basically four blocks of this
and uh it mixes all the uh
uh
you know all the different ones that are
done in parallel and this is basically a
free well it is a free operation
uh so
and then
i just read sequentially and then i also
do uh you know a rotate again when you
write
and
um again you know rotating them at the
end it doesn't really matter too much
but
it's free
so
uh
so following a
uh an accumulator variable a uh you know
you get the add xor and then the s boxes
oh i never
noticed that or whatever oops uh
add x or add x or in the s boxes and
then xor and then add so uh this was uh
a version i had before
then i realized that those two values
could be the same
so i'd be accumulating with add twice
um
so
i then
changed it so that you have a block that
starts with adding and then
every other and then a block that starts
with xor
and then every other so when you look at
what's being accumulated it's always uh
add x or add x or add x or and then what
you're writing add xor
uh
so on
um then
uh
so those are two different blocks uh
then i rotate all the values this is
what
made me uh
so
remember when i said that uh i didn't
like how some of those bits weren't
being used for lookups well when you
rotate the variables uh those bits that
aren't being used will then later be
used in you know other calculation uh
other lookups and all i did was uh do a
through d after the first block and then
e through h after the next
so
uh initial fill and finish um you know
i'm pretty sure you're all bored with
code so you know you can go look it up
if you want
but basically uh i used uh blake 2b
for the hashing of inputs and the
kdf at the end to expand it and you
might be wondering why i use blake 2b
instead of like like three
um
well blake 2b is 64-bit and uh blake
3 is 32-bit so i wanted to basically
have a native write function
on like a native read so um
it doesn't have to do any
uh
bite endian swaps or anything like that
so
you it basically just deals with only
64-bit integers
and then the finish is really simple i
just run over the entire uh
data
by
adding an xoring like 16 in parallel and
then you know combine do some you know
stuff so uh where can you find
this code
well it's
is
let's hope this works
it is on github as soon as this finishes
yeah yeah there we go
so
this could be you
i bet no one knows that i was there when
bs crypt was released
all right so benchmarks
um so
uh pbkdf2 shot 256 uh sha 512 decrypt
and bs crypt so
uh these the settings for all three of
these were uh set to
what a gpu attacker could do uh
for uh bcrypt uh
cost nine
because that was the one that you
couldn't have as much leeway with the
settings so it's basically 53
kilohashes per second per gpu
and so
as a defender you can spend almost 800
milliseconds doing pbk df2 uh sha 256
or
you could spend uh four milliseconds
running the script
so
you know uh so this is on uh actually
this laptop i realized that i should
have i thought of the slide last night
and i was like oh i need to
get a benchmark so i can do this but
yeah
pufferfish2 isn't on this uh
multiple reasons i didn't have the code
and two um
the uh settings are also not as
forgivable like uh
jeremy wanted to have it such that uh
you know he had a t constant m cost
which were uh two to the whatever that
value is like decrypted so it'd be hard
to
get an exact comparison
but
uh so
okay uh so this is again this laptop um
so it only has uh three megs of l3 cache
and uh
if you look at the green line um bs
crypt p equal to so this is with two
threads so it's running on two cores um
with each with uh two megs of cash each
so it's actually now pushing into memory
which uh as you can see gets a lot
slower
basically uh
oh right so uh pufferfish too fast
basically
what puffered fish does after every
round of encrypting
you know encrypting all the uh s boxes
uh it runs it hashes all those
so it has to
run through them with uh
hmac sha 512 it's a hashmall which is a
slow operation and it's not exactly
helping its cache hardness
so
it then
gets a little bit faster
for uh the defender
so uh
different cpu um
this one uh has six megs of l3 cache and
you know uh for
bs grip uh
p4
uh the last two are now hitting memory
um
so
uh the nice thing about it is uh
with multiple cores uh you know
so these are all
uh
i should mention that each one of these
points
is uh
quote the same hardness against a gpu
attacker technically uh you might be
able to be faster on the uh slower side
uh the smaller side so like 16 or 32 64k
those might be
not enough cash hard to you know push
gpus into doing memory lockups
i forgot to mention that earlier so
um so
minimum settings for password hashing
you should aim for
being a gpu being at most
10 000 hashes per second per gpu
and that's not like just any gpu
the best gpu for password cracking at
the time
uh which currently is uh rtx 3080 uh 12
gigabyte
version there's two uh there's one with
10 which is slightly older whatever um
but so when you
put in settings for
vscript with
p1 p2 and p4
it takes roughly one millisecond to get
to
the minimum strength that you should
have
so
um
basically this means that we can push
well beyond and make gpu cracking really
really slow
so
if you're familiar with
decrypt
cost 15 is ridiculously high it takes a
very long time to
generate one of those hashes
but
basically the equivalent settings for
bscrypt
to hit
less than 85 hashes per second per gpu
uh i ran this benchmark uh as you can
see uh i guess it doesn't really help
too much going with a fourth uh thread
even though it's a quad core
but
um
you know uh you can get under 100
milliseconds on uh this cpu is like
seven years old so it's not even that
new
so
uh it's
definitely good because usually your
maximum
time to do a password hatching algorithm
is
100 milliseconds you don't really want
to go much higher than that but with
this you know
uh well technically if you're doing this
on a server you wouldn't want to use uh
parallelism because the uh parallelism
is actually going to uh
lower your throughput
so if you measure with all your cores
doing it and then
you know you're like okay it takes 100
milliseconds well that means your server
can only authenticate 10 users at a time
per second
anyway
uh questions that was
i
definitely skipped something i don't
know what happened
because i was running overtime
before when i was yeah well that was
that was ahead of schedule i don't know
what happened yeah questions for steve
or is everybody totally clear with this
any thoughts on performance against an
fpga or asic
accelerated factor yes
so the question was uh performance
versus uh fpga or asic attacker so with
fpgas um
there's this one uh i forget what it's
called but it basically uh
it's four fpgas on a board you can you
can only get them used uh they're like
uh 200 dollars used but um
uh so
bcrypt on it is really is really nice
and fast because of the onboard cache on
it
well uh
that cache is limiting how many uh
units of bcryp can be put on it can be
running at the same time on the fpga
well when you that's only 4k if you were
doing 256k
you would then be 64
the speed
1 64th the speed
so
um that would drop it well below
gpus
and then i assume a6 are similar
but also no one's using a6
question for me steve
um
let's be paranoid
do we have reasons to think to believe
that
specialized government agencies in
unnamed countries could have
specialized cpus that are not generally
known or available
that can be
in existence today that have either
incredibly large
cash sizes or also can deal with the
memory hardware the cash heart problem
yes
but you know you're not worried i'm not
worried about them
no one really should be you should be
worried about some kid with a gpu
like
and and and the team have hashcat i
guess yes yeah you know some kid that
gets a gpu for christmas and then you
know oh i can crack passwords that's
that's really
any more questions for steve
nope okay well then thank you steve
and we are finished a little bit early
but the last talk of the day why kids
couldn't care less about your password
advice is at
six o'clock i would really recommend
that one as well see you back then