last talk for the day had passers
contract
um
originally we were having janice from
cyprus and london to talk about
uh
jumping going down the rabbit hole on
doing password cracking
he couldn't make it
and i just knew that i had to
make a call to miyalansam from norway
same country where i live and say to her
that you know i i need you to be a
speaker on a
short notice a pass for scott mia's
never been to vegas before she hasn't
been to b-sides or to pass for scum
before but this is one of those talks
that i'm
in a way really looking forward to
giving the topic i'm 51 i have well i'm
going to be 51 in september i have a
teenage daughter
mia is
just freaking awesome talking to
teenagers
and the title is why kids couldn't care
less about your password advice has
nothing to do with my relationship my
daughter of course
but i'm really happy and proud to
introduce
mia
thank you
so you guys it's so cool to be here and
i just need to tell you i will make
jokes about your age
i do respect you i love you of course
you're coming to my talk this late i
appreciate it there will be jokes
don't cry
okay
good
so my name is mia hacker grill lansam
so no it's not hacker girl
it's grill as in a hot grill
because my gaming name was gamer grill
which is a term used for a hot girl
gamer and i was like 15.
so i changed it to hacky grill cause i
don't even have a hacker name yet so i
just did it i am a pen tester though i
am an ethical hacker at orange cyber
defense which is the french telecom
group orange i'm from norway
and i am 25 years old i'm born in 1997
and i'm probably one of the youngest
speakers maybe
and that's awesome i get to do stuff
like this
i come from trondheim but i live in oslo
the capital
i was originally on the national team in
taekwondo
and i did sports sciences and psychology
at norwegian school of sports sciences
and then i was like i [ __ ] hate my
life i want to do something new
and i'm a dropout i just dropped out
googled online school
oh i.t security
awesome i had a puppy
and then i'm suddenly a single mom to my
puppy
i couldn't bring her to school
that's why i searched for online school
and now i'm in las vegas
i mean
what um so i finished my id security
school two years ago and i got a job at
orange cyber funds i'm also an author of
the
book
safe online which is the best-selling
children's book in norway when i was 23
and but i'm mostly known for helping
victims of image abuse i also work with
child abuse
so next to my eight to four job at
orange cyber defense i do this
non-profit
at night all my time outside of work i
help and answer victims
because i mean that that kind of help
should be free
i've helped way too many people that i
should have i'm 25 and my knees hurt my
back hurts
you know i'm getting these wrinkles
i'm working way too much and i've been
involved in fraud cases
identity theft it's everything i've had
hundreds of talking talks in norway and
won several awards for my work and
thousands of victims
we're going to talk about kids
and social media authenticating of
course this is passwordcon we're gonna
talk about passwords
how to teach children cybersecurity
sexual harassment and image abuse so i'm
like mixing my old talk with this new
one and i've never done it before so
this is cool
social media
places we we can talk together share
click like to have our very own profile
that's a social media facebook snapchat
tick tock
and 97 of children aged 9 to 18 in
norway they have their own phone
and 87
of the 9 to 10 years old and 90 of them
has a social media profile now
these are norwegian numbers but i do see
when i'm like googling and stuff it's
pretty similar to other places and i'm
really open to hear if you have some
more stuff to add i would love to hear
it
um
send them to me
so i use mostly social media to
communicate with my mom
i'm a mommy's girl i'm gonna call her
every day
um and i like to do it on video as they
live far away and i work
a lot
i'm very busy i don't get to see them
and i love using social media for that i
feel like i'm taking a bigger part of
their lives than just calling
so on social media and all of that an
application software we have all of this
stuff
what are the most common ones
so
raise your hand if you have facebook
oh wow
raise your hand if you have
linkedin oh that's more people
and raise your hand if you use tick tock
ah that's not so many of you huh
yeah so oh you have ticked awesome
so
80 of those aged nine to 18 uses
snapchat 65 tick tock 65 instagram and
51 facebook
youtube almost everyone
but do they really use them all pero's
talking about do you have a profile or
do you actually are you actually active
on it
that's another question
i have a free website which is just my
name and dot no and where people can ask
for help i also have an instagram with
some followers where people can ask for
help for free
and
i see that kids mostly ask on instagram
and snapchat if they need my help and
then we have the dinosaurs
they're coming to this um
to this website sending me emails and my
facebook page
most kids these days they have a pretty
empty facebook profile if you seen it
and then you have all the dinosaurs who
love writing about what they had for
dinner and breakfast on facebook every
single day
yeah
there's a lot of cool stuff to social
media and internet as well that's why
we're here right we work with cyber or
you're interested in cyber because it's
so cool but there are some bad sites and
i'm not gonna talk about all of them
because it's a lot
but
three out of four 19 years old reports
that they have blocked someone on social
media
seven out of ten said they have added a
stranger on social media
reports that they have been bullied
online in 2020
and some say they have received threats
online
and when i speak to parents i do educate
parents in schools all over norway
they say that they're afraid of their
kids being bullied that they will have
their nudes leaked
um that there's dangerous people who
likes children pedophiles
and abuse
but no one is mentioning hackers loss of
passwords or other personal uh
information
so how can we protect them then
do you guys recognize this guy on the
screen
oh he's sitting right there
so authenticating
that's a hard word to say
i just used to say like login or
whatever
and on most social media apps we need to
authenticate you guys have a username
you have an email you have a password
children does that too
and as pair says here children also has
to authenticate on social media gaming
platforms
shocking
that says the dinosaur pair too same
so even dinosaurs knows that children
also has to authenticate
they face the same cyber threats every
day just as we do
even at school they need to authenticate
to use stuff and gaming
and we do say
never share your password with anyone
not even your best friend
okay
but 24
of these children have shared their
password with someone
and here you have these um dinosaurs
telling the children don't don't ever
share this
but they do see where you write down
your password under the socks in your
closet because you walk there every time
because you always forget your passwords
that's how i hacked my dad
[Laughter]
sorry dad if you're watching
and
says that they know their parents
password on app store or google play
so never share your password with anyone
but here is my password
there is parental controls so you don't
need to give them the passwords
it's just a google search away really
and it's kind of lame if your kid spends
thousands of dollars on minecraft
try to get that back on the insurance
i was told not to drink tequila by my
mom it was a bad idea she said did i do
it
yes i did
did it end well
no
it didn't
did you you see that's what happens and
did i do it again
yeah
my mom told me not to steal cookies i
stole them
and i counted the cookies
we will always do what our parents tells
us not to do
but that doesn't mean we should not not
to that doesn't mean that we don't say
don't do this and that because we need
to tell them like the rules and how they
need to behave
but why do they share their password
even though you say
nah
so norwegian numbers from 2020
31 of those who shared a password that's
because they needed help with something
in case they would forget
seven percent to prove that i am a good
friend
and 59 percent
who shared a password shared it to help
out with snapchat streaks
yeah
so snapchat streaks is a bigger deal
than you might guess
how it works
after three days of snapping you get
these very cool flames we like flames
you know and it will start to count the
days that you guys have been snapping
each other
so after three days you get a flame
super cool and you want that to go high
high high but if you don't snap them for
about 24 hours
then the hourglass comes
it's saying that if you don't snap them
really soon you're gonna lose your
streak and you have to start all over
again
no
that's like losing your world of
warcraft account after 10 years and you
have to start leveling up again yes i
did that that was horrible
i broke up with my boyfriend but we kept
a streak for a few more weeks but once
he broke the streak i knew it was
officially over
that day was so sad
it can really hurt when a streak ends
some of my friends get offended if i
break a streak and others don't care as
much it all depends on the person
my parents took my phone away one time
and i gave my friend my login to my
snapchat so she could keep up my streaks
i was panicked about losing them all
because i couldn't get to my phone for
two days while i was grounded
numbers from my cafe
so this is actually my longest trick all
my other streaks are like 10 days
this is magnus and hi magnus if you're
watching
378 days
that's a long time i think
me and magnus we don't really hang out
that much
we actually don't really snap each other
either we used to for a while and we
won't work in it we work a lot we're not
that much on snapchat really so now for
like 100 days the only things i get from
him is streak streak streak
once a day to not break the streak
and this comes from a person who thinks
the streaks is stupid but i do i can't
feel what these children are telling
because if you have a streak over 300
days
you know you want to continue if you win
at gambling
you you take 1 000 you get 10 000 back
of course you want to gamble more
and also i remember when i had a
boyfriend and the streak was gone that
reminded me
this is the first time in one year that
we have not spoken for a day
and that is pretty sad actually
so what can we do about this
we need to be a god influence or a good
role models ourselves
so dear dino make sure you know what the
kids do but also yourself like saying
not share your password don't don't
bully people but then you're in the
facebook comments calling all the girls
fat or are saying that's stupid i had
salmon for lunch today because you don't
care about the news
children they do
learn this stuff from somewhere
school needs to implement better first
passwords
so some school still uses the last name
and the yearborn of their students i
remember mine quite well lam me 97 i'm
born in 97 last name is lansam
do you think i guessed the password to
the other students hell yeah i did
did i do something bad yes i did and i'm
sorry if you're watching
they also
use um easily guest passwords
and i want them to use some sort of
password managers or to step security
there's a million functions to these
password managers
and that's a million functions also that
is never even used
does the password manager people
check what their users are actually
using or not why do we need all these
functions what do i click what is a
vault what is this i don't know even i
i'm even confused
can we just make it really really really
easy so hey there password manager
people make easy ones for kids
and not so expensive ones to the school
because not our schools actually have
the money to use stuff like this and
that's why they have 80 people creating
la min 97
why do they share password with someone
else to get help
it's very embarrassing to ask your
parents for help
even i am like now if i need to ask my
mom how to like wash my clothing or
something i like um mom what do i do
with this shirt again
they think that the parents know nothing
about security
and computers
even if you work in i.t
doesn't mean that they will ask you
because they're maybe
even afraid that you will make them feel
stupid
or that you talk too much
or you're talking to dinosaur or too
nerdy for them to even understand
if they won't come to you for help
make sure they know where to get help
look at the other dinosaurs around them
you have the t-rex you have all these
other dinosaurs around them
talk to them and make sure they know you
can contact this t-rex instead of me if
you want to
it's important that they know where to
ask for help if this happens where do
they go
you are not their only
dinosaur in their lives
and also
why does kids not know about two-step
authentication
so maybe someone here noticed how i
wrote two-step altercation
but more up here i did two-step security
whoops
or maybe not
why is these words not standardized
on behalf of all young people
and all dinosaurs
please standardize it
it's stupid we have like 10 different
names for the same thing
and everyone is fighting now we need to
use this
it's nothing to fight about
the children especially the children
they don't understand this word what kid
uses the word authenticate
what do they say when they log into
their favorite game
i'm authenticating myself into fortnite
no they're saying i'm logging in now you
guys
we're gonna win this
they're logging in
logging on
it's stupid for everyone to have
different ways to do it and
like apps or sms or maybe email how to
set it up it's stupid standardize it
don't fight about it just agree
so i will say two-step security because
it's easy to recognize
two steps okay there's two steps
not two-factor two-step security maybe
two-step login security easy for
everyone to understand
so
also children they're pretty lazy now
they're really smart they can even hack
their parents
but they're just used to getting all the
answers they're not googling anymore
they don't know how to use google they
don't know how to find this information
themselves because they just watch
youtube and tick tock all day
we need to make sure that we just don't
give them the answers
some people some kids that are like 14
and they have all these social media ask
me what is two-step security
google it
don't just ask me find the information
yourself as well
understand what is important to these
children and why because when i speak
about snapchat streak me and you here
you're laughing
but for children it's actually more
important to have a snapchat streak with
their friends and loved ones than
being
safe they know it's bad to give away the
passwords they know it's bad they know
they're told not to but friendship and
love
beats that common sense
losing a snapchat streak may cause drama
fights lots of friends lots of status
and it's a way to prove who is the best
of friends and that's really important
to these children
i think that snapchat
should make two-step security a must
if you are going to have the opportunity
to have streaks
because they know that 59 of these
children giving out their passwords it's
for snapchat streak and snapchat streak
only
then they should make it a must
of course they can let them even with
the two-step security as well but not if
the parents took away their phone and
they're grounded then they can't because
they are just giving out the password if
they're gonna give them the two-step
security as well
it's not gonna work
and also they need to stop and think one
more time
children especially one young ones they
can't really stop and think too and two
three times
it doesn't work that way
and also i don't like children using
money but me you have kids here they use
all the money and on the minecraft and
fortnite all the skins and all of that
so maybe snapchat could have like a
packet that you can buy
if you're going away you're losing your
phone whatever
pay a dollar and you won't lose your
streak for five days
it's easy money for them it's not too
expensive
and it shouldn't take much time to get
that
also maybe parents can try to understand
how important the streaks are
you're taking away their phone which is
a punishment i do not support at all
because it just means they're scared to
do
a stupid [ __ ] because they're gonna lose
their games and friends
that's horrible
they should know that if they did
something bad
then you should have a talk with them
don't just take their phone
tell them and show them
why was this comment you said on
someone's picture wrong
you don't have to take away anything and
if you do
snapchat streak
let them log in once a day and fix the
streak i'd rather do that which i think
is stupid
and not necessary at all but it's not
stupid for them
gaming
i believe that a lot of ik people
they're into i.t because of gaming
me myself
i was on a gaming team i also my first
time on television was in 2014
it was this mia with this light very
very light voice
and i was speaking about gaming and
being a full-time athlete trying to
reach the olympics
and 86 percent of those aged 9-18 they
do play games online
and i loved games if it wasn't for
gaming i wouldn't be in las vegas today
good reaction skills skills they can use
in other activities i was a full-time
athlete doing good in school and
balancing all this stuff talking and tv
shows about gamers about this issue
they also feel that they're learning
english better
and most games they do need a password
kids they contact me or their parents
because they're getting hacked on their
favorite game
and when you spend like thousands
dollars
that's not fun at all
it's a lot of accounts that they maybe
spend years on leveling up or spend a
lot of money on
and they're really really sad
someone in the game tricked them and
said if you give me your password i i
can show you this cool skin
so where did i learn about security it's
gaming i built my first computer when i
was 15
just because i needed to play better i
needed better fps i didn't want it to
lag
i wanted a nice gaming computer i didn't
care about forensics hacking or whatever
i just wanted to play my games
the password they use
so the problem is they have now of
course because people like ped and says
that you need different passwords for
applications so if you get hacked on one
of them you won't get hacked on the
other ones
that's great and i agree
the problem is children need to make
multiple passwords
they also need to keep
to keep track of passwords safely
and they also have to think about the
strength of their passwords
we're talking about children who still
likes barbie and plays fortnite and they
need to think about grown-up stuff
the first very passwords are received by
parents or at school
and i remember this
very well because the passwords are
mostly related to their lives
sports gaming animals names numbers
colors
if you go to like um password leaks
and you search for my old email you're
gonna see football 1997
mia
my birthday and when i needed a longer
password because that's that was the
thing you know you need a long ass
password
mia
0904 0904
and then when you need special things i
just did the same and then
some kind of march
i stopped using those password when i
was 16.
it's just
luck that i was never hacked
16 that's like that's nine years ago
dangerous i never thought about that
before i was into gaming because i
didn't want to lose my account
younger kids they do rely on family
support for password maintenance
that's from nist
and
my parents never helped me with that
they didn't know things about passwords
i knew their password sorry mom
um i could figure it out all the time
bad habits they're learning best
practices at school
and by parents or other relatives but
they have bad habits
they reuse the passwords and they share
step as well with friends does it seem
familiar to what grownups is doing too
so when the grown-ups are giving the app
store passwords to the children
do you think maybe they're reusing it to
their facebook and stuff as well
i think so
oh here we also have another word you
guys two factor authentication
another word for the same thing
so this is epic games and they
you know fortnite is it's the biggest
games for children we have a 15 year old
norwegian player who's a world champion
super cool
i have friends who's professional
players
but even gaming platforms and and um
products all of these gaming people
they're making the children use two-step
authentication
they're even better than the biggest
companies are helping the children with
their security
snapchat and other platforms where you
know there's children there and they're
here to stay they should also offer the
same stuff they should offer them
something on this fortnight or the other
games you will get this cool skin
and what does kids use money for skins
weapons on the cs they use it to get
these things in the games
we need to give them a cookie when they
do something good
my dog i learned i taught her how to sit
by giving her treats
we're run by rewards as humans as well
we are scared of
of uh police officers but when you don't
see them you're gonna speed anyway with
your car
but when you see the photo box and oh no
there's a camera i'm gonna follow the
law now we're so scared of punishment
and we care about rewards that's how the
world works children they're like that
to give them a cookie and they will wash
wash your whole house
at least i would
other platforms love for the same they
should talk it's not my job they should
talk and like how can we offer these
kids something that will make them use
this security stuff
we need to realize that children are
here to stay and the bad habits
that they have as children
that will follow them for the rest of
their lives
and for you dinosaurs here
some of you may be maybe you own a
company you're a leader
you're going to be in your company for a
long time
it's not
just your problem because it might be
one of your children getting hacked it's
your problem because you're the one
who's gonna hire these children in 10 to
15 years
it's gonna backfire
that one kid that maybe gets her
password leaked on snapchat might be the
new ceo of snapchat
i also recommend you to go to cecilia's
talk tomorrow i think it's 10 30
yeah and she's gonna speak more about
this on short notice as well as a
norwegian woman where short notice
really cool and she's gonna speak more
about that
and what happens when these passwords
are everywhere
so here comes like my speciality naked
photos the queen of the nudes
yeah naked online sexual harassment and
image abuse because there's a lot of
things that can happen if you share your
password with your friend and now they
can see your snapchat memories maybe
they will save a little boop picture
that you have and not tell you anything
maybe a friend gets mad at you and
they're now hacking you
and saying i will do this and this if
you don't pay me that
okay
so we have the smaller stuff that can
happen which is sad but then you have
this really serious stuff that i work
with every day
sexual harassment
three out of 10 of the 13 to 18 years
old reports that they have received
sexual comments in 2020
26 reports they have been bullied online
sent a nude photo of themselves in 2020
and 13 of those got paid for doing it
and if you think how many children there
it is in this world that's a lot of
children
and i speak to them every day
and a lot of people ask
but just stop taking these nude photos
and the problem will be gone
okay should i just uh stop walking
outside to not be raped then
don't have a car because someone might
ski steal it
it's not your business and it's not your
problem what other people do
it can be love it can be exciting it
might feel good most people have you
watched porn
and you probably did touch your deck or
regina while watching it
it's the same thing just digitally it
creates a bun maybe they have a long
distance relationship
it's none of your business or your
problem
and some are poor
some struggle with drug abuse
and they need money
i say my body my choice
not in america at the moment i guess
but
that's what i say and i never shame
anyone so the next time maybe you think
it's stupid to take nude photos then
just shut the [ __ ] up
if you don't have anything nice to say
and you're gonna victim shame
just leave the room
on several forums and pages online
they are created
websites that are made to only harass
people non-consensual photos shared
online
it's like trading pokemon cards you
remember at school huh shiny pokemons
you have those words more than others
you have the pretty ones you have the
the ones that not everyone has
super cool and you want to trade them
and that's how this let's go to the
industry works as well
anyone got any pics of her
do you have this do you have that let's
trade
category a i call this me as abc it's
really simple i like simple things
because if not i'm not gonna remember
them
abc category a is what i say when i mean
where these abusers
gather
where they try to arrange trades um ask
for pictures and so on and of course
they know that now the police is
actually doing something
and you have this super super um
scary feminists like me alonso
who will come and catch you
and make you go to prison
so now they have to like authenticate or
they have to prove who they are and who
they are not
so you gather here you say yeah i want
to trade okay but you need to prove to
me that you are not the police
so they go to category b which is the
place where you
kind of authenticate where you identify
yourself and you prove yourself
that works this way you have it's
usually a file dropping service like
dropbox um
google disk
all of this stuff vola file mega share
and there's a set of rules don't be a
dick to anyone
nice to have rules and you have to
send a photo of someone you have to
publish it in that file
a folder
and then add the name of the picture as
your name that you will be added on
later
so you're gonna publish a picture and
then within 24 hours you get access to
category c which is the holy grail for
abusers douchebags and
idiots
you might see here discord it's one of
the most used applications for this
third step
you see a channel you create groups you
create text channels you can name it
whatever you want you can make it open
you can have it
um
just for invites
so here's nude photos europe
and you see this chat
these channels poland england norway you
can just click into the country you want
to see nude photos from
you also have categories for rape you
also can categorize after age and when i
ask people what do you think is the
lowest age in these groups on discord
and other platforms
it's videos and pictures of children
being brutally raped and killed
that's what i have to watch
people ask me why i want to do this
stuff and it's not that i want to do it
but it's because i speak to children
who doesn't want to be here anymore
because of this [ __ ]
and it's not just people hacking you or
whatever it's them trusting the wrong
person it's
all the platforms it's it's the big ones
up here who needs to help them to
understand
that they need to take their security
a step up
two-factor authentication all of this
stuff
i see a lot of [ __ ] in my what i do
um
[Music]
it makes me sick it makes me cry a night
it makes me hate it i am the most hated
woman in the itc community in norway
probably these pedophiles they don't
like me because i take away their toys
the young people doing this [ __ ] too
it's 12 13 year olds
who also does this stuff
and they hate me and i love it i
absolutely love it
they should and they should be scared
because i talk to children at the age of
16 who is forced to have sex with their
abuser to not get their pictures leaked
i talk to children at the age of 17
where the sex video stayed somewhere and
someone hacked their account found it on
snapchat memories cause it's cloud-based
and now they're saying give me a
thousand dollars or i will post it on
your story to everyone you know
i help and speak to parents of children
at the age of 15 who is no longer a lie
because someone decided to blackmail
them and post their videos online
they're dead
and it's really sad
children they're on social media
it's the same cyber threats
we need to understand and talk to them
about what is important to them
companies who are supposed to keep us
all safe and create solutions good stuff
for us they need to create more simple
solutions especially for the young ones
and also the elderly people
we need to standardize and simplify
password managers and password or
security related words like two step
factors something something something
casion
snapchat and other companies need to
look at the biggest factors of children
giving away their password and remove
the threat what do we do in cyber we try
to
make the threats go away we try to look
what can be leaked here what can happen
here what are the biggest threats to my
company i don't give a [ __ ] about your
company
if these kids don't get help
they are very much more important than
your software if you ask me
is a stupid streak to make people use
your application more important than
children's safety health and their lives
what is snapchat streak good for nothing
it makes us go there and send send snaps
and it makes them get more money as they
didn't have enough from before
it creates a significant risk for
children that they give up their
passwords
they think it's so important with this
streak
and
um as i usually say
if these companies and the people who
are leading them
thinks that the streak and other
not important stuff is more important
than there is they're facing please meet
me at the children's graves and say it
to my face
i'm standing there at their graves i
haven't even met them and i cry
does the companies do that no
but i'm telling you to do it
so i'm i've been talking about really
heavy stuff this is what i do every day
and some people cry when they walk out
of my talks
because the internet is as big as space
and that means we don't quite know how
big it is
of course you can count everything and
how many users on this on this platform
it's not that i'm talking about we can
never know anything everything we can
never know what's there and that means
we all need to take responsibility it
means we all need to care and we have to
face what is actually going on
i don't care if your platform got hacked
10 000 kids on your app got hacked
that's what i care about
so my title for this presentation you
guys
is why kids couldn't care less about
your password advice
they don't speak dinosaur
you see i have these cool dinosaur
earrings and i want to say thank you and
um i'm really glad that so many people
showed up i will take questions um you
can reach me on twitter instagram
londstemprotonmail.com linkedin just
connect with me
illustrations are actually made by my
good friend lynn
uh when she was 19
i believe in young women and snapchat
bitmoji i guess i'm gonna be sued by
snapchat now
they are very welcome
so thank you
jeff do you remember what we did on
stage in stockholm seoul years ago could
you help me
yeah okay yeah i i think we need to do
that
[Laughter]
thank you
this is nice
awesome
questions for mia
hi um first thank you for the
presentation and all the information you
provided in what you do
um i had a chance in the past to do work
in this capacity with a
three-letter agency here with the us
government
and i was fortunate enough to
uh be involved in a program i can't
disclose right now because it's a
classified um program they could
actually assist in what you're doing
and so my question to you are you aware
of that program because it did involve
nations in europe um to to do this and
what it entails if you don't know about
it
it allows the program to look at images
videos or whatever else of victims that
are exploiting in this capacity without
having to have the human
element view
the the content and have the machine and
ai ml components
analyze that and recognize it from like
photos that parents or other family
members provide to the law enforcement
so that's my first question or that
program there are several programs and
similar stuff around the world and i'm
not an organization i have a full-time
job and a dog
so i can't remember that right now but i
would love for to hear more sure and
then my other question is that there's a
component that i realized um that you
covered in the beginning of your
presentation where in my opinion focuses
more on
human behavior or child development
approach with like a psychiatrist or
psychologist to help parents parent
their kids because it is a big
responsibility for the parents and the
lack or ignorance of the parents not
being able to provide that guidance to
the kids for passwords or the big
spectrum of what you covered so my
question to you is have you approached
that
within your country or anywhere around
the world dealing with family
therapists psychologists psychiatrists
to
help or even school systems to help
educate the kids at that development age
so i actually was a part of changing the
laws in norway
a year ago
and i have also made programs for
parents i have also volunteered for red
cross
i also do about 100 talks a year just
for parents i also do
the crisis centers that women go to if
they're
if there's digital violence cases i also
educated the police at the police
academy
and i also have everything published
free for everyone
um so that's what i've been doing really
i've been doing this for five years i
was a full-time student
and i'm working on some really cool
stuff um for the rest of the years
so yeah
i wanted to talk about this kind of
stuff on this talk because there's a lot
of cyber people here but i do talk a lot
to the grown-ups and teachers at school
because these children they're being
taught this in school now in
kindergarten
but their parents are 30 40 50 years old
who taught them
and why does these people then have the
responsibility to teach their now
children we are generation [ __ ] up
because we grew up with this i was like
in the middle of this i had the nokia
and then when i was like 12 i got
snapchat
now the kids have tablets before they're
born you know they used to say that
norwegians are born with skis
now they're born with iphones in their
hands
so yeah i've been doing a lot of that
stuff and i would love for you to reach
out and tell me more and also if anyone
else
knows stuff that can help
please contact me thank you for your
questions
thank you so much for your talk and
thank you for your service to the your
community and our community um my
question is for me as a dinosaur who
learned a lot in this hour
one of the things that really drove the
point home as sad as it was was kind of
the anecdotes of the negative outcomes
how do you wrestle with communicating
with kids and trying to teach them the
dangers but not over frightening them
that's a really good question and i get
that question a lot so i've written a
children's book
i use their words i speak to children
who is six and seven years old and i i
say poop i say pee
and i say there is some grown-ups that
actually want to be your boyfriend or
your girlfriend
and and they think this stuff is so cool
and interesting
they come and take selfies with me so
for grown-ups if grown-ups can handle
what i'm talking about how how can
children live through them but with
children i am much more
positive things guys i'm a gamer
are you gamers do you play games me too
what kind of games do you play mia are
you on fortnite
i do this so i actually took on my
school of sports sciences we have our
own lectures considering children i was
also a coach for children in taekwondo
and so i i'm not like this at all to the
children they laugh and they
they speak they speak
to their teachers and they want to be
with me afterwards i think i'm doing a
good thing i haven't received any
complaints
uh yet
you never know about that so yeah
it's much more cute
and i don't speak about like
people kill themselves two six-year-olds
it's more like they they can get really
pain in their hearts
you know
so i can be cute too
thank you
so
as with others um
thank you for what yeah
thank you for what you do
um
[Music]
i was
given the
the sort of social psychological bonding
relationship trust
sharing things
even if snapchat disappeared tomorrow
their
people and kids are still going to be
sharing their passwords it's not
something
um
so
i don't know what
we can do you know what we here can do
about that other than
trying to develop techniques to safely
share passwords
you know for example you know you know
so you know
you know technologies where you can have
like sub passwords i'm sorry i don't
want to show throw out more terminology
that nobody understands
but
maybe
instead of saying
don't share passwords
when you know that that's not going to
work
find a way
to help them do what they want yeah
safely yeah
exactly
and also parents ask me because i say
that if you say to your child remember
to never take a nude photo of yourself
and never send it to anyone
then you are the last person that child
will come to when that happens because
they're so scared of you
so when i educate parents i say instead
of saying that directly and you slam the
door and you lock it
do what i do to children i tell them
what can happen
and to be careful and i talk about safe
sexting instead do not show your face if
you have tattoos like i'm [ __ ]
obviously
i will show up oh i have tattoos here
too yeah i'm [ __ ]
um i get up my eyeball
that's my nude photo
so i say let them think themselves and
that comes back to googling
don't just tell them stuff because
they're not going to listen
show them the consequences we actually
made two tv shows in norway
where i look through the everything the
transcript everything
one for the younger one someone for the
older ones who showed stories
and who helped the victims and didn't
shame anyone
and people were so shocked they won
awards for these tv shows and i tell
parents to show their kids this and it
creates a perfect opportunity to talk
about it so after seeing this what
do you know if anyone in your class had
their photos leaked
that's a better way than just have you
shared your naked photo
so i actually tell that to parents as
well and i totally agree with what
you're saying as well but also i think
that if i can make just one kid think
twice by adding a must for two to step
blogging then it's worth it because that
kid might be dead now and i have spoken
to dead children
not oh that sounded weird
but i've been talking to them and the
next time i get a message is the parent
saying thank you for trying to help our
child so if i can just save one child by
adding two factor
and that company spends a bit more of
their very nice party
money
on saving that one child
that's the only thing i care about i
don't care if if it goes from 59 because
of snapchat streak to 58 because if you
see how many children in the world that
thousands of children
that maybe now
still have a life
absolutely amazing talk i'm so happy
that i invited mia to come to vegas
thank you so much
[Applause]
and i i just gotta say i went shopping
with mia and with cecilia here as well
uh uh
two days ago
and i saw some stuff from from uh
stranger things show and i
called my daughter back home and like
i'm hi dad is in vegas
you want me to buy you a really cool
stranger things t-shirt and it's like
no
can you get me some cool hip-hop
clothing
and i was like [ __ ] mia
and i was like she was there and uh
i
used a couple of dollars
and my kid will be happy thank you again
mia and now that was the last talk for
today we got to get out of the room now
but mia will also be here tomorrow of
course and we'll stay here until sunday
so uh you will also see her around at
defcon so come up and say hi or talk to
her outside as well and i do speak
dinosaurs i practiced yeah