welcome back from lunch so this will be
a quite technical presentation I hope
you don't feel a fall asleep with all
the food so not today I would like to
talk about code reuse attacks for the
web and this is a joint project with two
of my colleagues with Christophe
khottabych and Eduardo Vela and myself
and in the last few months we developed
a technique that is very similar to
return to live C attacks in the binary
world and for the web and the idea of
this new attack technique is to bypass
cross-site scripting mitigation
techniques and this is today's agenda so
in the beginning I would like to give a
very short introduction to XSS and
exercise mitigations I assume that most
people know what exercise is and have
seen XSS in the past but I still will
give a short introductions then we will
talk about the concept of a script
gadget that's a way how we can bypass at
the exercise mitigations and we found
these gadgets and we were wondering how
how prevalent are they in the in real
world applications so we conducted two
different studies we conducted a
qualitative manual study on popular
JavaScript libraries and frameworks to
find these gadgets and we conducted an
automated study at scale of the Alexa
top 5,000 websites so see how many
gadgets we can find in real world
applications and what we saw there is
that these gadgets that allow bypassing
of these mitigations are prevalent in
almost all frameworks and all
applications that we see and basically
it it shows us that XSS mitigations are
maybe the wrong way of moving forward
and protecting it kinds process
scripting and that's why we are
proposing a new way of defending against
cross-site scripting and we do so we
focus on Dom XSS
for this part because solving all of
cross-site scripting is pretty difficult
and I will present talk about this in
the end of the presentation and then we
will also have a summary and but let's
start at the beginning at what actually
what actually cross-site scripting so
here I have a very simple example I
think all of you should have seen one of
those examples is a very simple
cross-site scripting
it's it's a reflected one it just brings
out the creating message and in the
usual case a user would type in his name
in
the the get parameter and then the
greeting message would be rendered by
the browser um however what the problem
here is that this a user name is printed
in this greeting message which out any
encoding so an attacker could just name
himself
script alert one and then this PHP
script would run it would insert the
script alert one here this would be sent
to the browser and the browser would see
a script tag and say hey there's a
script tag so I probably should just
execute it the server is telling me to
do that and the problem with this attack
is that here the alert is just a
placeholder for what you can do and
basically you can do with the cross-site
scripting attack you can do anything a
user can do so what you do is you craft
the payload in JavaScript then you send
a link to your victim the lik victim
click sonic and then this payload would
execute in the authentication context of
this person that clicked on the link and
then you can do anything that this user
can do if this is an administrator of
the application you can probably
administer the app maybe delete the
database or read the database send some
data away if this is a user that is
maybe a message board poster you can
post messages in his name you can maybe
read his private messages and also on
its course and it's pretty bad and in
theory cross-site scripting is a solved
problem so I think if you talk to
academia they would say yeah we know
exactly how to do this you put some
contextual encoding here the right
encoding function and then the problem
is solved and however theory is not the
practice in practice that's different
and here we see graph from Google's bug
bounty program and this is basically the
payouts that we pay for four bucks and
what we see here is that we pay about
60% of all the payouts that we give give
out to researchers our spend on
cross-site scripting and what we see is
that cross-site scripting is everywhere
um and we we have guidelines we have
trainings to mention the point that I
was trying to make before but that
doesn't help so developers still do
mistakes they still introduce bugs and
that's why we have 60% of the box to B
crossa scripts
and in in in the recent years a lot of
XSS mitigations were introduced so we
have ideas how to prevent the bugs but
we often see hey bugs are present and we
cannot really prevent their existence so
let's not try to focus on the bugs but
focus on the attacks and that's what an
XSS mitigation actually does so the idea
of an XSS mitigation is to block the
attack instead of preventing the
vulnerability and here I have a very
simple scheme this is a web application
so it has its rendered in a browser it
has a server and we see a cross-site
scripting injection we have a parameter
called injection and it's it's reflected
in the page and in this scheme I would
like to explain how XSS mitigations work
and what kind of different XSS
mitigations we have so the first XSS
mitigation that probably came up were
web application firewalls they are
pretty simple so they sit in the server
and they just look at all the requests
that come into the server and then they
throw a bunch of rules or regular
expressions or whatever onto this
request and then they are trying to find
malicious injections so they look at
this and they find maybe oh there's a
script tag in the request there should
never be a script tag in a request so I
better block this request so what web
application firewalls try to detect
malicious markup and then block requests
another XSS mitigation that works a
little bit differently our XSS filters
and one of the first XSS filters that
was introduced was the no script XSS
filter and it's kind of works in the
same way as a firewall but instead of
sitting on the server it sits in the
browser and it does exactly the same
things it protects you as a user it
looks at all the URLs that leave your
browser throws a bunch of rules or
regular expressions on it and sees oh
there's a malicious script or an onload
event handler or so so I better block
this and then it just removes the part
of the request that contains the
malicious markup and the idea is then
it's not getting injected and you're not
getting exploited then there was an
evolution of cross-site scripting
filters so the problem with no script is
that it has a huge number of false
positives because it just uses this
matching rules and the next generation
of cross-site scripting filters were the
IE cross-site scripting filter and the
chrome cross-site scripting filter they
work in slightly different ways but how
they work is basically that they first
look at the requests they tried to
detect whether there is malicious markup
in the request and
they wait for the response from the
server and before executing the response
they check whether this malicious markup
that they detected in the in the request
is also contained within within the
response and if that's the case they try
to either remove the payload or block
the full request they're different modes
and then recently we have a new XSS
mitigation scheme and it's the content
security policy and it works a bit
different but from a from a theoretical
point of view it's it's basically the
same so what these P does is that it
tries to detect legitimate markup that
is supposed to be in the page and non
legitimate markup that is injected and
then it will just execute the legitimate
one and block the malicious one and it
has different ways of determining
whether something is malicious or
legitimate and it has a white listing
mode where you can say everything from
example.org is is a trusted script and
everything from evil.com is not a
trusted script it has a non space mode
we can say this script carries a unique
nonce that the attacker cannot know
that's it that's why it's legitimate or
there is no nonce so it's it's malicious
and it also has a hash based mode but
that's not too important here but again
did the principle is detect malicious
stuff detect legitimate stuff block the
malicious stuff and leave the legitimate
stuff in place and then we have a nother
mitigation techniques which are HTML
sanitizers so sometimes you're in a
situation where you have a user provided
string and you want to render it as HTML
maybe you want to allow the user to to
make something bold or italics or
whatever so you want to allow injection
of HTML but you don't want to allow
malicious HTML injection and sanitizer
basically takes a string and it removes
all the malicious parts from it and then
you have basically assumptions you have
a safe string that you can render
without XSS and if we look at this all
of these mitigations work in the same
way it tried to detect legitimate one
stuff and try to block malicious and
what we looked at is whether this basic
assumptions of all these mechanisms is
true and this in a modern application
that is built with modern JavaScript
frameworks and the very short answer is
it's not true it's wrong and in the next
30 to 40 minutes I will explain why it's
wrong
so let's look at how a modern web
application works so here we see a very
basic HTML and JavaScript block that you
could find in any UI component library
so here we have a we have a button and a
piece of HTML and a couple of data
attributes here and basically this could
be for example a UI library where you
have button elements and then usually
you have accompanying JavaScript code
and this accompanying JavaScript code
tries to add behavior to the button it
might have hover effects and and it
defines what happens when you click and
so on and in this case this is very
stripped down case so here we just mark
that this development is a button and
then we have a data text attribute and
we say okay this is the text that should
be rendered on the button once once it's
in the page it's very simple but there
could be way more functionality here and
and then we just say in the script we
just select this button why this is
marker over here and then we say okay
let's render the data text attribute in
this button so that the user can display
but now there's a and what what happens
then it is this code gets executed and
then the button gets rendered the Texas
on the button and so on it's very simple
so now there's a question for the
audience but does anyone see a security
problem in this code with with XSS
mitigations in mind
yes exactly that's exactly the case now
if this example here so the problematic
the security issue is is here where we
take a data attribute which is by
definition data and we turn it into HTML
into code and so if we take these XSS
mitigations into account let's assume
this page has an XSS vulnerability and
we have xs/s mitigations in place to
defend against all the attacks so it
cannot be exploited but now we have this
exercise and that's a story yeah I
forgot this this this is this is what we
call X script gadget this is legitimate
functionality that is contained in the
page and that upgrades a data text to an
HTML and now let's assume we have the
XSS in the page so we have an XSS here
so the attacker could insert the script
but that doesn't work because the
excesses mitigation would block it but
now we can just insert a button give it
the same marker string and then a data
text and into the data text we just put
our payload and the payload is not just
data it's just a string any XSS
mitigation would would not block it and
interestingly we can also encode it
because the browser does some kind is
some some decoding steps when we read
that so in this case we can simply
inject this and then the script gadget
here in the page will will see both
buttons and it will upgrade our button
to execute script in the page and this
all of this is legitimate markup it's a
div tag it's a couple of data attributes
there are no scripts there's no unload
Handler and so on and this is basically
our script gadget works and to summarize
a script gadget is a legitimate piece of
JavaScript in a page it takes a
seemingly like benign piece of HTML and
upgrades it to code execution and that's
how we can bypass XSS mitigation and
here I quickly want to summarize the
attacker model so here we see how an XSS
works so we have the document object
model we have an XSS flaw in the page
and usually attackers inject HTML oops
sorry usually inject HTML into the Dom
but however we have this XSS mitigation
that prevents us from doing any
malicious malicious stuff but now there
is the script gadget in the page the
text in that takes non malicious stuff
and upgrades it to execute our payload
and that's how we can circumvent all the
XSS mitigations
and we found this phenomenon in in one
or two examples and then we were
thinking how how how widespread is this
how often do script gadgets exist in
pages is like an isolated issue or is
this like a bigger issue so what we did
is we did the quantity of manual
analysis of popular jobs and we wanted
to answer two questions first we wanted
to answer how common these gadgets are
in in modern JavaScript libraries and
how effective are they in bypassing XSS
medications so we compile the list of 16
popular libraries so we just went to
github we search for all the libraries
that at the most stars and Forbes and so
on and compile this list and it contains
things like angular aralia bootstrap
react closure library polymer so all the
popular frameworks and then we tried for
each framework we try to find a
mitigation bypass for one of for XSS
mitigations so we looked at XSS filters
at HTML sanitizers at web application
firewalls and at the content security
policy and in the next maybe 20 minutes
I would like to go through all of these
examples and give one or two examples
for each of the mitigation techniques
and try how you can bypass them so let's
start with the most simplest one with
buffs and XSS filters and wasps and XSS
filters as I explained that usually use
rules or regular expressions to detect
payloads and I already showed how they
can be bypassed right so so we have
legitimate code that gets upgraded so
basically when we look for gadgets that
bypasses we basically look for for
legitimate pieces of code that get
upgraded by a library for example where
a legitimate attribute is passed to eval
or where a text node is passed to in
HTML and so on and here I have a couple
of examples I have this longer one
example that I would like to present in
details in I have a couple of short ones
just to see how widespread this is so
here we see a construct from the
knockout library and they have this
concept of data bindings so you have
this data bind attribute which is has no
semantics in HTML it's just a data
attribute and then you can type in value
and then you can have any any kind of
off data here and what happens at
runtime is that knock out basically
when it bootstraps it says give me all
give me all the elements that have this
data bind attribute and then it gets
this is attribute and then what it does
it creates a data binding so it creates
a a function and this string this this
data value goes into this function and
this function is called by the framework
to update the value so whenever you
change the value it will call the
function the function will return the
right value then the framework will put
it into the into the right place into
this div element and then after the
after this function is created it will
just be called at runtime so effectively
what this creates is a chain from user
in from from from a attacker control but
value that is benign to a function call
that is executed so basically we have
code execution here and this means this
data bind attribute behaves like eval so
you have this data bind a tribute you
have the script gadget in the page in a
knockout library and this is effectively
just evolving this value so in order to
bypass an XSS mitigation or a web
application firewall in this case you
can just say data bind value alert 1 and
this will open an alert box in the
application and no no XSS mitigation
would be suspicious of this data binder
trick dude yeah couple of em other
examples this is from the bootstrap
library and a boot syrup library has a
tool type functionality so you can just
say render tooltip for me and the
library will take care of all the
rendering and the effects of the tooltip
and so on so how you do that is you just
put a marker attribute again on your
element that you want to have the
tooltip with and then you have a title
attribute and this is what actually
rendered in a tooltip and interestingly
by default this is just render this text
because you don't need a HTML in a
tooltip usually however bootstrap has
this data API where you can just change
internal configuration settings of
bootstrap by specifying a data attribute
so what you can just say is data
- HTML equals true this will change the
internal configuration value and then
this will be rendered as HTML so and
then we effectively bypass XSS
mitigation so again here's another
example from the dojo library so here I
don't even really know what this does
this is just the declaration I think you
can declare some variables or
configuration values and interestingly
all
these properties or attributes are just
shown into eval with some other code
around it so you can you can simply
break out here of the of the current
contract you can just type a load one
and you get an alert it's very simple
and here's a summary of the findings for
XSS filters and web application
firewalls that we had so we looked at
three filters at the chrome edge and no
script and for web application firewalls
we looked at mod security and we found
that in most cases we were able to
bypass 9 out of 16 cases for Chrome it
was a bit higher because chrome tries to
prevent false positives so all the other
filters are trying to over catch and
catch as much as possible but don't
necessarily want to sort so they catch
more than then what could actually be an
intern hey let's move on to the next
exercise mitigation and HTML sanitizers
so as I said HTML sanitizers work by
like just taking a string and removing
all the HTML the malicious HTML parts
and again we can use script gadgets to
circumvent HTML sanitizers because most
of the sanitizers would leave script tag
gadgets intact and here are a couple of
examples and the first one was not part
of the 16 popular library but it's so
weird that I I wanted to show it anyways
and this is of a library called ajaxify
and ajaxify
has a class and this class is called
document script and if you put it
anywhere it magically turns the element
into a script tag so it would it will
just take this value it will create a
new script tag will write this to the
script tag and append a script tag with
the Dom so and it's perfect because
class elements are allowed by all the
sanitizers that you can find out there
another example we've already seen is
the bootstrap example again so here it's
exactly the same we've seen that already
I explained it it was just data some
sanitizers allow data attributes to pass
through the sanitization and usually
title attributes are always left in
place but all sanitizers so in this case
this bypasses a couple of sanitizers
and we did a study into sanitizers we
looked at daum purify and closure and we
were able to bypass dom purify 9 of 16
cases and closure in 6 of 16 cases and
we have a github repository with all the
exploits and proof of concepts ok let's
now go to the most interesting one so 2
content security policy I don't really
have a lot of time to explain what cross
what how the content security policy
works I assume that there is some basic
knowledge but basically there are two
different modes I would like to look at
and there is a white listing mode and an
on space mode and in the wide Lysa mode
you you whitelist origins that are
trusted and it in non space mode you put
a nonce on every trusted script and then
on this generated a page page load time
and it's not known by the attacker so
the attacker cannot inject the right
nonce and that's why the attacker cannot
inject and additionally CSP has some
keywords to make your life easier so CSP
is quite hard to to deploy if you have
an existing application and that's why
some keywords exist that relax
CSP there's unsafe inline but that's
insecure by default so I will not talk
about it the second one is unsafe eval
and then there's strict dynamic and
first I would like to talk about unsafe
unsafe eval and so unsafe eval is
interesting because for a long time
people thought it's not very dangerous
to put this into your policy because
usually you only have one or two places
where you need to to use eval in your
application so you could go you could
just order those two places and then you
could put unsafe evil and securely use
that the problem again is with script
gadgets you might have a chain from the
Dom into evil and here's one example so
this is from the underscore templating
library and underscore has some
syntactic sugar for developers so that
you can write code faster so instead of
writing script alert one
you would just write smaller than
percent and then you can put your script
and then the underscore library when
when it will automatically evaluate all
templates that you have in a Dom with
this type so you can just have a div tag
and then we'll we'll execute code for
you so in this way you can bypass unsafe
evil and there are a lot more library
set dude
kind of things the second keyword I
would like to talk about is the strict
dynamic keyword so the strict dynamic
keyword is a bit tricky and it's mostly
used in a non space mode so in a non
space mode you need to have these nuns
in every script the problem is that a
lot of scripts that you include are not
aware of this fact for example you might
include the facebook like button as a
script or some other visit and this
widget might not be aware that you are
using a CSP non-space mode so they would
not take the naans and add it to the
newly created scripts that is libraries
create and what strict dynamic does is
that it allows trusted scripts to create
new scripts without a nonce so the ideas
if you notice the Facebook script the
Facebook script can load other Facebook
scripts without explicitly propagating
trust so if a legitimate script can
basically add new scripts and this is
interesting because we can again see
this in script gadgets so here we have
an example at bypass a strict dynamic
and this is from jQuery Mobile and
jQuery Mobile has a pop-up functionality
so you can just press a button there
will be this overlay pop-up and when you
do this for performance reason they pre
render this pop-up and when you click
the button it will just come to the
front and and not be hidden anymore so
the prerendered is and I guess a lot of
developer asked himself what is this div
element where is this element coming
from in my page so the jquery mobile
developers added a comment into this
development said hey this is the diff
this is the placeholder for the pop-up
that you define with is with the ID but
they just have this comment and print
the ID so in the ID you can just break
out of the HTML comment they use and add
a script behind it and interestingly
there is a they use jQuery to render
HTML so they don't use the native in
HTML but jQuery and when you rendered
HTML with jQuery jQuery will parse your
HTML and then it will instead of just
inner HTML being scripts which would not
work they see oh there is a script so
they create a new script element for you
and then they append this new script
element to the Dom so that it executes
so in this case we have jQuery which is
in your page which you probably trust so
it has a nonce creating a new script and
appending it to the page and that's
exactly by passing script dynamic
cause you have a trusted script that
does it for you okay now let's come to
the most interesting gadgets so about
the ones that bypass whitelist non-space
CSPs so let's assume we have a CSP
policy where we removed all those
insecure key words we removed unsafe
evil unsafe inline and strict dynamic
and we are super secure everything is
great these are the the hardest policies
to circumvent but actually we manage
this abided by using expression puzzles
and before going into details about the
exploits I would first like to explain
how expression pauses work so in our
study we found five libraries that ship
own expression puzzles so basically they
they build the language on top of the
framework a domain-specific language
that allows them to do like syntactic
sugar for developers and they do so
without using eval they are just
interpreting the code they basically
ship interpreters and I want to explain
this with the expression language in our
area so here we can see a very simple
example so if you can you can use an
expression you just start with these
dollar and then curly braces and then
you can just for example say things like
customer dot name and this this is an
expression it's not JavaScript and it
will be interpreted and then the earlier
framework will basically look up with
look is there a customer object in my
scope if yes it will return the customer
object and I will print the name here
for you and the nice thing is usually
you have to wait at abandons here so
once you upgrade update this name
anywhere in your application irelia will
make sure that it also gets updated in
your HTML and that makes it very easy to
to write HTML you don't need to write a
lot of JavaScript code to update a value
so here you can see what happens inside
or raelia so so whenever they depart
such an expression they basically see
that ok this is a nexus to to a variable
or tour to a to a function and then they
will just look this up so they have a
scope object in this case this is
already the customer object and then
they just get get this name put it here
and then they return the property
however with these expression languages
we can do more
so here is an example where we call a
function and this is again this is not
JavaScript this gets interpreted by the
framework and it will basically look up
the say hello function inside the
framework scope and then it will just
call it without using Evo and here we
see how that works so it will it will
look up the distain you'll get a
function reference that it already has
somewhere and then it will apply some
some arguments and we'll just call this
function and that allows us basically to
to execute arbitrary code and I would
like to explain how that works so here
we have a very simple payload in order
India really a framework that calls the
alert function so what we can do in or
radius we can just give an element a
name and we can use the S dot bind which
is again an attribute without semantics
in HTML and then we can just say okay
give me a reference to this element to
my local element and then we have a
reference and we can say okay give me
the owner document of this element which
is the document object and the document
object has a reference to the window
object and in JavaScript already XSS
world when you have whenever you have a
reference to the window object you are
basically you basically one it's like in
the binary world you you want to control
a point a certain pointer in JavaScript
you want to get a reference to window
and then if we have a reference to
window we can just what we can just call
the alert here and that bypasses the
mitigation because because all of the
JavaScript execution is happening in the
already a framework that's that's in the
page that's legitimate code and
basically we can do weird things with it
so for example here we have a cookie
stealer that is completely JavaScript
free so usually when you learn about XSS
you're your first payload that you write
is usually you have a document right and
you write an image tag a URL and then
you do plus document cookie
that's the usual way so here this is the
same but just with expression languages
so instead of inserting a script that
has this document right
you just insert this image with the URL
and then you just tell the already a
framework to fill the cookie in at the
right place so you just say here okay I
take take take the global object which
is window then give the document and
then put the cookie and there is no
JavaScript involved is all like
domain-specific language of Perea
and we can actually do a lot of crazy
things for example let's let's assume
now we have CSP in place and CSP uses
nonces to to validate whether a script
is legitimate or not so we can for
example use expression to just let the
framework insert the nonce for us so
here we have an example we have a script
and that the attacker injected and at
the injection time we don't know the
nonce right so we just add a nonce
attribute and in this nonce attribute we
specify an expression and say eh already
a framework please insert the nonce for
us here and then the aurélia framework
will happily do that and it will go to
the document we will say what is the
current script which is the aurélia
script and we'll just get the nonce from
there and add it to this so you have a
valid script that bypasses the policy
okay so we we looked at these four
different modes so we looked at the
whitelist and non-space modes we use
that looked at unsafe inline and strict
dynamic and what we see here is that
whitelist and nonces are pretty strong
we were only able to bypass in three or
sixteen cases or four of sixteen cases
but white lists have other problems so
we had a paper last year in CCS where we
showed that they are basically insecure
so you shouldn't assume that white lists
are the safest solution in this case but
what we see is that like those unsafe
keywords they dramatically lower the
protection capabilities of a CSP policy
even especially eg strict on any keyword
and when we envision district an in a
keyword in the beginning it was called
unsafe dynamic and then someone in the
standardization committees thought
unsafe dynamic is really a bad word it
should really be called strict dynamic
and I was I think in hindsight a very
bad choice okay so this this was the
study that we did on libraries and
basically we were able from from the
combination of libraries and XSS
mitigations we were able to bypass all
the cases in 53 percent of all the cases
and however we always stop at the first
exploit so whenever we were able to
bypass a mitigation technique we stopped
so there might be multiple other
bypasses and caches in the libraries
that we didn't look at and we found out
that basically the expression based ones
are the most powerful ones but they are
quite effective in bypassing all the
mitigation techniques that we've test
as a next step we conducted an empirical
study and we did that together with si P
and with some of us and Martin Jones and
we wanted to find out whether gadgets
exist also in real-world pages so now we
looked at libraries and these libraries
are very generic they have a lot of
crazy code in there they do a lot of
automatic things so maybe it's different
when we look at developer written code
and all that this is very generic
library code so we again had the same
questions we asked ourselves as how
common are gadgets in real world
applications and how common are they how
effective are they in bypassing XSS
mitigations in real world websites so
what we did is we built an engine that
can detect gadgets and verify them so
how this works is that we where we have
a team tracking engine that we build
into Chrome and Firefox and with this
engine we crawl the Alexa top 5,000
websites and these website might contain
a gadget here and if a gadget is
contained we have a data flow from the
Dom tree into a security sensitive
function so we patch the dormant and the
security sensitive function and
basically what we get out is a data flow
from the Dom to Security Center function
we can then use this data flow to pass
this to an exploit generator and the
exploit generator will generate a gadget
based exploit so here we see it's a
legitimate markup that that contains in
the data text attribute like like our
payload and our payload contains a
function here and we then in check this
gadget back into the page and then we
wait for a function call and if we see
this function call from from for example
a data text attribute we know that there
was a code in the page that upgraded our
data to code execution and we ran this
on the Alexa top 5,000 and we basically
found gadget related data flows and 82%
of all the websites and I assume the
other 18% we're offline or were just
like some static pages I don't have
JavaScript at all and then we ran this
82% of the flows through through our
exploit generation engine and we
basically verified about two hundred
eighty five thousand gadgets in the
Alexa top 5,000
those gadgets are not necessarily unique
there might be duplicates because you
use the same libraries across many
different pages so we looked at the
domains and we verified gadgets in about
20% or 906
however our detection and verification
approach was very very conservative so
we we didn't want to have false
positives so we we bought the zero false
positives rate by accepting a large
number of false negatives and we
actually looked at at a lot of flows
manually I looked at about a hundred and
most of the flows were exploitable so my
assumption is that we are somewhere
between 20% and 82% of the websites that
have gadget and from I just for my gut
feeling I think we are rather at the 80%
and not that the 20% as a next step we
looked at how effective gadgets would be
in bypassing XSS mitigations and this
was kind of tricky because most of
websites don't have these mitigations
and we cannot just deploy them onto the
web applications because we would break
the applications we could also not not
not say if there's a Web Application
Firewall for example because it's hidden
and so on so these are just theoretical
numbers where we looked at the number of
data flows we didn't actually try to
exploit things and we first looked at
HTML sanitizers and for example what we
saw is that 60% of all websites contain
a data flow from a data attribute to a
security sensitive function and by
default most sanitizers allow data
attributes so we believe that in most
cases sanitizers can be can be
supplemented as a second step we then
looked at access filters and buffs and
CSP unsafe eval and we just wanted to
know how many eval base data flows there
are in websites and about every every
second website has a data flow from the
Dom into Evo and last but not least we
looked at CSP strict dynamic and we're
trusted scripts create other scripts and
we found that about 73 percent of all
the sites have a data flow that results
in a script tag being appended to the
Dom by a legitimate script which is
pretty a pretty large number and which
surprised us and this is mainly due to
jQuery because of this weird behavior of
parsing text and appending scripts okay
so we did this two studies and what we
see here is that these script caches are
everywhere they are in all modern
libraries they are in almost all
applications and so we thought what can
we do about it so we have these gadgets
and XSS
education doesn't don't seem to work and
so we asked ourselves what is the what
are the root causes for it is this and
when we look at technology we see that
vulnerabilities are our technology
dependent so we already had this case
today the for example if you use
parameterize queries you you don't have
sequel injection if you use if you use
memory save languages you don't have
buffer overflows and memory corruption
blocks and the same is true for XSS and
the problem with XSS itself is that XSS
is is core to the web platform right we
create this we use HTTP and HTML so we
create a big string on the server side
we sent this string to the browser then
we execute the string as code then at
runtime we create new strings we pass
those two inner HTML and eval and
everything in the web is string based
and that is actually the reason why we
have xs/s in the web and we have to say
that XSS is extremely easy to introduce
it's extremely hard to find
in an application and it's one of the
most severe client-side vulnerabilities
that we have and that's and the root
cause is how the web platform works and
everything about it we haven't changed
the web platform in 25 years so the the
Dom API is that we use are still the
same that we had we introduced 20 years
ago in the 90s and so on and so forth
and we're trying to dance around the
problem of XSS and try to create all
these mitigations and layers on top but
we're never
tackling the root cause and I think we
don't we cannot take tackle the root
cause for all of XSS but we're trying to
do that photonics is us because we can
probably not change the HTTP protocol to
do not use strings anymore that that
would be too crazy but we can do we can
solve subsets of the problem and how we
want to do that is that we are trying to
Inc and we want to create a type system
for the Dom so right now the Dom is
based on strings and here's an intent to
ship so we already have a first version
in Chrome Canary and what we are trying
to do here is we are trying to replace
all the string based API is that we have
in browsers in HTML evo document right
and on script of source and so on and we
will replace these with type api's and
these typed api's will not accept
strings but types for example a trusted
HTML type i trust
the script type trusted URL type and the
only way you can create such a type is
through secure means so you can either
use a secure builder or you can use a
sanitizer or other secure ways of
creating those types and by doing that
we get guarantees a developer cannot
introduce XSS into an application
because all the ways you can get this
type is safe and if you only assign
allow this as assigning of types and
then your application is safe as well
you don't even need to look at the
application anymore and here's a very
simple example for example here we we
have a Dom element that's called foo and
we create a trusted type and we created
for example by a sanitization and then
we assign this to in HTML and that would
be fine because we have a type we assign
it to in HTML and now we will have an
enforcement mode that throws an
exception whenever you try to assign a
string to an age you know
so you assign a string here that would
just throw an exception I would not be
accept and that's how we can kill
Dominic success however we have a couple
of huge challenges and they are mainly
in the not in the security part but more
in the usability part so I think we can
create a perfect system that is
perfectly secure and no one would use it
or we couldn't use the perfect system
that everyone would use but that is not
secure and that's where we are trying to
right now working on getting the right
balance so we have two big problems the
first one is is it's backwards
compatibility so how do we deal with all
the browsers that don't support these
types and I think we have a good story
there we have a polyfill that basically
creates this typed in other browsers so
you could today you could use trusted
types in your applications if you want
and we are actually using them in a lot
of application and I know that I think
github is using them as well and
Facebook is also using similar concepts
type based systems to prevent XSS and
they are pretty successful in doing so
but the much larger problem that we are
currently tackling our unsafe
conversions and oh I need to hurry bit
yes oh
unsafe conversions so we have a lot of
applications that requires some form of
unsafe conversions where you have a
seemingly untrusted script but out of
the context you know this is secure in
this in this context so please make it
secure and we are currently thinking
about different ways to to enable these
unsafe conversions
and there here's a call to arms if
you're a JavaScript developer if you're
developing JavaScript libraries or if
you're just interested in working on an
exciting new web platform feature then
just reach out to us Y by Twitter by
email or just today and try to help okay
with this I would like to summarize and
conclude so what I showed you today is
that XSS mitigations work by blocking
attacks and not by preventing applique
venting the bugs
however we we see that script so called
script caches can be used to circumvent
medications and script gadgets are
legitimate pieces of JavaScript code in
an application that upgrade a legitimate
HTML to script execution and what we saw
is that script script gadgets are
prevalent in all libraries and all
applications out there and they can they
are very effective in bypassing all the
XSS mitigations and what we see is that
the web platform hasn't changed in in
about 25 years and we think that in
order to address this problem we need to
change the route or we need to era dig
the root cause and make the web platform
secure by default so that developers
just cannot introduce bugs because
trainings and guidelines are nice but
they often don't don't prevent your
developers from from accidentally
screwing up and in order to do so we
introduced this new type system that we
want to build into browsers and we are
still discussing with browser vendors
and and and other people to get this
into other browsers as well but the idea
is that when when we get this in
everywhere and when developers use the
system we can basically fight one one
full class of this I would like to thank
you for your attention and I don't think
we have time for questions but thank you
Sebastien thank you
one urgent quick question I think it's
very interesting what he said but if I
understood I didn't mention angular 2
and type in under 4 and and so on right
yes type phrases angle 4 is typescript
right so the the mythology you are
imposing to fix the problem it's kind of
the same that they already use yes
angular is using that concept already
right but I think it should be in the
platform should not be limited to big
frameworks because we see a lot of
crappy framework said it cannot afford a
team of developers implementing and I
don't know their own template compilers
and so on I think that should be a
platform feature but yeah we also didn't
look at angular 2 because at the time we
started this angular 2 was pretty new
and so we looked at angular 1 only ok at
the time he's here all day so in the I
think the next break you will will be
very busy
Thank You Sebastian
[Applause]