good what I want to present today in
this talk is actually some reporting on
research analysis we have been doing on
domain names that have been registered
on the dot EU TLD so we have actually
been analyzing all the registrations in
dot EU I'm actually trying to understand
how large bunches of malicious domain
names are being registered by malicious
actors and the work at present today
here is joint work between a research
lab at k-11 and also here it which is
the registry for dot EU so together
actually we did this analysis we go into
the insights that you can present today
how will the talk look like I will first
start with a little bit of research
context what do we exactly mean with
malicious domain names how do you ACTU
actually work what is the main idea what
do we actually want to research in this
analysis let me go a little bit deeper
into the data set that we have been
using and during the analysis the
malicious domain names that we actually
found in the dot au TLB and then I will
show you some of the insights we found
in on the doodle analysis we studied the
domain names from 14 months long those
insights was actually trying to
understand how the malicious actors work
and more important if you understand how
they work can we actually make it nice
order for them can we actually make it
much harder for them to register domain
names and the last two parts in that the
presentation will be rather short they
were actually looking forward if you now
did all that work of doing the manual
analysis how can we automate this to do
this on a more regular timeframe but
also on more TL DS and secondly if you
have all the information available how
attack will actually work maybe it takes
the time to take the next step how can
we actually prevent or detect this as
close as possible to the registration
time but first a little bit of context
so what are those malicious domain names
well most of you here already very
familiar with the fact that domain names
or key factor in Internet and also for
attackers they're actually using this as
kind of an enabler to launch our attacks
for spam they need domains to send
domains for their mails from to
communicate with a command and control
and botnets they need domain names
because they are actually much easier to
replace or to update than fixed IP
addresses same for fishing and for more
aware and the trend that we see recently
we
in the malleus community is that they
actually trying to avoid blacklisting
they're trying to be much more than hit
and run strategy so they actually using
in the main name and then they disperse
it they go to the next domain name
because once it's blacklist you can't do
anything with the domain name most of
the mail service will book it and so on
so you see that there's actually a very
fast flux and the use of the main names
for one particular attack and it's a
single-shot after study in 2013 over
these shows 60% of the malicious domain
names after one day is not used anymore
so you just use it for less than one day
you throw it away and you go to the next
domain name so that's the ID but if that
is the context we're working in one of
the richest hypothesis we had is if
malicious actors need so many domain
names well they actually need to
register domain names in bulk because
they need for a longer period of time a
continuous stream of new fresh domain
names that they can use for abusive
measures maybe that is the hypothesis we
can actually validate that but also we
can actually search one step further are
we able to identify such bold behavior
in registrations based on certain
commonalities common patterns that we
see between those malicious
registrations as I already set the long
term goal if you have such patterns if
you understand how that registration
process is working then maybe we can I
go one step further and detect and
prevent them before they do any
malicious harm or any harm and our
systems that's the main idea of this
presentation of course in order to do
such analysis we need data we need to
actually see the registration data we
need to actually be searching for
patterns in that data set so this
correlation between this net and arid
dot-eu is it actually run by error to
the registry
it's a seventh largest country code TLD
that we have they have about I would say
four million domain names now in their
data set and the data set that we have
been using in our analysis is only
domain names that were for the first
time registered so if the main name is
transferred or re-regulate we did not
take that into account in our analysis
but in our analysis during 14 months we
had 800 24,000 registrations about 2.5
percent of them were flagged as
malicious by external parties so this is
the data set we were working on all the
graphs and so all the figures you will
see today obey
on this data set what information did we
have available of course the basic
information about the domain name also
which register has been used went
already registered very normal of course
we also have as part of our process
information about the registrant who is
actually registering this domain name we
have a company name name the language
being used the email address phone even
a personal address the main idea of
doing registrations in the dot EU TLD is
you need to provide correct contact
information in order to register a
domain name of course you also need some
technical details to actually operate
with you don't know my name
so also named self informations
available and if you are using name
service within your own domain
you also need glue records IP addresses
but actually boots said the whole way of
actually looking at your name server so
this is the information that we got
available by actually collaborating
together with eret little au registry we
did enrich that data set with two parts
first we went to want to know which of
those domain names are actually
malicious because we can see eight
hundred thousand domain names we need to
know which are the ones that work they
are interested in your analysis and for
that we actually queried three sources
of malicious behavior the black lists we
used Spamhaus
we also create sure and we also use the
Google Safe Browsing list and we did
this typically on a daily basis for 13
days and then every week repeated until
six months after registration this is
one part now we know which domain names
in our data set or malicious the second
thing is we also wanted to see where the
name servers are located so we wanted to
have actually the geolocation
information of the name servers and
their field we use the next month
free database to look up the name
service at the time of registration ok
now we have all the components we know
which data should be using all their
instance that we have been mating we
know what we actually want to search for
now it's time to actually go and look
and at longer tweedle analysis but first
let me introduce you the concept of a
campaign so campaign is a set of
registrations that are registered with
malicious intent there's most probably
from the same actor so the same
organization the same team the same
person and now typically register over
longer
period of time so this correlates with
the hypothesis we had they'll being
registered in bulk over a longer period
of time of course within a dataset we
actually have to query data so for us
our approximation is something that we
can money we'll select based on a common
pattern in our data set and that runs
for a longer period of time and the
common pattern is linkable - it's the
same actor of the same team doing it
because they're using the same contact
information they have the same pattern
devils using the same tools to actually
create registrant information of course
this is all vague maybe let's look a
little bit deeper in one particular
example of a campaign
this is campaign c11 you will see
numbers later on and campaigns but this
campaign was running for about eight
months from June to February and
consists about twelve hundred domain
names that were actually flagged by
external parties so we did not say that
there are bunches external party was
saying that those were malicious how did
it look well mainly look to the
registration information that was used
the contact information of the
registrant they were all using the same
fixed email provider namely a private
domain name used for email communication
they had in that domain name two email
accounts three phone numbers and two
streets and I were using that them
separately registering but they're
actually combining the same emails phone
numbers and streets over and over to
create new registrant information they
also used four registers back to back
so actually sequentially over those
eight months time they used four
different registers to actually provide
them the services to register domain
names in the registry so you see already
quite a lot registrations for one
particular campaign so we actually
assume that this is all from one actor
if you're looking a little bit more to
the different campaigns this is the
overview that actually sketches a
highlight on what did we investigate so
we have the full period of 14 months
here we have 20 different campaigns so
this is or 20 different so actually
criteria that we used to isolate regular
set of registrations potentially coming
from the same actor we see some of them
are actually going up to 2000 registries
some of them are only about 100 120
registrations
and the the size of the bullets on the
line or actually the sizes of how many
oh and tens was that campaign on day by
day basis and you see it goes up to four
hundred registrations that one day one
campaign can deliver so some of them are
a little bit more on strict days some of
them have a very strict pattern that are
doing it on a very regular basis over a
longer period of time so this is the
base ID but of course this is just the
graph that we say this is the end result
let's now go and to look a little bit
deeper and what we actually found us not
interesting insights in those campaigns
but first let me recap how we actually
did that campaign identification process
because it helps to understand how we
came to the concept of campaigns so in
order to actually do that this is a more
iterative process we typically start
from all the munches domains that we
have our data set but there of course
you have like 21,000 domain names where
do you start looking at to find certain
selection criteria that actually can
link similar registrations to each other
well we have different tactics that we
have been using for instance you can
look two days that are very intensive it
publishes in registrations you couldn't
look to registration details or reused
quite a lot princes one mail provider or
one street or one email this is actually
being used in a lot of email accusations
over time then that's a good point
you could also look to registrations
that have recognized or patents for
instance we found email addresses with
very distinct patterns like this one as
a kind of a number and then a certain
mail provider and you also see the
frequent combination of two illogical
combinations of legislation for instance
a certain country and a certain mail
provider that only appears within the
magis registration data set and we then
apply this on the benign and the
malicious data data parts and try to see
which of those criteria do fit well and
the malicious set and do not pop up a
lot of results in the benign set because
that's the kind of grid of identifiers
it's really a good precise at indicator
for malicious traffic yeah
we will do that we'll discuss this later
but this isn't it no no here is it's
just if it's one a 50/50 or 60/40 it's a
really good indicator if you see that if
you apply to the militias it's only
giving a fraction of 2% it's actually
10% fraction in the benign then it might
not be such a good selector but we'll
discuss a little bit later on the the
way we can actually extend blacklist but
that's a good point so to give you the
example here we see the graph which
actually shows you the relative number
of registrations on a daily basis so you
see that this is the malicious number we
have the same graphs for the the benign
numbers with the malicious number have
actually spikes in traffic but they
actually have days where a lot of
malicious registrations have been
registered and those are good starting
points for instance for your analysis
or in those days there is it is there
any build behavior there where you see
for instance 100 of 200 stations or
using the same domain name or a mail
provider or using the same phone number
and so on this is one indicator another
indicator for instance if you say we
have all the malicious email providers
set up here we have countries what are
the hot spots of combinations of
countries and mail providers this is the
data on the multiset with the threshold
of you need more than 50 registrations
per dot we could do the same with the
benign and then see are there any hot
spots that are actually present in the
malicious set which are not present in
the benign set might be a good starting
point as well and for instance we could
start already with weak points in our
analysis we actually found out that all
the green points belong to campaigns and
the red dots do not belong to campaign
so this is actually a good conditioner
that those hot spots or a good way to
start to identify the campaigns of
course it's all kind of practically to
iteratively look into a filter data
within the dataset what's more
interesting for this audience is
actually if you looked in 20 campaigns
what type of criteria did we use in
selection criteria to select this is
this particular campaign so we see that
we're using domain name the register in
the name selves in some of the
registrations but most of the the
campaigns were actually selected based
on data used for the registrant which
name which address which email account
which email provider and those are the
ones that
have the most impact in selecting the
right campaigns out of the full dataset
good any questions so far before we go
into the insights what we found within
the campaign's yeah
okay let me reinsert that question after
the first inside because that might
actually be good nothing to answer that
what we used here is a full post factum
analysis so we actually have the data we
waited for a few months and then we
started the analysis of course then
we're looking
when was that know my name being listed
on a blacklist and that's actually dead
answer there any other questions
the question was why did you get the
data from two sources the registration
data was in the collaboration together
with earth we actually investigated the
data directly all the contact
information so on for the maliciousness
we actually quite the treat sources so
for spam house and sure we send out a
lot of DNS queries to query whether the
main name was in their list of blacklist
sir a blacklist domains and Google Safe
Browsing has an API to query so that's
actually the source we did not use for
instance let's encrypt or transparency
or other sources who actually enrich it
it could be interesting to see if you
enrich that how actually would that
change our analysis of could we find
additional campaigns but we did not do
that we respect to three providers no we
don't publish them because they're
actually containing personal information
personal identifiable information but
that is actually together with earth we
did actually search queries on that
database yeah indeed it's collaboration
so to answer the question when not
actually does the meaning is being used
I will transfer a little bit differently
how long did it take before domain name
and Interpol and blacklist and actually
we see here that there's a small window
opportunity once it's on the blacklist
yeah actually there's almost no use for
malicious that then intent possible
anymore so it's actually the moment
you're getting in there it's game over
and we see in a graph that around 75% of
the domain names is already flagged by
black his services of the five days and
after 30 days of registration then 98%
of them are already on the blacklist
and later on we only see two percent
being added to that blacklist service so
in that sense when are they used
typically in a window between zero and
five days I would say so which is
actually quite short not necessary the
day itself but typically in a short
frame so you might imagine that there
might even be an underground activity
that people are creating no main aims
and then selling them to malicious
actors that the hypothesis that we have
in the way the ecosystem is working
so yeah so the delay is because we only
see the data after a some period of time
well we see that even certain of the the
command and control domain names already
in use before the domain name gets
registered so for certain types it is
there the the fact that to be a little
bit later in the game here is because it
takes some time before we actually can
start querying the database so we don't
do it instantly whenever we get a domain
name is typically a 6 to 24 hour delay
and that's actually popping up there
also yes it's almost a nice later slides
but yes we have to give you an ID we are
performing I think 700,000 DNS queries
they to actually get that malicious
activity data so we're doing quite some
doing it more intense would be of peace
but this moment second thing where do
the data come from so I already
mentioned that we have three providers
but what actually is the data that we
see for what other campaigns being used
we see these are the typical Buse types
we see the majority of them or actually
being for spam so it's also quite
obvious that for spam there's much more
reporting the moment you get spam in
there you can report you can collect you
can see the four different mail service
domains get blacklist or commanding
control it's much more difficult to get
the whole hold on how many domain names
are being used for command and control
so in that sense I think the other
numbers that might be muscle more domain
names in a registration data set that
are used for multi activity but since
they are not arriving on blacklist we
don't have them in order malicious data
set second insight which of the domain
names which all the providers is be used
for blacklisting and which were actually
interesting well we see between the
Spamhaus
and sir that there's actually a good I
would say coverage by pulling them
together we see certain the campaign's
were only detected by one of those and
for others actually they're actually
finding the complement of each other
which means we actually need multiple
sources to get a good ground truth also
interesting fact if you're looking to
the last column the Google Safe Browsing
less than 2% of the domain names that we
actually consider you know how much the
data set came from Google browsing might
also be late
to the fact that the main names here or
more info structural and rated to spam
and there's always reported within the
browser again it depends on which are
the use cases that you're looking for so
in that sense when I'm talking about
malicious campaigns keep in mind it's
mainly what is being used for spam and
phishing good I already showed you the
graph and if you looked at the graph you
might already see with the 20 campaigns
certain things are popping up you see
some interesting things that already in
there and the first thing is there might
be actually a large variety in the way
campaigns are running so for instance
here we have a very smart campaign it's
only 37 days but it's quite intensive it
already has about 2,000 registrations in
those 37 days at the same moment we also
see within our data set that our
campaigns running over about 300 days
reusing registrant information and only
having 154 registrations so it's not
that all the actors are actually abusing
or registering the same boat number of
domain names with the same tools with
the same intensity another interesting
inside that we had is it seemed that the
malicious actors or humans as well in
the graph that they found here we're
putting the order of the day either
there at the moment that registration
has been done over day by day basis and
you see the the greenish blue line is
actually the benign registrations and
their daily share and you see they're
all more registrations during the week
LS in the weekend button you're looking
to the malicious registration we see
that despite so much order so you see
almost no registrations during the
weekend and most of the military good
stationing or happening during the week
of course we can't say that this is
purely because the match is actus or
working on business hours it it could be
we can only make hypotheses about this
another hypothesis could also be it is
much more interesting for them to mimic
the office hours because then actually
might go a little bit more under radar
if they would do all the registrations
on a continuous basis they would
actually the differentiate versus the
benign traffic but maybe they did that
they just overdid it
they're doing too much okay station
through the week first of the weekend
but we
such a pattern okay we can't make a
conclusive answer why this but more
interesting if you're looking through
the time of the year so we're doing the
same analysis for the full period of
time 14 months
is only the malicious traffic you know
again we see that it's like a summer
break a Christmas break and a spring
break I'm not sure what are they
actually taking holiday I hope they do
because it's from that time happy to
make a holiday but could also be that is
because they want to be as effective as
possible it could be if they're at lunch
you can use spam campaign during the
summer break that they actually has less
effect than doing the same spank
campaign in June or August so also there
we might see the pattern but we're not
sure if it's actually a fact that they
are actually taking a holiday or the
fact that actually trying to make it as
most effective as possible we saw
certain topics for instance on May 1st
and so on small spikes before and after
but also you have to take into account
therefore the one days they could also
be certain effects at the resource or
registers because they're using the
normal ecosystem to register domain
names it could be a spike on Black
Friday could be because one of the
resources are just giving them very very
cheap domain names so in that sense we
didn't derive in too much deeper than
the weak pattern that big pattern was
continued over the whole year though the
Year pattern we can see if you dive in
deeper details there are so many effects
that you have not under control that can
influence the data but but indeed that
could be effects there as well but a
little bit more about the business hours
we try to actually see at what time of
the day did they register and that's not
for all the campaigns but some campaigns
have actually quite distinct patterns
for instance let's look at see 18 18 18
we see that they're typically working in
box from 8 to 10 hours it's not that I'm
working continuously they're doing it
slow but all the domain registration has
always done in a kind of period of time
interesting again is mimicking or is it
actually that normal behavior we can't
actually know for sure yeah it's also
time zone shifts that's true
I actually think it's through the West
because there later in our time zone and
could also be that they're just lazy and
also only get up late at the morning and
so on
not sure but again we only see the data
we don't see the person after data it
would be interesting to see the one
behind the data more interesting on the
C 11 we see a morning and an afternoon
do they actually take lunch breaks of
about two hours it is quite long again
we don't know for sure
we only see that certain campaigns or
actually reflecting certain behavior
that we did not expect when we started
this analysis but but be reassured we
think about automation some others do
think about automation as well so here
we see campaign that is doing kind of
not so intensive campaign only few
registrations per day but it's always
doing it at the same hours and it's
actually doing it from January almost
two times a day and if you even mind
this European summer time this is at all
side that all system was just changing
through the summer time but you see
there are actually most of their
activity is always on the same time it's
just a chrome type or anything else
running on this system so not all of
them are working according to office
hours not all of them or just human
typing in things I didn't put it in the
presentation but one of the interesting
things we found actually typing mistakes
in registering deformation domain names
and so on so it might actually be that
they have a list of things that they
have to pull and it's easier and cheaper
to type it in and automate so now the
question is who is doing all that stuff
who is actually registering all those
domain names or who is facilitating that
so the first thing that we looked at is
what the register is actually enabling
them and we saw for instance register 5
we of course obviously anonymized this
register is actually responsible for 50%
of all the malicious domain names in our
data set which is kind of interesting is
that register of bat intent not sure it
could be that he's actually the cheapest
one and that the the malicious actors
are just being very cost effective in
reducing their their main names it could
also be because the whole ecosystem of
DNS
working with registrar's and resells I
thought a lot of results have actually
good contacts with this registrar or you
can pay in Bitcoin so they can many
different reasons but we see that this
one is popping out also their toxicity
actually means that more than one-third
of the domains that that register is
registering we already know for sure it
will be malicious remember the average
was 2.5 let's look at the domain names
well that email provides the domain
names of the email providers so of
course we see here in the top tree the
free public email providers that we can
use we see Gmail and AOL for instance is
interesting to compare we see that Gmail
has like 20% of the contact information
used for malicious domain names as a
gmail address about 10% has an a well
address interesting here Gmail if we
look into the toxicity only have 2% so
Gmail's are more likely used in benign
registration and in malicious
registrations whereas if you look to AOL
if you do a new registration with an AOL
address well our system will probably
already give you a red flag just because
of your email address keep that in mind
we see that almost half of the
registrations done with an AWOL address
in recent information is just malicious
in our data set
and the third thing I want to focus in
here in the top enables so these are
fixed email addresses used by attackers
if you just take the top three email
addresses used by registrants in the the
registration database
they already account for around 70
percent of all the malicious
registrations that we have in our
database and also interesting here we
see for instance the first and the third
email address is close to 100% toxicity
actually means that whatever they're
registered with I'm sure it's actually
with malicious intent well those are the
things that are not flagged on external
services but we can actually assume that
the error or test before they starting
to run or certain domains are not used
or not seen by the blacklist services or
reported to coming back on the the idea
of we have campaigns here we have
blacklist they do not exactly match one
on one here we actually try to to see if
you say we have about 20
thousand domain names that are in the
set of blacklisted data we also have
about twenty twenty-one percent of the
main names that are campaigns we see
60,000 of them or shared so that means
that if you say it's a part of a
campaign it's also being flagged
externally we were interesting to see
what what is actually happening in those
campaigns they are using the same
campaign criteria as the wounded are
being flagged but they are not flagged
so we did actually do a manual analysis
of those about four thousand domains you
see whether those domain names were
actually malicious intent or mistakes on
our site were false positives and our
conclusion is there that less than one
percent of them are false positives so
in that whole set about two hundred of
the domain names or actually potentially
benign we don't know for sure that all
the rest we actually could validate but
ever used for malicious intent that
actually means if you are using this
kind of analysis techniques there is
actually the potential to extend the
existing blacklist services with an
additional about 20% of extra
information which might be nice just
because of looking through the
registrant information on a domain name
and the last insight I would like to
discuss today is the fact that attackers
they are clever as well they adapt over
time so I already mentioned the
beginning that they have adaptive
strategies for instance this campaign C
11 has four different registrar's and is
actually jumping from register to
register we see certain small pikes on
the first one it might be that the
resale is from time to time also for
instance taking the cheapest Road or a
registration but the registers is
something obviously that we can see in a
graph but we saw much more variation
within the adaptations done by the magis
actus so for instance if you are looking
the registers we see some of them are
using three to four three registers in
line with the graph we saw before but
they're actually creating fake
identities over and over so in order to
actually register the domain name a
malicious actor need registered
information they need an email address a
phone number and address and they're
actually using tools or they do it
manually to create new fake addresses
new fake numbers new email addresses and
you see cert of them or actually just
stick into one phone number or one email
address but some of them are actual
using 20 50 70 of those attended peace
and what we saw in our dataset is that
they're often having actually a kind of
a pool of street names a pool of names a
pool of phone numbers and then I ran
them combining them to new registered
information which a little bit helped us
and actually compiling this kind of
analysis then the question is of course
now we have done a whole manual analysis
it's a one-time thing that we did there
are two options either we can try to
automate this analysis and even improve
with automatic tools the things that we
now found manually this is number one we
can actually also try to go to this tech
fact that we say now we can actually use
an information to protect the TLD to
protect the end users so let me first
look into how can we automate the
campaign identification and then look
into how can we actually improve the
quality of domain names and it eld so
the first one what we try to do is
actually now we actually grouped based
on similarities and patterns different
regulations together we can also use
machine learning techniques and one of
the techniques that we used in our study
was agglomerative clustering where
actually we actually grouping
registration together based on
similarities between the registrations
until we actually find a certain optimum
we did that and we found that we when we
have 432 clusters which actually thirty
forty four hundred and thirty two groups
of domain names the 30 largest clusters
already represent 92 percent of our data
set which was far as a good cutoff to
say let's look in it 30 largest clusters
within that machine learning set and
here we map it on the x-axis we see the
clusters that all automatically compiled
by the computer by the agglomerative
clustering on y-axis we see the 20
campaigns that we have and we're trying
to validate how well did we do where can
we improve why do we better then
automate it and so these are the three
insights that we have on this part so
what are the findings here well good
news the green ones here or about 26 of
those clusters we can find exactly one
campaign that matches that cluster a
campaign can exist out of multiple of
those clusters which actually means that
there are multiple similar
registrations rolling through the same
campaign but we see there's a one-on-one
mapping unfortunately it's not pays for
all of those receive for instance that
for three of them we see one cluster
which actually means very similar
registrations and they end up in our
analysis in two different campaigns and
we see it four three four three periods
that actually makes an assumption that
it's not 20 actors but about seventeen
actors at all being active within the
dot EU TLD and indeed for some of them
you can actually visually see there's
some correlation for instance the first
c1 and c2 also in time correct quite
nice and also if we inspected manually
what are the relations between the two
campaigns we see that it while reusing
certain the registration data bit in
between number using for instance the
same phone number and so on so if you
would have been doing or manual criteria
analysis even a little bit better
probably we would have ended up with c2
and c3 being one campaign and the same
for the other two so this is something
the automatic tool can help to improve
identification process the second thing
we see clusters that are not mapped to
any of the campaigns interesting that
means that we missed something and
indeed with this cluster 16 we did so
many validation and then the depth that
we were too restrictive in specifying
campaign C 20 so in the same days with
the same patterns but different email
provider plus the 16 was active so if it
would actually combine the manual and
automated but for sure we would say C 16
here is belonging to campaign 2000 time
at ik tools can improve so it's all bad
as we so do so badly in doing the manual
analysis luckily we found also finding 3
there was one cluster plus I campaign 15
it was not present in any of the 30
clusters that we found here and then we
started to looking in what is happening
here why does this actually not end up
in the the logit clusters well then we
looked into the smaller clusters so we
remember we had about 400 clusters so
we're looking into the other clusters
which of them all belonging to campaign
C 15 so the green dots
or the campaign and the red dots here or
all clusters contributing to that
campaign and we see that they have a lot
of small clusters with very similar
registration details even running on the
same days but they have a lot of those
different clusters so it looks like this
campaign is much more advanced actually
trying to circumvent automatic detection
by the string pills and indeed if you're
looking to see 15 what was actually the
pattern so let me give you a little bit
inside remember in the beginning we saw
quite easy campaign criteria where we
say well by using one de Mol provider
there were few streets and phone numbers
well this one was much clever and I
would even say we give him the award of
the best of was skating campaign in our
data set
it actually is about 500 domains that
were registered over a long period of
time 258 days and that were actually
using a generation tool to create fake
identities so they actually used the LA
virtual tool they loaded it with dutch
information and then also complement in
the last months with English surname
lost engine secrets and they actually
created 98 registrants with that then
the next step what were the domain names
looking like well interesting because of
this audience that were actually Dutch
words so this was also the reason why we
by analyzing the domain names it popped
up that have also gotten similar is some
rarities between different clusters so
they're actually using a large
vocabulary of Dutch words and they're
always combining two or three words and
there might even be letters in between
one binding letter in between which does
not make any sense in Dutch but we'll
done by the person typing in those words
and we see luckily that the same Dutch
words in that dataset or being reused
among different sets of registries
registrants
so within 98 if they would each
individually use a small set of domain
names and create them it will be very
hard for us to link them but now because
they were using the same word across 98
registrants we could easily see that
there were relationships between those
98 registrants we saw also certain
patterns in the way that were describing
Street and song say there made some
mistakes and doing your registration
which helped us to see but it gives you
the idea it's very hard to automatically
find out that all those registrations
together also interesting detailed they
actually have kind of not fully
automated but they were always
registering their registrants and
batches of 8 16 24 or 32 which was for
us an actual validation that we found
all of them but again we can do this
manually it's very hard to do this
automatically so actually I would
advocate after doing both manual and
automated we probably need both of both
worlds we actually need the best of both
worlds to actually combine both the
insight that we easily can see by human
reading to data also combined with a
tool that is actually doing it in a very
resistant way yeah and also well there
because they were using a generation
tool they were also reusing certain
registration details across different
registrants No so the question was is it
correct to say that only the last three
bullets were actually helping to detect
it in a manual analysis I think it's
true for a large part of the analysis
there were certain things that were
being reused but a lot of our tool as
well
so that we could link and they also made
some mistakes in the way that were
entering street names which also was
something unique compared to all the
other campaigns within our data set but
indeed it was mainly because of the
Dutch words that we had the good trigger
we need to investigate also interesting
this was the campaign that was not seen
very well with blacklist I think only
50% of them were on blacklist services
so with that actually going to the end
of my talk so I will promise you to tell
a little bit more how can we automate
this and actually making TLD more secure
well how can we go with detection of
prevention and there the insight is if
you now know all those characteristics
of how with the mainers or actually
creating new domain names for malicious
use what is the next step that we need
to do but actually at registration time
already detect or prevent malicious
domain names how far can we go there so
what we did is actually we again used
machine learning tools
we used agglomerative clustering based
on the similarity similar as we did in
the previous exercise we also using
classification based on the reputation
of a phone number email address register
and so on and we're actually combining
this in a kind of prediction service and
we now have already early results over
the large data sets on the past that be
around between 60 and 70% of the
malicious domain names can already be
found at the time of registration with a
very very low false positive rate like
to registration reading stations a day
which actually means we can easy a route
over the more than half of all the
messages domain names just by making it
much harder for the domain use to make
their Gator registrations into the
system and as we speak we're actually
deploying this as part of Eris trust and
security program to actually prevent
those domain names from being registered
in the near future within the dot-eu TLD
so let me conclude we actually analyzed
40 months of registration data we saw
the hidden strategies but already
mentioned in literature we saw some very
long running campaigns and some of the
campaigns already started at the
beginning or even continued after or
data set was ending so it actually means
that this is actually an underestimation
of how long campaigns are running we see
variety and intensity duration but more
important we see a variety and how
adaptive they are to actually lure
around the blacklist services we saw
some interesting alignments with
business activity on purpose or
mimicking we don't know we saw that the
top two facilitators have a huge
footprint they actually the top three
facilitators registrar's email addresses
or email providers actually represent a
large fraction of our data set and we
also saw that with the campaign analysis
we actually can extend you know how we
already have in blacklist services we
saw that we can actually work towards
automatic campaign identification and it
would actually be nice interplay between
manual and automated and we also see
that we can go to proactive detection
and prevention and I hope within six
months I can give you an update on how
successful this is actually in practice
about EU TLD
if you want to know more we also have a
paper published with much more details
on all the different parts of the
campaign analysis you can easily
download
only role provided there and with that
I'm open for questions all for lunch you
decide questions well I will be honest
we didn't say all the details we had
nice interesting conversations with the
team members and also with the dot au
TLD we give you the flavor but there are
much more details of actually helping us
in detecting and that's the reason why
we don't present the full data set that
we don't present this extra criteria but
give you a lot of flavor
we used email dress we used to street
name and so on but you're fully right
the more the more we disclose the easier
it is for attackers to actually apply it
even on all the domains of course we
like the idea that the Dutch are the
best but what is your confidence that
that you haven't missed campaigns in
your analysis yeah so we did for sure
miss campaigns from all the domains that
were blacklisted by spam house and all
those 80% of them ended up in one of the
20 campaigns so I would say the 20
campaigns already have like an 80%
coverage of the existing black services
if I look - how many domains are
probably probably generated by DJ and so
on I would say the 2.5 is probably an
underestimate so we're missing things
but we started from the point what do we
see from the blacklist services also for
the DJ's it's much more difficult
because a lot of domain name
registrations with DJ footprints or not
registered by the malicious actors but
actually by security researchers which
makes it much more difficult yeah
question so and you researched it for a
you top-level domain right do you have I
have two questions do you have an idea
why this EU domain was used in the first
place and if you put these security
measures in place are there not moving
to another top-level domain
very quickly so that that the effect of
these security measures are very easily
mitigated so why did we start with EU
well in order to actually have the idea
of actually working on improving
security this is the amount of the
people that
actually running the WD that's the
reason why we started there this is a
kind of close collaboration ready for
many years that we actually trying to
improve the security there so that's the
reason there you collect your rights
that actually by raising the bar on
one's own it will actually make it more
pushing to other zones but the main idea
is that we want to be very open so that
the LDS or often communicating to each
other in many conferences so we're
presenting this work as well the IDS I
raise the bar together it will be a
little bit harder for the attacker we
will never be able to completely rude it
but the attacker has to spend more money
and it's less effective in doing that
that's the main ID and in that sense it
might be the first step but were not the
only one working on this we see that all
the large T all these like for comments
one are also trying to improve the
number of multi degree stations being
dropped one quick last question yeah
okay so sorry
so fishing best practices recommend that
he use already classified domains
because a lot of organization use
devices such as IBM blue code if I'm not
mistaken and the idea is you try to
leverage the trust or classification
those tools already use into pretty much
starts from a trusted position right and
the question is why did you decide not
to consider re-registration or yeah
registration of or actually purchasing
of already registered domain so there
are two reasons why we actually closed
the scope the newly registered domain
names I would say the first one is the
context we need to grind through to know
actually what a domain name is malicious
or benign and when we are actually doing
a registration or transfers that
actually means that domain names are
already a reputation and in that sense
it could already because they have a
benign reputation that moment if you
don't have a clear view on how these or
things are evolving so this is one thing
the other thing is with the new legal
registrations we we we can still do
something we can actually prevent them
from being active if you say we have a
domain name there's already active for
about five years eight years what are
the means that you have in that
in place you say now we will start
preventing it from a registry point of
view you have no means of actually
something that might have legitimate
traffic that gets reported and then
start to block where's the impact of
something that is newly registered then
you can start communicating your legal
team can contact them and asking what is
the purpose of this domain name do you
have all the documents and so on and
that's the reason why we focused on
honor the newly but I think even the
ones that all registered already in the
past might actually provide additional
context to see even for the newly ones
those might be name cells with a lot of
toxicity for instance and in that it
could improve it but I think it's much
hard to do the detecting prevention
because once the domain name isn't as
active it's much harder to to do any
regulation on it okay
thank you
[Applause]