all right good morning everybody my name
is mathias madhu and today i would like
to talk a little bit about budgeting and
if you have an application security
budget i'm how you can best spend that
and and what kind of buckets you have
available to you and what gives you the
best return of investment so my name is
mathias i started my career at Ghent
University I pursued a PhD in
application security it was more around
code obfuscation and essentially I
started to realize that I'm it's not
really a good idea to to hide stuff in
code right you can buy obfuscation but
still the vulnerabilities are in there
right so I was doing static analysis and
and with my PhD I moved to the US I
joined a company called fortify that was
very small at the time I was the second
researcher in there we were trying to
find the sequel injection the cross-site
scripting sin code and over the course
of seven years I realized that that I
think we were really good at finding
problems in code I also saw that the
organizations that were using for the
fight they were actually piling up the
bots the bugs you know they were finding
good stuff the sequel injections across
sites good things really really good
stuff but also piling up the bugs
because nobody knew how to fix these
problems you know it is one thing to
find problems it's another thing to fix
problems and at the same time they kept
on introducing new problems in code so
um with without real realization I said
hey maybe we should we should start from
the beginning you know how is it
possible that people keep on introducing
problems in code how is it possible that
nobody knows how to fix code so with
that knowledge I I started the company
called sensei security where the idea
was to guide developers in writing
secure codes
um and I found some really good guys
partners in crime from secure called
warrior they were doing the exact same
thing they wanted to tackle the problem
like hey how can we educate developers
how can we tell him how to to write
secure code but at the same time how can
we provide him with tools and solutions
on a day to day basis that they can
write secure code so we merged the two
organizations and and we are secure
called warrior and and we help
developers write secure code and
essentially that's what it says we want
to make sure everything is running code
right ever
is running code so in sending of
building fences around it we think that
developers are your first line of
defense you really have to educate them
you have to give them everything that
the power the means to rise so today I
would like to talk a little bit about
application security and I thought
initially I would give this introduction
because everybody knows about that
but there's there's one interesting
stuff that I couldn't get rid of and I
really wanted to talk about it so people
say well if you write problems in code
it's gonna lead to catastrophic failures
and you can lose money can you lose
money of course you can lose money look
at that Ariana 5 rocket they tried to
cram a 46 bit number into a 16 bit area
that didn't work they blanked out the
error handling for performance reason
and it blew up 7 billion was gone 10
years of research was gone
so can it cost money absolutely that's
an example mixed up and this is an
interesting one and and and Sony they
say well it can lead to brand damage yes
it can lead to brain damage if you think
about it they go back through a sequel
injection but that that's one thing but
they stored all their passwords in
clear-text and an excel file that's
that's pretty bad right but then I got
the question last in my last talk and I
said you know but the stock didn't go
down you know it went down a little bit
but now it's up again and I started like
that is true it's it's not related to
money over here you know and they have
some brand damage and at the same time
I'm still talking about that so you
would say they still feel it but even
bad publicity is still publicity so so
now I I'm no longer sure if it was a bad
thing or a good thing for Sony because
I'm actually still talking about that so
I think it's only bad for the people
that were in that position that that
stored the passwords in the excel files
you know it's been bad for these people
but other than that you know I don't
know sea level people get fired
I think target is a good example I
cannot remember his name but it is a
dear dear Otis dear Otis the role is um
he wasn't video as the CIO and he had
got a lot of knowledge in the security
world so he was really well educated he
knew his stuff they got hacked so yeah
he had to go so these
c-level people sometimes have to step
down because of breaches so apps like
what's in the name in the old days this
is the the the Ariana five problem where
they blanked out the error coding or the
error handling and for that particular
problems of the rocket blew up this is
ages ago right but this is brand new
right sequel injection this is what we
that's what we face on a day-to-day
basis right this is really the new stuff
sequel injection well actually it is it
is quite interesting I got this frame
it's a it's a it's an X key from from
about psycho injection and and it's in
real frame I brought it with me when I
was doing the the MOOC interview with
with Philip it's it's a real frame and I
got that frame and it's an interesting
one so I brought a two to our office but
the really interesting part about that
was the back of the frame at the back of
the frame I received this frame from
from Jacob who was my manager at fortify
in 2008 okay so so this goes back to
2008 this is ten years old and at that
point it was not even rocket science
right at that point we were already
working on the problem for years so
sequel injection is not the new type of
stuff you know it's is something that is
very very old
and yeah go out there go onto the we
from sequel injection and you will find
a long list of companies that get still
hacked through sequel injection I think
they gave up after 2015 they no longer
add new entries in there of companies
that got hacked through sequel injection
because there's just too many and so
what what is the root cause of this
problem I think we're in an organization
so actually um who is a application
security person over here alright who is
the developer good mix that's gonna be a
fight right not only do not come along
very well and you're in one room that's
already good so so what normally
application security people you know
about problems in code I've never seen
an empty bug tracking system maybe you
guys have one but I've never seen one so
you're aware of problems in your code
and what you do is you ask your
developer hey can you fix the code and
the way you ask it it differs from
organization to organization to make it
politically correct
and the developer he doesn't really have
got a lot of good tools to help him
right and and we asked him to fix it and
normally the application security people
it's very interesting that you guys are
here because normally you are very
understaffed and sorry so so first of
all you're gonna ask the developer to
ask the the to fix the problems in codes
um well first of all yeah did the the
the application security people you're
understaffed
according to besom you are two people
per 100 developers so which means that
you have to guide 50 developers at once
pretty hard I would say at the same time
um there's a ton of overhead for every
problem that you find you have to find a
solution you have to file in the burgh
tracking system you have to split it up
in a meeting as a developer you have to
take out the the issue you have to find
a problem to the solution you have to
implement you have to test it you have
to go through QA you have to go through
staging you have to put it in production
so for the slightest problem that you
have in your code it takes a long long
time
to fix that so it costs a lot of money
so what I see quite often is well you do
the washed up tank or you try to do the
washed up ten you get rid of that but
everything beneath that you know is a
no-go that's no time for that um at the
same time people keep on introducing
problems in encode over and over again
so they keep on developing is never the
time in a company where you say well
we're gonna stop today we're gonna first
fix all our problems and then we're
gonna start you know from from from that
moment on oh that doesn't happen you
keep on introducing problems in code on
a day-to-day basis so they're stuff that
comes back um why is that it's actually
very hard for developers I'm not sure if
you know but static analysis solutions
can find 700 different categories of
problems so you're aware of the OWASP
top 10 and sequel injection is one and
cross-site scripting is a second one
there are 698 other categories of
problems that static analysis solution
can find so it's really hard for
developers to not introduce problems and
then there are the things that are
unfound there's still this notion of
false negatives things that you do not
find in your in your code so this is a
neverending story and why is this a
neverending story I think if you compare
that with a with flying a plane
it's never the case where somebody says
well I actually want to fly plane today
and
go to the airport and they give you a
plane and they say pure fly off but
essentially that's what we do in with
developers right they come out of
university we give him a computer give
him a github access and you say go off
write some code you see that happening
right that that happens on a day-to-day
basis so I think that that's the
starting point of the problem we should
you should educate these people first on
on how to write secure code and then
over time you should give him a machine
and make sure that they write secure
code right so where do mistakes happen
we all have our stuff we have IGEL you
have waterfall and and in that you can
actually implement various things you
know you can do threat modeling I saw
that good book at the Thorian booth from
from Microsoft that's really good book
can do threat modeling you can do static
analysis you can do you can do whatever
you know and you can take whatever
methodology I don't care this is not how
developers look at this stuff this is
how developers look at the stuff
developers look at it all from from a
very practical way they look at their
self they are a developer and they write
code they push it in a repository it get
built it gets deployed and it goes to
production that's how a developer looks
at code not not the previous thing they
don't look at a waterfall thing you know
so where do they have so work and
developers really help in terms of
security and the first two things you
know its themself the developer that
writes code okay and once they push it
into the backtrack
enter sorry into into the repository and
at that point they think that they're
gonna sprinkle some security magic fairy
dust over the code and everything is
going to be secure right and we all
respect each other in IT right so we
have a lot of respect so that's why I
was asking developers versus security I
think we have a lot of respect for each
other it's not the case right and if if
you as an app stack person has to go to
a developer and you're gonna ask him to
fix something in code they argue they
was gonna say no no you don't want to do
that and you first have to really really
prove that there's an exploit vector
that's gonna work you know and that's
gonna break and even then after a while
they still will not believe you the best
thing you can get from a developers
yeah maybe so where do people we're
developers versus security what can they
do what can they not do developers have
total control over themselves and how
they write codes security does not have
any control over the developer itself or
how he writes code once it's checked in
the developer has no control whatsoever
but the security person can still pick
that up inspect that and and find
problems in their or potential problems
in there all right so there are tools to
help you out okay so you have a
developer that can gets training he can
write code hey that's in this hi de he
pushes into the repository you can use a
static analysis solution when you build
and deploy and test you can use an
interactive application security when it
goes to production you can do dynamic
application security testing and with
goes in production you can use a rasp
solution or some self-defense in there
okay and each of them has their pros and
their cons so for example a a training
let's go to static analysis what static
analysis you look at code without
executing the code the good stuff about
static analysis is you can find a lot of
problems from a theoretical perspective
you know you get a you get a lot of
problems and then the bad thing is of
course that people who complain well
there's a false positives there's stuff
that it finds and it's not a real
problem in code so there's it's good in
that so it finds a lot of different
stuff it's gonna give you good coverage
over your code the same time it files
finds false positives and it cannot
really do well with dynamic frameworks
because you can only scan the code that
is there if it's dynamically built
somewhere well it's very hard to scan
the interactive application security
what's interactive application security
it's essentially some some monitoring
solution that sits with the QA people
and it's gonna give them some feedback
on potential problems that they can
further explore ok vast more or less
penetration testing solutions that gonna
treat your application as some sort of a
black box we're gonna send random attack
but not a random attack by attack
vectors because that's the first thing
but it's gonna send well-crafted attack
vectors and it's gonna
what's coming back from that solution
and is gonna decide yes it's a problem
where it's not a problem and the RAF's
runtime application security protection
is really some agent that you install in
your servers and it's gonna monitor
what's going on and if it sees a problem
or if it sees an attack that's gonna try
to block that on the fly so where do we
spend money if you look at these
training IDE help SAS is data and rasp
where do we spend money for some
organizations it looks like like this
they spend a lot on SAS they lose spend
a lot on DAST other organizations spend
more on training and SAS the problem is
nobody knows so so so what I would like
to do in the next couple slides I would
like to go through a couple things and
and figure out where people really spend
the money so first things first
umm what type of company would this be
and don't say my company please because
otherwise we have another problem
what what type of company you know what
and what kind of stage are they what
does management think about security
sorry or a start-up yes was not the
answer that I was hoping for but it
always comes out any any other other
takers what kind of company if it's a
well mature company yes actually that's
right actually this is it's it's the
oldest good company you know or the
company that is not hacked management
there's like well we don't see the need
for security because nothing happens
everything works everybody's happy right
yet what kind of type of company is this
yeah well there's a huge pile of money
you know I'm not sure well I don't have
that pile of money but yeah well that
this is actually Equifax today I think
you know this is the oh company we
got hacks we have to do something you
know we really have to do something and
what they tend to do then is they they
take a bunch of money and they say well
what did they find is it is it is it a
sequence action from wall we really have
to find the sequel injection problems
can we find some white hat hackers and
can we install a program and find more
of this stuff you know they want to find
more of the same stuff making sure it
does not happen any more
and essentially over time it devolves
that company okay so I started with the
company that has has no notion of
security then they get hacked they get a
notion of security or something triggers
it always something that triggers it and
then over time it spreads out so I think
this is this is kind of a view of a lot
of organizations are today and why is
that because they need training for
their PCI compliance sticker there's
really good salespeople in static
analysis that they can sell you anything
Gardner says you really have to put some
money into rasp right now oh I'm sorry
and and garner says you really have to
spend put some money into rasp and you
still have your bunch of money and
penetration testing I think I think a
lot of organizations are in in that
particular situation right now it's the
reality so where do we spend and and
then I went back into into besom because
V M is essentially building security and
maturity model it's it's based on what
actual people do on a day to day basis
so so they collect data and they figure
out what people are doing so iiii i do
not have access to that data
but i do have well everybody has access
to the report that they produce and if
you look into that report I found it
quite interesting to see that for some
of these things you have entire
practices like you have a training
practice you have a code review practice
you have a security testing practice you
have a penetration testing practice and
and then for ASP
I couldn't really figure out where that
really fit in the besom kind of vertical
meaning if you if you look for ASP it's
not even founded in the VM so so it it's
not there yet so people do not spend a
lot of money on that yet maybe they will
I don't know but but the reality is
right now it's it's not the case and
even if you drill a level deeper into
these practices you can find activities
in in all of the levels so they they
split it up in three levels where they
have easy things to do and then people
do quite often things and then really
rocket science things and even within
there you have all these three level
three levels covered for example for
training but also for static analysis
you have all the three levels covered
for dynamic application security and if
you look at is that's that's again
little bit minimal you know you find
include security testing in QA
automation so so based on that based on
on what I see in in in besom I would say
people spend on training on sass and ID
help and a little bit less on ist a lot
on - and very minimal on rasp but this
is this is the state of where we are
right now in application security and
where people spend their money okay but
you know I can say this is not progress
right I'm not making any progress I'm
not telling you what the best ROI
the best way to get some some good ROI
off out of your application security but
okay it only validates that yes we need
to spend money so now I would like to
take a step back and I would like to to
look at what we really do in application
security and what we really do in
application security is is on the right
hand side we have the sequel injections
the or stopped ends really the the
vulnerabilities okay and on the
right-hand side and and if you take
companies that yet have to hacked
through sequel injection they say well
it's in dast we found it in dust and and
and maybe we should bring that closer to
a developer maybe we should make sure
that that we can find that particular
problem very very close to two to
development so this whole notion of
shift left where you try to figure out
what the problem is as close as possible
to the developer right so you start with
finding the sequin injections through
penetration testing the next thing is
say well maybe you should find all
theoretical sequel injections so you go
through a static analysis solution that
finds all theoretical sequel injections
and then you really want to train the
developers making sure they know about
sequel injection so they do not
introduce it so you go you go from right
to left but there's also this notion
that going from left to right where you
really can say well let's introduce
coding guidelines and I found it really
hard to find good coding there are
coding guidelines there are good coding
guidelines don't get me wrong but
there's much more information about
vulnerabilities and attacks and cheat
sheets and all that kind of stuff then
there is around wasps or secure coding
guidelines the Android secure coding guy
there's there's not a whole lot of stuff
in in that area right while I think it's
it's very interesting because what we do
in our industry right now in application
security is
let's say we have a query over here with
four concatenations per meter one by the
way I think this is the only code slide
so for developers I'm sorry this is the
only code slide
you have four parameters parameter four
one two three and four let's say your
penetration testers come back and they
say you know what parameter 1 parameter
2 they are vulnerable to CQ injection
well you know the company is on fire
because it has to be fixed right now we
cannot be hacked through Co injection
and they're gonna instantly ask the
developers to fix the Seco injection and
they will fix that one if your static
analysis solution comes back and they
say well you know parameter 3 maybe if
the stars align in this way then it's
gonna be vulnerable to Co injection at
that point over here it comes you know
you can start your fight between your
application security people your
developers and your QA to really figure
out if it's a problem or not right
because the developers will not say no
no we're not gonna fix it you have to
prove it first and security guys yeah
you have to fix it so the QA comes back
and they you really have to find it an
attack vector to exploit that stuff and
and and everybody's mad at each other
right knowing the answer to the problem
is simply irrelevant fix it and it's not
gonna be a problem
just fix it ok but that's not the way we
work right now and if none of our
solutions point out that parameter 4 is
a problem today we're not gonna fix it
we're not gonna do anything the code is
working leave it as such right um while
tools are incomplete first of all so you
do not know if parameter 4 is really a
vulnerability or not um at the same time
if another developer comes on board
tomorrow um some some guy out of
university that had never heard about
sequel injection and he takes the code
and he copy and paste it into another
location it may also be a vulnerability
right it may become a vulnerability all
right because the context is different
this is how we treat application
security today this is what we do on a
day to day basis we try to find a
problem and we're gonna fix the problem
one by one okay
so there's there's a there's a very big
distinction between finding the
vulnerability and following coding
guidelines if you find the vulnerability
and you run a or you let people in and
they do a pen test or your static
analysis
Ellucian is is not pointing out anything
which which is hardly seen but let's say
your static analysis solution doesn't
show you anything what does that tell
you about the code you don't know you do
not know you know for sure if it's if
it's showing red stuff it's if it's
showing critical vulnerabilities you
know for sure you're in deep trouble but
if it doesn't show you anything you
don't know the only thing you can say is
that tool didn't find anything or these
hackers didn't find anything but you do
not know if your code is secure or not
at the same time if you follow coding
guidelines and you say for example use
parameterised queries always everywhere
okay if you do that you can eradicate
sequel injection because if you do that
on a consistent basis are always
everywhere you can eradicate a category
of vulnerabilities and you can start to
measure it you can start to measure if
you follow coding guidelines if
developers say net this is an exception
I'm not going to do that or if you
bluntly violate a coding guideline and
at that point you can actually compare
applications against each other you can
say well this this piece of code was
developed by group a and they did so
good versus another piece of code
developed by Group B and and they
constantly introduced or not did not
follow coding guidelines so you can get
a sense of how well that application was
developed and you can essentially put a
risk score on there and what what the
problems may be in the future of putting
a production putting an app like that in
production and you can map that back on
onto the previous graph right you can
say well on the right hand side you
really want to find the vulnerability
you can do everything you can with
developers and you can tell them what to
do but eventually you still need that
mechanism so these need to be in balance
I'm not saying that you need to prefer
one over the other because we know how
creative developers are if you tell them
follow these coding guidelines they're
gonna follow the coding guidelines in a
very creative way right and so you still
need that stuff you still need these
mechanisms that find the problems in
code so the whole idea over here is is
um how about making sure that you again
optimize your budget and optimize your
solutions because if you can eradicate
80% of the problems here then the 20%
these solutions are gonna find are
really the heart
problems the stuff that you really want
these tools to find you know you want it
you bought a complex ass solution for
example not to find the easy sequel
injections that's right or you're not
hiring very experienced
penetration or white hat hackers to find
a very simple configuration problem
right so you want to really make sure
that you use the expertise and the
knowledge that these tools and people
have to the most so where do we have to
spend it and I'll circle back to my to
my initial title of the talk which was
3.6 million is the average cost of a
beach and this is actual data this is
actual data from from Jim Ralph and in
in my previous calculation I used the
numbers from aspect security they also
put food out some numbers however there
is no really there's no source of where
that really comes from these are actual
numbers these are these are numbers from
Jim Ralph from Aetna he went through
that exercise he calculated how much it
cost for his organization to fix
something in requirements in design and
code and tests and in maintenance okay
and my feeling is in general I think
there's a general consensus that the
earlier you fix stuff the less it cost
you know putting actual dollar amounts
on there is hard and and this is from
one organization your organization will
be different but it's a good exercise so
what you can do with 3.6 million is you
can wait and and and get hacked and get
that breach and and be the Equifax for
example or you can try to be proactive
because with 3.6 million you can
actually do a lot of stuff for example
in code you can fix with 3.6 million
three thousand six hundred issues okay
so you can wait and fix one problem and
you still have to spend money then to
fix all the other problems or this is a
rough estimate or a rough calculation of
what you can do and how you can spend
your money to go a level deeper if you
say well I want to spend it on
penetration testing and and you you buy
some penetration testing the way you can
calculate this and again I'm just giving
suggestions here
you have to deal for your own
organization because every organization
is different what you can do over here
is you buy 10 days of penetration
testing they find why number of issues
the developer fixes the issues which is
Z numbers and that's a pretty big number
so you divide it through the number of
issues and it's still a big number but
let's fill in the blanks let's say you
spend 20 K on the penetration testing
and they come back with 10 issues and
your developers have no time to fix it
which is essentially a waste of my right
this happens all too often right this
happens really all too often we're just
we're just we'll have the paper you know
and that's it no so you have to fill it
in right you you've there's a developer
cost there's a developer cost or he goes
into the code he has to find the problem
to the to the find find the solution to
the problem you have to fix it go
through the key a that whole thing let's
say $2,000 and times 10 is 40 K so it's
$4,000 an issue pretty big number right
and fill out your own numbers to do this
exercise internally however there's a
side note here these are real issues you
really have to fix them if a penetration
test comes back with sequel injection
it's very likely that attackers know
about that problem too and will sometime
in the future exploit you so even though
it's a high number it's it's justified
if it's good stuff of course I'm a SAS
solution oh one second a SAS solution do
the same exercise I I do not see all I
do not see quite often people doing that
exercise close to none i Jim Ralph did
it for Aetna but other than that I do
not see people doing that within
organizations they just spend money but
they they do not know what the outcome
is of that SAS solution X amount of
dollars issues found y developer needs
to Fox fix it the pretty big number if
you divided through the number of issues
normally a static analysis solution
comes back with a ton of issues it looks
better than penetration testing but then
you go to the theoretical site right
from a theoretical perspective it is
vulnerable to CQ injection okay so
that's another side note the numbers
look better but but it's different
training what can you do for training
the effect on training nobody measures
the effect on training there's there's
very little organizations that know
exactly what the impact of training is
the impact of training you can you they
say we cannot measure that you can
measure that you can measure that you
you figure out how many issues they do
not introduce into the code yes it's
hard to measure that but it is possible
and if there are issues found by your
penetration testing solution by your
static analysis solution can they fix it
if they can you have training effect so
let's see what you need to do is is
measure use you have to start measure
you have to take these numbers
internally you have to look at how much
I spent what the issues are how much it
costs to fix all these things you can
put it in there you have to measure it
you have to calculate your ROI you have
to optimize your budget um what what
I've done throughout the last couple
years was I have a lot of members of
what people spend on solutions and how
many vulnerabilities I introduced and so
on and and what I did this this this
calculation and it's different from from
Jim Ralph's calculation by the way
because if I would use Jim rouse numbers
it would be very different actually it
would be more than my $45 but over here
I I looked into what I have in in terms
of numbers and I figured out that every
day a developer writes code it costs an
additional forty five dollars to fix the
problems that he introduces into the
code which I found very very interesting
so every day that you you pay for it
first of all the developer to write code
and at the same time you have to pay
another forty five dollars to fix the
stuff that he has written in the first
place okay so how can you bring that
number down well first of all you can
get rid of your developers that's the
easy fix right but nobody really wants
to do that okay so you really have to go
through that exercise and you can bring
these numbers down if you spend well if
you make sure that you you you know your
numbers you know exactly where you have
to put more money in and less money in
so that you can optimize everything
across what a developer sees and you can
help them out writing soup
okay I think that's the end of my talk
oh I thought it was 30 and 10 which is
40 so we're running a tournament we're
running a tournament today and what you
can do with that tournament is you you
can actually log in to the spiracle
warrior portal register it's gonna be
we're gonna post it on on social media
or you can take a picture of course that
would be the easiest for you right now
so we should have opened it up at 10:30
which is now okay if you go on there and
you fill out the registry code and you
add there in Benelux 2017 you can play a
tournament you can play against each
other it's it's not a hacking contest no
it's no we we want to we want to educate
developers we want to find problems in
code but also fix problems in code all
right it's a learning exercise so you
don't have to be the top notch expert to
try it out so please do not feel like
well I'm you know I'm not the best in
that no no no that's not the idea the
idea is hey it's a learning experience
go on there try it out and see if you
like it and and in the closing we
actually will give prizes to the number
one two and three in the evening so if
you wanna if you want to play if you
want to learn about how to write secure
code and how to fix issues in code and
you can you can do that today
and with that I would like to open it up
for questions so thank you very much
[Applause]
yes yes I have a question or a comment
absolutely so I really like to talk I
think you thank you great talk but I
think you're not going far too far
enough in your conclusions so what
you're saying is that for example
training is important or that code
guidelines are important but I think we
should go further and we should prevent
vulnerabilities from being introduced
for example you say you we should make a
coding guideline to only use parama
parametrized State sequel statements yes
but I think we should just prevent the
insecure way right why don't we remove I
don't know string based api's from
frameworks so that absolutely dead bugs
cannot even be introduced and I think on
the training point I don't think
training scales because you usually only
need one developer that maybe was ill at
the day of the training or that didn't
pay attention or I just forgot about
what the input was in the training so
instead of I think trainings are
important but instead of training so you
rather should harden stuff and make sure
that developers can't introduce bugs
even if they want to so so I absolutely
agree on on a hardening stuff I do not
agree on training of course because for
obvious reasons but maybe we should talk
and and we should tell you what we do
and on a day to day basis with training
and and continuous training but yes
absolutely on your first point and if we
can fix it in the framework we should
fix it in the framework and make sure it
does not happen the the unfortunate
thing is that we have a lot of legacy
systems and over there your approach
will unfortunately not work so you need
something else so you need to follow
coding guidelines and even if you fix it
up and then over there I call it more of
a refactoring exercise where you're
gonna then refactor your your legacy
code and and if you still can introduce
some some some additional libraries yes
you should do it but you still need to
refactor it and you have to make sure
that you refactor everything over there
and that everything points to that one
library so you still need these coding
guidelines that say don't do it yourself
crypto is a perfect example
don't don't implement your own crypto
and if you have done it well if you
it and you want to get rid of it in you
installed with it with a new system and
you have to make sure that nobody uses
it anymore because it's surprising how
often it's so widespread within the
organization and this team is using and
that team is using and suddenly
everybody is using it so replacing it
can be really really tricky but yes I
agree 100% with your statement the first
one yes have the mic so I have I have a
comment and a question
okay the comment is a thank you for a
presentation I found it's very too much
black and white yeah you see we have
right the red squares and green squares
I think as my colleague I guess we
should go further if a father even
laughter and the question my mind is
that maybe you should if you do kind of
tread modeling and if the code
requirements should be able even to not
have unsecure code from the beginning
because the guy the developer won't
write this code this is a comment and a
question is from your experience what do
you think is the best ratio between all
these boxes no so so I see that my
colors may be indeed a little bit more
black black and white that was not
that's also that is not intentional so I
think you really have to spend across
all these solutions because again you
will not you will not solve the world
with with training you will not solve
the world with penetration testing you
will not solve the world with with one
SAS solution no I I i well to give you
to give you an example when when I was
at fortify we ran a test and you were
trying to figure out what the web
inspector Lucien was finding versus what
the static analysis solution was finding
and what the overlap was between the two
well it's it's different tools they find
different stuff so so that was a quite
interesting in the exercise that's why
I'm saying you have to spend across
across the SDLC let's put it that way
what's the best way to spend it depends
on your organization it really depends
on your organization it depends on your
culture it depends on your technologies
that you're using it also depends on
what you've already invested in in
security solutions some some
some organizations have made bad choices
but then customized the solution in such
a way that it was is workable and
switching that out and another solution
in is hard so I cannot give you an
answer to that question that's why I'm
giving you a lot of options here how to
do it within your own own organization
but it it it it has to be across
everything that's one thing that I'm
sure of
and then you have to look at all the
different things in your own
organization to make sure you spend
optimal in an optimal way hey thanks for
great presentation in very welcome my
question there are two questions in fact
first how did you arrive at 45 that's a
pretty large number for a medium-sized
company with around 200 or 300
developers not to talk about large
enterprises second part of the question
is have you tried of rough solutions and
have they any impact in reducing this
number yes so so and so so first of all
on fortify I when I when I when I I
moved to the US and I joined fortify as
a researcher the way I got in there was
my PhD was around static analysis and I
was finding so I was actually
transforming a low-level code from from
from being totally clean to obfuscated
code and then trying to Diab the skate
and the way we did that was through
binary rewriting and for that we used
static analysis but the general concept
was was the same you use static analysis
you you do dataflow analysis to find
things in code so the way I rolled into
fortify was really through my PhD
through my through my through my static
analysis knowledge I'm have I word on on
rasp solution actually I did so
initially I started at fortify doing
more of the static analysis stuff and in
the end I owned essentially all the
runtime solutions which contained a rasp
solution which is now called HP defender
or something like that so yes I've
worked on on rasp solutions my
experience with rasp solutions is you're
holding the hot potato so your
throughout this entire cycle you're
gonna put an agent in production and
you're holding the hot potato because if
if it still comes through you
that attack and you say I'm gonna
protect against sequel injection and I
don't know what the legal consequences
is but but for sure I know you're
holding the hot potato that that that's
one thing lasting on rasp solutions it's
really really hard to get that
introduction it's really really hard to
convince the people to put an additional
piece of software in your production
machines that's gonna do security things
so if if you can get there good but from
my experience a lot of organizations see
that more as putting additional software
additional risk in production and
actually preventing risk yeah thanks
very much for that interesting talk I
quickly want to emphasize that point was
that we really need to help the
developers in developing securely my
experience is actually there in the last
year's it's more the situation that they
want to develop securely I it's a long
time ago that I had discussions about
not fixing it back mmm-hmm
maybe I'm belonging to no those few
people that actually did that money
calculations within the company I was
working for okay gives an interesting
insight I can really recommend to do
that but if you do that don't only look
at the money of the tools that you are
required of buying look all set your
internal costs in your internal
processes absolutely um I wouldn't be
surprised if you learned that by
optimizing your internal processes you
can say if much much more than but using
licensing costs for an external tool or
an external security audit absolutely no
and I think that so this this was a
little bit too - a slimmed down version
of my calculation of course but yes what
I what I try to slip in there was yes
you have that developer cost but in that
developer cost is essentially all the
cost that you need to fix a problem in
code so yes couldn't agree more
so I'm not a make so I'm trying to
figure out if my view of the world is so
if you look at the books of Vegard
McGraw he buys the feature set of the
codes of two arrows are actually
cortical box but the other half of
structural flaws exactly and so if I'm
correct you
focused mostly on the box absolutely yes
but we are the risk analysis and often
no no absolutely no no you're right so
so there's there's bugs and there's
flaws I totally focus on the bugs
because some of these solutions like
static analysis solutions also claim to
find flaws but that's not what they're
made for they're really made for finding
bugs so this kind of system did the
stuff that I outlined today works really
really well for for finding bugs in the
code because that's these are the
developer mistakes if you think about
floss yeah you really have to do threat
modeling architectural risk analysis and
that's more of a manual process I'm not
really aware of any good tools that can
help you in in doing a deep analysis and
there's there's definitely tools that
can help you with with architectural
risk analysis and threat modeling and
and and and you can put some data in
there so you have a good idea of what's
going on and and what you need to do
from a from a threat modeling
perspective and finding the flaws but
it's it's it's different it's it's still
a manual process you have to feed that
data into that model and that model will
then help you finding the flaws in your
system so it is very very different so I
I I do not have a good answer to you
what kind of I I'm not the expert in
that kind of field I'm I've done some of
that during my time at fortify doing
doing threat modeling but I'm not the
expert in that kind of field but it's a
different thing it's also not a
developer focus thing developer is more
taking on what the architect is saying
for for finding flaws it's more an
architectural problem where you need
your design people to get into one room
have a whiteboard draw some pictures and
make sure that the flaws are not there
yes yes that's right this is this is
100% I talk about finding the bugs in
the code there for one more question
quick one every surgeon for coffee all
right
you
[Music]