first off I want to welcome everybody my
name is Greg Hetrick I kind of took the
point on organizing this year's event so
hopefully it's a good one eBay has fun
turn the song so first off welcome so we
wanted to look a little bit of number so
that's not 2014 uh supposed to be 2012
we had a hundred three registered 70
attended 2013 we had 175 registered 203
attended that one was in Dubuque first
one was in Ames 2015 was at DMACC here
in town we had about 150 attended and so
far this year we had 177 registered at
the time we took down registration on
Thursday just so we could get numbers
for catering and whatnot so hopefully we
get a pretty good crowd looks like
there's quite a few in here so that's
good next thing I wanted to talk about
many of you know ken Johnson passed away
right before last year's event
he was the lifeblood of besides Iowa he
started it in 2012 and he kept it going
even after he moved to Chicago and he
kept in touch with folks in town and so
we really thank his contributions to the
insec community Iowa and the B sides
Iowa self we're also really really
blessed to have Ken's wife Jessica in
his daughter Savannah they were running
the registration booth and they're here
today to help out because they really
really like to to get involved with with
the things that Ken was doing here in
Iowa second thing was David Jones
so David Jones many nomás rants he
worked with besides Iowa as well he
worked at principal with with Ken and he
ran the lockpick village at the first
several b-sides he passed away in
October of 2012 from cancer and and last
year when they when they were going to
work when they're organized
besides 2016 Ken and reach out to Ryan
and said hey we want to do something for
David so we kind of wanted to
incorporate into this year's event so
for David just see it on your badges
just a notice that we really appreciate
what they did for us
another thing we kind of wanted to touch
on so right after last year's event was
canceled the folks up at miss conf in
Minneapolis reached out and said hey
guys you know we're sorry to hear about
what happened we really want to you know
reach out and help you any way we can
so they gave us you know those who are
registered last year we sent on an email
they give us free tickets to their
conference of Minneapolis which was
awesome I know several of us went it was
a great time so I wanted to give a shout
out to this year's event which is at the
end of October it's a really really good
time it was a great kind of community
feel of van lot like b-sides are they
did a great job I know Tom was there and
several others and we really enjoyed it
so I want to go to those guys a shout
out they also helped help me get the bad
just put together and I had questions
for him about different things they
helped us with that so again shout out
to those guys for everything they did I
also want to just one slide for Karen
Beal she actually designed our logo her
husband James helped us do some
organizing so I wanted at least give her
some acknowledgement for for the awesome
work she did on the new logo sponsors so
many of you know besides is a community
driven event we don't exist without the
help of sponsors every one of these
sponsors contributed time or money to
help us put on this event this is how
we're paying for lunch this is how we
got the t-shirts this is how we got this
venue thread connect at the bottom and
I'll talk about this in a minute they
stepped up late this week and said hey
we want to help with an after-party so
there will be an after-party it's at
five one five Brewing Company over in
Clive they're just going to give us a
lot of money the only caveat is there's
no food there but it's gonna be later in
the day so grab food they said bring it
in and it'll be fine
the folks who own that brewery we found
out are actually intersect guys so it
was great to kind of help the community
out locally as well so anyway there's
several of them have booths LRS has a
booth cyber reason has a booth Titus
they're not here yet but they were gonna
have a booth so you know stop by say hi
check them out you know see what they
got and thank him for their support and
no starch actually sent us a pile of
books everybody should got a raffle
ticket when they checked in will raffle
off but they give us books free e-book
vouchers oh there's something else I got
to get out there they also gave us 30%
off coupons and I'll set those out the
registration desk and you can grab those
when you get there I forgot to set those
out this morning here's thank you to all
of our individual donors so when you
when you registered you had the
opportunity to give an individual
donation and these are the folks that
did and and we said we'd give you
at the venue we really appreciate those
donations as well
they were great yeah we really liked it
you know the community comes together
and kind of helps ya you know helps
support these events Nick is here Nick
Stark is here from sec DSM they actually
are sponsoring our CTF in our lockpick
village and he's here to give a little
bit info about what's going on there
it's gonna be awesome so make sure you
get time check it out hi I'm Nick stark
with sec DSM we have a CTF going on in
room 150 it's down there by the radio
station kinda in the wall so come down
and check it out
registration is open at CTF datsuk DSM
dot org and the competition starts at
10:00 and starts at 10:00 goes to goes
to 6:00 and I just want to thank all the
people who were involved with setting
that up there was seven or eight of us
who got together and set up 41 different
challenges for you and it was it was
quite a bit of work so thank you to
everyone who was involved with that come
on out to room 115 we'll see you there
challenges toll are there 41 challenges
there's str challenges right there's
post forensic challenges there's pen
testing challenges a little bit of
everything in that thing yeah those guys
really put together a ton of work and
SEC the Ascend for those probably
several here involved with that anyway
so they might know more about it than I
do
okay a few housekeeping things restrooms
there's some restrooms just over here
that way there's restrooms at that end
of the hall as well the lounge this
lounge space over here is not used for
anything and they said we are free to
use it so you guys wanna hang out there
chat whatever you can use that room or
you know any other space around here
lunch
so everybody suit I got a lunch ticket
that's upstairs just up these stairs or
up the elevator over here that'll get
you I think it's like a buffet style
lunch that they'll have up there again
paid for by our sponsorship dollar so we
appreciate those ticket we'll break for
lunch from noon to 1:00 so and we have
so that the lunch
was split into two there's a small one
to the left and there's a great big room
to the right the great big room to write
is all ours t-shirts so we closed
registration for a day to get t-shirt
sizes so we have sizes for everybody who
registered before April 1st I did we
ordered 100 they were 120 people have
registered at that point I ordered 200
t-shirts so we have plenty of shirts so
I think I wanted to make sure everybody
who registered at a time got got a shirt
that that they rated before but I think
we're gonna have plenty so here at about
11 o'clock if you didn't get a shirt if
you registered after that deadline did
get a shirt go out there and get one
recordings so evidencing came in from
Atlanta we thanked him and he is doing
all our recordings for us we have
recordings of both tracks and we'll get
those up on YouTube whenever he gets
time we're not gonna rushing tomorrow
good lord tomorrow or Monday Wow we'll
have them up there so if you guys didn't
get it now if you can watch everything
again it's awesome or if you missed one
of the two talks no starch vouchers I
mention those though I'll set the third
soft coupons down on the table so grab
one when you happen to walk by the
registration table at some point and
then we'll action off for a raffle off
the rest at the end of the at the end of
the bed the Wi-Fi network I had it up on
here earlier but that's the Wi-Fi
network a password for this facility so
you can use that that's that that's it I
left myself 20 minutes Wow that was
enough time so we'll take a few minutes
we'll get our first presenter up and
going and we'll start to start her at 10
o'clock so take a break and we'll get
started