yeah
so what exactly are vulnerabilities your
flaws in the software that we don't know
about yet they could lead to an external
attack or gaining access to your system
for the cyber grand challenge
the game is focused on what we call
memory corruption vulnerabilities a
buffer overflow is one type of memory
corruption a memory disclosure
vulnerability or heat buffer overflow
are all different types of memory
corruption vulnerability to a computer
at its heart is a processor and some
memory in a modern computer you know
that you have a hard drive and you have
ram which is memory and you have a
processor or a computer turns on it
reads the data the code that needs to
execute off of the hard drive into
working memory into the ram module
because this is faster and the processor
then interacts with it then a buffer is
simply a logical contract it's a piece
of memory that has been dedicated for
one particular purpose by the program
so let's um go over a classic
stack-based buffer overflow
if I'm a program and the first thing I
do is say hello what is your name
you're going to tell me your name hockey
ok so in this program I've allocated a
particular area of memory on the stack
called a buffer right
why is that program is operating another
thing that puts in this area of the
stack is a pointer this is what it's
going to do next
so I'm the program i say well i'm going
to ask him his name but after i asked
him his name
I'm going to tell him his zip code so i
say hello what is your name instead of
you saying back
Hakeem you say back Hakeem and i live on
fourth ave and I have a lot of friends
and give me all your secret data and
that gets overwritten on my stack and
instead of after I ask your name instead
of going back and saying okay I'm going
to tell you your zip code
I say oh here's all my secret data
so we talk about what a buffer is the
stack buffer overflow
what is he what's the difference the
heat is a more general purpose area of
memory on the heap
it will be dynamically allocated and
used by the program is operating
we don't know specifically what's on the
heat there's no common usage of it
there's a buffer on the heap user data
comes in and writes pass into that
buffer but what's different is on a heap
what's after the end of that buffer
sometimes a buffer overflow can have no
effect whatsoever
sometimes an overflow just crashes a
computer most people see the blue screen
of death
yes yes that's typically a result of
some type of memory corruption but an
extension was written in openssl to
allow computers to say hey are you still
there
so we know the server is still up the
connection is still there
so a client can send a packet to the
server the server just repeats that data
back to the client
yes I'm still here here's your data well
there's a link field that comes at the
beginning of that data so the client
says I'm going to send you ten bites
here's your headlights they go to the
server the services oh you sent me ten
bites
here's your 10 bikes there was a
vulnerability an error in the way that
was written so a client could send a
packet the said hey give me 400 bites
but it only had ten bites on it
packet comes in the server goes oh you
said you sent me four hundred bites
here's 400 bites here's the 10 you gave
me
and then here's 390 bites of secrets and
it's not that packet back
it's a very straightforward and very
simple one of the things that's very
interesting and very compelling about
vulnerability research and expectation
is that creativity and that uniqueness
of every vulnerability
researchers once they find a
vulnerability
then they produce what we call a proof
of concept but actually gain code
execution on the Machine through using
this vulnerability and the way to do
that might be really bizarre
it might be really unique
it might be really difficult to find I
see so with the cyber Grand Challenge
turbines thrown down the gauntlet and
said we have got to bring software in to
solve this problem we've got to have
automated reasoning systems that can
respond to threats in real time but also
find these vulnerabilities both for the
software ever gets filled in the first
place
ok