a lot of critical infrastructure started
being controlled by computers
the power grid became more dependent on
computers
water you know delivery systems
communication systems
I mean again back then a few people had
cell phones for tech x is a
collaboration between a university and
Industry the program analysis power of
Ithaca New York's grandma tech
corporation a team of hacking demux from
the University of Virginia the joint
force is a few years ago to develop an
automatic software hardening technology
preventing exploits of software of
uncertain provenance they call it
pea soup pea soup technology is already
competition ready
having demonstrated its robustness and
effectiveness under independent test and
evaluation now they're developing a
cyber reasoning system they call Sandra
so it was kind of this natural melding
of talent we have strengths in the area
of taking programs and modifying them
you have to prevent you know
vulnerabilities from being exploited so
it was kind of this natural melding of
talent
it was interesting because they had
strengths in the area of doing symbolic
execution symbolic execution is a
different way to study software rather
than laying out a map of tests and
decisions symbolic execution build a
giant mathematical equation that
processes input in the same way as the
software being studied these equations
get very big very fast and can be
difficult to solve
I consider myself a hacker on think I'm
a pretty good one
there's both white hat hacking and black
hat hacking and you know we're really
focused on the white hat hacking
it's important to understand how these
attacks work because how can you defend
against them if you don't understand how
that works
cyber Grand Challenges a security
competition
it is trying to develop automated
systems to play this game of breaking
into other systems and defending from
other systems breaking into you
DARPA was very clever and how they
structure this
so they don't have to come up with test
to see how strong our defenses are the
other competitors are doing that
so that's kind of cool right now we're
testing each other's defenses by
attacking each other
the both sides the white hat and the
blackheads
our goal is to create a tool that can
automatically protect software systems
gives Andres exceeds the tech ex white
hat hackers can ride off with a
two-million-dollar prize
yeah