yeah
so basically what ass that was
hey mom let's say that I was taking exam
and this exam was are initiated by . by
about my group cuts cuts easy and I said
wow that that that's cool
although she doesn't really know what
did you see this that's a yes
meet shellfish a student-led team from
the University of California Santa
Barbara of all the reasoning systems
competing in the final event the
shellfish system has some of the
youngest architects the computer
security version of capture the flag is
just like the game you played as a kid
but the flags are made of data in the
field is made of brand new code
it's the job of CTF competitors to
reverse engineer that code to explore
and heal its weaknesses
- general courses quite old I think
they're the oldest CTF team now that
that kind of still exists
I we we always played a lot of cts and
when this you see was announced the
thinking was like holy cow this is the
future of hacking right
shellfish is the hacking team for UCSB
sec lab the school's computer security
research group their cyber reasoning
system
mechanical fish is their cyber combatant
in the CGC final event
it's powered by anger a software tool
box used to build systems that analyzed
computer code at the deepest binary
level
what is anger anger is a framework for
analyzing binary software
it focuses on both static and dynamic
symbolic execution
making it applicable to a variety of
analytic tasks
what you're doing when you're hacking is
you take a binary that just knows how to
walk and you make it dance right and so
we are building a robot that
automatically finds these binaries and
make some fans
the group's research focus is on
programming intrusion detection and as
our Internet of Things grows the chances
of program vulnerabilities increases the
team wants to stop smart home invasions
think one of the big things have this
competition is humans make mistakes
humans can't accurately find all falls
and programs or verify that their secure
and so we need machines that can do this
and machines that can help take a load
off humans and I think this will be one
of the big important improvements in
making appears more secure for users
if mechanical fish can control anger
team shellfish will take home the two
million-dollar prize