throughout designing our system for the
cyber grand challenge one of our many
concerns is how can we apply this to the
real world and the first thing that
comes to mind is you know
defending our own systems in defending
the systems of those who employs is
ultimately we have a lot of events every
year that compromise people's personal
information and it's our efforts and
CDC's and are possessed roots and all
the teams that are competing in darkness
event that will ultimately defend people
from these attacks when he had a
revolution to really get to a safe for
cyberspace
otherwise you will still keep hearing
all of the best story dissect a computer
security team working out of a
technology incubator in Athens Georgia
is building a cyber reasoning system
crispy to compete in the cyber Grand
Challenge capture the flag tournament
our team is involved in playing capture
the flag competitions and that computer
security face and for this challenge
we've set out to try and compete by
designing a cyber reasoning system a
cyber reasoning system
crs creates its own knowledge
autonomously searching code for flaws
then writing its own intrusion detection
signatures and security patches that are
definitely two types of people that do
these kind of calendar there's the
people do the official academic way they
do theory and there's the people that
play the CTF like us actually do it
manually we actually look at the bynars
we play the games and for this approach
we needed both of those and i think our
team has a component for each one of
those and we put them together in a
single system
and I think that we apply several skills
& Beyond software engineering we also
have a lot of strength and in the
reverse engineering and other tools that
we need to to compete
whether it's rebuilding a car engine or
figuring out how a computer program
works
people can learn about many things
simply by taking them apart and putting
them back together again
sometimes with changes that in a
nutshell is the idea behind reverse
engineering breaking something down in
order to understand it in the cyber
Grand Challenge automated systems will
try to find the broken parts fix or
replace them and add defenses and then
put the program back together but I
think that's probably one of our most
important assets is just our dedication
and that there's something intangible
about the dick addictiveness of CTF and
i think that the same goes for the cyber
grand challenge for DARPA and that it's
addictive and you have to have a amount
of dedication to apply yourself to
software engineering tasks in this case
it's just computer to computer that's
more of an equal playing around
if Chris pecan crunch the numbers
dissect will take home the two
million-dollar prize
yeah