[Music]
[Laughter]
welcome everybody
hello welcome everybody so which
probably closed the doors and start it's
already 16 v 3 53 52 first of all this
is six load just in case you're in the
wrong place make sure this is what you
want to be we have a minute taker Thank
You Dominique right there yeah and I
believe we have a jabber scribe as well
Thomas thank you so I think we're all
set
make sure you see the knot well this is
just to see if you're awake
actually you may have noticed this is
not the very latest and greatest not
well that doesn't matter
you have to be aware of the very latest
ingredients not well it was recently
updated I didn't actually manage to do
it on time but doesn't matter you have
to be aware of the very latest and you
can always get that on the printer
agendas and on the ITF webpage etc so
make sure you understand this something
you don't agree with it then you should
leave this is our agenda for today it
looks a little packed but I think we
should have at least in theory a little
bit of time left at the end which is
good with because we have sort of a
discussion plan for the very end so if
we have any extra time I'm sure we'll be
able to use it but basically we're gonna
have an update to 6lowpan & D which is
actually a collection of about three
documents with Pascal and then younggren
will use an update on the applicability
and use cases for six lo we have Charlie
on packet expiration transmission of
ipv6 packets or PLC and then we have a
new proposal for body area networks 15.6
I Sajjad and then at the end we have
Pascal again and with with the chairs we
can moderate session in total there will
be like 40 minutes so Pascal start with
some requirements and then we can have
more like an open discussion hopefully
with some folks from transport as well
summarizing status since Chicago we have
three new RFC's so that you le now
became our CA t-105 the Lobeck document
now is 8163 and not that it was a
working group document officially but we
definitely benefit from it this is draft
queuing given n on a to the 15 ie became
80 137 and as we had announced in
Chicago we actually went forward and
carried through and dropped the mesh
link establishment effort that we were
undertaking
partly or quite
in large part due to interest through
from Jupiter mesh and Zig mean and since
they no longer needed it and we didn't
get the required update then we dropped
it and then we do everybody was fine
with that status of document since
Chicago we have well back on router
you'll see an update on that that's the
long going and if see we will see a an
update by Singapore so we don't have one
right now but by Singapore incorporating
more comments etc a P and B is also part
of the quote unquote 6075 update which
Pascal will tell us about a little bit
more the other interesting one was
Bluetooth le mesh and we could have had
an update this time around but the
authors are very wisely
they say decided that it probably made
sense to wait for implementation
experience that's always a very good
reason to wait for a little bit more so
implementation experience we should have
maybe something by Singapore hopefully
or and the applicability and use case
we'll see an update now and of course I
mean 6775
update itself the main document there is
what's updated with working with
comments after that we actually issued a
working a blessed call which finish
about a week ago and there were no
comments during that period but I
understand some people are still
thinking of sending comments in so but
it looks looks reasonable and that's
that's pretty much it for status so
unless anybody has any agenda bashing we
can go forward Pascal
ah I'm not gonna insert anything here I
just saved next to no yeah keep the
laser okay so this is pascal chiba from
cisco so i will talk to you about our
suite of drafts which basically stands
from the RSC 6775 half date and yen goes
all the way to the backbone router and
the address protection drafts next slide
please so we have extracted the RFC 67
75 draft from the backbone wattle draft
they were both in the same place
initially and so we have extracted what
truly updates the RFC versus what is the
new proxy operation so basically the RFC
6725 update can be seen as early as free
association process where as the
backbone router is like a proxy
operation what does the router do to act
as a layer 3 proxy for neighbor
discovery next slide please
so status of the draft a refresher was
published late June so there's a number
of cleanup activities which took place
there was this big review that Samhita
published on the mailing list and we
acted on that we removed the text which
explained how you can avoid sending both
ripple dowels and Dadich and the this
being addition being made on the basis
that this should be a separate document
which really says focuses on savings you
can make when you get both on the same
network but this document is exclusively
about ng so the reference is to repower
are gone will have to write them
somewhere else we might have been too
efficient in doing this because well ok
well point is there is one important
thing which is the operation of the
sequence counter
and now it's rap so it's initialized how
it's reinitialized etc when you reboot
and all these text was actually a
reference to the past sequence in RFC
6550 you do the same as this as we
remove the references to 6550 now we
don't have any more operation of this
sequence counter so we are missing that
text and we have to find to decide how
we reinsert it either I say reference to
65 50 or we copy the text
so our RFC self-contained but it's it's
a clear goal that it obeys the exact
same rules because you need to be able
to use one or the other but not having
sent two messages in a ripoff already we
we have added two versions ago the
recommendation cos tend to use 7400 to
expose the capability to do this new
draft now we can live without it but
it's better and clearer to announce that
through new bits in that draft that this
capability spoiled there was also a need
for the address protection draft to
provide an additional status code which
means that the which basically returns
that the proof that was given for the
security token is not accepted and so
this data is provided sure but the
action and the status is in the a P and
D Draft and we had we separated the
privacy discussion from the security
consideration so we have to now those
two separate it the security
consideration is the usual security
saying and all the text which says oh by
the way we don't tell you how you build
an address we place no constraints and
what you do but if you do it please make
sure you further the privacy
recommendations this is now its own
section by the way there is at least one
implementation I've seen - I don't know
if the second one is complete the
document was ready for Lesko it was
actually last call I thought I'd fix
that slide so I'm confused
maybe I wrote it on the different slide
for each last call we do we finished
last call there are not so many con
some of them I received on directly so I
asked the author to publish them on the
mailing list it was not done so please
consider that is not completely complete
and sure this commands are published and
there we go for this side slide please
I know it's not the right slides yes
this one is correct that's a second
draft but I was supposed to be
presenting 61st no that's me mom when
Senate asked me to send them separately
so the old deck with everything in it is
difficult
yeah I think I got your three yes and
that is one of the reading this is the
second one of three and this is the
third a no two three with this as you
want once like and score it from the
website there's only one slide so what
these are the three year these are the
three years on and the attention back
nor others these are the new ones that's
the one it's opening act it doesn't do
anything because it's already open and
this one hollering I wanna swap yeah
mascot I can take the next person on I
didn't know a little eager that's all
you wonder that okay yep shut up reason
the slides to give whatever what do you
want make sure they're there yeah yeah
just burn up your work
oh not this one this do you have one
yeah okay that's how it's been like
[Music]
so for the people remote including
Samhita like Pascal is just switching
slides yeah some little background about
the whole work yes we are at the
crossroad of wireless around ipv6 and on
both sides there were expectations
requirements that was round about the
fence on what basically a start group
expected from the other
for instance ipv6 has design service did
multicast with these requirements that
there would be a twenty power of 24
multicast groups to make it perfectly
efficient but on the other hand those
groups were never the capability to
twelve this number of multicast group
was never present on their Tripoli side
meaning that it has always been
broadcasted as opposed to multicast it
that never prevented and it work but
that that kind of creates limit to the
applicability and efendi to experimental
e 10,000 the order of 10,000 nodes right
which this limitation rate comes from
the fact that multicast is broadcasted
now on whereas it's stringently
different now in a general manner net
India requires a very reliable multicast
or broadcast operation even if it's a
broadcast it needs to be very reliable
because that's how we discover address
duplication and as it goes we we all
know that due to some laws of physics
certainly the wireless will never
provide that cheap reliable multicast is
not something that radio can provide so
suddenly 49 48 62 cannot operate as
decide on ratios which boils down to the
fact that if it appears to work it's
mostly because the entropy of ipv6
addresses makes it so that the collision
is very rare
not because ipv6 operates as designed
okay
so this is basically the expectation
from the IDF and what yet Tripoli should
have or should be doing but that was
never present on the Tripoli side now
the same effect exists on the other side
as well there are those expectations
that the actually has an IDF which were
never really there in particular in that
era when you read that Wi-Fi recommends
that a proxy operation is performed on
the IP 4 and the up as it goes we have
never specified this operation and so we
have resorted to proprietary
implementations to decide how exactly a
proxy would operate in that particular
context and the one thing which which
certainly does not exist that cannot be
done without a standard is the
equivalent of the Association because
what those implementations do is that
they snoop nd and DHCP eventually they
resolve the traffic if nothing else
works and based on that they discover
that the certain address is present on a
certain IP and that's the way all these
proxy operation is kicked off basically
we now use
RFC 6775 update as the layer 3
Association process where has the
backbone router is the proxy and the
operation process so we are finally can
bridging the gap between a Triple E and
IETF and providing the missing link
which really enables a proper operation
of ntp over radios exactly so this I
already presented next thank this
already said ok and then this one has
the correct dates in it so like like I
was saying we have address
we are there go back yeah so now this is
what I was trying to say on the previous
slide where which is this is the pointer
to the last long review that we had on
this document and so we had the
disparity discussion we were a bit too
efficient in removing the some text
about the tid we have removed the text
that enables the DAO story for title to
refresh the DAR state and we passed
working with let's go okay it makes like
these so like I said I get some private
commands will address them but as the
auto computed earliest otherwise and for
like it just said we probably need to
point again on 6550 or to copy the text
which described how the sequence counter
is initiated know the lollipop thing and
all that sort of thing and dude question
for the chairs if do we have enough
review to call it victory or do we need
more oh well good time daddy one thing
you know on the how to restore the
information that was taken out I would
much rather I would vote for having a
self-contained document because if if
you have a pointer there for something
that would end up being normative ripple
and you are implementing something as
don't do with ripple because possibly
this could be a more general facility
you don't want ripple to be normative
great
so anyone the document is to be
self-contained so they'll be mine
so we lost the author of that text in
repo if he can copy
give me the text yes okay that's dark
I'll do it righto from Robbie so the
update allows the proxy to register to
the six proxy base registration 266 bbr
is what I understand right so extended
ero your option allows epoxy based
registration a proper registration to
the proxy on the arm of the target okay
there were proxy appears twice first
years we read it for instance why
five devices could register to the AP
acting as early as water for the to get
the proxy and the operation so that the
first occurrence of the word proxy there
is second occurrence that there were
proxy I think you're talking about the
second one whereby the root of the repo
dyrdek can proxy the registration to the
proxy on behalf of all the nodes which
it learns repo and maintains for repo so
that's why it's so important that this t
ID operation is aligned to the operation
in repo basically in normal run time you
won't see the dark periodically you will
just see the tail periodically but the t
ID inside the DAO that the root receives
will allow the root to maintain the
prompt the state on behalf of the
registrar cannot know the target Norgren
yes so that's why he one of the big
changes that we have in this document
versus 6725
is that we registered the target as
opposed to the source because the root
of the report do dag is the source of
the packet but what's being registered
is the target actually it's in my mind I
mean at least mine it's kind of quite
consistent with the usual use of a
target so I'm pretty happy with that
judge so you know the next question for
me from me would be is it even possible
from 6bb are to be register on behalf of
the target to what Budi register like we
have the box of registration now yeah
yeah sure if you get a no path now no no
I don't think the spec allows you to do
add to do that I'm sorry but I have some
text on that I just don't remember what
I wrote the reason why it gets
complicated is because of the di di
edition of the t ID now it has an
Associated state information which it
arrived matron so which has a lifetime
but we have to think it's true whether
it would be a good idea that thou with a
lifetime zero and no path now creates
their registration or not and and out of
my mind right now I don't remember the
arguments there are some and they are in
the draft I think I discussed that case
but they don't remember
can we take that yeah sure sure yeah
thank you so Pascal like using that
resulting changes in the draft are I
don't know yet can we integrate that I
say what question this is part of
working new bless call so okay so then
and the fourth common comments educated
so Raul let's have this discussion
remaining let's just clarify i I think
there is text on that because I kind of
remember writing it I just don't
remember what the arguments was so I
thought remote conclusion is if you
disagree with what the text that's in
document then please raise main on the
mailing list and we sorted out this is
Sarita Oscar hmm so I was referring to
Pascal's question and whether we should
explain the working group last fall may
I suggest that maybe we could after he
publishes the next revision maybe we
could have a short extension for one
week for people to review does that make
sense
maybe gaben Suresh what do you think
would that be semi terrifying question
would that be you know dependent on the
amount of changes that are put there
right because I was asked yet what my
question was not spared correctly my
question was do we think we have enough
review during this well group last call
to call it victory it was not about
commands relation that's how I
understood it and I mean I'm ok with
waiting a little bit more because we
know there are comments for coming it
would be a shame to not allow them to
come in I mean it's just a few more to
show yeah let's just wait for those
comments come in and then and then we'll
deal with whatever happens just like any
other word unless called there are too
many changes will do another work let's
go sounds good
[Music]
this is so you're going to the backbone
router of this one no all right so like
I said the the RC 67-72 update extends
the operation of the update from a bad
operation to a registration operation
for services such as proxy and e in the
future we may decide to use it to
register all our things but at this
moment its proxy indeed the bad man
router is the proxy and the operation to
which the update enables the
registration to next time okay so
actually I just published refresh
because the document was reaching time
out we have a we have an implementation
it has been demonstrated several times
at the ATF including at the 60s black
test with with a client by tomorrow I
the way certainly we could use more
implementation certainly I would love to
see more Interop in particular would
love to see a open source backbone
router implementation to test the
interpolation between two backbone
routers on the backbone because what
really happens is when you've got a
mobile device Wi-Fi or 6lowpan
that moves from one 6bb off to another
6bb also moves from ripple dag triple
deck which and and they are different
6lv are now the two 6ld are need to
agree on where the devices and that's
part of the spec does right enabling
movement I have not tested that with
another implementation certainly because
I only have mine so I would love to see
another implementation and and play with
it but that's where we are
I also asked I Tripoli in particular
dirty lever and experts to review those
two specs so this is happening
we'll see what pops up on the mailing
list my goal being you know this was
enough reviewed for the 15 for world I
would like to have an assessment of the
dirty Levin world just so if
if they see you know if you change those
three bytes this all these two words
this would be applicable to my face that
it's not like that that would be bad so
so I've asked that but otherwise for I'm
concerned I mean seems that this is well
already for well complies called in very
stable in any reaction there nobody pops
up yes I'm doing an open source
implementation now yes you where I know
I know I rehabbed almost is almost any
good enough okay
well we haven't formed that's when I
guess and then there is the address
protection okay and besides I see you're
in the room so please champion if
there's anything you want to add to what
I'm saying so certainly this is the
third piece of our story this is how we
perform source address validation which
is savvy because we have this state in
the 6lv are we can validate including a
crypto state we can validate that the
user of an address is the one which
registered it in the first place we can
validate that when a dirt was moved the
new place were the new device which
claims the address at the new place is
the same as the old device and we can
validate that with some cryptographic
exchange proof of ownership basically of
a token which was given the first
registration that's pretty much what it
is so we can have revamped it quite a
bit to be honest its editorial but we
have removed a lot of extraneous text in
appendix so there is a lot less
normative text which normally would help
later in the process we have I did this
section about updating your C 675 and we
claim that were review already for a
review by at least first review by
situated direct right for which the
chairs basically called around a sterile
cleanin who has been helping us a lot in
many situation if it is and it was an
experiment fifteen five if you need for
security
you know well someone was that the best
time but we expect that only after
summer will take will get the feedback
from zero again any question we have to
what we have to get moving because
actually took a lot of time
so next on the agenda the young moon
would be applicability a news case
hopefully I have the right slide since
time okay
hi my name is Jung Geun hyung so I
pretend they're sick throw up capability
and use cases okay this is the history
or you know or we discuss from this
issue from IP f-89 meeting three years
ago
so we present our first individual
thread and idea from 94 meeting and we
the working group adoption was done in
the last year so this is the second
revision so I would like to focus of the
goal of this document or this document
the goal is to help sick throw secret
instead of the patient by layer to
contain technology and help a newcomer
understand how six Lawrence Tech can be
applicable in practice so useful you odd
adapter oh I okay at idea so in this
revision we try to include some
practical six row technology so it is
the shuhite mesh and ricin so to update
based on tour last idea meeting so we
got a several comment so the goal is to
make this document or shortened and
clean and the pocus on a ability so we
specify six row then click in create
canal OD in the third so we make the LT
MP she is a example of the potential
six row l2 candidate and as I said that
we
include yeah we include two practical
six wrote implemented scenario it is
right silent schibetta machine and we
add a new new section of Qaeda line for
six row six repent altercation and we
moved to remove sixth row use case
example to appendix because we are
focusing on the applicability
so the some text poll use kissed is
moved to appendix so we add some
additional ad throw command and the
stamina are helped us many immersed so
she is Eddie's so one of the author of
this threat so in this document we have
seven six role in great canal G Teddy
z-wave really and actually and MSTP NFC
and PLC and I prefer 815 that echo so in
this earth ring create canal Agito
Piercy is under the individual director
so I hope so this technology and and the
trapped probe regarding this technology
should be some the working group
document in this working group and we
unmarked the LT MTC is the potential
candidate because we sub a and we
solicitation or visual state the
practical use of the six role but
unfortunately for regarding LT MTC there
are no or practical or six role or
deployment scenario so the storage' meet
or mark is the potential candidate yeah
comparison across the six road in color
technology so there are seven technology
and we want to compare so they are you
seized and their technology and seven
air and mobility Luke Lyman and security
requirement and problem you climb on a
radiance cutes requirement iterate and
there are some ladies are she were
trapped so as you can see there are some
[Music]
come on common point and there are some
different to a point so if you regret
this table or you can analyze or you can
emulate some increased acknowledge a
poor your target services so that's the
reason we are made this the comparison
table yeah and we add the new section
that is the guideline for nothing ipv6
there so he target candidate upon new
constraint air to technology that
consider running modified six row six
weapons Tech so we must consider that
item that is addressing model mq
consideration ratio s3 loading address
or simon header compression security and
encryption and additional processing so
until now we have the seven ring clear
technology but in future maybe new
wrinkle six row link layer technology
could be made so in this case we should
consider there are technology for these
items
yeah so we add some top practical to six
row deployment scenario that is why Sun
so this text or was up or her fight
papi he is the working in the white Sun
Alliance so you can see the rising
technology is a based on this technology
and among them why son Pierre area
network FAL technology
it covers something related on their
topic analogy so we found that my son
uses of six Rose Stagg is that is the
advanced metering infrastructure ami and
distribution automation ta so it is some
interesting point there six row
technology is really used in the real
world and another six row deployment
scenario is japanimation so Jupiter mesh
sophistication is based on piece of
technology and so to fight mesh in smart
grid is using the six ronita layer so
thick text or was a provide is my
credibility's and - - beer and so thanks
to their support for this document so
and we are headed some design space
dimension for sixth row use cases for
example deployment deployment put the
threading topology l3 1 l 2 and
something blah blah so originally we
described and we are right some thought
specific or the densities dimension for
each or sixth row technology but there
are lots of context so we delete many
part and we would like to focus on the
design space in here and six real use
case as I said there in the main part
only one or use case or purely there is
the smartphone based interaction with
the content devices and the other use
cases for using perjury that really and
MSTP and
NFC appear ci3 pureed other person that
echo that are use cases are moved to
appendix
so we make a district or shorten and of
work clear to how to understand what's
the goal of this threat
so Rachel so thanks Carolyn first of all
thanks for pulling all this together I
think it's a very useful survey of the
field I guess my question to you is one
of those things on the list is not like
the others which is MSTP which is wired
and everything else is Wireless have you
thought about doing some sort of I don't
know I'm just wondering if there's some
sort of a figure of Merit that might be
based on you know good put per you know
times distance times price or something
like that I mean how would how would
somebody you know choose a wired data
link over wireless based on reading you
know your your document uh it's the clue
kitchen so actually or we don't consider
the differences between wire and the
wire is so except MSTP other Canaries
are based on the wireless
right you can see so feel free to sorry
PLC we also Piercey Piercey is about not
the working the document yes so MSTP and
Piercy is the wire and other technology
is Wireless so okay also currently we
don't have text that are reflect your
question command so I'm thinking and I
tries to how-to or reflector so you can
help us okay thank you
basically I'm just reacting to what
Kerry said and there is some feedback
from the real world in in the measuring
business where they will tell you that
filarsky metering there is not one link
assertion that fits all situations for
instance via
building if you get lighten outside if
you don't have liner size your concrete
but yeah the return for implementation
and deployment that I got is that having
a layer 3 routing technique which allows
you to actually use multiple sort of
link and maybe you deploy both and you
see what works it's a lot better than
deploying only one and sound
a technician back later because that's
not right so so that's really where the
power of writing and using repo in this
kind of use cases is so visible because
you will actually use both wires and
wireless okay thank you Oh
any other questions comment so you can
see this document includes some the
barriers in cleared canal G so so I'm
not export of that area so we need some
other expert to review and give some
practical information of the six role or
in chronology uses in the real world so
I'm also asking and the carry says that
he gave us and other person emulating
your input of this document Thank You
charlie
okay well hello I'm John Charlie Perkins
and do I just say when it's time to
change slides or okay yeah I guess this
time so just a quick overview we've been
working on this draft to specify the
delivery deadline times for packets in a
6lowpan Network and currently we have a
packet delivery deadline time and then
also you can put in the time at which
the packet was first sent and with this
information you can make decisions about
whether to drop the packet because it's
not gonna make the deadline and you can
also make determinations about how long
it's been in transit so it's a pretty
pretty simple idea and it's also assumes
basically that you have a
time-synchronized network so it's you
can have a consistent idea of what time
it is so that's sort of an underlying
assumption and given that you have
different networks that are still
basically synchronized in time even if
they have different ideas of what the
current time is you could still do a
transmission between those networks on
next slide please so well after the last
ITF there was discussion about including
ASN as a time unit and so that seemed
like the right thing to do and so we put
that in there was awesome just some
discussion about how to handle the
reserved field we didn't do anything
about that it said just to say that it's
reserved but other than that the draft
has not been changed very much but one
sort of pervasive change was to the
draft currently is the name of the draft
is expiration time but I think deadline
is much more accurate description of
what is provided
so in the text of the draft it basically
usually says deadline or delivery
deadline or something along those lines
but the name of the draft has not been
changed
so let me except to say it's - go for so
next slide please
here's a quick look at the format for
the for the extension and it's safe well
basically there's uh oh means that the
origination time is present D says how
you can handle the dropping the packet
if it's for instance you you may allow
for this information to be transmitted
even if the deadline is passed if the D
flag is set to be 0
Oh question as best can see well charlie
there seems to be a very supportive of
this work yeah there seems to be this
this assumption that you know how fast
it takes to get there under the routers
in the middle know if this packet is
light or not light or or do you just
want to drop the packet when it's too
light but having no clue at all if you
can make it because it seems to me that
basically you should drop the packet as
soon as you know you cannot make it not
go all the way till deadline yes but
that seems to imply that you know how
long it takes to make it and my commands
pretty much the same I did last time is
constants if the route schedules the
transmission all the way using non non
storing mode all the way it would
probably be able to compute also the
various hops deadlines and so use that
recursively or use that along all the
hops so that each hop would know how
much time it has to follow this package
just to respect the schedule initial end
up doing that then you have a source
routing versus short version of TS n
days ago well you kind of do that with
TTL right I mean if you want to say that
this packet can't survive more than five
hours and I'm not talking about hops I'm
saying oh if I if this route schedules
this path with this source routing
information
uh-huh and it knows the packet must make
it by that time it can also say Oh first
up it should make it by that time second
hop
that time all expressed in ASL so you
already able to to to give the network
what is your reference folding
expectation you know I can somehow
imagine a network where you'd like to
have that close control of granularity
of planning but I don't know how to do
it and I think that this is going to
probably get a huge majority of the
applications and you know as you say
let's say that you have an intermediate
point where you're one microsecond away
from the deadline well you might want to
drop it anyway but this is simple enough
and useful enough that I hesitate to
volunteer for additional complication
okay so you can go out there and get the
implementation has been merged in with
open WS n it was presented also it's a
six dish by aisle I show and review them
as a natural customer for our for this
sort of feature and the implementation
has idea for earliest deadline first
policy which I think is one of the most
basic kind of deadline policies you
might want to use a question Kerry Lynn
I'm just wondering if you've got any
information on whether the dominant
delay is killing delay or transmission
delay or is this very by technology I'm
thinking back to Pascal's question or or
a response it seems to me that in a mesh
network for example to be very difficult
to predict that all of the hops are have
the same cost for example because it's
really as you get closer to the edge
those those nodes are doing more routing
on behalf of other nodes below them so
that potentially there's more traffic
going through those nodes yeah I think
you know does you know if you want to
take a look at sort of measuring the
distribution of delay times through the
router and then slice it up but
chewing delay time and other effects
that's a pretty good paper and as far as
I know they're you defending on which
network different effects are dominant I
mean some it's it's your network is
congested boom your that's it and I'm
not sure whether you want to count delay
because of interference versus queuing
delay on the router those are two
different kind of things so I'm gonna
sort of maintain them my blissful
ignorance here and just say well you
just want to say what the deadline is
and then let it go glut go at that I'm
there wasn't that carryout I want to
answer I think it depends on the
technology from the obvious and stuff
that we did in six ish networks the
delay time is mostly queuing you wait
for your slot actually had a second
question and that is how closely do the
clocks have to be synchronized do you is
it is it just within some epsilon in
other words can they can I sort of you
know oscillate within some you know some
s along what if I told you that we
measured experimentally that the clocks
have to be within 1% of the deadline
time that would be a total lie but you
could you could make any sort I mean you
can decide we could get into the
question of how hard is the deadline and
that would go back to this D bit that we
talked about whether you're allowed to
you know pass it along or not and this
is a valid point of discussion but on
the other hand maybe it's a better idea
to just put it out there and see what's
really needed you know maybe we can just
catch up for like two minutes tonight if
you're going to the social I want to
tell you about a project that you know
oh I'll be at the social if you want to
a quick question on the time
synchronization
so I understand that it works on 60 so
but do you have any recommendation of a
time synchronization protocol or how
time synchronized what time
synchronization mechanism should be used
for this draft no no we don't have any
additional implementation I see now I
shouldn't say that because you know I
didn't actually do this implementation
it was done by Elijah and folks so
presumably I mean if they're running on
a normal platform you can have a time
synchronization protocol running but I
don't have any additional information
about the specifics of that I think good
to have some sort of either boundaries
that I think Carrie was mentioning or
some sort of information of time
synchronization because it seems like if
this is a dependency for this for your
draft so some recommendation on time
synchronization our reference good okay
that's a good point
I bet if I compose a message to the
mailing list and we have discussion and
we can insert a description about that
I'm looking at you another minute so
Thomas time synchronization I I can
answer exactly for this implementation
in this implementation see the order of
across the network around 100
microseconds in commercial application
commercials around 10 15 microseconds
across 100 node Network but but this
doesn't have anything to do with this
draft right this draft just says time
stamp in time stamp out and whether
you're well synchronized or not well
synchronized not it doesn't affect that
olders draft is draft just timestamps so
I think I think you know how
network is synchronized doesn't really
matter it's to the application to say
okay I just received a packet which has
this timestamp what do I make out of it
I know what's wrong in my network I know
how much I can trust it but this draft
will carry it regardless right it's
independent right so what I understand
is pretty just to make a dumb example
let's say you send out deadline saying
here and say I want to have a deadline
of 1 microsecond from now and you're
just you're not going to really get very
far so we could insert some language in
the draft that says well you know the
precision of your deadline time has to
be affected by the precision of your
time synchronization but that won't
change the format of the packet yeah
agreed yeah but you know if the time
synchronization persists
precision is not very accurate name time
out - a time in - time out may not be
very correct so if you specify some you
know range of time synchronization
precision that would be good enough
ideal I believe but I think you can
probably discuss it on the mailing list
well if I I know if you see something on
the mailing list please comment all
right yeah Oh Gabriel so I had a
question trying to understand the
semantics of this thing so looking at
the D bit you turn it on then you're
supposed to throw away the packet if
it's beyond the deadline correct but the
operative word there was should so do
applications know if they have to rely
on this if they can maybe line it is it
meant to be just to get rid of
extraneous traffic on a best effort
basis I mean what kind of semantics our
application expecting or are there's
gonna be are they gonna be issues if
there are duplicates for account because
somebody did not obey that should as
they're you know open to do if it's a
should recommend that we changed should
immerse no I'm asking because I don't
know how it's used so I don't know what
applications expect it was a question
about that
application suspect very clear Chris
semantics then I guess a must is
probably a better choice but no other
application to with these things okay
it's meant to just get rid of extraneous
traffic that is fine okay I don't
have know how to answer that but I mean
we could ask six - folks they might know
sue Thomas I'm not answering six - I'm
just answering thinking out light about
applications if you send a packet with
one of these headers in there and you
said the D baked for drop after deadline
I mean you expect it to drop right so
you should you should make it a muster
set of issues
well if it's a should then I said the
bit and what happens so either I said I
don't set it and it just carries on or I
said it and must be dropped so I would
say that - must otherwise I don't see
I'm okay with must okay next slide so
well we would like to request working
group and Roush and adoption of this
draft I think it obviously has a purpose
SQL do you have a question
amber a little bit this is a I've never
I forget the name but this is a header
that you can ignore right so how comes
you can expect the most operations and
something you can ignore
I'm sorry so I I don't really see how
that can be a must like or a serious
must write it because it's optional the
process right so if you put it in you
cannot expect it to be enforced so this
is like ha by hop options in in v6 right
you can say you can say like if you
don't understand this drop the packet
right but like there's another RFC or
other CD which says that oh if you don't
process how by off options don't do them
right so like you're in a very very
similar boat like because you can say
must if you want right that's okay with
me
but the sender still cannot expect if
you sit the D bit that the packet will
actually get dropped because somebody
you won't understand
dislike deadlines option right so okay
uh can you say a little bit more about
why some would not would not understand
deadline option so let's say somebody
doesn't implement this draft on the pad
does not implement it no okay not at all
right so and you said that II bet do you
expect it to be dropped or not right
like I would say no you cannot write you
cannot so like you can put the must in
or a shouldn't but the thinking needs to
be like you cannot depend on this
happening this is still best effort
because you don't know who's on the path
who can actually recognize this right
because what are you saying is like like
I think Kerry said it best right if you
understand this like you must drop it
that's that's different from expecting
it to be dropped I think that is Gabe's
question right like how do you expect it
to be honored right well let's Carrigan
you know Charlie in in family there was
this discount eligible bit if for those
who were born that day there's there was
a de bit in the dlci and what that would
say is if you have to you have those
five packets in front of you and you've
got time to transmit three well if two
of them are the D bit then the choice is
clear it transmit these three others so
so basically this looks like a debit
with a time bomb on it let's read what
it is I mean before that time treated as
a normal packet after that time if you
really need to discuss something then
discount this one preferably but that's
a behavior that that can be enforced by
those who but the behavior that you
cannot get yes let me make an
application that is pro by design is
certain that this packet will not be
delivered behind that to beyond that
time unless you get this thing
implemented throughout then this
application will be broken okay so this
is you know you're discussing the
end-to-end behavior and part of the
value of this is in the intermediate
nodes in UTS right so if they have to
for instance do some preemption or
anything like that they might
preferentially that's what is all about
in frame right pre discount this one
prefer
because the application knows that it
will lose a lot of value or it does a
lot less value that these are the packet
so if you add those two this one has
deviate this one does not discount the
discount eligible bit or same thing
after that time this one becomes
preferably you know you inform read that
it should not be surrender after all
right I think Shelly the point that like
you know I was making at least I think
like most of us are making is that the
must doesn't give you much more than it
should but that's it like everything
else what you said is right
you know there have been entire hours
spent on mas versus should and one
argument is that people don't care about
should and I don't believe that argument
but anyway please Peter founder stock if
I want and deadlines be a little Mike
Peter how much talk okay sorry if I make
a network or make your own real time to
be executed I make sure that this draft
is there in all the in all the notes yes
and then I expect the must okay thank
you yeah so can I can I say that we
should discuss this in the mailing list
and then they will just do whatever
people believe okay so so as John
described somebody is pointing out it
we're 20 minutes 800 K so please add our
draft yeah so not sure I'm we're ready
yet to go to go for call for adoptions
but let's let me continue the
discussions about how applications work
with is that sort of thing a little bit
more and maybe go for call for adoption
after that depending on how the
interactions go great at this point it
seems a little bit like we need to
discuss but he also a networks okay
hello this is Jang ho and today my topic
is transmission of ipv6 packets of
replacing networks so this work was done
by me together with
young guns charging and the current
leads version Wow and today we would
like to record our she okay next page so
what is PLC PLC refers to power line
communication this technology uses the
electric power lines for indoor and
outdoor communications and Jesse has
been widely applied to support advanced
metering infrastructure so the figure
below is a simple example showing that
the smart meters transmit data to a
concentrator directly through the neck
power lines okay
next page so I presented this route last
time in Chicago and have received
comments from some interest and theory
and based on their comments I updated
this chart including that and the
following pass has are being updated
including the addressing modes the
unicast address mapping enable discovery
command frame header and connectivity
and topology okay next page so comments
after IGF 98 so here I would like to
stack Sumitra and Gabriel for building
the connection with itu-t studio so and
finally we finally we got the support
from Stefano and the theory they are
tube chassis experts from itu-t and they
have reviewed our drafts and following
on your comments so here I will not go
deeper into these comments but I would
like measuring that Stefano in the chair
of SEIU 15 which is a peer system which
is POC study group in itu-t and he
suggested that they sent the informal
feedback at first they exchanged
iesson schematic of issue ok next page
so following are the updates of this
route first is a first is the addressing
modes there are two kinds of address
using classic devices
the first is the 64-bit they globally
unique knowledge is and the other is a
16-bit shot address so in a chassis
network each device joins the network by
using the long address and then
communicates with other device by using
the short radius
okay next page and for regarding the
unicast address mapping we use a 16-bit
address only and for 100 1.2 since there
is one line referring to on the FC phone
fo4 so we could taste
simple format for the shuttle yes here
and for the itu-t co3 we put a penny in
front of the shuttle yes okay next page
and in this rushing we updated and use
and subsection namely the neighbor
discovery for they are Shibui 100 1.2
there are two kinds of routing protocols
why is people for layer 3 and the other
is low energy full for they'll arm for
Nia - so if they on ripple is used then
they the discovery process show refers
to day six on pnd and if I just AP
basics is used to assign addresses then
they duplicate address detection should
not be required and if and if they want
to uses the coexistence mode with Nara
or three nano Nene low-energy protocol
is used then the address registration
key finding the section attendee should
not be used because there is already a
defined pampu shocking protocol but
those mechanisms in six of handy for
managing the ipv6 traffic's and
corresponding header compression
contacts information can be used and
again in the at UT Nana or three since
they load energy protocol is used and
there is a predefined campus job in
protocol so we don't use a address
registration defined in Section plan D
what smashing sure that the arrow 3
supposed a section pen context talking
so we specify that those mechanisms for
managing the ipv6 prefix and
corresponding header compression and
context information must be used and
moreover for sending the ISR a
the chassis devices must follow the
corresponding sections of a six-pack
Andy okay next page for regarding the
command frame header the scarer was
defined in 9 or 3 mainly for the bamboo
shopping protocol and for the load ng
protocol we are so you know we specified
order in the header format it should be
put in the last position if more than
one carriers present and it should be
put before the 60hz harder and based on
Sumner's comment we updated our example
young our draft we put the
in between the fragmentation header and
the objective header we use and yes city
we use an ESA dispatch tried to indicate
there's another despite a follows and
this one-bite is used for the confirm
whether your stored command ID and then
unfollow stickyman payload okay
next page about connectivity
anthropologist here we have starchy and
mesh but in this version we clarify that
they are on logical connectivity not
physical links because there are some
confusing that if we consider the day on
physical connectivity the PRC devices
are connected in a trunk link but if we
consider the transmission just rains
then they are connected and logically
induced are tree or mesh topology and
with dis some name changing this section
so that it can be inconsistent with nano
tree which had they sealed previously
for coordinator to encode an inter and
the node Japan device okay next page and
last on I put I put a crashing that if
we if it is possible to include more
Casa standards and now the answer is yes
so currently we have 100 102 and nano or
3 and then Mochis a standard night color
and panel for prime and 100 1.1 can we
considered and we only 900 chuji any and
has been ruled out because currently
there is no deployment and about our
next step will be like to call for the
working group adoption so that we can
have a further discussion with at UT and
i should officially and again your
comments and feedback are always we
account thank you well thanks a lot for
this work i mean we had an early draft
by daniel papa wrong long ago and that's
the activity stopped and that was a
shame so it's very good that you're
taking this overall i thank you for this
I'm curious I initially did the first
work I was well off was for I to play in
1901 dot - yes which is the classical
stack that we care for I know I Triple E
IGF usual stuff now I thought that the
itu-t was designing its own stack and
and what kills me what bothers me what I
don't
ten years if we do anything normative
which we feel is normative at the IDF
for the stack of our itu-t G 99.3 is it
like is it a norm to be the standard to
be used by a ITU people who would want
this specification knowing that the ITU
does its own I mean is it a competition
to the the piece that you're defining of
or the ITU Network is it a competition
to the stack that baby out I mean how do
you position your work versus their well
did they ask you or did say oh we I mean
I mean I don't want to put the ATF in a
weird position while we are defending a
stack over or something replacement that
I already have right because they
already have six lap on the belt in 1903
that's why we gave them the Esk bite et
cetera so why should we be doing here
for that
I mean competition we are here I would
like to put because currently there are
many plastic devices and for guarding
the Nara ban piace - I also have let's
say the 101 thought to the GCP area
prime and what I thought they are 101
but Wow so I currently for the vendors
just it's very difficult to find a
really good pure standards for their use
so I would like to combine them together
in a single drop and if there is some
thing in common we can put it together
and that's but imagine you you say you
must use ng RI is to advertise this
right in your document then the ITT
already finds a stack and they say how
they do things
another is a collision there or
something right how do we resolve that
and are we are we mon dated for doing
this work i mean is it something that
that the ITU the chair of the itu-t 9-3
has asked you to do thinks it's nice
that the HF does this I'm just concerned
that we may have an issue trying to
define something for them that's all
it's just a question of the answer okay
so um so they did not ask me to do
anything but when I send this a job to
them and ask them for the review and if
you're very happy not sure they can find
someone who are still promoting their
standard and
they're still maintaining their nanny
Austrian crime but currently their focus
is only on their one day or two and so
no they have a some guy at you and focus
on that they adaptation there it would
be better yeah but to be clear now it
was not them that asked us anything at
all I was more this was brought here
we're wondering whether there's other
people in the world doing PLC what do
they think about this just like we asked
of an FC just so grass of any other link
layer we want make sure bluetooth et
cetera want to make sure that we're not
rotten you know conflicting with them so
we want to make sure there was no
conflict we got him involved the ITT
looked at this they're actually offer
comments but you know we might want to
clarify a bit further how they see it
because they the comments have been fine
saying hey okay this none of them has
said oh please don't do it or we'll
ignore it just been helpful constructive
comments but your point is about
clarifying what what is the function of
this which is whatever it may be I mean
because maybe you know I can read the
document from somewhere else which is
kind of informational and describing
what we do on the other hand if somebody
wants to know that no it is something we
are doing here I would not be so happy
so it's just do they understand that we
are doing a standard track document
which with the norm of how things should
work on their network or do they think
that we are just describing what they do
you know as an informational that that's
a very different beast so just yes well
sure we clarified us make sure there is
no later yeah yeah sure yeah yeah and we
we definitely will do that you did also
mention some but liaison liaison has a
very specific meaning in in the ITF and
that might have come from them they
wanted an official liaison there's some
liaisons already from certain groups in
itu-t I don't think we want to go there
for this because the way that it's going
so far seems to be okay the best way to
collaborate it's actually not through
establishing only big liaison zestful
that's for other types of interactions
but the best way is actually for the
people do what you're doing exchanging
information comments going back and
forth
and so I think we should push forward
with that and hopefully we don't have to
do a formal liaison which would have to
involve IAB into because I'd be handle
to your son so that's another process
altogether okay okay yeah I actually I
agree with Gabriel on the on the
collaboration part with itu-t Pascal we
we we actually got positive comments
from the PLC as the working group FG in
chairs so so yeah we we our
collaboration and I think if there is
anything new that are different from
what they are working on over there so
that piece there should be communicated
and a greater whole otherwise it is as
you know this is similar to any other
documents we have like NXT
I mean samhita position again this is
really where my confusion is you know if
this is an informational document saying
what they do then it's it's a separate
document just informational if it's
something that specifies new operation
in an O Matic fashion yeah there is
something new right and and if we do
that then we need to make sure that they
expect us to do something no matter if
not just like for instance in LP well we
are we have informational document about
other technologies but just descriptive
okay point taken
and a point like if are they doing like
El toast or l3 stuff like I questioning
they are doing l3 stuff or not okay if
you can say that my Kia my starting
point is they came to us some time ago
and asked for this escape field
meaning that they have defined the way
they operate so if we ever if we if this
is a document which describe what they
do it's a different path it's not just
on a track should not merge with this
other track piece for 1902 it would be a
separate document which would just be
informational now if we want to
standardize IP operation about their
network knowing that they've already
done some of that I don't know to which
extent but they've done it then we may
be in competition so the if they are
very clear that we are doing stellar
track documents here a map here you know
if they think we are just doing
informational describing what they do
and all of a sudden they describe that
no no we are prescribing operation which
are competitive with what they were they
yet then I'm sure there will be a lot
less happy but I mean maybe it's all
done I'm just was just asking well here
in this route there is some content that
refers to the annex part of 11.2 but
also meant something this is my own and
hopefully I will contact Li and they
actually sign and extra and that they
have no conflicts so just in the
interest of time I think we should
continue on the mailing list definitely
want to understand a bit better your
your concern but I think we will resolve
that offline not not in them in the next
minutes or hours or whatever so I think
we can definitely move to afterwards we
saw these at this point if it's resolved
favorably we could think about a call
for call for adoption and then in the
working group but we would like to
clarify that point first thank you very
much
now we have body area networks
Sajjad hello good afternoon the first
slide sorry so you can see this is the
first draft which is which belongs to
over less body area sensor networks and
we are looking to it with respect to
ipv6 how we can make it the part of
coyotes so the current status is this is
it for mislead off you just uploaded in
the zone and we're looking for we will
think about the standard track efforts
and sedation and straight back out
requested yes next time so there are
different motivation I will just
describe the few ones like one is like
population is increasing day by day so
this is the one of the survey like 761
millions in 2025 people they need health
care they need remote health care
another motivation is regarding GDP like
be on health care expenses are
increasing so on a report you can see
the different countries they have
different duties but the learning
stations like it's getting very high
especially with like with the USA it is
surveyed like it it will approach up to
20 percent of GDP in 2022 so these are
different indicators like which we are
looking which are motivating for this
document the next I will just introduce
the wireless mode area since the network
with respect to I I Triple E 8 u 2 dot
15.6 standard which is active standard
no and it is standardized in 2012 it is
as our lotion now it is it based on mac
and phy layer the main the main thing is
like it incorporates the better
penetration through the human tissue
without creating any damage to the human
tissue and it follows the approved mix
band which is medical implant
in kitchen service penned by USA so it's
uh it's following the specific
absorption rate guidelines which is
useful for human tissues next slides so
here you can see the different
application different use cases for
wireless what is a sensor networks a
patient can be equipped with different
sensors with this standard is specific
with them countable sensors like when
you and wanted the sensors inside the
body
and there are different use cases you
can use it for patient care you can use
it for elder care center you can use for
the fitness and fitness for the supports
is the next slide the scope like it
defines the scope it is basically a
short and low-power standard like ranges
mentioned from two to five meters and it
wants to work on value low-power it is
using I use some bands and there are
different bands very low back low
frequencies band I mentioned I will show
you in the next slide it compliance yeah
complies with strick non-interference
guidelines it is taking different
guidelines with respect to medical
applications as well is next slide so
why would you need to standardize this
sort of application with the IDF like
there are a lot of propriety solutions
which are available which are doing this
this stuff so we just want to make it
the part of standards so it can be used
by everybody there should be a standard
like which they should be a standard
body screen solution like current
solution or optimized for different type
of applications beside medical like
bluetooth is optimized for voice links
ZigBee is optimized for the sensor
industrial sensor applications Wi-Fi is
optimized for data networks so these are
the general general focus points which
they are doing is the next slide this is
the just a comparison slide between
different the existing standard and if
you to dot 15.6 you can see
if you want to work on very low power
like one milliwatt or less than 1
milliwatt
and you also goes it also you can also
get the high throughput like you can use
ultra wideband in this standard but
still they are following the human
tissues guidelines so you can see it is
low-power and indebted you can achieve
different again the purpose of the high
data rate it like this diversity of the
different medical sensor like if you are
using ECD so it's contained different
different sort of cables so you need
high throughput so that's why it the
throughput that data it's it's varies in
this standard the next type these are
the different frequency bands it's
mentioned you can see the human body
communication there for different
frequency band
it has different it says t type of file
layer like this narrowband ultra ultra
wideband and human body communication
this this is the speciality of this
standard makes yeah this is channel
access mechanism it's a little bit
different like other it's it work on the
same pattern like 15.4 is working on the
super frame that channel is divided in
the super frame but for the medical
application they have mentioned like
different phases like EAP like emergency
access phase you can see the different
EAP in a single in a single super film
then the random access period and you
can also see the content access
contention accessories like cap which is
also available in 15.4 so you it's
little bit different from 15.4 yes next
sideways so you can they are obvious
officially benefit for if we use it with
ipv6 like we have the addressing
flexibilities like and we have auto
configuration the solutions available
simple like if if you are connected with
ipv6 which means you are part of in 10
like you're part of you can be a part of
IO T's as well so that's why we are
looking for ipv6 there next slide so
there are different issues like but
especially we are meant to like the
packet size like frame size it's in the
standard at the frame size is 256 which
is different from 15.4 which like it's
127 127 bytes so this is a few few
issues we need to look if we want to
make it a standard track like how we
will deal like are we going to adopt six
low 6lowpan or we are going to look to
the compression mechanisms how ipv6 deal
with it so is the next slide
yeah they're different industrial you
can see different industries which are
adopting and making the chips for 15
15.6 XS instrumental instrumental all
devices so the work started so oh you
are the next yes
so this is it the brief introduction for
document - so first document so it's
still informational so subscription no I
hat I read the draft and there's really
nothing in there about transmission of
sick i pv six frames right usually we
need to ipv6 or fool it's like a set of
things you specify you know the unique I
said this mapping multicast address
mapping this one only has informational
text about body area networks and
nothing else so is that the inter after
or like whatever intending you know like
because because it's just uploaded in
the zone and just want to clarify the
need like that's why we mentioned about
well is body races are in Redbook as a
focus point but you are right like we
should also mention about the ipv6 sort
of things how it can be incorporated
like we have discussed in the group but
would you mention in the dock okay no
but all it says is like Oh
6lowpan does not work on this right it
says the frame format is different
6lowpan does not work right and that's
it it so because like
that the title is kind of misleading it
says like transmission off dadada or
something has to specify all this right
and that's that's why if you're talking
about the need for using doing 6lowpan
for this then it's different than saying
it's transmission over right so like our
like our focus is on like to use for
this standard for the medical
application so yeah and this in the
second step yes you all right yeah we
need to look in detail or we will manage
it with ipv6 and those sort of thing and
we're working on it but we thought like
after meeting we will add we will update
the talk to comment just to share point
of view there's nothing in here for the
working group to do so this would not
ever become a working of document
because there's something for us to do
so it was a good informational
presentation but yeah for the timing is
informational document but we will look
for the response and the feedback if we
get so we think for this oh yeah
so for next time think of there's
something for us to do then yeah we
should work you know think about that
but if there isn't then that's fine that
Pascale that pretty much it goes with my
questions why I mean do you expect what
do you want to build on that I mean do
you want to be able to image do you want
I see that there is need for reliability
would you like us to put 60 on that's
why as opposed to the classical 15 for
but that it would that fit the kind of
application that you have in mind we
need to know the applications I mean I I
really can figure out a mesh of that on
my body I yeah I think the idea is quite
cool I don't know what I would put on a
sick secret dish can be a good option
like exactly if you were to describe
this and and and mostly you know I want
to do a mesh sixties mesh on it here is
what's missing from six stage to get
this mesh on my body then we could act
on it right again many like the purpose
of this initial document is you I like
the importance of this standard like
which is which is not the part of this
so let me highlight this innate I know
we are looking for those solutions
okay let's go then we closed up mic on
this one okay yeah thank you
so this is Alexander Petrescu I work at
CIA in France I looked at a draft a very
nice draft I see a frame format section
there are about 300 bytes in this frame
is this the maximum transmission unit
256 256 so the MTU on wireless ban is
256 yes I think this is a good starting
point yeah that's why I mentioned in the
last night that like the issue like we
have need to think about this okay we
need to feed back so we can give space
to this standard which is important for
health care application and else care
system thank you thank you thank you now
we get to the final part of the meeting
which is going to be on fragments
Australia okay so this is this is a a
discussion that we spent a bit of time
last ITF I exposed the number of
drawbacks of the current fragmentation
as disclosed in RC 49:44 which are
mostly problems in the route of the
world unless we get clear signals from
the mesh underworld maybe the mesh
renderer is perfectly happy with 49:44
but that creates number of situation in
righto well that could be improved so I
won't we do the slides I did last time I
left them in the slide where in appendix
so if you don't know the slides from
those from the website you'll find that
after the apparent end of it you have
all the slides of my style of last time
but I will basically use your knowledge
of what you said last time to basically
look at
the prices are and what we need to solve
right please next line so then again
created that last time and yes that
there is there is another aspect which
needs to come for is that for the LP one
work we have also started working on
fragmentation and we have been thinking
of a number of solution space things
which could more or less apply to to the
work here so like windowing and vigil
retrial fragments so obviously the use
case is quite different decision will be
different but we may take inspiration
from the world even though they're a bit
of concept for fragmentation so
initially in the first is a very very
long ago first 6lo network there was
some TCP and the reason why there were
some TCP is just because of this problem
with fragmentation so people would rely
on TCP because they would get MSS Mac
segment size now the drawback of TCP
obviously mostly issues and very small
chunks of data is you have to pay the
price of anak donation back every time
and that's way too costly so the on the
industry moved to UDP coop etcetera
which gives the application the
capability to request an ACK really when
they want it and usually they provide
the AK is not is an uplevel act with
some semantics which come back not just
hey I got you but I got you so here is
what you should do with it so we on a
space where the acknowledgement is also
mostly loaded with application space
information and on the side of your
brain remember that we talked a lot of
streamlining last time explaining that
the packet could actually be reassemble
that the other and much faster if we can
streamline fragments are supposed to
recompose at every hop and actually this
gives us storing well that we can use
for each wise just rule of thumb is the
application is not chance if we can live
within the time that we gain by
streamlining following our or which
one's it next slide please
so the
summary of the plan that we discussed
last time prime one unless we do
something which is not documented in any
standard we need to recompose the packet
at every heart because we need to build
the IP base that gets us to write it and
then pass it to the next stuff so we
need to fragment parcel next our
precompose fragment pass the next Opry
compost and that's what create is this
very huge latency and buffer bloat in
the etomidate note
so we basically want to be able to
forward all the way there is no control
at all nothing which tells you how to
pace your fragment so to slow down when
the fragments can stay in the air
so implementations and to push on the
fragments as fast as they can and there
is no sort of interference and before
bloat which can be created inside a
network again not only that but if you
have multiple flows which cross in the
same row tonight we'll have to store
buffers for all these fragments at the
same time and we end up with the
classical congestion loss that we see in
switch Roberts but know with the number
of buffers that we are there that gives
us last Iraq Utley and using a fragment
as the side effect that we know that the
end point will be Lear waiting forever
to get the fragment it's waiting for
which is my last point if you have some
loss then the recovery SAP that come
beside will have to time out and
actually that's experiencing this which
led this RFC 73 88 about which which now
I obsess debug Network that's because
they did this is an MP thing that they
found that the prom they had was
fragment loss question David moving to
next slide I suspect my about to reveal
and I know next to nothing about 6lo
what exactly David black tears vwg
working chair trying to understand
what's going on here so what exactly
you're trying to do with that first
bullet okay so I mean that's when I'm
skipping what I said the previous
meeting every surface but you get this
mesh of 6lowpan devices and you're doing
repo rot rotting over it and now you're
the the 6lowpan
the classical
well to 2.50 not for network justify
will have 128 bytes of MTU which means
that if you want to provide the expected
service of 1284 ipv6 you will have to
fragment if I want anything which is in
the order of 100 bytes and above all -
ok yeah yeah some recent repeating or
something or audience l2 fragment that's
that that's really important so what's
happening is is the transmitter has done
an l2 fragment and now it says at every
l3 hop so what do you want to do with
the router shim so so you've got this IP
you've got IP which sees 1280 then
you've got 6lowpan which cuts it into
number of 6lowpan fragments right and
this thing will do multi hop over other
the ripple Network now if you wish or
Dell is launcher l2 nothing's gone wrong
because I go I go hop by hop over of
over l2 I hit the next I hit I hit the
far end of the link according to
according to IP and at that point I need
not because we are that's what we call
right over right every radio hop is a
router oh boy do I need no that's what
I'm afraid you're doing ok what I'm
right what let me let you finish your
presentation but oh boy right there out
over and there's mesh under when this
was written it was for mesh under in
which you recompose at the very far end
for route over there's all these
problems you put the packet at every up
all the way to IP layer and you've need
the full packet there to rot it to the
next hop yet the right and the problem
the reason said oh boy is for what gave
of the subscribers were out as we're out
over your your effectively asking a
router to route and forward no three
packet an IP packet that it hasn't
actually received it's got the header
and and
exactly
laughter yeah boy yeah customer customer
brought in Reigate load broken record
mode what has what what's risen the
first hello what's written there in the
first village has been possible for over
10 years now which is what you're afraid
of David it's been possible it's not
been described and people it has been
described I liked your book and it was
missing the well we can just get that
offline but you don't indicate that you
need to swap late now there is a
difference between an implementation
technique in their knowledge of document
that defines a protocol there is an
implementation technique that avoids
point one yes okay now of course we
still have to work with those other
points no point since we have to think
about what does it actually mean for the
first fragment to be sent the next
router actually forwarding that first
fragment and at exactly the same time
the original sender sending the second
fragment with your first point that we
have done everything that there's
nothing to do for the first right I can
do you want to keep that my own sort of
for later the point is I agree that it's
look mostly a local behavior that
doesn't need it's done at least to the
be done well but it's about creating a
state for the next fragments and and so
what is what what requires a protocol is
when do you know that you can clean that
state yes right and when this boils down
to well the last point about fragments
recovery if you if you have a fragment
recovery then you can use that piece to
kinder state and that's when there is a
relation that's may also to you okay so
the there is a number of implementation
issues or timing here
yes and number only would be a good
thing to think about those yeah and if I
hear what you just said you want to
conflate them with retransmission I want
to confuse well now that really the two
points in the middle I really look close
to one another
what is conflated is the recovery and
the solution to the recomposition
because you can use the the message back
which enable recovery to also signal
undone I got them all you can clean the
states in the middle what observation is
that this message back already has been
there for a long time so we have we do
radio layer X of all of our packets in
all of our adaptation layer packets
except for Mallika's including fragments
so it has already been there so you are
asking for a different kind of
additional retransmission it's the okay
6lowpan wide and 12 it's not a one hop
thing but it's a multi hop thing needs
to be very very clear right yes that's
why we talk man it's a lot of a pro
right yeah and I'm going to say the next
thing when you're at the slide that yes
exactly and that would that would be
next slide exactly so let's keep that
falling slide
Spencer Dawkins just as a nosy
individual just to help me understand
because I haven't read any more of this
wrath and David has are we talking about
many I mean like most packets being
fragmented or is this a relatively small
number there are four use cases in there
- mostly two of them in once in each
direction requires fragmentation when is
reflashing of devices quite rare and so
that's going down to the devices and the
other one is there are some example of
IOT devices which will capture a lot of
data in one bird-like vibration stow
that in a file and then you need to
stream that file all the way up then you
want to do that some blocks
most of the normal IH activity will
never never fragment so and and the last
question just to help me keep up so if
you do have the loss or you today if you
do have a loss
are you retransmitting the whole packet
or just a fragment the whole packet
expect
yes okay and you know it's not even that
it's today's cost of energy associated
to that a lot of latency because this
timer switch right timers are infinitely
long because this network is so slow and
it can vary it be very variable as well
so to timeout values about huge but but
the other drawback is mostly what
touches us at the sixth upper layer is
the devices are usually constrained
right if you're sending a new image to
to this IOT device and you're losing
just one fragment the timeout is
actually very long and usually all the
buffers are clogged with things like
that and now you can't receive anything
and that's really what created this RFC
623 de H yet because he was wondering
Jurgen was very wondering why he had so
poor performance on his six level
Network and the reason was once the
world is a packet being fragmented the
noise ratio beam being what it is he
would consume all his buffers and they
would drop the other packets you see and
so so he could debug that because he
introduced as an MP in that in that
device and that's that's the cool thank
you
ouch yeah we could see cramming there we
say coming one thing of course there is
a retransmission per-fragment which is
based on the radio lahic on the one hop
yes all right so we cover one hop we
don't cover the mesh
I hope I wrote it in the first slide
otherwise I hope it's very clear
document now if you progressed a little
bit on the network and you don't have a
knack back I don't know what then
if the packet gets lost in the middle of
the network you're screwed if if it's
after a few retry you can see progress
you're not screwed
and so I I think it's an important
problem to solve the bond statement is
important but I have some reservations
towards the solution we have not your
assertion but they would take care of
the meaning list so so one one of the
primary disadvantage Caston already
highlighted about the sender and
receiver boat for forwarding at the same
time so while the first fragment has
been sent from the receiver towards the
next table so it increases the collision
rate you mean the acknowledgments back
or American fragment so a sender is
sending a first fragment yes then we see
what receives it and then sends it
forward but by the time the the sender
has otherwise they rely right yeah in
the receiver this this was not the
problem currently it's one of this it's
actually fragment flow interfere with
one another
yeah yes so yes exchange it won't be a
problem
so the ANA at the problem that I see is
with regards to single buffer strategy
if any of the device in the net in the
in the path has a single buffer okay or
let's say the sender has a single buffer
then unless or until the complete all
the fragments are been received by the
end receiver it has to wait yes and that
would take substantial long time asking
anything about the buffers right I mean
so it's not prime again solution it's a
prime prime right I'm just saying that
you know there's a scenario where the
sender has only a single buffer let's
just a constraint node oh yeah that's
the three what goes priority since right
so let's say it has ten fragments to
forward and now in the current case it
forwards all the ten fragments in a
single the single stage without any
weight yes it pushes their service yeah
there is the yeah there will be layer
two acknowledgments there will be all so
but the point is now it has to forward
it five hops down the line oh it will
take a long time if you slow them the
other the source yes and you won't be so
the source has to now keep more a bigger
queue
for all the other packets which are
offering over the time through that's
right yeah I just want to good take into
consideration it's just just a higher
orbit here I'm gonna cut the line right
now
so after Thomas because we need some
time at the end we want to actually ask
some questions this is not about
designing a solution this is not about a
solution this is just about here are
some potential issues and then the
questions will be more like should we do
something about it you know that sort of
thing right so we want to get to get a
sense of the room of what whether we
should do something about this problem
I'll be very quick Thomas I think this
is an important issue that we need to
address it's a major major pain to have
to reassemble at every hop it's all
kinds of problems with buffers how long
do i wait stuff like this and I've read
your draft right before the meeting I've
sent a kind of a very detailed PDF with
melamine aiming points if carton says it
has been done great but I like to
understand how either we can have a side
mini I mean we need to do something
about this I think we agree it's
important there's been coming up so many
times I'm waiting for something I can
use and and and so either we come
together this week and we figure it out
or I don't know we do an interim but I I
mean this cannot be coming up again and
Singapore and again after that we just
have to solve this thing it's not hard
can we move to the next slide and then
we'll have a lot of time for question
response so I based on the points that
were released on the Prairie side I
basically made that list don't know if
it's complete but my view of it first
thing we need to provide fragment
forwarding so whether it's so secret
source you know you know node or we
actually explained we there are there
are pitfalls I described them last time
there are ways of doing this very wrong
which appear to work until they don't so
so those people have known some of them
at least we I documented a meager slides
a dresser proposed a way that everybody
understand that everybody validates that
does the fragment forwarding well okay
even if people have been doing that for
10 years in the hoenn implementation
I'd like the ATF to come up and say
there is
way that we recognize work and we will
do the trick for you and and yes my
draft sighs you can do it with MPLS
switching of the label what did they
tack on that pointing point is if you
fragment the first packet with if if you
follow the first packet with the IP
address then you need to leave a state
for the next fragment that you need to
clean later
second thing we may or may not want to
solve the second problem in the previous
list which was kind of this this burst
of fragments going on if we send this
burst like how just said we free memory
on the sender but we bloat the next hub
and then the next stop which may get
different births coming from different
places but the end of the day packet
last fragment loss all the bad things do
we want to do some pacing windowing to
avoid loading the network beyond its
capacity to avoid congestion loss same
thing for well next step sorry fragment
reliability do we want to be able to
retry individually fragments which have
been lost somewhere in the middle of
this mesh right so exhausted which rise
in the middle of the mesh what do we do
and last but not least easy and do we
want to be able to SWAT or more or less
efficiently based on the current state
of the network do we want to provide
some form of explicit congestion
notification so my my surgeon dropped
obviously as them all but clearly also
people might think it's a huge overkill
so so that's that's where the discussion
lies and then is maybe other solutions
in mind but at least my draft sighs all
this there is a way to do it next line
so I just said the first line this is a
path forward like Thomas said which
we've been there for so much time I mean
this promised in there it heard is this
is part of the purchase a weakness okay
okay and you're a police you'll find my
slides for last time with some drawings
and stuff David if you want to go
through them Oh
sometimes okay I can go through some
part of the slide sense let's see how we
can handle it questions so thank you
pass go for elaborating the issues with
route over so when the RFC 4944 is
defined is called attitude are 15 . 14
it took fifteen that fall it was mainly
designed for mesh under forwarding and
this is mostly at the 2.5 layer packet
forwarding with the 6lowpan adaptation
layer and English nation header and the
problems that if you want we use the
same technique for route over you will
have the problems that Pascal already
mentioned so the next few slides we are
going to learn and I'm going to put
together some of the questions and see
what should we scope and what shouldn't
be in scope so we know that we have
solved mesh under but we want to ask the
working group if the current definition
for fragmentation forwarding
fragmentation format under mesh under is
sufficient for other
6lo technologies if there is an interest
in the working group to revisit and
reevaluate that partly you know that
some of the other technologies that we
have specified in this group many of
them don't want to use fragmentation
because there because after emphasize or
that's what they have specified and if
there is any implementation in there to
that they may want to use some mesh
inter with fragmentation that is
something they need and welcome and that
second question is doubt over it looks
like you know Pascal has been promoting
this presentation pollution for some
time and today in the working group we
want to I think take a consensus whether
we are going to work on this route over
fragmentation solution knowing that the
current specification is not sufficient
so Debian do you want to get on the on
to the questions yo Carson do you have a
clarification question or something very
quick so what I do is go to make sure
that we actually discuss things that
exist so no actually the solution for
the info troll works forward over so
okay so let me ask the questions and for
first we'll ask question about mesh
under how many people here think that
49:44 and the collection of you know
associated document thank you goes six
no model is fine for mesh under work or
other than 15.4 or maybe even four
freaking therefore basically do we need
to do something extra for particular
mesh unders anybody interested in that
things that it's okay so I see no nobody
raising their their hand for route over
how many people in the audience think
that the working group should do
something or the IDF whatever maybe it
ends up somewhere else that the IDF
should do something about improving
fragmentation issues for our okay raise
your hand please
okay well three
[Music]
okay so that's number was lit more than
20 21 22 ish definitely looks like more
than half of the people right now hmm
yeah we will yeah both of these
questions we will report what we saw
here but we will confirm on the list so
you didn't get a chance to raise our
your hand here you can do that on the
loose we well the big question with the
three seconds that we have right now is
it seems reasonable to think that
there's going to be potentially some
work on route over Carson disagrees with
that no I'm not disagree with it and we
need to properly describe what we are
doing
yeah that would be part of what we would
do I think and then and then I you know
actually do it so the what do you mean
mother you mean there are three parts
that are muddled together here one is
describe what people have been doing for
a decade that's probably a good thing to
just write it up that may be a good
thing but this exercise is not about an
informational document no one that is
that's a great thing to do that goes to
go to your auric requirement to get out
of this moment not thinking the second
one is do we have recommendations for
implementations to do good timing in the
presence of these optimizations it's
probably also informational because it
just describes good practice all all to
do things but it could also be knowledge
of I don't know and the third one is do
we want to add a completely new thing
which is the
fragment retransmission mechanism that
goes over multiple hops within the six
toe pad that's a completely new thing
and and one where we may be getting some
transport pushback before we have
described exactly what what we want to
be I also saw other other new things
like ecn so there's different potential
new things that and I guess that's the
last question a design team should go
off and figure out and then for each one
of those new things say yeah we think we
should do it and here's how I'm I don't
think I mean it would be great to have
some background info but the main output
of this effort I think here from the
point of view of working group is if
there's something to be done
what is it was the normative text that
we're getting we're gonna add into the
collection of six love documents you
know in history is great and we can use
it and maybe we can even reuse it as is
that would be great we just need to
solve the problem or problems so I think
a lot of the questions you're asking a
right but that might be better for the
design can to go after each one of those
and that's something we can we have to
continue definitely we have to continue
so a final question I want to ask is how
many people here would be interested in
forming a design team to work on this
specifically the other thing I have is
the people who are raising their the
people are raising their hands please
send email to the chairs so that we have
the composition of that design team and
that way we can say we can finish on
time so the one thing that I would like
that design team to do first is collect
the research that we have available to
actually that and if that would be a
good input to the design team but there
may be other opinions but definitely I
think we have to close at this moment
we're officially at one minute are over
and there's a social and people have to
go grab it so at this point we will
confirm these things in the mailing list
but you
we're done hey both blue sheets right
here
is there another blue sheet in the room
somewhere thank you guys thank you
[Music]