so we are going to start maybe we can
close the door if someone at the back of
the room can please go and close the
doors so this is the six dish meeting
for those people who want to listen to
BGP that's the wrong room and this is
the new not well so it's kind of the
same as usual
so you need to remember that if
something is being discussed and you're
worried about IP are you need to please
let us know after the chance after the
meeting and then please go through this
slide I won't spend the time but all the
contributions to the IDF including this
what is being said in this meeting and
on the mailing list must follow the
rules in RFC 53 78 and RFC 81 79 please
if you're not too sure go and read those
heiresses this is a official meeting
minutes will be taken we have two
minutes
takers thank you guys and and two
helpers on the chibok as well we are
taking the minutes on the fly on
etherpad
so there is a on the data tracker agenda
there are number of buttons associated
to the meeting and one of those buttons
give you direct access to these are pad
otherwise the link is written on the
bottom of the slides here so if you can
please go to each our pad and if you
said something for instance you may vary
date that the minutes are taken
correctly and reflect what you in turn
need to say okay or if you want to
participate to the mean taking that's
only appreciated so we go through the
agenda we've got quite a full agenda
today so we will be giving a summary of
the FF and drop test which happened
Friday and Saturday
and the Agathon activity as well then we
go through the almost complete items
which relate to scheduling so the
scheduling function sorry for the typo
here at scheduling function zero and the
sixth up protocol and then we'll dig
into the security of Iraq so that will
be two main items that will be Manish
are talking about the minimum security
which is mostly done piece of work and
then Michael will come and present to us
the status of design team and if you can
address a little bit the street Rostova
Michael and then time committing so
we'll use the rest of our time for those
those drafts
we've got a new scheduling function that
Simon prisoners then Jonathan will talk
about the exam of the 60s example JoJo's
will talk about replication and
elimination so that's a technique that's
being discussed at that met and this
draft shows how we can apply it on six -
and then later we'll talk about an
expiration expression time which is an
activity that is happening at six low
but he will be giving us a short summary
of what's going on there and Bob since
you're here IDF to us but we have an a
OB Bob by please we get some AOL be time
I was just wondering if you could please
during the a OB come up and tell us a
little bit about what's happening at the
I Triple E these days oh thanks so much
it's a big surprise right okay so
confirm that are not takers are in the
room so Dominique I don't see yes so
perfect why can I hurt you okay so there
we go we already start and we start with
two announcements so we have to arrive
sees one of them comes out of this group
I don't know is very very related so the
first one is thanks to Terrell thanks
Tara for doing this work now we've got a
ITF information element that is
officially ours from from the Acholi
identified
five right implementers i give i ee i ee
d IE 5 and L and last but not least
congratulation to the others in
particular shave you did the bulk of the
addition we now add the RFC number for
the minimum support for 60 so that's
reader the core result of this working
group so far yeah
okay and now if we look at our
milestones and it's good that Suresh is
with us there is an interesting thing is
we did not update the my stunt with like
the security work so we really need to
work on that
apart from that yes so yeah go ahead and
do it and I'll approve whenever it comes
through four minutes and then we are
little bit late but not that late so we
will discuss about the sixta protocol
whether we we are ready for ASCO it
appears that we are from my initial
reading of the test that we were last
week I said zero will discuss as well
knowing that we are running for
experimental for that one and then we
will be talking about what we do for the
security what we put into my stance okay
soon enough now will be will have to
decide what we do after the security
work so maybe if we have time at the end
in the AUB we can start thinking about
what's next for this book and with this
myght I will give you the floor and
presenters you can please always stay
here because you're on TV right so I am
glad to report about the first half
inter of 60 interoperability event that
we have run on Friday and Saturday 14 15
July did event has been organized by
ship and you should be able to see your
slides in the monitor doesn't
work thank if somebody knows how to
switch on this monitor it is black and I
was saying it has been organized by
adhere list and it has been founded by
develop Ian's Commission through the
open Cola of NH 2020 project called the
F Interop as usual we add the support of
two company open most for the ad and
open for the film with this time we had
the fighter and I number of participated
company 16 and we had also several
implementation in particular we had the
say 5 different implementation for 60 SH
and 6 for Oscar so forgiving you an idea
of the people that are organized and
amid the the event here is a picture of
God so all the people that came and we
thank them for coming with their own
implementation and of course we were not
only people there but as you can see
there were many shank that we try to
connect and to let them work together
just a brief overview of how the event
was organized of course we got this
grant for doping whole of the I think
they're open and it was mainly listen
decay taking care of these and we
organized first meeting or WebEx
beginning of July for a meeting with the
company and discuss about the test
description we had the test description
little was prepared with editing Fame
Alicia and at the same time there were
some tests prepared are Sephora or scrap
and they it was led by a Sanchez
Colombini and as I said the event is
organizing the context of a filter and
so Remy act for the preparation of some
60 show online tool and I will talk more
about this afterward about the tests
that we wanted to run for this edition
we focus mainly
synchronization minimal because now it
is a receive we wanted to check if it
work and then sick sick stuff also and
finally some security expected both at
links layer and other related more to
the joining function so overall as you
can see here we had the 16 no test for
6p we checked several comment like a
discount and for minimal we checked the
format of the image be corner there are
setup of the channel or finger the
rotary my size and okie formula as I
said did event run for one day in - we
have a initial setup phase as usual and
then three main texturization and on a
Friday on Saturday after everything was
concluded we had the finalization did it
for giving you an idea of the fun that
we had so as you can see that was we
were happy to test the different
implementation with many device
connected again we had as usual the
Wireshark detector that detects a lot
and we gave a demo session on in tear of
how to use it online tool
I read that these pictures so thank you
for putting those because last time we
put pictures which involved mostly wires
and people were asking whether this was
a wireless event so you see we tried
also showing because and we were Akito
to test and validate the
interoperability once we finished the
test all the company involved were able
to report the results of the test using
a TST tool provided by Etsy and this is
a very efficient it allowed to the
and then compute easily the statistic
here are the results as you can see it
was a great success we had almost 86
percent of the tested and there were few
tests that were not applicable mainly
those related to to security and in
particular all the success one confirmed
that the advocacy eighty-one eighties of
minimalism working and Interop a lately
probably among the different phi d
implementations all these was a great
yes so Thomas can you go back into a
previous title to be to be very very
clear we try to not cheat because when
so let me explain what did I say no what
we do is last time we didn't kind of
enforce this rule and if you do a test
that it passes you're very happy to
click rate or green if it doesn't work
or you you you kind of don't click red
so last time we had a hundred percent
passing tests what we did now is we
enforce the rule okay look if you if you
try a test then you have to say pass or
fail if it's fail it doesn't matter and
if you come with an implementation which
did not implement that feature and that
we had you know eleven different
limitations so it's normal that not
every implementation gets that feature
please press not applicable so the gray
part here is that kind of gives you an
idea of the percentage of what was
implemented from the things and so I
think this is a very very positive
number you know two thirds of everything
that we've written was implemented by
the different in addition which is very
cool and from those implementations 86%
of those passed so it was a was a fun
event so as I said the practice was
organized in founded in the context of
the offender of a European project and
for those that are not familiar it is an
era piant project that they aim to
develop the sama online testing tools
that are available on a shared platform
and the aim is to be able to run
interoperability a test while staying in
without the need of being all in the
same place so the idea is that you can
be in your own species you can have your
artwork there and through an argent you
connect remotely to disciplic for my end
to the testing tools that are available
on internet right now there is a quite a
big number of tests that the platform
already provide or anyway will provide
in short term like six fish coop 6lowpan
Laura or Oscar and of course the it
would be great if you also contribute to
the project and you add your own tests
you come with the other proposition and
this platform should be widely use and
the will somehow become the instrument
for running the interoperability event
more often without the need of travel
and the cutting costs so during the
practice that we show with a demo how is
a platform can be used for running for
example ripple test and the idea is that
in the next event we will actually use
some these are online testfor for our
sixties plug days so just forgiving the
feedback of the event as I said already
before it was a great success we had the
very high percentage of successful test
in particular for the mini mala now
Eric's three eighty one eighty all the
implementation were working well and
then for a sixth of the shots that we
identify little detail that it would be
better to fix and in the next drafts in
particular for the add the common in the
current version we usually reply with
the success code with the empty cell
lives when we don't have anymore cell
available to be reserved but actually we
realize it will be better to use a no
response code filled with empty cell
list and then in the case of a
generation mismatch
right now in the draft we are
documenting to send a clear yes I think
I have a question here state your name
please
I'm from India according to the add
command if there's no available one you
returned no resource but for me no first
versus can I scatter something but I
don't have one more puffer for the
slaughter rather than theirs so I think
Charlie you you're going to present this
and you have this list as well so thanks
I keep the thought I think it you should
discuss okay thank you and the same for
the generation mismatch we are right now
suggesting to send a clear but will be
better to add their own technology so
these are all feedback that after what a
child will discuss so what we can say
again it was a good success and we could
actually see that there was
interoperability that the drafts are in
a good state of maturity and as usual
the event at the inner progressing and a
feeling of our the technology is now
well implemented and it works so our
next event as I said the aim is to use
the online testing tool and to ever
Aeromotive event we will fix a date we
didn't decide yet it will be at the best
as in other advanced of course feedback
atre we'd come by that time for sure the
tool will be available the event will be
still of annals in the context of the
filter of project and we will make sure
that there is enough information to know
how to use the testing tool right now
you can already log and try to use the
digital there are either there also a
feedback link so you can provide
suggestion how to improve and to make
so I wanna I want to stress how cool is
this
well right we tested everything from
synchronizing 15 454 e secure joining
and then scheduling function sorry
Sixto protocol to schedule different
nodes so this is you know we're we're
almost almost services very cool to have
seen this if you have any suggestions or
comments about the event that we
wouldn't do in the fall please let us
know if you have any days that work or
don't work for you one idea that has
been floated is to have a an event again
in a physical room with with our
disciplines that are remote so of course
Singapore might be you know a right
right time frame for that so if you have
any any comments please let us know
thank you thank you might like that
so think fade there you are you left
right back so this is the hex on
happening on Sunday and July 16 right
here after the black test and the same
participants you know that has to join
that this hackathon event and that the
goal is to go qkm funding the link and
you can also check here so here is our
outcome from the hackathon event there
are four items
the wines are integrator of open doors
in stacking in red with that during the
hack zone we are doing the temptation of
the rather hardware driver code and also
Creator opened up hoping the resident
stack and use the two for integrating
without reott so with this
integration complete and open option now
it can support all the major open-source
implementations and during the hexan we
also present to thy finger of a platform
and we have some probe progress by
updating the bootstrap of the test
accession of the finger up platform it's
more like flashing the hardware control
rheumatory the testing device before the
users really do that has the finger at
the future of test before so also we
have for progress on the joint security
we refactoring the GRC code and also the
key for the network it can be generated
at the right time when the open
visualizer is you need initialized this
means the way we can start to the
different network and with different
network key so they won't influence each
other so with this and the 460 show and
uh of the with the security bootstraps
and now is in the open Dobson project
and on the open doors insider we also do
the housekeeping and fixing and clean up
some the project ready to the open mode
and it has the platform and I also
complete said that it's on of a
commission which is a OneTouch security
through the Navi param param module and
also we fix the Sun back from the repo
we added the PIO and some configuration
option in the repo dao packet and is
referring to the RFC
64 fut and we this the for when the
Western Kentucky can be interrupted
thank you these were announcements
thank you thinking okay so now let's
move to the first section about dynamic
scheduling so I think I remember
correctly yes Travie your Europe cave is
not updated about the sixth of protocol
okay hi everybody I'm presenting an
update of the sixties protocol we are in
version 7 the last update was last at
the 7th of June this draft is pretty
stable
there's several implementations of it
completely independent implementation
supported in in vendor platforms and
also enough in open source platforms we
we've test some of these implementations
five different implementations on the 60
block test on the HC black test that
last last Friday and Saturday uh-uh
my goal today is just summarize what
we've been doing in the last in the last
month and maybe ask for the workgroup
last last call so during the last month
we've been updating some meaner problems
that were reported by different
reviewers Jonathan and Charlie's and us
very exhaustive list of commands we
addressed all of them we posted the
responses to the mailing list we fixed
some meaner things in some typos and
errors on with it some reordering of
sections to make it more clear and maybe
remove some some text it was kind of not
important or like repeated on what but
we are now this is status that we are
now on after the black test we have
identified a couple of things that we
want to comment on we want to see maybe
your your opinion or if you can if your
your point in either here or in the
mailing list one point is when we do a
60-odd the 6p8 command always returns
a success and depending on on the
outcome of the art of the add command it
it responds a list of the cells that had
been allocated for example if I issue an
ad and I want two cells and both of them
are allocated the response contains its
circuits a success plus in the list of
cells that it returns there are these
two cells this is full allocation if I
if I issue an ad but the receiver cannot
allocate one of them but only one it
returns that cell so I know its success
and I allocated only one cell and if it
if it none of them can be allocated then
it returns success this is the current
thing now but the list is empty so there
are some complaints on the
implementation saying okay buddy
I need to look at the list and I know
because of the size of the list is zero
that I couldn't allocate them but this
is a kind of a strange case because you
are saying success but you cannot
allocate any so the concern here is
whether we have to use nor s response
instead of or onea or another another
code as as you indicated thankfully so
that's one one of the possible things
that we can improve I don't know if
there's any comment on this so this is
ten free from area so here is the no
racers for me as beginning and saying if
I preserve a cell like five maybe five
is not occupied but my slot buffers is
already full I cannot reserve you more
so that case I return no resource so but
in this case it's different from that so
maybe they will get another resort a
return code for this okay so you propose
to have an additional return code for
first yes yes okay if we so
Tomas so if we add an extra return code
for saying we have no space at all I'm
sorry no no a return code for saying
none of those cells in your in your cell
list satisfies us we might as well add
another written code three for the same
partial because I think we try to I mean
the proposal of no res is to be able to
reuse its return code so we might as
well make some specific return codes
it's we have one byte for the return
code and we currently have like five
allocated right so we have 255 286 I
don't see any problem on allocating a
couple more angry if we can make it more
explicit even because someone detects
that there's error codes that are
ambiguous we can make them more or going
off specific that's that's fine so hold
it for you thank you yes let's get real
here if you make a new return code you
need to have a behavior associated to it
which is specific to this return Cal
okay yeah thank you
okay this is another point hum when when
for some reason a generation error is
detected you know when we maybe I look
at cells and for some reason we lose an
AK and then one side of the of the
allocation fails and one side allocated
cells but the other one not we have an
inconsistency in the schedule so in this
case in the current version we recommend
that when this inconsistency is detected
we just we recommend is not mandatory
but we recommend to clear the schedule
clearing the schedule can be very costly
because and it's costly if we take into
account that maybe you will lose only
one or two acts so the proposal here is
that to introduce a mechanism or change
a little bit the behavior so we can try
to correct that situation because we
know that if we detected inconsistency
it's due to the last operation we have
it who have done it cannot be
due to any other thing it's only can
happen because the previous operation
with it messed up or we lost an AK or we
lost a packet and once one of the sides
did not detect that so what we propose
to cope with the situation and enable
and it will be policy so we don't say
how but we enable a policy to correct
that problem is change a little bit the
text on correcting or coping with
generation errors and saying that when
we have when we detect this error you
cannot add or you cannot delete cells
well you cannot add or delete cells but
you can still the least encount
operations will work will you will be
able to send a list and count to your
neighbor and then the return of these of
this operation will tell you what's
happening and then you can correct your
own schedule with this result and then
you can then tweet kind of cheat on the
generation number and then stay in sync
again so that's our proposal and the
text we propose is the one in the middle
the two bullets the first one and the
last one are already in the draft and
the one in the middle is if the code of
the 6p request is count or least when I
detected that generation error the node
must execute the operation and return
the requested values and this can be
used despite of we have the generation
error to correct the inconsistency so
that's what we proposed we don't say how
that we say we support that by listing
and Counting we we can detect the
difference in the schedule and then
correct it you have any comments from
implementers about this or I think there
may be yet yeah
this is a Tanaka from Toshio actually
the the giant generation management the
works very well they're actually too
well
so we at that time we just only thing
that to issue the clear so my proposal
is maybe sound a little bit too radical
just throw away the general generation
management
so both peers can detect the the last
transaction fares or not so each the
time alt should occur when for example
when the the pier cannot receive the the
macaque or something it can be detector
and also the count or list the command
also the give your more information -
how can I say to get back the the step
the singleness the same schedule the
cells so again my proposal is for weight
enlargements that's I think that's
easier but the huge impact on that drop
the thing is if you if you drop this
mechanism you are forced somehow
periodically maybe to issue lists or
counts to in order to see if everything
is is correct which I think this is
safer in terms of consistency because at
the first action you do you detecting
consistency and you can react quickly if
not you can like the version yeah my
point is the timeout could be used for I
don't know more to force the list so if
time out I force a list so so Thomas I
have a I have a counter example and this
is the reason why we put the the the
counter in there generation the problem
you know yes with Max and all that you
can detect that something went wrong on
the communication the only case you
cannot detect is when an AK is lost
so you try you send me a response
I send you an act but you don't get the
AK and this is your last retry McCleary
try so I think everything's fine and you
say that you think the whole transaction
has failed so now what happens you
generation has bumped your Jerusha has
not bummed and so that's the consistency
I think we wanted attack with that with
that mechanism is that you say yes so I
assume this cases you fully have full of
this but you still don't agree and also
I detect the timeout because I didn't
receive your ACK okay yeah I didn't
understand let's so let's uh I think
it's we have too little time to discuss
this let's maybe have a little chat over
the over the week and if not during the
during the during the condom aeneas to
to to make it as clear okay yeah so it's
my last light on the next steps arm
there's a little thing I want to do on
its to clarify the use of the ITF ie
in the draft now it's just a very very
simple sentence I went I want to clarify
how this II's use well how its
encapsulated will be just one more line
explaining how to use it and then
resolve all these to black test outcome
issues or problems that we have
identified and then I'm asking for a
word group last call sorry it wasn't
paying attention so so I think the
changes are that we have identified we
have to have this discussion for sure
first the the the draft has been
implemented in many times it works well
I think we're very very close to having
a final version I think we need to
resolve the process outcomes may be
bumped of revision republish this and
then I propose that we have a workgroup
last call add on the mailing list right
after this 0:08 is published does that
work yeah I would like to add that as
you know this draft uses information
element III happening at the Mac layer
and that the hie is very very well that
we are doing this and they have created
a working test group 15:12 which is the
equivalent of our working groups which
deals with the link layer communications
it's an LLC and they are integrating the
concept of 6p as part of their design
already so they know it exists they they
included it in their design and I hope
that charlie is here at the end of the
room Charlie Charlie can you help me so
so I hope maybe Charlie you can tell us
a little bit more not now but at the end
of the meeting during the i/o be if you
can just tell us a little bit about the
1512 and maybe Bob will tell us more
about what's happened happening globally
in 54 but I'm just saying that in our
C's day and it's wrapping this this
operation nicely so be prepared for
question during the OB microphone please
I'm just saying if you can during Jub
talk a little bit about 1512 and all
that relates to this work well I just
came to the microphone to say that I
didn't have anything to say so
hopefully later this week I'll do that
and yeah all right thanks a lot thank
you let's not all follow that that
pattern any more questions for Charlie
before we move on you go for yours okay
thank you mrs. Devoto company from
Universiade reporters I'm the editor of
the item 66 of SF 0 this is version 5
they have published recently so the idea
of this draft was to build a dynamic and
distributed okay let's do this
scheduling function it's not an
accession now a lot of revision from
from the Commission thank you I would
like to thank javi and child and I thank
Jean who have made a very detailed
revision of the draft so I had some time
to address every other comments so
there's a lot of tickets we have the
address so the next question let's see
what happens okay I thank you frozen
well have a collection of typos so I
have some type of okay and every other
problems we have so some expression is
that in an extra text will be there so
those are all the details I don't
tickets if you want to see them exactly
so I just focused on the specific
tickets were to do the concepts and
mechanisms that were defined on the
assets Europe
and and some movement a big movements
off of text between them so the first
ticket was 67 which does for the some a
couple of sections okay this estimation
algorithm allocation policy which were
concentrated in the introduction mainly
and just refer to their specific
sections of their explain a little bit
what was going on on what were their
original ideas that were generated their
second and 68th but the difference
between allocated and use cells meaning
that located on schedule cells that
means we're trying to measure how many
cells we are using from the ones which
are already scheduled and this is kind
of aware how to measure the ibaka usage
of that and this is the only point we
can sense and that there's a change and
that we need to add react to that change
so that's why I added a definition
pacific definition page and then the
different is taken from one slot frame
to the next one so we react in the
universe not same time see so and we
have have tried to clarify that we only
work on transmission cells the XS from
one neighbor to the other this is a
neighbor to neighbor algorithm only then
we are going to the over-provisioning
okay there's a define and not like
that's a clear definition whatsoever
provisioning is and i think we have
added a this definition in order to
specify that we have a specific size of
the of the number of allocated cells and
we need are always a little bit more of
cells to detect that we need more more
space underneath
most especially to satisfy a new request
in the future and so this we are Hart
officially locating more cells so they
are using more that way what we need a
little effect if there's a new
requirement if we won't be letting sex
without that that these cells were less
okay there's no problem about it okay so
we're going to attacked it anyway but we
want to take more cells are required
okay this is was the problem we wanted
others on this time
then about the relocation okay there's
another one of the mechanism does that a
zero are also also addresses is there a
location of cells so location is clearly
defined on the for III section of six P
draft so which is the mechanization
would I should first over there and it
only decides when okay I said zero only
it says when their cells should be
relocated according to the packet
delivery rate value so we make sure the
hope the the average buckle give a rate
of the whole scale that we have control
on okay and there could be any many as
functions working so they want the part
which is belongs to this scheduling
function we calculate the average and
then we compare each of the cells we are
using okay if there's an increase or
decrease after a specific threshold and
well and of course we have selected
randomly we are going to win to keep
this very simple so that's why there are
main things right get random within the
the dissection is just a random here
there's no specific criteria how to
define which cells are going to relocate
use and there are no transmissions again
okay we react only if the transaction
was unsuccessful we only retry
afterwards because a requirement still
exists so there in order to keep it
simple okay again we don't use the
transmissions a we have kept only one
trigger event so any change in the
number of cells of you cells in fact is
going to trigger this editing function
under that and of course this estimation
argument works again against a specific
neighbor okay so we have a hub trap
shall we check here the number of cells
which are scheduled to each of the
neighbors and the number of you cells
against each of the neighbors so in case
there's a change because once that frame
and the next one we detected and react
accordingly
we were asked also to add a diagram how
it works so there's a trigger event over
there so we collect number of sides to
understand which are the number of cells
which is the number of sides in fact
that we are willing to use we add the
over-provision value know that two
attacks in the future if you need more
of cells or not and and then did we pass
this value to the allocation policy as
well they repair cells but so what
happens our question was what happens
when the over position is zero for
example say if the provision is zero we
cannot detect is there any more use
cells if you are required if there and
possibly that we generate a packet loss
in the queue so that's one of the
problems way of using another provision
of zero so we just had a fixed value for
our provision which is
implementation-specific
and then the the so there are two
thresholds here the two values fact not
result the over provision and SFC ofso
then there's no relationship whatsoever
between them we try to keep the both
thus estimation algorithm and the and
the allocation policy independent
between them so even though the within
the whole mechanism then maybe our
established our relationship between
them at the beginning or we don't define
any any relationship between them so
there's our own provision and there's to
be a threshold at the design when we are
going to change over to add more cells
[Music]
this location policy they won't define
how many and the other way size decide
when to make a change so
about the cell list error handling so f
0 does not handle those errors meaning
that we only if you if there's the only
handle what we are doing okay if there's
the unsuccessful we try again because
the requirement is still active and this
is of course I rather be chosen well
they already knows that timeout value
which were discussed in the previous
draft we have the we have defined a per
transaction timeout value because you
are required to assess scheduled
function however ok there were still
under discussion apparently that if the
time of value should belong to one site
go to the app and the packet delivery
rate definition there was no definitions
beginning of how to measure the packet
linear rate so it's calculated per cell
okay as a percentage of the number of
our knowledge packets okay as successful
and noise mean of course and out of 10
the only fixed value within the whole
track and there's no transmission of
course there as I mentioned before
finally the location policy mechanism
there are the initial value of scheduled
cells implementation specific then at
least a sub 0 threshold number of cells
must be allocated to each of the
neighbours meaning that this is the
initial value that we didn't define me
in the meaning and the gear so at the
beginning and we should be defining in
order to start this and to bootstrap the
process so they we need at least to have
this number of cells to start the
process and oops and finally if you have
any questions about this thank you so I
I have a question for the implementers
in the room who has this implemented
which implementations do have this SF 0
I think thankful you have it does come
we have that before but doesn't notice
abortion not diversion okay do who has
any version of us have zero implemented
is it yes taka a portal yeah I implement
this one the two I think the previous I
think the dust yes or last one or
something the base on their quantity
okay okay yeah so there are two
implementations in in the room that have
a zero and and have has anybody deployed
is at scale and not just three nodes on
a desk but but deployed is that scale
and verified or measured how how good
this works no okay so there's no answer
so I think I think they go per our
discussion you know yeah last IETF as
well yes I mean these edit what you
presented our editorial changes making
things clear and we can keep doing this
for ITF after idea verse right yeah
right
what is needed is is you know I'm I'm a
company and I look at this and I say you
know I have a smart dis smart that
application is sm0 going to be good
enough I mean how much you know if I
switch on my notes how long will they
take to join if I send it back it what's
the average max min max Lane see how
much data we need that kind of results
um you know especially because this is
zero so this is the this is the default
one and so we want to be it to be good
enough so I you know again we need
evaluation so so it's good it's good to
their implementations but there needs to
be effort and as editor I mean I
understand that you might not be I mean
or you might but if you're not the one I
you know go go find people who who will
deploy this either in simulation or I
mean we need we need results
yeah I think we need to advertise that
because there is a large component of
research we can actually be associated
to this work this is kind of the base
upon which a lot of research can happen
I mean where do the sales come from how
do we get known in interfering cells
that can be allocated by different
routers how do we avoid oscillations in
their location and their locations would
be stupid to spend our time in 6p
allocating and deallocating things I
know you get new thresholds there how do
you said that the last time we had the
discussion about the opportunity to make
this an experimental RFC and I like this
hedger because now we have we have
written to the world a there is a base
on which we'd like you to be out there
is what we would like you to experiment
with and be on about if we don't publish
it then people will say ok there is this
thing but I don't know where it is I
don't know what state it is it's a
choice it's also there's a time when we
are happy enough to kind of cast in
stone that okay it's not a solid track
document but at least it's the base on
which we want to work and I hadn't got
the impression that last time that's
pretty much where we well the idea of
finishing this as experimental now if
you care about the name sf0 looking
lightly that's wow that's it side of
that could be to rename it
but having publishing this this base
let's let's use that as the base of the
work about you know how we make those
decision of allocation de-allocation
I think we need it I think it's good to
throw that at you know Academy on say a
all those points are fantastic research
please help so Tomas says you know this
is a discussion we need to have a scale
of course I have a I have a problem
having the 0 SF being experimental I
mean what message does this send out i
yeah this is a you know all the work we
do here is is you know is for industrial
critical that net kind of things and
having the default won't be experimental
you know doesn't stand out yeah
so it's where she had some so input jvic
arresters do you have it no ok so just
another point what um it would be good
to evaluate the interaction of SF with
six
be-because 6p has a delay on the
allocation and no you have to take into
account that while you asked for it
takes some time to get it and maybe what
you ask it doesn't make sense yeah so
there's a relation that that needs to be
taken to come suresh krisshnan so if not
this then what right so what becomes as
a zero so like we have do we have
something in play I don't know right
like so think of that first thing second
thing is like if you want to make this
experimental that's okay but I would
like to see what the experiment is right
sure like what are you actually trying
to collect like the trap doesn't have
anything like that so like just putting
something in experimental like
previously like a couple of years ago
used to be a way of lowering the bar of
review saying like oh this is
experimental like you know people take a
lighter read of the draft I didn't I use
you and everything but I think it's more
valuable to actually document what is
the experiment what are you gonna
collect and like what are you gonna do
with it right and if you decide to go
the experimental path and I will support
it just make sure that like you know
what do you want to figure out like you
know like you what are the things you
want to collect and how you want to
bring it back to Sanders track in the
future yeah yeah James thanks thank you
thanks Josh there are other accepts in
being without I need more questions for
you thank you so this brings us to the
other part which is not I meant dynamic
scheduling which is the work on security
and you'll have to to theme to things to
talk about
first minimal security and then Richard
Michael will come in with a second draft
right good afternoon my name is up my
name is militia I'm the editor of the
minimal security draft which is the
OneTouch procedure for secure enrollment
in 60 networks yep so we published
0:03 version on June 15 and I was mostly
busy with the implementation efforts
in open wsn and the good news is that we
have no as thank very sad we had we have
an implementation complete in open WS an
environment and an ongoing
implementation in Kentucky base and
pre-shared keys I will go through the
summary of updates that we did in all
three since the last IDF and then I will
show some of the updates that I did that
I intend to do based on the
implementation experience so first there
is a couple of there was a couple of
exchanges on the mailing list
regarding the communication how
communication proceeds during the
drawing process so I wanted to clarify
this and I will make an attempt to
clarify it in the draft basically we
have a pledge which is or in all
terminology the joining node which is
pre-configured with locally relevant
credentials such as a pre shared key or
a row locally relevant certificate we
have a 1:1 hop radio neighbor of the
pledge or the three terminus joint proxy
and the join register and the
coordinator which is the central entity
that manages the drawing process the
pledge in the drawing proxy communicate
over a link local addresses and this
will be important for the later slides
is to note that pledge only needs to
know the address of the joint proxy the
drawing proxy however needs to know the
address of the jrc and there was one
issue that I would discuss later how DRC
finds out the address of how drawing
rocks he finds out the address of the
jrc the path from the pledge to the
drawing proxy Islay is insecure in what
concerns layer 2 security and it's
passes over secure and if I and the path
from drawing proxy to the Dre IRC is the
mesh part that is secured a layer to
secure a 15-4 this is Thomas
want to clarify it says insecure
layer to insecurity but there's an end
right yes yeah oh yeah definitely so
it's layers we know secure so it's clear
or the frames are sent in
clear on layer 2 but they are protected
end-to-end that the application layer
using go swap the joint frames and the
frames of the DRAM protocol so the first
update that we did is regarding who
initiated the security handshake where
we are using ad hoc from yet to be
determined a group so basically we went
from left to the right variety and we
removed one one exchange at in order to
remove one exchange we have the pledge
now that is initiating the ad hoc D etat
can shake where jrc can respond with an
optional sac which is defined in coop as
meaning that okay hang on I will respond
to you later on in the process
and this can be useful in in the use
cases where are there are many
concurrent requests by multiple pledges
on the GRC and the GRC wants to
alleviate the alleviate the load that is
on the network by signaling those to the
pledge to hold to hang on and wait this
is of course optional with pre-shared
keys and mandatory with a symmetric keys
the Hinda handshake is so right now to
come back to the initial point of how
pledge or the drawing proxy learns the
JR sees address as ice drawing proxy
essentially plays the role of a co-op
proxy and stateless lis forwards the
requests and realized the responses back
to the pledge for this we use an option
that is defined in my co-op option that
is defined in minimal security that we
term stateless proxy option and but the
issue is how the drawing proxy knows the
ipv6 address of the GRC and thanks to
Michael oh if I remember right we settle
down for this approach where basically
the the the address of the GRC is
returned in the join response
factor such that the pledge at the time
of the joint pledge learns that the
address of the the jrc and we did an
important optimization in the most
common use case which is when when GRC
is co-located with the dag root to omit
the data to the the ipv6 address of the
GRC in order and implied from the dog ID
so basically when a pledge drawings in
order to fully complete the drawing
process it needs to receive at the i/o
with the dog ID and then it configures
the the address of the GRC and one
assumption there is that the dagger root
is pre-configured with the address for
the whole process to kick off we had the
discussion in the security design team
about MTI algorithms to support and
Inter we mostly discussed the symmetric
part and we we quite easily settle down
for the CCM star equivalent in cozy so
this is a SCCM 16 64 128 it has eight
byte authentication tag and in terms of
non non non flanked it corresponds to
the 15 for CCM so that we can reuse the
same hardware for symmetric encryption
on the application layer as we do for
link layer security in terms of hash we
said we in the draft currently we
mandate sha-256 and in terms of
asymmetric keys we mandate the P 256
elliptic curve and ECDSA signature
algorithm but this is prone to change I
would like to discuss this further maybe
during the meeting if we want to support
the two 5519 curve Edward skur if this
would be useful as there were some
discussions today in in das meeting
about that so let me come back to the
implementation status in the open WS n
ecosystem we implemented the minimum
security with pre-shared keys and we
finished the implementations of
Oh boss co-op in Python and minimal
security the jrc part in Python as well
as the embedded part or squat in C and
minimal security Oh tree in C in what
concerns pledge and the drawn proxy and
the draft is fully implemented apart
from the asymmetric variety in contour
is also an independent of implementation
ongoing in Kentucky that we try to test
during the practice it is still
incomplete but it is ongoing and it will
soon be completed I'm so in terms of the
implementation experience I found a
couple of issues when trying to
implement this the first issue was
regarding the packet size and the most
critical was the drawing response that
comes down from the from the dag route
to the first hop into the into the
network because of the source routing
header and basically with this the due
to the join response payload if we
assume no fragmentation in the network
we are hitting the maximum limit of the
network in terms of the depth that we
can reach so this is so it's extremely
important that we optimize this in order
to build deep networks and my my
understanding is that wireless heart for
the moment goes up to eight hops dibs I
was able to test with six hop with five
hops in the with six hops but from the
notes way from the same manufacturer
which you know which compresses the
source routing header quite efficiently
so sorry
some clarifying question so you're
trying to measure how deep the network
can be until the moment when you have to
fragment right so there is no hard limit
it's just that starting at five what did
you say stops with random say five hops
all right if you have seven hops it will
work but you'll have to fragment yes
that's correct the the packets okay so
assuming there's no fragmentation in my
packet I have in yeah
Paquette I have a source route which
which lists the different hops to go
through followed by a bunch of headers
followed by the encrypted Oscorp payload
right and yes okay and so is is is there
anything we can do to that or is no
slide about that yes I have done the
next slide I have the dissection and the
packet dissection basically with the
join response in the case with five five
hops downwards and as you can see we
have the source routing header at the
beginning and these are some
modifications that I had to do in order
to make it work so I use the token
length set to zero in coop which is
which is allowed in co-op spec which is
allowed in coops work in certain
circumstances that fits very well with
the drawing process
I removed the content format option from
the draft in my local copy I still this
is still not present in all three so the
join response does not contain the
content format option but this is
implied I think from the in terms of
pledge because we are defining the
protocol on top yes it does contain a
URI the join response does not it
contains the message ID the message ID
the message ID so the pelagic is able to
match the yes it was note from that
message ID that that yes format is kind
of well known yes
so I think
Pascal I think is gonna say roading her
I think that if we had Dow projections
that we could shorten the rotor and
Kettering header but you could tell me
whether I'm wrong about that and you
said I think the routing header could be
further compressed too he's just said
right yeah okay this is pascal and there
are two venues that we can look at now
to make this a bit deeper without
fragmentation first one is is the way
you allocate your addresses and the way
you build them and the way they are ah
because I see there that you seem to be
using a six relish with is that four
octet that you're using so I did not
implement six flourish so yes it's
thankful but yeah it is but the question
is you know there are multiple ways to
compress the address what makes them
more compressible is if they share more
bytes you know if everybody builds on
the same thing and the best way to have
everybody build on the same thing is
really linked to what you're doing it's
because if you if you harm the short
address
yeah then you can derive you can make
sure that our unique along a path
because this is the route to win both
does everything in its own right so you
can derive shot address every hobbies to
work that's but I don't think I'm seeing
hops off to act I see I don't know how
to read what you're right but I think
that you're using frog that's per hop
and if you read your eye stuff from the
shorter dress and you sign the shop to
try so you know you think well then you
should be able to use a six or average
with twelve dates per hop so that's one
Avenue the other venue is as long as
your network is not too big and that
that will that will step in the future
but that's the point that Michael was
making there is a draft in the making a
troll which is basically saying okay
you're doing on storing because you know
we don't we know you don't have so much
room but actually actually I can shorten
the sauce rot headers by having just a
little bit of state that the route
decides to install into particular
devices so now it's not like an
explosion of state because the route can
maintain how much state it installs
but that you can really use that to have
a little bit of storing which again will
shorten your
right path and in part well you can
decide where you place this debt etc
that would be a limit Michael because
these things finds us a tree and at some
point you know you don't have as enough
state so you can't you can't shut down
every path to everybody but that that
can be a tool if your network is not
well balanced and you have a direction
where a lot of things go then you can
shorten you know this and I'm thinking
particular in am ia more use cases where
you've got those long lines of matters
along a straight and typically for that
the rod projection thing will save a lot
and then you can you without the
fragment connection you can authenticate
all the metals along the street without
taking a problem between so the good
news is this is orthogonal to the draft
I mean this is showing the full
dissection but it's orthogonal what is
not implemented in on the implemented in
our implementation currently is the
assignment of short analysis to the
stack so this will further save but I
think it's already good news that we can
go down five hops without without
fragmentation yes yes just just a
clarifying question I think we have to
stop after that so the number is the
five hops that is assuming eui-64 s are
used in source a header i understand you
then allied them if the beginning is the
same but this is assuming you are 60 or
64-bit addresses right to inquire yes
link layer yeah
yes okay so this will go down if we
goodness to bite yes and this is another
thing that we can improve basically this
is dissection sibour dissection of the
join response sabor decoding of the
drawing response and we are currently
using 26 bytes to encode 16 byte key and
one byte key ID so it's quite an
overhead and one proposal would be to
use the binary encoding to compress the
drawing response in something like what
they did in or scope with the compressed
cosy so that would be one proposal that
I would like to discuss also during the
meeting and the sec
this shoe that I find quite important is
the drawing proxy policy and although I
understand that we will not stand up as
a policy in ITF there is a problem of
how join proxy accepts those insecure
layer two frames at the during the joint
process because in the implementation
currently I had to allow it from any
node that I haven't seen before and this
can be easily spoofed such that an
arbitrary node can inject packets into
the network so the proposal is to
include to provide the mechanism to
accept insecure alert to frames only
upon a trigger and I think this is where
Michaels draft fits very well in terms
of the flag in terms of one flag that we
will use to signal that the drawing
process is allowed so basically the idea
would be for the final implementation
that upon about a button to button press
in the beacon we include the information
element with the joint process flag set
that we can use to to accept in secure
layer two frames and expired upon a time
out yes Pascal again I think it's a very
classical to have a few word in a draft
like that with which size throttle like
never accept any quantity in your amount
have and it's not necessarily a value
but that there is something which says
Oh any sense sensible implementation
will will have a mechanism to short out
the request you just take as many per
unit of time or so oh it's one sentence
you want it yeah so I understand to two
things one address at the sentence would
rather talk about throttle just the name
throttle it's already there I believe
okay sorry
and and and and have this mechanism to
switch on and off based either joint
proxy feature of the mode okay yeah so
that would be it so basically the PSK
variant is quite stable and
implementation ready and we have the
implementation and open WS and complete
we settle down for ad hoc roles in the
automatic
but it we have yet to implement this and
I will publish all four draft with
implementation experience before what I
hope to be the working group last call
and the reviews are of course very
welcome
a quick note that at the moment there
are two drugs that are that we depend
upon to have this work and maybe Michael
can come out a bit but there are debates
at this moment and there will be a lunch
on Wednesday about whether a dark in
particular and then there is a draft I
Peter as well that we need whether they
should have a home at the ATF and
without the F will endorse that this
work continue continues and obviously
will be pushing for this thing to happen
right yeah okay great okay thank you any
questions for militia thank you and to
finish the security Michael hi so um
that's not the right side here
interesting they'll never work okay in
the end so I have to look here all right
so I get my car in front of me so the
goal is zero touch joint protocol and
it's supposed to look very much like the
enema brewski would work but optimized
for six Tish and minimized and you're
using methods and protocols that we
already have code space for so in news
the Enver voucher document which is the
document that allows in zero touch the
pledge to understand that this is in
fact the network that it belongs to
these are in fact the droids you're
looking for
is is actually I said almost working
group last call but actually it it
written group last call was over and it
was actually supposed to be done in
parallel with this working group and
that was actually a mistake
so that's very good all right I think it
may take uh it's been through I think it
may take a little while to get through
the iesg
um but I anticipate by the end of the
summer I think it probably will be out
so that's good for us
the anima burski document was rewritten
in april/may um and you can come
tomorrow and learn about that if you
like but the key thing is that the the
the structure of it is now stable it's
about 15 page short pages shorter that's
always good and our document which
parallels it now has to be rewritten in
that same style and so that's on my
to-do list
Michael if you say come tomorrow you
mean to anima yeah anima yes I'm sorry -
anima yes
so as Pascal mentioned we need ad hoc ad
hoc will be our our asymmetric key
management protocol that we need to run
it it it could go in ace it could go in
other places and some area directors are
going to have lunch and they're gonna
figure out what's going on and and so
that's taken a fair number of cycles to
convince people that there's a problem
to be solved here both the problem of
where the document goes and a problem
that the document actually solves that
we need so the next steps are
essentially as I said - - we're
rewriting
brueski with with with six Tish in mind
there's already a document that we have
already but you know it it essentially
it's been it's been cut up into pieces
and and pieces have gone elsewhere I've
gone into six Tish minimal I've gone
into other places I've gone into Bruschi
and things like this and so now it's
time to rewrite a document that
basically we actually can pass as
opposed to just a collection of texts
and ideas and essentially that's it so
you see does this work yeah you can't
see that remotely so TLS becomes Edie
Hawk HT becomes co-op and the minimal
security joiners request is the is is
bootstrap with the ad-hoc protocol
so when you read the documents you
should see essentially you should be
able to put the two documents next to
each other and say oh yes so in brewski
for big equipment you do this and for
small equipment you do this and there
would be a kind of a one-to-one then
that should be I'll just make everyone
happy so that they say okay is
essentially the same protocol
conceptually but on the wire if the bits
are are much smaller and faster or
slower yeah so huh small bits just the
bits are the saint that the same number
of bits but they're smaller yes that's
right and and I'd like to change I'd
like to change the document to to
include the word zero-touch in the title
and actually I'd like to change the the
the internet draft name to include that
as well I think that will be simpler but
that probably that may require the
blessing of the chairs or maybe they'll
describe decide the whole working group
has to decide but so what I would like
to do is change the name of the document
so related document so with some some
things that as we were working on both
six dish minimal and zero touch we
realized there are some things that were
not specifically in related to the
security but that the security needed so
the two of them are we have one is this
enhanced beacon document and so this is
an additional information element which
we can now allocate care of that RFC
that you announced the beginning of the
meeting and so we can put some
additional information in the beach and
so the specific things that we needed to
we wanted to put in was essentially
there's a bit that says I am a joint
proxy okay and there's another bit that
says I'm a router so which means please
don't send a if you're a leaf node not a
routing node please don't send a router
solicitation eating up a multicast saw a
slot you can unicast one to me and I'll
answer you okay and that saves a lot of
you know multicast broadcast lots are
are pretty pretty precious and we don't
really want to use them up for stuff we
have to
them for da O's and so the the specific
enhancement that the join part was in
fact a preference you know how how
willing am I to to allow pledges to join
and so the suggestion is essentially is
that if there's a maximum number 255
that it means I'm not willing to have
proxies joining and as a result if you
propagate this through the beacon from
the DOE Dagon if the DOE tag happens to
say 255 then at the root says that then
everyone else is gonna have to say well
obviously the DOE tag doesn't want
anyone joining so none of the rest of us
should let anyone join and so in effect
the doubt the the ripple root can turn
off join processing through the thing
it's a good idea or not it seems like a
good work for me such information could
also be in the rippled eio as another
possibility crippled the iOS don't
necessarily propagate us as often sort
of a Michael sort of a mix yes if I'm a
new joining note I don't understand it
the iOS there if you're an if you're a
pledge you don't hear this at all well
you he's right if you're a pledge you
hear this yes but not the iOS
yes but the point is we could turn off
the announcement of this bit
it's what militia wants to do we could
do that indie iOS oh yeah okay the point
is that then it could also be done by
the fact that that all the nodes all of
the the routing nodes from the root down
are also sending beacons regularly right
and so this could also be transmitted
that way but I I love the edge I think
we need a quick draft at all which will
say oh basically the route is a Josie
and here is its preference and then as
you propagate this new option in the DAO
the the the nodes can only reduce the
value that you find in that bit oh so
you'd rather do it in idea rather than
in a beacon oh yeah because yeah it has
to be because it's linked to route yeah
it is a property of the route and then
it says property of the sub dag to be
able to use that route as a chioce in
the first place right yeah we've got
this compression which is more efficient
if the route is a
you need to know that somebody has to
signal it and it can only be the route
some point we secure those things and
the route will securely say I am a
jersey of Netaji us it belongs to what
the route exposes and what to the device
is for now if you want to be able to
announce part of that to the joining
node yes you take it from the DAO
as proxy you have it and you expose that
on the lower layer but but you need to
get it from repo so you're suggesting we
get it from in the on/off from ripple
rather than right it's a reference
there's a preference regionally
originally we also were not believing
that the preferences were necessarily
decreasing as you got away from the reap
route that's not necessarily but it
cannot amount so so the the the scenario
is that that I had envisioned is where
you had some diagram would help here
where you had some dense intermediate a
bunch of mesh okay where there was quite
a number let's say two to two ranks down
there's quite a number of devices and
the device says look I can here six
other beacons willing to do proxy my
battery's low
I'm not going to announce okay because I
can hear that there's other other will
other willing participants who have
obviously higher more battery so my
batteries too low I'm not going to help
that's not a process procedure you can
describe it as well usse trickier and
all those things and put the weight on
trickles which is based on your
batteries what would en out what would
that note announce downwards well what's
your notes on the DI you and what you
know and what you announce on your
beacon off to the noise
yes I agree so so maybe that what you're
saying is that the the ripple value
cannot increase cannot not the but that
in local you can decide to make your ear
and an e value much much lower or less
secure less trellis much bigger and then
you actually decide we should be
consistent with the other piece I mean
you can I would really use zero as no
because it's false I
and increasing it makes Oh better I mean
it's always this game of which is bad
with some other with low rank gets
bigger bigger ranks are worse so I think
we should make it consistent with that
so it's almost yes the drunk Rd increase
increases higher join parody actually
means less priority right so higher
number is less priority i I think you
know the joint proxy is a and this is my
personal opinion ah that's why I'm here
so the joint proxy feature is a 15-4 ET
SCH feature so III don't see why we
should start mingling this with ripple
and what not I mean I can run a 54
Network 54 HT ACH network without ripple
and and you know why are we doing this
like across everything so so propagate
this on off we left when that on the
meaning is because it's a fantastic
topic actually okay but it's mostly I
mean basically the view of it and then
the delay of to view of it so yes we
keep them independent but to find sense
like just the ability to turn it on/off
kenseth make sense that the global to
your dark level right because the GOC
wants to be a G or not or it's busy D at
this time and and it wants to come back
and and find since there are just too
many things coming in from that
particular network announced rattle it I
don't know maybe you your link for
instance the the preference with with
kind of the throttling level so by
pushing your di OS and the lower
preferences you will ask the distributed
process is to throttle more and there's
a lot of thing you can do if you signals
for repo how to do it but that's the
repo level that's a layer 3 global level
and then at the local level the node can
take this you know doing even less but
it cannot take this this is not doing
more you see it's not the same in every
nothing more case and feel the network
won't support
more so that's the point that the node
can can use up to the amount the network
whatever the units will be there go
ahead
this is malicious so I would just like
to say that I agree with the layer to
view because the the problem with the
the implementation was only how to
configure the exempt flag in 802 the
15.4 so basically when to accept
insecure packets at layer 2 and
everything else is taken care of by the
ipv6 forwarding and the the join
protocol so I would rather do it very
simply with the enhance beaker with the
flag depending only locally on the join
proxy is not to remove that the proposal
is to say a if you want to propagate
something about a more global knowledge
then then we need a way to do it as well
for instance the way you throttle is
discussed ok there is some some blinds
rattling to happen well maybe the level
is depends on network wide
metrics like how many people are trying
to join at this time so each GN should
slow down more because too many people
are coming here and that's not something
that an individual layer 2 can know and
the one thing I really opposed is that
you learn something from your parent at
layer 2 because you don't know in which
direction propagates you need to learn
it from your layer 3 parent just like we
do for that yeah that may be a really
good point you need to learn it from
your layer 3 parent so from a process
point of view I believe following the
ionic considerations in 6550 we can
allocate new ripple d io options that's
not a problem we don't have to go to
role to do that the question is should
we do it in this document which is
defining a layer 2 object should we
define a layer 3 object at the same time
because we're still the
extensions to these hands beacon for the
pledge to listen to right because that's
a bit like that's Carol yet the question
we have about what's coming up for six
stop right at some point we may end off
sixth up to I Triple E and if this
document is a single document then only
go file for it will be a lot more
complicated right so so you'd like to
documents well I'm just no I didn't say
that I just just put one one of the
Lawrence on the table for those
viewing at home Thomas has just pulled
out a really large bottle of Cola
because he anticipates a long
conversation now I have no particular
preference either way but like we can do
it both ways if both of them are
possible so if you want to do it in one
document and we can probably do a joint
last call in here under all bugginess is
like yeah yeah I'm not worried about
that process I'm worried about what the
you know about handing off or whatever
so the other point is this document has
not been adopted so we good to adopt it
as it is and then if you want we want to
have a tell I will write as another
document that talks about the layer
three option okay and then if if you
want to make it one document yeah
so I hey I'd like we cannot adopt right
now but I'd like to get a feel from the
room about whether you think it's a good
idea why do you think it's not a good
idea so those who think it's this draft
the draft drawing and how about enhanced
beacon joining new Intel proxies you
exist so who alleges that proxies exist
so who who read the draft we have
over there behind the pillar yeah a
little maybe ten people a little less
than ten people eight people okay among
those who read it who objects well yeah
okay so who who thinks adopting this
this draft within the workgroup is a
good ID please raise your hand now who
opposes to the idea of adopting this
word document within the word group
please raise your hand now okay so the
same people who read it will raise their
hands and we did not have all right oh
they don't see behind the pillars I
don't have the eyes but what somebody
behind the pillar raising your hand for
the no question no or no answer there's
no hands up for know okay that's
interesting important information for us
thank you okay so I have well I let's
write the document and then and then you
can see what it says okay because I
think that'll be two pages to start so
the other document that came out of or
was removed from the the zero touch in
one touch document was rekeying okay my
slide so this is intended to be a Comey
based thing leveraging a key that was
set up ideally through through the OS
co-op used for or a so sorry leveraging
the key setup either through ed hawk or
the existing keys that were one touch
okay so that there's no additional key
management overhead that's happening
this way how that works as remains to
determine um so basically it is you know
you have your network wide key um you
have a key ID for it one okay um I
believe we have in minimal we have
eliminated key one key to I can't
remember if we did
it's not specified so we leave the
possibility to return multiple keys and
run response right so so that the
there's if we're gonna very we have to
return two key IDs so you have key one
and key to that maybe sorry ID one and
ID to that responds to six dish minimal
x' key one key to k1 k2 and then we have
to rekey them which involves giving
everyone a new set of keys and then um
when the dough DeGroot believes the jrc
believes that it has communicated with
enough nodes preferably all of them but
maybe there are some that just there no
one exists anymore it's given up on them
at which point starts using the new keys
and when it starts using the new keys
that's a signal to all other nodes that
have the new keys to stop using the old
keys so we have a basically a rolling
rekey there so first of all the first
step is that everyone gets a new key and
then the next step is that we use it and
actually the third kind of step as we
tell it them to delete the old keys but
actually put a timer on that so this is
all intended to be essentially Komi
based which is simple management over
co-op as the based on a yang model it's
relatively small and simple in terms of
bytes used and that's a second document
so Peter and I have done some work on
that nor work needs to be done I don't
think either of us have looked at the
document since last IETF maybe peter has
I don't remember I have I have heard
that that the situation you know this
working group tried to use Comey for 6p
and we weren't happy with it at the time
and that it has gone in the last four
years gone through a significant change
and it's much much easier and smaller to
deal with and so that's a good thing and
it's probably the right answer from a
IETF why you know what are we doing are
with management kind of thing why would
you need to rekey well either because
you actually care about crypto hygiene
and want to recycle your keys now and
then or be because there's some node in
your network which has gone bad and the
only way you have of cutting them off
from your network is to change everyone
else
key so that's the the oh I need to
move move I need to get rid of of malar
from my network okay so that's pretty
important but rekeying is going to take
recognize that rekeying means talking to
every single node with at least a couple
packets and getting a response from them
and you can do it slowly
it could happen over hours or even days
depending on the bitrate of your network
but that the slower you do it the longer
you have a bad guy on your network okay
so that's the like the caveat there's no
the document doesn't say how fast to do
it that's up to you that's gonna be you
know quality of implantation or
something like that to do it so that's
this document so we're completely out of
time oh okay I'm sorry I thought this
was earlier in the document and well
that's good so that's a second document
please read it if you think that it
belongs in this working group then I
would love to have a mailing list
discussion about that yeah and who's
shabby no Simon
Seymour so thank you thank you my phone
is so weird no more questions for
Michael okay so now we're entering in
the last we're right on time because we
jumped one ten-minute thing so we're
right on time we're now entering the if
time permits and time permits
section we have four new work that is
the first time I believe that they're
being presented
so Seymour has a scheduling function
called a SF tour zeroes thank you so so
yeah sorry one thing that's important
please keep your time uh you have ten so
switching back to the scheduling topic
here what we are proposing is a
scheduling function called AES F which
stands for autonomous scheduling
function where you have two main
concepts the first one is that you have
autonomous slot frames or spot
friendlies
cells in them which means that in the
SWAT frame you have cells that are self
maintained locally by the node only by
the knowledge of the neighborhood so the
basic idea there is that the at the node
you know your neighborhood and you know
the MAC addresses of your neighbors and
you're going to use the MAC address and
to hash it to actually find out a slot
and channel offset deterministically to
communicate with that node the second
concept in a SF is that you have one
slot frame Pro traffic plain typically
one for the teach synchronization one
for the routing control one for the
application but you could have a bit
already as many as you want and each one
benefit of that is that is so these lot
frames are isolated completely by design
so they don't interact with one another
the SWAT frame length is going to
dimension your schedule like in any
store I'm but the key design point here
is that because you have one slot frame
for traffic plain you can very easily
dimension the traffic capacity for
explaining the applications of that are
mostly distributed routing network so
that was everything takes basically
distributed like in the Ripper Network
and we have very extensive
experimentation of these ASF in testbed
with over 200 experiments in three
different testbed ranging from 25 to 380
nodes and we demonstrate of June 5 9 s
with a ability in that context with
ripple both storing an on storing mode
abroad and or not trafficking now this
comes obviously with major limitations
which I wanted to highlight here
it's a least suboptimal for few reasons
the three main reason are on the slide
number one the cells are not cascaded
along the past you cannot do very quick
forwarding a to be followed by B 2 B 2 C
etc the slots are all shell we don't
have and the schedule is always provided
for the worst case so you going to be
you have to choose between energy
efficiency incapacity you cannot
dynamically add more cells for traffic
between a and B if suddenly you need
more traffic between A&B I'm going to
show here a brief overview of each of
the three different types of such frames
we have three types the first one the
simplest one is absolutely equivalent to
the sixties minimum so you basically
have a start frame here in that case you
have a single slot which is used for a
reception transmission it's a shared
spot and all know that's a rendezvous
slot so all the nodes are waking up at
the same time same channel offset and
this is used typically for unable
discovery it's just for any broadcast
communication with node you do not know
yet so it's it's used most often at the
defaults not frame and forwards in
control data so if you're on the side
you see only four channel offset so the
one thing that for each of the stratum
you have in a staff we actually dedicate
a subset of the 16 or of the M available
slots for channel offsets so here in
that example we have a that that's what
frame has four channel up set to play
with the second one is the receiver base
last time in which is used for unicast
communication in that one the nodes
maintain well they have one static
receive but which called OBC base they
have one static receive slot here the
green one at the channel of certain time
of self is on the hash of the of the MAC
address of the node and then for each
neighbor which is unknown by the 886
neighbor cash for each neighborhood you
compute the hash of the Mac and that
gives you coordinate sin x and y for a
transmitted shared slot that name it's a
shot slot because you have multiple
senders every one also because you might
have multiple nodes listening on the
same because the hash is not clear area
the last one is a sender by slot frame
the exact same thing except that now the
cell that is fixed is for sending so you
have always once sell based on a hash of
own MAC address and then you maintain a
receive cells
for the other note that you want to
listen to and that is typically used for
privileged neighbors such as the teach
time source or a poor parent because it
gets more costly if you do it you cannot
you could also choose to do it for all
neighbors
it gets more costly because then you
need to listen to all neighbors it's a
little more cost in energy so this is
all put together that's so as I was
saying before you have one member
traffic plane each dot same as diff
different subset of channel offset and
that way to isolate and the SWAT friends
have each different size and we
recommend the size to be co-prime so
that when they repeat they do so
independently and the slots are going to
overlap every now and then but they do
it in a uniformly distributed way when
that happens the I Triple E President's
rule for all slots is actually used
meaning TXE has higher priority than an
Rx and smaller slots from handling has
higher priority this is study draft so
we have a description of different slots
from tax we have a definition of how the
coordinates the cells are computed we
have an example schedule of the voice
for slot frames we have definition of
all the configuration parameters you
want to take the question now I was no
previous like I can write yes well there
is this habit to use different slot
frames pascal's we have four different
priorities
I was just wondering since you're making
different slots fives is if you keep
them or align time wise or because there
is this risk risk of a collision so at
some point you would say a what if I
could use some CSMA in there and I was
just wondering if since you have so many
of them you constantly use them as a
priority now they kind of most of them
are the same priority like traffic now
some of them may still the aya priority
like like the time and you may be
thinking oh those which are higher
priority I may synchronize them a bit
ahead of time like two milliseconds
before the lower ones so if there is you
you can still do some form of CSU mail
I'm just now you get this possibility
I'm just asking sure using
I'm not sure it's possible to do that in
compliance with the Tripoli 15-4 IDO not
defense what is your main or
desynchronisation of this rostrum right
which is can you have different
friends which are not synchronized yeah
I think Pascal means different slot
frames same slot structure yeah just
slot frames of different lengths that
are well know they start the minute if
you have like an epoch right
don't use well I've a different epochs
which which are shifted by like two
milliseconds for different soldiers I
was wrong you cannot do that no oh they
would be independent networks well they
are mostly right yes so do that beyond
independent networks but it's just the
same for everything just shifted back to
me a second so that the I probably it's
always there first and you can always
detect it it's just yeah but on the
other hand we also have different
channel of set religious zealots frame
so whenever you start listening you
actually are on one particular channel
so you will not start hearing from from
one that starts a bit earlier on you you
will like you know when you start
receiving which one you're actually
listening out anyway so that you have
collisions right even and and there is
no no thing which will make a higher
priority transmission at a better chance
than the lower priority you don't have
any other media I don't even have or
between transmission in the same slot
frame because all the short frames here
must have different channel offset
meaning they will rely on the same
physical channel that's one particular
point in time but but you might have a
mode might have multiple things to do at
one given point in time in which case I
Triple E president's designing takes
over the eye yeah so the only collision
you're happy they scheduled level
collision aids which protects and the
prime numbers are bad luck this day then
but the highest priority is going to be
alone it takes precedence so it's going
to be the only one transmitted at the
time
the soft frames the soft frame has a
handle and these specify the priority so
yeah I think I think that's I think that
works and and I proposed you guys are
not talking about the same collisions
Pascal is talking about a collision on
the radio between nodes and you're
talking about collisions between
schedules on the same note mmm having
disconnected discussion okay
this was Dominic thank you very so a
question so thank you for oh so we have
a definition of configuration parameters
one thing that's not defined yet is how
to how to discover that configuration
there are two options the preferred one
currently would be to have a new
information in amount in EB so because
it's a join time thing so as you join
the network you should know which slots
friend we're gonna have and how to
maintain them so here what I mean in the
world that tell you what are the length
of strata frame which which says our
receiver base Center base which one's a
rendezvous etc the other option is to do
it with sixty comments yeah overloading
yep and yeah feedback design itself and
what the traffic should cover how to
discover configuration and so on so so I
have a single question has this been
evaluated yeah it's been evaluated
experimentally with like many
experiments are three different as bad
up to 280 node five nines reliability
movie okay any questions thank you
thanks for staying in time thank you
very much next on is Darden on success
examples
hello I like to talk about these six
teach examples and this draft was but
this document was written like two years
ago
then the protocols have evolved some
other protocols appear so we needed to
update this document the goal of this
document is just to provide a reference
for new implementers to like how cystic
frames should look like so here we see
different cystic Franks in this document
okay and what in order to read this
document we have we use two tools we use
open WM project using the open aureus
and framework and also the open dahlias
and visualizer as a simulation and also
using wireshark the latest release which
implements a situation dissection and
six stop detection as well here we see
the date apology of the simulation note
so we use three nodes in simulation
being not one day de bruit not to win
the child of night one and no to being
the parent of note 3 so once the network
is formed
Varsha will capture every single frame
exchange between within the nodes here's
the third of contents of this document
so he will see all the all the examples
of the frames of safety so if you see
here we have it has become our PL Dao
and the IO and a garage friends we have
icmpv6 echo request and reply and all
the sick 6p comments well now like to
give you just a small example of one
frame which was in this document so it's
not one in on three so yeah so here we
see not one destination - not one ping
in on three through
not number two so here we see
destination is well number no.2 in the
frame layer we see note 1 in the source
in this in the source and then we see
here the destination is well not 3
so here no to past the frame 2 node 3
and then just the reply the replied
going for 3 to 2 and then the reply
going for 2 to 1
well this is a very simple drop of yeah
all the all the Cystic frames necess
Texas this week will deliver a version
number 3 with including 150 comment list
we was missing we we did some editor
changes and us a what's next is this
document really useful for implementers
today for to them to have a reference
and if it's working to be adopted as a
working group Thank You Jonathan I want
to add a couple of points here for this
draft this is indeed a copy/paste
exercise of a wireless out Wireshark
output agreed but our experience has
been we've we you publish this a couple
of last couple of eyes years ago it was
used extensively at blood tests it was
then kind of forgotten we didn't update
it it disappeared and at the new block
test we had again the same questions how
does this header fit with this what's
this bit with this byte and I'm I'm uh
you know I I I like the fact that it
shows on paper exactly how the headers
fit one after the other and how exactly
the six large fit with you know that
kind of stuff so you know it in my mind
this is this is definitely informational
but this is something that we could
contemplate us as adopting as a
workgroup document
actually Suresh this is a case where I'd
really like to have your advice so this
is a very useful document for the
implementer twil
should we progress that all the way to
RFC or is it something that the working
group should keep maintaining what kind
of form is the recommended practice for
document like this as Christian so so
personally right like I leave it up to
you for a minute okay but like I'll tell
you what Guilin I'm using myself okay
when I'm talking about this do you think
this will be useful in five years after
its published okay so that's the kind of
like how I judge whether something would
be useful or not if you think it is go
ahead with it if you think it's not like
keep it as a wiki or if you think it's
gonna be outdated a it's gonna be
published don't bother
right like so and I don't want to judge
that for you but that's the kind of
guideline I'm gonna use like because I
wrote that statement along with us some
of the other ideas about the support
documents so I kind of want to follow
like some kind of consistent guidelines
because we see like all kind of things
because there's some working groups that
got shattered like long time ago which
actually chat right and saying these
kind of things so we're having some
difficulty like applying like the same
guideline so if you want to have a new
deliverable for this right that's what
I'm gonna apply so I'm saying okay is
there archival value for this if not no
don't do it as a separate document put
it in the appendix or something or or
wiki or whatever or a draft that's
maintained you decide okay thank you
okay I have another one for Michael very
short there is the use of ripple info
document would that make sense to to
have some some something like that as I
next just to show what's going on those
packets you're asking with the use of
ripple info benefit from having this
text at the end of it yes other cases
that we present some examples that would
really be awesome and it would also
to address what suresh said it would it
would also document the situation as of
now as of that document which is a
standards track document it would be
useful in five years when somebody goes
to implement something that needs to be
compatible with what's with what's
deployed and so even if we do things
after that they would be saying I am
compliant to this particular use of
ripple document in my data plane and
here's some example packets that you can
test with right so that actually would
be awesome just we need to make we need
to make sure that we got the the
relationship between there and that if
there's if there's a bunch of sixth ish
stuff there that it's clearly this is
layer two so if you're not six dish
don't do this
find some other other thing thank you
yeah I think Euler and forever time then
thank you George's and you can you
strictly stick to the dude only one my
name is George George papadopolis and
I'm presenting the draft about
requirements as I rode along with Nicola
Mount Olympus called to bear about
packet replication and elimination in
complex trucks sixty Sh so 60s networks
thought should not be only reliable but
the tarry music as well meaning that the
data packet that is transmitted need to
be are transmitted in predefined and
constant delay right so meaning that we
should exhibit ultra low jitter
performance so assuming that we have our
wireless topology as a source this
destination and the two relays here we
may implement what's called promiscuous
overhearing to do so assuming
considering that we have the wireless
reading which is by nature a broadcast
then any neighbor may overhear this
transmission right so here what I'd like
to pay attention is that in such
scenario we may have a scheduler where
a cell where we are where we are having
a couple of multiple receivers and this
need to be addressed and in addition to
we may have collisions and
acknowledgement right next if we want to
increase the if we want to reduce the do
the performance we may employ in the
packet application where each sixties
are note will transmit each data packet
first to its default button from the
ribbon and what we call here the
alternative parent to increase the
reliability and to reduce the jitter
performance this transmission will take
place in two different unicast while
they may be overseen here we need to pay
attention on the ripple vio message but
potentially we need to be extended to a
low so that each 60 node to have some
additional information about their
potential parents and a list of parents
but we may need to have what we call
here alternative parent next by
employing packet replication it's
straightforward that we are having
duplication so the we we have
unnecessary are trafficking the network
we need to employ what's called
elimination to reduce this unnecessary
traffic to do so each sixties node once
it received the first coffee the first
copy of the data packet it will discuss
the following copies here are esprit 60s
architecture the sequence number is not
65 detector does not take position about
how the sequence projects are tracked in
a packet however it comes with tagging
packets for floated if occasion which
will be great to efficiently apply in
this procedure of packet elimination
here I have a simple example for you
guys to see how looks like the TCH
schedule here I have the cell where I'm
having the source transmits the data
packet and then I'm having the two
receivers so we have things to toggle
with with multiple receivers the
acknowledgment for the from two
different guys so we need to avoid
collisions or whether we need we need to
discuss whether we are going to have one
acknowledgement to acknowledgment or not
knowledge meant and then another thing
that I want to point out here is how s
is going to request from both our
listing it from both destinations these
are this cell there's another thing that
we need to be discussed if we want if
this packet application elimination
procedure is interesting here is a
summary of some of the requirement that
I wrote in the draft that is related
with the alternative party selection so
we are going to talk about ripple in the
i/o message but may imply that may add
some additional information the
promiscuous were hearing again we are
having the the reservation for two
destinations like to judge me the packet
to different destinations how to request
this cell the acknowledge the police how
to avoid collision at this
acknowledgement because we are having
two destinations that are going to
acknowledge the same transmitter and
then how to perform these packet
elimination by employing tagging packet
flow identification efficiently or
whatever here is if some of these were
are willing to review this draft loss
was like basically I'm sure that I'm
having some nice requirements so I will
be doing get this this feedback from you
guys thanks so much so these raise your
hand if you're willing to read and
review this draft all right so you have
at least two volunteer 300 400 years for
it's good and then there's your hand
they're only so that's five volunteers
thank you listen via thank you so thank
you I'm afraid we're out of time thank
you
I'm afraid that we're also out of time
for the last presentations or usual I
understand it I mean you already
presented this the interim meeting I'm
happy to continue discussing the draft
that a follow up injury meaning or on
the main in list but we're running out
of time sorry this traffic yeah and
we're 30 seconds towards the end I think
metadata you wanted to say something
really really quickly yeah sure thank
you busca
thank you I just want to let you know
that at 6 p.m. I will be talking about
an ongoing project founded by Issa where
we are looking out to integrate IOT
network with satellite connection if you
are interested be app if you join it is
in Paris room and I will show to you
what we have done so far and the
defending many results that we have I
think the event would announce it on
some many English already so I will be a
peaceful joy thank you Thank You Maya
and also please be aware that Bobby Lee
who is living now as Center some slides
about the status of the I trip
reactivity or NATO to that 15 and 15 for
in particular and we have no time to be
on them but would be adding them on the
data tracker with the slides of this
meeting so you'll be free to go ahead
and see them thanks Bob for the slides
and with this I'd like to close the
meeting thank you very much