yes I want to talk to you about one of
which I just opened up the TTL in the
registration
[Music]
we don't seem to have an area director
I'm not sure we need one starting now
and we only have an hour we have a
number of presentations so thought I'd
go ahead and get it away okay yeah
so I'm Donnelly sleek with Huawei and
rest white Lincoln so we're the
co-chairs yeah this is the area director
she's not here right now so the basic
information these slides are all
available for download
people should note the note well IPR
requirements like to request people to
review documents when we call for that
so that will get higher quality
documents and if you have knocketh you
have that you want to get through it's
always helpful to review other people's
documents and then probably they'll
review your documents so this is the
current agenda we do want to have
somebody to take notes there's something
to be
cabbar described and at least convey any
great thank you yeah we've Russ is doing
some stuff there so we have blue sheets
for people to record their attendance I
guess is this one set going around it
doesn't seem to be that huge a throng of
people here today I could have but I
don't think this meeting reps okay so
just gonna just talk about the status a
little bit and milestones and then go
through with a we have a final
presentation so this stuff adds up to
about an hour so we can't generally go
over on one thing we'll have to go under
it something else
generally speaking mandatory sub
general protocol from Julius UNIX you
guys fellows information model beer and
Babel and it's or specific routing
anybody want to change something or an
island or add or delete or reorder or
anything okay so it's basically a couple
of working group drafts the table
applicability graph is actually expired
it came up for expiration
during the refractory period when you
couldn't can't post before the IETF
meeting and there's the main Protocol
draft RFC 62 6126 biz
so the applicability draft has actually
been in
we're gonna blast call for a while and
they really weren't hardly any comments
and there was a review that review needs
to be responded to so Cera's have
decided we'll just declare that to have
not passed this working group last call
needs to be revised and reposted and
we'll do a working group last call on it
in the future possibly at the same time
as we do it on an RFC 6120 six bits
we'll see what the discussions on the
Main Protocol draft revealed at this
meeting there is a home net Babel
profile draft and there's a series of
personal graphs at the bottom here so no
be there are presentations actually this
is out of date the yes the the Babel
Information model draft is a working
group graphed now as we decided last
time so I'll update this slide it should
be listed up at the top rather than
rather than draft stark Babel
information models we say draft IETF and
that should be up at the top sorry about
them and their whereas this previous
series of three informational RFC is so
milestones we've we actually have the
the third item here should also be in
green because we did it drop that so
we're actually not formally behind but
it seems like we will have me submitting
these drafts to the iesg
this month so we are a bit behind on
these later milestones unless there's
some questions we should proceed with
the presentations
[Music]
yes all right she's the link directly
asking it just doesn't
[Music]
I'd like to tell you about some recent
extensions to Beverly mandatory selfies
please so I believe that you all know
that one of the girls of this working
group is to create a successor to two
documents the Babel based protocol which
is six one two six which was written in
2011 and experimental and 75 57 which
defines the Babel expansion protocol
which was written four years later and
our goal is one of our goals is to merge
those two documents and produce emergent
document that is better than either of
the original documents and at the
standard tract next please so basically
the protocol remains the same six one
two six bits is the same protocol at six
one two six you did like Babel you'll
probably still like six one two six this
we've made for substantial changes to
the protocol a lot of editorial changes
documents reads I think much better than
the old documents but we've made for
substantial changes now let's reset the
theories which have been implemented
which I feel very comfortable with which
are a incompatible extension and that's
what this talk is about
unicast hellos which I'm not sure about
the implementation status of at least I
haven't seen the implementations which
are an incompatible extension and that's
what David is going to speak it out Hey
David's cannot see just to clarify that
question mark we have so far one
implement well I know I have one I think
torque you may have one as well but we
haven't done Interop yet or a thing of
doing it this week okay we have one and
a half implementations ok I'm always
dubious about fractional implications
there are two places where I've
significantly relaxed the protocol given
much more freedom to the implementer in
both cases I've been careful to make
sure that if you obey the old
specification
you're still compliant that's route
acquisition and that's been implemented
for ages actually the reference
implementation was optionally with the
right flag violating the old protocol so
now I want to make this behavior the
default that's perfectly compatible and
I would like people to help reviewing
that the section of the document is
called route acquisition and we very
recently found a way to relax the whole
time requirement we believe that is
compatible we believe it works
it was unimplemented when I wrote this
slide and since then I've met met you in
a corridor who told me by the way it's
implemented now but I don't know if it
compiles so we hope we're going to check
it soon and that is an important
extension for reasons I won't have time
to get into please review and implement
and tell me if it makes any sense and
you see that there are two big red
incompatible here I'm going to come back
to that later next please
okay so to remind you
bable bable packet contains a bunch of
tea Ellie's gles have a type a length
and a body and six one two six says if
you see some extra at the end of the
body please ignore it just make pretend
that didn't exist and that place was for
extensions at the time I didn't know
what extensions would look like and then
75-67
I designed once they have been
implemented what extensions look like
safety Ellie's could have a type a lens
and a body they have exactly the same
structure as the LEDs at the end of the
TLD after the body and if there is a sub
TLD you don't know about you just
pretend it wasn't that neck please
now sometimes if extension data is not
understood
you want the whole TLV not just the
extension data to be ignored and you
cannot do that with 75 57 sub gles and
so to avoid this issue the source
specific extension which i think is the
most important extension of Babel which
is due to Mathieu booty who is sitting
over there uses three new TLDs which
mirror the update the request and the
sectional requests which are called the
source pacific update the sources that
it required the South Pacific SEC no
requests so that the whole TLD will be
ignored by implementations that don't
understand the extensions next please
not so you cannot do that with subdial
visa and what I suggest that I think it
was Chicago was to use a new address
encoding can you address family to that
new code ease and Babel R and a new ie
will be silently ignored by existing
implementations and that the working
group was polite because this is a
polite working group and they received
the idea I would say somewhat cautiously
and so to prove that I was right I have
met you and Wendling chuan who is not
here today to show that I was right by
implementing source specific routing and
TOS specific route in respectively using
a new AE and the problem can you ask
your students to prove that you're right
is that sometimes they prove you're
wrong and that's what they did
defining a new a E was an absolute mess
and I put the gory details in written in
a polite manner in Appendix C of the
document next please
so what Mattoon Gwendoline convinced me
off how that I was kicking and screaming
was that we need a mandatory bit so in
six one two six this innocent TLC has a
heartbeat with the most significant bit
sets that is a tie between 128 and 205
255 it is mandatory and if you see an
unknown mandatory TLD you draw a sub T
LV sorry
you drop the hull and closing
eld and Curt motton Gondolin has shown
that that works beautifully force or
specific routing and for gos specific
routine and both extensions are
implemented they have been tested and
they have been written down in internet
drafts next please
now there is one technical difficulty
which is that Babel uses attack a
stateful parser when you versatility you
retain some data and later on until we
can refer to this data it's a very it's
a fairly simple procedure that allows
saving in the case of ipv6 networks a
good eight octaves for prefix and so
that's very useful and unfortunately
because you have the state you have to
maintain the state so we don't entirely
ignore it lv that has been suppressed
due to an unknown mandatory subtlety you
still update your parser state in other
terms parsing does not depend on which
extensions you implement a packet always
gets parsed in the same manner and if
you're not convinced that's essential
think about TCP dump it's not defined
what kinds of extension TCP dump
they found implements and you still want
TCP them to be able to parse a Babel
packet please okay so what complexity
does it end add to the implementation so
the main difference is that now you have
to parse empty of these no matter what
even if your implementation doesn't
implement any sub judice you still mount
must parse sub tlvs
in order to check whether there are any
that have the mandatory bit set and an
example of an implementation that
doesn't do any sub tier and accept GL
these is s Babel D the S stands for stub
are simple or stupid or whatever and
this is a very a an implementation that
was written just to show how small an
implementation of Babel can be and this
implementation when I implemented
mandatory bits in it grew by 38 lines of
C that's basically 30 lines of the
TLV parser and the shoe calls to it and
the binary size increased by fifty six
bytes that Deitz right next please
okay but mandatory bits are incompatible
with RFC six one two six old
implementations will not ignore tlvs
that contain unknown mandatory safety
LDS and in principle this could break
your network if you're not ignoring the
TLD that you don't understand the same
is true of unicast hellos and now we
need to make a choice one possibility is
to say well if nixing six one two six
routers with the new extensions breaks
the network just don't do that okay so
before you insert the tos specific route
or a source specific route or into your
network make sure that all of your
routers have been upgraded to the new
version of the specification the other
possibility is to bump the protocol
version on packets that contain method
to bump the protocol version the
protocol version is currently - we could
bump it to three and that and the
problem is that for many of our users a
flag day is just not possible so this
could be done without imposing a flag
day by simply saying continue sending
packets of version two but if you send a
packet that contains any mandatory bits
then this particular packet must be
version three in other words you will
still be sending packets of version two
in just an occasional your deployed the
new extension sending packets with
version three solution it's not that
easy with a distance vector but you
could stick now a new TLV on every
router propagated across the network and
then you would understand who
understands mandatory and who doesn't
and you could avoid the guys who don't
understand mandatory so basically in
capability yeah exactly but it would DV
it's not that simple but it works fine
so what I'm suggesting here is pretty
similar it is simply that you use this
version number as the capability so
version them
at certain point I'm ruined the guys who
don't understand the news version number
if you stick a new TLV they will just
ignore the TLV and the new guys will
understand oh the capability means if
this guy doesn't advertise it with this
capability I have to avoid him because
he does not speak the version if there
is a subtle difference then yeah there
is a difference so then there there is
the wording that I'm proposing if we
decide to do that perhaps I will
conclude because the next one is my
conclusion slide so mandatory subdial
these are a simple elegant feature that
drastically simplifies at least two
extensions to the protocol at least one
of which is actually something that
people want to use they are incompatible
with the old spec they can break your
network if you enable the new extension
without upgrading your old reuters and
this could potentially be avoided by
bumping the protocol version thank you
for attention
thanks joyous david's canaussie
i really really dislike the option of
bumping the protocol version so first
point is I disagree that we need a flag
day you can have two separate ones as
you actually discussed if memory calls
in Chicago first you do a way of where
everything supports the mandatory bits
and just drops those and also supports
unicast hellos and drops those and then
many months later you can update the
routers one by one to send start sending
these so that is one solution you don't
need a Flag Day which means you flip the
switch for anything on a twats which
makes it a lot more bearable the if you
could go back one slide please you
propose two solutions so the first one I
think could be doable if we have those
two separate days the second one well
there's also a third possibility which
is all RFC 6120 six is version three
period I don't like it either and it's
still a possibility that is still doable
but this one honestly it's gonna become
a
of remembering wait I have a one that
supports version two and one version
three wait that one showed up I can do
v3 now what wait I have to go back down
it's gonna it sounds like a terrible
headache and we try to avoid
capabilities invade it's actually much
simpler than that but this fax has is
that you must accept packets of their
both versions so where you have your
version different front to you put in
version different from both two and
three so in reception you just have two
versions that you accept on sending
you're allowed to always entry but what
is recommended is that you send to
unless you've got a mandatory bit
somewhere so it's actually much simpler
than you make it well if I start sending
some packets with version 2 and some
packets with version 3 and I just do
that when I'm like writing the packets
and I just say oh what's one of those in
there or not I think you can construct a
scenario where you end up breaking the
guarantees of loop avoidance of Babel
because you're telling something to
OneNote that you're not telling the
others I'm not entirely sure on that I
would have to build an example know you
can create black holes sorry our black
holes no Kay I am I I'm just basically
gonna agree with David but I'm gonna
point out that on unless RFC 6120 six
not this the original says that what
you're supposed to do if you get a
higher version numbers throw out that
packet and do nothing at all to the
state of that that Pierre I don't know
if we know if existing implementations
when they got a version three suddenly
and they only implement version two from
a peer are they gonna just keep it state
alone the exact sentence in six one two
six is packets with a version number
different front to a must capital must
be silently ignored so the rest so it
should work they don't say anything
about what the implementations did that
what the spec says well yeah input
you know are you fairly confident that
what we have these implementations that
would just ignore that one packet and
would not assume anything about the pier
yes yes because that's a fairly simple
requirement here my goal or chitosan so
I'm not really soozee astok about the
version 3 version to stuff what happens
in version 4
it's a silently ignored right what
happens to all the so so just be clear
so we need to keep around carrying
around all the I must send her version
to code if I don't have any mandatory
sub t lves I should send as version 2
right so what happens when we go from 3
to 4 do we still send us version 2 and
everyone keeps all their version 2
parsing code around yeah that's why I
don't like it so that's the reason and
so I think that figure something else
that that's what I would say yeah maybe
like the business of you've heard a
version 3 packet from or you've heard
880 LV that says I speak subtil tlvs and
therefore I'll send them from from
another device that's as good to me as
anything else you're allowed to send
packets over multicast right not select
which one I'm saying if I have heard
from Pier X this TLV that says I speak
the new tlvs
then I remember that when I unicast to
them right that seems better to me than
remembering that they're aversion to or
something Tokyo named Joe Johnson and I
agree with all the people who say that
they don't but this is annoying and too
complex but I'm also not sure whether or
not it solves the problem because we
have widely or relatively wildly
deployed extensions that may exist in
two different versions so a best for
cannabis up so specific extension exists
in a version that would be compatible
with version 2 and one that
Penson sake of ease so if you deploy new
Reuters with the new version then
they're not going to speak so specific
with the old we'll only exchange non
specific routes yeah so I'm not sure it
solves the problem then you have half a
network it may not fail at catastrophic
but I'm not sure the complexity is worth
the gain and what we achieved that looks
to me like a consensus you allowed to be
part of the consensus as well okay so
are we there are further kirara many
more we need you to cut that awful
earlier this seemed like a very
important point to discuss but we have
quite a few presentations so I don't
know what any further on this right now
so
this is a very cramped ping box again
hmm all right hi everyone my name is
steve kennedy i work at Apple and I've
been playing with Babel for a few years
now uh or maybe at least a year anyway
I'm here to talk about unicast hellos so
this is work in collaboration with
mainly Toki and Julius to spend a lot of
time like either writing code at their
dock but also with a bunch of other
people that contrary to the document or
on the mailing list apologies if I
forgot anyone also none of the names
listed here apart from myself or almost
none of them read the slides yet so they
can't be held responsible for any
mistakes in them alright next slide
please
so the main reason I got interested in
this is when I wrote my first
implementation of Babel one of the links
it was running over was some custom
wireless link that would TDMA between
frequencies and one of the properties of
that is that multicast was a disaster
unicast you would get reliably because
you knew when the other pier was
listening multicast yeah not so much and
so I was kind of in this case this
wasn't my implementation it was the
original one and it was just she kept
falling over so I went and dug up into
it and figured out there was because of
the multicast so he got me thinking can
I send them unicast oh no that spec says
no in a big red must so because in Babel
hello's did two things one was discovery
of the piers which really needs to be
multicast and the other was link quality
estimation pure liveliness and Traverse
reach ability detection well the fourth
part of that anyway so I was thinking
maybe if there could be a way to kind of
split those two apart that would be
really neat especially when you have
link layers where you have you can get
discovery of the other nodes do some
out-of-band mechanism so that's kind of
where this started and then this is
applicable only so two links where
multicast sucks two links where there is
no mult
and also too if we start wanting to
build security and a lot of the security
mechanisms that exist today
don't play nicely with multicast so
one-to-one relationship and the keys are
often that way in that case it makes it
a lot easier to do everything over a
unicast so that's kind of the general
idea on why I think this is work is
important next slide please
so problem statement and the reason that
the original spec doesn't so all says
that you must send hellos multicast is
that they have sequence number and
interval that correspond to all the
neighbors on the link so anytime you
send a hello you need to increase the
sequence number you can't just send it
to one then bad things will happen so
that's the hello T of ease for those
that have forgotten but the great news
is there are 16 bits of reserve that
could always come in handy in here so
next slide please the way we built the
solution is to just rename this reserved
field two flags and take the first one
as the unicast flag and then what this
means is that instead of having a
sequence well what the flag means is if
it's not set this is the multicast
hello' if the flag is set this is a
unicast elope
so multicast hellos are exactly like the
previous ones they're backwards
compatible they work fine and they
sequence number that they carry applies
to this link sorry so you're sending it
to all neighbors on this link and the
interval is a promise that before that
time expires you will send another one
the unicast flag on contrast means that
this is a unique a solo so conceptually
it is designed to you specifically and
the sequence number is specific to you
so then I can send one to neighbor a and
one to neighbor B and they can have
different clocks they can increment at
different intervals so add a recurrence
at different speeds they're completely
independent and yeah so both psycho and
the interface stick to those next slide
please
in terms of what this means for
interoperability if you only send the
multicast hellos we're still in spec 161
26 what is necessary for this to not
break the network because Jose was
saying earlier is that nodes need to
understand the unicast flag the bomb
that arises if you don't is that you
could end up seeing hellos with
multicast and hellos with unicast with
like two sets of sequence numbers so
instead of having something that
increments slowly it's kind of jumping
back and forth and that can really throw
off your like estimation costs so that
would be kind of subpar
so what we mandate is that if you see a
unicast flag you need to understand it
so one that simple solution is to you
see a unicast flag you drop that hello
and that makes it very similar to the
previous behavior or at least if you
don't know what that neighbor is saying
you will kind of completely ignore him
and not establish neighbor relationship
so at least you avoid other problems the
way it's currently written in the spec
is that you need to understand both
which i think is a good solution but
that gives us a transition path also
it's not mandated mandated to send both
so implementations that today just send
the multicast ones or stones back but
implementations that for reasons of what
links are using whatever only want to
send the unicast once that's still okay
you could end up his case where some
nodes that only do send unicast and so
knows that only send multicast on the
same network those will still
interoperate if they both understand
both next slide please so what do you
need to actually implement this it was a
surprisingly short once I actually got
back into it
so in the for the multicast hellos you
need a sequence number for yourself for
interface and an interval as well and
then for each neighbor you need the
sequence number and the interval from
that neighbor in the neighbor table what
this adds is now in the neighbor to go
you also have your outgoing sequence
number unicast to them and the incoming
unicast sequence
and interval from them that's all you
need to add and also when you're
computing the cost you can react
differently whether it came over unicast
or multicast because like key TX for
example was designed for the multicast
properties of Farrow 211 next slide
please
and that's mostly it for unicast flows
one interesting problem that came up was
there cases where you want to send most
of your hellos using one methodology
let's say you want to send most of them
using multicast but every so often you
want to send one unicast in the previous
back if you did that you had to send one
with a very long interval and then keep
sending them so in order to make that a
lot easier we introduced what we call
unscheduled hellos and what those our
hellos with an interval of 0 so since
the interval is defined as I promised I
really promised to send another hello of
this type in this time frame when it
sets the 0 it means I'm not promising
anything I'm just giving you this hello
then one of the main use cases is for
the sub tlvs for extensions when you
send those you still increment the
sequence number though in some of these
cases it actually doesn't matter because
if you're just using it for let's say
the RTT information for the RTT
extension you don't need it but it still
that was a vision we could have gone
either way we just had to go with this
one
and the unscheduled hellos which you
shouldn't necessarily use them for the
neighbor acquisition because you have no
way of telling if the neighbor went away
if there's no interval that they told
you they would send you something it so
they're really kind of used as this side
mechanism if you still need a Hello TLV
for the subtopics that's not part of the
document that they should not be used
for neighbor acquisition and there is
nothing preventing you just after you've
received an unscheduled hello start say
to send a unicast hello to the guy you
just learned about and does that count
as neighbor acquisition I'm not quite
sure sure absolutely fair what I read
the document does
though I think unless we edited that
afterwards what it did say at some point
was that what did you document said
before is that if you don't see any
hellos from a neighbor for a while you
must set the cost to infinity and forget
it and I think that what the doctrine
says now is that if you don't see any
schedule too low for a while you do the
same thing so if you only ever received
on schedule too low that's not good
enough to stay established neighbor is
that what it says now
for memory Julius is that there's some
sounds good right okay and yep let's say
on schedule close and next slide please
and that's all I have any questions
thanks for your time sorry the questions
I'm sorry John Baudelaire bus um quick
question so on the so presumably when
you're multi casting hellos new
neighbors could arrive at any time and
therefore you should never really stop
certainly podcast ellos if you sent a
unicast hello in somebody responds does
that mean that they're dropping that
hello is then done and you stopped
sending hellos apart from your
unscheduled thing that you said just now
it depends what you're trying to do if
your only way to discover the peers is
with multicast ellos which is the case
for most deployments of people today
then you keep sending them because
that's the only way you're if two nodes
come up at the same time it's the only
way they'll know about each other okay
however it's it's unicast if I said
hello to you and you said way back to me
yes if I keep saying hello to you you're
gonna get confused surely and this time
doing a wait still allows for everyone
no I don't get your question because you
keep sending hellos periodically in
Babel okay it's not a one-time thing you
keep to have a neighbor you need to keep
receiving hellos from them and when you
receive flows from them you need to
reply with I heard yous so if you keep
hearing close and I heard you from a
neighbor you know they're there it's not
a yeah maybe hello it's not the right
you know the ship set has sailed a long
time
gonca yeah it's a periodic thing all
right okay so I have two comments one
thing you didn't mention is that you are
allowed to send multicast hellos over
unicast and that's an important point
and that's something that was explained
to me by Margaret because I didn't
realize it so six one two six says of
that multicast that hellos must be sent
to her multicast and Margaret noticed
that actually what I meant to say within
my mind Thank You Margaret is that a
Hello must be sent to all neighbors on a
given interface because there is just
one sec no counter and in particular
nothing breaks if you send it to all
neighbors over multiple unicast okay so
the new version six one two six this
says that multicast hellos must be sent
to all neighbors either over multicast
or over an exhaustive set of unicast and
given that I'm not quite convinced that
just this observation is not enough to
solve the your problem
and so I keep wondering I've lost a lot
of sleep staring at the text while we
were editing it and apologies to
everyone who was fed up with our
spamming as we were discussing sexual
details I spent a lot of time thinking
do we actually is it worth the
complexity in this case the other
comment I'd like to make which makes me
a little bit uneasy is that we are
contradicting ourselves there is tag
that belongs to you that says that you
wrote that says that you must force both
kinds of hellos and texts from me that's
in the mallow manner says actually if
you really insist you can ignore unicast
hellos
we're not contradicting ourselves
technically because what that means is
that you must parse the unicast hello
and you're only allowed to drop it after
you've passed it
[Music]
so I think we should spend some time
during this week discussing go over all
of those things I'm not sure I'm
entirely comfortable with the unicast
actually thinking off why meeting would
be really useful for this outside the
working group because I actually have a
lot of questions about the unicast as
well but I'm not really sounds like a
good idea today cool uh - yes that gets
organized please email the or whoever
once organized that Julius Europe to
organize this meeting so we discussed
this week you know please email the list
so anyone because I don't want to take
up the whole yes to answer your first
point that is absolutely true one of
that's when I first came up or sorry
when I first wrote up the proposal for
unicast flows I called them instead of
unicast multicast I called them personal
and public precisely because they don't
need to be sent over recasting multitask
but that was gloriously shot down on the
mailing list so we went back to this but
there is that a big woody absolutely one
of the other benefits of unicast allows
is to allow you to have different
intervals per neighbor which depending
on how let's say if it's a wireless
think how far they are can improve your
call I think we're going to have a blind
description and stuff of this site one
oh yeah
filly's what's going on as the talks are
mostly people are talking for the length
of time allocated then the questions are
expanding it a lot so we're kind of
running short on time the next is table
information model by Barbara and if you
could run under time that would be good
but
okay so um we agreed at the last meeting
in Chicago that we would make this a
working group thing so I at the very
last minute remember to upload a working
group draft with just a couple of minor
changes from Chicago I know you didn't
oh I'm sorry next slide um pretty minor
stuff and then I added an open issues
appendix next slide and this is what
I've currently gotten the open issues
mainly from discussion and from comments
from Julius of course the first one is
that once we get all the babble stuff
stable we will need to go through and go
well make the data the information model
match the draft but it's sounds like
there's still some instability and so
I'm not going to do that just yet
there's some other things that are
pretty detailed and you know maybe
Julius will get some time to think about
whether he really cares the statistics
and log stuff I think probably is
important and so in my next drive I'm
actually gonna start looking through and
maybe suggest some possible statistics
that could be collected but that's what
I have any comments really yes I think
that in your second points that I wasn't
radical enough and that a lot of the
list of things that are in your second
points should just be flushed oh they
were removed you just you just asked you
should in a digit after removing them
you said but maybe they should be
interface but maybe not and so since
that was and maybe maybe not I just left
the question where rights they should be
removed okay I was then we'll just take
that issue off when issue gone that's
perfect I think that's it okay thank you
let's see so the next thing here it is
the beer I don't know when I Sally are
you here I think she was well we've all
gone to the next one right now and we
can go back to this source visit
regretting ok so hello so I will present
you the update to so specific routine
with I made a 3-bit in da ville' next
week ok so just a few backgrounds the so
specific routine is a routing polygon
which x10 next up voting and well the
routing decision depends bus all the
source and the destination address of
the packet so routing tables maps pairs
of fresh figs to next dot and its main
use cases for suis forum cost centric
mutual me so we're using prefix of a
like a table addresses so the natural
solution for Bible is to add the source
prefix to any data structure and also to
message but the most is the most
important problem is that the source
prefixed
cannot be just dropped for an update
otherwise you may have routing loops so
the typical example is that when you
have a specific footer which has a
specific route legacy water if we drop
the sauce prefix will announce a
different route and then you will have
the rottenness necklace so the previous
version of the draft were using three
Elvis and this new draft introduced and
only one subdial visa sauce prefix sub
govt and you see that it's a very
simpler next twist
of course 6126 doesn't hinder mandatory
subsidies and so cast Lagasse
barber water will drop the subtly and we
have the example seen before and causing
the routing loop so this extension is
incompatible with 6126 nextly so about
implementation status it's implemented
it works and it shows currently an
experiment was set jelly next to it so
one of the main remaining problems is
about white out requests so 6126 says
that requests white cut requests for
routing table dump but the program is
what exactly means a wild-card request I
mean in 6126 so a legacy water only
those routes which are not so specific
so when you say says give me a for
routing table dump the only request for
legacy routes so the question is does it
if we send our routes included source or
specific phone those will break the
semantics or not and if we send one of
the four Emmys if we send more routes is
there a big waste of the bandwidth so
and the salt point is a technical detail
which will see afterwards
next please so there are has been many
proposal and there is for that kind of
propose also the first is okay we
request a food and we send the food and
the second is to say we will request
exactly what we want and we will receive
exactly what we want
the second is a slightly
is a compromise we each we only say
periods here how my extensions and we
receive perhaps some waste wood but
normally not a lot and the last
proposition was to duplicate market
request next please
next which I will skip this this side
and we can come back it's the detail of
our or proposal
so another thing was about white card
updates so of archived updates is in
fact a workout reflection so it's not
the same program because typically it's
when a rotor shutdown isn't a wire
cutter attraction so of course so
specific booster must be retracted to so
I think there is concerns is that there
is no need force or specific workout
retraction next bit so as a conclusion
so thanks to men that resub theories
because the extension is really simpler
but the code and the statute it's
implemented it works and now there is
something to to fix so first to choose a
subtlety number so for example 128 and
also chose a proposal for so specific
request
I personally personally like the simpler
one which is sending for damp and
finally I would like to request the
working group adoption for this draft
thanks for your attention ok are there
any comments miss no turkey Alan
Jorgensen I also like to just dump
everything option David's gonna see so
first off great work I really think the
working group should adopt this it makes
sense in the Charter in my mind I was
one of the ones loudly complaining about
the full route dump and now that I've
come to look at the solutions and how
none of them are like
greatly satisfying I can totally the for
if the full dump it's probably not that
bad
full table dump and adopt please okay
well we will issue a call for adoption
on the mailing list I think this rash
turn around for for quite a while now
others still some questions it seems
reasonable to adopt it
if the just consensus on the list so
we'll ask for that thank you so we
switched order because he went out of
the room and good afternoon everyone
I'm some decent from the te my
presenting I'm a presentation about a
potato of appearing Bible project the
first page is still the brief
introduction of our pure technology and
we know that fear is a new multi-faceted
technology and they have they has many
advantages and it does not require our
signaling protocol to explicitly bill
much cuts the distribution trees nor
does it require intermediate you know to
maintain an imperfect low stage so and
windows that appear technology splitted
networking into three levels and the
first level is overlays and the peer
transport level and underling and we
know that in order to forward peer
encapsulated package must be
transferring the network after the
network was able protocol it's the under
it routing protocol and we can use
Babel is our soldier under
protocol appear so banging beer key
parameters can be Kuwait by able
protocol and widows archivo
device is distance-vector routing
protocol that operates in a robust and
efficient efficient posting ordinary
world as well as the various networks
and the steps URIs for that chilled he
introduced stopped your V of our
extension so we can use a new sub Q V
for beer information transport
transportation let's see that to be how
to how to do that you know such a pure
information includes if IB we have a
prefix and am purest information and
based Aaron Islam and this information
can carry the Bible update message
through the new beer infrastructure V
and the the military beach you know
latter its new Beijing Bible protocol so
Manito repeat of a PR subtlety should be
said if you charcoal only return as a
subtly the suture must seem to not
understand theory and so we know that
job we can use paper protocol a protocol
your technology and beer can use peer
computers the forwarding plane according
to the information is that conveyed by
your a protocol and this is under a
protocol of beer technologies and also
we can use be MLD took away the notice
the information between H nodes then
this is then the multicast flows can be
forwarded from numerous nodes to eat
egress nodes the PRT is a new virtual
groups
documents in beer or group next please
let's see the form art we know that we
can define a new type of beer somebody
loved me
Oh your information in bevel hmm but we
still have to associate some some Yogi's
but there is no substantial piece in
bevel protocol so how can we achieve the
destination and so the two sub sub
Yogi's are carried is payload so well
the who sub sub T o P will be encoded in
the payload of beer sub choppy and the
so the list of perceptual we will
include the list of the peers of T or V
itself and as a potential ins of the two
stops of journeys so we can Kawai the
also a pair information news network and
we know that fu there is many Network
because that was a different dynamic
protocols such as you see is pf1 BP and
also level so there is all writing EC
sauce pf4 PDP extensions
yeah so so so the three protocols can be
used its underlay of peer technology and
also we think that paper can be uses
under a protocol enemy knows our chipiya
architecture does not relate all that
are seeing other men performing if our
procedures so how to support tunnels
that will allow to turn appear across
the sutras in Babel is for further study
we because according to the previous
slides we know that if we counterpart
the P R sub Jovi
Norwich and Imperial pumped transported
to the other route are seeing the battle
walk so it may be the beer already
playing computer you in several notes so
it may be questioned but we suggest that
we can use we can update all the returns
to support is extradition and also the
beer technology so the letter S will not
be a problem I think and this position
has been implemented implemented
lemonade then so you can find the
information and the holding is based on
the update version o FC 61 fantastic
space King on July dry night I think
June 9
I think it's based on the coding version
of that so you can as it's working so
any comments and accept that so although
I don't know which group issued this
charter belongs to so I think that's a
scar yeah what is
oh yeah this so I believe that this
document should be in Babel if there's
interest for it the other IGP is there's
wide knowledge of how to safely extend
those OSPF and is and we have a good
decade couple we won't talk about how
long we have an experience for extending
OSPF and i as is but I think that Babel
it's still been moving and that
knowledge is not as broad plus I think
that the set of people who will be
interested in consider implementing it
are here so first I think that's some
very interesting work from so it's not
necessarily interested from the point of
view of the applications my
understanding of beer is a deer
functions in a deer domain which
intuitively speaking and I'm afraid
because there are people in the back of
the room I'm afraid of but roughly
speaking would be a data center and or
in a ferret our network and I don't
think Babel has been much deployed in
this kind of environments on the other
hand is very interesting is to see how
difficult it is to implement to
implement beer with a distance vector
protocol if you look at the basis at the
basic beer specifications they assume
that you're doing SPF and as you pointed
out there is the example of a thematic
Tunnel creation that really assumes that
you have full topology so how much of
beer can you do when you only have the
partial view that Babel gives you that
is something that needs to be checked
and you can do it with rip with AI GRP
and Babel and I like EIGRP but I prefer
Babel so I'm glad you do it here yeah ok
then I'll finish quickly so I think it's
very interesting work there is one thing
that makes me uncomfortable is your use
of sub sub tlvs so we would need to
decide what to do is that
as to adoption I am Not sure there are a
few extensions that we have that are
mature extensions notably the RTT
extension is deployed quite is deployed
is being deployed quite widely and it
still hasn't been adopted because in
this working group we have been
concentrating on getting the base
protocol specification okay so our
specific routing is something of an
expected section because home that needs
it so I'm not sure that I have the
feeling that adoption for now would be
premature okay we have one person in the
queue on network we'll go to them and
then that'll be it because we're
essentially out of time so I switched to
Dennis now hello can I close you him no
yes just one comment I hope quick looked
through the repository that's why do mmm
the one on github and investor poetry
all of the previous history has been
replaced with the initial commit I think
it would help to preserve their commit
history of them of the work that it's
based upon so you can either see what
was in the source code and what was a
leader to implement their extension
that's that's it
just let thank you okay you wanna
respond quickly and IRA he seemed to be
commenting that that he you need a you
should professor changes in the github
version I not sure I understood his
comment yeah
the main Cody is being a separately see
profile so he can find all the detail
information in CFL okay yeah okay so I
we're kind of out of time continues the
music really interesting topics on the
mailing list
and well so I'll see y'all there and in
the next term meeting I guess thank you
that was Dennis
you