[Music]
you are so silent good afternoon
everyone and this is the best session in
Prague sorry for the minute lost at the
beginning I'm alone but Thomas is here
remotely the new note well please wow I
guess you know but please take a look at
the latest version of that slide and the
latest RFC's which it mentions very
quickly I'd mean I'll send the blue
sheets today we'll have someone
presenting from remote in addition to
Thomas being a remote as well so it's
her first four best
so we'll experiment but I guess it could
go smoothly any comments on the agenda
Ali sent Olli slides late but since he
was the only one at the at the bottom of
the of the agenda it didn't lead to any
agenda change time management will try
to be a bit strict and if anyone can
help me in taking minutes I'm fine
I'd be I'd be glad but I can live
without it
very rapidly because we don't lose time
we don't have any new RFC for nine month
which is quite a while but not stressful
but we have 20 to work in hope documents
which are quit quite Lively three are in
is GUI now i've Sierra - q7 in working
hopeless call or waiting Shepherd
that alley we have one which is I don't
know the status we we like some answers
to the last call comments and ping you
on that one yeah the comments from Eric
yeah I'm gonna publish soon and frankly
I'm waiting for the two drafts eatery
and EVP and overlay and I'm you know
okay wondering what's the status for
those two they are both of them they're
waiting for Alberto is Oliver oh yeah ah
yeah all right Loredana transfer
question yes I'm here
and yes the services you're waiting on D
with respect to one of them just clarify
the III you had a comment on the and
adding the IANA code request in the
draft and I did that that I it was just
a couple of lines of modification and I
would appreciate that is a very quick
check if you can check and you know give
a check mark on that and then the EVP
and overlay takes much longer to review
so that one you know you can do it as
your timer that requires brand new you
know your review from top down a lot of
that thank you so much for your
consideration and I'm gonna take care of
that very soon as I said I've almost
like a 7080 percent through the comments
and the other 30% gonna be done soon
okay thank you very much Harry so it's a
bit unusual but we'll be talking about
meap's
I've always wondering why but we like
work to be finished cleanly so we had to
mips and nobody wanted to work on this
they've been couple of people trying but
never managed to go a bunch on the end
but we've su no volunteer and who's
going to do a quick update is working
very hard in addressing these charter
items or milestones
20 K because the receiver is here
Harley I mean wrong kami kami
my name is nada I took over these two to
draft from Jeffrey so today I'll try to
explain the current status of these
draft so I have revised the draft much
much more times based on the new doctors
comments and the first one is the for
the first month I separated the texture
convention and the actual management
objects into different modules and in
order to based on the request from the
doctors in order to improve the
readability of the documents I have
revised the description class in the mid
definition and a ground and terminology
sections
currently I am revising the I am
preparing the latest draft according to
the latest meet doctors review so I
think new pattern new revision will be
submitted after this ITF meeting for the
second one BDP Imperius raya 3bp and
birch cosmic so the you see the the
discussion in the mailing list the
doctor suggested ask to reconsider the
design of me modules so please
understand dubs
some more revision will be required to
finalize this draft so I really try to
give some comments from the especially
technical point of view for this the
second draft and I would like to confirm
the purposes of this mod gives me
modules
so for the first one the purposes of the
modules is to provide the textual
conventions to represent the tonal type
internal identifier the other purpose is
to provide the paternal information to
other mid modules designed for
monitoring and configuring l2 l3 VPN
match cast the purpose is the purpose of
the second to me is to monitor the
operational information of the l3 VPN
much cast-on provider edge routers and
to configure em brf's
and EMS ID on the provider ID shelters
and of course to provide the
notification mechanism to the network
administrator so this is my
understanding so please let me know if
my understanding is not correct
okay okay according to the doctor
comments he said there is there may be
some the program in the coverage of my
modules so actually the second one busy
p.m. virus l3 VPN much just means
currently does not have information
object to represent the this information
components so I think these are required
for managing and configuring the l3 be
within March cast so I am thinking to
add the management object for
representing this vehicle these
variables into the mid definition so
what's next is I am really seeking the
input from the working groups so
especially from the technical point of
view I am NOT an expert in this area so
please give me some comments
so for example if there there are any
information that should be included in
or removed from these mid modules so pre
let me know and as especially the
comments on the use case scenario of me
modules they'll really help for me so
anything I would like to keep working to
finalize these we draft so the comments
are always always welcome
nothing thank you very much jeff has a
very brief comment you probably should
not put anything into the nib to limit
the generation of each be update
messages that's a piece of the generic
BGP and infrastructure and this is not
something that could be really
controlled under this module thorium our
previous slide okay before configuration
variables mmm great limit BGP messages
don't do that oh yes okay thank you very
much anything else okay thanks again
[Music]
thank you thank you for those four
minutes 59 seconds you've ordered me
I'm agent Farrell I just want to do an
update update on draft great best data
center gateway mainly because although
the file name says data center gateway
this is really now segment routing
enabled domain gateway as follows so
when we started this we were interested
in data center sites that were running
on segment routing and wanting to
connect across non segment browsing back
backbones or certain granting backbones
we've revised that just to generalize
the concept for any domain that is
segment route incapable largely speaking
that required a global search and
replace in the document and not very
much else apart from going back and
looking at all the changes and say no I
didn't mean that one the work is stable
it's referenced by a document John and I
wrote to provide a bigger landscape so
this document is doing the protocol bits
and pieces and the new document provides
the landscape and that's targeted at a
spring working group so a reference
model a picture two domains that are
during segment routing and some backbone
made up of one or more ases with
multiple roaming and we want to be able
to steer traffic right the way across
from a source in one domain to a
destination in the other domain so we
want to do segment routing end to end
and an actually traffic engineer how
that traffic goes across those AES is
which points of interconnection it uses
so there are two aspects we have to
handle one is gateway discovery how do
you know what other gateways are out
there firstly what are the gateways to
your own domain and what are the total
set of gateways that are that are out
there and providing rich ability into
domains very briefly we use a route
target to autodiscover
and we then install import rules so that
only the gateways to a domain import the
routes to that they care about
so all gateways to the same domain will
import each other's routes and then Auto
discover the clinic of the current set
of gateways to that domain the other
thing we need to do is understand how to
get connectivity across the backbone so
what we do is when when a gateway
advertises rich ability it includes a
tunnel encapsulation attribute with a
new TLV basically saying here's a here
is reach ability to an SR domain and we
can put in a SID there as well if we
want which allows the other end of the
tunnel to build a full explicit if you
actually explicit path segment route it
explicit path it's been suggested to us
that reading the other document that the
full framework actually gives a better
background to why these protocol bits
and pieces exist but I think it's still
worth keeping the two documents separate
so the whole magic is when a gateway to
a domain discovers other gateways to the
domain it actually also adds those to
its advertisement so back in the
original picture there are multiple ASAS
BRS along
path and they might start dropping paths
because they're not optimal well you
want that information to make it all the
way through so by having all the
gateways advertised all of the other
gateways you actually get that through
combining that then with BGP LS and a PE
you get the ability to do full
end-to-end traffic engineering so we
still need to write management and
security sections we need to make a
first-come-first-served code point
request which will obviously involve us
also talking to IDR it would be silly
for us to make protocol extensions here
without talking to IDR and we would like
more reviews especially as I said in the
context of the document that gives much
more background it's a really simple
draft turned out that we didn't need
much in the way of protocol extensions
and question for the chair
its traditional can we adopt it and is
it appropriate to adopt it in vessel
should it go to IDR and what more would
we need to do to start the adoption you
don't need to do much more I just like
to have a sense of the room of who has
read it okay thank you
so I guess we'll pull the list I have
memories I have one comment there is an
alternative solution to this which is
being so nice which is the BGP as RTE
policy framework which is being
discussed in I think segment in spring
and in IDR as far as I'm aware and that
does actually if the use case is traffic
engineering between data centers end to
end with segment routing that is
actually what it's also supposed to do
and it's using bindings it's and stuff
like that
so I'm not a fan of having beauty
contests well I am just wanting to point
out that there is there's another desert
anything else yes we are aware of it and
the reason we wrote this was because we
think that that that that other approach
is not so much broken as in as if it was
broken it could be fixed it's just not
the way we would do it I think I what my
personal view is that the as of the
policy framework is even I you have more
options or even it's more extensive
because you can have even multiple paths
across multiple pieces of the network
and you can actually do even more
complicated traffic engineering than
what you're suggesting here in my view
but we probably need to go to the
details yeah I think we might we might
it might be worth looking at looking at
that in the context of the the new
spring document that that's on this
slide and just saying okay so that's
actually what John and Adrienne are
trying to do so would the would be BGP
srte
solution achieved that as well right
yeah yeah I think we need to I think
understand and look at it I haven't done
all the due diligence myself but I do
know that that document is actually
addressing the same use case more or
less at Jeff foul so they addressed that
last comment the te policy document is
really more about traffic string of
different types so it's really about
tunnel selection to be all the foot
traffic is physics I found there and to
bind those tunnels to know the
individual each be routes so it's it's
potentially usable in some of the same
context is this but the only sense that
both of these are sort of BGP and SR and
no view of the network can let you do
this this is more about actually how the
time the different domains together so
if you use and as of the policy of
binding sit which represents the data
center on the other side you actually
achieve the same thing
that's crude what your visibility points
change a little bit and that's a lot of
work this back of its getting you is
visibility more than in terms of
choosing how to bind the traffic so T
the T policy is about colors on the
routes that's really winsome yeah but
also the de part of it that's true yeah
so I think I I think my comment is I
will again so my comment is basically we
need to look at those two alternatives
and figure out a way for properly rather
than trying to come up with two things
which are completing a bit and I we need
to look in my suggestion is that we need
to understand what I hear your
suggestion to read the document yeah
yeah I did read this document and I read
the policy so in my view as a people see
is more expense is actually more
extendable and and actually does this
use kids it is definitely more kitchen
sink so I don't think they're actually
incompatible but I think they they do
have some overlap police agency so I'm
wondering given that this draft is as
you mentioned is talks about their
specific implementation and aspects of
the framework draft should we do the
working group should we wait for the
working group call on the framework
draft before adopting this one
when you say framework draft do you mean
I'm not disappointed that yes frankly we
could if the spring working group were
gain to me so we should discuss it okay
but I'm kind of reluctant to delay the
necessary protocol work that people want
to implement waiting for a working group
to discuss a and an architectural
framework difficult because you couldn't
wait to discuss it on the list taste it
yeah I mean discussing is you have to
talk to someone when you discuss in
otherwise your own so another question
is this draft the only
draft related to this arching draft or
there are other draft related to this
the so this this name document here
points out it lots of other pieces that
come all come together and those are
other pieces are are you doing it in the
other working those are other pieces
that already exist basically when we did
the work that's in this document we
found a gap also this is the only gap
and and and and the one I've just
presented fills that gap okay thank you
hi I'm Lou burger I'm gonna be giving an
update or an impact discussion on how
the network instance model work that's
taking place in the round working group
is going to impact layer two and late
layer 3 VPN device models for context we
have broken down the representation of
virtualization that happens on network
devices into two things we have
something called logical network
elements which are separable separately
managed partitions of a device and then
we have network instances that we use to
model burps and BS eyes layer 2 and
layer 3 VPN that's what we're going to
focus on right now I'm gonna try to skip
a bunch of slides but I want to say one
thing that's important here we model
both using a new capability within yang
called schema mount
what's even mount allows you to do
someone else use this analogy I really
like it you use a whole module you treat
a whole module as a grouping meaning you
can import a whole module and a
different place in the tree and that's
what we're using here is a fundamental
building block there's a tree
representation you can read about it
[Music]
here's our basic model we have something
called a network instance it's a
top-level module you'd see it that the
root of a device and we instantiate what
we call it a network instance pervert or
for vsi we have an ni type network
instance type that we would expect to be
specific to every layer - or layer 3 VPN
technology so if you have something
that's specific to
bgp layer 3 VPN it would go here if you
were gonna do a VPN it would go here is
a different type this is really the PE
information PE facing information used
to support her 4 vs I in order to
support the modeling of
information that's in the network
instance context in the birth context
and this in the seee context we produce
something called these route types you
can have one of these and it's an
implementations choice which they use
you can read the draft as why we have
three that's really a yang ism but
logically you can think of there's a
place where you drop your verb or vsi
representation this is again what would
be used to model the information that
goes to the seee the seaside and that is
you would put there any top-level module
so oops somehow there we go so what do I
mean by a top-level module underneath a
l3 VPN
instance we would have some l3
information that would go in the PE
facing side and you have put routing
information underneath the ver fruit and
you could have OSPF if you're running
OSPF between the PE and C II didn't even
have rip if you really want it or bgp or
whatever protocol makes sense the schema
mount has a notion of instantiating new
data through this scheme amount
mechanism so every instance gets its own
piece of data even though the schema is
the same the data in it is instantiated
per in this case Network instance the
data that's reinstated has a slash after
it that's mounted modules you can also
from a there's a yang ISM again the
ability to you can reference information
from within this context to information
that's outside the context for example
you could have something inside OSPF
referencing the interface information at
the top level through something called a
parent reference I think of it as a
symbolic link that's why it looks like
an app
so this says you can reference
information models can reference
information at a top level when you're
four
client-side you wouldn't actually be
able to retrieve anything underneath
here you would go go back to the top
level so in terms of impact we think
there's three areas of impact you have
core informa core facing PE information
that is not instant specific so that's
not perverse that goes either into the
protocol like BGP or if you don't have
another home to put it elsewhere you can
put it at the top level Network instance
we really think that's mainly going to
show up in the protocols if you have
core facing information that is per
instance that goes under ni type and
then I'll see in Cee information goes
under birf again the intros up here is
an implementation time choice so we
don't specify it we don't tell you that
you should be doing it we're not saying
the this working group should tell its
vendors what to put inside the C
effacing context that's the vendors call
but what information gets configured on
in order to support of Irfan's let's say
example BGP your Artie's your DS that
goes under and I type that's it
this is gonna be followed up by two
presentations one from the l3 VPN
authors the other for the l2 VPN authors
sort of thinking about how they fit in
maybe it makes sense the weight to hold
questions until those
that's it it's the next set of slides on
it's the next
give me one second what do you think I
am the named the indigent Francisco
I've date on a three-week and young
model and has described the changes that
will be coming because of the network
instance related changes so after the
after the last IETF there was a revision
submitted in l3 VPN young model that
mainly is about removing the private
definitions of some of the data types
like our DN RT and reusing them from
IETF routing types besides that there
are a bunch of updates in progress
mainly they are following one is md n md
alignment which is removal of state
containers which are really reflecting
the flight config state and those have
to go away from the model secondly
alignment with the network instance
model as you described earlier the model
was of menteng network instance
container conditional upon that type of
network instance as default versus the
named Network instance this has changed
and what what's going to happen is in n
as more details coming in the next slide
based on n I type as a 3 VPN some of the
the portions of the model content will
go in there and bgp related
augmentations for l3 VPN which fall
under the category of core facing
configuration and then for instance
configuration in BGP those will be will
have to be placed in the right places
so here is an example of it's a young
tree depiction our DS NRT kind of
configuration it is per per Network
instance configuration which will be
available under Network instance and
under a particular Network instance with
case being n I type as as new VPN the
second category is BGP specific l3 VPN
extensions those are still per Network
instance extensions and those can go in
here is well under l3 VPN case ni type
being l3 VPN one example of that is
label allocation mode which is for is
per network instance configuration then
the second category is for BGP specific
extensions the second category is cone
facing instance configuration like ESB
are options and one example for that is
SBR option be peering the region route
target knob and such knobs will go in
the augmentation of BGP model at the top
and it was mentioned earlier that aim in
the hole routing mod the hole routing
model and control protocols and a
protocol bgp under that is mounted under
under a network instance by using schema
mount but here because we are augmenting
the top BGP container and l3 VPN is a
separate module we can control it not
from we can control it in such a way
that it won't show up in the context of
our Network instance under the scheme
amount so this way we can achieve the
three categories that what this is
described in loose presentation through
bpn top configuration and then the BGP
specific configuration which is per
Network instance as well as for the
court facing instance
so as next steps will be submitting
revision 0 to with all these changes
then we'll be requesting a detailed
review of the model and then once all
the review comments are addressed we'll
be in a situation to think about
workgroup last call
Patrice reset school system okay so
today just to as a follow-up of the
boring stuff
the being so let's go with LT VPN so I'm
going to be quick
basically what we've done is we just try
to finalize the yang model so we can
also call the workgroup task all very
soon so we've been doing the all the
details about episode warriors also make
sure that the we are compliant to an MDA
style and we play also bit with the
instances make sure that people's are
happy we name it a bit so how about the
latest I think we are very close to get
it done
so and hopefully and on the evpn side
well there's the same thing for the
Ethernet segment Yang and the VPN yang
we try to finalize pretty much
everything we add the last bits and
bytes and advice and the episode of wire
stuff also that we added recently to the
Ethernet segment so again try to align
the model with the nmda so on the VPN
side again all the last stuff that we've
been doing so we add the VP WSVN and
aware to it absurd wires reshuffle a bit
the model between the interaction
between a VPN any VPN and also mainly
for the for all of them as you can and
those two models is we added the
stagehands identification so everything
which is over data so that one
unfortunately we the team wants to
apologize we got issues to upload the
latest draft you're gonna see it very
very soon but and then what we're gonna
do is send an email on the list make
sure that people pay
beep attention to it and the work will
be done on that thank you yes Manchu
Manchu from Siena I wanted to give you
an update there was a presentation in
the pal working group about the pseudo
wire yang model and we we basically said
that we are doing that in the best so we
have to consolidate into a single pseudo
wire yen the container that we have here
and I think the only other things there
is the pseudo wire types ATM frame relay
all that and multi segments for a wire
so rest of it we have it covered but
some of that other things will pick it
up okay thanks for the update
any other question all right thank you
[Music]
I am Satya so the talk will be on the
bgp multipath in interest option B and
it's a simple idea and the the problem
existed s or just thought of writing a
draft on this what is DGP multipath it's
like when you are more than one path to
the destination in the forwarding
alright and it's used for load balancing
and redundancy and it's a standard
concept almost all the vendors support
it but there is no standardization in
the sense that there is no internet
draft or the RFC which says like what
are the requirements for the multipath
but pretty much everybody kind of
assumes that they they agree on some set
of ideas although it's not in paper and
most implementations take into account
that the next stop of the path that
needs to be unique right in the l3
Vivian case or any VP in case there is
also an label along with the next stop
but that has not been taken into account
so I have a very simple diagram just to
you know put this problem in perspective
and I have a case and I bgp network in
which r1 is the source router and
generates a prefix 1.1.1 and that is
propagated by r2 route reflectors and
then it goes to the destination which is
not to the receiving router and the
router flickers do not set the next talk
to themselves so in this case even if
there is multipath configured at r2 it's
only going to install one of the paths
in the ribbon then in the fifth it is
going to reject the other path from our
r2 it won't take it as a candidate
multipath this is a very standard
straightforward thing now if we decide
to change the next stop at the route
reflector using like next stop self
which is again very standard then at r2
we will receive both the paths and they
will have different next stops and then
both will be treated as candidate
multipaths and they will be eligible and
then both the paths will be in the then
just a quick introduction to interests
option B this is defined in RFC two five
four seven and here the control and the
forwarding over the SBR or thought no
system boundary router is it both the
control plane and the data plane is
across this is yes and the next stop is
reset at that but I guess we are
I didn't write it but there is an option
whether you want to reset the next of at
the receiving is we are also or not
so again just very standard diagram we
have the worth of the VPN existing at P
one and P and the advertisement is
across an a is from a s102 a s 200 so
the C one is sending a prefix 1.1.1 / 32
and at p1 it is in the context of the
worth its advertising with touches about
distribution Rd one and then at s PR one
it has to set the next after itself
right and notice that in p1 the
advertisement came with the label l1 and
in asbr one it is set well to write and
then it goes towards the receiving S
which is deceiving sorry s 200 and there
I just choose that on SBR - it is not
resetting the next stop which is kind of
standard behavior now we take a case in
which the c1 is dual home to p1 and p2
and as in the first in the previous
figure here the VPN prefix on spr one
changes from label l1 to l-3 and then
goes toward c2 and split second later
the same advertisement or rather than if
the advertisement from the same seed out
1.1.1 is sent to P 2 and P 2 attaches
its own Rd right which is active - and
it goes to s PR 1 which again rewrites
the next hop and the label so what
happens is on the P 3
once both these advertisements at
Prescott received it is going to install
only the first one because the next stop
is same right so that's the key thing so
there are a couple of ways we can do
this like how do we make the both the
parts to be multipath eligible at p3 one
is we can use a different next of policy
at the SPR so the policy could be that
if next hop is incoming on the inbound
policy if the next hop is p1 we can set
it to some look back and that loopback
is generated at ASB r1 and then send
towards the receiving areas because you
need to reach ability for that loopback
right so but that would entail some
configuration over it and we don't want
to clearly do it for every kind of next
stop so the second thing we could do and
I think that is easy fix is we can use
the tuple next hop and label when
determining the multipath and the
receiving P so in the previous from the
previous figure even if the next stop at
the receiving P which is p3 is same as V
r1 then that's the next stop the labels
are different so then both the paths can
be programmed in the forwarding right so
what happens is if for example I am now
wanting to send traffic from p3 towards
c1 for two different source nuts which I
didn't show from two different sources
and the destination is the same which is
the 1.1.1 at c1 from t3 to SBR one there
is only 1 LSB right I mean even though
there's like separate levels rather I
should say the path is the same and then
at SDR one what happens it's the traffic
can be split up according to the labels
that we get so so in this way we can
utilize the available parts in the es
hundred which otherwise we are not able
to use today
so that's pretty much the talk question
thank you
so hi my name is Sami from VMware so I'm
gonna be presenting a draft on Geneva
with evpn so you need as you folks know
is an envious fee encapsulation it's
being adopted now as the standard poor's
enviously in cap and evpn currently as a
control plane does not use Geneva as one
of the tunnel encapsulation option so
this draft is about extending the tunnel
encapsulation options at EVP and support
to include unique to one unique thing
about Geneva as well is a genève allow
the tunnel to carry option tlbs so it's
an extensible tunnel in caps that allow
option to be transmitted along with the
tunneling cap so evpn controlling can
play a role here as well on negotiating
between the network virtualization
endpoint what kind of option can be
transmitted or AC
along with the Tom Lincon so we are
defining a bgp extension here that will
carry what options that will be present
in the tunneling cap after the column
header and as shown here those are gonna
be carried those tunnel option types are
going to be carried in a new tunnel
encapsulation attributes up yet so we
are gonna have a sub TLD type for each
option that will be carried and it's a
regular klv or mat similar to what
genève is going to be carrying in the
founding cap so in terms of operation
the bgp encapsulation extended community
is currently being carried on only
en route that BGP extended community is
carrying the funnel encapsulation
attribute tunnel pipe to be genève
autonomy capsulation and the tunnel
encapsulation tunnel sub DMV for the
Junaid will carry those tunnel options
up the alleys that can be transmitted
and received the operation is
straightforward so if an NDE is
expressing what option has to be carried
on the tunnel in caps and he is not
expecting that the other and he to be
sending any tunnel in car any option
other than what he is capable obviously
is that I think yeah that's about it in
terms of operation so for the next step
of course we have to a bit more because
actually genève tunnel in cap caddy as
well next protocol it has some other as
well parameters that can be negotiated
or signal between the NBN point so I
think we are going to be progressing the
draft as we are solid defying more the
control plane requirement from the NGO
ski stem so so the draft definitely is
going to be progressing or we are going
to be adding more meat and more
information to it as as we go and as we
are as well so the defying the
requirement from zangoose is that so I
think that's about it we can have
comments now versatility so this is a
control plane for in vo3
or specifically for Jinnah veer it's a
control plane for Junaid for the Geneva
tunnel in cap and but as well given that
Geneva is the standard for enviously in
cap now or hope is going to be adopted
standards and you can sigh as well as a
control plane for standard only cap
right yes it might be now given some
developments it's a solution that so
this is why we I was talking more about
we need to Salah define more a
requirement requirement pull the control
plane and this is works that's going to
be done by and viously so enviously
working group is working as well on
solidifying a requirement document so
this solution document can progress as
we are solidifying more the requirement
to this what I'd say okay
any plans to address other in vo3
encapsulations I know all these you name
so this solution documents focused on
Geneva just a clarification with the you
know your answer to Gregg with respect
to the VX man encapsulation there is
already you know a draft that is going
to become you know a VPN is a control
plane for VX i kneecap and it's going to
become RFC soon it is sitting in the
pipeline so when you're talking about
the other end view a tree encapsulation
if it is really expand yes it is already
there if you're talking about the you
know GP e or GUI then as needed we can
add it I mean this is a VPN is a general
control plane that can handle any kind
of encapsulation correct the scope of
the document is still Geneva : Nokia
just an open question so if we are
defining options specific to e GP and I
understand this is the right document
right but if we define something
specific to the Geneva header
I guess you have to go to the Geneva
draft like if you want to take one of
the reserved bits in the definitely
definitely if I think for your comments
Jorge on the multicast bits or as well
as other comment about the local bias
and so on if we are going to be defining
an option here Lisa goes for enviously
if you are going to be changing
something of
the most when Bo City my people are
gonna be signaling between the NVE
what's gonna be available in the header
or available as an option then we need a
control plane for that or signaling to
be done yeah
make sense thank you thank you Sam
[Music]
No
afternoon my name is Jorge rollin nokia
at this traffice about blue protection
in a VPN networks here you have my
Cather's and what is this about is about
you have any VPN broadcast domain and
you need to get it protected against
loops first consideration there is a
distinction between a local loop and a
global loop what is a local loop is
something local to an to a node for
instance in the example here in the
diagram you have on p2 for instance if
you receive traffic let's say broadcast
from host 1 and the traffic goes out
they see two attachment circuit two goes
to se and comes back somehow that is a
local loop until loop that is within the
same port same bra or Castlemaine in p3
you have the same thing so it's a local
loop because it's actually within the
same P right and same broadcast domain
so those two cases are not addressed in
this draft because the assumption is
that the local implementation should be
able to deal with them but we are
addressing in this draft is a global
loop that is caused by a backdoor Lane
somewhere and the between sees that is
causing you know this in this example
this loop between p p2 and p3 so this is
what we are talking about these global
loops so what are we doing to prevent
that so what we are doing is basically
uh completing the RFC 7:43 to mak
duplication mechanism with an optional
loop protection procedure it's a fully
compatible with the the base e TP and a
specification is not adding any control
plane piece of information and the only
thing we are suggesting is upon
detecting a loop based on multiplication
event
carry out some of the the following due
protection actions so there P shoot this
card the P detecting a loop for a given
flow should discard that flow that is in
loop and while allowing other flow of
flow sorry and optionally the P can also
bring down the the AC where the loop was
detected so what you have in the draft
is not working yeah so in the drug that
you have these diagram a bit not clear
but basically there it's an example with
two P is P 2 and P 3 and you have a
local attachment circuit with Mac two
injecting broadcast traffic and P 2 and
P 3 they are part of the same VPN
broadcast domain and you have also a
backdoor link between AC 3 and AC 4
obviously you have a loop here so the
way we detected is actually taking
advantage of the immaculate Asian
procedures in in the VPN and those
procedures
basically what they say is if I receive
a if I learn a Mac locally in AC 2 i
really ties it at the same time I'm
sending that traffic over the backdoor
link and over the core obviously on P 3
I'm going to receive the route but I'm
also at the same time I'm going to learn
the same Mac locally on AC 4 so I'm
going to be advertised a Mac with a
higher sequence number and so on so on
and so forth at the end of the process
when you when you reach a number of
moves of Mac moves you're going to
declare that MAC address as duplicate
right and all this is specified in a VPN
so the new thing we are doing is once
you detect that Mac 2 is duplicate and
you add it to a duplicate Mac list we
are taking some actions so what RFC 742
says is basically the action is if P 3
is detecting
Mack to us duplicate it has to stop
advertising Mack to can and log an event
and that's it so we are extending that
and we are saying well p3 should
actually start a retry timer and p3
should actually trigger some blue
protection actions and those actions are
what we call we should blackhole Mac to
in this example and a black hole in this
context what it means is that Mac 2
should be installed in the rich table as
a black hole MAC address black hole MAC
address is not associated to any
attachment circuit or any a VPN tunnel
it's just a black hole Mac and what that
means is from that point on for any
ingress frame on p3
if the source MAC address is Mac to the
frame should be discarded if the
destination MAC address is Mac to the
frame should be discarded - and as an
option we are also suggesting that if
you wanna be more restrictive you can
actually as soon as you detect an
ingress frame with a source address Mac
- you can actually bring down the
attachment circuit now the the black
hole Mac is something that you you can
flush after the retire retry timer
expires or with manual operations or
even if you receive a better Mac route
for the Mac so what is this draft
informational well because it's
compatible fully compatible with the
seven four three two procedures is not
modifying any VPN routes and can be
deployed even if you don't support this
in all the peas in the broadcast domain
obviously it will help better if you
support this in all the peas in the
broadcast domain but it's not necessary
and why do we think it's important it's
because the backdoor links happen and
actually as a culture in the in the
draft we have an operator and that they
are concerned about these kind of loops
they
time and obviously we are one from the
working group to provide some feedback
about this work and and comments are
appreciated even Ali's comments
especially my comment so basically the
detection mechanism is already you're
leveraging the detection mechanism which
is already in the RFC 7432 that's right
right and RFC 72 this cusses how to take
care of the control plane and you know
stop advertising the MAC addresses and
notify the operator mm-hm and here
basically this is discusses what actions
will be taken on the data plane by
stopping the traffic flow and optionally
disabling the attachment circuits yes I
think four so that is fine it just for
that aspects of it frankly the draft is
two variables you know I mean you can
condense that to a couple of pages I
will say max I hope you don't take this
comment around way--just it is awfully
lot of requirement definition and
discussing too many things to capture
the essence of what the giraffe is going
yeah and the reason why we decided to
put this together is because their
multiplication section in the RFC we
thought it was not clear enough and not
likely yeah the problem with having a
giraffe to talk about the data plane
action and the result of the data plane
action is to make sure you know to
prevent the loop in case there is a
backdoor you know that's fine I'm saying
you know it for that fine let's have a
draft what having a 10-page draft for
something that we can write two pages
for I think it just I'm saying that
giraffe is a bit verbose if you can
condense that all right so if you have
any comments about what parts of the
tribe and now we do whatever sure house
on the tree okay thanks
any other comments
Sathya Francisco so can you go back to
the slide where yeah so on a c3 and a c4
are they on the same yes of different
yes on the same work same Ethernet
segment or different no differently okay
because now if they are in the same is
in a segment there is no loop right okay
serene
all right so one more draft this is pimp
Roxy in E VPN networks this is the list
of my cars and basically this draft is a
natural evolution to of the the work
we're we've been doing in a VPN the idea
is if you have an e VPN broadcast domain
within optimizing a VPN to take care of
the the flooding of the art messages
enable discovery messages even IGMP you
know MLD and all that so we didn't have
the same thing for pim and the idea is
if you have a some ping routers that
that are sharing like a LAN or an EVP
emerald-cut domain you should actually
do something to optimize the flooding
that you get and here you have an
example in this slide where you have a
broadcast domain an EVP an broadcast
domain and you have some multicast
routers some non multicast routers and
some hosts and if one of the multicast
routers sensor hello a pin hello that
gets flooded everywhere even to the
attachment circuits what where we don't
have any any multicast router same thing
with pin joints or pro messages they are
flooded everywhere right so we can do it
better in along the lines we are doing
with IG MP we can do actually the same
thing with with pin so the objectives of
this trap is to reduce a limited
eliminate the the pain message of
flooding in the poor we also want to to
Ford the IP multicast streams
efficiently we are also improving the
and the assert mechanisms that we have
in PEM with this with the help of this
PIM proxy and along with this we are
also providing a support for all active
and single active multi coming with a
synchronization of penny States so these
are the procedures that we have in the
draft at the moment I'm going to go
through some of them so the first one is
the what we call the multi
rather discovery so we are defining a
new EVP and route type that we call MRD
multicast router discovery route and
this router is actually replacing the
pim hello's in the core with bgp route
it's actually replacing the soft state
hello messages with the hard state bgp
route so the idea is a TV access you
receive hello messages team kalokhe
messages from routers and you add the
pim router to your neighborhood database
and you trigger this multicast or MRD
route and you take their the the IP
address of the the router the secondary
addresses if you have such a thing
dr priority and that's pretty much it
for the timing you handle the timers and
the gen ID and other things locally the
receiver piece basically based on the
route we add the multicast routers to
the neighborhood database and you
generate the hello messages again we
also have we take advantage of the same
route to also autodiscover IGMP queriers
so there is a flag in the route where
you can actually indicate whether the
route is a is a four-year right and in
that case we with just one route we
discover both things so pimp routers and
IgM peak warriors you have a question
about this yeah so stick - so in PIM you
know we have a lot of other PIM options
or hello options and the arm that
potentially could be useful like a load
balancing or there could be other things
so I'm wondering a little bit if it
would make sense to instead of having a
fixed format like this so maybe hello
like a list though hello options to be
in the route and it could be coming for
implementation dependent perhaps which
which hello options you choose to
actually include them in the BGP route
yeah so we thought about the rest of the
options because they are in the
I agree with you in the hello messages
there are lots of them basically we we
decided to put in the NLRA insisted the
main ones that we thought were important
we also did decided that it was some of
them they liked the timers and jain ID
doesn't make sense to propagate that in
around and for some other options we
thought okay maybe in future revisions
we can add some tlvs or some attributes
or something like that
but if you have some feedback about what
options we must include for sure we
would appreciate yes I would say so two
things one is I wonder if the format
should maybe be more flexible so you
know it's easier to add new things later
and the other thing is yeah if you make
it more more flexible you can still
recommend which one should be used or if
you choose stuff to make it more
flexible yeah then we should discuss
exactly which ones should either but
yeah just thinking is worth thinking
more about this okay we appreciate the
feedback
all right so next one is um obviously we
you also need to do something with the
the PIM join and prune messages so
basically here what we want is if we
receive a pin join for the same source
group or star Komachi basically we can
do proxy and generate a single route
summarizing that we are using here the s
met route which is the same route that
we are using in the IGMP proxy draft and
the only difference is that we are
extending a little bit the route so in
the the flags
failed there will be a new flag we call
it P flag and that is indicating that we
actually received a pin joint from a pin
router and the information there is also
applicable to pin and when that happens
basically uh we need we need also to add
the upstream router information
which is not needed in a IGMP along with
that we are also introducing a new route
type the RPG prune drought and therewith
the reason why is because we need a
state for the Eskimo gr PT states right
and we need to to propagate that in in
BGP as well important thing that we are
doing is we are optimizing the the PM
assert procedures so one of the things
is when you have a bunch of team routers
with you know sharing the land sometimes
you may have two or more upstream
multicast routers injecting the same
multicast content and then then actually
trigger assert mechanisms and and we
could do that and just let the assert
messages do their thing
but we thought that you know since the
assert mechanism is actually painful for
the routers and we don't want any
duplication in the this EVP and
broadcast domain we thought that we
could do better
so actually what we are doing is if we
receive pin joins for the different
upstream browsers we are actually making
sure that we don't have any any
duplication at this ithi p.m. broadcast
domain so we divide the procedures in
procedures for the downstream piece and
obscene piece so what we do in the
downstream piece is and here you have an
example on p1 if we receive a pimp join
for let's say a star Komachi but
different upstream a neighbor p1 is
going to pick up the the higher IP
address as the neighbor and it's going
to send a single assessment route with
IP 5 in this example now for the
upstream piece if they receive two or
more routes for the same the same s
Komachi or same star comma G or star
comma G and s comma G but different
neighbor different apps in the
so they basically they procedure is the
following so in this case P 3 and P 4
they will pick up only one upstream
neighbor
it'll be so the the neighbor coming in
these the estimate for s Komachi is
preferred over this R comma G so in this
case they will pick up our R for now
once they do that basically the peas
they instruct the datapath to discard
multicast traffic coming of multicast
traffic for s 1 G 1 coming from a
different router than the selected one
in this case P 4 would discard multicast
traffic traffic for s 1 G 1 coming from
r5 and immediately after P 4 will
actually send a broom as 1 G 1 IP 5 r PT
message to our five so that our five
that stops sending the multicast traffic
so with this basically there is no way
you can have duplication and this shared
evpn broadcast domain and we avoid the
assert mechanism between r4 and r5 yeah
finally I'm talking about a multi coming
a little bit just as we we do have in
the ICMP proxy draft when you have multi
coming it my main happens that our one
since the a joint message to p1 and we
actually need to synchronize that state
in p2 as well if p2 is part of the same
internet segment right the reason why is
if you have a failure on p1 or the link
p2 must have already the state in order
to be able to do a fast failover that's
the first thing of the a synchronization
the other thing is because now we are
building the the hello or the pin
neighbor database based on not only on
hellos but also based on the MRT route
the MRT route also has to be tagged with
the Ethernet segment identifier to
actually synchronize the beam neighbor
databases and that's pretty much it so
with this basically we
we complete the set of multicast
optimizations for a VPN broadcast
domains and I have here that we need to
agree on the the route types to be
supported we already met the ICMP proxy
and uh and the authors of this draft and
we agreed that we would reduce the road
types as much as we can and an open
question is whether we need to support
any other procedures like a bimbo
bootstrap or RP discovery or even dense
mode and yeah we need some more feedback
and comments from the working group I
just try to be quick on time very good
question sy6 when we are trying to
prevent another for the s-1 g1 dropping
it on the PE 4 I mean from dropping on
ipv4 so P 4 I'm guessing not to forward
it to the PD to write forward to do a
broadcast I mean in general so for the
core a split horizon would take care of
it wouldn't it no it's you basically if
r5 injects traffic for is one g one
right into P 4 P 4 this is broadcast
domain so it would actually fly to the
rest of the PE s right right so we want
to avoid that and then there is the
other streams are it comes from our 4 2
P 3 and P 3 sends it to the broadcast
woman right yeah so I we want the the
multicast content coming from our 4
because the this was their selected
stigmas select your conclusions I know
there was some work in the past on
trying to do be SRO a BGP it gets very
complicated I'm not sure if it's worth
the effort but at least there is some
work if you're interested that
maybe can't look at not sure if you want
to support then small but it depends of
people deploy but generally trying to
get people away from dense mode and I
thought embody might be more relevant
perhaps yeah ok
oh thanks Thank You Holly
the flow is all yours and ready for a
co-presenter if I was gonna cover the
second portion of this presentation mr.
Phil good afternoon my name is ELISA
Jesse and I'll be presenting few drafts
that first one it is EBP and MVPs MVP
and seamless intro and next slide please
oh so here are the co-authors of this
draft and the objective is when as the
existing central offices are getting
transformed into the next-gen data
centers we're going to have a mix of em
VPN and a VPN Pease in the same domain
and if the multicast VPN is a spread
between these a VPN and MVP NP is
question is how are we gonna interrupt
between them one way to do it is have a
gateway and go between the EBP and an
MVP NPP is via the Gateway but that's
not very efficient
and this graph talks about how we can do
it more efficiently and considers three
criteria first one basically not needing
gateways in your data center if you want
to go between these pease the second one
to give you a better optimum forwarding
you know among these P so you don't have
to do it rumbling of the traffic and if
you want to go between EVP MP 20 PN or
vice versa don't have to
to do the through the Gateway and third
is you don't have a gateway to four
region eight so let's for visioning the
requirements are pretty intuitive you
know have optimum forwarding among the
PE is whether there are M VPN or a VPN
optimum replication so if a VPN and so
one thing I needed to clarify ahead of
time is when you when we talk about a
VPN one can I get puzzle and say okay
evpn is l2 why the hell are we talking
about
a VPN to MVP and was that is l3
interoperability between them this is
not l3 VPN this is I are building a VPN
that does both l2 and l3 so the
Assumption in here is how you're going
to interrupt between IRB VPN that does
both l2 and l3 and MVPA and with the
optimum forwarding the Assumption
optimum replication basically what we
want to do is have only a single tree
for a evpn IRB for IR for if you can IRB
regardless whether the traffic comes
from l2 or l3 so we don't have to do
multiple replication support for all
active and single active multihoming is
needs to be done because that's the
major feature in a VPN of course
interest support needed and we need to
support all of the EVP and service
interfaces that is captured in RFC 7432
plus we need to be able to do the very
efficient l2 and l3 switching so which
means we need to be able to support this
relation against Gateway support
selective and aggregate selective
tunnels as well as optimize the storage
of sort of the hosts multicast estate
which can be a stark emoji or eskimo G
so
to do that the solution is very simple
once you modely okay then you can see
how simple this solution is so we're
gonna model the EVP and Pease
if you look at em VPN Keys you can think
of it is a PE with a bunch of IP where
if this IP where are the US tour
a host multicast addresses there and
these IP where are connected to a C's
and you terminate post pimp Oracle on
these ACS and then toward the core you
do bgp signaling and you set up the
overlay and underlay tree using RFC 6513
and 40 so we leverage that work and we
are saying that well if we model our a
VPN as we have this IP we're connected
well this model is already defined so
this model is already defined in our
baseline unicast PE and we are
leveraging the same model for the
multicast I'm you're saying that the IP
verbs are connected to the Mac where we
are the IRB interfaces and by the way
these IRB interfaces can be considered
as the ACS for the MVP n so if you
leverage that model then you can say ah
my EBP and PE can be modeled can be
model as a MVP NPEs
connected to a bunch of mac vr af-s vr
these IRB interfaces so basically I'm
gonna for the interoperability between a
VPN and MVP and Pease I'm gonna treat my
EVP NP is @m VPN and VPN language to the
other MVP so well that's all good and
dandy but the
there are few things that needs to be
considered and one of the challenging
aspects is how to do the how to solve
the multi all active multihoming and is
horizon that we had on a VPN are we
gonna take care of it on the if you're
trying to use em VPN for Rocco and for
that you have six minutes seven nearly
and you have a ten minutes left and you
have nine flights to go so I'm gonna be
usually inside to kill another no I
think I'm gonna cover the other pretty
bottle time from my other protection so
because this is important so I'm not
gonna get into the too much of details
but the eggs we need to handle all
active multihoming in here and the
problem is when you do IRB you cannot
use are you know what you work the
mechanism you've defined in RFC 7432
because that is only intended for the
single bridge domain and not for
multiple bridge domains and so forth so
what we do we expand that mechanism and
we are saying that okay you know what we
we cannot live we are expanding the
mechanism in pvp and VX land which we
call local bias and we use their local
bias in here and we're saying that we're
gonna be doing that not just for a
single bridge domain but across multiple
bridge domains and they trap describes
in detail how do we do that so once you
solve this main challenge then the risk
falls into its place and basically from
the MVP and then from IRB interface to
the MVP and to the IP where to the core
that's all
ambient procedures so these are slide
talks about
we gonna do the blocking across multiple
bridge domains in the same IP ver as you
know it considers bunch of you know a
given IP where fee is connected to a
bunch of Mac waves and each Mac
virtually represented by a single bridge
domain and how the local bias mechanism
can be extended to handle look
prevention in case of the all active
multihoming so that covers the first
part of the presentation the second part
of the presentation dealer is going to
talk about the solution how we're going
to cover it for the introduced e and the
procedures that we can use to take care
of the introduces scenarios as ali
mentioned this solution applies also to
the DC and we have actually implemented
it with Ashutosh and others and our
customer is waiting for its delivery so
ali went through the modeling very well
i don't repeat it here so the evpn IR
bps our model as MEP and when traffic
comes from a local source it's routed to
local receivers behind you from actors
or it's bridge to local receivers on the
same Mackworth if there are remote
receivers across the fabric then traffic
is delivered to the to the fabric you
via the IP birth and it's encapsulated
with the IBM Z or s flimsy encapsulation
associated with that work and the egress
leaf traffic is received on the IP birth
and if there are local receivers behind
some mock birth it is delivered to those
receivers one important aspects of
aspect of our solution is that the
tenant multicast signaling terminates at
IKEA
so we say families the inside the fabric
the tenant multicast signaling is
delivered via BGP MVP an other important
aspect is that there is no dependency
between the instantiation of macros on
different pease on the ingress and
egress we also support multi is
selective MDT we add bgp advertises a
mapping between the tenant source and
the group and the underlay sourcing
group using SPL and only peas which are
interested in a particular tenant source
and group will join the underlay tunnel
some diagrams to clarify we have
different settings of the receivers so
there is a source behind microphone on
p1 if there's a local receiver behind
microphone is just conventionally
bridged but for a receiver one on p1
traffic noise to go to the IP berth and
routed via the IRB interface also all
the peas that are part of this em VPN
they they join the I pimsy tunnel in
this case that white tunnel so they so
if there is some remote receiver lock on
p3 it will send out joins to p1 in the
end BGP MVP and others family and the p1
will deliver traffic to through that
whites I pinch the tunnel so everyone
including p2 will receive that traffic
but I'm p2 since there is no local
receiver traffic is dropped and p3 it is
router 2 receivers behind my first 2 and
3 this is the SPM z case so in this case
p2 doesn't join the tunnel because it
doesn't have any local receiver so so we
are saving some bandwidth here
so the mix Landy see can interoperate
with the MPLS van and when we say MPLS
van it can refer to legacy and VPN over
IP MPLS RFC six five one four or it can
be the NDP an european IRP proposal that
we that we are presenting but we will
need gateways in this case because the
encapsulation on the two domains is
different and usually for redundancy and
load balancing purposes we have more
than one gateway between two domains so
we have to address the multihoming
between the gateways so in this case we
have a source behind in v1 that source
is viewed by any receiver on MPLS domain
as a multi-home between the two gateways
and note that any signaling that comes
from one domain to the gateways is
ryojun ated on the gateways with the
Gateway next stop so that's why on the
other domain the p's don't know anything
about the details and the other domain
so in this case receivers in the MPLS
one sense that joined to both the
Gateway and the traffic from source
lands on both gateways and is delivered
to the MPLS man if there is some
inclusive tunnel on MPLS when this
traffic may get received by gateway to
but Gateway to has an RPF looking to to
the source on weeks nine you see that is
why the traffic drops on gateway 2 and
there's no loop but if there are some or
local receivers on gateway to they
should the traffic should be delivered
on gateway to parallel multi normal
procedure I guess I have to skip this
slide this is a case where the source is
gateway one you can go over the draft
and learn more about it
any questions or caravan okay not sure
if there is a question for you for rally
well we discussed already a few issues
that and there are a lot of holes in the
document or things that are not
explained yet I guess but one of the
things that are there are not a lot of
holes we discussed - and I mentioned
what are those are and how to address
what I think to make sure that we are
not missing anything less
they're probably discussing yeah wisdom
that's fine can we go to the that
diagram where you have the multi-home
see I don't know where it was that one
yeah for instance just a question about
this so let's say you have behind the
switch you have a source and you have a
receiver behind p3 okay and you have all
active multihoming so because you have
all active multihoming yeah the
multicast traffic can be hashed to let's
say p1 my question is if your receiver
is in behind p3 how do you make sure
that p3 in the umh selection picks the
right P p1 and not P - because we're
doing it via the source active discovery
and pH P one sends the si discovery and
p3 knows where the source of source B is
and hooks up to death how do you
discover the source via the live traffic
the same way as a median so when you
receive
traffic yes okay that was my question
okay thanks so you I don't know if you
already mentioned in a trap there are
some caveats with this solution right
there there gonna be some scenario that
we discuss of mine I'm gonna mention
that explicitly okay those like those
scenarios probably not cover if we
cannot come up with a solution for those
scenarios is going to be explicitly
mention yeah sure
any other questions no all right well
it's pretty much ten minutes to do your
choice linear to be different even less
so I got the till for the to elect one
IP ending or DPS for active let's go to
IP Elias and
so we got a lot you 42 right or not all
the presentation I did are you doing in
your eyes oh no no including mirrors
we're gonna do it you know including the
arch because Nagi is gonna be taking
five minutes maybe six
you have until 40 okay but you won't be
able to do
Elliot's beeping no LS 15 this is gonna
be five minutes at the end no but I have
a ten minute presentation I lead you
took 20 minutes for that one okay that's
why oh no no that's one okay so IP
aliasing this is gonna be very simple
basically the IPL is saying in a VPN has
been defined for the two runs for the
MAC addresses and then when you do IRB
there are two flavor of IRB one is
symmetric one is asymmetric asymmetric
gets resolved to your local MAC
addresses so you can leverage the IP
aliasing already defined for the l2 when
you go to the symmetric then the
symmetric IRB needs the IP aliasing at
the IP rods and this graph covers that
and and it is pretty straightforward in
a sense that I could have covered that
in the existing IR redraft but it has
gone through the working group Glasgow
and that's why for the new draft so I'm
not going to cover what the aliasing is
the first white talks about what the
aliasing is we don't have a time we
assume that everybody knows the aliasing
procedures for a VPN and in a nutshell
these things this proposal
leverages like you know
exact same procedure of evpn aliasing
which we do for mac addresses it says
now use it for the IP addresses for the
symmetric IRB and once you do that the
fast convergence using the mass withdraw
and all that works so it is a short
draft I encourage you guys read that and
as I mentioned this is to cover the
symmetric IRB case I go ahead alright
okay Ramadan um are you playing to it
include the RT v or you don't belong
here
RT v and formats which are not really
for aliasing because that's it exactly
so but it would be nice to have it all
together for this okay alright that's
one thing the other thing is for
aliasing for RT tools if you learn the
the mankini key binding through
gratuitous harp and basically you hash
it on one link and you bridge to the
other guy right you discover them both
you are going to advertise it from both
P so in that case you don't really need
any aliasing right then with the same
token we wouldn't need the aliasing for
the bassline evpn yeah but in the
bassline evpn you can receive you know
unicast
what the same principle applies in here
in other words if you receive it on both
you can say you know you don't you
wouldn't need aliasing because both will
send however you can not assume you're
gonna receive it in both because it can
get traffic and get hash about the ARP
traffic as well as the ARP message as
well as the traffic can get hash into
the morning yeah it depends on how you
learned in the IP really yes okay slowly
I'll be very quick question it's very
quick so in this graph you assume that
the B
arrogant and the health reroute target
are different right what was the first
one the the yeah the the to route target
yes and and the l3 well one is Mac with
the other is IP yeah but you are using
the EBI idiot out in both right
nice I'm gonna be using two different
RTS and the Evo I know the EB eyes are
different we use two different avi or v
ni a 1 v ni corresponds to the L to the
other v ni cars 1 so L 3 1 v ni
corresponds to microwave the other v ni
cards must wipe it so should we maybe
put a note that they cannot be same
otherwise absolutely
Thanks ok next one which one you VPLS
all active yes and then after that I
think it is near Aryans if you are
making two presentations it's five
minutes each
right right well for you I do mine in
four minutes
and I give six minutes from me right
four minutes nine slides yeah okay I did
that same thing go alright so we had a
drap a couple of years ago on a VPN VPLS
how they do a seamless interoperability
and we ran into issue for all active so
that draft was limited to single active
which means activist and by multihoming
and then has been implemented by
multiple vendors and is a working group
document which we're going to request
for a last call and discover this draft
covers the scenario that instead of
single active you have all active and
inactive the reason we didn't address it
at that time because it wasn't a
straight forward with the all active the
issue is when
when your CI device which has MACD wants
to send the traffic to your Mac a when
you have all active the traffic is
hashed to for the same VLAN to both p1
and p2 and these EVP NPEs
if they have pseudo wires to VPLS p3 so
for the same source mac and the same
VLAN pv3
receives it via two pseudo wires and in
terms of its learning is going to
flip-flop between the two pseudo wires
is going to trash pe3 so the question is
how do you solve these Mac flip-flopping
when you have all active VPN and all
activity we can is very important is one
of the as I say key feature of the evpn
so to address that we do it very you
know simply we are saying that we're
going to be using the concept of the
mirror pseudo wires and for a given PE
for a given EVP and PE based on the DF
election on that Ethernet segment and on
that Ethernet segment based on that DF
election if it is a DF then that's full
of wires becomes D F and we're gonna PE
- we'll use the same pseudo wire label
okay so that's why we call it mirroring
because PE 2 uses the same sort of wire
label as PE 1 when you do that PE 3 when
it receives a traffic it basically
assumes it receives the traffic from the
same originating PE and it avoids
flip-flopping so the advantage of that
takes care of the Mac flip-flopping and
the traffic from the evpn toward the PE
it gets load balance across both to the
wires but from the VPLS PE to EB PNP it
goes it gets sent via only a single to
the wire but that's okay I mean that's
that's
the VPLS works anyway and the load
balancing is basically asymmetric in one
direction in one from if you can PE 2 PP
LSP the load balancing is done on a per
photo basis over the core in the reverse
reaction is done on a pair of VLAN basis
over the core so that that basically it
and that the draft talks about what
control plane changes needed we can
leverage a lot of a VPN and Ross and
basically very minor changes is needed
on the control plane and a bit of
changes needed in the data plane but it
discusses in detail what those changes
are and it talks about the also how you
handle the multicast traffic in vs.
unique chance or I should say bomb
traffic that covers multicast broadcast
an unknown unique ends so is a is the
interesting graph definitely encourage
reading it it is the second part of the
draft that was written a few years ago
that we didn't have a solution at that
time and this not proposes a solution
you took six minutes six minutes
you got four
but often folks
Neeraj from cisco these are the
co-authors I'm gonna be talking about
extended evpn mobility procedures for
EVP and IRB use cases as the title
suggests the main objective of the draft
is to define mobility procedures for Mac
and IP for all evpn IRB use cases and
the work here is based on top of Mac
mobility procedures defined in 7432 so
essentially we classify all the mobility
use cases for EVP and IRB into three
main categories scenario a where the Mac
IP bindings are always fixed across a VM
move scenario B where a host IP could
move to a different IP binding and
scenario C where a host Mac could move
to a different IP binding so for the
scenario a it's pretty much the existing
Mac mobility procedures can be leveraged
and applied to scenario a it's the
scenario B and C with changing Mac IP
bindings that are complicated by the
fact that in evpn i rvv advertised both
Mac and IP beach ability by a single Mac
IP route type two with a single sequence
number attribute attached to that route
that signals the route version for both
Mac and IP components of that of that
route so essentially if I have an IP
that moves to a different Mac binding
now how do I assign sequence number to
the new Mac I feed out
if I treat it like a fresh route and
assign a new sequence number then the
mobility for the IP component would not
take effect because it's already
advertised with a higher sequence number
similarly if the Mac moves to a
different IP binding if I treat it like
a fresh route assign it a new sequence
number the mobility for the Mac
component of the route would not take
effect because the Mac is already
advertised with a higher sequence number
so okay okay just few minutes two
minutes okay sure so basically the
solution that is defined the key part of
the solution
is that we associate the sequence number
attribute only with the local Mac
component of the route so only with the
local Mac route and the Mac IP
essentially inherits the sequence number
from the parent Mac and we define two
key rules that must be followed when
assigning sequence number to the Mac the
rule 1 is essentially same as the
existing Mac mobility rule and the rule
2 is essentially that when I learn a
local Mac IP route the sequence number
assigned to the Mac component must also
be higher than any older Mac Association
for that IP so essentially with these
rules in place I'll skip the the
baseline scenario but essentially when
the IP moves to a new Mac binding rule 2
comes into play and the new Mac binding
gets assigned a sequence number that is
higher than the older Mac binding of the
IP and the Mac IP essentially just
inherits the parent Mac sequence number
but the when the host Mac moves to a
different IP binding then essentially
the existing rule 1 again applies and
the Mac IP simply inherits the parent
Mac's sequence number so just a few
other things that are also covered in
the draft it covers the Mac sharing
scenario where multiple IPS could share
the same Mac binding it also defines a
duplicate IP detection procedure for the
use cases where the IPS might be
misconfigured with two different Mac's
something that wouldn't be covered with
the existing Mac duplicate Mac detection
procedure and it also talks about
sequence number synchronization across
redundant V's so that's basically what I
have sorry ok I would have loved the
discussion but we're not taking question
just so respect to kill a Jew is a
across the world thank you maybe we can
discuss over the list or
okay last you hear me hi hi yeah all
right okay you can start I am the one
going through this right so indicate me
whenever you okay to change this right
yeah so hi this is Kali Raj you have
nine minutes from Juniper Networks today
I want to introduce you to this draft
which basically talks about how to
create private MPLS namespaces which is
private labels using BGP next at least
so basically this is a problem statement
how do we achieve predictable label
assignment at a receiving router at a
router who is not me myself so as we
know that MPLS has locally significant
level allocation semantics so with that
in mind how do we get a predictable
label allocation at a router so it
basically combines two RFC's together
we know the upstream label allocation
that is are say 5 3 3 1 and we have all
25:47 VPNs so if you think about it
25:47 VPNs provides us different
forwarding context for IP so this
mechanism basically URI uses 25:47 and
uses some extensive signaling to provide
private MPLS context for MPLS forwarding
an exciting so here I'm trying to
explain what context tables are and how
do we use it for an off box label
allocator
so in this diagram I've shown a router
which has its own low but locally
allocated I mean local a significant
labels in its blue fab which is the MPLS
wave and we see that this doctor is
connected to through two interfaces as
an example the G zero zero zero is a
shared common interface which kind of
goes to the core and g2 0 0 is kind of a
private interface which comes into a
specific forwarding context you can
assume this is like interface that comes
into the CVR of for l3 VPN so if you
think about it this is very similar to
l3
P n where a dot MP Lazar zero is instead
of a dot and a dot zero and the
impedance R zero global fabious the core
so the seal one is the context label
that is locally significant and it
points to the aide or MP lists tables so
taking the power lives with l3 VPN the
CL one is like the VPN labels and
whatever traffic comes inside that that
is the pl one that becomes a private
label so I can have multiple routers in
the network where I create the a lor
MPLS fab and I can install the same
label value PL one so that I am able to
deterministically get the same label
value at different routers using which I
create this private MPLS web on a shared
MPLS network so this way users can
create multiple MPLS planes in the
network and use them with their own
label values with decide forwarding
semantics so that is the main idea and
each MPLS plane is actually identified
by a context protocol next half just
like l o0 identifies one router in the
network so the context protocol next to
identify is one MPLS plane in network
next i please
so this slide basically explains the
constructs and some of the constructs we
described in the previous diagram so the
main thing I want to point at this slide
is that each MPLS plane that is
identified with a context protocol next
hop the service routes can bind through
this MPLS plane by using that context
protocol next hop address ask the
protocol next arc and the bgp update and
the label can be a private label that
the application itself allocated next
site this so these are the protocol
extensions that are being done for this
mechanism the first draft is what we are
talking about right now that is a for
4364 style extension to provide with the
basic the link for the private labels so
second draft is a multi next wrap
attribute which basically allows other
bgp route to carry multiple next hops
with different forwarding semantics
which could be a four
would push Papa's lap the forward is
applicable for both IP and mpls traffic
but pushpop swap is applicable for MPLS
traffic that's right please so these are
the details of the route types that this
mechanism provides so the first route
type is that call the context for our
next operatives meant every router that
creates a context web error and pay less
for MPLS plane a hydrolyzes the context
to other BGP speakers and applications
so prefix is the Rd : context protocol
next hop address so as we already
mentioned context protocol next hop
address is the same IP address on each
of the routers which are participating
in that MPLS plane so the Rd is the one
that uniquely identifies each instance
router so and the attribute of this
route would be multi next hop attribute
which would just say push the context
label towards me where meaning is a
global l o0 and all of these routes have
the route target identified the MPLS
plane because it is just a lcvps next i
please so once the context has been
advertised to the applications now the
applications can install their own
private label values into the a tour
MPLS context just like we do install the
l3 VPN IP vrf routes and so the prefix
is nothing but a Rd : label and the
forwarding semantics can be anything
that the application wants which could
be identifying a certain resource which
is the next hop that is attached to
next wrap interface that attach to the
MPLS plane or a vr of that is attached
to the MPLS plane or when they're out is
getting the advertised to other speakers
in the MPLS plane it will be forwarded
to me where me is identified by Rd :
the context protocol next hop address
now the ID : context protocol next hop
address is resolved over the type 1
route that we saw in the previous slide
which is how we push the context label
over the private a private label to
reach to hit the correct context trip
next slide please
carry right you might want to think
about leaving room for questions
okay you have to lift okay so this slide
has a lot of detail but if you think
about it it is very similar to l-3 VPNs
so p1 and p2 are like the C's in a
European which come into a forwarding
context and once we come into the
forwarding context we are in a MPs plane
and we use the same l3 VPN context label
to remain in the same l3 VPN plane
I think I'm seven minutes now so next
slide I have shown an example of a use
case I think next slide so here we have
a case where we have a virtualized
environment and a bunch of routers are
vcv p1 which is a conglomeration of v CP
+ VF p1 v f p2 and there is a fabric
interconnecting all this
so there is an upstream node the service
forwarding helper which basically that
is getting all the traffic that's coming
from the core now the problem that here
we want to solve is the service
forwarding helper needs to direct the
traffic towards the right in V F P so
that we don't have an extra fabric hop
in the virtualized environment so the
way we are solving it using this
mechanism is v p1 is able to have a
context fehb for itself at the ssh and
he is able to program the routes that he
allocated locally significantly in his
embolus r0 into the VP 1 dot embolus so
that when the traffic comes from the
core SSH knows exactly whether the label
l1 is behind we have P 1 or V F P 2 so
this is one use case and because this
just makes an API into the network's
forwarding plane I think more use cases
can emerge so the backup slides have
more use cases described that you can
have a look offline that is what I had I
think I can take questions now if any
anyone for questions if not I'm closing
this session thank you everyone thank
you Carrie ash and see you in Singapore
thank you goodbye everyone
where are the blue sheets if you see
them next to you
[Music]
you