[Applause]
start in one minute stop eating the food
and sit down
Curt can you take notes this thank you
anybody want to be a jabber scrub we
have a note-taker you get a free gift
yeah actually it's they light up in
different patterns you get it's a rave
in your hand man okay this is Dee crow
if you are not looking for Dee corrupt
you're in the wrong room Lou sheets are
sick
oh yeah blue sheets are circulating I
believe we have a scribe of his Kurt I'm
sorry you know Curtis taking minutes and
a job ascribe is yo thank you very much
introduction okay yeah welcome to
decrypt the first meeting you all know
Marie and some of you know me I come
from the security side of things we
there was a Charter tweek you may have
noticed this was merely because I
noticed we weren't chartered to actually
deprecated Shawa and so I asked Alexia
to start that I realize in retrospect
that was probably me lessly pedantic but
I like putting him to work please note
the note well well is very likes to say
you have the right to remain silent
anything you say can be used by the ietf
you have the right to consult with your
attorney about your obligations and
other privileges about intellectual
property this is the formal version note
that the RFC numbers have changed a new
version of BCP 79 is issued that's the
RFC eight one seven nine mostly it's a
boiler plays the same note so 15 minutes
John you have the floor we seem to have
one open technical technical question
please
in the original the this is part of the
Charter that I don't think we have
changed is to add new and add new
signing techniques to D Kim and the
first and there have been two and
perhaps three of them one is to add hash
keys for RSA because we as we all know
there are bugs in DNS provisioning that
makes it foolishly difficult to publish
a key that doesn't fit in a single 256
byte next spring and and RSA key is
bigger than one K bits don't do that so
right so the thought is we could do what
other crypto protocols do and publish a
256 bit hash
and put the key itself in the signature
that's technically straightforward as
far as I can tell there is no
disagreement about that and Scot says
he's working on implementing it I think
Murray said he would look at it I know
I'm looking at it for the girl stuff
okay the second thing is to add elliptic
curve signatures again I don't think
there's any any disagreement about that
we seem to agree that we're doing what's
called pure IDI DSA which is ev2 five
five one nine without an extra level of
hashing and the signature is that's okay
and the contentious question is do we
also want to add a hashed or instead we
want to add a hashed version of of V V
DSA signatures now the hash in this case
there's no operational advantages the
hash is the same size as a signature and
the signature is small enough that even
if that even if a future electrical
curve algorithm had keys twice as big or
written four times as big it would still
fit in a single expert so my personal
preference is that since the hash key
says a hashed elliptical curve key adds
no operational advantage and since Indy
Kim since there is no signature since
there is no negotiation between the
sender and the receiver a receiver must
implement every possible crypto scheme
that any sender might use to
interoperate
I would rather minimize the number of
schemes and just add two other than
three so Mountain Thompson so there is
actually potentially a security benefit
to hashing and that is that when you
hash you end up putting the public key
in the message that you're sending and
as a consequence of that that public key
is then covered by the signature and
there are various ways in which
signatures are used but one of the less
obvious properties of signatures is that
if you generate a signature over over
something then it is possible it's
certainly in RSA and maybe in in some of
the elliptic curve variants to generate
a key that will validate with that same
signature
so you can generate a message sign it
and then I can claim to a sent that
message whether or not that's
interesting or an attack that actually
makes sense in this context is is
something that will require like a huge
amount of analysis but I'm just pointing
out that the potential here for us to
gain some additional defense against
people switching switching keys out for
messages just operationally we've had
this is operation that we've had we've
had these signatures for a decade and I
don't think anybody's mentioned this
issue until this month so I so if it is
if it's a practical problem it's a mr.
has to be a pretty low level one it
might be a pretty low level one I'll
also point out there being signing
messages with 512 bit RSA signatures and
no one's really made not sure for us
about that either so that's not really
and persuasive argument for me Phil Han
Baker yeah III I think I need to see a
example of quite what's being alleged
here in that yes there are some games
that you can play but that's kind of the
right the reason that Dorothy Deming
pointed out that we needed to have the
hash in the signature in the first place
but that's what so I was a big proponent
of hashes because you can make the
configuration experience easier for the
user because you know hash is you can
make them small enough to be but then
again when I started to look into what
you would want to manage a DNS zone or
whatever basically I don't think that it
actually does do any good because what
you probably want to have is some tool
that is organizing your hashes and your
keys anyway and so it's not very you
should not be having to cut and paste
the keys into the DNS zone file
anyway so that advantage went away so
III I support just you doing the Rakhi
yeah just just for people who aren't
familiar with the am the unhappy czar
not going away anytime soon just for
backwards compatibility now so I'm
channeling Jim Fenton saying if we are
trying to minimize the number of things
that need to interoperate do we need
both hashing and elliptic curve aren't
they two ways of solving the same
problem so um just two I take what I
think Martin's argument was on Eric
rajala on about the potential ability
which I also don't know how to exploit
is that say um say we had some situation
where a message was referred to um where
where you have an existing published
message and what I want to do is I want
to claim ownership of that message and I
can't change the message by Ken
I can't publish mething stuff in DNS so
what you do is you basically make a new
key which generates the signature on the
message um and then you put that in DNS
and how you can ask them it's one of
those to a corresponding to this to say
I don't know how to yet but that would
be the thing warrants concerned about um
we you would have to put put it in the
same zone is the real key ship of the
message right because it's it's not like
an S mine signature on the content
you're cleaning ownership of the the
thing that music this is exactly the
same content this is absolute is a same
issue error found that acne right it's
the same underlying underlying issue um
so right um I I certainly um I guess it
seems to me that like the natural thing
to do if you want to minimize the number
of things you have to do and you think
you know we have to hash RSA is to say
let us let us go forward hashing all the
time and then um and then I appreciate
that like 1024 bit RSA has a nonce way
is its way out but um it was anyone to
be it to finish
but you know at some point arm which may
not be too far in the future um we may
at the point where people simpler that
world where the large volume messages
receive have two signatures on them one
of which is either eec or hashed RSA at
which point you can say I'm tired of
supporting 24 10 24 hours RSA and
listener and because you don't have to
accept anything in particular and
because that what happens in receptors
you ignore it um then this isn't like
this isn't like you know receiving h.264
where you're like don't have internet
video if you like decide on what they
uses before is it matter if you don't
get like the beacon validity that's what
so it's perfectly easy to exam in the
market and say well we're now at 78% of
my messages or one of these two modern
things and I just don't care about
twenty fours anymore so um so I have to
process the long tail so I think what I
would have a key for is simply saying we
are consistently hashing and then at
some point not lawsuits in future um
until I say always in that far away then
you can just throw away them a hash code
path um so if we're finding them as code
paths that's axe isn't it because I say
we have to me if we think anybody's
gonna do hashed RSA then we have to have
passion and you're talking when you say
but using the term hashing you mean like
hash the content inside and then
negative I'm saying if the issue is
about whether the keys ought to be
hashed or not oh that's right then then
then then consistently hashing is the
thing that will lead you in the future
to have only one go path yeah not until
some weather or whether or not the
signing over the key is a value or not I
think the we have to consider the fact
that the future is much bigger than the
past and as I could points out we have
we have evidence to suggest that this is
something that we don't have to worry
about a long tail I agree with eken
anyone else others sorry yeah I think
I've talked to everybody who is doing an
implementation I don't think any of us
see see it's a meaningful simplification
in in doing two hashes
is that fair so I'm not gonna like lie
down on the road on this one I think if
if people are implementing this want to
avoid the extra step then then that's
that's fine a little little concern
about the signing of the key I think
this
that's part of the reason why we signed
over identities in in TLS and various
other protocols but again like I said
couldn't couldn't pin anything to it I I
guess I will say that upon consideration
I don't think it's worth having two
forms of the EDD essay so I think why I
would prefer to hash it upon um and be
clear I guess there to be two here pass
the key all the time thank you the
public key all the time if people don't
think we see that then I think the
answer is to do hashed RSA and unhatched
so my rank order will be hashed hashed
key always hash hash key for RSA on hash
key free DVD essay um finally all
finally hashing hashing and on hashing
for VSA and hetero sex I think I almost
agree with you except for the universe
except for perhaps the order of some of
the preferences I also agree fewer is
better right so I think I guess I'm
willing to defer I think I and my people
were thinking that sense of the room but
I'm going to refer to the sense of the
room like like the only other thing to
consider is that if we have to go post
column on this one then we're gonna have
large keys how's it gonna be hashed Oh
most likely I mean this is a rather
speculative but you know what one of the
one of the techniques that the post
called Oh months users rather watch yeah
they're all actually be large if we have
to go post quantum most likely TLS is
gonna be using the way on that anyway
right yeah and if we startin before you
go I'm just one comment like you're
absolutely right but if we have to go
postpone and we're gonna have to revise
this document anyway so everything's up
in the air anyway so if we got could you
post a note to the list explaining
explaining an issue about the key
swapping and then we'll just incorporate
that into the suit direct trauma put
that message you know in the security
considerations we're not doing this
we're not sure the risks but here's what
it is okay as far as I can tell what we
are primarily
arcing about is the is speculative
future future simplicity of the code
paths depending on we think what we
think is gonna happen in the future and
if we think in the future we're gonna
end up having to have hash keys in its
you have always hash keys I'm thinking
the future we're gonna having largely
unhatched keys that it's you start
always on hash keys so that's to say I
think we all heard guesses on that
willing to defer to the consensus the
room I guess I don't know how you wanna
I've ever heard of any people talk about
it so I think you know you want to go
home or do you want to like whatever I
don't think we need to hum now I'm
peppadews let it go on the list and
figure it out that way if we go post
quantum we're probably going to be
looking at a new version of SMTP let
alone TLS or whatever yeah yeah
if you look at what it would take it's
basically everything goes out the window
so just a month or about bring back UCP
okay we're done with this one yes I must
say it's a very clever thread is what I
had when I hadn't thought up until you
until you mentioned it right I'll
provide text and before you disappear
John because oh I was just about to ask
you are you done the I the review that I
wrote of the draft hit the list I may
have mentioned that I preferred hashing
in it and that caused an enormous it
wasn't just you rat hole
yes I don't know who started the
particular thread through your Apollo
there are a bunch of other comments in
there that I think are really important
yeah although tonight it seems likely
that we will we will break break the
draft up into separate pieces so like
the comic the stuff about deprecating
sha-1 it's an out no is now wasn't it
did or didn't work for Belarus
that that would be fine oh yeah the more
verbose thing is a problem that I'll get
to later but the there are there were
some comments in there that I think are
pretty pretty crucial and I want to make
sure that those don't get lost
particularly when we get things moving
between documents yeah I'm gonna close
the loop on that yeah I missed the
cutoff now that doesn't open again I
will I will spirit its through them into
the next version okay great thanks so
this is kind of a strange thing to
channel but well citizen channeling
anything and did anyone find the stuff
on this roof remark if so please contact
so um I also just since I'm just a list
a few minutes ago but the names of these
things um so um is it as well yeah both
the DNS and the okay good so if anybody
I I think anybody V Malia Josh the
suggestion that the name should say to
55.9 where other than her 256 um and not
just better than they should discuss it
but if not people remind us where we are
we have extra time too so we're little
heads good just as we start at 10
minutes early so you can ignore it to
some degree the time limits on these all
right so the dekum usage document is
supposedly and probably the simplest
these the changes as I recall are that
we are deprecating use of sha-1 entirely
we are increasing the floor as a part
and put it for the number of bits and
keys that we should be accepting to 1024
and there's a third thing that I escapes
me at the moment but essentially this is
a an update to deke him directly that
doesn't add anything but simply tightens
up base requirements sorry so Mike
should I talk about that one so yes
that's all this is Seth who just
mentioned something is going to be
shepherding this document I think we're
pretty close
modulo what we're about to talk about
too less calling this it's it's a very
simple update document so glad Martin so
Martin Thompson though there are a
number of things that I had concerns
with this document I mean what you have
on the slide is exactly it I think we
should not do PSS in this document
absolutely okay that's so that's a
no-brainer then we have two things and
what you have right there
is almost the sum total of the document
yet it somehow manages to be five pages
and two of those are in our fault but
yeah well yes but I think you might be
able to get it down to two and I think
that simply means providing some
rationale for why the document exists
and then saying must not use char one
must use keys of 1024 bits or higher or
you know maybe we can make it a little
higher than that even
I think 1024 is perfectly reasonable at
this point in time the document
currently includes a whole chunk
of text from the DK MRC verbatim without
modifying it it's very confusing we need
to stop doing that
yep and the other thing is we don't need
to modify the a B and F which is say
have to tell people not to use those
code points and modifying the ABN F
makes this document bigger and more
complicated and we have iona
considerations and all sorts of other
things that really don't advance things
we just need to tell people just stop
using that it's broke I think there was
a idea put in someone's head that the
way you deprecated something is to
pretend like it never existed before
yes I agree so we'll fix it but I'd like
I said I plan to get this last called in
short order there's really not much to
it there's no reason yep anything else
so this one um I'm just trying to think
about what the security properties of
all this are so the existing so I'm just
gonna use for a second of people indulge
me um so um these visiting attacks on
sha-1 or all collision attacks and we
don't have any free image attacks yet
maybe we never um so the the collision
attacks on the so engine egg about like
how do you support a collision in this
system I think the way you exploit the
collision in this system is and or no
you say like why it can't because like
the produce it is all produced by via
pop by the center but if the way you've
put occlusion in the system is that um
say you have like a mere relay that just
spin filtering and now what I do is I
give you two messages one of which and I
can you throw any of the input right but
I give you two messages one of which one
for you to sign that is innocuous and is
it is it full my pornography or whatever
and then I take this inter off and I
shovel to my party traffic one on so I
don't know like it anybody's written
down what you might actually be ideal to
do with a collision attack on deacon but
i'm i birthed someone thinking about
that i'm i don't know the system wanted
that right now on the on the irrelevant
point is that there are two more clocks
there's the clock when you stop making
um someone's integers which is the one
where collision attacks don't work
longer become an issue and there's the
point where you start perceiving them
which is the point where pretty much
could become an issue and so and
so on it might be nice in these
documents to say something about what we
think the times appropriate time scales
were phasing out acceptance of sha-1
which I understand that we can't do for
quite some time but um I know I mean
that the browser's made a lot of noise
remember I stopped accepting sha-1
certificate so I wonder I wonder if we
should I wonder if we should say
something at least about these you know
we expected to some point in future with
some big time scale ways but they
actually say you stopped accepting them
as well I think you just wrote our
security considerations like um if
somebody someone can actually so so as
Adi refused to actually take any tokens
but it someone remind me to do it i
wobble okay thank you it'll be short
like the rest of the document on living
apropos of the Ayane stuff in my draft I
move sha-1 to historic that we think
that's a good idea
yes okay that would be one I nted change
this I thought this did that maybe
that's not Thursday I was that was in my
draft I don't think it's at Scott's
graph it should be in Scott Scott okay
yeah thanks for that reminder
it's in my graft I'm gonna take it out
of yours and yeah so they both drops
include a similar sort of modification
if there is a way for I enter the flag
something is you know do not use we have
a call exploit that we have a column in
this in the register we're talking about
it says obsolete or current yes do that
this is very I know some of the security
related some of the crypto related
registries have things like should and
should plus and something like that or
whatever that says that the status is
likely to change to be stronger in the
next version let's not go there says
Martin okay nevermind like if it said
thank you yeah John the meeting at mean
as far as when do stop except accepting
them that's sort of more of a mug issue
is its most let me for ten years we told
people sha-1 is bad and it's most in its
appears to be largely a matter of
figuring out who's still signing with
sha-1 and beating up on the disiike we
can persuade them to change which is not
really the I ATF's remit you know and I
think
I don't know I don't see how we can say
anything other than the obvious like
stop accepting them when there's when
they're sufficiently if you useful
useful signatures Chris Newman a concern
I have about the document is I'd like to
see actually must check the key size of
the key is at least twenty four now I
don't care how you use the result of
that that can be up to policy but you
must check this the key size we had this
I noticed we had this problem in TLS
implementations where things thought
they were generating keys of the right
size and they weren't and and it created
Interop problem so I'd really like to
get that check in early Kurt Anderson
responding to John's comment about
people accepting sha-1 yes just the very
fact that this draft is in flight
provided a lot of leverage and three of
the major folks that were still actually
sending sha-1 were convinced last month
to stop doing it and have stopped doing
it in the month subject so go true so
going what has stopped and the other two
are moving in that direction so going
back to D Marc we don't need an
experimental draft anymore right yeah
sometimes I think perhaps I have a
different spin on what what I was
suggesting maybe this document should
simply say must not and let's not create
or accept and then it is a matter of
policy for those who are deploying this
and we can have in there security
considerations text about when those
things might actually start to need to
be enforced is it okay if we say must
not generate and then just let it wither
away that's the challenge there is what
Chris was talking about which is that
people end up generating 512 bit keys
and signatures and then you end up sort
of in this situation if people I think
it's a useful hammer for people to have
in the sort of policy and deployment
area just simply say the ITF ITF said
and so we have a way people can use that
in their communities to actually have
the things happen all right before we
get to Phil is there anyone in the room
has an objection to saying don't
generate don't part don't accept okay
good segue Phil yeah I think that we
should say it must not generate on the
acceptance side depends upon what you're
going to be using foot them for if
you're using the signature as evidence
of the message validity as was used in
the DNC attack then of course yes you're
looking at the semantics of the message
and it really does matter if on the
other hand all you're doing is doing
spam filtering which was the original
idea of deacon then you know breaking a
sha-1 hash breaking an RSA key that that
looks more like a proof-of-work you know
if somebody's going to break a sha-1
hash to to get a message through my spam
filter you know maybe it's what so I
think in general in terms of how the ITF
works if we go from must to must not on
the receive side I think it sends a bad
signal to ourselves in that it's tells
us that we can tell the the community to
turn on a dime and one of the things
I've been weighted with sha Wan was that
I was telling people to do sha to like a
year after it was published by nist and
people ignored me and then suddenly we
have kab forum say okay we've got to get
rid of char wanna we got to do it in 18
months and so I don't like the idea that
that's an acceptable thing to tell the
community so I think that going through
the phase of must not create may accept
and you know the discipline of realizing
that we can't just yank algorithms of
out is useful because it will cause us
to maybe be more careful in the future
so that it's interesting you you you're
like an interesting counterpoint to what
we've been hearing which is the
community asking us to give them a
hammer by which they can hit themselves
over the head to move for it look there
there's a there's there's a certain
amount of inertia that a must not accept
will solve and so you're actually this
is the first question to give which is
it's not to say it's not valid but say
they've been saying could you please say
must not could you please say must not I
finally relent like okay well if they
must not and now it's sort of the
opposite perspective it's interesting to
hear both ways so Seth blank Val mill
basically it feels like we said should
not in 2010 before and there's been
plenty of time for realize it to do that
and the must 2007 so a decade and the
must not language is what's necessary to
hammer everyone else it worked at MOG
last month we had you know there are
three major ESPs who I won't name in
shame but who were still signing with
sha-1 we talked to them and they all
said with the threat of D Krupp and must
not were just deprecating sha-1 language
saying this is coming these
conversations happening right okay all
three we go we don't need to keep going
on about must not too much longer about
go ahead mom Thompson I think in
response to these comments the the key
thing here is that the signature still
exists and it can still be input into
things like spam filtering and whatnot
and if we have the right text in the
security consideration is talking about
when this matters having the headline is
still valuable I mean I think people are
asking for the headline headline thing
is going to be the body of the document
must not blah blah blah and then there's
gonna be some deployment considerations
that say you know this is gonna take
some time and people are going to still
be signing with them and there's still
value in having that signature there in
some contexts but I
think it opening to to back away fully
from this thing yeah not already there's
also a timetable from publication to
when it actually gets approved and then
then the card has to go Coonan we had
this discussion in other working groups
also operating Saarinen and in most of
the case you have to understand there's
two different things we are talking
about here there's must not implement
and must not use those are very
different things
implemented or actually the vendors who
make those products they hate must not
implement people task means that they
immediately if they want to be
conforming it this documentation they
have to remove the whole code which
means that then they can't have a
backward compatible plat flag I said oh
yeah but yeah we have to see this
product here that doesn't support it so
we have to have it and they say sorry we
can't do if it must not implement then
you can have you know like for example
OpenSSH has this you know if you want
user group 1 and solve one you have to
enable these flags to be able to use it
but you can still use it must of use is
okay I think that's that that's
something that we can say but of course
usually we don't give instructions but
you can use because we say that it's
actually you know policy policy
requirements for them you know these
people who are using it must not
implement is really annoying in that
sense that and if you say oh we can
burst not with some kind of oh you can
use it if you want it it should not it's
not much not anymore if you have any
reason why you want to use it then it
should not with some reason and it's
always good thing to say the reason why
you wanted but then you can use it if it
is not well cut the line after Kurt yeah
yeah I only want to about must not under
should not have the experience that all
these should or should not in the ITF
drafts also only our justification to to
not move forward I'm more often wish
that there is a must not also in that
case and everybody who can't follow that
must not is free to not use
months yeah Kurt Anderson so given that
we all realize that there's a certain
cadence to getting documents out and
published and and updated maybe we can
write a timetable for moving through
these phases into the document so as was
suggested we start off with a must not
send then we add maybe we put a deadline
next year June of 2018 must not accept
and we write that into the document so
that there's essentially a tripwire in
there and Ayana changes the registration
in June of next year that says must not
accept in the meantime it so should not
and it becomes a must not and everybody
can point to that they both get the
headline as well as we don't have to do
another document and it just happens
so what I've been hearing in the room so
far is most people are in favor of just
making it must not generate must not
accept all right let's take a home how
many the question is how many people are
in favor over the documents saying must
not generate or accept and how many
people are not in favor and how many
people don't have enough info to decide
so all in favor all those opposed all
those who need more information that
seem pretty strong and favor yeah
they're great
yeah well standard ski will confirm it
on the mailing list but don't we have to
confirm I'm a list that's when we do it
insecurity that's not the point the
point is it sounds like you just took a
vote people who object have their
objections been aired and discussed or
did we just do a vote okay so
Fintan and jabber says that he agrees
with must not generate but it's too soon
for must not accept what see well you
you got the sense of the room so you
need to take it to the to the mailing
list of make the final decision and let
people the chance to object one where
the other so it's okay to say there was
a room consensus you know rough
consensus but you know it's no more than
that mm-hm
okay so apart from me not must not peace
of this conversation I think we've
covered all the known issues with this
draft I sent her some my own review
comments I'll get Scott to do a new
version no he'll be able to hear that
and see the notes of this or hear the
transcript and figure out what else we
discussed but I I do plan to get this
sort of last call this fast as I can
reasonably get it done without missing
any important points there's really not
much to this left the ECC I don't think
Scott is here is he Scott Rose oh yeah
I'm sorry hi I'm Scott Rose NIST
basically I don't think this draft is
needed anymore
Amy because this is for there's a
community out there that needs to also
implement FIPS 140 stuff having some
internal discussions it seems now that
there's actually a roadmap for this sort
of thing to get EB DSA into FIPS 140 so
things are kind of progressing barring
any kind of strange management stuff so
in effect the actual reason this draft
exists is gone if there is a bunch of
people that really really really like
ECDSA over the kerbs mentioned on the
list and otherwise I'm not gonna work on
this anymore we can label it dead yeah
yeah okay Wow no you got another four
minutes sorry I'm really sorry I'm very
very do you want me to say it again wow
that's that's actually seriously great
news that too
Feb 19 and will show up in 5th cool no
no no you're on the hook now you have to
include the standard disclaimer that
you're not making announcement about
future product uncle bub we are done
unless anybody else has other business
for this working group okay we may or
may not see you in Singapore thank you
everybody
where is it
I think
you