well actually did lose the order easier
is it gonna read his first his vehicle
and then John and then is W
[Music]
[Laughter]
alright should begin alright good
afternoon everyone this is the DC
working group I will remind people about
the note well you've seen it many times
probably and don't need to read it
hopefully you know it the blue sheets
are going around we do need some jabber
ethernet note-takers so if anybody is
willing to assist in doing that that
would be awesome you know put some notes
out on ether pad and we'll we'll use
those as two to produce the minutes
anybody willing to do that anybody
willing to do jabber scribing
so I can cope with both but I would be
distracted yeah
alright thanks and just so everybody
knows I'm Bernie volts one of the
co-chairs and and I'm telling about
sceeto and do not have a working group
secretary but if anybody is interested
let us know okay the agenda is as
follows we'll take a few minutes to do
some administration at minister via
agenda bashing things like that
then we'll have john grochowski present
on some DC PV deployment stuff a Comcast
we have a discussion on secure dhcpv6 as
there were some issues raised recently
on that document and some concerns and
so the question is what do we do about
it do we need to make some significant
changes do we drop the work or whatever
and then we have two presentations on
some individual submissions on some new
options for dhcpv6 and this in some
cases they should be before all as well
just a quick update on the working group
document status there were two RCS
published the failover protocol for v6
and the prefix length hint issues one RC
is in the editor queue and we have six
working group drafts that are currently
active details can be found for those on
the data tracker so quick update on 33
15 biz we did have a working group last
call last summer which generated about
270 issues we did publish a new version
in March of 2017 which addressed most
but not all of the issues and then we
published one in May which address the
remaining issues and and we initiated
another working group last call on that
document
and received reviews with about 30
mostly minor issues there's a few that
were a little bit more significant but
most of them were fairly minor edits to
the document we did publish a no 9 which
addressed all of those issues and Roth
sent an email out because he's the
consensus scholar on the document that
you know he believes the working group
has reached consensus on the document
there will likely be a - 10 before we do
send it on one made dependent will
depend on what happens with a secure
DHCP v6 work because currently the 3315
biz does reference that and if we
determine we're not going to make much
progress on that document maybe it's not
appropriate to reference it another is
that I had meant to update Appendix A to
include some clarification regarding the
lifetimes that was an issue raised by
Jin May that we addressed in the onine
document but I forgot to mention it in
the updates the changes that we did and
hopefully we'll get a few reviewers to
review the changes we made for the O
nine and confirm that they're okay or
provide us a few additional edits that
we will make so please do review the O 9
and again the goal is to publish the -
10 in early August and send that on to
Suresh our ad and the iesg eventually
and we'd like to thank Ralf for being
the document shepherd and doing the
working group consensus determination
work any questions about any event and I
didn't really stop to ask if there was
any issues with the agenda that we
wanted to rearrange things but I assume
somebody would have stopped if they had
would have stopped me if they had some
concerns
okay so John you're up and you know this
to stay in the pink box and all that fun
stuff
okay so John rejewski so after the last
I during the last ITF I saw a hummock in
the hall I was telling them about some
of the things have you been up to and I
think they thought will be valuable if I
told you guys a little bit about the
current state of these PP six at Comcast
X library yeah that's a little this
slides didn't line up when I converted
them because I only did them like 45
minutes ago so yeah as Ralphie knows
Bernie as well you know over a decade
ago three of us and probably a handful
of other people it's been a lot of time
specifying how v6 was intended to
operate within all the cables
technologies DOCSIS ear outer pad cable
etc DSP has been a critical part of
stockist networks since the beginning of
its time that that didn't change with
before and I think you know as you know
we don't have we may not have some love
for DTP DCP in the room right but I
think the the byproduct of its
availability is unquestionable right
it's it's basically enabled companies
like Comcast to take ipv6 connectivity
to tens of millions of customers right
so that's yeah that's material so we did
that work in 2005 spend a lot of time
over past 10 12 years writing things
like these P servers C MTS's network etc
and next slide and we'll talk a little
bit about where that stands today so
today in our network 99% of about 44
million cable modems used HP v6 and they
are v6 only 90 percent in growing of our
ear adders our dual stack provisions so
they both get an i na and an IP D and
99% of and that's probably about 20
million 21 million
and for set-top boxes which is a video
our video platform 99% rp6
only no before and that's probably north
of you know 1616 some million right next
slide
maybe the cable modems use embedded
their their own kind of embedded
homegrown DC v6 clients so like you know
you'll get these from things like you
know Broadcom or Intel some of them you
use open-source implement v6 client that
we used for our set-top boxes or set-top
boxes if I can go back you know need to
move the slides but I'll point back to
that they both get in I na and I PD so I
set that walk is more like a video
gateway right so it's a host and a
router so we treated a lot like a near
our right and our set that box happens
to use the dibbler implementation
probably you know slightly you know aged
version which you know I'm sure I'll get
some criticisms for here momentarily but
we happen to know somebody in the room
that has knows something about diddler I
think next slide please
huh yeah yeah yeah so some observations
it has been extremely stable probably
you know honestly that this wasn't an
arbitrary decision we took a look at a
lot of the other implementations and
landed on this one because of its
stability and ease of use I came with a
lot of things that worked just out of
the box one of the things that you know
we're working on right now is shrinking
the binary size so it's a it's a rather
large binary size unfortunately that I'm
getting yelled at at work to kind of
help rectify maybe I can get some advice
perhaps at some point but it was
actually it actually was actually quite
easy for us to kind of work up the
configurations to kind of make these
things very you know DOCSIS ish or cable
like so there are options that must be
transmitted as part of the DCP six
transaction that allow for us to
provision these devices one of the
things that we did notice and we try to
you know we I think we tried and refrain
from hacking diddler is when when
dibbler does a proper shutdown it sends
a release that was actually causing
some some issues for us on the
provisioning side of things so one of
the things we talked about was modifying
the kind of the the the implementation
control script is to simply kill mine
the process which would prevent the
release from being sent but that was um
we don't do that because it was it was
not friendly so one of the things that
we're looking at doing so I'll kind of
pause there to see if there's anybody
has any questions or comments we'll talk
a little bit about futures and then I'll
get out of your hair but I just want to
give it a minute to see if you guys had
anything questions or the working group
had any other comments or questions so
one of the things we're looking at now
with DSP p6 is really trying to optimize
we have I mean if you think about the
math that I just told you right yeah
there's probably we're probably
approaching a hundred million bindings
in our DSP platform and you know this
this server platform there happens to be
somebody yeah both multiple people in
the room here who know about that
so what we're so now every day is a
first at Comcast and and what I mean by
that is every day is a first new record
right of number of v6 devices on our
network right this uh yeah we reached
his first first last last June and then
every day from this point four is
basically brand new another another kind
of new day so what we're finding is is
that with the increase in these number
of devices and the number of
transactions right because every DC
client it performs reliefs release at
some interval sorry renew at some
interval many of devices actually do it
every day right so where we are now is
we're looking to really you know would
that with the growth that v6 has really
it really enabled us to pursue it's
unencumbered us from that point of view
right we've been able to add many more
devices because of u6 as a result the
scale is is now almost doubled over the
past you know ten years so now we're
we're looking at opportunities to kind
of really optimize these be these p v6
and one of those optimizations is
perhaps going down the path of stateless
TTP six haven't haven't done anything
more than just some kind of some unit
testing and frankly there's some people
back back at the office that deserve all
the credit not me we just we just
offered the idea up and then so
folks who are you know who I trusted
quite a bit at work went off and did a
lot of that work but those are some of
things that we're looking at some of the
other things that we talked about as
part of the unique prefix per host is
looking at doing previous delegation
over Wi-Fi unfortunately that does not
involve either diddler or our use of CR
today the DCP server is embedded within
the within the the wireless aggregation
device but it still should be of
interest to you guys as well right so
with that I think that's my last slide
anything that you want me to touch on
before like we take questions or
comments so right now with the the
client the nibla client you're doing
both the address assignment and prefix
delegation the relax yep cool yeah it's
it's yeah I mean it's it's a nice
implication thank you
yes oh so you have to keep me attend
this project and to give me an
alternative to replace it with okay you
know I get from dibbler I keep getting
sorry buddy support for ipv6 prefix Loa
could get delegation not enabled I think
that one's not his fault I think it's
yours where on your home readers that
one yes yeah that's a good one though
that's I appreciate bringing up that
point we we had some bugs to fix we are
in the process of implementing sub
prefix delegation I don't know if that's
really ever been a topic that you guys
really wanted to needed to a warrant to
get in cuttin and you know involved with
it was a little bit of a knife fight in
kind of the combination of v6 ops and in
particular home net but it's it's gonna
happen I do have a large population of
gateways today that do this we just
haven't gotten around to releasing the
getting it across the entire population
of devices so in Tim winners UNH I wall
so in that case you're you have some
algorithm for how you guys are gonna
carve up the P sub P DS yes okay
are you gonna document that there he is
I think we write it down in some either
a internet draft here or a cable apps
document anyone get somewhere I have to
take it up but we we talked about it
there was like you can do a Glee
remember this you know deep and wide you
know it's either a bunch of it's either
a bunch of like so like at that point
just full disclosure we would in the
situation like that the home router
would get a 56 absolutely right and then
we would either do like 58 or 60s oh
yeah honestly this days of the game we
have enough experience with it to know
that this whole idea that people are
gonna want like 254 64 is in their house
we don't know we don't say that yeah so
so we think something on the higher end
yeah maybe 58 or 60 should be sufficient
but saying we know we still see issues
where gateways will take their delegated
prefix that's shorter than yeah 64 and
I'm not putting the PIO it still blows
my mind I mean yeah it happens it's bad
it's we get them all the time
um the other question was you do any
stateless or is all your stuff stateful
you always use DHCP and all these
deployments the staple version you're
never giving out options in the home
yeah in the home there should be
stateless D to be b6
okay in the access network always stay
always I mean yeah yeah I mean that's
the way that's the way DSP was born and
cables and that's you know it's the
shortest distance between two points
there was for us to just kind of keep
going the same thing yep
any other questions comments no cool
thank you thank you dude do you have
stats on how many hosts use their RDS
ue6 stateful assigned address I mean you
do support stateful internally in the
home network where you don't not I don't
want to say University raised because we
have a mix of implementations slack is
everywhere are you this test is
everywhere right we have some gateways
that do anything that does state lists
the state full but there are some
gateways that don't do have D that don't
have d TP service at all right if memory
serves correctly and I think you're
asking me which ones which which what's
the yeah you asked me like how many
leases are being known in the the point
that I realized recently is that
depending on the size of the pool that
these things have
they can end up being like privacy
issues because they don't change if
they're like if you have a host that
prefers DHT v6 assigned address I don't
know what typical has - then it becomes
very important how big the size of the
pool that the Gateway has and how often
it changes the event like the answer
that I'm about to offer you that so
basically what one of the things I know
that we did is we went from the last so
0 0 0 2 FF FF is the pool right so
65,000 yeah yeah so I'm not I'm not a
huge fan so I rather almost just turn it
off right that's kind of dangerous yeah
I mean it's it's not good for privacy
because it's likes trivial to scan that
number of addresses yeah but what John
this is Bernie what what devices are you
talking about here is this anyway the
home games are you talking about like if
I'm sitting at Wi-Fi at home right so
soon before I have a NAT so no but it
depends on what the gateway vendor does
because you don't usually supply them
with a built that off of a document that
I wrote eight years ago oh okay yeah I
mean it was just just active predates 62
or whatever it was and other crap like
that because you could make it from my
book one to do here so we had to go we
had a business we have to like chop chop
move along right so so we kind of just
moved on without it's also the it's also
the quest it's also the case that its
rotations important too even if you did
rotate it all right you know yeah now
you know it's not with these keywords
dude right that gateway will continue to
renew that address for as long as the
upper 64 will change that the lower
support could change but my guess is
most clients to put their old address in
it'll be a hint to the server and then
it'll it'll help to see whatever there's
new allocation is so so then so then we
need to make sure that implementations
are preferring other addresses yeah I
mean I think yeah yeah that's something
that you mentioned in passing here this
one no but we do is it's privacy problem
right yeah they prefer these three six
assign address yeah it has to do with a
default address selection so they do
algorithms it's it's kind of out of the
box you don't you don't quite know what
you're gonna get it does vary a little
bit but yeah it depends on the address
scheme most of some of them will choose
privacy privacy address over the 41
ninety-one address but if they're not
doing that then it's a crapshoot I've
actually seen deeds
be be preferred and the I don't know I
can't offer you a number right but but
my memory serves my memory tells me like
it's preferred the vast majority of time
yeah cuz it's a rush and compared to
before right that's that's the thing I'm
getting at here and before you have the
fad right and so your address is nota
mised but in you know but nv6 somebody
can just like track you using the last
few but understood i i'd like to have
that conversation with you lorenzo and
if you're looking to have some
collaboration era i'm open to that
i like the idea of kind of specifying
the kind of the pitfalls of having a
very narrow base for address allocations
on the flip side i have concerns right
so like one of the things we're noticed
and it's not that different with with
with slack privacy i want to make sure
that we don't explode the impact on the
neighbor tables right like this is this
is a serious concern that I have no I've
seen this blow up so my gateways already
right
ralphe ralphe drums still living the
dream amen the question was about
temporary versus permanent addresses do
you have any idea whether clients ask
for temporary permanent what they I mean
that was that was our intention when we
originally came up with that division
but I have no idea whether whether any
clients actually make that distinction
and use use them as they were intended
that is the permanent address for
incoming incoming and temporaries for
outgoing I've even lost that in the
shuffle do not say like so when I go
barreling down the path of trying to you
know get you know v6 down or something
oh yeah I go right to you know na and no
no snow temporaries I mean I it doesn't
ring a bell
I was so as as as a result I'll say I
don't think there is heavy requesting
end or allocation of addresses in that
regard okay anyone else super thanks
guys all right thank you John
[Music]
all right here we go okay okay so this
transition is about help I'm touring
across key so I'd like to present to
what's been happening with the secure
DCP recently I am NOT echo out or I just
tried to move this work forward and been
mostly unsuccessful with this so epic of
history so this draft or its
predecessors we're around for quite a
long time we went through last call in
March
there were several reviews in general
they were favorable they said that the
draft has improved in terms of clarity
and completeness in quality was good
however the major issue rised was that
there are no existing implementations so
and this draft is quite complex so
people are uncomfortable with moving
this draft forward and then after a
while a primary author recently she
disappeared and stopped responding for
males for for couple months fortunately
she got back like two days ago but she
missed a lot
in the process so we hope that the issue
could be addressed with having a canal
in Prague however and shortly after the
hackathon was announced we discovered
that there's a problem that I got me
used to to sign the packet as has the
problem with the limitation so it's it
was too small for for some of the these
three packets so and after that long
discussion and shoot and people stepped
back and try to ask the basic question
so what are the problems we are trying
to solve and these are some of the ideas
that were mentioned so as you can see
this is you know a very broad spectrum
of things that people could consider in
in general when you think about security
and DHCP so lots of issues lots of
technologies trying to solve different
problems so we thought that ok so this
is not exactly going you know towards
completion so we stepped back and talked
about what what are the the problems
that we're trying to solve so we had a
meeting Constantine so all the outers
and people who are involved that
commented they were invited only only
four people showed up we went through
different use cases and suddenly the
conclusion was that it's probably dead
it means current form and after that we
also had a chance to talk with Kathleen
who is a security ID and she suggested
that we could consider different options
one of them would be to publish this as
experimental another one would be to
trim it down to cover just the
opportunistic encryption as a way to
mitigating pervasive monitoring attack
so during the discussion we tried to
define what are the use cases that this
just could address so the first one is
the corporate network so you have
devices that are trying to connect to
the today in corporate network and but
then exactly
no people jumping up and down waiting
for this waiting to develop the
solutions and deploy it in in corporate
networks and we strongly believe that
the reason is that you can you can
protect the first hope with 802 and dot
1x when we're talking about
communication between the client and the
relay and between the relay and the
server can be protected with IPSec there
are also other technologies that can
help with this environment for example
the HP v6 shield so another use case
that was frequently mentioned is the
coffee shop so you have your your device
you come to a coffee shop you don't
exactly know them but you would like to
use the internet so the tofu trust of
unfused use model it was mentioned
suggest agent but when you at first
glance it it sounds good
but if you take a closer look it really
doesn't hurt that much so it helps a bit
with pervasive monitoring in the sense
that that you could encrypt the traffic
but actually you don't know who you are
connecting to so whether you are
connecting to the right server or maybe
rope server and also the argument that
ok so it helps with providing monitoring
but if the if the server is
participating in the monitoring you are
out of luck anyway so people came up
with some ideas that ok maybe you could
put some stickers like you go to coffee
shop and you scan the QR code and then
based of that you can confirm whether
this is the right or or bogus server but
this is very easy to circumvent someone
can go in and stick new sticker on top
of it so it doesn't help a lot
so in the last use case that we have is
inside their attack in corporate network
so this is something that that threat is
very interested in so the idea is that
okay you are using 802 1x so you are
authenticated to use the network but
then you can impersonate someone else
like to elevate your privileges or cover
your tracks and also in the discussions
one of the slightly uncommon use case
was mentioned that if this would ever be
deployed in a military this could be
used when someone steals the device and
gets access to the network it can
broaden the impact of the attack so
these are the use cases that we
considered so ok given all that I think
I covered all the aspects of the
discussions that we recently had so now
I'd like to consider what are the next
steps so first we could fix the problem
with signing the with the with the
encryption size limitation there are
some known techniques for that and then
we could publish this as experimental so
this is one option another world another
option is to scope down this work to
cover just the opportunistic encryption
this requires some work but still it
could be done the tip the possibility is
to work on a problem statement first
so basically step back and agree on what
are the problems that we need to solve
and then deliver a solution that solving
only those problems and final option is
to drop the work so I'd like to ask you
what are your opinions what are your
preferences
you know and also if there's a general
discussion on any of the you know things
that um I presented earlier people have
follow-up questions around some of the
things that that we talked about we'd
love to to hear those
so Tim one airshow nhi well I vote
opportunistic encryption on this one
hey I also be okay if we want to go back
and look the problem statement I think
you know I think we're gonna have
problems if we don't work on this
problem and it's people are gonna look
at 3315 biz and wonder where the
security stuff and we can at least tell
them we're working on it I think one of
those two works I think dropping the
work and just walking away probably
isn't gonna work yeah there's another
aspect that you know that we are about
to send 3315 beast to ASG and well there
it might be you know because it tends to
approve it if there are no sexy
security-oriented solutions yeah so that
my preference would be one of those two
okay Fred Fred Templin Boeing so so what
I need is is really a very simple thing
I need a way for the client to
authenticate itself to the server so I
don't need to have all the encryption
and all the you know the other stuff
that would come at this so how would
that work what I'd have to write my own
little thing or what would it be an
extension of 3315 to do just a client
authentication so it depends there are
couple options
the 3315 this still has the
authentication option and and there's a
registry of algorithms so you could
write this very simple job that you
asked for a new assignment assignment of
a new value in that and then define your
algorithm for for doing that or
alternatively you could use the parts
from from the from the existing draft
but I think going quit using the
authentication option would be simpler
okay okay that makes great sense
thank you okay
Francie's consider po I say if we have
some hustles to do new work we should go
directly to the problem statement
because from the beginnings one of the
program of the security CP this exam was
to have no problem statement so kind of
solution I was very news about this part
and I give you one of the source of the
final situation where we are so if you
have soy sauce put it in a form
statement okay yes I this burning also I
guess one issue with doing the problem
statement stuff is can do we think we
can get to agreement on what we actually
would would want in an end solution not
I'm not saying that it's super when
we've English it's not problem statement
you have French with the s2 program
because it's not obviously is not only
one problem to solve okay yeah penny but
if we cannot agree what's the problem we
try to solve will just fail if we jump
into the solution because so you know
it's it's more no it was more bad you
know the forethought from which you drop
the work which is obviously we can all
agree that that we know what that means
right the problem statement might end up
that we you know we don't know you know
or I look at it more as a requirement
statement you know what do we require
that a problem statement because I think
it should be sort of the combination of
the two to say what are the problems
that we're trying to solve and therefore
what are the requirements you know and
the question is do we think we can get
two and a group understanding of what
those are because different people may
want different things okay so it seems
that we can easily cross out the first
one nobody's really favoring this with
the opportunistic encryption I I don't
here
anyone really interested in that either
so Tim Tim was interested in it I think
sorry yeah and and we certainly know
that one of the security IDs Kathleen is
interested in it yes but she said that
it's better than dropping the whole work
so it's it's better than nothing yeah
okay so in the case we have three
options so or well I guess there's also
question about you know we haven't had
that much discussion and we'll have to
take anything that we do of course of
the mailing list to just sort of confirm
but I guess we you know if there is a
consensus in the room that would be
useful and so I guess we should go
through the four options and ask how
many people are in favor either in terms
of a home or a hand-raising and the
other question that I you know do we
want to ask people just to limit
themselves to one of the four or are you
allowed to vote for more than what well
or do you want to make any statements
yeah yeah right on time
good luckily for once Kathleen we're
already second day so I'd be really good
with you just doing the opportunist
encryption because I think that's kind
of easy ish and I bet I can get some
IPSec people to help I know you didn't
want to do it right at the IPSec at this
at the same layer but using similar
principles that we get some people to
help yeah and it would solve the airport
use case like I don't use wireless at an
airport we also have I Triple E doing
things like standardizing the function
to randomly assign MAC addresses right
they're going to that kind of trouble
and we can't even do this very basic
level of encryption at the very next
step right so if you think about like
the fruit they're picking off we're not
picking off the fruit that we can be we
have already
Parviz eons the HCP so we have already
something which had a useful since
article from DCP and just use fake
one-time identification it hasn't right
I'm not sure if you are having language
FC 78 44 the idea is that the client
okay yeah so anyway their idea is that
the client doesn't send any kind of
identification that is useful or stable
it's just changed changes it so yes you
can you can scoop it with provide
monitoring but it's useful it's sorry -
useless - case so only things we can
give it is a MAC address sound and cell
to scope of the ACP to hide the zoo MAC
address but also specific solution
facets but it's only things yeah you
have to really so Kathleen we already
set KD again to comments on that
so encryption would help to make it be
an active attack to be able to look at
whether or not that function is in use
and my other question is how often is
that ability understood and used by
deployers of airports networks and
coffee shop networks well it would be
the clients that would be the ones that
have an anonymity profile and so it's up
to the client implementers to implement
that and you know just like the MAC
address random is any server would work
with that yes I mean no there's nothing
that the server would have to do
obviously there is you know if the
client changes its its addresses very
frequently its MAC addresses very
frequently and also therefore changes
its its client identifier that it
presents to the DHCP server
it would have to change his hat
because if the lease is still active so
the idea would be that you go into one
airport you might get MAC address a and
client identifier a and then you go to a
different Airport and you know you would
connect differently you would have a
different MAC address and a different
client identifier okay so I guess I
would like I still would like to see
opportunistic encryption as a
possibility as just the lowest possible
thing you can do to ensure that it's
just active attacks I would either get
at this level um you've done seven years
of work on this and to throw away the
idea completely just yeah I mean we've
in Racine and I have been reading drafts
and I don't think any have come through
yet where eckers read them but you know
for the last few years and it's been a
comment on every single one that we'd
like to see some encryption yeah one of
the problems with such lonely drafts is
that the original authors basically left
there's a new team working on it and the
goals has changed in the process so any
new authors yeah I think we have some
people that are or we have some but
suits so how many active actor Altos we
have like maybe two I think there's
probably like three people that I think
are interested in Shawn Chen and to the
karlon okay yeah okay do you want more
help I think I think we want more help
but we don't we what we really want help
on is you know not not the encryption
protocols or the cryptographic
algorithms because we you know we're
just gonna take things off the shelf but
technical guidance on exactly how the
bits should go over the wire and how the
stuff is constructed right because
that's where we're not none of the
people well I can't speak for everybody
but certainly I'm not a security person
and so you know we kind of know things
at the 10,000 foot level and stuff but
we need people that that can actually
tell us yeah that's the right way to do
stuff
and provide that kind of you know
protocol guidance okay
all right um there's a lot of expertise
in the IP second the IPSec working group
is small but there's a lot of expertise
there so I sure I could Corral
one or two people to help okay and how
will they react if we go there and say
okay guys we need your help but we don't
want to use IPSec what would you be
using then if you're not going to be
defining something so the problem here
is that that the first hope between the
client and the relay its multicast in
one direction and the client only has a
link-local address and so it needs help
anything's off the link so can you use
in this case I don't know so I think
what we want to we don't want to replace
the relay you know we don't want to
replace the relay agents and so we need
a protocol that really works at the DCP
layer because the relay will forward
DHCP packets for us and there's a
mechanism to do that and so we really
need something that works at the DHCP
layer because we can't do it at the IP
layer unless we do hop-by-hop and the
problem with hop-by-hop is that you know
that that I mean that could be an option
but now we have to put that logic in the
relays which is something that we don't
really want to do right so the IPSec
will work fine it's the key exchange
it's the the key exchanges the whole
problem here an IEP to the multicast
thing is gonna be you know they tried to
do this in routing protocols and did not
have a lot of success with Karp III
think we should go talk to them and I
think it's a conversation we can have
saying this is our use case for a first
hop you're gonna have to talk about the
IPSec will work fine you can put any
rule you want in there like you could
manually configure this right obviously
we don't want to manually configure it
that's the problem but I would work for
the relays because you then relays
aren't gonna be able to pick up the
packet they'd have to exchange I'd have
to think about this Tim when Tim's
better at this and I mean this is why
Tim's suggesting you know he's worked
with the IPSec working group for some
time he obviously does all the v6 IP sex
testing that we do at the lab he'd be
that kind of stuff if you want to talk
details he's the guy you want to talk to
Mike and he can walk you through all of
that but it's beyond me he's not here
this week unfortunately we already
answers came up the discussion find
Sansa I heard some help about the pur
Couture part to see if there is
something usable we have a lot of hard
things to adapt disappea to do
securities you can go to one exchange
with me together twist a nightmare of
course you have no address so you can
choose any stone de her security
protocol so we already go on this so
it's why I suggested which one or two
weeks ago to go back to province admin
so to to see what we want first before
just going on down see is a lot of hats
program different aspirin with no easy
solution so so I believe we should not
jump to any conclusion first or define
exactly what we want but fancy if you
want me to notification that's that
pretty hard to do no then even if you
have notification just a key exchanger
it's hard to do with only one package
inside yes usually you can have true
career response yes we only went to it
no response
one it shows one exchange
okay and I just want to make sure
everyone understood since the
opportunistic security just means no
authentication right okay so descrition
and so and there's one thing I want to
say here so drop the work is okay with
me
given that okay so if you decide to go
that way like 33 15 biz has to probably
do something more so you cannot use a
cuts does doesn't exist right like so
and so I'm fine with working on the
problem statement like do opportunistic
encryption is okay first one not okay
like it does not really make sense
because if it's not usable why would we
bother right so I'm fine with all the
other three things and if 3315 business
comes out quickly or I can actually do
this now and like take it lean like a
cur and get a signal review done for
that right like so make sure they look
at it and say okay like what about this
and that could give us information about
what goes into the problem statement
after right because if they say like oh
you need to encrypt this because this is
like personally identifiable MAC address
in there and then we say okay cool like
that could be something we look at but I
don't think we've done the security side
of this and I think we should so like I
asked explicitly call first sector
review for this like couple of meetings
ago right because this was obviously a
security thing but I'm I'm talking about
doing the security review for 3315 this
which is like a huge document but I
think it'll take some effort but if like
you know caffeine can come back with
like you know review of it saying like
hey guys like you need encryption here
or is it on then we have a different
path to go forward because we are the
authentication option and then we say ok
we have authentication on this and we're
all set right so I think that would be
my preferred way forward kattiline so um
just to tap onto that when you send that
request over it sounds like you're not
just looking for a security review but
for a threat analysis
okay no but but there is a security
consideration section but just to make
sure if that's okay yes so for the
threat analysis aspect I think what the
depending on who's doing the work
I might have to pair up people because
there are things that you guys know that
may not be may not be known so so like
threat analysis is a whole yeah whereas
the security review you're getting the
knowledge of the reviewer and if they're
not deep in this space you're gonna get
a very different review than somebody
who's deep in this space and then even
to people who are deep in this space you
can get very different reviews okay so
so if I if I paraphrase you like maybe
I'm misreading but like you want us to
do a little bit more homework before we
come to you because is that a fair
statement okay okay so there's no soul
at FC 78 I think 19 that's privacy
analysis it covers some of the attacks
it's it's not it's not the full scope
but at the time we were focusing on
attacks that can impact privacy so we
hashed out on the list but so let's try
to put some more effort into like the
security consideration see what the
threats are and then throw it out to the
seg there to see if like that sounds
reasonable
okay okay funny you don't look on this
no I'm just trying to figure out are we
gonna so are we gonna ask about these
four or are we just gonna proceed with
saying let's see what what 3315 analysis
shows the lecar okay so a different
rather than dropping the work we would
be suspending the work on this pending
the outcome of what the iesg finally
decides about whether what we have in 33
or 50
this is acceptable or not like the
signal earlier can happen before the ESG
right so like just waiting for an
initial signal review and then we decide
okay but I mean yeah I mean it's just
the process of going through this review
the security reviews and stuff like that
okay which we should be able to do
fairly soon
so it's it may not really delay things
that much and it's if somebody really is
an interest on one of these you know
isn't drop the work they can start the
work yeah so okay okay so seems like we
have a plan so I think so I think we're
sort of deferring the the action until
we understand but still when we have
someone to go in to review the security
considerations in B's third one which is
that we're really trying to figure out
is there really a problem that we need
to solve right and if what we have today
is acceptable then we don't there's no
problem we need to solve security on
privacy considerations
well we have we actually have both in
this case okay all right so I think
unless you know that's what I mean does
anybody have any feelings about that
that's a bad direction does they may
want to so so I just to summarize I
think we're going to do now is wait to
see what happens with the security
privacy analysis of 3315 bills to see if
there is a problem that we still need to
solve and based on that result we'll
have to figure out what we do with the
work anybody and then you know we'll
we'll confirm that on the list C but
otherwise okay good good okay thanks
okay thank you all right so next we have
a remote and union have to hit the red
button or do I still have to hit the red
button can you hear us can ya hear you
excellent thank you so you can begin you
know I'll probably have to run the
slides for you so let me know when to
advance
okay sure good afternoon everyone my
name is Srinivas Mallory I have a
prediction in Bangalore so I could make
that possibility because of some
logistic issues
I hope this demo presentation will go
but without much buffering and other
problems can we start with the next
slide already okay so the this
presentation is about one of the graph
that I submitted individually and the
context here is Internet of Things we
are using your protocol over five the
life I appreciate the mission in IOT and
mission to Mission communication
scenarios now this is used to manage the
devices and to collect the data from the
devices for such cases and as you all
know did CP v6 is still popular in
mayate networks to get the fixes and IPS
of course so we realize that that is
need to support some options to enable
every services I would hear any devices
these options have acquired in dhcpv6 of
course we thought of proposing same for
p4 also to negative life that's it so
that can be more easily
okay now before we proceed with the
proposed draft just to set the context I
want to use this slide to talk about nwm
so a library Shinto mission protocol is
a specification defined in Open Mobile
Alliance a device management vendor data
collection it's a client-server protocol
just like any other claims I'm gonna
call it works
and this runs on constrained application
protocol which is IETF RFC seven two
five two so this constraint application
protocol provides service for end of
this just like HTTP except that it runs
from UDP to make it lightweight so now
if you see this diagram lightweight
mission to Mission client managers some
data objects obviously those data
objects are nothing like the data that
we want to exchange in Iwate scenarios
by example maybe the location of the
device temperature humidity this den of
objects are defined in is what objects
and you can see two different servers
here one is boots webserver and the
other one is actual like recognition
Commission medical management server so
the boots web server is the one which is
used to push up the client device and
during the most traffic provides the
information that is required to get
connected with the actual management
server so doing boots fabric provides
information like management server maybe
the URI required to connect and also
some security credentials or certificate
such things also but the whole problem
which we are talking here is the
bootstrap server information itself is
hard-coded on is manually configured
today on aw my devices so that's an
article practice because the server
might change in between if we want to be
bootstrap it's possible that the server
is no
my level so there should be a minute to
get it dynamically so can we push it the
next leg okay
in summary and what we are proposing is
as I said the bootstrapping server
information is are coded or manually
configured today at the client devices
so we see need for the few options
require four of them in the two of them
they are appended February 406 here one
is the UI itself which is required to
get connected with the source web server
we can use dhcpv6 option this one then
the second one is the certificate that
is required to connect with the first
our server the same these two options
I thought execute the proposed for me
for also the v4 is not so popular in
Iwate networks today just to make sure
that the options are available for me
for I thought it's better to focus okay
can we can we go to the next line okay
now we are already starting with the
options that we are proposing the first
one is the bootstrap server URI
I mean it's the option structure and now
of course any can talk about it it's
it's right for what this URI is I mean
the standard format it's a string that
we use it's not an ultimate extreme so
how to input this URI it's already
mentioned in our options related or axis
which is provided in that I dropped as a
reference so can we move on to the next
one so the next one is a LW MDM server
certificate that's required to get
connectivity so here there are few
issues have two concerns arise
which I am trying to address one is
about validating the certificate itself
how do we validate and there are two
comments received our reference provided
about I've seen seven two nine six
section radar six and what type of
certificates can be encoded that Senator
comment I received only created so so
this certificate is used to get
connected with an Olympian bootstrap
server and when the important point here
is in the MM term case it's possible
that the bootstrap server and management
server might be same in such cases the
same options which we are talking here
can be used for management server also
which is not explicitly mentioned in the
draft so you know facility paw ah oops
I think your words yeah yeah so
force is upon so uh I sent an email on
Solis because I believe lasted not about
so I agreed to agree to sell torpedoed
which is section free that six is the
specified and I propose some
improvements so it can just read the
list on discuss with me if you mean you
have multi tests or you need something
else yeah is not this comment just few
minutes about maybe three minutes ago I
was trying to understand and I will get
in touch with you through the email to
understand it better and so some very
it's again it's a good idea
the same thing but it's in the specified
are you have an opportunity to do
something which I believe would be
better in the in your context okay I
will referring some more about the
encoding formats liking the comment I
will refer this RFC and update this and
the next one is of course again the
bootstrap URI 24option structure again I
am not happy about it
it's stranded one so maybe we can
already move the next about it and here
we are again the certificate that we
want to use puppy for clients there are
some concerns expressed about this also
about the size of the certificate itself
might be very big and we can't
accommodate it in the private option as
this was already a comment I received
from me and they also suggested to use
some other reference where one of the
autopsy talks about how to import bigger
options in TV for options so I mentioned
that already in the draft and this is
also common I received today from France
if I'm not wrong so that's it I think
that there's nothing much to talk about
options they are trying forward except
the use case which I feel it's important
here so the next steps which I want to
discuss are there few comments which I
already addressed which I've issued
earlier through means there are new
comments which I received today and on
them of course and the one more
important thing is I'm sure there might
be two other people working on this i
OTE just kissed since in I use I would
like to know if there are more those
cases where someone drops
be quiet so that we can pour that when
when draft on document so that it covers
all I would be related scenarios at
least known I would be billeted
scenarios if not all so that's something
I want to understand from anybody in the
room and of course the next step is
there if this makes sense I would like
to hear from you to know if it can be
adapted SBHC okay this is Bernie volts a
few questions you're on you mentioned
that most most IOT stuff is using v6 and
I know you could define v4 options but
if nobody's gonna use them it may be
better not to do them because the v4
option space is a little tighter I mean
you know maybe v4 is dead and we don't
have to worry about it but you know just
a question I mean it may be better if
you don't need them to just remove them
because you know it just preserves that
resource I understand that point but I
wanted to reverse this because when we
see the devices that are coming in to
properly market we see one statement in
[Music]
support a journalist they say as of now
I am a poor ipv6 will be supported later
this is the kind of statements we keep
listening
so maybe whether such devices which are
still not completely ready maybe we can
still use me for that the reason why I
wanted to keep it of course as you said
India Cherokee nobody is view is going
to use v4 at all in any scenario then
yes I think we can skip it and also when
my point is maybe in industrial
automation kind of cases where a polite
way to the mission protocol is running
I'm not sure whether they'll completely
go for me for or they're still use they
own internet with sorry they will go for
me fix whatnot they might use their own
internet v4 it's okay you know if you
don't need it don't ask for it but if
you think you do that's fine I
I think they also follow the rc7 2 to 7
guidelines so you know there's not
really much we comment on the question
about doing an adoption call really goes
to Suresh and the question about is
there a you know there
there probably is no other working group
that would cover this technology and
therefore it really does fall back to us
and as long as you know Suresh is in
favor of us doing the adoption call I
think that we can easily proceed with
that yeah so there's no other working
group that can take this so this is done
in an external SEO right seeing us
discuss this with other people
especially in the core and such groups
who are doing things towards IOT but I
don't find any suitable working group
that's because the awm itself is not so
so I don't mind like but as long as like
make sure there's like you know somebody
to review this here and I'll try to find
review outside but I my only concern
would be like whether this will get
enough review here so like we can look
at the option formats but the content
itself I'm not sure how we can get
review here so like maybe we had to
figure out how to do that but I don't
mind if you are out this and like we'll
figure out how to do that if there is
interest to do it here I can find some
people who are working in thing to
Amenti to be working group that's
another thing probably which is the
closest thing I can think of if there
are few people in research group yeah we
can find them there but like want them
to come here and like do the reviews
right so that's something we'll figure
it out okay it's not going to pass
working group laughs all right thank you
thank you so any other comments all
right well thank you okay I thought for
instance is getting him okay well thank
you yeah thank you
okay and now we have it Willis to
present on the on demand extensions okay
now it's a different one okay okay thank
you for letting me present stuff here
I'm not part of the FCC speak up a
little bit I'm sorry so this is work
that is being done in DMM group and I'll
give you a very short and high-level
description of what we're doing and why
we need help from DHCP or why are we
proposing to have to define some new
option or options and actually what we
need from the DC group is more a review
of making sure that we are not violating
any DHCP formats or message passing or
things like that okay
regarding the DMM stuff we are reviewing
that in DMM okay so a very quick
description of what's happening in DMM
and we are talking about mobile networks
so in mobile minute networks one of the
problems that we have is to maintain IP
session continuity while a node travels
around the network so when and moves
from one point of connection to another
it might move to a different land and as
a result we'll need a different IP
prefix and as a result its original
source IP address will go away and that
might be problematic for existing
applications that are
the middle of exchanging traffic so the
way mobile networks resolve this problem
a long time ago
is via tunneling so if I'll give an
example from proxy mobile ipv6 to the
network through Max and the LM a is some
mobility anchor which exposes traffic to
the rest of the network and we create a
tunnel between the LM a and the Mac to
make sure that traffic which is destined
to the mobile network over there will
get there even though its source IP
address is really this prefix so that
the traffic can go to the corresponding
node over here and when the mobile node
moves from one place to another
it's the responsibility of the network
to update the tunnel to the new Mac
and as a result IP continued continuity
is preserved so this is what exists
today and it works fine and everybody is
happy but this could be optimized and
the problem is that we have many mobile
nodes and many corresponding nodes and
you can start seeing all the traffic has
to go through that LM a and if we
continue and even have much more we are
getting into a problem failure it's a
bottleneck there are all kinds of issues
around that
and in DMM we are trying to resolve this
problem and we are trying to resolve
this problem in different ways all are
good sorry so one way of course is to
distribute the enemy and have several
enemies and by that direct part of the
mobile nodes
many others to another enemy and so on
and so forth so we are resolving the
single point of failure and the
bottlenecks and stuff like that so this
is one solution that we are trying to
define and there is another solution or
another way of looking at things so if
you think about it before I try to
explain why I see continuity is
important but really some applications
don't really need IP continuity they
could manage managed very well a
modification of their source IP address
they will reopen a socket with a new IP
address the user experience won't be
really affected and everything works
well so if we manage to present to the
network when we need IP address
continuity and when you don't need IP
address continuity we offload some of
the activity from those mobility anchors
that I showed before and for that one of
the things that we need is a support in
DHCP okay I don't get into too much
details about that but this slide shows
different types of IP addresses or
actually services that an application
can request from the network
maybe I'll just describe to one is
session lasting IP address such an IP
address is guaranteed by the network to
be valid as long as the session is still
running
this is excellent service from the
network and of course it requires the
tunneling and it's costly and the other
one I want to describe here is non
persistent non persistent means no
guarantee you are getting an IP address
it might go away you will have to deal
with that and I showed that there are
patience that can deal with that of
course for session last thing we need a
mobility anchor or an LMA and for
non-persistent we don't need okay
so actually in the draft that I
referenced in the mailing list we
introduced two new options we tried to
limit the changes that we are requesting
from DHCP we are not experts in DHCP and
we didn't want we don't think we need
too much activity in DHCP and ok so one
one option is to be able to when we
request a prefix through prefix delegate
delegation we want to be able to
communicate to the network what kind of
service we want and in the reply we want
to see from the network if we receive
that service or not and there is also
another need which I'll talk in a minute
so the IP continuity service option is
the new option that we were requesting
this is the option in which mobile host
indicates to the network what type of
service it requires and for the network
to provide the information about what
has been provisioned the other option
has a star on it because I'm not
absolutely sure we need it and I would
like to consult with you I will describe
it later on as I said before there is no
impact on DHCP message flow we're not
changing anything we are not changing
any format we are just adding new
options so an example for the IP
continuity service option it should be
encapsulated
in the prefix option options area of the
prefix delegation option this is where
it has to be I am trying to show here a
schematic of where it is and it's
similar to the status code a status code
option which also appears in that
options area so this is where we see
this new option coming in it's a very
simple option the length is 1 it has an
option code and the service type is
coded and we actually need 2 bits or I'm
sorry 3 bits to code of different
service types so this is this option
some usage rules and we are all and I'll
talk also about backwards compatibility
so usage rules the client is always the
first to request this option the server
will reply using this option only when
it initially received the request for
this option and once the server replied
with this option any subsequent messages
which are related to this prefix should
use this option and should not change
the value so it's not like I requested
session nesting IP prefix I got one and
then at some point I'm trying to renew
the lease but with a different type this
is not allowed backwards compatibility
we assume that there will be servers
that won't support this these new
options so we're trying to define rules
for backwards compatibility yes
about this our are check-ins free--free
1/5 B so femoris bestow command and say
we know the option should be in York
you know you know yes good so so it's
sue should walk with a program with a
compliant server okay so so this is what
is you and what we are saying here is
okay let's assume the client requests a
prefix with this option and since the
server will ignore it it won't get a
reply it will get a reply it will get a
reply as if it was just a nominal I a
prefix option without oh so I didn't
understand Oh
so that's that so but no it's not a bad
because the reply will not include the
community service options I see no I see
okay so I'll fix I'll fix the text in
the draft to say what happens in that
case and so so the right message flow is
the client will request prefix with this
option will receive a reply without this
option and will deduct that the server
doesn't support that okay okay thank you
okay so I'll fix that and of course our
server cannot reply with the prefix with
that option if the client didn't
initially request that object okay again
for backwards-compatible yes I do not
read suit off but I believe you I did at
least one you a ho when he has some
prefix but not for this kind of right so
we so actually we defined an error for
that we had a typo in the error I got a
I got an an email from the list about
that and I'll fix that
that the error said address not
available something like that and and
the comment was you should write prefix
not available
so I'll fix that so I see you have a
comment here about the client recording
the information that the server doesn't
support the option it's tricky not
necessary the client could continue
sending this option in following
messages if it still makes sense from
the right perspective because there's
capability could be an ended lighter at
the time and the client than would pick
it because otherwise when you visit a
new network and it detects that okay is
this ability is not enabled and then
it's it gets an a bit lighter the client
would never be able to detect this so so
I'm trying to think I think that in the
text in the draft I have to visit that I
wrote that subsequent subsequent
messages should not have that option but
every once in a while it can introduce
the option again it's probably easier
just to say said always exactly
especially as you're saying the option
will be ignored I wasn't I wasn't aware
that the server will ignore it but will
reply but since it does maybe this makes
more sense so I will fix that okay oh I
didn't talk about the I want to talk
back about the anchor preference option
okay what is an anchor preference option
and why I'm not sure we need it if we go
back to this slide we can see that we
have several anchors in this slide we
have three anchors and there is an issue
of how does the network allocate a
specific anchor to a note the anchors
here are the enemies yes
now we didn't get into too much work
regarding how to allocate anchors not
yet at least
in DMM but I was requested but by one of
the delegates to enable a future
algorithm where the node knows what's
best for him and will ask for a specific
anchor now the node is not aware of
anchors but the node has history about
prefixes it received in the past and if
it comes and says give me this prefix
it actually means I want this route this
LMA or this
because the different anchors provide
different prefixes so we thought to add
this option where a node requests or
hints hey it'll be nice if I get this
this prefix meaning this is the LMA I
want or the anchor I want it doesn't
necessarily have to receive this
specific prefix but it wants to receive
a prefix from that LMA okay now when I
read and by the way the network and it's
written there the network doesn't have
to provide that prefix it's just a hit
now when I read the prefix delegation
draft or IRC again I saw that this
already exists so I said hey maybe we
don't need it but the interpretation is
a little different and I wanted to make
sure that it's okay or whether I need
another option the interpretation that I
understood from the RFC is when a note
requests a certain prefix it wants that
certain prefix and what we're saying
here is when we hint on that prefix we
will be satisfied with any prefix
associated with the same enemy I I think
that you know that the nodes really
don't care it's the server's policy that
comes into play there and so it's much
more server thing that you have because
what you know the prefix that comes back
as the prefix it's going to use and if
it isn't if it's on a different LMA or
some of the same LMA it may not know
well I know it won't know right and so
it's really that really comes down to a
server policy issue so that's something
that is really something that the the
implementers are the service that write
to support the LMA stuff would be more
concerned about right is the client
would probably not you know doesn't know
so right because I think you don't need
a new option to just you just request
the client you just have the client
request that prefix and then if the
server gives it that prefix or gives it
some other prefix it's really up to the
server to determine what
meaning that has right so this was my
thinking I wasn't sure this is why I
didn't remove that before coming here so
what I'm understanding from from this
conversation is I can remove that option
and I'll be left with only one option
very simple option and that's a good
thing well and you may need I think what
you will need to do in your document is
to put a note that you know it is a
matter of server policy in this
particular environment how that
requested prefix okay is used yeah
because the normal policy for server
would be hey there's a diary can I give
that prefix to that client yes or no
okay and and if I can it usually does
but you wanted if it can't give it then
you want it to assign a you know not
just pick an arbitrary prefix but pick
one on that LMA and if not yeah yeah
okay but it's more of a server policy
thing that you will probably need your
documents yes I heard come on you read
the famous beefs document which is that
is not really enough I'll just say it in
the least so you're talking about 33 15
bits yes
no so I must admit I didn't read that I
read 33 15 and 36 33 yes you should be
sweet cheese okay so I'll do that and I
think I got quite a few comments on the
list in here which is very helpful so I
will pretend I'll read 33:15 this and
then I will issue a new version of the
draft and I'm getting to next steps so
so I will probably be happy to receive
another review on that new draft just to
make sure that I captured the comments
correctly and that I didn't break
anything and if I get a V from DHC I can
go back to the mm and say DHC approved
that we can continue our work yes and I
think if you know because options will
eventually require both Sanders action
and expert review you know some of the
people that are viewing it are active
that you see working growth will get a
review at that point but I think it's
still better that whenever you make a
change or like when you go for a working
group last call come in the DM n let us
know about it because that's another
viewpoint so if you make any substantive
changes you know I mean if you're just
republishing to keep it alive or
something or make a Natori elaine's no
big deal but if there's a substantial
change makes notify us about the change
and also if you go to working group last
call include us in the working group
last call cycle just so that we're aware
of it that's a good plan okay thank you
very much yes so I'll do it on Monday D
for both so I'll do it well it's nice if
they can do it right it's one less thing
you have to worry about no but I had to
watch out I'd like people that I slip
things by me all the time sir okay well
anybody have anything else they'd like
to discuss before we close the working
group meeting all right well thank you
and and if you haven't signed yet the
blue sheets please do they're important
and thank you for attending
you