good afternoon everyone
wait hot afternoon everyone this is dots
hopefully that's what you're here for my
name is Roman Danilo and I'm here with
my co-chair Tobias gunroom and we'd like
to get started
so getting handed out right now is the
blue sheets you've likely seen this a
number of times since this is Thursday
of the week but the noel has been
updated thanks we already have jabber
scribe and a note-taker and again the
blue sheets are going around we have a
fairly fairly full agenda but we have a
buffer a buffer in all the areas to have
the conversations to include the drafts
and the hackathon experience we have an
agenda split between the use cases
requirements and architecture and then a
collection of various protocol drafts
before moving forward would anyone like
to bash this agenda okay okay I take
that as a no moving forward
no no what there's one more slide so
just to give everyone a status since we
last got together in Chicago on your
left there you should see that all the
various drafts we have have been updated
due to the hard work of your author and
editor team you're gonna be hearing from
most of them today we had a virtual
interim meeting that check tweeted us
halfway halfway between Chicago and now
in June which laid out which laid out
where we need you to head and then there
were two individual design team meetings
on Tuesday and Wednesday to talk about
specific draft areas specifically the
informational documents was on Tuesday
and then on Wednesday there was
discussion about protocols and I believe
that the various presentations will will
cover some of those specifics related to
that I just wanted to highlight where we
stand in terms of kind of scheduling we
had been saying in Chicago and coming
out of the interim
that the vast majority of our
informational documents would be
completed in the summer time we had
aggressively said use case requirements
in July and then in September with the
architecture document the idea of course
being to stagger them and then we have
very ambitious Lee had said to talk
about the protocol documents by the end
of this calendar year I'd like to talk a
little bit about that after we go
through the individual presentations to
see how closely we're still tracking
against that schedule okay so with that
that summarizes where we stand and I'd
like to hand it over to the first
presentation which is getting us right
into the use cases so Roland you're up
okay hi everyone I'm Roland Evans with
urban networks and so we just got 0 7
out about 5 5 hours ago
if you remember at the interim meeting a
little while back we talked about 0 6 0
6 we revamped a lot of the use cases we
actually added nine new use cases and
unfortunately due to emerge our on my
part we lost some of the some of the
revisions that had taken place between 4
& 5 so first of all on 0 7 fixes those
inadvertent revisions and think so hamid
for pointing that out there is a home
net use case that we need to get the
sense of the working group on that that
was actually taken out in 0-6 and was
put back for the sake of discussion and
0-7 we need to hear from the working
group what the consensus is around the
youth clickability
of that particular use case we added
some additional context to the main
sections for the inter and intra domain
use cases to add a little bit of flavor
to just to talk about why there are some
differences and why we believe that they
actually should be separated out into
two different broad categories and we
fixed some of the informative references
so now we're trying to track 0-8 si welc
candidate when we revamp the use cases
we put in a lot of good operational
contacts but not enough dots contacts if
you've been with us for a while you take
a look at like 0 0 in 0 1 we were very
very dodged heavy in terms of talking
about the messaging flow between dots
clients and dot server it was a little
bit too much without enough context and
so we've added some good use cases in
there but we've gotten some good
feedback from some of the the
contributors for the document that we've
gone to light on the actual dots
interaction so we need to add those a
little bit more dots flavor to the
actual use cases show some grammatical
and terminological things that we need
to take care of we'd work on some of the
so the orchestration section is good
stuff but again just some of the
phraseology and things of that nature we
need at least one additional intradomain
use case talking about suppression of
east-west attacks within a transit
provider and of course if folks have
additional ideas for other use cases
that you believe belong either in the in
the inter or intra domain sections
please feel free to share those on the
list and then based on the sense of the
working group with regards to the home
net use case then we'll need to make
some edits based on that in the
presentation one I have a question a
couple of years ago Andrew Mortensen
actually let off a discussion about the
home net use case on the list you know
we've had a couple of people reply but I
don't really think we've received enough
input from the working group on that
particular use case so we'd really be
grateful if people could read that on
the list look at the use case and then
tell us number one do you think is
really applicable and number two if it
is applicable any suggestions that you
have for streamlining it we'd be
grateful to hear those
so thank you very much
technically I believe we have 5 to 5 5 5
to 10 minutes for discussion if you have
questions about use case graph the
co-chairs appreciate that the latest
revision was very very recently so
you're not demanding that you have read
it overnight if you have feel free to
speak out if you have comments please
feel free to say so now specifically
also if you want to reiterate your
feedback about the whole net use case
yeah so the floor is yours for questions
or feedback Flemmi interesting mm-hm
with respect to the home that use case
what is your concern about that use kids
because it's not sufficiently different
from several aspects of several the
other use cases that are already in
there reading the write-up of it there's
nothing that seems to be very unique
about it and it's very rather verbose
for being non unique ok so it's not the
scenario that you feel does not apply
it's just the way it's written right
yeah is that correct no again I think
the scenario is duplicated if you take a
look at the broadband access use case if
you take a look at the very first use
case which is a endpoint network with a
single upstream transit provider there
doesn't appear to be a lot of difference
at least as far as I can tell between
those okay
but again just to clarify this scenario
itself you don't view that as out of
scope you just don't think the way it's
described right now sufficiently
separates it from what else is in there
that is my individual opinion yes I
think hi there are chunk of region come
from curate of ellipse with a few
suggestions first of the three to name
it first of them speaking about the use
case with Mississippi requesting
assistance from other emesis peas I
believe it's important to review the
work that's done by another work group
especially CD and I
because though videos MSSP and the
content delivery network are pretty much
should be designed not in the same way
though some of you that use cases may
play here
the second suggestion is as follows
there's the 3.2.1 paragraph about the
suppression of outbound just traffic
originating from consumer broadband
access network in terms of out banned
outbound sorry traffic it's important to
think about it because from the point of
the side which is which originates an
attack actually the denial of service
attack does not it doesn't differ a lot
from an attack of another kind so like I
don't know sequel injection and things
of that sort
thus this this is I have to disagree
with that thus I believe that due to
this this use case may contradict with
the working group chapter in a place
where it says that the working group
will focus on signaling and coordination
mechanisms directly related to denial of
such attack detection classification
traceback and mitigation because of this
I'm now coining a term but this I'll say
abuse signaling might be I think in
itself which will require maybe another
working group for that those you're
coming yes okay you know I have a third
suggestion but let's it's just a
technical one the big because there's
some inconvenience
cause by there's a github page for use
cases which doesn't get any up doesn't
get any update currently the version
which is on data tracker is seven from
July 20th and the version which is on
github is five from May the 4th which
also rises a question of what it all has
to do with Star Wars with the poor's sir
that's a silly joke
yeah yeah our well noted on getting the
getting github updated to your first
comment if you can give us some pointers
on the list specifically the SDNS D&I
stuff you like us to take a look at that
would be very very helpful with regards
the outbound DDoS issue this is a
completely distinct from other types of
bad traffic emanating from broadband
access network in that it negatively
affects the availability of the
broadband operator in can have an
extremely high impact we've seen outages
with literally millions of users
hundreds of thousands is very common
that are the result of outbound DDoS
attacks that are launched from a lot of
different devices computers and so forth
that are that are part of botnets on
broadband access networks on broadband
operators on spend a lot of time dealing
with this and suppressor pressing
outbound DDoS attacks in a number of
different ways to help preserve the
availability of their network for their
subscribers and pretty much right now I
mean there's there are there's kind of a
constellation of tools that are used by
different broadband access providers and
it's a little bit kind of bespoke you
know for each one they have different
mechanisms and so the idea here was to
illustrate the fact that number one dots
could in fact be used to signal for the
mitigation action of suppressing the
outbound udaas attacks that there be a
standards-based mechanism to do this so
all of the different broadband access
operators don't have to roll their own
you know custom way of doing this and
secondly it also offers up the ability
actually quarantine potentially nodes
which are launching lots of outbound
DDoS attacks some broadband access
operators have implemented quarantine
mechanisms but again it's all very very
customized and it's only really the lot
of the larger ones that have a lot of
development resources to sink in to that
that kind of system and so this it's
very distinct from confidentiality and
integrity issues like sequel injection
that sort of thing it's very specific to
DDoS attacks and not only does it have
to do with DDoS attacks that are
initiated by compromised machines in the
the user base the broadband access
network but also by attacks that are
leveraging misconfigured services on
devices to do things like different
types of reflection amplification
attacks and and so you know someone
sometimes the aggregate volume can be
quite high and disruptive to the entire
user base of the broadband access
provider but the trend okay I see a
point it I need to mention that the
content that we observe is the
maintainer or owners or users of wood
nets they attempt more to hide their
activity from the network which networks
which originate the traffic because it
ultimately causes the elimination of
some parts of botnets their aim of
designer of a botnet is actually to hide
its activity from their from the okay
let's say personal computer on which
it's either sites because other way the
user will get aware he could and now buy
an anti-virus and solve the problem so
we've even saw trains and this kind of
stuff actually heating computers from
other
joints and viruses so it's really
changing now I think we may continue the
discussion in the mailing list if it's
yeah so again I'm just speaking as an
individual here opera involved the
operational community that doesn't match
what we see at all we see the fact that
the bad guys who are using botnets to
launch DDoS attacks have so many
different nodes that they don't care um
if many of them end up being remediated
because they have so many extra spare
ones it is easy to compromise new ones
also in terms of hiding
DDoS traffic that's not really easy to
do um very specifically there is a
scenario with the reflection
amplification attacks where typically
the initiator of the attack is most the
time we see them actually being servers
that are in Internet data centers either
being their servers that belong
legitimate organizations they've been
cracked open and they're being abused or
their so-called bulletproof hosters that
cater to criminal elements and those
machines are capable of emitted in
meaning spoof traffic right the spoof
traffic then comes into the broadband
access provider network and it hits
these devices that are misconfigured
with things like Open DNS relays for
example or SSDP and that they stimulate
those nodes to then send you know the
relatively high volume traffic out so in
that regard the initiators of the
traffic are certainly I guess you could
say that they're heading in a way
because it's difficult to trace them
back in many cases but the outbound DDoS
traffic that is stimulated that is
sourced from the broadband access
network is not hidden in any way so in
the interest of keeping us on schedule I
would ask for this conversation to go
back on the mailing list and please on a
thank you thank you for pointing that
out the chairs will make sure that the
drafts are synchronized on your table
thanks for that pointer Kathleen
Moriarty Andy um just a question what
are the plans for the use case document
maybe a loaded question but a question -
who is this question - working group in
chairs okay the poll ends coming up at
the working group when we last discussed
this is that we would publish the
working group document the architecture
document and requirements document as
separate informational and the use cases
your honor sorry did I not say you lose
cases yeah I meant use cases
requirements and architecture which are
three informational is to publish them
as individual I'm sorry publish them as
distinct drafts as informational okay so
the isg discourages these documents as
as publications because many don't feel
that there's archival value in these
documents I do see the archival value
personally you don't have to sell me
what but if you do want them published
as individual as informational drafts
each separate there will be a little bit
of a as long as they're informational
you just need my okay on it as and it's
in your Charter in your milestones so
that's all fine the is G is tending to
encourage just to let a draft drefs
never disappear now even once they
expire so - like link them off of a wiki
or something like that and not go
through the full publication process I
leave that up to the working groups I
work with and if there's a strong desire
to publish I will work with you to do
that but I wanted to let you know of
this preference before you get to iesg
review and learn about it okay
yes looking good here Brian I heard of
this new preference kind of new kind of
new yeah in right oh yes in light of
that it was there and these milestones
were agreed and with the intention to
publish so at this point I would say I
understand that there's a preference not
to do it anymore but also I would say
there is an agreement that it there was
a previous agreement to do it so that's
the procedural answer the practical
answer is I strongly believe that the
use case is document and at the very
minimum also the architectural document
are very very valuable for future
readers to understand this and I believe
even the requirements document will be
helpful a number of these dots cases are
non-trivial and the use cases really
helps to inform what you do with that
so I do believe they are quite valuable
as informational documents that's my
personal opinion
everything can be combined or not I
think that is something for the working
group to explore now that we have heard
of this minimization I actually don't
think it's really reasonable because you
know combining it would still be the
same volume of reading for the iesg
it will not change the amount okay yes
but and the number of times you see you
know X number of stains on your
documents yeah so what I just wanted to
raise all this so that we thank you
current viewpoints and I am an ad that
does support these documents so so
that's fine I will support what you want
I just need to make sure that that's
what the working group wants are there
any other opinions in the working group
because I just made a statement on my
own okay so on in terms of you know
publication versus non publication you
know I personally individually don't
care one way or the other we've already
received positive feedback from the
folks working on architectural
requirements that the use cases
revisions have been useful to them the
only other thing I would say is that you
know DDoS is kind of an arcane you know
subject compared to the rest of security
is its new to a lot of folks and as we
move towards you know getting things in
you know into the standards track
we want to encourage folks to number one
implement dots and number two make use
of it that some form of guidance and
context you know from the use cases we
think may be useful for the implementers
and the some some of the actual
potential users as well whether or not
that means that they should be published
separately whether it means I should be
folded into another document I don't I
don't have an answer to that but it's
important I think that the use cases are
preserved in a published document that
can be cited you know to a vendor for
example okay so Kathleen Moriarty again
to your point about the summary and how
things tie together what has been
received very positively is overview
documents and they would come at the end
of a working group lifecycle and it
might pull together a lot of the
information that's in those other types
of documents but it would also show the
connection between the various drafts in
the working group and any other drafts
or rfcs from other working groups so
rtcp RTC web is an example of of a draft
that was viewed very positively and it
was an overview so they're they're kind
of similar they just come in a different
point and they cover a bit more in terms
of you know the connection between
standards and what's been kind of
overarching more overarching right yeah
yeah just to one of your points okay so
the working group understands that thank
you
slamming andreas yeah I mean I still
support all three documents I think we
had a little bit of discussion around
that actually in the design team meeting
this past week my read of that was that
the general sentiment was that people
were still in favor of these documents
as well so you know if anyone wants to
speak up differently you know by all
means and that's also something I think
that we can revisit late a little bit
later in the process as well right
Kathleen okay one last note to your
question again I think with the working
group last call on this document I
because we still have like activity on
this you
we have at least one more fairly
significant out date left yeah I think
it's too early to call for working group
last call at this moment for the use
cases draft okay thank you
moving to requirements yes Bob Moskowitz
speaking for Annie Mortensen and chill
ready and I would say that Annie did the
lion's share of all the work on here but
fortunately for Andy he is at home where
he belongs with his wife just had a
child so I am thus tasked with really
going through Andy slides that that he
worked on and we'll go through here on
the where we stand with the dots
requirements draft the changes since oh
five we had good work group feedback
following the last IETF at a github
issues for all work feedback so we have
been tracking that on the workgroup and
is again be done a wonderful job of
saying to then keeping keeping that
going address all the new issues in all
six set up for that
ten issues were closed since the interim
we have one remaining issue
well done quite well on this draft and
completing items that people have
brought up what we have for those these
are some of the ones we've closed add
authorization requirements clarify
replay protection requirements and again
you can go and you can see what these
issues were and what we said so if that
is there clearly in the github client
must set mitigation lifetime client may
incorporate server feedback and servers
must support black whitelist management
so those are examples of some of the of
the ten issues there are five of the ten
that we addressed in this this round
the one remaining open issue is the
overlapping request handling where two
or more uncor dots clients may report
the same attack and what to do
particularly if they're overlapping
policy requests a server should handle
this gracefully conflicting filters are
more likely and so the pull requests
forthcoming on this to handle this one
open item so there will be an old 0-7 of
this one issue unless somebody says one
more up to go we but we will handle this
one issue and and and he has pretty much
worked out the texts in Terrell and I
are pretty comfortable with that we'll
review it one last time before we do
indeed post it so and that's the point
we have not received any new issues for
some time we really believe that in
terms of the requirements document we
are at closure this one issue which is
standing which I just mentioned this one
issue we will put into the next version
of the draft so you can work read the
wording on that you can check out the
wording we've done on these issues and
then the Tulsa ten issues and how we
handled it but we really believe that we
are with the 0-7 we will be done and
ready for workgroup last call so that
completes my slide presentation this is
the github our location where you can
see all this and we're welcome you to to
go and check it and at that unless Andy
or Tara want to pipe in from online I'm
open for comments and questions thank
you very much
artem tkachenko once again have a few of
suggestions as well I promise not to
comment on the architecture document
because it's far from last call
so give me some time
regarding the definitions there is a
definition for a client signal let's
limit the the that is limiting the scope
of a requested mitigation just as well
the requirement si g500 5 tells us that
the dots clients are responsible for
specifying the types and scope of the
mitigation there are some key points
here first of all the dots client is
supposed to be some kind of middle box
or software demon sitting in the victims
infrastructure the whole document thinks
and speaks of the dots client as a
decision-maker but in case of attack
that's actually consuming bandwidth and
limiting the data that's seen at the
victim side it appears like doats client
may not be a good decision maker because
it doesn't have enough data next the
dots client is once again in some cases
it's believed to be some kind of
security appliance well yesterday the
TLS group figured out that most
endpoints like middle boxes like what's
gonna be a dots client I'm not built for
full-scale packet capture which actually
is so while the upstream transit
operator running is a dot server is by
definition capable of doing this I'm not
even speaking about the perceived
quality and I mean quality of aware of
this middle box some of them at least
but the issue is that the debtor
actually could
know about the attack lots more about
that kind of attack of the the scope of
the mitigation and it's not that
feasible to leave all the
decision-making towards the client there
are also issues with congestion in this
case and all lastly they this is
inconsistent with the characteristic
requirement on the page five the bottom
of it
which tells us that the purpose of the
whole document excuse me
is to design an advisory protocol yet we
here see that let me code that in case
when this client requests to stop the
mitigation the server should stop it in
like three hundreds of seconds imagine a
scenario where we have a king of dots
client service yeah the architecture
document even features a concept of dots
proxy which is essentially chaining and
when an agent sitting on the Left
client-side requests to stop the
mitigation but the whole bandwidth of an
attack is quite larger than its upstream
could actually handle so he just cannot
stop the mitigation here in this case
because it will essentially bring the
whole service down I think that here we
should once again examine what the dots
server must treat when the dots or must
treat the mitigation is terminated and
when it should do it but it's possible
not to do that
and yes let's Andrew answer this because
when he wrote that much that text and I
will say that this is an advisory
message before I drove over to Andrew
and though the client says I see this
attack as you said in many sessions many
time the server says you see this attack
the tack is really something else
we recognize that that that many times
with this is what the client sees as
attack may really not be what the attack
is that the server having the broader
view can see something much different
and so even where the client says I'm no
longer being attacked but the server may
say um you're not but everybody around
you still is so so those sorts of things
so I'll turn over to Andrew and let him
go and before injure starts I'm cutting
the line so the three that are in line
that's that's it okay well to the week
that the can everybody hear me first of
all make sure we care you Andrew great
so to the point that the the server must
see the mitigation I believe there the
text in there as well that says the
server may is no longer the server can
continue to do it can continue
mitigation but the clients it is no
longer responsible for that mitigation
so if there are service agreements if
there are other business relationships
between the client and server the
clients responsibility is isn't is done
and if that's not sufficiently apparent
in the the document we will we should
address that the I just said
thanks for that sorry can you hear me
again yeah alright so I don't know if
that is sufficient if making that clear
will be sufficient for you but if if
it's not we can continue this here on on
the mailing list it does sound like you
want to see an issue on the in the
github tracker yes is for now the it
seems some clear I think we'll need to
get back to it in the Middle East yeah
thanks
one suggestion would we want to use
mailing list for that or github wishes
you can bring it up on the mailing list
and maybe it's that how you're reading
so that may clarify what the issue is
so no bring in the main list first
unless it's really clear about something
and then let the mailing list maybe
clarify the issue and then put it up
there you should have all the discussion
on the man list we're using github to
track that we have an issue whose
resolution won't have it and on the mail
list so please absolutely bring the
issue to the man list and then the
author's editors will make sure that
it's dropped in and tracted github for
us yet one other things so you were as
saying that you feel the text is
implying that the dots client must be
some sort of detection device and that
it must the detection will be the
trigger for everything ah that's that's
not necessarily the case and I believe
the architecture document does have a
scenario where there's a manually
initiated mitigation where an operator
uses uses dots as the vehicle manually
regardless of the presence of any attack
and regardless of any detected attack
correct but I see you point that this is
not necessarily the case but this is the
case there is a use case excuse me I'm
cutting this discussion at this point
because they want to leave the other two
people in the queue also and I suggest
that we continue this on the meanest
apologize for that good thing thank you
very very brief clarification on dot
says is not tied to any particular form
of detection classification traced back
or many
into to any particular mitigation model
or technology is deliberately
independent of those things secondly
there are use cases which denote other
types of things besides security
specific devices making dots requests
and thirdly we did have a use case in 0
0 and 0 1 I believe which was an example
of mitigation service writer not being
able to heal on mitigation because of
our capacity issues and so I believe
this comment we should think about
bringing that use case back in to show a
failed mitigation is illustrative of
this type of issue
thank you shortcomings communications ok
yeah I'll do a report of implementation
later so in this presentation the
feedback from our experiences in so yeah
I would do the feedback about feedback
about sir requirement later ok ok so
maybe we're not quite ready for last
call but we'll take this to the list and
we'll bring up the list and see how
close we are like to think we're close
but they'll be up to chairs one question
is co-chair who of you has read the
latest version 1 2 3 4 8 somewhat 8
people ok ok and now you can raise your
hands if you also have read some of the
other versions but I guess that's yeah
ok that's quite a number good I think we
need to move like how can we determine
what kind of score ok so maybe maybe we
wait for the next version and then push
that what's your timeline for that
Andrew freaking quickly getting here he
comes I'm I'm a slow ghost yeah so the
there's the 1 outstanding issue as bob
highlighted in the presentation I do
have some text on that I won't be
sharing that with the other co-editors
and then I expect that
go immediately to seven so I I would
anticipate actually early next week
assuming that aligns with the other
co-editor schedules but it should happen
very quickly why don't we do working
through a blast call when there are no
more open issues in the github okay then
thank you and thank you thank you for
your time yeah Nexus architecture
I believe Nick hi I'm Nick Teague Andrew
put some slides together again so I'm
using props so for the architecture
draft we had two revisions since the
last IETF we've incorporated all the
working group feedback issue tracking
eyes on github there are currently no
issues issues feel free we're awaiting
additional multihoming discussion that
was spawned from the discussions we had
last time that med and Tara have put a
draft together form from which I think
med is presenting shortly the changes
since the oh three was to emphasize
reduced client control in recursive
signaling caveats so that was the client
control over network path of mitigate
traffic may be reduced defined dot
sessions we had previously kind of like
being having lots of discussions around
the word sessions so we tried to clarify
that a bit better and went from signal
sessions to dot sessions which is
somewhat so we try to just define it as
an established bilateral exchange of
data between dots client-server so
similar to sip don't miss something we
closed issues 14 and 15 respectively
remaining work which is um incorporate
any changes resulting from additional
use cases and multihoming discussion
obviously there's been some discussion
around the home net mod stuff we'll see
if that brings anything up and also if
anything pops up in the malt
humming discussion adjustments resulting
from implemented feedback economies I'll
be presenting shortly and he's got some
very important and also you know good
comments to come out of that and then
we're also gonna meet for a
comprehensive review because just a top
down through the whole thing because
it's been a while since I think we've
we've a tackled bit from a you know a
kind of top-down you we've been like you
know doing it II bits as we go along and
that's it any questions comments
complaints Rowland diamonds Arbor
networks um I think a lot of people in
the working group know that we've been
working on use cases and the
requirements kind of um you know in
parallel with one another and informing
you know one another
bilaterally so to speak and we do have
one more Rev of use cases is going to
come out we have one maybe two now
additionally use cases and then there's
the whole net issue that needs to be
decided but we do not anticipate any new
requirements that have not already been
anticipated and discussed in these
documents will arise from that last
revision ok cool thank you but I was
easy okay any other comments okay then
we save some time catch up okay thank
you moving to a second architecture
discussion about multihoming and for
context setting is we got together at
the interim we had mentioned that there
were some things that we needed to talk
about related to the architecture and
one of those was related to multi-homing
and coming out of that interim Chiru man
actually said they would write something
up to the mailing list to get the
conversation started but the origin of
this draft is actually one better they
actually made a draft about some of
their thinking so thank you for for
forgetting the conversation started in
this formal way so the the background
for having this rough writing and
presented in this in this in this
meeting so and just a recall of the
minnow people that we have to have when
we wrote this this is the first ones to
completely the dots architectural
document with not how many specific
specific aspects
because currently there are some text
which is in the architectural document
which is in the building which is not
sufficient most of the text is likely to
focus on the single haunt Network and
the other one is to identify what are
the specifics to the medium in context
so that D will drive the behavior of the
dots client and the discreet ways when
it comes to centimeter Gatien request or
maintenance associated with with
upstream that servers and the last
objectives we set for when we wrote this
document is to sketch some guidelines
for all the entities whose are involved
in the estimate a home in the context
for instance which the server will
select when you replace your request
should you and also there is another
problem whether the use of the inner
cast addresses is is useful useful or it
is harness in some in some context and
especially in the context of the
military helmet so why this document is
is needed so the first one is that if
you have a list of that server that you
are configuring to you to your desk
client or your does gateway if you just
select one of them in an arbitrary
manner you it may happen that the
records that you are since the server
want to be handled by the server built
because the server does not own that
resource if you are asking for a set to
black hole that is a given IP prefix but
if that server is not located in that
same network which is which is routing
packets with that with that IP prefix it
can do nothing for you so it's useless
for for won't help the dots client to
mitigate in the context the other aspect
that if you are just blindly and forking
all the requests systematically to all
the good servers which are configured to
at this point what that's good way it's
something which is sub optimal because
we are just overloading the apps in the
server you are asking for an SOS alarm
but all this this server may not be
affecting you and then another problem
is that if you are you have a list of
that servers and if you go sequentially
to contact each of them you are just
increasing the delay to to mitigate the
requests so that it's suboptimal
so that's why there is a need to to have
some guidance somewhere in the
architectural document or in a separate
document to guide the DOS client and the
disc gateways on the way you will place
the request and the maintain the
association with upstream the servers
so how which methodology we have adopted
for this when we read it so we started
from the the effort that that is
documented by Roland so that we just
extracted the viable use cases from
there and we wanted this use cases with
specificity of the of the mr. Harmon for
instance whether we will have one or
multiple absent providers whether we
will use one single or multiple routers
to interconnects with absent providers
or whether we are using the provider
independent or provider assigned
prefixes in in this context and once we
have you mounted all these use cases by
specifics of the D multihoming then we
describe the recommended behavior for
each of the use cases that we have
identified so far for instance if there
is if we can use a unicast or not if we
can plus a fork the request or we or if
we have to stop it in the does client
itself so basically this is just a
summary of some example at least the
main trends of the use cases that we can
cover when we are we're dealing with
multihoming I am not listening in this
one the other use cases in which you
have your mitigation provider it's not
your own transit provider and this is a
cloud hosted by in a cloud basically you
have three three three flavors there
which are three of them you are likely
to encounter in an enterprise context
and one and the the fourth one which is
likely in the world that context in
which you have SCP SCP which is
connected to multiple and multiple
domains first typically a fixed X line
and the other one with a mobile element
and the E and the D traders this is
typically the entreprise network in
which you have a multi hond you may have
multiple absent providers if you want to
play with your top team as your Cecily's
and in industry flavors you have francis
the typical one usual is in one single
router or one single CP router to
integrity on absent provider or if you
have the using dedicated routers to
interconnect to upstream sales provider
so once we have identified this may
flavor of having multi-home at the human
we will start to see now if we enable
the das service somewhere so again there
will be a variety of of of scenarios
there you may have all your ups
observers preferences that support the
dude server but you may also have only a
subset of this providers who offer to do
the server but whatever the scenario
that would be experienced there there is
a constraint that is that some of the
dist servers that will be available in
this absent providers may not be
reachable through an arbitrary path they
will be reachable only from the router
connected to the absent provider who is
offering to you the the dead server so
this a producer requirement there to
associate the link from where you have
learned your good server and so that
before for placing ups three subsequent
requests you have to always select that
but otherwise you will have failures to
contact with the server now once we have
identified the scenarios in which you
have a placement of your dead server if
we see now at the client side a gander
there is a variety or a variation of
scenarios there with or without adults
gateway you can have a gateway somewhere
in the DCP on the router it may be look
at it elsewhere there is no requirement
in the does in the dots architecture
that the dot functional element be
located in the the tablet or or in the
indeed pad that will experience the DDoS
attack so you you have this kind of of
scenarios there this is only again this
is only showing examples there you may
have an if Francis V we we focus on the
first one in in which you have for
instance a gateway which is connected
located in one single router and
connected to two upstream providers the
this gate reference does get referenced
as it it has the responsibility decide
whether we need to receive a request
from internal clients it has to decide
to decide to which upstream that server
it has to transmit the the request or it
has to frog the request to all the app
standard server which is about in the
question on this or yes let me address
not have two questions for you first one
is I think we've tried to take a general
design principle in the group for now of
saying we want to address the simple
scenarios for
and then we can always extend later on
with more complicated functionality so
you know the meta question is whether
you think multihoming is an absolute
requirement for what we're doing is the
first step in dots to address that
scenario all these scenarios that you're
specifying the second question I have is
you seem to be getting into wanting to
standardize exactly what adults gateway
is and I don't think that we want to hit
down that path yeah the questions yeah
for the first one yes I do agree
personally as we don't need to overload
the current built architecture with the
demented Holman I did make current for
this take on this is that is to make it
clearer than the current dot
architecture is mainly forgetting for
the single haunt and to leave
multihoming for something else so that
the group will have time to focus we
tend to study it further so this is for
the first question okay for the second
one the the dots gateway is defined as a
back-to-back this client and the server
service is fine the dots get by anyway
but anyway that's another how do you
glue your client and your server into
this is an internal implementation we
are not specifying that but how you are
placing your request this is just a
normal that's client and the in the
other side how the dot server will
receive and process at the the the
request this is how we are defined that
yeah I mean if I would rephrase that I
would say we recognize that it's
possible to combine a dots client and a
server and we call that a Todd's gateway
and that's it yeah we don't go any
further than that in that actually means
how that works
protocol support all of that is out of
scope yeah what we have seen in the
indeed dot sake - sorry is that does get
ways is a back to back agent which is a
DOS client and the server and for me
this is sufficient yes and that's it and
that's what we require for this work and
that is it in terms of what we spacers
actually and agree with that and they
want only to focus to just yet that
little yeah question is co-chair
because you said well this multihoming
you don't need it now but you may need
it later there may be no later so I'm
just I won't just want to make clear
like if you believe this is essential
then say so and if this is an
essential requirement assuming there is
no later that would be good if you could
state it if you believe it needs to be
covered if if not then that's fine for
me as well yeah this one yeah so just
called me to deliveries for that we
started from the dirtiest cases and all
what M explained here is extracted from
the dots use cases so for me it is
something which is the working group
have identified in in this work you've
adopted document and they don't think
that personally that this language is
interesting that we to handle there is
something which is specific to milky
homi which is not unique to the other
solution that we have so far which are
just you have you a single hold and then
you have your apps improve that server
there are something which is specific to
be to be elaborated but those details me
in balance did those architecture to the
now that's why I prefer to have it
something outside the dots architecture
so this is two levels it's important but
we may need to handle it in a separate
document
Roland haven't rubber networks does
absolutely must support multihoming it's
been designed from the outset to support
multihoming there so far I'm seeing
nothing that here that actually sits
within the realm of das of dots itself
some additional deployment guidance
regarding PA space versus P I space you
know makes a certain amount of sense but
as we very consciously have had
multihoming which is a hard requirement
in mind from dots for the outset I fail
to see anything in in dots that is
lacking in the protocol itself nor in
the conceptions of the dots
communications knows it precludes it's
used in the multihoming environment and
as you noted we have several different
multihoming cases in the use cases
document as well as the overlay provider
which is topologically distant and in
both six and seven of the use cases
document we actually spend a fair amount
of time talking about the additional
external considerations that have
nothing to do with dots itself that's
required to make those models we're
it's a follow-up question may be rollin
or one of the requirements draft authors
do we actually have a multihoming
requirement if you believe it absolutely
is required I think we should ask yeah
okay so if you come back to us cases we
have an at least if you focus on the
client side as I mentioned you may have
seen ours in which we have the Gateway
and the others in which we we don't have
gateways I do agree with Roland here
that there is no implicit implication on
the protocol itself but there will be
implication on the way the dots get
oriented those claims will use the dots
to contact the servers so typically if
we now if we forget the topology and we
just focus on the dots a suggestion
themself we have a variety of scenarios
there depends on the use cases typically
if we offer as you don't sell CP that
you multihomed in there's two
Association there's the one from the
client that is likely to be invaded in
the in the CPS self it has to maintain
two Association one with the dots of all
the network attachments but when it
comes to a two other scenario which are
more ready-to-work to the enterprise
network we may have sinners in which we
don't have the the gateway and it's up
to the on TT which manage that network
to decide how to configure the clients
whether the clients will be provided
with with build addresses of with the
others of all the servers out or it may
decide to have a good client be
configured only with one and only one
dot server so it depends on each
configuration that you have you have a
set of implications there and
recommendation in the way this dots
clients will contacts their upstream
providers and all these recommendations
are elaborated in the in the draft to
give an example if we just resume on
this one and if you have your your you
have our original CP that's embedded
those client and if it happens that all
your absent providers are providing to
you that
server there are the first implications
there is that because we are configuring
names off for the best server if you
want to resolve that name you must use a
dinner server which is provided by the
exact absoluteness of providers it's may
be obvious and so on but this is the
list of items that need to be to be
handled again for the other selection
and so on there's also the establishment
of the association that must be
maintained with all the app same as AB
same servers but when it comes to send a
mitigation request then the the DOS
client has to decide whether it needs to
contact the appropriate server for a
given let's attack because they attack
maybe just received for your from the
mobile network and not for the fixed and
it's trans yes
for me so I'm not sure I agree with this
I mean specifically the second Pole
right because that seems to assume that
there is a very tight coupling between
the provider of the access network and
who did that service provider is yes and
perhaps you forgot my introduction on
there I say that's when you focus on the
resident CLK the time machine here which
assume that this server is provided by
your upstream network providers and I
said that if the the dot server is not
Frances hosted by a cloud service
providers we are not in this in this in
this in this use case this
recommendations are tied so how would I
know which use case this is the plumbing
specific this is this is why this is
tricky to handle this is deployment
specific that's why I'm pushing back a
little bit on some of this yeah because
they're very quickly gets very
complicated yeah we have to we have to
figure out how to agree with you know
this particular to this Roland Diamonds
Arbor networks first of all one second
what Fleming said secondly I believe
that we're running a risk here of
imbuing too much mitigation logic and
context within dots a lot of this stuff
is external to dots in my view that it
really goes into the orchestration of
systems
and mitigation systems and so yeah I
want I want to hear more but this this
seems like it's Mickey's we're talking
about some problems that that aren't
necessarily problems the DNS server
recommendation in particular it doesn't
make sense to me oh yeah after using the
DNS servers learn the same network I
mean why can't I I don't understand why
I can't can't point it you know wherever
I want right in this matter of fact das
also has to be able to function in the
absence of any DNS at all so I said -
has to be able to function in the
absence of an Indian s service at all
may I suggest that we let you continue
and finish your slides and then we maybe
take one or two minutes to discuss on
the summary at this point only
clarifying questions if you need them at
this point and then we bundle the
questions at the end please continue
okay so the next part is is that this
lies disease showing some samples in
which indicus is not is not recommended
for in plus in the ders requests the
first case in if you have the provider
independent addressing if for instance
the declined the Internet client is
using any cast to reach the Gateway and
that means that the death signal will be
received by the the gateway which is
according to the shortest path within
that that Internet work and that could
very well just forward the request to to
the appszoom that server but because you
are in a provider independent address in
there the the DOS attack is not only
experienced from the network provider
one but it is also experienced in from
the network provider too because your
you are using provider independent
address in there so the request in this
case because you are using any cast
indicas addressing your mitigation
request didn't wasn't received by all
the gateways that are located in
distinct locations of the routers and
the mitigation is only enforced in the
partial path and not all in all the path
in which your experiment experienced in
the dots
in the other case if you have the
provider assigned for instance assigned
the assigned schema in this case again
if we assume that you are raising a
unique as unique as to within the
internal a internal network your request
will be received for instance by EDI
gateway which is the katadyn r1 the r1
the Gateway which is in r1 will forward
the request to the upstream server but
the the attack wasn't Tracy isn't isn't
subject to due to the IP address which
is as assigned by NATO provider one but
if it is it is subject to the idea that
we design by network brother to the
server which is located in the domain to
should be contacted instead of this one
but you have a problem there because the
request was sent to the first gateway so
in these two examples this is just to
illustrate in cases which which are the
cases in which it is not recommended to
use anycast addresses when you are
contacting your upstream that server
that it happens to be your dot Gateway
yes Roland yes you that you okay yeah so
this is this is not my last slide and I
prefer to focus on the questions so I
think we have about two or three minutes
for questions please yeah that's so
decisions about you know whether or not
to use any cash addressing in the
topological issues that you describe in
this slide I mean this is network
engineering 101 do we really need to get
to that level of detail
in our recommendations if we do that's
okay I mean I certainly see the need to
to you know it could help to put some
operation because we already have some
you know guidance as to some of the
things that are external to us that the
operators need to do so I can see you
know you know be sure to consider you
know your normal network engineering one
at one you know tiny a route ability
reach ability types of issues I'm not
sure that we didn't really need a
separate document for it so I can see
this recommendation being a
recommendation
the deployment recommendation but I
do you believe that a separate document
is really needed for this or do you
anticipate it being unfolded into use
cases or requirements sir I the most
important is to have information
somewhere and recorded by the working
group and this is an open question tool
to the welcome to decide how to form it
is there's a list of behaviors and
guidelines on the way you does client
and gateways have to behave in the
metahuman context how to document that
form it's just a logistic it's up to
decide I mean I don't read this as you
know don't create running loops and
don't create grounding black holes I
mean that's how I interpret this was
anything else so I think we need a
little more discussion this I would toss
out a couple of data points first not 20
minutes ago our area director told us
while you have the reinforced by that
seems like a lot maybe you should
rethink sure you have less so I'm a
little scared to say maybe we have four
second of all we were talking about I
think a little earlier whether there are
any requirements relative to
multi-homing I actually saw a definition
for a multi home client but I saw new
requirements for it so this kind of
helps kind of inform what we do here and
I also notice in this document very
helpfully it talks about requirements
and architecture and borders kind of on
implementation so I also would suggest
maybe we need to decompose all of which
I think we need to do on the middle list
in the interest of moving forward just
for clarification what induces from cut
is that the DHD doesn't recommend to the
big discussion of the use cases under
requirement document and not the yeah
not of the information documents first
so I don't see the link between the two
the two discussions there but anybody
less just a lot of story so the
underlying reason for the is geez advice
is to manage the amount of documents
that are coming i postulate this and you
may or may not agree but i think i
actually very much welcome that you put
this in a in the form of a document i
mean this is very useful and it's good
to read it that way I do agree with
Roman that probably we need to see like
where these do these things roll into
the existing documents like use cases
requirements architecture what's the
implications
so Kathleen Moriarty ad I'm not as
concerned about you know number of
documents and watching this it was more
that I'm interested to hear it maybe on
the mailing list or show hands or
something interest in this as opposed to
the you know a very few number of people
that stood up right because that doesn't
that's that's not the working group
that's you know a couple of people's
opinions that's well taken
do you wish us to ask for a show of
hands at this point or should I mean so
multi-homing is important at the interim
meeting we very clearly stated we're
blocking the architecture document on
resolving it and we have news cases that
do multi-homing so we need to say
something about it or kind of deal then
bring to closure or what the working
group needs to do during multi-homing i
don't think we know what to do and boy
it's really phenomenal we have a lot of
text that describes what we could do in
the multi-homing space i would suggest
that we don't know what to do next and
in the interest of time i would say
let's take it to the mailing list to
figure out how we tease this out what
its implication is for this draft what
the implication is for other drats any
objections at this moment otherwise we
will proceed as as stated thank you so
next up we're switching to start talking
about protocols and implementations and
first up we have Konami who's going to
tell us about the experience and
actually before he starts I like to say
how amazing it was that we had a
hackathon session for dots go dots
I believe waiting for good odds and like
it was even like listed as one of the
good achievements at the hackathon and
I'm very happy we have that and I'm very
much looking forward to hearing more
about the implementation from Konami so
that's really great go for it
yes oh I want to hear about implications
of Konami I also want to hear about
implementations from others to you thank
you and I'm kinda mean he's come from
NTT communications
I'd like to introduce the goal
implementation of thoughts okay yes we
open the code then yeah I hope this is a
good news too yeah you are this
grip this code is available in github
this URL and yeah you can search for
this code by the hitting call dot maybe
and then the license is about 2.0 so
it's free to use and yes you can deploy
the code only by a gogit command so yeah
you could do it so then we joined a
hackathon of this IETF this these ideas
are lost weekend and with this code
actually the most of code was developed
and tested internally beforehand so
what-what we developed in this hackathon
is that first we made the code of easy
to be deployed in various environment
for example we made a docker compose
file for each services and also we
refined the configuration part which is
rather complex and second we clarifies
that documents read any other comments
in the code and enriched especially for
newcomers to this field ok then at the
hackathon we made a demonstration of one
user scenario which triggers a black
hole running from victim side so the
demo scenario was constructed in the
current environment so it can be ported
to your environment
a project attracted at least four people
which includes iyx people are ISP people
during the hackathon then we explain
what dot is and showed the demo okay
this is the second good news we do demo
on pizza bites
today so I from seven fifteen to
nineteen fifteen the end so yeah
pravin visit us on the site okay this is
a demo in one paper the demo scenario is
enabling DDoS protection in upstream
network by totes protocol the hot you
can do I hope you can see in this demo
is that adult quiet in victim sites and
the mitigation request to adult server
of asymptotes fingering channel then
adults ever received and validates a
request then start mitigation by kicking
a blocker in this time of the blocker is
Gobi City server which triggered the
call routing in a service operators
network in fact the dot client is in
some cloud service and service providers
network is in fact in our lab network
but dot dot request conveyed over the
Internet so you can see this table in
bits and bytes okay I'd like to
introduce three lessons learned from our
experience so you know we talked about
these lessons love lessons learned in
the yesterday's design team meeting
about a drug to repeat them in order to
show you here you hear from you first
point yeah about this description on
specification on mutual certification is
needed I think our current draft is
using a DTLS based client certificate in
Louisville in lab we tend to use self
signed certification then the question
is how he binds the DTS or a TLS channel
and customer which is a mitigation Scott
so a CN or as in Osawatomie indicators
should be used so it's not clearly
documented and the second question is
what else for mutual authentication we
would like to find some other technology
for mutual authentication then a
question is again how can we bind the
authenticated entity with customer
education Scott that is a question okay
the second point I we are still
searching for good risk of library as
our other alternative crop ETS which is
using signal channel can be used for
data channel so we took these strategies
but we want to implement it on risk of
if we cancel if you have opinion about
this strategy over you if you know good
risk of library please assure to the
working group
okay so third point is about a heartbeat
mode yeah we think as we're hot with
mode should be allowed between those cry
out dot server yeah as a starting point
of implementation in love we used zero
how treat mode but also we realized that
there are several use cases as discussed
in the last I heated meeting for example
our residential CPE use cases and at
Hawk cry out so yeah so must in recur
with or recommit ruff 6:03 should be
relaxed this is our proposal yep sorry
Fleming arisen yeah so I know the
question about open source rest can't
came up in the design team meeting as
well so I asked around and what I have
learned since then apparently is that
open daylight
actually has a rest conf module in it
it's not clear how easy it is to take
that out but there is some code there at
least that was the only thing that I
learned about yeah I I don't usually
without an already woolen damansara
networks um from operational perspective
I would support relaxing the Harvey
requirements you should
yeah thank you it Archer a virgin curve
once again
accurate ellipse regarding the relaxing
of the must here I had better considered
in it once again because the lack of
heartbeat in a what possibly congestion
network path due to you know denial of
service attack can itself indicate
necessarily necessity of mitigation
taking place so we should I think we
should not we should reconsider this
but don't agree on relaxing this usually
okay yeah yeah
they person immediately meeting gave me
good advice
we must habit if we must implement how
to beat but we can use zero heartbeat
body sorry oh sorry yeah yeah the
suggestion is that we must implement the
heartbeat but we can use zero heartbeat
mode if we want
okay she thank you I'm exist so Nick I
drew was in the queue first five typical
under pearls before swine how's the baby
yeah yes in daily does implement rest
constant and I successfully in the past
I guess the question I have is whether
that is have for interrupt because that
would be a single implementation for
this herbicide the client-side I think
is not a particularly issue but like and
all those people
I can't use magic here because I
couldn't fully follow but maybe my
acoustics is not as good as yours can
you can you come back up perfect and
button seating I was saying that open
daylight open daylight has is a fine
restaurant implementation I'm wondering
if it will be sufficient to meet the
requirement for two unique
implementations that are interoperable I
have had no problem we finding
client-side implementations that is you
know clients using restaurants but if we
are stuck solely with open daylight and
not sure that's sufficient to my
understanding and Kevin correct me two
implementations is a requirement for
full standard strike not for proposed
standards so that means we are we are
okay of course it's always good to have
more but from a from a status
perspective we are fine again Nick
Teague no I just wanted to echo regard
echo some the discussion on the zero
heartbeat idea it's not so much that we
should I I agree that we should have a
must implement the heartbeat and then
have an option to turn it off for
certain scenarios where it is understood
that's turning it off poses a certain
risk or poses a certain change in the
way that we we deal with the logic there
are arguments for ad hoc communications
which don't require the constant to
backwards and forward of a heartbeat you
know such as certain MSPs talking to
each other or in subscriber networks
where you maybe have three million you
know who knows so I think there is a it
was just echo support that and you keep
us moving I'm cutting the line after
Flemming Rowland omens represent works I
just wanted to clarify my previous
remarks exactly what Nick said that's
what I meant by that
let me enjoy yes so on the whole
heartbeat thing I mean I I have enormous
ly mixed feelings about the heartbeat
on one hand right you know scalability
I'm very concerned about it right
especially with some of the use case
scenarios we have on the other hand we
have scenarios to say we have to be able
to traverse Nats
I don't know how to reconcile all of
that but I am concerned you know about
heartbeat in general in this protocol I
don't think it's well under civil the
implications are right now yeah okay
yeah we also need to test how to beat
can overcome not seen so yeah we need to
watch a condor heart beating yeah yeah
so given that feedback I think that
cascades into multiple drafts that were
trying to get done so this certainly
speaks to the protocol drafts themselves
but it would appear that the
requirements language might need to be
tuned as well so it seems valuable to
put a note out as a github issue so we
track this either closure to figure out
what we've resolved or we can further
discussion as to what to do next
Roland you're just going to say when you
need to have more discussion about zero
heartbeat configuration scenarios and if
if the sense the working group does end
up that we believe that that's valuable
then we need to actually put a use case
in to illustrate it so what cascades
into more documents yep
yeah about ionic consideration yeah we
think IV need assignment for the fraud
for number four six four six which
represents dot dot for signal channel
which is in spectrum lost motifs in dots
of a UDP is used in our implementation
and we used four six four seven for
datachannel but exactly we need some
assignment when yeah our protocol is
standardized and here here are imitation
specific problems is written like this
first point is traffic that color
collection
the atrophic information should be
returned from dots others are like an
incoming traffic block traffic post
Rocky
but we noticed that we need additional
software components to collect those
data from new network equipment or
mitigation boxes but it is very
implementation specific so we cannot
make any assumption beforehand but it is
required so yeah this is a difficult
problem to maybe do to implementers the
second point is partially invalid query
quest
well mitigation requests can contain
multiple scopes but when the mitigation
requests we include varied scope and
invalid Scott at the same time what is
appropriate appropriate behavior so
reject or apartheid because only so it
can it could break some interoperability
with other implementations so second
point is that yeah yeah this is the
second point of our limited
implementation specific project Oh
Roland Islands Arbor networks on traffic
data collection in export statistics my
views at there outside the scope of this
working group as you say it's very
implementation specific there's a lot
more than PPS and VPS to be concerned
about right just all the different layer
7 stuff and there are mechanisms like IP
fix and other things that can be used to
return this information to a requesting
dot's entity outside the scope of dots
we're basically now turning ourselves
into a network telemetry system if we go
down this path so I would recommend that
that we think very very carefully before
we do this again my individual view with
regard to partially valid requests I'm
not so sure that determining validity is
necessarily something that we need to
make a judgment on on the dot server I
think that that's more something that we
need to make a validity judgment oh and
with regards to the orchestration
systems and other things so I'm not not
so sure that that necessarily applies if
this since the group is that it does
apply I have my recommendation would be
to pass the valid request only
okay so yeah yeah we think at any time
we need to make some decision about some
behavior this kind of things we when we
do that interoperability with other
limitations but I thought your opinion
this yeah not it today thank you
okay as a next step
yeah we a recommendation is now Oasis so
we'd like to make it to the adoptee to
the various deployment scenario and we
keep going on the implementation of
working group draft and make feedback to
the specifications so yeah we can
collaborate on it so you have feedback
is we're very welcome all right David
Olson sent wine from your implementation
I'm wondering if you found from the
message sighs any concern about the size
of the Datagram whether we need to be
concerned about fragmentation or
anything
lovely have you made the the coop and
the sea poor and the DTLS and all that
together okay yeah we just tried small
mediation request so yeah we've
redirected try that yeah thank you for
that you know big it was yeah do you
know how many bytes it was in the unity
packet I mean II about you know about
okay yeah yeah I'll get back to you
later
so yeah those is getting popular we
realized in the hackathon so we'd like
to do inter interoperability testing as
enix Hakkasan eitf 100 in the design
team meeting we talked with implementers
each other and we saw that a similar
channel interrupt
would be the first step but it is not
committed yet but we it loves to do
start yeah this is the end of my
presentation thank you very much
yes this is really cool
and as you said it would be nice to do
some interoperability and maybe more
hacking at Singapore 100 who would be
interested because thank you no ability
it's always nice to have more than one
so who is interested in doing that no
commitment at this point I'm just asking
for interest any show of hands any
shyness
yeah so that we have one two at the back
three okay do you want to state your
name and company for the record or
rather not just show of hands so to
leave the bar of commitment less okay I
see you I know you're fine any so that's
that's at least three different
companies if I counted this and yeah my
hand is raised oh okay cool so that that
gives us four plus entity that's five
that would be awesome yeah so then
please if you have any questions or need
any help in preparing for that let the
chairs know we would we will do anything
in our power to support that so that's
great okay and thank you so much I'm
sorry the ID as well so she's smiling so
this is yeah so thank you very much for
Kaname for making this first great step
forward and I'll be looking forward to
more in Singapore awesome yeah and one
more thing I wanted to repeat about
doing Interop that came up in the design
team meeting if this puts someone that's
on the fence to participate your code
does not need to be open source and
you're releasing no IPR by bringing your
implementation so if you are kind of
wondering do I does that imply kind of
anything that I bring it
in terms of kind of a note well or
anything else it does not if you have an
appliance or you want to bring your
thing on a black box you can absolutely
do that so next up we have Nick who's
going to start talking about the dots
signal and data channel and because
we're a little bit behind time Nick I'm
cutting some time off so I'm I'm giving
you a 20 minute blocked for both given
though I don't think I'll even need that
but I think we'll see okay so I'm here
challeng thiru I'm going to do the dots
in single channels draft these were
adopted last time or shortly thereafter
so we've had we've dropped a couple of
versions since the transitions of the
first transition the double-o was tramp
was the adoption and were on o2 now
we've addressed all comments receive
from the working group of both drafts so
far going on to the signal channel
specifically the mitigation requests we
replaced the idea the the terminology of
policy ID with mitigation ID there was
some confusion around the term policy
and everything else that that we wanted
to kind of clear up session channels the
session configuration will also replace
policy ID with session ID just to keep
kind of keeps a uniformity in that
aliases could be created either using
the dots data channel or direct
configuration direct configuration being
somebody typing something on a command
line somewhere or into a you know into a
GUI or whatever it whatever it is
previously data being kind of like I
think referred to as direct connection
so it was just to kind of give it a bit
more clarification than that one the dot
server derives the dots client identity
using the algorithm discussed in session
seven of RFC 75 89 on net cough to
couple dot signal and data channel
sessions you can read that enjoy there
are some further discussions around that
we had from con amazed implementation
regarding things like identity and also
tying in the the signal
channel and the assets that were being
communicated a single channel while the
prefixes and so on and aliases and
everything and tying those to the
customer at the back end of the decor
had been gone through the day channel so
there were some some some some resupply
Seng that needed happened there which
obviously would be informed by what kind
of Mae's been doing so we can take that
offline and have a look at it
the next updates Dave Dolson actually
put in an email this morning I think
which we obviously have had a chance to
really address yet and there was a
number of questions and comments in
there which we will have to look at and
address so assume some of those are in
addition to this if you have read that
that email we were going to add in a -1
value for a lifetime parameter
mitigation get indicate an indefinite
mitigation lifetime so that somebody
could basically say keep doing this and
don't stop until such time as we decide
that to remove send a suitable
withdrawal it just a case of like you
know mitigate me or mean it could be for
always-on services well how whatever
anybody wants to do we also did a new
parameter mitigation request the signal
server to initiate mitigation after the
service eases receiving client signals
so similar to the discussion around the
harpy before you could also have
something like oh well if the heartbeats
disappear or if the signals disappear
then Autoport or mitigate or whatever
that would be a switch some customers
would want that some people won't people
wouldn't would trust it other people
don't so some people might just be doing
a maintenance and I wouldn't have told
you further next updates again in can in
addition to whatever they've brought up
that we need to address or anybody else
is the mitigation lifetime was
negotiated we there's a little bit of
confusion minute cuz the mitigation
lifetime is it's negotiated in the
request response but there's also some
some negotiation in the signal channel
session configuration so we just need to
kind of like figure out exactly what it
is we mean by that and what we're doing
with it and whether we want that to go
ahead it doesn't make sense to do it in
two places and especially if one takes
precedence over the other or anything
like that
and I don't you can do it on a on a you
know on a session configuration basis
person so that's on the signal channel
there any questions comments anybody
wants to run out before I go into the
data row Lederman's over networks what
was the logic behind the proposal or the
thinking that it might make sense to do
this do the mitigation session
limitation during the session
negotiation what's the logic behind that
I don't recall yeah so I can't remember
the discussion that it came up but it
was it was there and obviously I think I
think it's it's it's worth making note
as well this this is our first revision
since we adopted this one so there's
probably some baggage there and there's
some changes and everything else would
have occurred on a on a rolling basis
that we that some things have been you
know there may be some overlap or
anything like that so so I wouldn't put
too much okay yeah I just want to point
out for folks something proposed to
think about is that it's certainly a
viable scenario we're in a given dots
client request different mitigations at
different times with different values
based on the specifics of a particular
attack so we want to make sure that we
preserve you know that kind of
flexibility on the part of what the dots
client wants to requires yeah yeah no I
don't think it makes much sense to do it
on a on thing I mean you might want to
set defaults or something but I don't
but even then that could be configure
the later flemming run flemming under
isn't this is just a general question on
both drafts one of the things that we
talked a lot about in the beginning in
the rehab in the requirements as well
there's a need for extensibility yeah
it's not so clear to me when I look at
these drafts exactly how that's
satisfied I'm guessing that I use a rest
con from the data Channel right there is
some underlying machinery that we're
gonna be taking advantage of it might be
helpful to just elaborate on that on a
signal channel on the other end I'm not
really sure how it works maybe that's
just me not understanding you know I
think that's a fair comment at the
minute to take and I think that's
something we need to kind of address
yeah
so data channel so we extended the the
the ACL yang model to handle fragments
in support rate limiting action there's
an example of it brief bit on the
filtering of fragments we haven't really
done a whole look changes on the data
Channel other than other than around
this so the filtering of fragments to
defend against DDoS attacks use any non
non initial fragments you can read on
the slide they're exactly what it does
is just to add it some additional
filtering capabilities into the into the
filter transfer portion of the data
channel and it just brings it in line
with with various mitigation potential
mitigation strategies and so on that we
that exist and that's it so any any
comments concerns again this is like
first drop I think since we adopted
these so with the still way to go Dave
Bilson yeah is this one github or will
you put it on the dot Skippy sorry I was
actually gonna talk about yes we will
put it on the dots WG github so that we
can start opening issues and everything
else yes so I just want to finesse
finesse that so we're saying we're gonna
pronounce github so we'll have version
tracking on the top on the document
there so we can do polls and we're gonna
do an issue tracking yeah we can do a
lot okay everything we've done for
architecture and requirements on
phenomen can you see that list with the
node of extensibility the fleming broad
and the things that konami got out of
the hackathon guess yeah good start
thank you
well the diamonds are worse i forgot to
mention on with regards to the idea of
the always on or perpetually you know
enabled mitigation you know until such
time as terminations requested we do see
that in the real world with regards to
financial institutions and so forth yeah
i mean we we have experience of it where
it's like oh we want to there'll be some
demand some some kind of murmurings on a
forum somewhere and so you know it's
it's there for a couple of weeks or a
month or whatever until so or campaign
or something like that so it's just to
kind of cover that you know it so they
can be handled via dots versus a
coordinator
okay maybe a quick question is couch
here
let's read the draft quick show of hands
if so we get a feeling about the state
of review at this point I mean I know
it's new oh wow wow that's much more
than I expected two three more like
eight nine Wow okay that's yeah okay
that that's a good set of review for an
early hard have you of the people who
raised their hands
have you already submitted some of your
comments or is there like a lot of it
and no sorry my question is the other
way around if you have read the draft
but not yet submitted your comments but
intend to do so could you indicate that
okay so there is a wave coming for you I
think probably I'm just speaking on your
behalf I think it would be good to
submit these comments soonish so they're
yeah yeah okay yeah I think I mean what
we can do is once we get the github up
we can now start to distill lows and
maybe it's best to wait till github is
up before we start flooding it and then
that way we won't miss any you know
github and mailing this plans will mail
out once the github straight cool cool
for your expectation I I think the get
up should be up fairly soon yeah so like
expect a few days so hold your breath
and shoot away okay thank you and I
think we are so we're back on schedule
so we now have two individual drafts to
discuss first up med you're gonna talk
about server discovery again another
topic that we raised at the interim so
thank you for putting a draft to talk
about what we talked about yeah yeah
yeah just a reminder of the context is
that he there's a need for the best
client to know the IP address for the
name of the disturber to contact and
currently the dots architecture is
silent about that he assumed that based
on magic the does client is configured
with the information for the dot servers
to be a contact so there's a void there
and you are trying to fit that that that
void with this document so may have bid
this day is to go back to Roland
document and to extract these cases and
to classify the cases but I am not using
all of them I removed one that a it's
not my favorite but to balance that I
removed the the hum let you skate which
is not running so if we just consider
all these use cases we classified them
whether they require a CP or not and
also whether there is a need or or or
whether the the dots the the Daniell of
service mitigation service is provided
by the absent if your provider or it is
provided by a cloud service provider so
you have the the device combination
there so if if we start to examine this
this list and if we we have in mind how
we can answer to the previous question
area we have how to configure or to
provide to the disk line the identity of
the does servers to contact if we focus
on the first use case the first use case
for instance there is a single a single
network which is single found for this
one we can just answer to him yeah it's
easy just use an in u.s. address you you
would just hit your dad server that's
easy but the problem is that there are
other use cases there that your the the
dots mitigation service is not your
upstream provider if that means that if
you are using in the COS address you
want never reach the dots that server in
the meantime if we we have the other use
cases that require to have an integrated
that's client for those it is just
appropriate to avoid
requiring new functionalities to those
clients just to reuse and to diverge on
existing features on this on its own the
on on this on it on this note that is
the leveraging on existing tools to
discover the the dot server is
appropriate that that's why we think
that's using the straightforward in a
material for that case would be will be
recommended but in the the other
calendar we see that all of them or
almost all the use cases are using the
CPE and if you have the network
providers today we are provisioning on
providing configuration information to
to the CP which it it will attach the
network and we are just using DHCP and
other tools TR 16:9 and so on to
provision the CP so it is just intuitive
for us as a provider just to reuse these
tools to provide dots identity using
this existing tool that's why the use of
the DCP may be appropriate for this case
so if we suck if we do a summary of this
Aleph we consider all the use cases each
of them you have some specifically there
and know of the tools that I mentioned
the use of the mdns for instances of
Innoko the use of DHCP does not does not
that not solve all the problem for all
the use cases so each of these use cases
have some its own unique requirement so
it is unlikely that one signal solution
should is to be recommended for Ford for
that so that's why we we we are
proposing this unified discovery
discovery method in which we are don't
find at least year four steps to be
followed by the dots client the first
one is that simple that to assume that
this is something which is explicitly
configure to the dots client if you have
some day which is configured just go go
go with your local configuration this
low configuration can be manual can be
static or can be written by DHCP once
you have this information with 50 you
just proceed with with the service
resolution the service solution will
provide you with the other information
for instance to discover whether you you
have the same IP address for both the
data channel or the signal Channel or
whether you use TCP recipients on this
kind of stuff and if the service will
restore files then you can use other
tools which are available locally for
instance you can use DNS service the
discovery or mdns at the end of the day
if all of these steps fail then you you
can use the the unipass address as a
last resort and in the document we are
not required or recommended in the order
in which you can proceed for the
discovery just an implementation we
decide to run all of them separately or
just stop at for instance for the first
one and doesn't implement the others so
this is this is the main contribution
from this document to say that it is
there is no justification to have to
have one single mechanism to discover or
thicken
the disk servers to those clients it is
all it is likely that we will need
multiple tools to discover this
information to provide this client and
it is good to have for for deterministic
behavior of those clients to have a
unified algorithm that will be followed
by this distance implemented
implementation and this is what we are
providing while providing here
yes Rolla Roland avanzar Burnett works I
have a question
there's a lot of discussion about
anycast here it seems that there's an
assumption that any caste is going to be
a pervasive addressing mechanism for dot
servers what is an assumption based upon
oh there seems to be an assumption that
any caste is going to be a pervasive or
very common no addressing mechanism for
dot servers is am i misunderstanding
that because there's all this talk about
any caste no well it's it's it's only
for the simple reason but that's if you
read the ducts architecture or there's
any confusion it is message there ok so
um and earlier many me you know means
ago we talked about the fact that
initially you know while you know dot
says on its initial adoption curve that
number one explicit local configuration
whether that's manual or whether it's
via some kind of provisioning system is
going to be we anticipate being the
overwhelmingly you know pervasive way of
configuring dots clients to to tell them
which servers to communicate with I I
would break number one out so that we
don't lump all those different things
together because you know these
different mechanisms here actually in
the draft they are separated into
billets different the static one on the
other one to dynamic one with the cheapy
and so on yeah
yeah so I won't go into details how all
these mechanic the specification of - if
your option dismiss regression or all
the other tools which you can find more
details on in the draft and this is my
last slide slide sorry - to have some
discussion on the only draft and how to
proceed for the next step don't say
sorry discussion is good so comments I
see two people coming to the mic oh we
have a minute
so shoot away please be brief entity
communications so our previous slide
please okay yeah as an implementer we
would like to keep those clients simple
so we'd like we don't like to make it
masked to follow those implementations
in order to make keep it simple excuse
me I'm just cutting the line out rolling
because we have to keep moving we have
one one other presentation here yeah
yeah and this is why the texture is
clear you may implement there is no
recommendation to implement all the
steps there okay anyway yeah that's that
we can take the language to to see how
we have it really the recurrence from
but the intent is not imposed as you
implement all the steps and all the
mechanisms that's that's at least the
current state of the draft that it's
dependent discussion we will update that
to - and to reflect it okay Martin arson
and cocl so this may be out of ignorance
because I'm pretty new to dots but is
there any mechanism foreseen for
bootstrapping trust because otherwise
like doing automatic discovery and then
doing
out-of-band or manual confirmation of
trust seems a bit of them well and why
wouldn't you fear it yeah
this is really a very good point and we
have that effect in the Hindi draft that
we for the the cpu's case what we are
considered as we are leveraging on
existing the practice we have result for
sip server services and so on is that
the the trust is is manufactured with
UCP so you have this shipped when you
have the device which is manufactured by
the provider but if you are in other
situation in which you you cannot allow
such practice what we discuss in the
Security section of the document is that
you can use the risk i which is the
anima and you must have to to discover
and to establish to establish the trust
automatically but to do that you need to
start from the name of the server and
then to run all the authentication
afterwards so we had both which is
discussed in the draft and if you read
it you find this kind of details there
this is really a great very good finding
does it need a second answer book look
at we should look at net carbs
zero-touch which also comment on it and
say does Netcom zero-touch give us
anything
although razorba networks on there needs
to be some some good discussion with the
architecture and requirements folks
about all this yeah okay thank you we
are still on track and moving and thank
you very much for this presentation very
interesting and the last presentation
and I apologize for being a little bit
rude on Bob when he inserted ok thank
you please ok hello everyone so I will
present the last evolution of our draft
so just to remind so the change so the
first initial idea was to use hot buy up
option in ipv6 so basically to store
information and then remember the
information and on path so we presented
a different place including of course
those up second six months so we
understand that even if we restrict
ourselves to the let say in trudeau
menus case I mean some issues
so it's not recommended actually with a
new version to use it and to have a new
proposition so our proposition basically
no we want you to keep the original ID
of where and when we come with ipv6
which originally was 12
let's say a safeguard mechanism where
you are not able to reach from the desk
E&Z that server to a signal the attack
so we want you to keep this original ID
but we so in these versions we want
don't want to necessarily add new to a
new protocol like we proposed before
what we need anyway in watch is similar
to what ratified to have something it's
synchronous meaning that we don't in
this oxygen americanism so I really want
to emphasize that it's not be used as a
first mechanism for signaling it just a
ways that for instance in Pachuca in
case for example if you use it a bit you
don't realize that the client is not
responding in can retrieve soft
information so we want basically to have
this kind of repository where so that
doc playin can infirm the servers as a
resident can retrieve information so
let's say it's a it's a bit different
that for example as you go to it's
similar but in the sense here we want
something where we can put some
persistent informations even before the
attack I mean meaning in the case where
the clients maybe maybe realize it it's
an attack but it's not confirm yet can
push some informations that if the
attack occurs in the client is not able
to signal the attack afterwards the
sûreté can still retrieve some
information that can get critters and in
finish and as I say it's independent of
the boss protocol between the client and
the repository that we call now and from
the successor and by the case that's it
for me I just yeah I want to hear
something back and son Roland diamond
server networks a question so um in
terms of you know resiliency of the
communications channel one of the
recommendations would be to have the
actual dots communicated
take place out-of-band right on an
out-of-band connection of course a lot
of folks won't do that right
but given that that's one way you know
to ensure the communications you know do
have a clear pathway between the client
to serve client server what is the value
of having an additional in band
auxiliary channel what is the value of
that I mean the is easy the proposal ear
is a is a mode to have an image from an
ocular point of view as well to have
some humor can let's say put information
in the persistent way I'm still not sure
I follow because again if I want to
ensure that the communications channel
is available and clear I establish a
completely parallel and AB in
communications channel write
communications path right for dots as
this being discussed today in the
architecture draft so why would I want
to use this specific mechanism for an
additional auxiliary signaling mechanism
in the in band path I don't understand
that I mean in the sense that in the
case of the attack the current may not
be a bit even to send again it's a
single information but some information
is already stored in the repositories at
the Zurich and which so maybe the client
basically now is the case of the kind
it's completely isolated the Sarika
still retrieve some information okay
thank you
so if I could ask a clarifying question
so just that is that a new use case to
talk about yeah not now but I think I'm
kind of so Toby has gone wrong Bob a
working group chair hired off
I'm also confused a little bit it's like
I can see maybe I want to upload
information to a server in case I'm
going death or silent yes I can see that
I'm not quite clear on the but this
student is my own stupidity I'm not
quite clear what's the benefit of
uploading it somewhere else instead of
uploading it to the server
and so I'm not grasping what what you
try to solve maybe you can enlighten me
so yeah so the original am I really so
it let's say Z Z original idea that we
have is that for instance - let's say I
have these informations that you
multiply different places that you can
still retrieve and I don't know if the
server in my opinion should be only be
let's say to say reach are requested
when you're really need mitigation it's
what I understand but so may I comment
on that okay okay so like we have a
relationship client-server situation and
maybe I have more than one yes in which
case I would inform all the servers yes
okay if I go silent do this so I don't
see a strong need to have another
repository of which I'm not sure that
the other service will see it if
something goes wrong so I'm not I can
see this is interesting when I'm I'm I'm
not so seeing it as a strong requirement
personally again to be asked when I'm
working group chair chair head off okay
all the diamonds are more networks I'd
really like to see discussion at this in
detail the benefits and how it's on
visage to work on the mailing list thank
you okay thank you
so this brings us to the end of our
formal formal agenda
so just to recap where we stood based on
all the discussion going through the
architectural eustachian requirements
document we were tentatively thinking
that we would be able to go to work
call what we heard during the design
team meetings and through this session
is that we need at least one more
version across all three of those
documents to to consider ourselves done
so not declaring working last call
there's issues to kind of work out but
please bring issues if you have them to
the mailing list we got requirements
from the hackathon that may suggest
changes those things should be come
through as well and then overall we need
to think about based on what Kathleen
was suggesting how we might want to be
packaging kind of those documents we've
talked about it before and we can bring
up that topic again adding one note I
think the perception from looking at the
documents progress the requirements
draft seemed to be closest to working
good last call so if you have issues
with it
please post them within the next two to
three weeks because like by that time I
could imagine that we might come close
to they have closed everything other and
then we would initiate working group
called for the requirements first so if
you have something for that please close
it very very timely for the others as
well
but just so you have a feeling about
like the steps sorry and I know well the
diamonds are where networks we're going
to schedule an interim meeting between
now in Singapore so my next bullet was
we will absolutely hold an interim
reading we've been finding them to be
very successful so we'll put something
on the calendar not half way between now
and and Singapore if there's a desire
for design team meetings in between that
or multiple interim meetings kind of let
the chairs know the shares know we can
kind of figure it out but again
somewhere halfway between now in
Singapore which historically was October
early October or late September yeah
sorry current best practice experience
would be one into a meeting between two
buy it yes otherwise I think it's a
little bit overloading yeah and the last
thing to point out is we saw five
interested parties for the hackathon we
will not name them we're very excited
that there are five
we would like to plan kind of that that
will start the discussion before the
interim meeting about what we might do
because experience suggests that there's
can only time about scoping and
preparing what will be done to make that
time most most productive so if you did
not voice yourself as one of those five
please please kind of let us know we be
excited to have more so with that to us
anything No thank you very much
everybody for coming
great great presentations and so we will
see you all in Singapore thank you and
have a good evening
bye oh and last thing remember bits and
bytes there will be a presentation of
the dots implementation and blue sheets
who has who has not signed blue sheets
yet can you move the blue sheets over to
the people okay please thank you thank
you everyone