yeah it's good thanks
Vonnegut before we get started we would
need a minute particular I'm looking for
volunteers so someone - it's a great
opportunity for any of you who happen to
be actively involved in this little trip
before to join you
until cookie at some of the other places
we really am looking for volunteer to a
minute makeup okay we have a Java
scratch that and we need to big job of
making like only to make take our home
there's any little template okay
rewarding not they audience
is this all
first session keywords
[Music]
this meeting is under a denote well
since you said that if you see or you
write is under your software ears that
proposed agenda and a beta he gives you
SEC PCL we put previously a you know a
free transfer discussion there but we
found that in anyway forgiveness passed
in the first application by step so
essentially it's definitely remove this
then that I can remember this during the
first invasion by staff who shoots in en
PMA architecture enough any change
[Music]
Eadie's pointed out that he doesn't have
new slides for the asynchronous
management architecture presentation he
basically wants to cover some of what he
would like to propose so I don't really
hasn't done any new slides because we've
done all the slides for 30 seconds there
so we should be very short pieces most
of us are familiar with what in for
voting anyway so it's more the
discussion and
look we need a minute taken I'm going on
Vicky thank you very much okay so I was
looking at the mile stones yeah okay so
if you look at the DTM data track though
you can see that we have a set a
milestone for Joe charted items and of
the work that is currently actively in
progress apparently we were going to
finish 50-50 place and TCP CLV fall by
December 2016 now obviously that hasn't
happened these milestones aren't fixed
in stone
they're aspirational but obviously we
are slipping on this and the face the ad
they like to point out that this is a
surprise to him for some reason the main
point of this slide is not to say oh my
god were slipping on this it's it's the
point out that these are key items that
we're still working on and there is some
pressure to make progress because if you
look at the next slide these are some of
the other items that we have on the
Charter that are are hanging waiting for
the core building blocks to complete so
there is some pressure to the primary
authors and the working group to really
get going back on slide
RFC 5050 base TC it's the Barbie we have
a wavy main projector for noticin and we
need to get 50/50 base and TCP CLV floor
done they feel in lasts more once
they've dropped out of last wall and
lighter changes at the working group and
the main author team have wanted to make
which is fine we do need to get these
finished so that less of a demand on the
or between it's more of a demand on the
rest of the work
really please have a look at these
documents give them an even a a light
review I'm looking at some of the
younger guys in the room which one of
the old hands and say have read if
there's stuff you don't understand if
you could if you don't see why it's
there please ask it may be an omission
then may be a valid reason for it but a
good bit of discussion on this is
productive at this stage and then we can
put it back up the RFC view and really
get these moving the other two items at
the bottom of slide has to be obviously
stop is going to talk about the sticking
out of trust to be out of the 450 15 s
that what I can imagine we'll take a
compare amount of time this morning and
the other thing that came up over the
last two meetings was bundled security
protocol is relevant in this context it
may not be applicable to all the users
of undal protocol there are those out
there who want some way of securing
bundle protocol and it without it I
think we would get serious questions
from the IES three of the why're you
releasing a protocol that cannot be
secured in a standard way
okay I'm sure Scotty and look it's not
moving at this point I'm sure there will
be ways that we can say you can encrypt
your payload and the fumbling bundling
capsulation will give you an 20
encryption of the lightweight encryption
but in the same way that IPSec helps IP
or works alongside IP the proposal is
that under security protocol acts other
than the B team set into the name so
that is another critical early delivery
from from this working group though and
given its security related that needs
some federal review if there needs to be
some visible comment on that document I
know it's being reviewed in other places
from the IDF but we do need to good
feedback from the IDF themselves
otherwise if this started after the
security groups they'll say okay you say
it's been reviewed we see no evidence of
that we see no no chatter on the working
group mailing lists about this so this
is a visit
Niq leading with loading Roman roads on
the audio stream amazing alert alert
please can you have a good look at you
can say and 50 50 beds empty CPC out
these are the next items charter items
that we have not really started working
on I know there's various within the
room who have opinions and some ideas
and labor discovery have knocked up
draft so far on things like key
management have you managed ETA Mises
and I know it's gonna speak about an
architecture he's had pick around for a
while
there's also addressing enough in a
wider scope howdy how do we handle
multiple addresses for multiple DTN
domains are we going to try to force a
single naming scheme there's a pinging
circulating on this but they all need
really be the bits finished
we need the basic building blocks in
place so that we can build on them so
yeah they've got early 2017 dates it's
not happening but you need to be aware
that these are milestones that you have
to deliver but does anyone have any
comment about the fact that we are
delayed
okay
Schiaparelli just one point that I will
bring up now and not emphasized later on
which is that bundles and Bunnell
encapsulation and VP SEC are not
alternatives bundle mone encapsulation
security depends on VP SEC existing so
it's it's not like it it it's supplants
it in any way
DP SEC is required in any case it's not
good though it still is great I can see
test it okay it's on good okay thank you
okay good okay okay okay good all right
thank you
I'm Scott Burley I'm here to talk about
a couple of things the latest draft of
the beef abyss specification and and as
as part of that a discussion of custody
transfer and and a way that we might
separate custody transfer from from the
bundle protocol itself so next slide I
think this is the the only slide on on
BP is which is essentially that the
seventh draft of the specification was
posted in middle of June I believe that
this draft reflects whatever we had
reached in a way of consensus on all the
comments that have been received on the
sixth draft except that there are still
needed to be authoritative references to
the CRC specs because I was I was
unsuccessful in running down good
references and anybody who is able to do
that I think there was some traffic on
the net about some possible references
and I'm happy to take that and
incorporate that into the spec and just
an oversight I stupidly failed to move
the CRC to the end of the canonical
block header and that was just an
oversight that I will fix that also I
think there were a couple of small
comments that came in on on the email
list
in the last couple of weeks and those
I'm quite happy to incorporate so at
this point I believe the the sevenths
are after the BP piss Peck is reflects
everything that we had agreed on in
addition to that it reflects what I
think is a was a tentative agreement to
extract custody transfer from the bundle
protocol spec itself and and define it
in a separate document there are a
couple of ways that we've discussed
doing that one is retaining custody
transfer as as an extension block and
and as a set of modifications insertions
that would go into the bundle protocol
specification itself in several places
and I think three or four months ago we
posted a sample draft of how we might do
that
sometime after that draft went out it
occurred to me oh I think I've got a
better way of doing it I think we could
do it you know simpler and I think more
powerful way if we combine custody
transfer with bundle and bundle
encapsulation and and do it as
essentially a a new reliable convergence
their protocol and so I'll talk about
that for a few minutes next slide this
idea went out in a draft that I posted
under my own name rather than the
working group name because it's really
it's just me thinking out loud at this
point and the idea is move custody
transfer out of bundle protocol and
standardize bundle and bundle
encapsulation and and make custody
transfer a feature of bundle and
bundling capsulation since the idea of
making
custody transfer reliable convergence
layer protocol entailed encapsulating in
bundles anyway and it dawned on me I
want to combine the two things I think
there are a number of advantages in
doing that and I'll come to those in a
moment
so in this formulation custody transfer
would be an optional feature of
capsulation and once again turning the
ibe into a reliable convergence layer
protocol along the lines of TCP CL and
LTP that would be able to operate over
disrupted links which which I believe no
other reliable convergence they are
protocol that I know of can do it's this
is potentially very useful next slide so
the advantages of of this approach one
is that the the I think what what I'm
aware of is as the key benefit of
custody transfer is is preserved by by
doing this and I've not been a great fan
of custody transfer for some time the
there are a number of reasons for that
the the the one is that custody transfer
reliability relies on retransmitting the
entire bundle no matter how big it is
rather than portions of the bundle and
another is that that retransmission is
driven entirely by expiration of
timeouts and the the timeout interval is
something that is I will argue
impossible to calculate in the RFC 50/50
world because custody transfer it no
node is required to take custody
transfer so you don't know which node is
supposed to acknowledge it so you have
no idea how long it'll take for the
bundles to reach that node and come back
again so any
thing that you do in in in in custody
transfer an IRC 5050 in terms of
retransmission is is by definition you
know less than then efficient it'll
always we transmit either too early or
too late because you can't do it
accurately I think that for these
reasons I've been saying for a long time
just use reliable convergence there are
protocols instead and I think that is
still the case but Keith Scott has made
the point a number of times that there
are use cases where nothing but custody
transfer can do the job because the
there there is no reliable convergence
there protocol available for some of the
use cases he's been looking at you
really need a reliable converters there
a protocol that handles transmission
over inter directional and possibly
disrupted links and nothing but custody
transfer does that so the this work is
an attempt to reconcile those two I
think two entirely valid points of view
and let me recognize your God who has
something to say at this point yeah your
I have a semi semantic question yes it
occurs to me that TCP in the especially
when you look at the end to end model of
the internet secures bytes on the wire
but doesn't do anything how they are
being handled at the receiver side so
it's a reliable transfer it's not a
reliable pick up storage and whatnot and
so so comparing custody transfer which
also says something about durability in
the receiver side storage may be
marginally or subtly different from
transport semantics and just wondering
whether you are taking those two
semantic aspects apart or whether you
are intentionally or unintentionally
mingling them a bit I
so it takes some some discussion to
exactly narrow this down but I will I
think argue that the approach that I'm
advocating here unifies those those
those two concepts that it that it
provides depending on how you implement
it it provides security on a hop by hop
basis and provides a reliable
transmission that is compatible with
that security but also and so it also it
is supposed to guarantee us that you're
going to have enough space ever having
received something reliable and keep it
so I'm not worried about the security
yeah I read about the the reliability
part in storage so if you get the next
bundle you and if you have taken custody
you can't evict it and drop it on the
floor because you have taken custody
where is just the fact that you have
received something reliably completely
and so on still would allow you to drop
it and this is the semantic difference
I'm wondering and I just well I'm not
saying that this is bad to combine the
two I'm just wondering whether this is
happening in intentionally whether we
should spell this out jail I'm inclined
to think we should spell it out clearly
right and I think I think that that
there is that implication and and I
think we should confront that
implication and and and and make sure
that we understand the what what would
evolve from that I mean I think we need
to be aware of it absolutely right so so
this this first point on this slide is
again thinking in terms of the many
conversations that the Keith and I have
had on on custody transfer and how he
has use cases that absolutely need it I
believe that this formulation preserves
that capability that is
the idea here is that when you what when
you've got a portion of the into NDT and
network path that cannot be traversed
successfully by any any of the reliable
convergence layer protocols that we've
defined so far tcp CL or LTP or others
that that encapsulating the bundle in
another bundle whose destination is the
the convergence layer next hop provides
that capability it enables the the
transmission on on that that segment of
the path to be unidirectional in in each
direction to follow different paths and
and for the the the transmission between
the two to be over links that are
intermittently connected and possibly
very long delay so I think that's that
that's the number one advantage I see is
that the the advantages of custody
transfer are retained in context that I
think makes sense in the overall DTN
architecture the second advantage that I
see is that removal of custody transfer
from bundle protocol and substantially
simplifies bundle protocol and
simplifies implementations there will be
potentially some implementations that
would not want to support custom
transfer and and or might might want to
not support it initially but add it
later on and I think this structure
supports those those kinds of
implementation efforts I'm thinking in
particular of hardware implementations
or firmware implementations where the
complexities of custody transfer might
be difficult to support at least in
in an initial round of FTA is that sort
of thing the the interface I think is is
quite clean here in that the the the
bundle and bundle bundle and bundle
encapsulation protocol is is a
self-contained I think well structured
specification within which custody
transfer operates but without relying on
inserting any new procedures into bundle
protocol itself the the end points of
the custody transfer are our
functionally convergence layer end
points even though they happen to be
bundle protocol end points it's it's
tunneling an advantage I think that is
less obvious is that we've been thinking
about bundling bundle encapsulation for
a long time as a mechanism that supports
an additional layer of security for in
particular security against protection
against traffic analysis and that's
because the the encapsulated bundle can
be encrypted as the payload of the
encapsulating bundle and the destination
of the encapsulating bundle can be you
know anything at all and something
innocuous and once it once the bundle
reaches that that interim destination at
that point it can be extracted from the
encapsulating bundle and and routed to
its real destination you know safe part
of the internet we're not worried about
traffic and analysis next slide
something that I had not expected when I
started trying to write this into the B
IBE spec is that it simplifies custody
transfer itself there is no need to deal
with the partial custody transfer
procedures that
we talked about at the last meeting that
methought about it over or a longer time
and had been in lurking in custody
transfer in RFC fifty fifty all along
that it was always going to be a huge
problem if there were fragmentations of
custodial bundles on the end and paths
we had no way of dealing with it it just
wasn't even considered in RFC fifty
fifty and one way or another is going to
be a huge problem well this makes that
go away because if there's fragmentation
between the source and destination of
the convergence layer of bundle and
bundle encapsulation transmission that's
not a problem because the by definition
the the bundle has to be we assembled
from fragments at the destination and no
matter what what the fragmentation was
the bundle that is going to be
acknowledged in in in a custodial
acknowledgement is the entire bundle we
assembled from whatever fragmentation
happened on the on that that short path
and again there's there's no need for
any special procedures in forwarding
nodes that don't want to take custody
because the forwarding nodes that don't
want to take custody are just forwarding
those the custody is is only happening
at the source and destination
everything else that happens to be in
between they're forwarding there's no
expectation that they they can or need
to or or even will take custody of the
bundle only the source and destination
are of the custodians it's compatible
with multi point delivery which has
always been an issue in custody transfer
and RSC 5050 the look through our see
5050 and and and it will say everywhere
that multi-point delivery of custody
transfer is undefined
well there's good reasons for that right
because if you if you go with the the
original RC 50/50 definition of custody
transfer if there were multiple possible
custodians custody acknowledgments would
be received from multiple places and the
current custodian would have no way of
knowing which ones are sufficient to
authorize deletion of the the bundle
that has taken custody of it the there
there might be multiple possible
custodians that that refuse there might
be multiple possible considering this
that receive it and don't say anything
at all and the the current custodian has
no way of knowing anything about how
many copies it needs to resend in in
this formulation that goes away entirely
because if there's a multi point
delivery then each of those points each
of those neighbors that you would
forward the bundle to can be a custodian
you you send it custodial e over over
because convergence layer hop that
happens to be bundle protocol called the
ib e and and each one of those
transmissions is a separate custodial
transaction and and is booked kept
because individually in the
implementation so suddenly we gain the
ability to do custody transfer through a
multicast tree because each of the
branches of the multicast tree is its
own custodial transmission one more
point I think this is the last one is
that several years ago a visiting
researcher at JPL worked out procedures
for bundle delivery time estimation
based on contact plans the contact the
the basis for contact graph routing in
the in the ion implementation of DT N
and that that work was was published
there's still think more things to do
along that line but I thought that at
the time that that was a very promising
way of getting a plausible idea of how
long it would take for a bundle to reach
a destination and over a range of
probabilities and and and that in turn
is I think a a plausible way of of
estimating the the round-trip time for a
custodial transmission and and and given
that this approach offers the promise of
reasonably efficient custodial
transmission because the round-trip time
may be something that you can estimate
with some accuracy which we never could
do before and the key to that is that
the next custodian is the destination of
the encapsulating bundle you know who it
is you can estimate how long the bundle
will take to reach that destination so I
think there's a lot of attractive
features to this formulation Nick's line
there are a couple of disadvantages that
that I think we all need to be aware of
and and and spend some time talking
about one is there is a little bit of
extra overhead because you encapsulate
the the original bundle in in another
bundle and that means that there's a
another header primary block and
extension blocks but onto the front of
it I'm very sensitive to overhead we
care about that a lot in in in
spaceflight operations communications we
don't have an awful lot of spare
bandwidth but even even given that I
would say as long as the bundles are not
tiny the the additional overhead is as a
tolerable cost
I think the advantages are compelling
enough to to motivate using this
formulation even when there's a concern
about overhead and the other is and I'm
sure this is
I'm accompanied in discussion there the
the key difference between custody
transfer in this formulation and and in
Narsee 5050 is that you must know in
advance who the next OD is going to be
you because that's the destination for
the encapsulating bundle I I think that
there's been a sense for some time that
there were important use cases that
where that was not the case and I and
I'm certainly I think we need to talk
about those my own personal expectation
is that in realistic operational use
cases you pretty much always know who
you want the next custodian to be I
think in all of the the use cases that
Keith has identified for example the the
next custodian is known it may be two or
three bundle hops away but but you know
you do know who you want it to be if you
genuinely don't know who you want to
take custody then again I will argue if
you don't know who you want to take
custody then you have no way of knowing
when to be transmitted and and in that
case I I think it's I think I would
argue that the potential impact on never
performance is I would say not
acceptable but that's a that that's my
own personal opinion on it I would say
that opportunistic forwarding is not
necessarily incompatible with this
formulation because in opportunistic
forwarding I will I will propose that
the next custodian is always the
neighbor right you discover a neighbor
and you want to do custody transfer out
to the destination great the next
custodian is the neighbors you've just
just discovered if they don't want to
take custody then it's not clear that
you want to send them a copy if you if
you want to send them a copy any way you
can and and in that event
you maybe don't want to turn on the
custodial retransmission switch I think
that the advantage of being able to do
somewhat reliable custodial
retransmission by knowing the who the
next custodian is and knowing the
round-trip time on that basis outweighs
the advantages of being able to operate
in an environment where the next
custodian is unknown I think that's the
end of my slides and so any questions
well oh within a DTN network many
nodes say node 1 2 or 3 4 node 4 is
destination node 1 is the source and I
know that from node 1 perspective know 2
& 3 are custodians all right
and they're possible additional nodes in
between okay so when node 1 does that it
will address to know to ask us to do
write it in the destination of the
encapsulating bundle right I would say
if it if it knows that node 2 and node 3
our positions are potential custodians
yeah that it could address the
encapsulating bundle to node 3 and and
have it go directly that way okay and
and not expect custody to be taken by
node to its vault because it's won't be
addressed right right right right right
and and but then I think that's that
that's a an operational option but that
you need sort of do it either way okay
but then if it's a you know for it well
but you
said summarizes they only have really
one pursuit in my network but if I want
to use many because I mean it's a very
unreliable path and it may take forever
between whatever for whatever reasons my
question is how does so no two will
actually D capsulate Andrea encapsulate
right yes so how does node one tells no
2 no 3 is the next one or it doesn't
know well ok so I think it's two answers
to that one is it can be argued that it
should not tell node 2 that right
because right because its source routing
and maybe that's not a good idea the
other is that if it really wants that to
happen and and I think we should thank
Lord wood for pointing this out on the
email list you can do that right because
node 1 could encapsulate capsulate the
original bundle in a bundle that isn't
in it that is whose destination is node
3 and then take that and encapsulated in
a bundle whose destination is no - so
you can you can do the source path
routing if you want to it's probably not
a good idea but but but if you want to I
think you can do it that way okay so
that means unless you do that kind of
trick it's kind of a a buy up custodian
thing yep that's right
yeah but but I think that's why a system
depending on the knowledge of the right
Zaca seed into the next one right and I
think that's okay that in itself is is
consistent with what RFC 5050 right you
could you could have multiple custodial
hops on the end and path and and you can
still do that the the difference in in
this formulation is you need to you need
to determine in advance who the
custodians are any top John that'll um
thanks Scott really interesting my
initial reaction of oh you want to psych
Casta transfer out of 50 50 bits great
put it in bundling bundle not convinced
but you make some interesting arguments
there do you in in in the world of
opportunistic forwarding I'm keen to be
able to move custody in more than one
direction yes so sort of multipath
absolutely yes do you think that this
supports multipath custody tracks I
think it absolutely does yes and I would
say it does that because suppose you're
sending four different copies right you
send one opportunistically and you may
not think you may not get there may or
may not so you so you hold on to the
bundle and you're going to send it again
the next discovered neighbor on each of
those transmissions to each of those
neighbors as you discover them I would
say on each one you would do a custodial
bundle bundle encapsulation transmission
to that to that custodial node and and
that node itself then would extract the
encapsulated bundle from the
encapsulating bundle and could determine
on its own whether the next hop on on
its path to the destination needed to go
over a bundle encapsulation or it could
just be sent over some other reliable
convergence their protocol okay thank
you and thus last one and you said a
couple of minutes ago that I recently
had this in my head as though all nodes
of the network need to support custody
transfer I think you mentioned a couple
of minutes ago that you could send more
than one bundle hop away and get the
distant mode to accept custody - yes is
that correct that's I would say that's
correct yeah absolutely
okay there the the intervening bundle
hops would not be custodial that the
transmission between those might very
well be reliable the custody signal
would come from the the destination of
the encapsulating bundle okay thank you
Rick Tyler and thanks Scott I like this
for two reasons first off there's always
been a danger in my mind that 5050 base
with custody transfer inside became very
close to routing and there's always been
a sense in the in in the working group
that fifty-fifty should 50/50 base
should be about transport and not really
touch on routing because it's a pretty
open research area in places I think
we've got some ideas of how it might
work coming out of the the research
group and so I like the fact that the
separation of custardy Transfer had a
50/50 base kind of puts custody transfer
and it's almost routing into its own
document the other part I like is
bundling bundle is gonna happen and so
we may as well define it properly
somewhere I agree completely any I know
there's been a lot of pushback about oh
we don't need tunneling it adds overhead
but people are going to tunnel so let's
define it so I'm I'm in favor of the
separation and actually describing both
thanks
hang on yeah John Darrell as JavaScript
adds asking a question at brain in VP
second we had difficulty with security
destinations because it presupposed
routing information if you select a
custodian that is more than one hopper
way will we run into the same problems
as when we try to define security
destinations alright that's a fair
question I think we don't the reason I
think we don't is that because we're
doing this is because at the convergence
layer the the the route from the the
current custodian the local custodian of
the bundle and the next custodian can be
entirely defined by the routing protocol
right the the the the route that it if
you're going from from A to D and and
there are bundle routes bundle nodes in
between the convergence there protocol B
IBE does not know or need to know
anything about the the specific nodes
along the route that can be handled
entirely by the routing so it's it is a
little bit sort of brain bending because
it is bundle protocol at both levels but
I but I think it avoids the the the the
problem that we very properly I think
identified and reacted to in the in the
BSP specification that is the the the
the convergence layer transmission is is
something that we already have in in the
in the architecture I think it's a clean
separation between the what essentially
is is end to end at the convergence
there and and the route that it the
bundle takes to get from one end to the
other at the convergence layer
and I jump in there sorry regulator and
I seem to remember during the discussion
about the removal of security
destinations in EPP set one of the
reasons given for removing it was we
could do this with bundling bundle
encapsulation I think sort of
self-fulfilling prophecy
I think that's exactly right I think
that that's there was part of the idea
of bundle bundle encapsulation from the
beginning precisely
okay next question stop are you asking
for funding for the encapsulation to be
to be accepted as working group document
if if the sense of the room is that this
is ready to go then I think we should go
ahead with it because we're you know
time is is ticking along if if we need
to spend another cycle talking about it
first
before everyone is comfortable with it
I'm fine with that
either way is okay you want to explain
the employee would you like a chance to
ask you sense of the world and I kinda
maybe there's a I personally believe
that this idea is mature and I don't
know of anything that I would want to do
on it in the next four months I think
it's ready okay so the room has actually
read this deal okay all those who read
it how many don't you think this is
ready to be accepted as a working great
document in you'd like to start to their
way and rethink it obviously that's a
very low number so we're gonna take this
foolish
[Music]
so anyone listening to the audio screens
please get on the list as soon as you
get a chance
ie money to actually daylight wherever
you are and raise any objection because
and obviously we will get that on the
list but within the room but I as a
chair I think this is probably yeah John
daddle um just a point of order really I
suppose so as you mentioned just now I
think somebody's going to do but gonna
want to do bundling model anyway
personally I think this is worthy of
working group adoption anyway
question is does it have to be
absolutely perfect before the working
group adopter I would suggest not
perfect the question was is this yes
personally I think yes thank you
so next up we have a prey who is
hopefully able to remotely participate I
can see him on meet a co-ed with your
there can you try pressing whatever
button either involved with your end
okay I think press those buttons you're
very loud and very small Hey
yes maybe I can turn into being very
large and very quiet I don't think so I
think I'll need you to flip for me okay
hi my name is Ed borane I'll be
presenting the BP SEC updates this would
be the low five version of BP sac and we
talked about the O four version last
time we received a couple of comments in
the meeting and then I received a few
comments directly since the meeting some
got rolled in to the O five and some
didn't and I'll address the ones that
didn't get in before we had to upload
the latest version next slide
I'm not sure if the next slide is up the
mix Lloyd's offense or become incredibly
loud oh I'm sorry I I can try and speak
softly so I wanted to go through a
summary of VP Zack for those I guess
what I wanted to start with was to ask
who in the room has read the BP stack
document anything from oh four oh five
we have two three okay so let me start I
have a couple of slides of summary and
then the updates from oh five and then
the outstanding comments and then
addressing the cipher suites so if we go
to the next slide the next slide so the
so this summarizes the major points of
the BP SEC approach the first of course
is the motivation why do we feel we need
a BP SEC protocol BP SEC is meant to be
an in bundle security mechanism what
this means is for the cases where
different blocks inside of a bundle need
different security services and this is
to try and recognize the fact that
sometimes not all blocks are put in a
bundle by a single source or when they
are put into a bundle by a single source
they may represent different kinds of
information and a classic example is a
case where a user would want a payload
block to be encrypted but may want other
extension blocks to only be integrity
signed so that others along a path could
look at them the reason we bring we
point that out is if you don't want in
bundle security there are other ways of
trying to secure BP of course users can
protect their own data at the
application layer and give cipher text
or payloads that have already been
capsulated using other standards for
example if a user was going to apply
something like CMS and generate a CMS
document if you will as the payload that
could be sent along and give
users and and application layer security
similarly and has got touched on earlier
users could select a secure convergence
layer protocol if they exist in the
network and also get security from that
perspective through a chain of trust so
BP sack is is meant to address the case
where the security is is implemented in
the bundle itself by the BPA not by the
users and not by the convergence layers
actually just a comments copper Lee and
I wanted to add an additional note on
motivation which is protection of data
at rest if you're doing multi hop
transmission and the data resides in in
in the bundle MO somewhere along the end
and path III will contend that it needs
to be secured while it's sitting on that
node rather than only while it's in
transmission between nodes
yeah well completely agree and and that
I believe is is in the spec I just
didn't pull it into these slides so if
we take that as sort of some of the
driving motivations for the document the
next thing the document talks about are
what are the design decisions around BP
sac the major ones that came out was of
course that different blocks in a bundle
can and should have different security
that the processing order of those
blocks at the various receivers must be
unambiguous and that we must be able to
add new cipher suites at future dates as
more come available next slide so so
then the the spec goes into what does it
actually mean to have security inside of
a bundle and to do that we use extension
blocks to house security mechanisms in
that we have a confidentiality mechanism
and an integrity mechanism we decided
some meetings ago not to have a separate
authentication mechanism there's a fair
bit of treatment in that in the document
and we've also made it a topic of at
least two or three
working groups in the past so for the
blocks that we define we have a block
format what we call an abstract security
block which was a concept kept from from
the original BSP and and that abstract
security block is recognizing the fact
that all of all of the two security
blocks that we use in this back while
the the BI be for block integrity block
and the BC be for block confidentiality
block have a fair bit in common they
both capture the list of targets to
which they apply they both capture sort
of that key information is part of
cipher suite configuration and they can
both hold extra data associated with the
results of applying the cipher suites
the block integrity block itself holds a
signature or signatures across the set
of targets that it applies to and the
confidentiality block notes that its
targets have had their block data
replaced with the results of an
encrypting cipher suite and the
confidentiality block may also carry any
additional results such as additional
authenticated text that that is beyond
just the cipher text that would be
produced by a confidentiality encrypting
cipher suite so then another interesting
part about the block format was we did
come back and make an optimization
several working groups ago that said an
individual security block can target one
or more other blocks in the bundle and
this was meant to capture the case where
if you if you made it a one-for-one if
you made a one for one mapping between a
security block and a single security
target you may have cases where multiple
blocks need to be signed or multiple
blocks need to be encrypted with the
exact same key information with the
exact same cipher suite parameters and
at that point you're just repeating
redundant information in the bundle and
it's far more efficient to simply have a
single security block that says the the
security controls and configurations in
this block applied to this range of
targets we did originally have a concept
of a separate CMS block in BP sack
through through significant
discussion in this working group and in
some other groups we said that that was
probably not something that we were
going to pursue in the core BP sac
document and we created a section that
said if other specifications wanted to
define new kinds of security blocks
there were certain considerations that
needed to be put in so that new security
blocks would be compatible and could
coexist with the security blocks in this
document finally there was a section of
block processing rules again determinism
is important here there were many cases
in the original BSP where we lost Turman
ism and we wanted to make sure that we
didn't have that issue again so there
were some rules there in terms of if a
BCP target is encrypted than integrity
on that target if there's integrity on
that target it must also be encrypted
bibs don't target B C B's or blocks
protected by BCPs to avoid circular
dependencies if you do those kinds of
things than at a receiver you can come
up with a strict processing order for
security blocks and that's something
that's helpful next slide and so then as
we finish up some of these we we come
back and say that we really don't want
to apply security directly to bundles
whose payloads represent fragments in
that case we would recommend some kind
of encapsulation mechanism such as bibby
if you want to turn that fragment into a
non fragment block by encapsulating it
implying security services to it and
then finally nodes themselves determined
by security policy if they are the
destination as we mentioned just prior
there were concerns if a source node
tries to assert a security destination
because that starts implying routing
decisions at the bpa layer itself it is
it is better to have the individual
receivers determine whether they feel
that they are the security destination
and should be processing these blocks
we've created a security considerations
area to this document which attempts to
list out the attack types we see in a
DTM
and mapping how BCB and vib apply in
these cases and then we also as part of
the security destinations make the
argument for why security policy should
be out-of-band configured in the network
and not included in the bundle itself
while confidentiality and integrity
blocks can be included in the bundle the
policy that says whether the block
should exist or shouldn't exist or if
they are existing what kinds of keys
should or should not always be used
that's dangerous to put into the bundle
because if you do go through a malicious
BPA and that BPA may drop blocks even if
a BPA can't resign or add new blocks or
intelligently modify blocks they can
certainly drop those blocks from the
bundle and if the blocks that are drops
or are ones that are carrying security
policy then the receiver
wouldn't have all the information
necessary to to handle the
implementation of its security policy so
that's a brief overview of the VP SEC
document for those who have not who have
not had a chance to read it or whoever
read some of the latest drafts what I
wanted to talk about next were just what
are the updates since the O 4 version
next slide please
so in general there were some minor
editorial cleanup through the sections
if you do a diff between a 4 and a 5 you
will see some some wordsmithing and some
correction of grammar the major updates
are in section 3.5 the block
representation we did add something that
was missing which is to really just
explicitly state you can't have
duplicate targets in a target list for a
vib we then added some an illustration
for both how we think cipher suite
parameters and security results as
fields would be represented in the
security block one of the things that we
and then we referred to section 310
which we talked about on the next slide
in terms of how those would be populated
next slide please
so on the when section 310 originally we
had put into the BP sac document the
list of the list of common security
cipher
parameters and result IDs and one of the
comments that we got back was really BP
sex should not be inventing their own
IDs for these things that there would be
other registries that we should try and
look at a Cosi was one that was brought
forward and I read through the cozy
documents and really it looked like the
the cipher suite parameters and the
result IDs were based on the cipher
suite itself and so that's what we tried
to adopt as a philosophy and BP sac
I've cut and paste the text of the
specification here but essentially what
it is saying is that a bi b or b c b
block must have something in it and as
part of the block format that says this
is the cipher suite that we are using
and then the parameters the key
information the result IDs that are
associated with that cipher suite the
identification of them how they are see
bore encoded how they should be
interpreted is really up to the cipher
suite definition itself and isn't
something that we would put as a
registry in BP sack next slide we
cleaned up some of the canonicalization
the canonicalization area for BP sack
it's noted that the primary block is now
immutable and therefore does not need a
custom canonicalization and additionally
really all of the non primary blocks can
be canonicalized just as they are in BP
bits with small exceptions the
exceptions being that when we are
canonicalizing for confidentiality then
we all include the block specific data
because that's the only data that is
turned from plain text into ciphertext
and then the other is we we choose not
to include reserved flags when we do
canonicalization for integrity or
confidentiality in the case that
reserved flags are not preserved or
somehow changed along a route
we removed the conformance section which
was section 11 in Oh for the the only
text of the conformance section there
was that some thought should be given to
authentication we didn't think that that
sentence or two really warranted a whole
section in the document for the IANA
considerations we will need a registry
for cipher suite identifiers and we do
need to allocate block types for bi b
and b c b and then we added a reference
for Co C at the end
next slide so so what we have presented
in terms of updates were the requested
the observed changes from the last
working group and from some review that
did not get to the list and I'm
encouraging reviewers to post to the
list after fo v was posted for this
working group we did get some additional
comments which I've listed here and I
think that author will also be posting
this week to the Tamilian list to start
the discussion not none of the issues
that came back were really particularly
significant there were there was some
discussion that says even the reduced
discussion in 310 about how cipher suite
parameters and results are stored would
be too much and couldn't be piece X
simply say that the the block in that in
that scenario is really opaque and then
it's completely up to the cipher suites
as to how they populate it and and is
the concept of cipher suite parameters
versus security results itself
presupposing a design of the cipher
suite and we can certainly look at that
the reason why I say that's minor is is
that the the the text that we have now
and BP sac relating to this area already
points to the cipher suites themselves
is providing the definitions on the
enumerations and the format of these
things the other is that there were a
couple of cases I counted 5 where we
felt that must is being overused and and
I agree with them and they're relatively
easy to change and then in section 8 to
2 and this is in the security
considerations area where we're
providing an analysis of
of BP sack in the context of certain
types of attacks there's an assertion
that sign in a crypt implies a certain
level of security strength essentially
that an attacker cannot successfully
modify a bundle if they cannot decrypt
the bundle and that if you really were
to split hairs there are some people who
would come back and say that's really
maybe not always the case
and instead maybe the appropriate
security verbage is that you require an
IND CCA - encryption scheme and and
there are some other text associated
with that which again we would put up to
the mailing list none of that actually
changes the protocol and it doesn't
significantly change the analysis but it
would be a correction of the assertions
that are made in the security analysis
next slide one of the things that was
brought up at the last working group was
that BP SEC could go forward in its
current form but would require at the
very least an interoperability cipher
suite and so I have posted a a draft
cipher suite that says here is a common
integrity and a common confidentiality
cipher suite that should be used for BP
SEC for interoperability we picked
something that was relatively simple not
certainly as simple as something like H
much sha-1 but H Mac sha-256 and AES GCM
128 are both common cipher suites
they're well known they are both
represented in cosy which means that
they also have a predefined sort of
representation and Seamore which would
also be helpful since these will be busy
extension blocks and VP biz is going
into Seaborg so that is a draft and we
probably aren't going to ask for that to
go into last call right now I think it
would be good to get some other eyes on
it but probably by the next working
group meeting I think it would be ready
to go next slide
so to sort of wrap up we really haven't
seen any significant concerns expressed
so far in BP SEC certainly moving from
four to five week we did address the
issues that we have so far the largest
remaining issue seems to be any
discussion on the common of whether BP
SEC says that Cyprus we parameters and
security results are simply opaque and
to be determined by the cipher suite or
whether it enforces a key-value scheme
and then just allows the cipher suites
to provide enumerate the keys and
provide the encoding of the values I
think we can probably resolve that
without much issue and then I think
probably by the next working group
meeting the interoperability cipher
suites which are out there in draft form
now would also be ready to go so that
that is that is the current status of BP
sac so at this point we're really not
aware of any significant issues that
would prevent this from going forward
[Music]
that's okay OS - Spenser Dawkins the
responsible area director and this one's
for Edie just making sure I understand
the reason you need a de registry for
cipher suites is because this is going
to be they won't be one this is the list
of the ones that are specific for BP
sick or is that writer yeah that was the
thought certainly there are cases where
we would point solely to existing cipher
suites but in our security
considerations area we mentioned that
the nature of DT ends particularly
things such as security at rest would
likely provide constraints or
recommendations to cipher suite
parameters specific to
in a DTM and that would probably mean
defining new cipher Suites okay so
that's next one answer I guess my next
one is probably for the work probably
for the larger working group when when
do you all expect to be sending this for
blast i TFS call share the working group
do does the room and by extension those
on the audio screen think this document
is ready for last call ed said he had a
couple of little mates who wanted to
sort out as part of last fall it needs
some more public review on the list but
I think that is aware of that and I know
some of these offers for viewers have
been asked to post their reviews on the
list of those in the room can I see a
hand if you've read this recently I
asked with three or four of them any of
you think isn't ready and that you would
have reservations on dad or is it worth
getting an early security ID review do
they do that sort of thing yes I believe
they do they absolutely do this mr.
Dawkins again and just as an
advertisement for this pretty much all
the review teams and directorates will
do review as requested so you don't even
have to know you don't have to wait till
you're close
we're transport is doing a review for a
six load document that the working group
is considering adopting but they want to
know what they're getting into
so so the the review teams are really
becoming a lot more helpful and a lot
less of a source of late surprises
a direct review absolutely chock-full
might be a good thing to save any
surprises we'll take the final question
on last nor to the list the only
question is the security guys who like
to see more comment on the list to show
that the working group
[Music]
just to cover our private conversation
um mark raises the point that one thing
that the cause BP SEC to drop out of
last fall like a stone is that if we
suddenly make a change to DP base be a
50/50 base so I'm looking at Scott and
given the 50/50 basis in law school and
the working group believes it's pretty
stable now we're fingers crossed that's
not gonna wreck the process of abuse
[Music]
ex-cop early at this point I do not
anticipate any changes to any
significant changes to be be dis there
may be some that I'm aware of but as far
as I know I think it's stable at this
point yet yeah apparently the chairs mic
wasn't working this now good lord
yeah apologies for those who could only
quietly hear me so next up a brain seat
boss if you're there edge so I'm gonna
push the red button to make you two
always gone thanks Brian
can you hear me
whatever time zone Brian is in I have to
press the red button what happens do I
just press the button
hello Brian we can see you sorry I press
it again okay that was my bad touch
anything okay so this presentation is
even shorter than the last
IETF one and it represents even fewer
changes and hopefully the final changes
for TCP CL before so next slide please
and I'm just going to discuss in here
changes since the last draft revision
which are very few and then hooked up to
questions actor so next slide please
so these next two I believe slides are
identical to last presentation and are
just included for background information
that the motivations and drive for this
updated TC PCL hasn't changed since it
was originally proposed and the point is
just to both simplify and correct what
was already a proven convergence layer
in TCP CL v3 so the next slide please so
we are continuing down the road of not
making any major changes to the workflow
of
TC PCL the current v4 workflow is
simplified there are fewer branches and
fewer options than in v3 we now have a
proposed new set of Ayana
registries for the type codes and region
codes before t CPC open for just two
completely separate them from v3 since
the registries themselves are easy to
create and it makes it more obvious that
v3 is B 3 and B 4 is before if somebody
is actually implementing both versions
they will probably notice that the codes
which I've shared semantics between the
two versions are numerically identical
in their proposed registries but they
are separate tables and since the
workflow of v3 is preserved there are
only a few additional types and codes in
those new proposed tables next slide
please
so edits since the last keep IETF have
been that there has been no change to
what's been written regarding the
transport security using TLS and it is
clarified that GL
is mandatory to implement as part of the
CL before but optional to use for any
particular session and it's negotiated
per session so it's a combination of the
two end points establish a session of
whether or not TLS is to be used as I
mentioned on the last slide we're
proposing separate IANA registries just
to keep the two namespaces independent
of each other and protocol extensions
have been added to the contact header
although the form of the extension is
defined in the CL spec no uses of the
extension are defined right now and then
the very last change is as a suggestion
off the working group the individual
message content headers have been
modified to make the fields octet
aligned which avoids bit backing and in
some cases avoids having unused flags or
certain types of messages so it's likely
and this is the last in the deck so all
of the comments to date at least I
believe have been incorporated into the
the current spec and this is good in
that there are no as far as I know open
issues but there is not as far as I've
read a lot of concurrence in the current
state so that's something to bring up
and another thing to mention although I
realize now that I omitted the link from
this presentation although the last
presentation does include it there is a
working implementation that's very in a
sense trivial just to prove out the
protocol itself but it is full-featured
and it is something that can be used for
interoperability testing and it's purely
convergence later it has nothing to do
with the agency so it's just getting
what we would call a bundle but there's
really two the big data from one end of
this session the other end thanks Brian
I think we got a question yeah John dad
I've got to say the second one in terms
of the TLS thing you say it's mandatory
to implement the optional sorry
optional to use Y optional to use if
it's mandatory to implement why not
Manchester to use that was brought up as
a question at the left IETF and there
were some strong objection to strong
objection from the point of view of I
believe the IETF I'm not sure what the
right phrasing is not best practices but
security practices that mandating the
use of TLS across the board is not not
the right way to go as far as getting
approval from the wider IETF I believe
in IHG the Rick Taylor chipping in on
this one and it's viewed as fairly
standard IETF practice to mandate TLS to
implement but obviously you can't
prevent somebody just choosing not to
use it so it's a good compromise
position and the protocol is that
provides a way to enforce the policy in
both directions from an endpoint so an
endpoint can either declare in the
contact header that it simply does not
support TLS and don't try to use it
because it's not going to work but
contrary to that there's also the case
where an endpoint can choose to say yes
I do support TLS and if the other side
of the connection doesn't then the
connection simply refused at the point
of contact
ideally all of the end points would be
set up to be cooperating brain can I ask
you to post a link to your Python
implementation if it's faster you're
you're willing to because that would put
put it on the mailing this to be really
handy yes thank you any other questions
security considerations section and it
was kind of ringing a couple of little
alarm bells to make something I'm
helping to do the same in another
working group and I kind of got the
feeling that because this is based on
another protocol we should somehow be
referencing the security considerations
and the other protocol ATT speeded and
what new security uses are arising from
the use of this extending effectively
ascending this thinnings tcp are you
offering to suggest some text John yes I
think I am okay it's in last call at the
moment okay so this document is in last
call I suggest that perhaps given we've
got some queries and John is gonna
suggest some text sure we hold this in
the last call for a little bit longer
hmm this is back to the milestones and
the we have lots of things lingering in
last call conversation I had read mark
earlier about the number of documents we
have in last call of course July August
is very difficult because everyone is on
vacation so putting it to well everyone
in quotes is everyone seems to be on
vacation
so if we were to say our standard
two-week last call then we push the
buttons
the concern is that a number of people
are currently or just about to disappear
on vacation so we're tempted for those
documents that are currently in last
call to suggest a sort of end of August
go ahead so that gives the documents
that are currently in last fall which is
BP BES BP sec oh no sorry Pisac is not
in last call yet tcp CL this is your
chance to comment through those final
reviews and then we'll get those buttons
pushed and get it moved into the review
queue for certain start in September
Scott Pearlie if we on the list
determined that the SEC was also rated
for last call could we add it with the
same end date I'd be happy with her well
we don't specify the end date we just
start we push it up the chain and then
it takes on a life of its own they were
all come in to come out of last call T
and start moving I agree that they they
probably will end up in sync at the very
end of the kid any other questions for
Brian or no thank you very much Brian
okay and I'll wait then comment
yeah comments to the list please so next
up we've got aired again we have the
same slides from Ed from last working
group he promises not to go through all
of them in great detail again he just
wanted to raise some questions about the
asynchronous management architecture in
detail and if you're there I'll let you
Karen okay I am here can you hear me yes
and the volume is appropriate now yes
okay
however I'm sorry what'd you say can you
make your window bigger you're in a tiny
do is that right there we go that's good
ok so hello this is that again I wanted
to talk a little bit about the
asynchronous management architecture the
reason the slides are the same is we
didn't update the draft from the O 5
version that was here at the last
working group because we have not of the
people who have reviewed this document
to date we've got no additional comments
saying that there's something specific
we wanted to change through the working
group we I did get a few emails this
week related to whether or not there are
things we wanted to add from a section
point of view but ultimately when we
started looking at network management
quite a long time ago we said that there
certainly a you know a set of standards
and ways of doing terrestrial network
management how was it different in a DTN
and the answer that we came back was the
asynchronous nature of this the the need
to bake into a network management
solution some level of automation and
perhaps some level of autonomy and the
asynchronous and and that sort of
captured in terms of how did you manage
a network asynchronously well you need
automation and autonomy to do that so
the AMA is is a capture of what we think
it means to manage a network
asynchronously the question from last
time from last working group was does
this document or could this document
satisfy the need for a set of network
management requirements for DTM or what
would need to be added to this document
to make it satisfy the requirements for
that so with that context I wanted to
briefly represent the materials and the
topics that are covered in this document
and then ask the question if there is
something missing from the materials
covered what would it be and could we
adopt
materials are add to this document in
the context of a working group item as
opposed to just an internet draft format
EDA I'll do that for a second chair
quick quick question to the room
how many here are completely unfamiliar
with the asynchronous management
architecture okay so one or two Eady
just because you've presented a lot of
this before can I ask you to keep this
very concise please because most here
are very familiar just what everyone's
time and effort I am happy to not talk
through any of the specifics if we
wanted to just go to a conversation on
do we feel there is something additional
that we would have to add to this
document to make it capture network
management requirements and could we do
that in the context of a working group
document I'd be happy as a chair to move
on to that I might refer those who
haven't read this document it is
actually well written and the slide pack
which is available in the meeting
materials is a good slide back so can I
suggest those who aren't familiar with
this catch up with it and probably we
jump ahead to a conversation two people
have opinions about this in class
management architecture Edie but well so
my opinion is that this to me although
as the author and biased is to come back
and say this this is what we felt
defines what it means to asynchronously
manage a network we didn't break out
requirements in terms of shell
statements but we did spend a fair bit
of time explaining desirable properties
constraints why we need asynchronous
mechanisms and what those mechanisms
should look like and what features they
need to provide and so I think from that
we could either add a set of specific
requirements and assumptions and
constraints or simply say that they are
inferred in this document there had been
a previous out of the IRT f network
management requirements document and
we could adopt portions of of that table
of contents the difficulty that we had
when we were writing that up in the
context of the IRT F if I recall was
that while we broke out different
architectures and different scenarios
because they looked different from a
physical standpoint many of them
collapsed similarly from a network
management standpoint and many of them
really came down to just needing that
kind of asynchronous management that
we're talking about here so in terms of
the things that make this document a
little bit different from the network
management requirements document I don't
know that we need whole sections on
architectures and whole sections on
system concepts beyond that which is
already in the AMA okay I mean Rick
Taylor but the lunch a ton personally I
think this is incredibly useful work
this is useful for my day job and also I
think it's intellectually interesting to
look at how do we manage disconnected
networks and it's it's an interesting
problem and also very useful to solve I
think we could spend an awful lot of
time wordsmithing the most perfect
architecture document but I think that
might be a waste of valuable effort I
would prefer to see the architectural
document being concise to the point and
fairly general as an informational
document without getting too caught up
in the minutiae and I think it's a lot
of it is there already and I obviously
need to do a good review of this
document rather than just critiquing it
at the mic but I personally I mean I'm
supporting it on this one I think this
is valuable document to people think
that from my perspective it has done a
lot of work on this already the IRT F
did a lot of work on this already so
we're not proposing burning a lot of
cycles creating new documents the
suggestion would be to adopt to this
document as it currently stands finish
it a little bit if required and then
it's a useful asset for for the working
group
yeah careful man where's Edward this is
a would be a target informational
document not a protocol document yeah so
informational yeah John that was kind of
my question I can see this ayah this as
an architecture document I guess
informational but what is the road map
for this topic now is there an intent to
go write another document that says this
is something you can conform to if we
looked at the trailer it says we cannot
work on a product call itself therefore
it would be either a recharger or
sending to someone else or so but I
guess we need to discuss ok Scott
beryllium I'm just speaking in support
of Rick's idea that we adopt this as a
as a working group item so expensive
Dawkins is responsible ad having some
familiarity with the Charter what I
thought that when I thought that text
meant was that you would not go into
business for yourselves and like say oh
we're gonna replace that comp or you
know something like that so so what I
was what I was wondering was whether you
would could be a would be able to do
like an applicability statement that and
this bit of proposed standards so you
know that's something that people can
perform to and stuff like that based
based on the architecture to occupy I'm
not saying that you should I'm asking if
people have thought about it and I'm
kind of saying if that seemed like a
good idea to you it would seem like a
good idea to me just to respond to that
I know ed and myself and various others
have been talking to the various neck on
for net mod groups talking to the
there's a seaborne light weight
management group that's kicking off I
can't remember their name at the moment
the point of this document is to say
here is a heir of the architectural
requirements specifically to DTN but
they have applicability outside of the
traditional DTN communities so we've got
some interest from some of the data
center guys to say well actually
asynchronous management starts to become
useful to us when data is moving so fast
that you you you can't consider it you
can't do stop the world anymore because
you you lose millions so yeah awesome
yeah so that you know most be delay
becomes relevant again so from my
personal perspective is yes this isn't
on the Charter at the moment but I think
this is relevant work whether it gets
done in this working group or whether it
gets done elsewhere or bits get done
here there and everywhere I see this as
a as a multidisciplinary effort not a
DTN reinvents management for them
because there's not enough of us and
we'll get it wrong and that you don't
have to so what what I'm like I say I
what the working group to decide what
the working group wants to work on
because that's what working groups do if
the working group decided they wanted to
head off on that direction and thought
it was the right thing to do I would be
supportive so they just have to have
that as a data point as you're having
the conversations mark I think part of
to me the answer of this is having at
least some drafts of what that would be
then we can discuss if you know then
this is Jefferson
Noby I think that there are some
specific parts of the the the old draft
didn't network management requirements
that maybe should be that would be be
merged on this one or the other option
is to to leave this work as a new draft
for the art
or in MRG team so you know I'm think
about the Spence I chose to do that so
if you're willing to suggest the
comments on the on the mailing list is
the best place to start
I mean if currently this is a personal
draft if we accept it as a working group
document then I think it's quite
legitimate to spend some time saying
well how much work do we want to put on
this are there ideas as you say that we
can bring in from my RTF or from other
groups
I see energy or or whatever and say well
actually we can use some of this and
spin into it into a nicer document
without reinventing the wheel law or
because I don't want to say the
informational RFC sound useful but I
don't want to I don't want given that we
have important things like BP base BP
Zack the you know these core technology
protocol stuff that we need to get
through I don't want to say oh let's
stick some more things on the working
groups desk and waste time on it but get
your ideas on the list see whether it
can be brought in if okay I'll just pull
it back how many people in the room
think the working group taking this
document on is a waste of our time and
we have better things to do so I'm
asking for the negative who doesn't
think this should be worked on in the
working group okay and then how many
people actively support this and are
happy to contribute comments and reviews
and good ideas okay so that's a that's a
pretty good for this group given I know
some people are sitting in just to see
what we're doing so obviously we'll take
that to the list as well just to confirm
but I think ed people are happy because
you can't see the content of the room
that this is a useful piece of work for
us and it is a charter item right mr.
Dawkins again so I guess the thing I
wanted to say on that was you're
observing correctly I believe that this
is you know this is not what DTM does
particularly
but if DPN was chartered to do this as
part of what DTN does it is it seems
more likely that you would get more get
people who are not participating in BTN
now and to work on this so you but you
may be looking at more than just the
people in the room to do you would be
the ones who would be you know doing the
work so you just to mention that this
this is something again I'm gonna be
sure and mentioned to the rest of the
isg in the IEP our Friday afternoon
session thank you thanks Spencer I know
following up from what I said earlier
Edie and I have been talking to Benoit
and some of the things the net mod
groups have been doing with what they
did call yang push but asynchronous
notifications and building on that we're
not talking about protocol definition at
this point we're told this document is
about describing the DTN perspective of
management how that is addressed may
well happen outside of this group but we
may have a little magic DT any bit as
part of a much bigger picture and I
think it is you're right beyond the
scope of this group to solve and to all
of that we can find a home for it at
some point
okay any other comment no no comments
for me thank you very much sorry Magnus
here so as chair trying to summarize
next action items we haven't
specifically as a room but I guess we're
deep abyss is going to another working
group last call given you know major
change structural change in it we would
ask for and that would kind of an end
August timeframe for the working group
Lascaux given as it's more than just you
know small changes we're actually you
know removing custody in it just me to
be precautious
um so we would love to get people you
know saying if you agree with it then
just not be silent but says I read it
it's fine you know go forward we would
like to get those kinds of emails on the
mailing list
kasi transfer we would ask for a ring
adoption you know in the next week's
maybe tomorrow you should ask this
afternoon and give a couple of weeks to
to respond to be sick yeah we would go
working group last call with the BP SEC
there is this ah with the BP SEC that's
the second document of the
interoperability cipher suites the
question for me is whether I like this
is a question to the rest should that be
rolled into the BP SEC document as a
section to say if you're using BP SEC
here are the cipher suites that the IETF
suggest you use or should that live
outside as a separate document if he
lives outside as a separate document
then it probably needs to be adopted and
go into the last call alongside because
I can't see putting forwards the
security protocol without a standard set
of Interop cipher suites is going to
work I my personal opinion is push the
two together but I think we'll take that
to the list sorry Karen
[Music]
sorry TC PCL I think it's done we may
have additional comments so let's say
that by the end of August we'll will
essentially close and then you know push
forward with BP best to to the is G and
AMA the architecture document we would
ask for we can group the option you know
in the next days a week this does that
summary make sense to people or yes just
a comment from Ed brain Christian at
last working group ransomed okay with
these as a separate document
but okay yeah I think it's proven that
you separated Cyprus sweets yes so you
could I think the point was at the time
was that if you separate the cipher
Suites from the core document and you
can up rev for the recommended Cyprus
sweets without having to touch the core
document I think that was the idea just
in case someone suddenly breaks sha-256
or quantum suddenly works and then okay
so does anyone have any final comment
they wanted to make any questions
particularly in light of the custody
transfer split out which I thought was
going to be a much bigger debate point
than it has turned out to be any other
business basically otherwise thank you
all very much mark and I will do our
best to get these take it to the list
comments actually on the list this time
and we'll see you all in we'll see you
all in Singapore and on the lists thank
you very much