[Music]
sir Bonnie this is Jane I'm just testing
to see if you can hear me can you speak
up if yes remotely SAR Bonnie grand mark
before before we get into the
presentations I just like to introduce
myself and my co-chair here with us who
is in absentia for Arjuna Arjuna is with
us probably online but Leandro Navarro
from the UPC a researcher in Barcelona
Spain we're partners in crime in this
session today so I'm Jane Kaufmann from
the internet society the work I do there
focuses on infrastructure development
leandro does lots of work with grief net
but other research with net Commons
a group that looks at a lot of the
community networks across Europe we've
worked closely with grief II and other
partners here in the room to develop
infrastructure from the bottom up as
they say so we're gonna get started but
I have to do some housekeeping for
everyone's benefit the Charter for Gaia
is online so please if you need to see
what the Charter is take a look I
refreshed myself today and have a look
so you can see what the purpose is from
a research side from across the IETF
side otherwise I'm supposed to tell all
the speakers you must stand in this pink
box because you have to speak into this
microphone for the remote participants
to hear you a and B so that it's
recorded so the other thing for you all
to know and I'm gonna pull it up right
now there are some rules of the road
with respect to these meetings and
you've probably heard that from
everybody and any other session you've
been in there are blue sheets
circulating we need you to sign up so
there are blue sheets on a clipboard who
has it
waive it please circulate it because
everyone needs to sign it
note well is everyone familiar with this
you agree as a participant in this room
that your contributions are part of the
proceedings here this isn't overly
legalistic but this is important from a
legal perspective from an IP perspective
given we're here to share information
about the great work people are doing
around the world
it really isn't from overly legalistic
but if you were in another session and
you're a company or you're just you're
an individual coming in here to talk
about a certain standard IP sometimes
intellectual property comes into the
picture here it's our expectation that
that's not the case but please make
yourself familiar with this does anyone
need me to read it for those online I
don't think so
and for those online that can hear us we
can't hear you so we're gonna bump you
to the last part of the agenda so Roche
from grief Annette is gonna go first I'm
gonna pull up Rosie's presentation in
about two seconds
but is there anything that anyone else
has questions about before we get
started okay great and I'm just making
sure I have everything checked off you
all know about the blue sheets please
sign them we have the note well
otherwise we're gonna get under way but
the key thing for all of us to know sort
of as a level set we're here today to
talk about important ways for people to
have more access to connectivity I think
all of you know that connectivity brings
economic and social development
technology's getting cheaper there are
better ways to deploy technology for
development it's a key thing that many
of us in this room focus on for our
daily lives which is a great job to have
so the key thing for Gaia now is what
we're really interested in doing
speaking in absentia for for Arjuna as
well we're keen to reboot Gaia so that
it's beneficial to the IETF to all of
you and to bring some energy back into
the group to see if there's a way we can
look at putting an RFC together
informational and just how we can do
that as a collaborative so this is
bottom up community driven collaboration
if anyone has any questions we can take
them afterwards about what that means
there are some seats down front if
anyone sit great so again I'm Jane I'm
one of the co-chairs along with Leandro
Roche from Gwinnett is going to be up we
are going to keep to a strict time that
was something that we had heard from
feedback from others so is fascinating
and awesome as these presentations are
gonna be there about eight minutes long
with two minutes two questions we hope
for more questions after and if people
feel really motivated you could take it
outside to the coffee and maybe the bar
but we're just gonna try and keep on
track here because we've got such great
people presenting we're gonna do that
any questions before we get started
cool okay Roche you're gonna be up and
we need you to stand in this box here
I'm going to present research work we've
been carrying out for two years I come
from definite which is a community
network and taking advantage of this
situation my connections with other
members we came up with some ideas and
how to to move this forward and here I'm
gonna present essentially cloudy but the
idea of community clouds as open
comments and this is a very important
detail we claim that we are in giving it
we are developing community network in
comments and this has a very a lot of
implications the Commons is a very well
recognized method for organizing and
managing some resources like natural
resources and what we are exploring is
how these models can be integrated in in
the telecommunications field or more
precisely in in the in the network area
then anyway so I will make a short thing
or I'm already making the assumption
explaining why and what's what's the
the inspiration then I will explain you
how we alright thanks so yeah they just
the research bang we followed then the
short comparison between the community
clout and beef in it and finally I will
just finally present Claudia so as I
said the Commons honor and acknowledge
model for managing resources they are
community driven this is very important
and we also distinguish with the concept
or introduce the open comments because
some of the Commons are closed and ma
and make sense of their close just thing
about for instance a fishing ground or
watering system the capacity the
production capacity of that resource is
limited on the contrary if we think
about the human-made infrastructures
like networks we can expand them more
and more so and this can be done as open
comments these are given at ease and
success or for us it's a success case of
managing a digital infrastructure as a
local commons and inspired by definite
or through our participation we came up
with the concept of community clouds
because a network without content
doesn't make sense so how to help to
develop local and local locality is
another key issue in in all this story
how to help to develop contents to may
give sense to the to the network as a
whole so the first question is are they
are these comedic clouds visible and if
so can they be sustainable what we did
well we studied the goofiness case we
came up
inspired by definite because there is a
full frame of governance and how to do
things in giving it and just to give you
an idea at the moment there are more
than 330 thousand working nodes in
definite close to forty thousand we
there are there are about between 1550
and 100 notes attached every week so
these demands a lot of
well clear participation rules we
translated this into a framework for the
community cloud then we identified what
was the the enabler or the initial
interval and we came up with the the
software stack is that the first thing
to be developed and then once we had the
software double stack developed we came
with a feasibility analysis and then we
studied this or start studying the
sustainability because this is an
ongoing work so what we do in in
definite essentially we are building
this is the three layers we have the
physical layer the network layer and the
service layer the service line it's what
gives sense to the rest because the you
the users want what they want are
essentially services they don't care
about pings I don't care about jitters
they don't care about nothing since they
don't care about em pill yeah anything
else
so in giving that what we do is to say
that we built and operate so the first
and the second layer network
infrastructure open and participatory
based on that we proposed to build the
yes and the passed layers as well as
open comments and this is what we call
the community cloud similarities we have
similar stakeholders meaning that we
have volunteers we have enterprises we
have public administrations and we have
governing bodies involved the
participation framework attire at high
level looks quite quite close the same
so thus for the economic tools and the
communication and coordinate
coordinating tools and there are some
common enablers like the need of having
a set of technology ready to be used and
early adopters and so on but there are
also differences the boundaries what is
it about in the first case it's about
network something that is very specific
and well-defined and on the community
clouds we have something that it's more
fuzzy and there are more interrelations
like we have the infrastructure but we
also have the last layer and
like so this is are the internal
components and then and this
infrastructure is already built over the
top of another one which is the network
and as I said before we identified the
software starting to develop and this is
what we do so essentially we put in
place some yes and pass components to
let the people or start providing SAS
and essentially and this is probably the
two last transparencies here are what we
what we need for BMS we we do it with
token and BMS are necessary to for the
rest of things then we also activated
and history what we call doesn't win
discovery service this is essential in a
distributed an open network where people
can contribute in a disk coordinated
manner contents it's something that was
really neat and was a demand of the
community because it's otherwise well
it's difficult to track what's inside we
also have usually authentication for
many applications rely on that and then
we have a semi-circle translator which
are now implemented with over the local
component and then we also added some of
some services that are very popular in
deep net which are essentially the proxy
and the graph server and DNS these are
net tools that are needed to handle than
the community the community network and
for SAS we implemented synchronized
sinking which is a distributed file
storage and then the peer steamer and
what we evaluated was this the file
storage service as first exploration of
the sustainability the conclusions is
that gives PC well now it's used the
experimentation to are done in I don't
know about the time all right and then
questions or okay so we we made we may
employment indefinite or we start there
and there are about 60 or more clouds
code is not working there so yeah and
this is how it look like we we also it's
all managed through a website everything
is there and so there is a single point
of entry and there is also that
something that the user said that it was
needed because otherwise if there was a
lot of tools here and there and it was a
bit difficult so now questions anyone
have a question okay
and make sure you speak into the
microphones because we're recording and
it's part of the audio-visual feed hello
great can you introduce yourself as well
yeah my name is I'm rich from the
University of Capetown Thank You Raj I
just wanted to know whether you have any
data on how many people are using the
cloud services and what are the
different applications and what's it but
is they'll take basically this is the
first stage and we very local and
there's fusing little dissemination but
we have well 60 dog totally running
cloudy and here the key issue is to find
something that gives value to this
infrastructure this is the same case as
the network if there is no a key or
something that give value it will be a
nice piece of software we have developed
but it's utilized and the same happens
with the network right so I'm just a
table from AfriNIC so I was just
interested in a comment that you made he
said users interested in the services
but you don't care about pings and so on
I don't know where they got that out of
context but is it really true I would
think they end users I think so yeah
they would be concerned about the
quality of service called of Expedia so
exactly what yeah yes
the video like they have click works and
that's it
yeah yeah so I think the comment was
that they change the service we don't
care about what's happening on the
network level but maybe it was my fault
I apologize so what I said or tried to
say is that they usually don't care it's
just a way that our every flick that we
want to understand what's underneath but
it's not coming or you can find Roche
later all right thank you okay next step
is Nico pate from ultra Mundi and Nico
will tell you who he is and what he does
and but just to remind folks blue sheets
please sign we're keeping to eight
minutes per presenter two minutes of
questions hopefully people are around
after if you have more questions but
we're having all of these folks speak
here today so that we can try and reboot
some good work but also for you to know
about what's going on around the world
with some really cool bottom-up
community based connectivity projects
okay
Thank You Shane well my name is Nicolas
I'm part of a grassroots organization
that's called Alta Mundi we promote net
networks so this is a very bad photo for
a slide sorry
the community is installing wireless
link and we we promote communities
inside the networks so community
networks and networks in communities and
we I want to share with you the last
year of work that we have been doing so
this is not something that we have been
doing so this is something that we have
been doing together with many other
community network members leaving a mesh
is one of them
so liberal mesh is a distribution
software operating system for community
networks this operating system modifies
how routers work to turn them into
devices that are that helped community
networks they grow and it's not only
distribution it's a meta distribution so
each community with each particular can
create their own software that runs on
routers that allows them to create
networks so the general approach of
libera mesh is to create a big free
solution and this is an interesting
concept because we are so used to deploy
to be the technical people to be the
ones that deploy network infrastructure
but as when you get to your house build
your own your first house for the first
time and you need to understand which
components are part of house and this is
the same if you want to be you're the
owner of the of the network you need to
understand how it works but for this we
make it as easy as possible and the
people for the people to be able to
deploy the neighbor without having to
learn all these complex stuff that we
did with so the default configuration of
this software allows has a dual layer
mesh routing strategy that allow people
not only to create networks around
buildings or villages small villages
automatically let's say you know they
don't have to do anything to make the
network work it's just works but also
allows communities to connect with each
other without having to understand how
this works so they can understand how it
works but they don't need to understand
how it works so it's like plugging a TV
or but with networking and we try to
abstract this idea of IP addresses
Macha
addresses routing and all of that behind
a an abstraction layer that allows
people to relate with the devices with
names instead of with numbers and it's
much approach all in this way also well
thanks thanks to this two layer approach
the device allows the mesh allows to
have many routes that take you to the
same place dynamically so for example in
a common scenario when there is a mesh
network in a neighborhood let's say and
many neighbors have not not all of them
but some of them have internet connect
connections like a connection that gets
to the rest of the networks they can
share the connection and the traffic
balance itself like if I'm close up to
chain that has connection I can go
through her instead of through rojeck
that is far is far from me and also has
this self-healing and roaming capability
so if the network for any reason breaks
there is a no that gets down or the
connectivity from Jane has go down so
the routing protocols deal with these
equations and also also with around
roaming so you could get metropolitan
area network like a village network
where you can walk through the village
and the TCP connections stay up so it's
it's like GSM networks but with home
technologies and this is actually pretty
scalable we have six villages network in
Argentina for example and these are run
by individuals not by but nobody
non-technical people so it's it's good
it's it's a good analogy but this this
approach has its downsides so first it's
a do-it-yourself approach because these
devices have to be so you have to
a device that that was thought for home
like a home router and you have to
change the software that comes inside
the device and then you have to create a
weather sealed box to put it in your
ceiling and then you have to create to
put using a dish that increases the gain
of the antenna to reach further
distances so it has a lot of manual
engagement that is good in one side
because people makes it personal but
it's bad in the sense that it's much
much much more complex to deploy at
larger scales and sometimes communities
want to deployment at larger scales the
other the other topping is the other
topic is that is router dependent so
dissolution requires manufacturers to
create open devices for us devices that
allowed themselves they are permitted to
change the software that comes inside
them and particularly the problem is
that we are manufacturing dependent this
process is manufacturer dependent and
something that happened some years ago
that it was the FCC lockdown so FEC
ruled that the devices couldn't be
modified the software that can to the
inside the devices couldn't be modified
anymore for whatever reasons were
relevant for them but for community
networks was a committee networks that
used mesh technologies was a very big
problem because they they they from that
open moment on they lacked the raw
materials to create the network so we
started this project they live around
the project that is again not all term
on this project but a collaboration
between 1207 organizations plus for fund
funders so liberator is an open software
and open open-source software and open
source hardware router for community
networks by community networks this is
the solution that we found to prevent
from here on these these situations
the device comes with everything that
communities need like we are always
struggling with for example if a router
has one radio at 2.40 I have my radio
what if it has a to perfect for gia has
radio then it's meshing and it's sharing
with the community at the same time so
we have less bandwidth if it has two
radios which radios it has if it has
connectors or they knit the antennas are
coming solder in the device so a lot of
problems that we have to deal with
complexity this device will come with
everything sorted out so communities
don't have to care about these things
it's community design and it's open
source Harvard as I said and it was up
it is being because it's not here yet
but is it is being a collaboration
between the private with the private
sector for the manufacturing and the
design and distribution of the device so
it has been an opportunity for us as a
civil and as grassroot organization to
approach the private sector and create a
synergy between us okay and what's
pending for us for Liberator at least
for this period first polishing the
Wi-Fi right drivers the the open-source
Wi-Fi drivers are lagging behind the
closed source and they are buggy so
problems to deal with TV white space
this frequency that has been freed we
are working on these it will come with
TV white space capabilities and they
user interface and what's next other
media's for example fiber and coaxial to
be it for community to engage with this
new new technologies 802 11 AC it's
relevant for community because we will
have more bandwidth and having powerful
devices that will allow to have local
services inside of the devices so that's
it questions we have time for questions
about two minutes please introduce
yourself at the microphone it was a
really small person
I kneel stand over icicle 19 super cool
word
have you tried working with the tourist
omnia router because I think it's one of
the only open source and open hardware
routers and were luckily here hosted by
some of the providers of those have you
looked into that hardware we have done
very thoughtful dig into what's
available and there are devices around
but none of them are fitted to the needs
of the community network moment yeah
like if this device comes with sulphide
sheer house radio at 2.4 gigahertz radio
spec so we dig we dig into this and we
ended up deciding but we we are we are
super enthusiastic about having more
people doing our open however in this
field because it might be interesting
because they are a company behind it
have kennels or help train the further
support and the second thing that was
interesting how does it relate to leet
and open wrt are you building solar pond
yeah on top yeah
Rosi much shorter guy regarding tourism
near the problem is the price
essentially it's a bit expensive and I
think yeah the device is targeted to
developing country so it has to be as we
we have done it as cheap as we could and
there is no profit in here so so it will
be solved video energy any questions
okay thank you and it goes around if
people have questions after and thank
you we're trying to keep to time I know
it seems like I might be a slave driver
on that but we're just trying Nielsen to
your question about equipment it's one
of the biggest things we see out there
of problems if you've ever dealt with
customs we get switches stuck in customs
for three months at cost that you
wouldn't believe and we're donating the
equipment and I've had to actually show
up in a country again it was cheaper for
me to fly to Tunisia and go in and say
hey ho what's up with those Cisco's
forty five hundreds but in any event it
happens and it's a big policy issue
related to regulatory as well if you
really want to open up your internet
keep it in jail doesn't help if the
gears in the customs so Gareth you are
up next this is a measurement a cool
measurement project Queen Mary
University Gareth Tyson
okay hello everyone I can't start
speaking without the cue of my slide to
remind me so I wait till it pops up okay
thank you thank okay hi Evan as J no D
introduce my name is Gareth and I'm from
the Queen Mary University of London but
you'll immediately notice that there's
lots of other fuzzy logos on this
presentation mainly because these are
the guys who did the real work I'm just
a kind of attractive person they always
push outs to do up in their behalf I'm
two of them are actually sitting here
I'm wishing Josiah so most of the
attitude goes to them anyway so some of
you are already aware of some of the
measurement work we've been doing in
Africa and the purpose behind this very
short presentation is just to give
people a brief update so the premise
behind the work that we've been doing is
pretty straightforward the internet you
know Africa is evolving quickly that
means understanding the status quo is
difficult which means making strategic
decisions investment decisions that
logical different decisions is also very
challenging so we've been doing a bunch
of measurements on the continent to try
and understand how that change is
happening and the long term vision is to
try and take all these measurements
together and put them into an integrated
platform and make them pretty much open
to the community so you can just click a
few buttons and find out exactly what is
important to you at the time but it's
not that trivial so we're not really at
the stage of having an integrated
platform so what I want to talk to you
about today is just some of the works
that we've been doing and incidentally
all this data is available freely to
download free to analyze it's just not
in a pretty GUI yet so a major theme of
the work that we've been doing is
looking at content delivery on the
continent so how web is provided to
people so when I say how content is
provided I largely mean how web
providers and CD ends have deployed in
the continent how would they make it
accessible to their users so we've been
generating quite a few plots like this
so this one on the Left here is actually
for Google so this is mapping the Google
servers available to people on the
continent so the first thing you'll
notice is that there's actually quite a
few dots in Africa but at the same time
there's even larger number of dots
spread around mostly in America in
Europe so this pie chart shows a great
bang for you so this blue part here is
the number of servers in Africa well
obviously the remaining ones
Tikku the red are those outside so the
red is actually in the united states so
we've been doing this and digging into
it to try and find the key bottleneck so
that we can alleviate them so this is an
animator through this but of course one
of the main bottlenecks we find is that
network delay in Africa is much larger
than we see elsewhere so we've been
doing studies to try and look at how
intra Africa connectivity's there and
how routing works so this heat map for
instance shows inter country delay from
network samples we have listing
countries and of course you can see that
your country delay is on the whole
fairly good with a few exceptions like
PayPal and Congo which is quite poor but
there are these big red so these
indicating delays are typically around
half a second far too long to have a
particularly satisfactory web experience
the graph on the left as well is showing
that the reason for this is even more
attractive is that much of the traffic
that points is actually leaving the
continent so instead of being routed
directly through appearing fabric in an
exchange point it's actually coming off
the continent into the United States or
maybe into Europe and then making its
way back in again so that graph on the
left is actually chained taken from a
European exchange point and the blue
line is actually showing the amount of
traffic that's coming through that
European exchange point from Africa and
then not down into Africa again so this
is one of the major bottlenecks that
makes deploying CDN notes quite
challenging so another major theme of
our work is trying to look at how
network operators are reacting to these
observations because obviously operators
are not stupid they see these things
happening and they try to modify their
behavior to reflect them so in this
particular study we were looking at how
operators in Africa deploy web caches
because obviously if you see that a lot
of the web servers that your users
access are actually based in the United
States the most sensible thing to do is
to maybe put a transparent cache nearby
to yourself so that you stop doing that
particularly because African transit
costs extremely high compared to most of
the parts of the world
and again without going to too much
detail what we found is that indeed
Africa is a far higher level of web
caches than most of the regions in the
world to give you some context here
Europe has about 8% of networks with web
caches that we observed why is that
about 36% for Africa so it's much higher
so I just want to end with a few final
thoughts because those are three of the
studies that been running concurrently
at the moment but they weren't easy to
do and in fact they involved a lot of
hacking just to get them working so the
whole theme behind this work has been to
try and put together a solid measurement
infrastructure in Africa so that we can
actually make these types of
measurements much more easy and much
more methodical so just to give you an
idea of what this means this graph is
showing data from the previous slide the
one that's looking at transparent web
caches and these bars are showing the
number of sample points were getting and
all of this is African countries apart
from a couple example this one is the
United States and you can see that the
samples that managed to extract from
Africa is far lower simply because our
penetration advantage points are much
more limited which means that the
veracity our data is also much more
limited another cool thing that we need
to start thinking about is how we can
actually fine-tune methodologies to work
for Africa so the previous previous two
slides ago when I was showing you the
delay told you that if you want to ping
let's say an IP address in your
next-door neighbor's house it might be
taking the order of 300 milliseconds
many of the measurement methodologies we
use to date make the assumption that
nearby hosts have low delay and as soon
as that breaks the methodology breaks so
finding new ways to actually evaluate
the situation Africa is paramount the
other thing I want to say is that these
types of studies we're doing and not
just for fun the idea is to try and push
this towards a type of system that
allows us to farm recommendations
ideally recommendations that can be
automatic that individual Network
providers who want to improve their
infrastructure so this type of analysis
is only one piece of the puzzle and the
reason I say that is because we believe
that there should be some sort of
community effort so there's a lot of
people out there who are doing these
types of measurements perhaps in other
parts of the world so ideally we can
kind of you know come together share our
expertise and maybe push hard on getting
its infrastructure item
these measurements so can anybody guess
what this is it's actually a shameless
plug so there was some other pictures I
could but they were far more erotic in
nature so the shameless plug I'm giving
you is that we're actually running a
workshop later in the year in Nigeria
with these two gentlemen here is the
real guys who were doing the work it's a
workshop specifically looking at almost
perfect time it's a workshop
specifically looking at internet
measurements in Africa so there's a URL
if you're interested in this if you're
doing in this work please feel free to
click on it and yeah take a look
questions for Gareth hi hi most
interesting work I'm Miriam Cunha from
the ripe NCC and I have a question about
the methodology you've been using
especially for the delays so to give you
a little bit more information we've been
using a platform that I'm sure you're
very familiar with wonderful that's
where I'm standing yeah I thought I
could add another shameless plug here
because I have some of those devices
with me and people are interested go on
so so for those of you who don't already
know ripe have deployed a very nice
platform called Atlas which is
consisting of these little boxes which
you can take away and plug in to your
home network your office network and it
allows kind of geeks like us to log into
them and launch certain types of
measurements so we use those quite
extensively so the first study was done
extensively over Reika parts of the
second study we've done over ripe as
well as speed checker as well okay and
then the third one we didn't do over
ripe and the reason for that was that we
needed two slightly more fine-grained
control over the W gets basically so
wasn't so easy to do yeah things because
as you said later on of course it's
essentially the measurements you know
can only be done and they get more and
more useful the more the bigger the
platform gets and the more of these
little probes measurement probes you
have so if people are interested to host
one of those probes in their homes or in
our networks then I might be happy to
talk to you I have some of those with me
so maybe then we can increase the data
it you know you can collect and analyze
yeah they're for free free
one minute thank you very much for the
ride we've been using it quite
extensively one of the challenges we've
had so far is the distribution of these
probes at AFRICOM a is in Nairobi we
give a presentation at a workshop the
distribution is quite problematic in
many of the places in Africa some of the
countries have a huge distribution of
them other countries are very very very
small and also appear the same networks
have a lot of problems some networks
don't have so that's why we want to work
on a methodology that helps us to
distribute these probes in a more
efficient manner so that the coverage is
more disability and not the same the
same networks that how hundred probes
and others have zero thank you so much
for the probes we are also distributing
some of them but we we are glad to have
more thank you thank you thank you and
ripe also has anchors we're helping to
place some of those in Hayek's peas with
AfriNIC which is another way to get some
of those measurements so thank you too
ripe next up is Carlos Romero from Suns
Eleni networks
hello everyone and I'm gonna change
topics my presentation is not gonna be
technical at all actually because part
of this global alliance to global access
to the Internet for all is about the
people is not about the technology so I
was invited to well I've been working on
mapping the different community networks
in Africa since June last year and in
the previous guy a meeting I I presented
the map were we identified 37 community
networks in 12 African countries and
that map event only led I sock to to
assist me together in a partnership
organized the first summit on community
networks in Africa when I presented in
the last guy a meeting I said that we
were analyzing and going into depth into
some interviews that we did with the
with the representatives of 10 community
networks from eight countries that came
that came to that were so so in the last
six months this is a bit of an update of
what we been up to on the community
networks in space in Africa so first of
all that deeper analysis has been
published I don't have to go through it
but the the report is available there
and there has been another second summit
on community net was in Africa that took
place during the african internet summit
that i'm gonna go through it in more
detail just now but the materials and
the presentations are also in the link
in case you want to check them out about
the deeper analysis one of the things
that came very strongly is conversely to
I mean in a way supporting part of the
definitions that are coming up from
other community networks in the world
but something that came more strongly
from the continent and I'm gonna read it
out in Africa a community matter is not
simply telecommunications infrastructure
deployed and operated by citizens to
meet their own communication needs it's
a tool to improve what a community is
already doing in terms of their growth
and the development by contributing to a
local ecosystem that enhances the daily
lives of those that are staying in the
community is more groups of people that
have the technology that the technology
come and supported rather than creating
communities of people via the technology
and something that came also but the
presentation I did of the whole report
is is available there and the YouTube
video that Nikko recorded during during
the AIS is also available there if you
want to have more more more in-depth
information about it but other things
that can related to the presentation
that Roger did is that these
organizations that are running community
networks in Africa seems to be you
managed in this local ecosystem that go
beyond the technology the technology
using the commands all their other
economic activities in the community
together with the community network are
managed the same way trying to benefit
as many people as possible
for instance providing training in
digital literacy in cybersecurity in
many other things actually it's about
keeping those ties that strongly tied
together in brutal African societies as
as they grow that networks other things
that are very important in the in the in
the community mental space in Africa for
instance that the public access
something that is coming very strongly
as well is that most of them are powered
by solar energy unlike here we were
talking about that router over there I
can remember but probably the
consumption of that router is very
higher that the consumption of the rotor
like the liberal rotor that we are also
involved with that can be powered at a
low cost in the places that made this
connectivity in the continent so only
thing that was important and at
analyzing the needs and the and a and
and the community because in Africa is
about what they are struggling with
identifying those barriers and with
those barriers then we build up the
agenda for the second cement own
community net was that happen during a
is and those barriers are around
training like technical training
business training where nough cebause
some of the technologies that we all
hear talk about but they don't master
but so there was technical training
provided by ICP P there were
presentations about different topics
that they suggested and there was also
deployment of putting that knowledge
into practice and for nodes were
connected to a community network that is
in Kibera in Nairobi so there was a
hands-on exercise of building the
community of the community networks in
Africa
to bring them together to support each
other to be there for each other because
at the end that's also what they are
lacking they are lacking that confidence
of feeling probably what you are feeling
an IETF
that developing technology is part of
being part of a group of people
like-minded people that are pushing the
development of the technology in a given
direction the same happens with the
community leaders in Africa and I want
to talk a bit about my particular
experience instance Eleni I've been
involved in since Eleni for the last six
years is a community network in rural
Eastern Cape in in South Africa that I
started as a collaboration between the
University of the Western Cape that I
also represent and the community of
Manco see a man cos is a community where
people live and below $2 a day where
they spend 22 percent of their
disposable income in communications that
means that the traditional mode with
mobile models of providing connectivity
are very are not providing affordable
communications to the people in the
places where I work so we started
working with a very small model
replicating a first open hardware and
open source hardware called village
telco and mashed potatoes to provide to
create a network of voice over IP
technology inside the community to
reduce the price of the connectivity
with time we connected it to two to a 3d
router and allow us to provide breakout
calls to national numbers and
international numbers to half of the
price of the people of what the people
pays with incumbent operators and also
to receive incoming calls from them from
there and over time especially in the
six in the last six months we've managed
to set up our own communications tower
halfway in between the community that is
by the coast and on Tata that is the
bigger town now we have our devices and
we have a connection in a data center in
the university which means that we can
access fiber and it's not only about the
fiber and we
connecting schools and high schools and
some other business clients and around
the around the coast to make the
business model sustainable and and start
creating local employment and preventing
that the rural the people that are
currently living in rural areas that
normally emigrate to towns and leave
these these areas without skills now are
able to remain there and again as the
case of all term only this is done by
local people and for local people and
this is the accommodates that we have
from the tower there are four other
communities for now that have approaches
that want to join and want to join
forces with us and replicate the model
that we have established since living so
now the question is how to move forward
well our whole idea is to reuse all the
knowledge and all the experience than if
Annette has been creating with regards
to managing this infrastructure as a
commons because it's the most beneficial
way to develop the ecosystem in the area
so at the moment we are busy a kind of
creating that that model and trying to
understand and starting to provide these
services to sensors any Meadows Manco
see that is a we've incorporated a
non-for-profit umbrella organization to
provide services to those community ISPs
that are gonna that are already in the
area and that are gonna continue being
created in the area and some of the
services are related to helping them
with the with the licenses with training
with procurement of equipment with the
default terms and conditions to meet all
the other regulatory specifications and
you got well you can read them all
they're access to our IR resources etc
but for me in the context of an RFC I
would be very much interested on
documenting what is the process to a
start-up economy how can we work
together we give in it to do that and
have some informational documentation
that someone can follow a questions for
Carlos about two minutes we may have
more time I'm gonna try and set up a
zoom session in a minute to bring in the
two other presenters but Leandro is
gonna speak after Carlos but any
questions for Carlos
actually Carlos before you sit down I
want to ask you one question
so how did you start it well a sorry a
well it started by in this case myself I
went to the community because we had
some links there and I started working
with well asking by authorization
authorization by the by the local
authority in this case the tribal
authority of the community and they
appointed some people to start working
with us to see whether they had interest
and what was the the people inside the
community that could absorb the skills
at the beginning and to a start they
will open this and transmitting this
inside the community to other community
members so yeah that's basically the way
we started and could you just explain
tribal authority cuz some people might
okay so some some most rural communities
not only in South Africa but in Africa
have a double administrative system so
there is the traditional authorities
that are based on normally patrilineal
authority that were established several
centuries ago and then the more
democratic a official government and
mini static government that so the
tribal authorities are the the
traditional authorities are those chiefs
and those leaders that have been there
for generations in the different tribes
and differing cultural groups techniques
and the groups that are in thank you
very much and this is a common issue
that we've seen in projects we've worked
on in India you have to go to the the
chief of the village the head man the
head woman whomever it is that helps run
that and sit for days weeks sometimes
and just talk through the process okay
next up is Leandro and he'll tell you
what he's doing with net Commons and I'm
gonna try after Leandro speaks to pull
in the other two presenters through zoom
we're having a little issue here with
the audiovisual or the visual more than
anything so up for land
hi um my name is Leandro Navarro I come
from University in Barcelona and the
work week I'm presenting is related to a
EU funded project where we work with
several community networks and
researchers in mostly in Europe but also
with participants in other countries my
talk is not going to be technical but
you know we talk about like an
artificial space where we can
communicate that is enabled by
technology
yeah not naturally prepare for it and we
need to build networks we need to build
infrastructures and then our work is
focused on on on this common space
infrastructures that are developed
cooperatively and then of course I mean
once these infrastructures are enabled
technologically then as they become
bigger and bigger you need to organize
them and the Commons is I mean the
theory of the Commons is is a nice way
to to define the governance models and
the ways of participation the ways where
citizens can build expand and use the
network but then I mean we have seen
successes and failures and in this
particular project one of the areas
where we are looking at is is that we
call it business in a kind of a general
I mean generic way of the business and
organizational models for community
networks and we try to understand how
they work which models work and why and
which patterns are typically happening
in most of them which ones are signals
of failure and and and well the
objective is also like it being able to
understand the different community
networks in different places how they
work and also to be able to produce
materials that help communities to grow
or to improve or to develop from scratch
so ideally we can provide some training
materials some
some support to improve their
effectiveness let's say and then when
I'm talking about mainly governance
tools I'm talking about for instance
that communities can define what they
consider as a commons what is the common
infrastructure imagine like for instance
when if you talk about an IXP the XP has
a commons kind of infrastructure
despite that the participants in the
commons they do business so we need to
identify what is the code the
co-operative part what is the
competitive part let's say which are the
attributes as in other organizations
there are different stakeholders
typically community networks are started
by citizens that they have a need for
connectivity but these citizens can
become professionals they can create
companies they can interact with
government governments with regulators
and so on
so it can be complex we talked about
like governance tools in terms of
communication tools bylaws agreements
licenses tools to manage the network and
other things so so for instance when
resources have to be allocated when
there is a conflict when when there is
responsibility when there is data
retention when there is for instance
complex infrastructure that has to be
paid every month and you need to split
the costs like like an XP would do you
need to find ways to do that so that
people spend time doing productive
things and not do not spend the time
discussing and just like a quick
introduction this is what we have done
in the last one and a half years somehow
there is a report online if you're if
you're a test I can share the link it's
it's a it's a report that looks at how
some communities most of them in Europe
but we also have one in in India how
they govern themselves and then we try
to identify patterns things that
typically happen when when they work
well and think typically things that
have to be avoided but because they they
go to the bad outcomes and then we found
out that on the process we found the
several communities willing to
re-engineer some of the processes based
on their learning exercise so for that
and also like a template for producing
perhaps a joint document in this group
which is one of the initial objectives
of the of the Gaia working group is we
came up with this kind of model is
called the business campus or the social
campus that it's a simple way of
defining the business model of an
organization that can do whatever
business but it can be used to - as you
see here - to talk about how the how
this business is sustainable I mean how
they exchange money or services or goods
and also that how what is the impact of
that business like community network in
in the in the local environment so we
came up with a kind of template model
for different community networks to this
strife I mean which are the the their
key partners which are the key
activities they do like deploy in the
network or which are the key resources
like the participants the routers and
everything what value what product they
produced further for the customers how
they relate with them what are the costs
and revenue streams so it's it's a
competent manner to try to summarize how
a community interacts with the Excite
with the external world with with the
environment and also based on on this
experience with definite we also defined
kind of generic structure that can be
used to put that to describe how each
community deals with different things
like with agreements with participants
with economic activity with conflict
resolution and then on top you can see
that there are some good practices in
different aspects so we try to use these
two templates the business model canvas
the outside world
and the andes diagram to describe how
the community works inside and then well
why we have done instant exercise with a
few community networks this is one in
France for instance this is another one
in Italy that describes how they look
from outside this is another one in in
Mexico another one in this is the
definite kind of umbrella organization
this is one of the given ed communities
in in Barcelona which which is part of
this umbrella community and well several
examples this is the for instance the
internal diagram for one of the
community networks in given F in
Barcelona and it explains how they apply
the specific aspects which are the best
good practices so we we try to really
really summarize and produce a set of
forms kind of like diagrams which allow
people to look at different models so
they can understand the differences and
and learn from it and then we also went
to the idea of collecting some kind of
abstract patterns things that happen
typically and then we came up with this
for the moment like nineteen patterns in
the document every pattern which is
driving I mean what it what it is one
example one solution a bit of discussion
of things that when that we know work
well with some examples and things that
we know that doesn't work with some
examples so we can help communities to
realize what is some ways to do things
ways to avoid so the idea its is to
cover like with these patterns we cover
most of the aspects of how a community's
work internally and then and then my
interest was like a proportional short
discussion if people would like to be
involved so we can expand the list and
and analyze more communities and produce
a like not a longer document but a more
compact like a collection of of like
diagrams
which is cut the internal it external
perspective and also if we can
synthesize the list of let's say
patterns and anti patterns that help
others to improve the governance and
then for instance just just an example
of a few of the of the outcomes of this
process is that communities learn and
they realize that some things could be
done could be done better which means
they can scale up or they can reduce
their overhead which in the end it's
more impact for the community
surrounding the infrastructure and and
that's it
I mean I hope you join us in this
discussion I don't know if you you
mentioned before but we have a mailing
list and if you're interested you can
join the list it's Kyah - request at a
RTF org and then you can just say
subscribe strife and then you can join
the list and follow the discussion
afterwards okay thank you and if anyone
please go ahead and let's see if you
have any questions for Leandro or anyone
else who presented I'm going to and it's
hot in here if anyone sitting next to a
thermostat may be Gareth we could see if
we could turn it down oh gosh we wish it
were ten it's about a hundred and ten so
anyways we all sit here together I'm
going to try and pull up a zoom session
and get two of our presenters who are
trapped in the other computer here on my
computer so if you look I'll engage I'm
gonna disengage the visual and I'm gonna
try and get them on the computer here
and we'll start up in a sec so go ahead
does anyone have any questions or throw
stuff out and Luis Martinez who helps
run a community network in Mexico you're
up hi Liz Martinez from Isaac Mexico
Leandra do you think that there is the
model is applicable to any kind of
community meaning should it can be
applied to a community in a rural
environment as Carlos is working or
maybe Europe an environment as someone
as we are
working in Mexico with these marginal
communities around the cities do you
think it's a pliable do we have data
that shows that they can be measured by
the parameters yeah I mean in the list
we already have resumed attica this is
one example and we have the Givi
community network in barcelona which is
a specific urban community so yeah I
mean apart from the technology apart
from the location I mean typically
community networks are alternative to
the code to the business model of a
profit oriented model and and of course
they have different characteristics
different environmental factors and
that's why we try to cover I mean that
that been in the same kind of mood or
the same objectives they have local
local differences which depend on if
they're in a rich poor urban rural
gsm-based Wi-Fi based fiber base so so
beyond that you I mean communities that
develop some kind of organizational
structures and and it's interesting to
understand
I mean how we can extract the lessons
learn so that other communities can use
it to improve because I mean the main
objective is helping them to become more
efficient and to scale up and therefore
to be able to serve the local community
with the lowest cost and the Hippias
impact but yeah
hi great talk Gareth Ison Queen Mary so
I was curious to us several cns that you
mentioned and obviously CN s mentioned
by other people
to what extent these interoperable are
they using completely different
technologies or are they all running in
fairly the same way but basically if you
get enough of them would eventually all
converge you mean to operable in that
well in terms of the technologies that
they use like if I set up a CN you set
up a CN are we using the same protocols
are we say using the same routine
mechanisms are using the same management
systems yeah for instance in our
speaking in our local experience with
giving it even add some mix of of
different islands with different
technologies different software I mean
open source software commercial software
fiber based networks Wi-Fi based
networks so if you look at them from an
IP perspective from an Internet Protocol
perspective yeah they're there people
find ways to make them interpret book
you need to deal with like routing
issues with topology problems with
decentralized services which have to be
located in different regions nothing
that different for what you would find
on the open Internet so the reason is
maybe some components that haven't been
dealt with in all the standards are
unique to CNS and that might be a good
candidate move forward with attempts to
standardize it so that in the future you
just plug and play yeah in a way I mean
what we are trying to do is is coming up
with with an interoperable set of
organizational standards it's I mean
protocols so that communities deal with
organizational problems sometimes
supported by by software sometimes
embedding these social protocols into
the into the networking protocol first
we have working on how the routing can
respect the community license instead of
following the digital algorithm which
which is dictates where the paths where
the traffic goes so that there are also
opportunities of a cross layer work
Thanks okay
thank you yeah so we're having a little
technical difficulty I keep sending
emails so Lakshmi and shravani we need
you to join the zoom link I just sent
you and that's gonna we're gonna give it
about two minutes because if you don't
we're gonna have to skip over and keep
talking about what we may want to do on
an RFC you can join the gym zoom session
I just sent you that would be really
festive
well can you hear us yes well ah there
you are
okay no they are already in the online
forum me take off forum so we don't need
to join the zone sighs okay then that's
just fabulous so Lakshmi is that you yes
that's me yeah okay great so sarvani is
up with you so we're gonna have her
present and I'll put the slides up there
you are excellent we were having a
little moment here so we're gonna have
sir Bonnie are you there okay thank you
um okay so we'll have you come up in two
seconds okay thanks for that we just
have a little confusion here thank you
very much so give me two seconds and
then you're up sorry about that
so buddy why don't you go ahead and
introduce yourself and I'm pulling up
your slides now so just tell me when to
change the slides for you okay I am
Shivani
from the drama team at iit bombay the
principle investigator of this project
is Professor Baker and Vica he is a
professor at IIT Bombay Department of
Electrical Engineering and I am the
senior project research scientist
working together on this project on
grandma grandma literally means that it
is the road it's a road to the to the
village so we are looking for solutions
for connecting the rural India which is
which is unconnected next slide so this
is our team here is our team we bought
with a with a group of people who are
dedicated project project project
research scientists we have PhDs and vrm
takes working together along with us and
in this project because our backer and
beaker is standing in the middle there
what is the current scenario of the next
slide what is the current scenario of
unconnected between India as well as
globally around 4 billion people
unconnected globally and the situation
is very grave in India where around 800
million people in 640,000 villages are
still unconnected and out of these 50
thousand villages in India still do not
have voice connectivity so the situation
is very clear what happens is that what
we look at is that the tower is located
the telecom tower from a private
operator is located at a distance of
around 5 to 10 kilometers away from the
village now how do you connect these
villagers so we we are looking at
solutions on connecting these villages
when there is an availability of the
tower 10 to 15 kilometers away from the
village situated within the nearest town
or the city rural India are connecting
rural India is a great challenge in
itself there are some of the challenges
these are like unavailability of fiber
backhaul this is the next slide can you
please change sides unavailability of
fiber backhaul is one of the important
issues like in the Government of India
is trying to connect all the villages or
the gram panchayats that is the block
level headquarters through the fiber but
it is a long process and it is not yet
fulfilled year the next one is low
average revenue per user the telecom
operators even though they have it are
close by 10 to 15 kilometers or 5 to 10
kilometers away from the village here
does not cover the villagers because the
average revenue per user is very less it
would not get back the return on
investment is very low
there is Intuit in intermittent
availability of electricity there are
often power outages in the villages and
also dependency on on the electricity is
very in smarter it's not a
cost-effective solution at all and then
there is difficult telling 80% of India
is hilly so then it is very difficult to
reach rural India the next slide this is
dramas intimate journey drama began its
journey in the year 2012 with a
quantitative assessment of TV white
space in India so during that time there
was there was there was much discussion
about the usage of period space and we
thought that okay first we should begin
with the quantitative assessment of how
much exactly is there in 2013 we started
with a technology development of our TV
UHF band devices and we established the
first India's first at my TV bed space
test bed in five villages funded by Ford
Foundation in the year 2014 after one
year of giving
providing Internet services to the
villagers in in the village in the five
villages we did an impact assessment
study and that actually threw a great
light into understanding that what is
the
of the villagers how much would they be
able to pay when we asked them for a
payment and what is the role what how
can a sustainable model be built around
these the services that we are providing
to them
in 2016 we scaled up the project to 25
villages and this has been funded being
funded by Tata trust it's an ongoing
project now and in the end this your end
we are trying to go into
commercialization of our devices
currently it is in the prototype stage
can you please change the next line
now India's India's connectivity problem
is very different from that of the rest
of the world we have we be down with as
frugal 5g we want our technology
solution that has to be go fast it has
to be cost-effective it was really low
or something similar to do-it-yourself
type of connectivity wherein the devices
can be connected it should be easy then
there is no mobility don't we are not
intending to use internet at high-speed
trains or buses but we are trying to
look into in a in a sort of it could
speak emitters that type of mobility oh
we are not not high speed but we are
looking into at least connecting and we
are also looking into connecting larger
coverage so there with our technology we
would like to cover as many villages as
possible any please can I cannae please
change lights next slide so what we
think is that is that the given thus the
same scenario occur tower is located 15
kilometers away from the village
we we are using people space in the
middle mind now as you all know next
light TV white space is a solution it's
like it's an utilize part of the TV
spectrum in India it is it is found that
it is it is it is at a time only 8 to 16
megahertz is of operation and India has
only one terascale TV broadcaster that
is the special so for 70 megahertz to
585 megahertz
is solely the property of new fashion
that is the telestrator P podcast now we
would like to use so the rest of the
part that is apart from the 8 to 16
megahertz the rest of the part is it
remains unutilized it has not been
utilized at all so we would like to use
that part and provide Internet
connectivity the villagers can you
please go to the next thing now TV red
space over microwave links as you all
must be knowing that these are the two
options point acquiring microwave links
there is we can cover less distances
whereas in the t-38 space we can cover
more distances next slide there is a TV
back space does not require strict
line-of-sight connectivity that is the
five point eight it is point-to-point
microwave links required now you can you
it's our money it's hard to hear you
sometimes so this is the this is the
middle mile network architecture if you
look at the look at this is how we are
connecting our villages currently so
this is an architecture that we are we
have adopted so given a pop on the left
hand side if you look that the fiber
point of presence is there at a cover
from there we are connecting through if
the distance is 5 kilometers the
villages are 5 kilometers from the tower
at the point of fiber is there we try to
connect it to the TV right space or else
what we do is that we the backhaul is
through the 5.8 in the unlicensed man
and then it we take a drop to do a
village that is strategically located
and then from there we connect to the TV
rights face to the villages so this is
the architecture and the entire thing is
being controlled by the Sdn controller
so this is a technology that we are
currently developing and at any as you
can see on the right hand side of the
slide that we are connecting it through
the Wi-Fi access points in the villages
so it is true people can use it in the
the internet on their mobile computers
as well as the laptops any please go to
the next slide
sure and sir Bonnie you have about a
minute because we do want to get Lakshmi
in okay yeah so this is the TV white
space link specification so it's just
there I would like to talk about the
this is I indígenas the next slide then
indigenous technology development of us
we have we are developing the technology
ourselves to make it more cost-effective
the next night okay some of the next
again the next so this is our technology
solution and it's deploying deployment
on the field the next which is the
villagers using internet in the villages
then it comes the sustainable model what
we think is that when we reach to the
villages we need a sustainable model to
be working at the village level the next
slide and here we have developed a model
which is a fragment public panchayat
partnership model so the so the private
and the private provides the bandwidth
in our situation the public provides the
infrastructure and the panchayat owns
panchayat is the local self-government
at the village level that owns the
network at the village level so this is
the next life so these are the village
level entrepreneurs the panchayat works
through the village level entrepreneurs
the village level entrepreneurs other
ones that they invest in the in the
network and they recover back 80 percent
of the in in the form of coupons in the
form of that they recover back the money
and can you go to the next slide please
absolutely but you really have 30
seconds yes this is the impact
assessment study that we did so the
villagers over a period of one year they
have saved $300 four months they have
saved 18 miles per activity and three
kilometer three hours per activity so
and the next leg the last life so this
gives an overview of what the village
the entrepreneur does so there is
digital awareness there's e-governance
services that comes to the villages and
at the end there is a revenue generation
that is the motivation that 80% of the
revenue goes to the village and the next
night thanks thank you very much
Giovanni and thank you for your
understanding we had a little technical
difficulty mostly my fault
in the beginning does anyone in the room
have a question for Shivani she's with
granmarg for those of you that have just
walked in we have about two minutes of
questions anyone want to ask Shivani a
question true Bonnie are some of the
villages paying and just because I am
trying to do five devices at once here
are people paying into the system like a
dollar or two dollars to use the network
per month or no so the first stage of
the project that we did when we set up
the test bed over there we did not
charge any money from the villages but
the 25 village that we are deployed
currently here and we are rolling out
the business model the business model of
the village for the first time in
Maharashtra very close to Mumbai a
hundred kilometers away from my and
Hyorin we are charging the money from
them and it is exactly $2.00 for $2 per
month that our user is paying for the
Internet thank you very much we have
time for about a 30 second question and
answer session so if you can do a speed
round Niko and then we'll turn to
Lakshmi because we really want to make
sure we can get him in okay I am
Nicholas for from Malta Mundi I just
wanted to ask you if the innovation that
you are doing with TV white space and
the device that you're creating are you
thinking about what open sourcing or
something related with that thank you
yeah
yes we currently we are waiting we are
waiting for the license the test license
from the government we have applied for
it already so it's in the last stage now
so once the test lies and so our
prototypes are ready we would like to
test the prototypes in the field for the
first I mean we have tested it in the
last project we have tested it already
but we have made modifications to it
currently the devices and we are testing
it we would like to test it once the
license comes true and after that we
would like to open source so the design
is going to be open source and so anyone
can use the design and can start
manufacturing so that is that is what
our agenda is that we are not going to
so commercialization is going to be
based on the open source we are not
going to materialize as such by not
getting some money out of it thank you
very much Rabbani and we appreciate your
patience and that was an excellent
presentation we're gonna clap here in
the room and there may be some questions
after but we're gonna turn over to
Lakshmi so we can get him in and make
sure that we hear from the great work
that they're doing Lakshmi are you ready
I'm ready
go hi oh hi everyone
does anything remotely not to be from
NYU this is joint work with a lot of
people it's on something we call green
apps the main contributor is Talal are
not who is one of my PhD students was
basically leading this work so next
slide this is a picture of a cell tower
we deployed in a really remote remote
place in Gama called commune and what it
essentially gives you is it's a
solar-powered cell tower which has a
radius of about 2 to 3 miles and you
see that you know it's built out of open
BTS and extensions of open VDS and it
can enable a wide range of cellular age
services and we essentially built a
platform called green apps where we can
essentially deploy apps on the edge off
grid so that we can even run these apps
without need for any connectivity to the
Internet so it's a highly localized
cellular ecosystem we also have a
direction of backhaul this is a place
that we did not have good cellular
connectivity so we used a high gain
directional antenna to build a backhaul
to a cell tower that was a few miles
away and we could get two to three
megabits backhaul and I'll briefly talk
about that as well next slide so this is
a picture of a similar deployment in
Nicaragua in another remote place called
feral lagoon and this is in
collaboration with say cell which is a
is PE over the run by Edwin twig Sanchez
next like all these are powered by no
open VDS nodes and many of you in the
audience might have actually used many
of these nodes and might know more about
this than I do roughly the power
requirement is slightly not 100 to 300
Watts depending on you know what are the
features you activate and what vein you
want to operate on next slide so what is
the larger idea the larger idea is if I
were an independent third party cellular
provider like can I just deploy a bunch
of cellular nodes and call myself a new
ISP can I call myself just AT&T and
literally roll out my parallel isp
network now that comes with a lot of
challenges right one of the big
challenges is that how do you interpret
with an existing cellular network how do
you
sure that people from other cellular
networks can call you how do you make
sure that you know you offer a similar
compatible space of services that are
traditional cellular network hands right
now apart from all those features one
very important feature which we want to
enable is this notion of edge based apps
where you can literally deploy apps on
the end node like on the edge node along
with the base station and you can
control these apps through the cloud
over a low bandwidth ring and we have
built essentially built one such
ecosystem next slide so let's just knock
out their bones with respect to you know
what it takes to deploy and what did we
observe one of the funny things we
observed was that solar power was
actually good enough if you want to have
a coverage radius of up to five
kilometers we also did a very detailed
economic analysis I'm sure you cannot
make much out of that chart over there
but the bottom line is there are a lot
of people who are deploying cell towers
you powered by diesel generators we did
a very detailed economic analysis of
solar versus diesel in terms of battery
in terms of panel in terms of space and
so on and we basically found that up to
five kilometers radius solar powered
cell towers are much more economical
than diesel-powered cell towers and you
can also build solar powered cell towers
that came around 24/7 then you don't
have even you know traditional
electricity coverage even if you have
zero electricity covered it becomes cool
run 24/7 next slide so this is the slide
about signal boosted back hops right
initially we tried a whole bunch of back
hard night no traditional cellular and
we tried to just use SIM cards to see if
we can get some bandwidth but then we
boosted the signals significantly we
were able to see anywhere between 5 x -
10 x
improvement for TCP and close to 10x
improvement for you DB the UDP loss
rates were a bit higher but in theory
which we are able to show that signal
booster black holes are technically
feasible so there is very powerful for
deploying cell towers at the edge of the
network where you don't have extra
connectivity so you can literally take
an open BTS base station and you can put
a signal booster backhaul and you can
very easily exchange coverage in in the
if you want to use that type of
mechanism next slide
we also deploy the participatory white
spaces of white spaces solution I will
not get into details but when you
operate these types of networks in areas
where there is no connect I mean there
are potential competing solutions you
see that in many of these places the
full spectrum is not used so we can
essentially use participate to avoid
spaces to keep changing the channel so
that we are not interfering with any
traditional providers next slide so just
to talk about the applications for the
last few minutes we have a larger
architecture which we call as
distributed network services or DNS for
shock for a forum for the pun on DNS but
essentially the architecture is about
how do you literally run these
distributed applications such that you
know a portion of the application can
run in the cloud and a portion of the
application runs on the edge right and
how do you essentially extend the
traditional Sdn framework to support
full-fledged distributed applications
now compared to a conventional Sdn there
are two things that are fundamentally
different here one is the link between
the cloud and the edge is extremely
flaky and extremely intermittent very
low bandwidth and very high latency so
traditional lesbians do not work on
these funders the second thing is that
the app itself is fully distribute
so the app cannot be completely
controlled by the cloud and the app has
to have an independent existence even if
the link completely goes down so it's
more like a replicated Network service
so next slide actually I'll skip this
slide let's go to the next slide so the
first thing we wanted to show where if
you want to build one such a parka
texture you need to really handle
identity is very carefully and then I
say identity it's not about network
identity network identities and
resolving them is actually easy you deal
with a lot of identities at a device
level and at an application level every
state that you use in your application
has an identity right and one of the
questions is who controls that identity
who owns that identity so there is a
huge trade off between what do you want
as consistency properties and what do
you want as likeness properties how do
you handle mobility off identity how do
you handle mobility of state across edge
nodes and you know cloud nodes and when
you have distributed applications
operating over the same state how do you
make sure that they are actually
operating in a consistent manner so
there are specific trade-offs as
specified in the cap theorem between
consistency availability and partition I
will not get into details here but I am
just saying that we build the identity
space management solution to handle this
next slide now we also supported a whole
set of file system primitives around get
and put I'm calling pootis or post and
also such as a way of essentially
building applications in a very simple
manner as if it looks like a file system
so we built a whole suite of
applications on top of a simple
primitive setup where we had just
basically primitives on getting data
putting data and searching for data
based on the identity space if people
are familiar with distributed hash
tables this is basically a similar
building
but it's really extending that concept
to an SP an environment in that low
bandwidth and hi Dennis next like so
like about 30 seconds thank you so they
built a huge spectrum of applications we
build an application where people can
buy and sell goods across different cell
towers we built an application that
people could sense agricultural farms
and collect the data in a distributed
fashion you could send voice message the
voice message could store get stored at
the local base station then get
synchronized with the cloud then get
sent from the cloud to another base
station where the receiver is and the
receiver can check voice messages
similarly we can do a distributed
messaging next like we can support web
caching full-fledged web caching and we
can actually show that you can control
the cache and next slide final slide is
we recently use this to build a fish
line in Nicaragua and people are buying
and selling fish using this platform
with that I will stop and take questions
Thanks thank you very much likes me that
was fabulous and I appreciate both your
instar Bonnie I'm taking time too and
waiting anyone have any questions for
Lakshmi a note that if you're on the guy
list we can ask questions for folks
later and all the presentations are up
okay if there aren't any other questions
right now thank you very much Lakshmi
clapping we appreciate the the
presentations from you sure Bonnie and
from everybody in the room and I'd like
to take two minutes if we can I know our
time is up and I'm conscious that here
at ITF we want to keep - time for moving
forward there seems to be momentum or at
least I've heard today that there are
different there's interest potentially
and learning more about different models
out there would anybody here in the room
today want to participate in an
informational RFC where we bring in well
it would be up to you because it's your
work that
doing but would anybody be interested in
an informational RFC about some of the
work they're doing from a Community
Network side or from the measurement
side I'll leave it up to you open mic
what do you think
maybe one comment is when when the gap
working group started there was a
discussion about what could be the
outcome of course one outcome is any
outcome has to do with the this the name
of the group is global internet access
for all then the work there were several
people from the community networking
environment that they pushed to look at
a dot but it is that that's the only one
that's only one example of a very good
one but one subset of the initiatives so
we're discussing about what documents
are produced and definitely Gaia has
been great for meeting people but at
some point we also need to deliver or
the windy need to deliver from time to
time we had one one informational
document like some time ago it was
painful but delivered so the thing is
can we can we do it again can we do it
more efficiently what are the topics
that we think could be interesting so
that's the open discussion so I'm
Allison Menken I'm the IRT F chair and
this is my first time with you guys but
you shouldn't feel you have to do an RFC
so it's really what is valuable for the
goals of the group and if an RFC would
would benefit the advancement of this
work it's good but if it wouldn't it's
also fine I just wanna make sure that's
clear thank you very much Allison anyone
else
Roche from Griffin ah yeah as a
practitioner community member for us the
process of as a practitioner as a
community member for us it's very
valuable we have short time because
working with communities it's very time
consuming and Africa human but it's also
good from time to time to sit down and
try to do more formal word like writing
and trying comma to come up with
synthetic documents and this it's
valuable for us because it help us to to
sing about what we are doing and because
in the daily base work it's difficult to
all through this process just an
opportunity to learn from the technical
community in the ITF an insulting a way
to stablish context so from at least I
think I can volunteer for the giving it
community if there is other people
interested in pushing this for us it's
it's valuable and it makes sense
excellent anyone else
let's go ahead sir bunny
we can't yeah so yeah I would I would
like to participate in such a thing
because currently we are looking at
different so we have developed the
sustainable model and we are looking
into the model how it is going to work
in the field the business how in how
many years the investment that there
would be a return on investment in how
many years and and how would the village
level network sustain itself
year after year when we move out of the
network would there be would there be
some women entrepreneurs in the village
who would be trying to take this up so
it would be interesting so we would like
to contribute
would like to contribute to this ok
thank you very much Carlos thank you
very much just amplifying what Rosie
said about the value of this work in
particular for instance what Leandra was
proposing about documenting this best
good and bad practices around business
or sustainability or governance models I
think it's very important for those
incipient networks that are considering
how to organize themselves what to
replicate and what to avoid so in that
sense I would price those efforts and I
would if possible I don't know if it's
possible and I didn't know you were the
chair and I would like to I just it was
just running through my mind but is it
possible to not once the document is
obviously concentrated and made
available to
a snippet of organizational models that
compact document made in a video format
because most people in that era starting
community networks in Africa they don't
know how to read so it would be very
valuable to actually translate the
outputs of the best practices into a
format that can be available to the
people that are starting thank you
I think Alison and I are kind of
agreeing but tacitly absolutely and one
thing I would say we it wasn't mentioned
here but one project we know of they're
using color coding for the engineers
because they can't read any of the
manuals that are being produced they're
not they haven't had formal education
but they're incredibly bright people who
are doing lots of great work and so when
we come in as outsiders and we have our
own manuals and our tools which are all
quote either enabled on a device or in
the cloud it doesn't work yeah and this
carlos is saying i think a video
presentation will be amazing at the
Internet Society we do have some
resources where we could help try and
participate in that and if there are
others who would want to it talk to
AfriNIC I don't want to volunteer you
but cool uh that's a great idea well in
order to be cognizant of the time it's
about some one past five and we're
supposed to be out of here at ten of but
I don't want to cut off the great debate
and all of the cool people here in the
room who can talk about actually
providing access and low-cost solutions
and places that are hard to reach I
think everybody here is all about
providing access to the infrastructure
and improving technology and people's
circumstances so I think for those of
you can you raise your hand if you're
here from a community network and you're
gonna be here tomorrow or Friday
excellent we have about four or five six
people and who's doing measurement
studies awesome so if you see these
people around and if you want to connect
with them outside the room we can
continue the conversation and obviously
let's continue online through the gaia
group and see what we can agree on and I
think Landrieu gave us so good ideas a
path forward on let's figure out if we
can keep the scope fairly concise and
then I'll see what we can have for
contributions
and I just want to acknowledge Arjuna
who I've been skyping with and Leandra
for your help and everyone else in the
room that got us ready for this meeting
so thank you very much we'll be back
with you hopefully in Singapore and we
really appreciate you coming here today
and thank you very much and thanks to
the remote presenters that's everywhere
in the room working the system commander
Mundi hi we are Imam we have our members