Oh
[Music]
yeah
Oh
[Music]
hello what hello can you hear me
just working it's not
testing one two three
hello a beep hello hello testing is this
working at all it's working a little can
we have it work a little more yeah I
think the volume needs to go up a little
bit guys is this actually coming for
amplified just this one's going through
a tiny bit
but on it we're trying to get the volume
sorted out of this level hey we go thank
you
testing oh yeah this one's working now
alright now we have our AV issues sorted
out
we'll get on away very shortly okay
Mark's just going to dole out the blue
sheets we already have a note-taker that
image in skis thank you very much if you
have a volunteer for Java relay that'll
be much appreciated anybody we don't
have a reserved chef if you have a relay
you got it thank you Thank You Lee yeah
I think if anything the volume is now a
little too high
does anybody it's good okay sounds very
loud from up front okay we have the
usual why she say not so usual note well
there's been a slight update we couldn't
tell you where it is but you're expected
to read this and know how to know how to
perform with it I should leave that
there for a minute if you are unable to
comply with the note well please depart
the room okay assume that everybody has
read that and is able to comply with it
okay son of a full agenda Bosch window
usual quick update on working to
document status then due to have Jewish
Kroger check talking about the home at
Babel profile and Matthew PTA about
sources arriving within Babel we then
got tired of talking about the naming
architecture and service discovery
documents that we have and sort of the
three latter drafts shown there draft a
CTL on our factory home net documents
but they're um they're they are related
and relevant but I think the main thrust
will be on the CLD end document and then
it has going to continue to talk about
some the NCP security and summation CP
experiences any comments on des
assume not okay so gray were you going
to put the the HNC be stuff graphs
before the I'm sorry yes yeah at Ed's
request we'll probably put the density P
security nation and CP documents
actually before the name and
architecture ones so that some one of
Ted's collaborators can actually and be
in the room flat thanks around 210 okay
so yes working Hopkins update had a
minor update they will profile which do
this talk about Ted sock and also than
we talking about home it's also nine as
you'll hopefully recall just over a week
and a half ago I started a sort of final
one week work and route past all on this
I had a couple of comments come back so
those will need to be incorporated but
I've had a group I are a director that
we will then push that directly to ITF
last call through his ad review and that
we will kill off the whole net with a co
three documents as there's no longer any
need for those two doctrines to go
together as a pair with basically
everything that's needed being
incorporated in the previous home at dot
o nine document we do still have another
other documents which is still
technically around and part of the
working group the latter three in
particular hybrid proxy is still waiting
on DNS SD work front enemy delegation in
Roman architecture eh the options still
probably necessary but I'll waiting on
what we decide as a group to do with the
name in architecture as a whole make
sure that those actually are they fit in
a consistent that all group and it's a
big question on this first one in the
sect which isn't actually working the
document just ends earlier draft eleven
her name in architecture which is
essentially as Einstein have been
replaced by TL diem simple maybe
clarification protector so so I'm still
holding the intention of eventually
making that be a second document that
that is the extensive or advanced home
that name
hopefully that will address the comments
that Andrew Sullivan made earlier to
this as well earlier today okay so
without further ado then let's proceed
with the Jewish talking about having a
table profile would you like the canola
do you listen you like yourself hello so
I'm Julia scrubber Trek and I'd like to
just a few words six lies about the
draft so it's a very simple draft that
has two parts a first part that tells
you how you parameterize babble in a
home that it says look if you have a
Ethernet link use metric 96
okay so babble doesn't tell you what
kind it just tells you you have 16-bit
metric values and here we are saying
look an Ethernet in the home that is
metric 96 or you must do ipv6
you should do ipv4 because obviously if
you have two implementations of Babel
one is ipv6 only one is ipv4 only they
will associate but they won't exchange
any useful words so all of those
parameters have Babel are written down
here and there is a second part which is
somewhat more technical because it
requires understanding of both h and CP
and Babel this speaks about the
interaction between H and CP and Babel
so it tells you things that are pretty
obvious that you think about it like if
you announce an external ipv6 prefix
over H n CP then you must ensure that it
can be routed to next please
now this draft is almost ready it has
just two issues one is that it still
refers to the old version of the source
pacific routing extensions that you will
tell you a few words about that later
and the other issue are the security
requirements next please so in versions
there
zero zero - zero one and I think that's
a typo because the current version is -
zero - so that should be - 0 1 it says
how net implementation of Babel must
implement H Mac based authentication
with preferences and must enable in
require authentication and the link when
instructed to do so by H and CP and I
thought at the time I put it into - 0 0
that that's reflected the desires of the
working group however what was not
obvious to me at the time is that this
requires defining a new sub protocol in
H NCP a protocol that negotiates keys
between H and CP routers and so on and
defining a new sub protocol for H and CP
is out of scope for this document so in
Chicago I asked for this requirement to
be removed from this document and asked
to differ
security to a different document of
which I would not be the editor next
please
and the charts created the committee and
so the committee had a few meetings over
virtual meetings discussed us and
finally the committee didn't do any
protocol work but at least understood
that a new sub protocol is needed so I
think I communicated that badly last
time I didn't make it sufficiently clear
that they knew that some new protocol
work is needed for agency next please
so in that 0-3 I remove the requirement
5 and I added a security consideration
section and basically so I've removed
the bits to negative to fit on a slide
but there are no secrets it's in the
internet browser can archive it says
that the security of a helmet network
relies of having a head set of trusted
internal links with reference to the
agency P documents that are secured at a
lower layer it recommends that you
should not use untrusted links for
transit so that you don't carry
in the HNC PR bable bable traffic or
untrusted links and if untrusted links
are used for transit which is not
recommended then H n CP n Babel must be
secured using an upper layer security
protocol and it concludes on a sad note
by saying that at the time of writing no
protocol for autonomous configuration of
agency BN babble security has been
defined next please
and so what I would like to have the
working group today is that we wait
until the source specific routing draft
until make--the draft is adopted by the
data working group so I don't know when
it will happen because the Babel group
is meeting is later today and as soon as
it is adopted to update the reference in
this draft to the new version to have
somebody review the security
considerations that I'd written not sure
I've done my best
I've written them in good faith but I am
NOT a security specialist I really
appreciate that if a security specialist
could review them and then I would like
to ask for last call thank you for our
attention okay Thank You Jose are there
any questions for Julius
Ted lemon um this isn't actually a
question I'm gonna be doing a
presentation on the HNC P piece of this
in a minute
which we haven't talked about sorry it
would be good if we could talk if we
could actually have a conversation about
how that ever like what your reaction is
to that which I'm sure will happen thank
you sure so I'm not sure that you want
me to try hi
so much abou T so I will just present
use the new version encoding of the
source specific routing in Babel so just
a few background about the way in
Hammett Babel is currently the mandatory
routing protocol to implement for
Annette and the source specific
extension is required so the draft has
been written a long term a long time ago
in 2005 and the current Lisa but the
working group has introduced mandatory
bits which gives a really better draft
simpler but incompatible with the
previous definition so here was the
previous encoding where we have three
new TL reason for update route request
and sec no request pushing the sauce
prefix at one volt at random parts in
the message and the new encoding is just
to have one source prefix meant that we
sub T re so you see it's really cleaner
and the results in better code simpler
and yes so because it's a theory is
mandatory this extension is not
compatible with
6126 but of course the base protocol
remains compatible so as
conclusion for this working group so the
specific routine in Babel will use the
new format which gives a much simpler
extension but which is incompatible with
so we will need a flag day to say now we
use only the new version as gyro says
this may way we may wait for the barbel
working group to adopt a c-stand you
draft thanks for your attention okay so
any questions for Matthew okay well
we're racing ahead of time just before
Ted star sorrow is a mystery sure of it
administrivia that I forgot to do at the
end of our introduction as hopefully the
reason the list no this is going to be
marks last session co-chairing list he's
stepping down and I myself will be
stepping down off to Singapore
it's been five years I think now I think
office wouldn't route session was Quebec
in two thousand or maybe six no six
years 2011
so yeah time to move on hopefully get
some new blood into the group and maybe
actually get some reiteration going
because we've burnt out it's been a long
difficult slob
Terry is still interested in hearing
from anybody who's interested in
volunteering as a co-chair and still be
talking to people this week if you are
interested please email Terry but also
mark and I look available after the
meeting if you want to talk with us
first
okay thank you Oh way out push over to
Ted and as we've read will do the 2d NCP
related documents first
hi so there isn't actually a document
associated with this yet but it's my
intention that there will be if the
working group agrees that this is the
right way to go which remains to be seen
so the motivation here that what
triggered me to get started on this was
actually the conversation that that
julius just referred to i as Julia said
completely misunderstood what it was
that he was asking me to do in our last
meeting and that's really part of I
think why the the work didn't go
anywhere but I actually got motivated to
to dig in deep to this about a month ago
and so I you know reread all the
documents and stuff like that and so the
motivation for doing this work is that
is that we would like to be able to
secure various protocols that run on the
home net that would include babel h NCP
potentially it might be useful to be
able to do dns sex signing it's not
clear exactly how that's all going to
work yet but but basically the key thing
is that so and the other motivation is
is i mean the other aspect of this is
that we don't really know that we need
this but we I think we do need this or I
think we will need this and if we don't
do it now we're going to be in trouble
later so this is why I'm motivated to
work on this now so the status quo right
now is that the HNC P protocol offers a
key sharing mechanism unfortunately it's
not a secure key sharing mechanism in
two ways one is that as far as I can
tell there isn't a way to configure DTLS
to work with h NCP and so even though D
TLS is required to secure the key
sharing protocol there isn't a way to do
that and so therefore it's not secure in
that sense and the other way that it's
not secure is that it's a protocol for
sharing symmetric keys with more than
two entities and hence is not secure so
and and and the
essentially what what the HNC protocol
does is it tries to nominate the best
key or the it chooses one key out of a
selection of shared secret key is
presented by various DNC D participants
and again you know it's a it's a shared
secret so sharing the secret is not
really giving you much security so I
think that maybe partially my fault that
it's this way because I argued for this
years ago and didn't really get involved
in writing the document and so I get
what I paid for but here we are we need
something that's secure and so this is
what I propose
what I propose is that every node that's
participating in H NCP should generate a
public/private key pair and each node
should share its public key is a TL v NH
NCP it's pretty straightforward it's
really no different than any of the
other things that h NCP is doing so now
because every node is sharing its public
key in h NCP every other node every node
has every other notes public key that
means you can do DTLS because now you
have identifiers for every node you have
you have a key for every note so so if a
if a node connects to you the DTLS
handshake can occur using your key and
the key that you know that that node has
and this is a way that you can identify
which nodes you're talking to and this
works not only for for Babel but it also
works for h NCP so with h NCP you know
you start participating participating in
H NCP as an unauthenticated participant
and once your key it but you sign all of
your messages using your key and once
your key is known to the other
participants then they can validate that
you are actually who you claim to be by
checking that you signed your H NCP
message with your key and then so you
essentially have a tofu mechanism for
distributing keys which isn't great but
what it gives you is the ability to both
notice that that a host to know which
host you're communicating with and to to
communicate secretly so for example if
you wanted to diffie-hellman now you
have a basis for doing that
so but that's all it does it doesn't
it's not security it's it's a way of
it's a way of knowing what the note is
that can be used in a security
infrastructure but it isn't not itself
making things secure so just to be clear
about that so if I think that this is
useful I would like to have this I get
the impression that you know Julius
asked us to write this up and so I think
that at least in principle Julius agrees
that this is worth doing I'm hoping that
others agree that this is worth doing
and I'm willing to write the spec if
somebody else wants to participate I'm
happy they have helped Barbara Stark I
think this is exactly the right approach
and I'd be willing to help because I
feel really bad also about not having
done anything since Chicago welcome to
the idea Robert Reich that so if that is
successful it is much more interesting
that you make it I think we all have
this problem of having a actually
determine trust answer in a helmet and
if agency P can provide can provision
cheese to everyone in the network
distribute public keys that would be
really bad big not only from the point
of view of the routing protocol and
agency P itself but especially for all
the application layer protocols that we
want to secure in the helmet yeah one of
the other things that I really feel
motivated to have security for is the
TLS key that's used by the user
interface of your home net right now
when you talk to your HTTP server you
aren't using TLS or if you are you're
clicking through some kind of warning
and it would be nice if we could figure
out a way to make that work as well
although that's not entirely clear from
what we're doing here because we're not
actually sending certs around we could
also have a cert TLV though and I always
find it very unpleasant that the only
thing that goes unencrypted over my
network is what they print usually are
the most sensitive things right good
point and I was going to say that you
know using x509 self-signed certificates
you could achieve the same goal and
within DTLS using TLS handshakes you can
share them
around and if they wanted to have yeah
they could share them around that yeah
the the problem with with with those is
that you'd have to choose
you'd have to elect you'd have to elect
a top of the you'd have to elect a
signer basically no every device does
its own well okay so if every device
does its own self signed certificate its
effectively what you said it's just put
in the package of an x.509 yeah yeah
well right you're right we could we
could just have that TLD and maybe
that's the right thing to do I don't
know I mean there is a point to be made
that we could be using Acme to get keys
for each of these devices that are
actually signed by a PK by the PKI and
then your browser wouldn't even pop up a
warning message when you try to talk to
your web tier to your UI on the on the
device which would be great so yeah
these are things we should have that
conversation and figure out whether bare
key is the right thing or whether certs
are the right thing but but anyway I'm
glad to hear sorry some positive
feedback yeah I have a couple questions
but I'm starting up can you go back to
your first slide please Ted to first
slide yeah yes this one so it's quite
clear from the presentation how this
would authenticate subsequent messages
between H and ours but not quite sure I
can't see how this addresses the first
issue of how you limit which a channels
can participate it provides a thing that
you can identify hnr is with the process
of limiting which H NRS Connect is out
of scope but that is to say I haven't
I'm not interrupt
well I don't know I mean it might be it
might be worth putting that in this
graph too but but you know it
essentially it gives it gives whatever
or whomever is managing the network a
handle to use to identify bad actors and
to also or alternatively and a handle to
use to identify truck trusted actors so
the more reactive and proactive
prevention well you know the we haven't
gone down the path of defining the user
interface of the home and that's what
this does is it basically allows all of
the routers in the network to
to prove that they are who they are and
to repudiate sorry all of ya all the
road to repudiate routers that are not
identified and then those routers can
show up in the user interface and the
end user can say well I don't recognize
that Robert right you know the routers
can actually have like something printed
on the box that says this is the idea of
this router and then when you go into
the user interface you could identify
that's the router that you wanted on
your network and if you see a router
that you didn't want on your network
well you can check the box next to it
that says don't allow this one yeah but
it's looking very useful you know about
wavin aside I participate in a monthly
in SF Coordination called various other
DNS vendors and you know folks and on
our last call good half of that call was
taken up in the discussion of how you
would dispute things like DNS SEC trust
anchors within a home scenario happens
at lot C of my area and Steve prophet
was around in that discussion and this
is exactly something we've talked about
meeting for that right thanks David scan
Ozzy Apple so first off this is really
cool I would really love for the trust
anchor or however we want to call it the
trust establishment the first step to
not be out of scope because every as
we've seen with most of the security
issues this is one of the sharp edges
and if we just say oh we pump that down
the road then everyone will just not
implemented and at the end it'll be just
pointless because anyone can just roll
new public-private key pairs anytime
they want to they want to so I think
this should be an integral part of our
design so let me say this I think that I
think that I agree with you entirely
about your motivation for wanting to do
this I think making it part of the same
draft is not the right move because I
guarantee you that this draft will go
faster than the other one because the
other one is a harder problem and I'd
like to have this solution published as
quickly as possible that doesn't mean
that that we don't do the other bit or
that we say the other bit isn't required
right now nobody's making HomeNet
writers that I know of so we have a
little bit of a an opportunity gap here
where we can fit in this work and so if
we're all motivated to try to make that
to me
what you described happen I mean I think
there's a variety of different ways we
could do it we could do it with with
proximity with with you know with codes
on things and user interfaces we could
do with buttons I mean we could do it
with like you know okay I'm gonna plug
the two routers together using these
ports and then I'm gonna say go I mean
there's lots of different things we
could do but basically what we're
talking about is coming up with a
laundry list and publishing it I think
because I don't think that we have it's
not clear to me that there's one method
that we can require like we can't
require NFC because NFC isn't available
with everything
we can't require you know UI on the
front of the box because some boxes will
have it some won't I mean you know your
Alexa device you could just say hey
Alexa you know add this router and then
plug the router in and Alexa will say
identified new router but that only
works if you have an Alexa or an Apple
home or whatever the Google version of
that is so we can't I don't think we can
mandate mandate a single user interface
but I think having a laundry list of
user interfaces and requiring that at
least one of them be implemented and
available is probably worth I thought
chopped so that is a difficult problem
as Ted said I mean everything else that
we talk about here is software or
firmware so as I said holy I totally
agree I wasn't recommending that we
enforce say this particular hardware
solution by that I mean this particular
radio of this particular button do I
however the laundry list approach is the
one way to guarantee that no one will do
any of them or that two vendors will do
different ones and also this really does
impact what you were talking about
earlier do we use Rockies versus x.509 I
don't feel strongly about either of them
but it impacts this so going forward on
this we can realize that we painted
ourselves into a corner because we're
missing this bit or that so what I would
suggest we do is actually write out that
laundry list anyway not because we think
it's definitive or the final thing but
because it gives us something to work
with and then sit down and think about
like well can we come up with can we can
we draw a circle around parts of this
laundry list and say if you implement
any one of these plus that
one that's enough or I mean can we come
up with something that's reasonable to
require but that's where that's when I
say we need to write a laundry list
essentially what I'm saying is we got to
start somewhere and I think that's where
we start that sounds good to me
great thank you okay hearing no further
questions
now I will tell you an adventure story
[Music]
to the authors of hn CP and the various
demons that i'm about to complain about
please know that i really appreciate the
work you've done and this is not this is
not a slam this is just like you know
there's still work to do so I I'm very
late to this game I had been meaning to
set up H n CP and it made a couple of
failed attempts to set it up over the
course of the past three years but I
finally actually got around to doing it
about a month ago when I was trying to
do this security research because I
didn't actually really have a clear
mental picture of how how h NCP worked
even though i you know read through the
documents and so i figured the best way
to find out is just set it up and see
how it works so i have a home network
it's got a Comcast link and I also have
a tunnel to hurricane and I have ipv4
ipv6 I have an edge router which is an
abuti Linux server and I have a bunch of
Wi-Fi routers they're all running either
open wrt or lead so I figured I had
already I already gone down the path of
discovering that getting a Chen CPU
running on Ubuntu was not trivial but I
really wanted to get it running on a bun
too and I did eventually thank you
Julius
but you know of course obviously I
wanted to use whatever was convenient on
the open wrt routers and so so I did
that as well the implementations that I
had to choose from or agent H net D
which I could not get to build on a bun
too for more money
hi Simha which looked in
interesting but wasn't didn't have any
documentation and shn CPD which had some
documentation but the main thing that
was great about it was that the code was
very readable and so I was able to it
was it's relatively small so I was able
to just kind of grok it and I was able
to get it to build and that was great so
that's so I wanna be using a Jeannette
Dion open wrt because it was a package
and I want to be using SH NCPD on Ubuntu
because it was compiled able so I
installed it on a bun too I installed it
on open wrt I enabled it enabling it on
open wrt was actually quite a bit of
work the documentation was sufficiently
detailed to get me through it but I had
to really think about what was being
said and I had to really build a mental
model before I could get it working like
I couldn't just kind of flip a switch
because you wind up having to actually
change sort of the default interface
layout of of open wrt which is a real
pain obviously in production we would
like that not to be that hard
anyone abling it on a bun too was
actually pretty easy and then the
network went down boom you know I was
just sitting there hacking and so the
network didn't go down when I turned it
on I went down about ten minutes later
and the reason it went down was because
all of my lease is expired as soon as
the lease expired sorry I actually have
a slide about this as soon as the lease
is expired on the upstream from the open
wrt router which is how it was connected
the open wrt router Deacon figured all
of its ipv4 addresses on all of its
interfaces and my host then lost its IP
address and ipv6 for whatever reason
wasn't working and it really sucked and
it took me kind of a while to get my
network back like I had to go around and
like go to the serial console of my open
wrt router and I had to like you know
turn on my TV and switch it to the
console of my my Ubuntu box it was kind
of a pain Julius Julius crabber check oh
if that is a little bit rusty because
all of that stuff that I did two years
ago but if memory serves the reason you
lose
10/8 when you lose ipv4 is because the
gateway stops acting there's nat gateway
to give a chance for a different
function and gateway to collect itself
as the nav gateway yeah okay so you're a
navigator I said okay I don't have any
IDE for let somebody else take take care
of Nats so I believe that is working as
designed yes so I'll get to that in a
minute
so this is actually not the last slide
even though it says conclusions so I
don't really feel like this is quite
ready for demoing if you're if you're a
true believer you can get it working
if you're not a true believer chances
are you're not going to get it working
that is obviously we are not done yet so
and and you know that's understandable I
mean this is a prototype we got all our
work to do the point is that that I got
to discover that face to face and now I
actually am a true believer and want to
get it working so I had a whole bunch of
questions when I was when I was
suffering through my network collapse
which by the way my wife was using the
network when this was happening and I
was not expecting the network to all go
down at once and so it was really
embarrassing it took me a while to get
it back so where where's the problem is
it in the specification is in the
implementations are they all broken
what's the deal and I don't actually
know the answer to those questions but
here's what I think based on what I've
observed thus far there are some things
in the in the specification and that
would particularly include the thing
that Julie has just referred to which
caused the part of the problem that I
saw which is that I couldn't even talk
to my routers over over my ipv4 local
mattad addresses that's broken that's
got to get fixed that's that's not the
right default behavior another reason
that it's broken is because we don't
have a naming architecture and so even
though I'm pretty sure that I actually
had ipv6 I can't it's been a month and a
half since I did this I don't remember
the details but my recollection is I did
a by vb6 but I couldn't figure out what
the ipv6 address of the router was and
so I couldn't get to the user interface
so I had to
anyway so getting a working naming
architecture would really help with this
because then I could have just said you
know connect to the because there's a
there's a default name for the router
that you can connect to that's supposed
to be guaranteed to work and when my IP
before routing was working it was
working so if we had naming working
better than that would work and there's
just a bunch of integration work to do
and I think this is not a hard thing to
do and I'd really like to do it I'd
really like to get to the point where
somebody is curious about H NCP or about
home Ned we have like a very short like
very short set of instructions that we
give them about which version of open
wrt to download and if you're running a
bun to here the packages you install and
it just works I don't know if that's
realistic but I think that's something
we should at least try to do because if
we don't we're not going to do the
learning that we need to do to find the
flaws and the work that we've done thus
far so one of the challenges I ran into
is the spec is like you have to read the
whole spec and then you form your mental
model and then you read it again a
couple of times and then eventually you
understand how it works I think that
could probably be improved and I think
it would be worth doing that it might be
that it gets improved in HNC P Biss spec
or it might get improved in a
informational document a table stock or
something like that but we got to do
something about this I think that the
way it's done the amount of work that's
involved in understanding the network to
the point where you can debug it is too
much and and I think that in h NC p
actually isn't that complicated so it
shouldn't be that hard to understand so
we should do something to help and that
is my last slide comments or tomatoes or
[Laughter]
hello so I'm sure I'm one of the
implementers of HD so thanks for your
bug report I've never had such a formal
bug report ever in my life
so did you can you provide me the
lockers
or did you do I couldn't figure out how
to get the logs
okay did you document what you
experienced in a draft so in mail or in
a big report so I was in kind of a hurry
and so so I have not done all the
documentation I would like to work with
you on on actually solving these
problems I mean that's actually what I'm
alluding to here I think you know I'm
not saying somebody else should go off
and do this integration work I'm saying
I would like to do this integration work
and I'm happy to hear that you're
interested in yeah I appreciate a lot
that you're working we are really all
testing it I have to admit that the
implementation is a bit old that said
the way you present it you're discussing
the validity of the protocol based on
your failure to make it run in your
network right and that disturbs me quite
a lot like in front of 90th audience you
come I was not actually we got students
students like 19 years old they can make
it work so I'm sorry to be that ours but
you were on the slide you literally put
on the slides like not good for them or
not good for like I'm not sure that that
makes me feel any less insulted but but
so so just just to quickly speak to that
point what I'm getting at is not that so
of course I'm perfectly capable of
getting this stuff working and not
speaking for myself I'm speaking for the
actual end users who are the targets of
this technology the people that we
actually want running it for them it's
just too hard even for a reasonably
knowledgeable network person unless they
really really want to get it working or
it's their assignment or they're a
student who has a lot of spare time
which as looking back as a student I
remember having like an amazing amount
of spare time which I didn't think I had
at the time but anyway those are in our
target audience and this has to work for
our target audience and that's what I'm
getting at it's not again really my
point is not to say that you did a bad
job you did a great job it's just that
we aren't done yet and there's a lot
more work to do
right I just want to point that yeah
home that is running is not running out
of the box of the open the village
routers because when you install one
well it's not a day enabled by default
so you have to explicitly enable it
which is already too much for an
end-user second point is that your use
case if I understood it right was with
10 L upstream interfaces which is not
exactly the base audience either
so if sorry with you used tunnel
interfaces right I actually never got
the tunnel working that I wasn't even
really concerned about the tunnel it was
just it was just you know I mentioned my
configuration for completeness all right
well normally it's working like we were
testing it it works I mean part of the
problem is that my edge router was not
running H net D because I couldn't get
it to build on Linux on when to so hi
I'm Bob hinted comments so I don't see
the problem with v4 stopping to work I
think you should look at icmpv6 known
information queries ping 6 - W or just
pinging the all nodes multicast address
will make it very easy to learn although
v6 nodes and then you could have gotten
the address of the router so I get get
sounds to me like getting the V being
able to to local v6 communication you'll
be able to when v4 breaks again you'll
be able to then get to your router and
reconfigure it yeah that makes a lot of
sense and thank you for pointing that
out
mark tells least speaking as a
participant I regarding who's our target
market it's good to keep the end user in
mind so that we can create something
that really someone else can put
together and make deliverable the the
target market for this group should be
you know arrow and apple and Belkin and
d-link I think I'm doing that in
alphabetical order yes
but all you know in you know somebody
that's going to sell it and support it
not to mention service providers as well
that have their home gateways so it
doesn't have to be perfect okay it
doesn't have to be completely turnkey
we'd be given the tools for them to turn
it into something that's perfect if if
if our target market is somebody like
ubiquity or Google then I agree with you
but unfortunately if our target market
is some of the smaller router vendors
they aren't going to do that integration
work and the way that you address that
market is that you put the code and open
wrt and make it work you have an open
wrt distribution that out of the box is
doing the right thing they still gonna
skin it with something of course yeah no
no but that's all they're gonna do
that's my point the only thing they're
gonna do is skin it so if we want it to
work it's got to work in open wrt no
arguments there we've been doing that
since the very first day of trying to
get it working well and hope the wrt
just don't set your sights so high that
you can never reach it they can do a
little bit of work as well and it might
start with ubiquity and Google and Apple
and then the other guys follow who knows
that's all
hi George Michaelson a penny so Ted I
actually think what you had was an
extremely real experience and I don't
think it should be disregarded I think
that sense that something should be
intuitive and you should be able to
construct from scratch it's understood
to have components you build from the
standard component and then you hit a
moment where it doesn't work I actually
agree with you that's a very strong
signal something isn't baked yet and it
might be as simple as there's a wiki
that's not being kept up to date
ascribing some of the stepping stones
you have to bridge over or it might be
diagnostic elements I'm going around in
my head thinking if I were building
systems than they had potential to
become unreachable I'd want a heartbeat
signal coming out of the router and some
packet form on the wire saying me me me
me me so that you could have at least on
low-level TCP dump or something and seam
packet flows on an unbound interface
discovered what you wanted I mean sure
it zeroconf
dns SD something would have been great
but even primitive things should have
been there so I personally think what
you've had is a very real and valid
experience and I go to it's not quite
baked yet it
should be possible to do what you tried
to do it should have work and you're not
done and if you couldn't get it to fly
there's a story there that we have to
think about Thank You Lee Howard thank
you for bringing this you know field
report I think this is exactly the kind
of thing we ought to be welcoming
question was there a home net project at
the hackathon this week I there was no
home not that I'm aware of there were
many using open wrt okay yeah from what
I saw yeah that's that's that's pretty
common there are lots of and there I
should say there is one on multi prefix
employees right is sort of a spin out of
this work it's really the home net stuff
has been done so many times at the IETF
it's really we've moved on to other
things okay I'm just it sounds like Ted
saying that hey there's still more to do
and maybe we do need to wait till we've
got the naming stuff at least suspect
and and that would be you know room for
more implementations I also I could
imagine doing an interim hackathon maybe
at Ed's house we have two bedrooms extra
actually on that note Lee actually what
I think might act might be quite useful
would be to see if there are people who
are interested in doing this and would
like to form a set up your home net with
home net we're a support group I didn't
want to say yes I support group
interrupt testing is a little more what
I think I'm hearing than additional
coding I mean the thing is you don't
really know like doing it doing it at an
IETF really is going to work because
it's not a it's not a you know that's
not where you run into the real problems
right it's when you're it's when you've
got a raw network that's that you have
to cram it into as opposed to you're
building a hypothetical Network Julius I
just like to expand on Bob's point about
naming so one of the reasons for the
apparent complexity of h and CP is that
it is a link state protocol that floods
the whole pathology of the network and i
mean the main algorithm an agency PSPs
algorithm for link assignment and that
how they're in doesn't equal topology it
could very well do is do is a diffusing
approach that was decided for debugging
reasons you do wonderful
okay so in addition to having the
standard protocol that are implemented I
open wrt so things like note request are
simply having the names of the notes
over DNS over if you are locally
connected you do have the full topology
in H and CP and you do have the names of
every single of your nodes in HNC P and
here there are two issues issue one is
we don't have the tools you would like
to be able to launch a command on your
local node and get the full topology and
by the way yes roots are here it's green
because you sweat it over H and CP that
the green Rooter is called whatever so
we haven't built such a tool last year
with the students but the tool never
reach production quality because there
are two kinds of students there's two
bring their stuff to production quality
and those who disappear immediately
after they got their grade right and she
happened to be the second but we do have
the code we do have the tool that gives
you that and we don't yet have the color
of the router over H and CP because we
don't know how there is no interface and
open wrt to find out what is the
external color of the plastic enclosure
so that's a missing few we need a camera
that was a mirror exact second point we
want those tools to work without any
authentication I think so and if
somebody were to add security to home
net to H and C D it would be good to
think about this use case you want to be
able to determine the topology of the
home that even if you're not authentic
authenticated anyway yep yeah thanks I
would actually love to see that code
even though it's not production quality
chef historian I just wanted to point
that the in DHD when you install it on
open wrt part of the UI you get a graph
yeah that's that's really cool of the
topology yeah and that's one of the
things that we presented in many many
bits and bytes and so that's why yeah we
are not so much active in terms of demo
anymore because we have been in the past
a lot
so I think yeah the color the code might
be a bit rusty and yeah help on
maintaining H the t's welcome really we
need help and and for the wiki like yeah
there is no wiki because we don't spend
time to do the wiki because we don't
have time to do the wiki so help on that
as well he's welcome Jordi palette I am
a user of open wrt and naturally from
Lille
which is the revamp name of open wrt and
I believe it was about nine months ago I
was dead testing
they have meta stuff and it was working
for me so unfortunately because it was
working I didn't take out any any report
or anything because it was working right
so we're using home that is your edge
router
I tested several configurations yeah ok
cool I heard of the part of my problem
was my insistence on using Ubuntu as my
edge router makes life difficult I take
it we're being chivvied well thank you
everyone for that discussion I know how
yet another thing to present and this is
a lot longer so sorry about that so the
reason this is long is because I'm not
actually getting a lot of feedback that
tells me that people are following this
work I'm just curious
has anybody who here has read I know
there's one guy in the back and there's
one guy up here in the front who else
has read the the relevant documents
thank you Tim okay that's not too bad
actually so I'm gonna I'm gonna kind of
give an overview I'm actually going to
skip some of the slides there here for
completeness in case somebody wants who
didn't follow the entire presentation
wants to read them and of course you can
ask questions and I'll go back to them
but most of the slides some of the
slides are here just because they might
be useful for answering questions so
first of all the goal of the naming
architecture Billy you look up names on
the Internet
we have to be able to make it possible
to look up names on the internet obvious
we want to be able to publish services
that are reachable anywhere in the home
that we want to be able to discover
services anywhere on the home net and
for those of you who are familiar with
this problem space the reason why I'm
emphasizing that is because mdns does
not work on an entire home that unless
the entire home that is only one link so
non goals these are things that we've
talked about but are out of scope for
this document that doesn't mean we won't
ever do them publish it DNS zone for the
home that in the public dns make service
discovery available off the home net
allow off home net devices to publish
services in the home net and secure home
that naming and service discovery using
DNS SEC these are all things we might
want to do but not in this document name
resolution so what name resolution means
is that we have to be able to tell
devices who to talk to in order to
resolve names provisioning we have to be
able to provide resolution we have to
answer the questions when they're asked
and one slight challenge is we don't
actually know how to solve this problem
what if your multi home and you want to
access Netflix and you look up your
Netflix server using the resolver for
ISPA
and then you connect to the Netflix
server with stream on ISP II that's
going to suck and more importantly
that's going to generate phone calls and
nobody wants phone calls and that's
going to make that's going to limit
deployment so we need to figure out how
to address that I'm gonna hit that point
first because it's really important so
well I already explained this so there's
my theory about this is that there are
two kinds of hosts there are multi home
FEA coasts I mean fake means capable and
there are multi home not fate hosts and
all hosts right now because we haven't
defined how this is going to work fall
into the category of not fake but
hopefully some will go into the category
quickly and I'm hoping particularly that
folks from Apple and Google who have a
lot of influence on this and maybe folks
from Microsoft will participate in that
if we figure out
do it so the idea with multi-home fake
hosts is that if you're if you're multi
on faith then you get prefixes for each
of the homes we'll say there's two so is
PA n is P P you'll get a prefix for both
ISPs if you're capable of handling it if
you're not you only get one prefix and
the home that has to figure out which
one that is which is a problem so if
you're capable you get one prefix and
you get a list of DNS resolver IP
addresses the addresses of DNS proxies
and it's a different list for each ISP
so you will contact a different IP
address if you're looking up a name that
you're going to use to connect using ISP
a versus if you're looking up a name
that you're going to use to connect
using is P P and the reason for that
I'll get to in a minute I don't think we
really need to solve this problem for
ipv4 we don't really have multihoming
for ipv4 anyway so you know we're not
really losing anything but it was one of
the one of the key things we wanted out
of this out of the home that
architecture was to be able to multi
home and if we can multi home but
multihoming makes your life miserable we
haven't succeeded Andrew my name is
Andrew Sullivan I'm just wondering
whether you could say why you think the
host is gonna have a theory about which
is P it's going to use it has to I I
don't think I don't think that I don't
think it's going to have a theory
because because because it makes sense
in the abstract I think it has to have a
theory in order to succeed like so think
about your Google browser right for your
your Firefox browser or whatever right
it is you you you say go to netflix.com
when it goes to netflix.com that's got
to work and so because it's got to work
that means that the browser has to
figure out which is P it's talking to
which sucks but there isn't a way around
it the only way around it is to just say
multihoming yeah so this this feels very
much to me like the economics answer of
in the long run it will all come out
fine in the long run we're all dead and
and the same thing is true here right
that the if every application has to
start knowing oh I'm making this
connection and now I need to know which
is P I'm going to use multihoming isn't
really a whole lot of use so it's right
so for me to understand them so we enter
I mean the general the general
expectation and this is the way it's
been implemented in Android and I think
in Mac OS and iOS is that the hosts are
sorry the application just says connect
to netflix comm and then the operating
system has an API that goes and does all
of the math that I'm talking about and
so from the application perspective you
don't do anything differently at all
except that you have to use this API if
you try to use connect if you try to use
get host by name it's not going to work
you just say connect to host and that
works this is something that we've
discussed at length both in myth and I
think in some other working group with a
camera which yeah so so the the I'm just
I I understand that that's that's what
the background is here but I I think
that I think that you're gonna need a
lot more so first of all the document
doesn't have this you know stuff in it
right right now so the document the
document is not up to date with the
slides so it this is this is at the very
least I think a an instance of the thing
that I sent to the to the list where
what we're doing is is changing our
scope a little bit in order to make it
simple and that might be the right thing
to do but but this is probably not what
everybody thought they were gonna get of
out of out of our plan so that's really
the rock on me yeah so actually Andrew
I'd like it if you could ask answer a
question about what you just said which
is because I pretty much agree with what
you just said except for one thing which
is what would we have done instead
right and that has that has always been
the worry right that that we set a high
bar for ourselves without a clear plan
for how we were going to be able to do
it and if now our answer is G you can't
do that then that our architecture is
fundamentally wrong well but I really
that could be the right answer but I
just I want us to make it explicit not
yeah not something that we just wander
into right but our answer isn't G we
can't do that I mean we had a working
group which unfortunately got closed a
couple of years or a year ago that was
working on the specific problem and so
so our answer is you can totally solve
that problem in fact their existing
stacks that have pieces of the solution
to that problem built into them already
they don't have this particular piece
because this is actually a slight
enhancement so the piece that they have
is I've got two interfaces when I ask a
question about how to connect to netflix
I want a different answer for different
interfaces and I want the connection to
go out the interface that the answer
came in on but but this is sort of the
point that I'm trying to make right that
that a given host in the home net
doesn't even know that there are two
ISPs right that the that's that's a
problem the router has this cannot be
solved at the router so I mean you know
this goes back to happy eyeballs and
things like that the first you know you
need to figure out which of your
connections is going to work better and
I've long been a proponent that happy
eyeball should not just be about ipv4
versus ipv6 happy eyeball should be
about what is the best connection that I
can get and so that's part of it
and then you know the first thing you do
with any connection is your DHCP query
but and that gets into the weirdness
you're talking about I mean your DNS
query sorry
gently ordering and one of the problems
that you're coming up to is that
different domains different networks
have different
stuff in there DNS servers but also even
when they go to the authoritative
servers they get different responses
based on where the query is coming from
but this also gets to the fact that the
home is a different domain and so this
idea that there is one DNS is a real
problem and it's been a problem for a
long long long time because for the same
long long long time we've had different
domains having different private stuff
within their DNS servers that the other
domains don't have and it seems to me
that somehow what we really need is a
happy eyeballs with four DNS so that you
can find the right domain where you're
oh happy eyeballs doesn't David salt
everything I'm gonna let him talk thanks
Barbara David's canaussie so yeah to
answer these points happy eyeballs does
that so this actually like Ted was
saying we stuff a bunch of work in this
working group but this particular
problem is solved we've had this for a
long time at least on iPhones where you
have a Wi-Fi interface and a cell
interface and you want to use series you
want something to go really fast because
users don't want to wait and can you
allow a elaborate and B at the mic to
the mic please George well to finish
what I was saying one of the things it
does is that it does DNS for each
interface because indeed the answers can
be different and then it sends the query
over that elaborate enhancing that to
use the multiple source addresses that
you've received from the various ISPs on
your home network is by no means a
stretch right this is not hard you have
the technology yeah but I totally agree
with you David I mean from my
perspective the this looks bad because
it's it's it's it's like when you're
solving a quadratic equation right you
you you multiply everything out you get
all of these terms and it looks really
messy and then you go through and you
figure it out and by the time you're
done it's like really
but but you had to go through that
process and that's all this is it's
really not that hard it's it's just a
matter of doing it and as David has said
most of the code has already been
written
it's just we need a couple of little
extra pieces of shim technology to get
the information into the stack on the on
the iPhone or on the you know laptop or
whatever so that so that it can do what
it's already doing when it's got to
inter fit to physical interfaces it's
exactly the same problem I should point
out that how difficult is chartered not
to rely or require hosted changes which
does make I'll work a little bit well
that's so that's why that's why we have
the the solution for non fake oast but I
think I think we need to solve the
problem for we we actually need a
solution to this problem we are chosen
we are charter to find things like this
and actually then hopefully something
will spin up a myth work like for
example perfect transition perfect
transition for another draft which is
happening in interior or 6-man maybe
discover and we have an array option for
that it's called multi provisioning
domain discovery of looking for a
provisioning domain and the ability to
get some more information for I mean I'm
repeating stuff that most people here
already here this morning in six-man
there will be another presentation in
interior and another presentation in
captive portal as well so please come
and comment these drafts as well thanks
I don't thing that I also disliked those
proxies the DNS proxies and I really
don't want to require DNS proxy for to
be able to manage my different domains
even though the home domain is not on a
different interface really than the
other interfaces and so I think as we
allow ourselves to have multiple DNS
servers we also need to get away from
this idea that the home has to be you
check the home before you check anything
else and the home has bad news for you
Barbara really bad news remember that
we're doing service discovery and naming
the service
discovery is going to be in home darpa
yes it is but that isn't necessarily
going to be distributed on every single
one of your home network routers in
which one is the one you know what I'm
saying what I'm saying is not that
therefore every home that router has to
be doing DNS proxying all the time but
what I'm saying is you have to have a
proxy in the home net because the query
has to go to some place in the home net
because otherwise if you say there has
to be a DNS server there has to holding
that responding to DNS query is whether
it's a server it has to intercept all
DNS queries and say is this home ARPA or
is this external and if it's external
then proceed to launch the query
externally as opposed to the device
itself querying the local DNS server and
querying the other devices can't do that
how would you do that happy eyeballs
multiple DNS servers no that's not the
way that's not what multi remember
remember the whole DNS architecture has
this idea which we all believe in sort
of that the DNS is uniform so we
wouldn't but it but that's what it looks
like and and and that's what every
that's what every stack assumes so we
can't demand that everybody changed
their stacks to do this this query a
really bad assumption George for my team
ik Ted how many slides have you got I've
got then we're about a third of the way
up here the preservation like it's not
that this is a low value conversation
because it is absolutely a high value
conversation but I think it's at the
wrong time I only hear the rest of your
argument I don't know it's better you
get to continue so that we can
understand context you're early in the
stage III agree with both of your points
one I think we really do need to have
this conversation and two we need to
finish this slide deck two
I think that having this conversation
also is something that is not entirely a
home net thing although it's certainly
highly relevant Stewart yes I agree we
should move on so I'll make a very quick
point which is a request for everybody
discussing the microphone the term DNS
server is easily misunderstood so let's
say recursive resolver or authoritative
server because they're very different
beasts and yes in the same name indeed
indeed that that distinction is part of
why I think that company we were having
the confusion we were having in the
conversation so yeah let's move on a
little bit so this is just some more
text about how to how to how to
provision devices I don't think we
really need to go into this right now
just know that this information is here
if you want to talk about it later we
can again I'm calling it a DNS proxy
because because it's it's it's DNS proxy
is like a switch in a network you might
plug directly into the router or you
might plug into the switch but the
switch is the lowest common denominator
so that's why I'm using that term and
what it has to do is it has to determine
whether the name is local or not if it
is local it sends it to the local
resolver if it is not local it sent at
the ISP resolver and as I mentioned
earlier the source address the reason
why the resolver is PA has a different
source at a different address and there
was Oliver her is BB is so that the one
actual piece of software that's sitting
there listening for these requests can
look at the source address and say oh
this is a query for is PA or oh this is
query for is BB that's all it's for so
and and to Barbara's point this doesn't
have to be a proxy that's just minimal
so a service discovery so the main model
for service discovery is the one we've
all been talking about for a long time I
don't want to go into a lot of detail
about it but it's the discovery proxy
formally the hybrid proxy I have written
a new draft which I will be presenting
in DNS SD on I think Wednesday
yeah and this is Stewart and I have
basically been conferencing
every week for the last two or three
months about this and so we've done a
lot of work and so Stuart's got a whole
bunch of cool stuff which you'll see in
here I've got this this is my main thing
I actually coded this up because I
wanted to make sure that I didn't miss
anything and so so it's a split model
where you have a very simple relay in
every home that router and then you have
one or more discovery proxies that are
talking to those relays and providing
actual DNS lookups or answers to DNS
lookups so every link has its own
subdomain of home dot ARPA there's an
advertising proxies own the story are
you still using that name advertising
proxy I realized when I was writing
these slides that we hadn't actually
talked about that in a long time so the
advertising proxies well you'll see that
on the next slide but but this is just a
terminology question I'll refresh your
memory you actually talked me out of
doing that oh we the discovery proxy
let's a remote device that's not able to
multicast on the link reach in from the
outside and say do these queries for me
the advertising proxy was imagined as
the mirror image of that which is a
service that's remote can reach in and
say advertise this for me using
multicast you are totally convincing me
that we should actually try to be moving
away from multicast we should not be
encouraging more use of multicast occurs
as expensive on Wi-Fi it's if expensive
and unreliable and hard to do on mesh
networks there's a number of reasons why
multicast is valuable for certain zero
configurations in our ears because the
network gets bigger it rapidly becomes
not a good solution thank you so so in
place of in place of advertising proxy
in the slides that follow please
consider using the term authoritative
nameserver jabber scribe requests it
happens that I know the name of
everybody who's come to the mic so I
haven't needed it but please do say your
name when you come to the microphone yes
okay so so basically what that what this
means that there are
our n plus-1 zones where n is the number
of links or possibly there are two n
plus one zones because actually after
the discovery proxy has two zones for
each length but anyway the point is
they're purling zones and then there's a
then there's a zone in which things that
use Stewart's registration protocol will
register their names hosts browse all of
these zones either directly or through a
discovery broker which is another thing
that Stewart has a draft about so the
required infrastructure here is that
every home net writer can if needed so
every every hundred router has to have
the following things on it has to have a
discovery lease actually it doesn't
really have to have a discovery broker
it has to have a discovery process it
has to have as it has to have the
software to do a authoritative server
for the home dot ARPA zone and it has to
have a discovery relay every home net
when it's running will have probably a
discovery broker certainly at least one
discovery proxy and should have a this
is the problem with name changes and
inflight should have an authoritative
server for the home darpa zone and every
link on the home that will have at least
one discovery relay and ideally actually
it's probably better to just have one
but anyway so a typical home that might
have it might look kind of like this
right it might have home DARPA that's
the Agra the authoritative the zone for
which there is an actual authoritative
server with state it will have the link
one homes on our pizon which is the zone
on which we receive mdns stuff for link
number one it will have the you know
it'll have three links like that and
then home DARPA assuming that we have a
discovery broker home DARPA will be
listed as the only browsing zone so when
when you want to browse using this
remember this is using RFC 67-63 DNS s D
so it's actually using DNS to do service
discovery not mdns so when you do dns SD
you go you look up you get a list of
zones that you have to browse which can
be an arbitrarily long list
ideally it's not arbitrarily long and so
here we're saying if we have a discovery
broker you're just gonna look up in
one's own home DARPA so what happens is
the host sends a message to the DNS
proxy or whatever asking the question
can you find me PTR records for the
domain name underscore IP be underscore
TCP home daughter the DNS proxy says oh
that's home DARPA I'll send that to the
discovery broker discovery broker then
then sends a message the advertise to
the to these so the authoritative server
for home dot art by asking if it has any
PTR records for IPP TCP DARPA and at the
same time it sends to whatever to start
discovery proxies it's aware of the same
question only for only it actually
explicitly names each of the links okay
like this okay and then the answers that
come back suppose that there's one one
of the printers is using the
registration service and so it actually
registered a name in the authoritative
zone that will send back an answer that
yes there is an IP p t CPM DARPA in PTR
reg printer home DARPA I'm using like
sort of geek readable names here
actually these names might be human
readable names like printer space at
space dead space desk or something like
that it doesn't have to be reg printer
but it's just easier on slides so the
and and then suppose there's also
another printer that's only doing mdns
and that's on link one it'll also send
back a PTR record I'm not putting the
relay proxies in here because they're
just kind of therefore they're there
they're essentially just a way to extend
for the advertising proxy to ask sorry
for the discovery proxy to ask questions
on multiple links so so the broker gets
back answers from two different sources
it puts them together and sends the
combined answer back to the DNS proxy
and then the DNS proxy sends the
combined answer back to the host so this
is the sort of topology we've got here
we've got
a number of different places and some of
these functions might actually be
combined like it's entirely possible to
have a discovery broker that's also a
discovery proxy and and just kind of
merges those two functions and you know
you could have in principle you could
have the discovery broker the
advertising proxy and the discovery
proxy all be one piece of software
that's doing all three tasks or they can
be completely separate and be speaking
DNS protocol to each other it's it's
entirely up to the implementation how to
do this but they the functions need to
be there in the sense that it needs to
be possible for the broker to talk to a
discovery proxy actually it doesn't
really need it the broker could just be
talking the broker could be talking to
its internal discovery proxy which is
talking to a relay proxy on each link
and so there's actually no need for an
explicit break between the discovery
proxy and the discovery broker but you
know they are separate functions in the
functional chart I am gonna skip these
slides because I've already explained
this but they're here for your reference
so basically the reason I put these
slides in here is in case anybody needs
to drill down more and wants to ask
questions but I don't think that we need
to go into detail because I think
everybody in here already knows this
stuff so the status right now is that we
actually have a lot of the specs written
they're not done they're mostly - zero
zeros but we thought this through pretty
thoroughly and I think that we're not
too far away from having something which
is either mostly complete or entirely
complete and I did an implementation at
the mdns relay right after that Stewart
and I changed the spec so it's not in
sync with the current spec but it'll be
pretty simple to update it and actually
you look the code will be cleaner so
it's great the registration protocol is
nobody's done in an exact implementation
of the registration protocol but Tok
sorry I don't know how to pronounce your
name
has done a a piece of it and the code
that he's written should be eminently
adaptable to do what what Stewart's
written so my point being aside from
that one little thing that we tubed on
earlier if the working group decided
that what's in this document as it is
now is the right thing we're actually
pretty close to done and I'd like to
encourage the working group to think
that way in the sense that it would be
really nice to be done so so if the
working group is okay and I've come to
the working group with various proposals
at various times and been shot down I'm
really hoping that the working group
isn't gonna shoot this proposal down
because I think it's pretty complete I
think it does what we need I think it's
good I'd like to do it Julius do you
still hate me I'm enjoying our
discussions about Julius crabchek so I'm
sure I'm not the only person here
looking at that specification and
thinking there's lots of moving pieces
in this fewer than in your previous
proposal that there are still quite a
few and I think it might be worthwhile
to sit and think really hard then wipe
the blood of her eyes and check very
carefully whether we actually do need
all of those moving pieces and I've
tried to start a discussion at some
point many months ago on that and your
answer was your proposal doesn't meet
the requirements at which point I asked
what are the requirements and you
answered very good point there aren't
written down yet so what I would really
appreciate so that we can feel more at
ease with this and I'm not saying that
I'm against her in favor
I'm just saying that I would feel much
more at ease if we could have a listed
requirements and perhaps rather than the
formal list of requirements which are
always difficult to read a list of
scenarios if we manage to solve those
five scenarios we are fine something
like that not necessarily an internet
draft emailing a carefully redacted may
link to the mailing list
would be fine but just to have their
basis to discuss stuff yeah I think
that's a reasonable request hi chose
Michaelson from aap neck so I think
you're right to say that this is
something that should probably be close
to done for the level of which it can
define how to do things and I think some
of the confusion in the conversation at
the microphone at least for me as I
understand it is that I think people are
wanting to see much higher abstraction
of behavior and talk about decision
logic for the right name and the right
address which I hold naan microphone
noise to say that's a multi-dimensional
problem and I think saying oh we solve
that in happy eyeballs no you didn't
what happy eyeballs does is it projects
a single dimension of problem to say
what best is and on my platform of
choice Android there is another
dimension there's a hit knob that says
preference Wi-Fi over cellular at all
times and it has no consciousness that
my cellular provider may be offering
zero zip zilch zero charge off can't
access the high bandwidth TV and the CDN
provider that I get from DNS lookup may
well say no no no use this Wi-Fi binding
go suck it on Wi-Fi consume my Wi-Fi
limits and leave me unable to use Wi-Fi
to do other work it's a
multi-dimensional problem the best
mapping is a higher-order question what
you have laid out here is an
architecture for saying based on coming
up from the ground based on being multi
provider how do I find what name to
address mappings there are and you
introduced actually I will say I think
Stewart was absolutely correct to say
please use the correct labels for the
DNS functioning elements I think that
was an extremely important comment and
you do that and I respect that you
introduced an idea called a broker I
like that idea
I see brokerage is a very good
abstraction for what is the best choice
because it puts it into that
multi-dimensional question it depends
the best is not what happy eyeball says
it's a complex decision that you are
describing in architecture for building
that model I like that I think you
should close off on this it's good
thank you that's your chair sure from
Apple I just want to start off by
thanking Ted for not only doing all this
work but taking the initiative at the
last IDF we agreed to focus on this and
Ted set up a weekly two-hour conference
call every Thursday which was kind of
grueling but it it kept both of us
honest and we had to like make some
progress for the next week's call so
Thank You Ted for making that happen
I think we were so burnt out on that
that we didn't have time to sync up on
this I think one of the things we should
do is make some diagrams make theirs a
lot clearer than words I don't know
whether we'll get that done between now
and the DNS SD meeting on Wednesday but
maybe we could try if you have a good
way to make diagrams I'd love to see it
okay and and the other thing I will say
for people's information one of the
drafts I did as the result of this is
the roadmap draft which is an attempt to
explain how some of these moving parts
fit together and to explain why each one
of them is there you know that also
could do some ASCII art diagrams in it
which I didn't have time to do but for
people who are interested in figuring
out bit more that's why I wrote the
roadmap because we realized they were
getting to be many moving parts and it
was not obvious to outsiders what they
were for
I'm Andrew Sullivan and my employer
tells me that I don't speak for them so
I'm not going to mention who they are
the I agree first of all with what I
think what Stewart was just suggesting
which is that the number of moving parts
here is is probably actually the
irreducibly small set and and I think
that that's okay but I'm a little
concerned about the about the suggestion
that we heard a moment ago that we don't
really have requirements because we do
write we had this architecture document
that we published and it's got a lot to
say about this about what the naming
thing is supposed to do and and and this
pozole as I said to the list and I said
I suggested earlier doesn't entirely
meet that and I I'm mostly persuaded
actually that that's fine so I guess
what I want to ask is you've got this
last bullet here it says we could be
done in fairly short order and get on to
the advanced HomeNet naming architecture
and I want to ask this time why you
think that that would be a thing we
ought to do because I'm not totally
convinced if we think that this is too
complicated people are going to find the
next one to be you know non Euclidean
geometry and it's probably not going to
get published yeah so you know the
problem with any this is the reason why
I actually sat down and wrote code
because the problem with any spec that
we theorize about is that it's really
easy to theorize and you often miss the
details and unfortunately when you stop
theorizing and start writing code you
realize that there are complexities that
you haven't thought about and that's
what you're seeing here what you're
seeing here is that is that this has
actually been implemented the
implementation is not big it's like
2,500 lines of C code which I would
really rather not have used except that
it's got a run on open wrt but so it's
it's it's it's really it's really not
that hard to do and of course my
implementation doesn't have all of the
stuff in it so I guess I'm exaggerating
slightly but it really it really isn't
that bad the thing that's that makes it
look bad is that all the details to the
best of my ability are here and to me it
feels like we're close to completion
because we're kind of to the dregs we're
kind of like like the the multihoming
thing is kind of the hardest problem
that's left everything else seems
totally tractable I have a specification
for how to manage the interface between
the if you read the mdns relay docket it
actually has a specification for how to
manage the interface between the the
mdns relay and the discovery proxy and
that would fit very nicely into hn CP so
in fact it was written with hn CP in
mind
I think I think we really are very close
to victory here and and it's not as bad
as it seems and therefore I think that
if there is interest and I don't know
that there is I mean I get the
impression that there are a fair number
of people in the working group that are
interested in the advanced hum that
naming architecture if I'm wrong about
that then absolutely we don't need to do
it I mean I'm interested but one person
being interested isn't enough so so if
it's just me great we can stop and and
frankly this is a lot of work I'm
enjoying the work but I don't need to
keep doing it so yeah if it's really up
to the working group whether to do
whether to do the follow-on work and and
indeed if we don't do the follow-on if
we decide that we really don't want to
do the follow-on work there are some
simple simplifications we could make to
the simple on that naming architecture I
don't think that's worth doing because I
think that even if we decide now oh we
don't really want to do this we might
decide in five years oh we really do
want to do this
so I know I think it's I think it's it's
it's an open question as anybody I mean
I'm curious maybe if I could get a show
of hands does anybody even remember the
the previous on that naming architecture
document okay of those people who
remember it
do you remember it fondly or unfought
Leith if so so raise your hand if you
remembered fondly I think some questions
are better left unanswered I know how
you feel about it Julius so so we didn't
get really good a rate in the show of
hands there so I guess I guess when I
asked if anybody remembered fondly no
one raised their hands so maybe that's
that's the answer to my question well
from the chair and it's not necessarily
that it's not fun this I think longer
term we do need to do this I should I'm
part of my rationale standing down is
that I would actually like to really get
into some of this stuff and I think I
can do that better from the floor rather
than from the chair so come while
Singapore or later I really would like
Thunder stuff I propose that actually we
go to a call for adoption on the list on
TLD M sorry this is not of this
particular draft just tell him yes on
the sticker draft and then press on with
it I would kind of like to reinforce I
think what Judas was suggesting that we
need maybe a little bit more detail
about the end-to-end process one of my
concerns from the chair with the earlier
documents we had around naming and in
part why the front end name delegation
of stuff and that has been passed so
long is that even as a naming guy myself
I hacked I couldn't follow the
end-to-end resolution process both for
internal names and for external lanes
with the documentation we had I think
it's important that it's clear to people
how hosts do get all the names and from
that when if you're the host okay okay
are they any other questions on lunch
okay Thank You Ted so I have one last
thing as I said earlier this is Mark's
last session as well group chair so I
would like to sincerely thank him very
much for his open for the last six years
and I hope they will feel like wiser
[Applause]
so long and thanks for all the fish and
yeah it's been it's been a wild ride
some incredibly good work has been done
and I appreciate every single time
somebody gets out there and tries to
make a home network and make it better
and contribute more code because that's
what we're all here for I can't wait to
go buy one of these and install it in my
home and it just work make it happen
guys thanks I got okay
if you haven't signed blue sheets could
you please do so we've got one set here
the others must be out in the room
somewhere and thank you all and I will
see you in Singapore
you