[Music]
right yep yeah
not just these lovely
good morning everyone brave people of
Friday morning and being scheduled
against quick and still being here
that's great thanks so much so while you
are so dedicated I am sure it will not
be hard to find a note taker and a
jabber scribe we have a note taker
perfect and we have a jabber scribe
someone willing to jabber scribe
jebra scribe
do I need to ask the last person to come
in to be the driver scribe
[Music]
hello everyone welcome very much to the
human rights protocol considerations
meeting Friday morning July 21st also
welcome to remote participants we got
quite a full agenda here and a bit
different schedule from normal we made
two changes in the schedule as discussed
on the list is that we have a longer
session then normally because we often
ran out of time and instead of having
three or four speakers for inspiration
we took one so we would have more time
for discussion you would go into a bit
more depth I'm also happy at the end to
see whether you think this is a useful
model we should revert back or we should
go out otherwise they are the
administrivia we have a note-taker do we
already have a volunteer for the
different scribe we have a jabber scribe
excellent thanks so much please join the
main list if you haven't done so already
poor requests for drafts are welcoming
github you can find the intros the
minutes and a website there I said we
have quite a full agenda does anyone
have any other points for the agenda
agenda bashing one to approved here we
go so this is the note well if you
haven't noticed it well then you haven't
noted so well during this whole week
because it's Friday morning so if you
have any IPR claims you would like to
make or you have any IP are things for
anything you'd like to present please
tell us now because else it's too late
so as always it's very important that
you review documents not only because
then we have a man can have a more
informed discussion but also the quality
of the IETF documents depends on your
reviews so please review documents your
own working group also in other working
groups and then we will also
review your documents so the step
research group we have been we've been
quite Britney we have been working on
the topic since ITF 91 we've been a
proposed research group since ietf 92
and you see we have a pretty consistent
production of work actually with a smart
increase in a number of drafts and also
continuously new things coming about
which you also see things in the
presentation of it so what we're trying
to do as is in our Charter is to expose
the relationship between protocols and
human rights with an initial focus on
the right of freedom of expression and
the freedom of assembly we've tried to
propose guidelines and also see how
those guidelines could work in practice
and also to increase awareness of the
human rights community and the technical
community about the importance of
technical workings of the internet and
its impact on human rights and then we'd
like to start off with a presentation
and Q&A with wilt Milton Mueller Milton
is professor at Georgia Tech dr.
famously of network and states and
ruling the route and he's gonna tell us
his findings that he's working on with
the paper with prasanna ba da also from
Georgia Tech Milton
[Music]
well thank you I'm pleased to be here
I'd particularly like to think I've and
Niels for inviting me I think it's very
interesting that they were so eager to
have the discussion I do want to say
that the idea for this paper was in fact
Farzin s and she couldn't be here today
she has a bit of a human rights problem
being Iranian and living in the u.s.
she's afraid to leave or at least was
until the Supreme Court settled that
issue we hope so so I'm here giving this
talk and it's called Ric wium for a
dream just to give you a brief summary
of the somewhat provocative points we
want to make yeah first of all we want
to subject the belief that we can
promote and protect human rights through
protocols and standards or architectures
to some critical assessment and I in
particular have a very long background
in an old guy in science technology and
society studies and history of
Technology and you'll see the
intersection of that discipline to what
you're doing here we think there are
tendencies within this push that
oversimplify the complex relationship
between technology and society and that
you all might benefit from this critical
assessment fundamentally we believe that
human rights are primarily a political
and institutional accomplishment and
cannot be reduced to a matter of
technical design although we of course
believe that technology dis equilibrate
s-- existing institutions and alters the
way society works it's not simply a
matter of technical design and there are
also some disturbing aspects of
potentially negative aspects of the
trying to make policy or protect or
enable rights through your tech
designs so let me first try to
characterize the views boom that we are
criticizing and the fact of the matter
is we quickly discover that there is not
a simple or uniform statement here that
is some clearly theoretically derived
position we have a spectrum of views so
at one extent some people are asserting
that human rights can be protected by
design or through the internet protocols
and given that technologists have a
moral and legal responsibility to do so
this in particular is coming from a sort
of international law scholars like
Kareem cath and Florida who are very
steeped in the Universal Declaration of
Human Rights so that's another aspect of
this so the many people within this
group are very eager to connect not just
generic things like privacy or freedom
of expression but very specifically the
actual human a Universal Declaration of
Human Rights of the United Nations they
believe that that can be enabled to the
protocols or as one of them put it quote
baked into the architecture at design
time now a slightly weaker and probably
a lot more practical statements of what
you're trying to do come from your own
HR PC document not what I don't know
whether to call in RFC or not yes I
think it is so it talks about Internet
connectivity as enabling human rights in
other words taking a technological or
creating a technological capability that
advances freedom of expression and
there's a statement in there that the
architectural design of the Internet
converges with the human rights
framework which we frankly don't know
what that mean there's another statement
that the human rights enabling
characteristics of the Internet might be
degraded if they are not
find described and sufficiently taken
into account in protocol development so
that is again a step back from the
harder position that human rights can be
protected by design what they're saying
here is let's be aware of impacts or
potential impacts when we're developing
protocols to try to relate this to the
academic literature we find that there
are sort of two distinct positions here
one of them is a stronger claim the the
famous claim at least made famous by
Lessig but developed by others before
him that code is law and then there's a
somewhat weaker and we think more
accurate claim that the technology
mediates rights that is it is a kind of
an intermediary between the
accomplishment of Rights on the one hand
and the the technical the the efforts by
people to use it in ways that either
compromise or advance human rights and
that latter point is I think articulated
in Laura denardis work and of course the
code is law claim has a lot of
precedents including the Lessig Joel
ridin burg Mitchell somebody named
Mitchell who I don't even know what's
probably the first to articulate that
claim
now just to sort of summarize the
differences in the two perspectives with
the code is law you're focusing on the
ex-ante initial design of the protocols
or the architecture whereas at the other
perspective you're focusing more on
ex-post attempts the infrastructure is
in place and people are trying to do
things to it that either compromise
human rights or advance human rights for
example denardis and others have
frequently focused on the famous SOPA
and PIPA laws
which we're trying to use domain name
system blocking to to enforce copyright
or prevent copyright infringement in the
United States now this is clearly not a
design a really a redesign of Internet
protocols that was an ex post attempt to
use the capabilities of the
infrastructure to block or filter
certain kinds of things that were
perceived as violating copyright the
code in law perspective is fairly linear
and deterministic essentially it asserts
that whoever makes the design makes the
rules and you're all kind of bound by
them whereas the other perspective has
more of a two-way relationship in mind
and they view the infrastructure as a
site of struggle over rights and this
struggle we believe is as much if not
more political than technical so with
that characterization sort of the theory
and practice will now go into our
critique well the first thing that we
notice and again this point is certainly
contestable at some point but for a very
large extent the Internet is already
designed its basic architecture is in
place this is not to say that it doesn't
change that there aren't marginal
adjustments and changes that there
aren't new standards but any kind of
protocol development that's going on now
and the IETF is not going to have an
immediate and major impact on the way
things work much less on the degree to
which human rights are enabled over the
Internet and there's something also
interesting about that is you know if
indeed new standards or new processes
within IAAF are needed to protect human
rights it seems that seems to indicate
that its current architecture does not
necessarily protect human rights that
this again is more of a site of struggle
rather than baked into the architecture
the second problem is we have some
difficulty understanding the extremely
strong linkage that is asserted between
the UDHR and international law and the
technical architecture that is to say if
you say I am trying to protect through
my protocol the confidentiality of data
I know what that means very clearly if
you're saying I'm trying to protect the
right of privacy as defined in the UDHR
I'm not sure I do know what you mean if
you say I'm trying to protect the entire
set of human rights and enshrined in
this standard I'm absolutely sure I have
no idea what you mean by that because
the UDHR and the whole complex of
international human rights law is
extremely extensive and complex it was
formulated in fairly imprecise terms
they're not all of the rights in there
for example the right to a job I'm not
sure you're going to help that with your
protocol development maybe the right to
developers to a job might be in some way
advanced by what you do here but some
rights as the the committee here
recognizes in their document are not
that relevant to ICTs or connectivity so
again that's that's a big step back from
the general claim about human rights
now even the rights that you consider to
be the most relevant to the Internet
contain serious internal conflicts so
one of the obvious ones is free
expression versus privacy the human
rights declaration says that everybody
you know the famous article 19 after
which I think Neil's has tattooed on his
forehead somewhere says that you know
freedom of expression everybody has a
right to seek and impart information
regardless of frontiers it's great it's
one of my fav
formulations of the right to freedom of
expression but then later on it says
everybody has the right not to be
defamed to not have their reputation
besmirched by others and so those two
things can obviously clash so how do you
do that in a protocol free expression
versus intellectual property is
intellectual properties actually
recognize human rights so and it's
ironic that many of the people who are
in the forefront of the theoretical work
on this human rights and protocol
development connection were people who
were resisting the attempt by copyright
owners to fake copyright protection into
the Internet infrastructure and there's
clearly they were doing this kind of on
free expression grounds and on
differences over the scope of
intellectual property rights so again
there's it's not clear that there's a
linear or simple relationship between
these rights and the protocols or the
even the infrastructure due process for
the accused versus swift justice for
victims that you could view that as kind
of a tension if not a contradiction
obviously human rights puts great
emphasis on due process but it's also a
human rights issue that if you don't
catch bad bad people who do evil things
so there's a tension there now again the
the HPRC people are not naive they
recognize this in their documents but to
my mind the response is quite lame
they're sort of saying well you need to
balance them okay how are they balanced
how are they balanced in a protocol this
is not clear to me decisions on design
and deployment need to take rice
conflicts into account okay what does
that mean to take them into account how
do you reconcile them how do you
make these rights into the architecture
when you are that when you have these
conflicts and needs or balances so that
is what we consider to be one of the
major issues with the the linkage that's
being forged problem three probably this
won't be too controversial code is not
law okay and to understand this you
simply have to ask yourself where does
code come from it's not purely exogenous
it doesn't drop down from the sky
whoever writes code is responding to
economic incentives almost certainly
probably political doing it in a
political environment and there are
certain kinds of legal and political
constraints so there's a reciprocal
relationship between what code gets
written and the surrounding society and
in fact code and architecture can be and
often are overridden by laws and
regulations and so a good example of
this comes right here from the IETF and
the famous interaction that this group
had with the kaliya
which is in the u.s. called the
communications assistance for Law
Enforcement Act now if you remember is
sometime in the early 90s the telephone
systems started getting digitized and
the wiretapping technologies of the
law-enforcement agencies and Intel
agencies realized that their techniques
were not able to capture information in
the same way so a law was passed in 1994
and this is really before the internet
was a big thing
perceived as the widespread mass medium
so they passed a law forcing us
telephone companies to redesign their
network architecture to facilitate
wiretapping of telephone calls by law
enforcement and then of course the
internet became a big thing and the law
enforcement agencies noticed that they
didn't have any such capabilities for
the Internet
and when the IETF was working on
standards for voice over IP and related
things
somebody suggested to them I've seen
assertions that the FBI asked the ietf
but I've never found any verification of
this request but certainly there was
discussion of what to do about whether
their standards or voice-over-ip should
be made Kalea compliance and so they
formed the famous Raven working group I
think it was in October or November of
1999 and it concluded in May of 2000 and
the IETF basically said no no thanks
we're not going to write rewrite our
standards to make them compliant with a
US law as you probably remember the main
reason for that was not so much human
rights per se although the the tenor of
the group was very very Pro privacy Pro
individual rights and anti-government
anti-surveillance but they basically
said we're a global standards
organization and we're not going to
write standards to the specifications of
one government so did that settle the
matter did we have successfully protect
privacy on the Internet well of course
what happened next is that in 2004 and
five all of the law enforcement agencies
went before the US Federal
Communications Commission and filed a
petition to expand kaliya to broadband
providers voice over IP telephony and
instant messaging of course this laws
would only apply to us-based providers
or people with the major jurisdictional
Nexus in the US and of course the civil
rights civil liberties groups oppose
these requests the Electronic Frontier
Foundation in particular was in the
forefront of the opposition but this was
post 9/11 America and surveillance one
politically over privacy and individual
rights so we got a kaliya compliant
broadband providers however the
technology of the internet was
sufficiently diverse
complex and changing that there was
continued to be this struggle over
surveillance and privacy as you all well
know indeed in this period the FBI and
the NSA continue to claim that they're
going dark and privacy advocates
continue to worry about the massive
scope of surveillance on the Internet so
what lessons would I grow from the Kalia
case well one of them obvious ones is
that the so-called bad guys or the anti
human rights forces can use a standards
process to they can specify you know
let's get into the IETF and try to urge
them to do something let's get go to the
regulator and tell them to pass new
standards that were a compulsory so
there's no nothing about doing things
via standards and makes it throw human
rights it the other conclusion is that
code was code in law was law the ietf
refusal to make its architecture
modifications did not settle the matter
by itself and after the FCC intervention
there were some law dictating code and
then we saw norms code law and markets
working together as elements in a
political struggle over privacy here's
another problem we do want you to
consider and that is if standards
developers do think of themselves as
being in the business of translating
protecting and balancing legal and
political rights then they are or might
be considered by others de facto
policymakers and if that in fact happens
then others besides human rights
advocates will become interested in your
standards and protocol development and
enter into this arena where things are
shaped and indeed in the current
environment we think that standards and
protocol developers might open
themselves up to the charge that they
lack legitimacy that is to say political
legitimacy or
democratic legitimacy to define enable
and force or balance rights
it doesn't seem outlandish for me to
imagine that if indeed you find
yourselves actively shaping human rights
in a way that really tilts the social
environment in the way that you want
that you might find governments knocking
on your door and saying well maybe you
should have some representatives of our
point of view in your committees forget
about technical expertise you guys are
in the policy business why can't we have
a you know somebody from the ministry of
communications of moldova here because
we have a perspective on what rights
should be protected and how they should
be protected
as we said earlier the the argument that
technology mediates rights is we think
more accurate and more useful because it
better captures the reciprocal influence
between technology and society but we
view much of the current literature on
this topic as being somewhat a
historical in effect they might be even
trying to reinvent the history of
technology or science technology and
society studies because this argument is
true of every technology not just the
internet regulation and control or the
the level to which you achieve rights
and freedom are always dependent in some
ways upon the specific technical
features of the communications medium
now I'm going to give you two historical
examples of this so one of course is the
printing press and if you go back to the
15th century and read some early
discussions of printing technology this
was certainly perceived by Protestant
Reformation as a technology of
liberation and indeed it was for a while
because it allowed you know dissident
groups like Protestants to disseminate
their views in in mass form in ways that
gave them a competitive advantage over
the old stodgy Catholic Church but and
kings and princes were also challenged
by this so what happened well the
government started to clamp down on
printing presses through various
mechanisms one of the most simpler ones
was simply to arrest dissidents and put
them in jail or kill them which goes on
today of course but sometimes they try
to exert more systematic economic
control over the printing press for
example by licensing presses and
awarding monopolies to particular
publishers to publish specific kinds of
books particularly in England the
printing press was highly licensed until
I think the early 18th or 19th century
mmm-hmm case abroad a radio broadcasting
is equally interesting what
you have is a technical feature of radio
communication namely the control of the
radio spectrum and governments asserted
control or nationalize the spectrum in
order to achieve control over
broadcasting technology in the u.s.
broadcasting was essentially not
entirely anarchic people were
coordinating what frequencies they use
but it was extremely open and there are
all kinds of new broadcasters pouring
onto the airwaves in the early 20s and
the government stepped in and
effectively nationalized the airwaves
and used its control of licensing
broadcasters to impose a number of
regulations particularly pertaining to
content and other kinds of performance
metrics on the broadcasting industry and
of course in most of Europe simply you
had a single national broadcaster so in
all of the early stages of these
technologies and what I'm suggesting is
kind of a historical cycle here these
technologies were technologies of
freedom indeed not so much because of
specific technical architecture made
them promote freedom but because they
were new technologies in a state didn't
know how to control them yet and this is
particularly true of the internet where
we had you know just kind of burst onto
the scene unexpectedly by passing
telecom monopolies and bypassing
national barriers to censorship and
control and of course later on states
learned how can we control this how what
can we do to stop this what can we do to
stop that so you really have to pay
attention to the historical trajectory
of the technology it is important to
understand how and why these
technologies broke out of the chains of
previous technologies but it's also
important to understand that inevitably
those who want to control will discover
new ways to control just as people who
want to evade control will discover new
ways to evade control so that
leads to one of my final points which is
that design is ex-ante it happens before
the fact and rights violations are
really ex-post and knowledge of how they
occur and where they occur is really
after the fact so true assessment of
human rights impact of various technical
developments can only occur after the
fact and standards are protocols that
seem to be secure or protective at the
moment of design may actually have
unintended consequences they may be
exploited in ways that you don't
anticipate or creative people may think
of ways to subvert them in ways that you
did think of but didn't quite work so we
again would emphasize a view of rights
and technology as being an ongoing
struggle very much influenced by
economics and politics as well as by
standards the one of the objectives that
we've heard from people involved in the
HRP see is that they want to change the
language that you're using to describe
the technologies but we're not sure that
simply changing language will have any
actual impact on human rights on the
Internet
again it might make you more aware of
certain things but by itself the change
of language will not have much of an
effect so to conclude we don't want
anybody to go away thinking that we're
against human rights we're in favor of
human rights and in particular I mean I
can't have to qualify that statement I'm
very much in favor of freedom of
expression privacy the classic civil and
political rights I don't know about all
of those things that are classified as
human rights under human rights law but
the idea that you all are in a very
powerful position to advance those
rights through Internet Protocol design
I think is needs to be moderated
and looked at soberly so the idea is not
to discourage you from being aware of
human rights or to believe or or to in
any way divert you from a commitment to
those rights that's simply to challenge
unrealistic expectations that could in
fact backfire in certain ways and
otherwise might lead you to to waste a
lot of energy on things that are not
really where the action is so open it up
to discussion thank you um so I don't
see anybody at the microphone I don't
know Neil's whether you had had any
comments someone is coming with a
microphone thank you please remember to
give your name at the beginning hi there
my name is Andrew Sullivan so I I guess
it probably won't be too surprising that
I'm somewhat sympathetic to this to this
description of the issues and in
particular I think some of us were a
little nervous during this work because
the problem I think for that you
mentioned about you know sort of
involving the standards process directly
in in in political tussles but I wonder
whether there is a more generous reading
of the not-quite RFC and that is to to
read it as just an exhortation to
protocol designers if you think about
the consequences of potential technical
trade-offs they make for any given you
know right situation and and and if it's
if it's just that that seems a little
less a little less controversial that
you you can make decisions that can have
you know potentially rights enabling if
you believe in rights rights enabling
consequences or rights disabling
consequences and and and maybe part of
the difficulty is there's there's a
little bit of a tension in the text
sometimes between the more exhorted Tory
kind of version of it and more
optimistic version that I think you were
critiquing so I don't know if you have
anything to say about that
Thanks yeah I think that the
conversation I had with Aubrey was very
enlightening to me because in some sense
when you're talking about enabling the
creating technologies that enable again
I think that's great and I think that
the the internet did indeed enable
article 19 of Human Rights by creating
this global connectivity and that was a
fantastic achievement and we should all
support it and I wouldn't have wanted I
wouldn't have wanted policy makers or
international lawyers to have any kind
of a gatekeeping function over that I
think the great thing about what the
internet community did was they created
this capability and didn't worry about
the consequences you know they just did
it and and that advanced human society
greatly but whenever you create a
capability you don't really know how
it's going to be used completely it
could be used by people for purposes
that you don't really know and we're
certainly learning it now about the
Internet so in terms of the awareness of
possible impacts and again you have to
be modest about your ability to know I
think it's great to encourage the
considerations the aspects the awareness
I have no problem with that at all but
again just be modest about the ex-ante
versus ex-post problem and realize that
things that you do now might actually be
used in ways of just really appalled you
later hi Bob Hinton been a little while
since we chatted last so two things the
thing at the beginning where you said
that the you know the Internet is
basically static so so that there's a
there's a lot of truth in that but it's
not the whole truth I mean I think the
recent worth the ITF has been doing on
you know ubiquitous encryption and
privacy I think you know isn't it seems
very in line with human rights to make
it harder for people to look at traffic
you know I mean there was there's a big
tussle going on right now with TLS with
the new version of TLS as to whether how
easy or hard it is for middleboxes to
look at the encrypted traffic so I mean
that that's a very active discussion
here so there is still a lot of things
that I think affect human rights going
on here today so it's not completely
static obviously it's the basic package
switching architecture hasn't changed
too much
and the other thing I've always thought
for a long time that when you design
technology or in this case protocols you
are making policy decisions you may not
be quite aware of it but what the
capabilities you build in those
protocols or the capabilities you don't
build in effect what can be done with
them and that that's very much a policy
I mean it starts from the creation of
packet-switching
was a giant policy you know compared to
what what the telcos were doing with
circuit switching at a time and it's
allowed a lot of things that you
couldn't do you know it certainly made I
think wiretapping harder is package
packets are more distributed than they
used to be so you know if they're I
think policy and technology choices are
not these two separate domains there's
not the policy people and then the the
protocol designers there's a lot of
overlap here and I agree it's good that
when we do design we give this some
consideration you know it's hard to know
exactly how it applies but you know it's
worth thinking about yeah I think the
the by the same token you say that
you're making policy decision do you
want policy makers looking over your
shoulders you make those decisions or do
you want to be solving let's not even to
call it solving technical problems do
you want to be creating technical
capabilities and you want a free hand to
do that or do you want governments and
politically representation to constrain
you in those in those choices my
personal answer to that is no I like to
do what we think is right but it thought
they do have policy impacts yeah I don't
doubt that they do it's just that you
probably don't know exactly what they
are
kkeok Maya I have a few comments I think
it's a bit too straightforward to think
like the IP revolution or internet
revolution is like a radio or the free
press because we're much more flexible
and I understand that on the on the
lower layers maybe the technology isn't
changed that often but when you look now
at what's going on in terms of
clarifications on higher layers where
also human rights most likely need
protection we're changing the
architecture every few years you know
ideas come in but I think there we have
always a possibility to rethink what we
really want and build in capabilities
that we would like to have on the policy
makers what you just said
I think they are already in the room so
there's I mean you can't say are they
should stay out or whatever they are in
the room and we have so I am mainly
activating other standards organizations
not so much the IETF but we heavily
reusing what the ITF is providing and I
think that's practically a trend all
over the world or all of standards or
network standards that is done in these
days is whatever the ITF standardizes is
defective the thing to take for the sort
of communication so the regulators the
government's whatever they are very
active in other standards but is much
more than here that's my understanding
my feeling and from that I see that the
ITF has
light momentum to use its capabilities
to bring human rights issues whatever
issues into their protocols to make sure
they are there and the other bodies
simply have to live with that at least
at the moment and I think this is
something we should take into
consideration we should keep in our mind
that the ITF from my perspective can
really make a difference here thank you
just one question for you maybe stay at
the mic for a second so when you say the
architecture changes every two years or
so what what are you defining is
architecture it depends I mean like as
you see now when we talk about
everywhere about virtualization talk
about what was a big issue in this this
idea of slicing the whole thing that
everything moves into the cloud so
things are not anymore on the or not not
only let's say on the client these are
all movements that I mean I don't say
this is something that is good for human
rights or bad but we have to rethink
Human Rights on that basis right and we
we really have to see how can we
implement things into this movement so I
that doesn't mean that therefore the
transport layer or physical layers sort
of resolved all the other problems but
at least on those levels that we
currently work we should keep our eyes
open
yeah I don't have any fundamental
disagreement with that I think I would
just emphasize that maybe you've made a
bunch of technical decision incremental
ii over the last 10 years that have
enabled this movement to the cloud and
this movement to the cloud is going to
have a number of policy competition
implications that there's no way you
could really design for in your
protocols there you know you need to
massive levels of concentration which
requires some kind of regulatory
response by antitrust or competition
policy
you laters but that's not really your
problem to solve but even though it's an
indirect outgrowth of your a whole
series of technical decisions I just
want to say I
I understand did you say it's not our
our task but when you see the
discussions that were for example in
when it came to TLS this is sort of made
our task because some people want
certain things that others don't want
so the maybe if you say it's not our
task yes from a technical point of view
maybe but the confrontation is brought
here anyhow so I totally agree that when
it comes to TLS issue what you're doing
is saying we are designing for
confidentiality which is a classic part
of the triad of information security and
I'm all for that the question is you
know there are going to be
countervailing forces you know maybe the
the TLS mechanisms you come up with well
some states will say you can't use those
and they'll try to regulate their
infrastructure to prevent that others
might find new ways to get around it
that's all I'm saying is that you're not
settling the issue by I you know
creating more secure points in in the
network last but not least thank so much
for this Milton and thanks so much for
the reference to of beating the mic
thanks so much Milton Ron I thanks also
for the reference to the movie a requiem
for a dream i I'm I'm afraid that this
now slowly starts to become a more of
Inception because I'm going to tell you
to wake up from your dream and then
you're going to tell me wake up from
your dream so let's see how how matter
we can get but let me go back to the
last time when I thought I was awake you
know as a reference and that was at the
previous ITF and that's where we had a
talk from from Dave Clark who said
are the author of the famous hustle
paper and said there is a tussle and
that is something that you seem to seem
to acknowledge here as well and I think
what we've been saying in a draft we
need to make the tussle more explicit so
my question would be here what are you
adding to that discussion because as
others have said there are already
policy makers here there are already
nation-states here pushing their
influences with the Raven process so you
that you've seen we have also seen
Wheaton of crypto standards we've seen
also the explicit request for the
weakening of crypto standards we've also
been other requests so I think the that
you seem to describe the policy layer as
a separate layer whereas whereas it's
integrated through the whole stack and
I'm a bit surprised that you as a
Science and Technology scholar haven't
mentioned the concept affordances
because network and the technology
always has specific characteristics
which inhibits or stimulates or enables
or disables a certain behavior and
you're completely rights that you cannot
completely predict that but it doesn't
mean you cannot think about it and it
doesn't mean you cannot model it that
doesn't mean you're going to be right or
you can take that into account in your
your analysis and with the internet
there is also not so much an ex post and
an ex ante but it's a it's an ex to
Dante you know we are continuously
evolving the the network and we have no
idea how it's going to be used there was
sudden uptick of decentralized bit
BitTorrent protocols and then it seems
that distribution was going to be much
stronger but now we see a very big
tendency towards centralized a on many
different layers of the stack you said
it's not your problem well it is our
problem if that leads to a less
resilient network and so that's when we
start thinking what can we do about that
so I think it definitely has
influence on what we do here and then
your reference to the printing press and
the radio I was very surprised but also
it was great because the printing press
initially was embraced by the Catholic
Church because then finally they did not
depend on monks to copy to copy and they
could distribute and they thought
finally now everyone is going to have a
Bible and we're going to have ultra
dominance well it turned out differently
right and and but Bethel bred said a bit
before you in 1928 was that the the
promise of radio can only be fulfilled
if the listeners talk back and that is
exactly what were what we're working on
now with the internet so everything has
specific affordances and you see
different ways in which control is
possible and which control is harder so
we've seen for instance the possibility
of shortwave radio made the distribution
of news much easier but then there of
course was jamming but jamming was a
very large economic investment to do so
you're also making it harder for people
to censor the deads also work we're
doing here and we've seen now the
discussion on deck you know sni headers
etc with also a new worker LS which
makes censorship harder so I think there
are definitely affordances there and not
just on privacy and and confidentiality
I have some more points but I think I'll
leave it with that well I'm not sure
what your point about the historical
things are to reinforce my point that
there's an ongoing struggle on the site
of these technologies the Catholic
Church thought printing press was you
know they assumed we control things and
but the economic affordances of the
printing press you know almost anything
make one of these things and start
cranking stuff and now you connect that
to
a dissident movement Protestantism and
suddenly you've got something under
control and then you start yet a more
systematic institutionalized regime of
press control which lasts for 200 years
the same thing with brought just Brecht
apparently didn't know that I guess he
was thinking about only about
broadcasting but broadcasting was
preceded in pioneered by you know early
1900s hackers known as radio amateurs
and they were talking to each other that
was the whole point they were using
short waves to bounce signals around
publish contact with people all over the
world and it was the radio amateurs who
suddenly just got this brilliant idea of
connecting their record player to their
transmitter and start broadcasting music
again you had greenly diverse and open
development of the radio for about five
years and then became institutionalized
and controlled through the technical
leverage of a chief by allocating and
assigning radio frequencies so I I don't
see you know how you're channeling my
point so I say that there are different
affordances to the different
technologies a way in which the internet
is governed makes it harder and that's
also part of the later this political is
that the the process in which we can be
controlled and can be influenced our
difference then we get back to the
tussle that here we can take the tussle
more explicit and can seek to
counterbalance it right I gotta say
something about the tussle so I I was
there when he did this paper at the
telecom policy research conference in
what way about 2002 or something like
that
and to us that was like oh so the the
engineers have discovered policy
struggle well it's like what you want to
call it that's cute that resonates with
the engineers but this is what we do
this is what we talked about for the
last 200 years this is political
so of course there's tussles over
technology just like there's over you
know healthcare or you know other kinds
of public policy considerations Allyson
medkit I'm the I work for Salesforce RI
r TF chair and I don't want we have some
time I interested to know how people at
room especially you think of the Kerala
effort that's going on about values and
bias in algorithms and there too there's
a very funny ring component to the
discussion and the kind of neat alliance
among parties it's not just a dominant
it's not just policy folks got folks but
also say journalists and I think there's
place paid for that the Fourth Estate
here too so I thought maybe with some
comments about that yeah so the the
algorithmic regulation issue I think is
simply an extension of the overall that
you know you create a capability right
and then you find what it does and some
of the things that it does are
unanticipated and whether may be bad and
some of them may be fantastic and then
society starts just the abilities based
on what had lurked out what happened
with your first pass and this is was a
state right now you know we had this
great Google search algorithm and then
we covered various ways it could be
gamed or various ways in my
discriminatory results and so now people
are wanting to take that was in make
them more transparent and the
possibility or capabilities of regulate
algorithm needs to be also tempered by
the the concept of you know reward
innovations so if you develop this great
algorithm there's wonderful things but
then you have to expose it to everybody
you have no sort of intellectual
property protection for it that I
deterred from developing other
algorithms so there's no free lunch in
terms of regulating ability you have to
be very careful how you do that that's
my perspective I think there's probably
people here who know more about them
than I do we haven't really focused on
the out connect regular much in our
research Phillip oddly I just wanted to
follow up on the earlier comment about
how the architect has changed to me with
a big thing that's changing was maybe
unexpected 15-20 years ago we thought it
would be we'd end up with something that
was highly distributed and lots of
people in there Garrard advising
applications and we actually ended up
with huge economies of scale see we sent
it up with monopoly basically or that's
the big trend isn't it have them not the
particular application area you seem
more more monopolies in terms of the
technology because become so expensive
to build or make making them make the
chips of the Foxit office so I mean and
that must have big implications for
human rights I guess so yeah I really
you may be talking about what Tim calls
the cycle I don't know how many of you
familiar in it but it does have a very
important point which is that all of
these knowledge ease go through this
phase and then in the early stages
there's lots of small innovation going
on it's a very free environment and then
the basic structures are discovered and
works and what doesn't work discovery
get some solid ation then you get
institutionalization and some kind of
ties to the government and more rigid
regulation and then maybe somebody comes
along with the disruptive innovation
that'sthat's equilibrium you know 10 20
years down the road maybe 50 years down
the road for example with a telephone
system it took a really long time to to
break out of the monopolies that was
formed
analog circuits which technology in the
in the 1920s so the Internet is really
following this pattern in many ways I
think you're right that we we thought
it's going to be completely distributed
and and essentially various forms of
consolidation and concentration have
occurred and are occurring and yeah and
that's more economic structure than the
human rights but I believe that the
economic factors actually have as much
impact on freedom the legal the nominal
the rights that it have an environment
where you have a monopoly it doesn't
matter a whole lot what your non-legal
rights are you really don't have many
options to exercise freedom thank you I
think that's a great note to end on
Thank You Milton for coming and talking
about a paper that you're still working
on I really appreciate you coming in
speaking to to this group about it and
look forward to reading the paper when
you in person any or Farzana have
completed it so thanks a lot okay moving
on okay so the next thing we have is I
guess you're talking about Neos your
paper on well we talked about this draft
in the last meeting and it was me
actually setting up a structure about
things we talked and then some people
wanted to take it on there is not a new
version out I wanted to check in with
room if anyone interested in working on
whether we should pursue this further
and if people are interested in working
on this
Stefan got me last time I said I was
interested but in practice I didn't do
anything so if someone else wants to
step in wet otherwise try to resume but
don't hold your breath
I saw one hand in the back and that's a
turkey Tara Tara Kea
so and that would that would be good so
we'll be in touch about how to get
involved in and working on it
ah don't know where else you want to go
with that one well that's great that's
great that's great progress so then we
go to the next draft which will be
presented by she's el Affairs OCHA
she's Ella are you in remote room and
think with yourself you so we can put
you on the screen hi yes I am connecting
from Mexico it's 3:30 in here it's warm
for everybody that you can fry right now
I'm going to present later a draft that
I've been working on reveals about
freedom of association and Internet
infrastructure can I have that it's then
it's nicely perfect so we can read about
is the last session the objective was to
document form self assembly and
Association that in protests that did
not have a negative impact on the
Internet infrastructure this started
like thought out like that because
apparently there's a consensus the eight
human rights were tokens considerations
research group the denial of service
attacks are no
to be promoted by the ietf because they
damage the intern architecture so we
were wondering how this does the
internet architecture enable and or
inhibit freedom of association assembly
including protists that is encompassed
by this right along with many other
rights like freedom of speech and even
privacy so very quickly the difference
between assembly and Association it's
just a question of a matter of degree
and assembly rather temporary and as an
association is a bit more formal and
less of humours while we were working
through this we can very we came up with
a very interesting concept that was the
concept of forest association that has
echoes with the internet architecture
itself because these rights are
envisioned as freedoms which means that
nobody is supposed to be forced to join
a group or if even forced to leave a
group it's just a freedom you can either
join or leave whatever group you choose
either temporary or permanent also
another thing that we've been discussing
we haven't quite reached consensus and
it would be super interesting to see
when you think is if the internet itself
was an association and assembly or an
association let's just treated as
synonyms right now because if it is it
should be protected by these rights and
that has other impacts on let's say
other kinds of networks right so if the
Internet is the network an association
and an SM we are also essentially
networks so we were wondering and we're
still wondering if this is something
that we can definitely assert next
please well just as a side note the IETF
is an assembly we could even consider an
association even though not in an
association doesn't have to be a
corporation or it doesn't even have to
be legally constructed it can just be a
bit more formal and a bit more more
permanent and RFC 3233 defines the IETF
said an open global community of network
designers operator vendors and
researchers so in this sense IETF is
definitely an assembly
Association protected by these rights
next please even the mere discussion of
RFC's would not be possible without
these human rights and justice an
historical side know the work protocol
find its way into language is computer
networking because of this need of
collective agreement next please
so we mapped out a bunch of cases and
examples but I really want to emphasize
the difference between free association
and forced Association because I think
it's one of the most interesting ones
that we've been able to come up with
starting by the text of the ICCPR on the
UDHR
and then taking it to the internet
architecture and see how it won impacts
the other and how the text impacts could
be interpreted in terms of inner
architecture so free association it's
very easy let's just think about mailing
lists you join a mailing list
you're tired of mailing lists you just
unsubscribe the peer-to-peer preppy
protocol it's also a an association and
assembly issue because it allows for
collective collaboration ideally it
would be without the need for
centralized servers and but there's very
different models of that and this took
us to a next question that I will talk
in a couple of talk about in a couple of
minutes and then the issue of forced
Association we're thinking about denial
of service attacks as I said there's
apparently a consensus within the human
rights protocol considerations
research group that there's some denial
of service attacks that are legitimate
there's some that are not but the IETF
should not be making those distinctions
in terms of content that's from free
speech free speech perspective but taken
from an association and assembly right
perspective we can we ask ourselves two
things first if the denial of services
attacks
putting race the entire internet
architecture so to speak could this be
an illegitimate form of association
because they and given that the Internet
it's an association itself if we are
able to concede that if we put at risk
the Internet as an association could
that be an illegitimate association form
that should not be promoted in terms of
like your architecture that's one
question and then the other must be
taken into consideration that DDoS
attacks are also a form of forced
assembly and Association because some
most times and sometimes they are done
without the agreement or even the
knowledge of the in both parts and the
Internet of Things has brought
interesting discussions regarding that
with ISPs the logic of forced
Association is the same because infinite
user the edge user needs to accept the
policies and practices of the edge
networks that provides access to other
networks like for the user to connect to
join the assembly of the network of
networks of the internet if we are ready
to concede that they always have to
connect through an intermediary and
while connected to an intermediary well
not always that let's just save most of
the time while connecting through the
intermediary they have their first to
accept the policies practices and
principles of this network so can we say
that internet connection thrice peace is
a form of force Association next please
we've also been discussing which model
is better for freedom of assembly and
Association centralized or decentralized
and why both things have to seem to have
their pros and cons the centralized
models they protect anonymity and
privacy they are usually more resilient
networks and more resistant to
censorship mechanisms but also
centralized structures have enabled
people to group together to identify
each other better they recognizable
places more visible and also in some
some other cases
they enable for quicker interactions and
even dissemination of information so can
we say one is better than the other yes
no and why I'd love to think I'd love to
hear out what you what you think on that
next please
so just a quick set of preliminary
conclusions the Internet does have does
impact the ability for people to
exercise their right to freedom of
assembly and association and then can we
think and assert that the Internet
itself is a form of Association and
assembly and therefore it should be
protected as such this would be very
interesting because of the consequences
the legal consequences it would have and
as I was saying the consequences it
might have and other networks and then
to get access to the Internet one could
argue one is caught in the First
Assembly with the access network next
piece that's it comments are we missing
something did we mess something up or
anything like that thank you very much
Oh interesting tower looking right - yes
so because but never from freedom so I
was so essentially the arts then of
course you would have the right to not
be part of that Association right I mean
that's where my - right now but it's
super super interesting but mourner
unique from other rights perspective we
can also build on the right to be fine
and totally level for example if you
could get the lease today range from
your burning can you actually
you
boss protests then what would it be so
that was actually the the origin story
of the draft but I think if there may be
value in whether it's this draft or just
a two-page document that says even the
people taking part in this research
group have been convinced that yes DDoS
is just an attack and nothing else that
I think might be useful
thanks so much
Gisella thanks so much for calling in
from from Mexico and for for staying up
I we don't hear you anymore our kind of
lost in space now but at least at me it
was nice for what it lasted okay yeah so
we lost audio but thanks so much easily
so we continue with the next draft which
I'd like to ask Andrew Sullivan to to
come forward
hi there oh I even get to drive my name
is Andrew Sullivan and I'm here to talk
a little bit about a draft that Neil's
and I put together but I hope that
mostly I won't talk and you all again
tell us how wrong we are so I just want
to give a quick outline of what this
thing is about and what we've described
in here and some issues that have
already come up in discussion on the
list and then we can maybe have some
discussion here so some of you will
remember that I was one of the critics
of this claim that protocols are
political that was in the HR PC research
document and there was some
back-and-forth about it and I think the
document ended up a little bit weaker
than it had been but also on it you know
some of those claims are still in there
and I think that there's been some some
discussion about it so we wanted to
understand Nielson I wanted to
understand what the possible positions
are about this and then try to
distinguish among them so at least we
could understand them and then maybe and
I think he's more optimistic about this
than I am but maybe we could answer
whether there really is a political
dimension automatically to two protocols
and so we've got some described
positions the first one is just this
value neutral position which is which is
a position that certain it has a very
old tradition but there are people who
who continue to think this today so the
values are all
analogies here with mass media
development or traffic or dams and
rivers that kind of thing
where where they change the world and
they make the world different there is
some say there's been some suggestion
actually that because of this we've got
some category mistakes in in the
document that some things are are not in
this category that should be or maybe
there are some things in this category
that should be in the next one the the
last of these positions is that the
protocols are inherently political so
this is the position that was
controversial before and so obviously we
were trying to make it as clear as
possible here uh and and this is the one
and I think you know Bob was sort of
suggesting this earlier at the
microphone I think this is something
that Neil's believes that the protocols
are fundamentally you know politics by
other means you're making decisions and
you're making political decisions
fundamentally there is some some people
read the postman things there's there's
a bunch of stuff from Neil postman in
here and some people read postman
actually to say the previous category of
stuff i I don't know what postman says a
lot of the time so I'm not I'm not too
keen on on on adjudicating that dispute
in any case those are the positions that
we were trying to to outline now we
identified some some issues in the
zero-zero we hadn't defined politics or
political and it seemed that there were
a number of cases where we were
stumbling over that so the zero one
that's already out but probably you
haven't read it has attempted to to give
a definition of that this is the working
one and it's there on the screen
or you can read it on your own screens
later if you would like on but it seemed
pretty obvious that this this draft is
gonna go absolutely nowhere if we don't
if we don't come up with some definition
here so so we've done that there are
some other examples that people sent to
us feedback that we should include we
didn't include the Raven process but I
guess we probably better maybe we need
some more discussion of RFC 69 73 maybe
there are some other cases so if you
have some other cases that we ought to
be looking at we are keen to hear about
them Eliot leer had a really interesting
set of remarks about
how the document says the ietf is not
the protocol police and of course it is
true that we can't go out and force
people to use our protocols or anything
like that but there is a little thing
here right so we're quite aggressive
actually about about our IP our rules
the the ITF is extraordinarily strict
about what you may and may not do so
much so in fact that you know authors of
documents that are being published in
the ITF can't put them under different
under different terms they have to go
into the IETF terms they can put that
they can put the document the same
document under other terms somewhere
else but they can't publish them as an
RFC this has come up several times
because people wanted to put you know a
Creative Commons licenses on things and
so on and it's not allowed and the
reason for that is because the ITF s--
IP our position is that it wants to
control derivative works so that some
other standards organization can't come
along swallow the thing up and then
close it you know with with a change or
something like that so that there's
there's a practical reason for this well
that's a kind of protocol policing right
that what that is is an attempt to
enforce certain kinds of abilities of
other people to do stuff with the work
product of the ITF so so depending on
how you interpret protocol police
there's a potential thing here and I
think we're gonna work a little bit
harder to to tease this out some more I
think in the in the document it's not
there yet but it it would be interesting
there was also this other question about
a single vendor end-to-end thing like is
that a different political kind of
situation we have a lot of these now
right there's a lot of stuff deployed on
the internet very widely deployed on the
internet that is end-to-end controlled
by a single vendor and and maybe that
changes that changes something about it
so we want to investigate that okay so
these are the questions that we have
anyway first of all whether if this is
at all useful or maybe it's just useless
and we can stop um if if we updated this
you know would we get any more reviews
also we want to know if people think
this is actively harmful because there's
lots of stuff that you know you can
write down that you shouldn't and
obviously there's probably stuff we've
missed so I invite you to tell us what
we've done well or badly I think that's
it right yeah okay I think oh this is
Shanker well I think certainly you have
expressed a number of concerns several
times throughout this research group and
I think there can't be anything wrong
with writing them down in a structured
format like this and making them more
clear so I think if nothing else the
process of writing the document I hope
is helpful for people observers like me
who often didn't follow the discussion
between our philosophers up at the front
there so now whether or not that means
it actually needs to be moved forward
into a document I can't say I think
there's no harm especially in a research
group of publishing it as it as an RFC
stefan-boltzmann speaking why I have to
concern with the we see a draft one is
that it seems there was a lot of overlap
with HTTP at LPC research draft because
it's our protocols political is already
is a basic question of the research
draft maybe one way to solve this
overlap would be to focus on explaining
to people because the research draft is
very harder to read
it's a lot of things a lot of discussion
so maybe your short draft focusing on
the ordinary IETF participant and
explaining why what is the discussion
about our protocols political could be
useful because in the current state it's
not clear of what is the purpose of the
AAPC political draft on the second
concern is the section on the voluntary
standards it's not clear for me it if it
refers to volume 2 in the elaboration in
the creation of standards the IETF work
is done by volunteers a sort of thing oh
is it about adoption and implementation
of stand on by the rest of the world
which is when we created the standard
with people have to deploy it or not
which is the older question of protocol
police
so it seems to me that the current
section 9 completely mix the two things
okay thank you thank you admire speaking
I think on the protocol police I would
think we you could extend it so far as I
understand you say it's about IPRs and
who creates and owns the protocol but
the ownership in fact also includes if
you how you can extend the protocol and
we had issues in the past practically
from an outside body we wanted to to
extend the protocol at the ITF said no
for technical reasons nothing to do with
human rights or politically reasons but
I think it shows that the owner of a
protocol has a certain power over what
can be really done with it and where it
can be applied and that is something
that it's not just in the beginning but
also in the evolvement of the protocol
and maybe also when it comes to
evolution into a new protocol because if
you do something today and then a new
generation is needed everybody will look
into this room and say what do they have
to say right so that's maybe also
something you want to act there so this
is very interesting but I could you say
a little more about about the cases
where somebody wants to extend it and
and the ITF says says in effect no I I
mean I can think of some examples of
that but some of them are more
controversial than others so it's a
little more I mean if we I'm I work with
3gpp right so when we came in the
beginning and wanted to do practically
the circuit switch network with SIP then
there was a lot of controversy saying
practically SIP is not meant for that we
were able I think to 99% of these cases
to resolve one way or the other some
things like charging lawful interception
and so on they will stay problematic and
always ray give phrase for discussion
but I mean we have a way of of resolving
that and I'm don't wanna touch whether
this is good
or not I just say the fact that the IDF
forced us to practically delay our work
for quite a while
shows how powerful the IDF is at that
point it was painful for us in the work
that you want to undergo here it might
be a factor that could be used in a
positive manner the other thing that
came to my mind I was I didn't say that
before was when we talk about such
things is it and really still the
protocol or is it not more the protocol
and who does the protocol so there are
two things that can evolve right the
technically things that are written down
and the group of people that governs it
right not sure if this is addressed in
the draft I think it's very weak right
now and I think that that's a that's a
that's an important point that I think
is a little bit obscure right now
thank you very much hello Cara okay
thank you for the presentation I wanted
to challenge the notion that technology
is valuing neutral I think you cannot
you cannot technology drives its values
from its users so these values also
applied to technology itself one one way
like one way I like to illustrate this
is like using the concept of like
muscles hammer so if the only tool you
have is a hammer then all your problems
start to look like nails and so I think
like that that's one way the investor
it's why it's important you cannot only
consider technology by itself also
consider it's the whole set of its users
when determine its value think sit but
but you're not you're not disputing that
there are people who think that the
technology is neutral and all of those
values are actually in the humans I
think those people are wrong yeah yeah
III think the I think the extreme
position in the other direction is wrong
but I lay it out so okay thanks Alfred
aureus speaking personally I think it's
actually very useful to be working this
out and I think it's especially useful
at this point to sort of work out that
whole notion of protocol police which is
some
we talk about frequently which is police
of the protocol as a protocol versus
police of how the protocols are used
where one is indeed the case and and the
other is it so I think it's very good
because that that conversation is always
somewhat ambiguous and defining it and
getting past that ambiguity it is a good
thing
ah so I think if it were just for that
it would be worth it because that is a
conversation that needs to be had in
understood so thanks icing problem yeah
I'm not at all sure if this is useful so
there I can see that there are two dip
those kind of more and we're looking at
more outward looking scopes that that
that's a fair point I think but I'm not
care about I did up images work to try
and document by this there might be and
I think you know the discussion would be
irresistible so maybe this is one where
you guys are still willing to push it
along then see where it goes and it's a
yeah I mean I would be concerned that
you what you said basically but there
are some things that are better not
written down sometimes right so so then
I guess the question that I would have
is is what would you say to Stefan's
point before that the research document
is actually you know it it tends it's
got all the survey the literature and
all the rest of it in it and so for a
lot of sort of IETF participants it's a
little opaque and so maybe this is a the
you know the quick and dirty guide to
aimless thinking about this or something
yeah no I'm not saying I'm not saying
I'm anti decide say I just don't know
you know I mean I don't know if you can
kind of lay out or you know the various
positions different people have been
aware it's understandable that the ITF
community and still short and
understandable to the idea community
right and I'm fairly clear that I don't
think you want to kind of pick one and
say this is a
this is the right answer yeah I'm not
too sanguine about the possibility about
myself right so so if the John I'm also
not convinced I'm also not sure that the
ietf community really wants an
introduction to Heidegger we have you
for that right shortly speaking to the
overlap on between the research draft
and this draft I think that they claim
that we work out in the research draft
is that protocols have an impact on
human rights which is a very different
claim than politics are political so you
can say yes Human Rights are political
but that doesn't make it the same and I
think what we do here is that we dive
it's in a similar way as we do with the
Association draft is that we look much
closer so we zoom in deeper and we
analyze the case further so the research
draft was kind of seeing where this
research area makes sense at all and
come up with guidelines and now we're
like at a next iteration to try to
understand what are the specific
problems did the initial guidelines make
sense and what are the ways to
approaching and documenting this and
because this is a topic that comes back
and again and again and again on on the
list and in discussions it is very nice
I have a shorthand to say yes we talked
about that let's have a look in probably
yeah yeah and you know maybe this is
something that would be better as a
academic publication and then when
that's the kind of done thing to try and
reflect that in a in and I into the
platform as the ITF you might be better
that that analysis is not trashed out in
the typical kind of a RTF IETF style
I'm not sure I'm not arguing to not do
this but I just not sure it's useful so
this has been helpful to me my my
conclusion from what I've
is that at least one more iteration of
this would be helpful and at that point
we can decide whether any further work
is useful so I think I think we'll have
another go-around thank you so here we
get to the presentation of the hackathon
HTTP status code 451 and there we have
the combination of two of line
presenters and an online presenter olga
cruz de leyva al poker please come ahead
and stand in the purple box and is meet
echo working again and if so Siobhan can
you put yourself in the queue so we have
you on the screen there Siobhan great to
have you there meter how can we have
Siobhan Largent's been great good to see
you there I will give the controls to
help and I'm sure among you three of us
among the three of you you can make it
work so I can tell that some of you are
quite interested in implementation as
well as the policy and perhaps you've
been waiting for a bit to see how these
things play out so we're going to look
at some of the things we've done to
monitor and track the success and the
implementation of RFC seven seven to
five so that's the HTS code four five
one so we were at the hackathon and we
got the implementation so I mapped oka
this is all go kristef aber and so this
is what we're what we're doing the
hackathon we which got the best new work
so it went quite well and at the
hackathon we built tools that basically
track that they crawl and detect set
case of censorship online so it was a
matter of really trying to see if this
RFC is in use its deployed its way of
declaring incidence of legally without
content online
so it's also quite a diverse
participation from groups that you may
not see in other spaces and working
groups because it's represented by civil
society and I suppose part of the goal
is to bridge the gap between policy and
tech so I think that she been wanting to
maybe look at some of the implementation
is that right okay okay so the purpose
like I said it's three to add some
transparency improve tracking and also
to understand how how the implement if
it can be implemented if the specs
commitment said and used in practice and
what flaws there are so you find that HB
403 for example isn't isn't necessary
suitable for this kind of task so the
implementations there were I think five
five six invitations in total there was
a crawler which scans the web WordPress
plugin which implements the actual
status quo and daemon that collects all
the data and centralizes it the block
collector and a browser extension a
chrome Chrome extension that allows
users to report incidents that they
detect online as they browse and also an
alternative Prada which validated some
of the standards or what's on the specs
we built to really relay a censorship
data in JSON so part of the goals also
to build a standard well at the
beginning of a perhaps a description of
incidents where or observations of
blocked contents
No so yeah so yeah so this is an
alternative college to the one please
and it's okay yeah yeah
[Laughter]
is what the current use the description
of most
and if you have a suggestion David
perhaps really potentially useful and
also documenting a common description
that she liked about happening but also
be useful for the last part of the
report we talks about revision framework
and we did some case studies on little
junkies different ways in which and so
we saw that geo blocking the IP address
is pretty common
keeping forms of freedom of expression
laws way or gradually expanding them
over the years also happens frequently
Ice Cube locking is pretty common in
Iran and India and in the US legal
blocking in case of upgrade law takes
the form of notice in takedown so to
summarize the status code is useful way
of providing information about a legal
dog but standardization work needs to
have needs to be done before you can see
widespread usage yeah that's it for me
and in the draft we try to consider all
of these that you can see in the screen
and talk about what possible
implications that is called four five
one can have and I guess there are a
couple that are more relevant than
others or more concerning than others
and so one of them was privacy privacy
and anonymity because like the if the
user tries to access the website a web
page that is blocked the he or she often
would get a four five one response but
then would get redirected so that could
include potential privacy breaches and
it it can mean that the user can be
identified the same is because the four
five one is cached by definition so
there is a trace of that the user tried
to access blog content on his computer
so if the computer is lost like it's
possible to retrieve this information
and also the observers of the network
have access to to see who try to access
the blocked content so those are some of
the biggest concerns and in terms of
censorship it's it's a great tool of
censorship monitoring it doesn't solve
the problem of censorship and we make we
want to make it to a point that it's not
it's not okay to censor using four five
one because it's not okay to censor
point so it's not a way to make
censorship more ethical more than
anything it's just a way for for the
user to sort of see why they cannot
access certain content because as we
mentioned in the draft the response
should include the legislation like the
link to why which lies applied and why
the content is blocked and also who made
the decision where there was a court
decision or which governmental body
actually asked for the content to be
blocked so
I guess we would like to try to run the
crawler in different countries and to
see what content is blocked we did it we
did a short small test run and read it
in Turkey and some LGBT content appear
to be blocked using four by one and so
we are currently working on running it
in Russia and potentially there are more
countries where we would like to try it
in to sort of monitor and measure
censorship and yeah we'll gladly share
them with you and the next item it is
worth noting one of the outcomes from
from all of this that's I think it's
worth noting is that the language is the
way we think about this change slightly
over the course of the work we did and
we found that there's maybe less of a
desire to encourage the adoption of
4-5-1 but more to actually track it
there's a risk that you might end up
actually sanctioning these acts of micro
censorship instead of making them more
transparent so there's always balance to
be had between you know encouraging a a
standard and and putting it out there so
that people can use it when they need it
so that might be one of the things that
that's needing clarification perhaps in
a revision so we do have a few resources
here that you can look at there's the
code on lining it up and there's a live
demo as well at net box org slash
dashboard which is an outcome of this
work thank you are there any questions
anybody at the mic I don't see anybody
at the mic anybody heading to the mic
okay
spoon uniting speaking I just try to
understand this thing I wrecked the RFC
just right now and what I'm wondering is
understand that also intermediaries like
providers could be ending out this kind
of four five farm code to block content
on behalf of government or whatever and
are there any considerations if HTTP is
used or the NSA kiss use there is kind
of thing doesn't work anymore so well if
they already means on consideration if
yes what will be so it is possible to
inject a 4-5-1 page in a ISP intercepted
page page load HTTP resource code if
it's not encrypted like you say with TLS
HTTP there's a separate set of problems
the content isn't visible to the
intercepting party at the moment for
five one use is really envisioned for
used by the entity from which the legal
block has been requested is the actual
publisher which which restricts its own
content so yes there is desire in cases
where authorities used block pages
already to have them delivered with a
4-5-1 status code but realistically
there's no desire or plan to put this in
any way in terms of intercepting HTTP
content I think in that case it's
completely up to the it's completely up
to the publisher on how to do that or
whether to do that and I think
personating that's the way it should be
and that's certainly how the RFC is at
the moment I'll just read I'm not like
defending like what's going to happen
with blocking in the implement I just
see these problems now whereby in
fighting against blocking it's just a
question I think you kind of mentioned
it is that there's you know if people
start using this and then you go off and
measure it in some sense that could
distance end people from using it
because then they you've measured it you
might report on that right and have you
thought about kind of ways of
collating results are not anonymizing
them necessarily but maybe you've done
this already of reporting out in
regional or functional or some aspects
of what's worked without necessarily
calling out the person who's publishing
before five one yes we started to look
at this and one of the ideas we have is
to use the IP anonymization IP address'
anonymization
work that's going on at the moment where
we can choose a kay-kay sample to create
a more anonymous grouping or because we
don't want to provide the actual I
physical IP address but we do want to
give an idea of which hands which
regions are impacted so in terms of
monitoring these are questions that
we're looking at and we need to answer
these questions so that we can publish
actual useful data but you know in the
time given so far we haven't really done
a analyzation or geo implementation at
the moment yeah I guess there is -
because I know it's a networking context
it's a natural thing to go and yeah do
some kind of surveying and or use that
map or something and then publish traces
may be anonymized something but in this
case if you publish the urls that you
find that's not so good that's another
problem I mean one of the ideas we had
before is maybe to put the URL in a
image but that also has accessibility
issues and one of the other ideas we
have is in the protocol perhaps to
encode the URL so that it's not in
clear-text
so there's a risk if you have a list of
all these as blocked sites then crawlers
are going to consider your your own site
which hosts the transparency report as a
dangerous site so in our current
protocol we do specify and encoded an
encoding of URLs which I think all
implementations have switched to at the
moment so the probiotic of the 4.1 URLs
are actually um base64 encoded in the
current spec of the vertical simply so
they're not visible and they don't
become a problem to people passing
around the data okay so that's one thing
is just going to accidentally mistaking
this for the resource that is but that
is censored or even just clicking on it
in your editor you find text editors
have feature
you think yeah I'm okay thanks thanks
and close the queue okay um I want to
add that this is really dangerous what
we do let's say I'm part of the fight
against Internet censorship since many
years and we're trying to organize you
know if this is just joke 4-5-1 and then
it can be used as form of protest right
in the internet so if if they force you
to remove something you put a 4-5-1 on
it and as a protest a sign of protest
that this should not be right and on the
other side if we start to take serious
then we are kind of like it amazing the
end of freedom of speech you know so
we're kind of organizing a measure where
where the enemies of freedom of speech
can say well we just goodbye and so I
just want to put the morning here on the
table that this can be really dangerous
if we take it too serious this very
special hour see well thank you for your
comment I think we're aware of this I
guess the idea behind it is that they
are already doing it and for example in
Russia 4-5-1 is used a lot by because
there are different laws that are
regulating internet there is the law
about bloggers being distributors of
mass information and so if you don't
register in a certain registar your site
can get blocked and so there are various
laws that are for a like a citizen who
is not very much into tech it's like
okay it's blocked by law then it's it's
sort of a valid reason for blocking you
know what I mean so if you don't know
what the law is about exactly and that a
law is actually kind of a censorship law
you might think that
whatever yeah there is a reason because
also and I guess it's worth mentioning
that some of this content is like
pornography or online gaming which can
like I mean censorship is a I guess we
have to define it as well because it's a
very you know like the line is the thin
line between censorship and what's not
censorship so I guess we have to
distinguish in-between that but it's
it's a way I guess of measuring
something that already exists rather
than encouraging compliance with the
status code okay maybe I should add then
as an answer on what you said maybe the
view in Russia can be very different
from what I said I don't know the
situation there I can talk about the
view in Germany where we have a really
fighting internet censorship and it's
really a tough one because they really
wanted the government wants it and it's
also a discussion even in Switzerland
you know known as free country again we
have internet censorship on the table
politically and and there is where I was
commenting okay thank you um I I had
closed the queue we've got four minutes
left so really it's a discussion to take
to the to the list and because I have a
feeling it's gonna go on for a bit but
sorry but I had I had asked to close
thank you thank you very much and
hopefully we could continue the
discussion on the list and from what
I've heard there's a good chance that
there will be a hackathon on this again
in Singapore so really good thing to
discuss on the list okay just a quick
update on the status since the last time
draft irth RPC research has gone through
the IR s G review and I guess it is just
about to go into the is G conflict check
and I on a review but Allison is coming
to the microphone so can we straight to
be completely clear I was I
at any time you tell me to do it I like
I have already right yeah okay all right
also thank you yes no throughout this
week nothing new came up that needed to
be and even through today's meeting
nothing came up that needed to be
changed so I think we're fine thank you
RFC ahead okay thank you very much whoo
and with only two minutes left I don't
know that there's a lot of time for open
discussion of the drafts papers and
ideas so I would just like to say that
submit them to the list and we'll get
them talking did anybody have a quick
something they wanted to say like there
is my paper on blah and you should all
check it out if not please use the list
it's got some discussion on it sometimes
it could use a bunch more and with that
there's an open mic for a whole minute
and a half out also the co-chairs I
think would also really appreciate input
on that that we change their formats
made the meeting a bit longer it had a
longer talk so a comments on that
whether it was good bad should do it
differently at the mic or afterwards
would be great because we did change it
because there were comments last time so
we want to see if we did the right thing
and changing it at this point seeing
nobody at the mic and nobody with
anything to say I guess we had a whole
minute extra that I could have let
people talk earlier but thank you and
thanks for coming even though there was
a bunch of other good stuff going on at
the same time please be active on the
list please come up with new drafts
Thanks Oh does anybody still need to
sign the blue please do so so then we
get a room again next time
[Music]
you