so folks this is the htdp working group
if you're not here for the htdp working
group please leave in an orderly fashion
we're just about to send the blue sheets
around Thank You Barry you anticipate
our needs as always excuse me
so some preliminaries this is the note
well statement this is the intellectual
property terms which we participate in
the IETF under which is very important
it's one of the primary functions of a
standards body is to give you well known
terms for intellectual property and
antitrust so please if you're not
familiar with this you can use your
favorite search engine for IETF note
well but you do need to be aware of this
it affects your contributions here
another bit of policy which
unfortunately doesn't get quite as much
attention we strive to have a harassment
free environment here there is policy on
this which is in the reference to RFC's
and we have an Ombuds team so if you
feel you are being harassed or you come
across a situation that causes you
concern you can contact these kind
people at the bottom either personally
that's why we have there
or using the email address or you can
talk to the chairs if you'd like we take
that very seriously as well so the blue
sheets are going around please sign them
we need a scribe for this session do we
have any volunteers come on Marie I saw
you out oh yo yo
thank you you're a kind gentleman can
you handle the job or relay or should we
get some octopus I gotcha ever you got
the jabber okay you've got the chipper
our agenda we have two sessions in this
first session we're gonna go over our
active drafts and then we are going to
go over a few bits of proposed work that
has been discussed if we have time at
the end we have a presentation on
secondary certificates any discussion of
this sessions agenda just to give you a
preview the next session is exclusively
about quicken HTTP so we can hold all
those discussions till then okay all
right so let's go ahead and start our
first discussion is of RFC 62 65 this
which is the cookie spec and we have the
editor of that spec here Mike hello I'm
Mike West and I have been working on the
RFC 265 this draft I have a brief update
for you all today basically boils down
to two things thing one I am slow and
thing too I have questions
before we get to details of the draft I
want to talk a little bit about the code
that we have running out in the wild
based on some of the drafts that are
going into this revision of the cookie
Draft after a long ramp up to an
increasing number of users and stable
chrome rolled out the restrictions on
the secure attributes and I think chrome
56 at the end of January of this year
that led to a short-lived surge of bug
reports from people who are now being a
affected by this that weren't affected
before that has basically trailed off at
this point and I think it's something
that we're going to keep in place
firefox shipped the same restrictions in
Firefox 52 in March of this year as far
as I know they're also planning on
keeping this research and in place I
haven't heard anything from either Apple
or Microsoft about their implementations
but this is certainly something that is
affecting large numbers of users and
servers today and I think it's something
that we're actually going to be able to
ship and keep in place the second thing
our cookie prefixes so there are two
prefixes to find the Medoc a double
underscore is secure and double
underscore host based on the chrome chip
these last year Firefox shipped these
last year as well based on the metrics
that we have in chrome the secure prefix
sees practically no usage I think there
was something like 16,000 set cookie
headers that we saw over the last month
whereas the post prefix sees also not a
lot of usage but something like 0.005
percent of the set cookie headers that
we see carry a host prefix and I know of
at least two see a session fixation
attacks inside of Google that this is
actively prevented so it is pretty
useful it's something that I'm happy
that we're shipping again I haven't
heard anything from either Apple or
Microsoft but Firefox and Chrome are
both shipping implementations today
seems like cookies shipped in chrome 51
last year
Mozilla folks were also working on an
implementation it looks like that
implementation is stalled but it still
seems like there's interest in that
implementation from Mozilla again I
haven't heard from either Apple or
Microsoft but we're hopeful that this
kind of thing seems to have a lot of
popularity with developers we see
something like 0.01% of site cookie
headers have already adopted this which
is actually larger than I would have
expected given that it's only
implemented in one browser and that it
provides enough protection that
developers seem interested in the
defending themselves against CSRF using
this attribute so with those
implementations in minds let's
to the draft that is cleverly up on the
screen in front of you right now long
story short I'm just slow
I missed the draft deadline for this
IETF I have a draft on my local computer
that has all three of these
specifications stuffed into it that I'll
upload as soon as those restrictions are
lifted so that you can actually take a
look at it and give some feedback on it
one area in which comments would be
particularly helpful it regards the
layering between the cookie
specification and the fetch and HTML
specifications that are currently being
worked on in the what's up ug standards
body in particular same site needs a
couple of me has more understanding of
HTML and a fetch then I think it
probably should have for this document
but it's not entirely clear to me what
documents the IETF actually wants to
reference and to what extent the IETF
document can pull in concepts
specifically from fetching from HTML
that have a lot to do with web browsers
but don't have a lot to do with clients
like curl so figuring out exactly what
that layering should look like and
providing a clean entry point to those
other specifications is something that
I'd love to get y'all's feedback on I
can imagine pulling things out of the
same site portion of the spec and
putting them into HTML putting them into
fetch
and then providing a set mechanism of
some sort that would set the header
based upon a set of attributes they're
passed in I can also imagine using the
request concept from fetch directly in
the cookie specification order to read
that kind of data ourselves but getting
feedback for me all about what that
layering should look like would be super
helpful the last thing I would note is
that martin thompson put together a
draft last year that was adopted by the
group i forget what the name of it was
eat cookies or he's non-secure cookies
or omnomnom it's not entirely clear but
the the basic idea is that we should
treat cookies that are delivered over
HTTP in a different way than we treat
cookies that are delivered over HTTP
given the amount of adoption of HTTP
over the last year and a half I think
it's probably time to revisit that
specification more actively
and start exploring what that space
might look like this goes to the point
of defending against pervasive
monitoring and also encouraging
advertisers and others who embed their
party contents to migrate to TLS in
order to allow the first birth migrates
to TLS as well so I think that's an
interesting spec I think it's something
that we should look at I don't think
chrome would implement it as is but I do
think that there are some subtle changes
and minor directional changes that we
can make to it that would make it pretty
appealing both for Chrome and hopefully
for other vendors as well yeah so I'm on
Thompson the point of that draft is
really to establish a set of principles
by which you might set policy and so the
policy that chrome implements if they
start going down this path will be
necessarily a subset of the things that
are described in the document and over
time we might see that change and that's
one of the risks that we have with
writing documents like this is that this
is the this touches on policy space and
we need to allow for the fact that the
environment changes over time and as
Mike points out it has changed to the
point where this has become interesting
in the future it may change to the point
that we can actually make a more
definitive statement about it but for
the for this intervening time we have to
think about allowing user agents the
ability to set policies and providing
some sort of guidelines and a framework
for doing that and I think that's the
intent of the draft and I'm very happy
to talk about what those policies might
look like or what guidance we might
provide regarding that yeah so folks
puzzled I'm just curious if Mike you
wanted something more definitive or or
if you agree with that standard I do
agree with that statement I think the
direction of the document that you wrote
is the right one and I think that what
we need to do collectively is figure out
ways to get to that without having
sincere negative side effects on the
ecosystem and I think we can do that
that's all I got so if you have any
questions or feedback about cookies
great
I would be happy to have them so just
from my standpoint and I don't know if
I'm wearing a hat or not personally I'm
willing to try referencing the what
working group document I think it is
going to require some talking to people
and thinking and we'll see how it goes
but I'm willing to try that makes sense
to me I can basically see two paths one
is that we reference that document when
we use its concepts directly the other
is that we provide an entry point to
that document with a lot of boolean's
and parameters that get past it and
allow the embedder of cookies whether it
be a user agent or whether it be curl or
whether it be something else decide what
the what the meaning of those terms is I
would be I'm kind of unhappy about doing
that because I think this document
should define the terms in a way that is
interoperable but putting those
definitions into HTML or into batch is
also viable okay cool thanks folks all
right the next up is expect CT I believe
so Emily Oh full screen my old friend
okay hello
I'm gonna give a quick update on expect
CT um the main thing is the next slide
which is that we're getting ready to
ship an implementation in chrome this
will be branching very soon it goes it's
going out with chrome 61 which goes to
stable in September if you are a site
operator who's interested in using
expect CT now would be a good time to
start thinking about that
it would be great to have some sites
using it as chrome goes into beta so
that we can you know figure out if there
are problems figure out how it's working
etc before it hits stable
okay so I wanted to give a quick update
on some of the open issues and well
hopefully neither of these are open
still but we'll see so one of them is
fairly minor I updated the reporting
format to handle both svt's in both 696
two and six nine six two bits format so
it specifies how clients supporting
either of these versions of CT can
report their at cts the night the next
open issue is cores this is not we
discussed this on the list a little bit
this isn't really the isn't really that
relevant to the ITF except that it
affects implementers of this spec so I
wanted to just talk about it a little
bit your slicer in front of you Emily
okay so the issue here is that um expect
CT reports like many other types of
reporting that that browsers implement
arguably fall under cores restrictions
that prevent web content from triggering
arbitrary requests to two servers that
don't expect those requests
there are various hacks that we
unsatisfying solutions that we discussed
on the list one of them was to just bite
the bullet and send pre flights for
expect CT reports this is not a hack on
the face of it but it turns into a
little bit of a hack because of
implementation concerns we can take
reports and stuff them into a request
that does not need to be preflighted
according to cores or we can just
knowingly violate cores those are our
options right now um what I have ended
up doing in the draft right now is just
leaving it up to the client to decide
what makes sense obviously does it make
sense for you know non browser client to
send pre flights and browsers can also
reasonably disagree on whether they
think that these requests are
our subject to preflight and crumb what
we're doing is we are sending pre
flights right now but my plan is to go
take this up with the fetch spec and see
if we can carve out some kind of
exception that makes sense for reporting
requests because the fact is that there
are a number of reporting requests
reporting requests right now and other
kind of browser generated requests that
violate Korres and will continue to do
so for the foreseeable future so that is
where I think things have settled I'm
curious to hear whether people whether
people agree with that but other than
that if those if those issues are
resolved I'd like to see if we're ready
for working group last call because I
don't have any other open issues or
plans to make changes right now hi Nick
Sullivan CloudFlare just a quick
question about expect CT can the report
URL be on the same host name as the
event that triggered it this would sort
of avoid your core's issue and it would
be easy for us something like Loffler to
deploy widely if that was possible I
don't think the draft says anything
about it right now but I think I think
the chrome implementation does not allow
them to be on the same host name same as
for pinning because of looping
possibilities so so Martin Thompson I
don't know that we ever really got to
the end of this one I think there was a
lot of talking but we never really came
to any conclusion on other thing and I
would like to reach some sort of
conclusion can you explain to me why
it's not possible but the origin of the
response that contained the expect CT
header in the origin of the pre-flight
it's possible but incorrect I mean
that's the that's not what the origin
had her is the origin header is the
the contexts that initiated the request
so yes so who generated in this case
it's the it's the entity that generated
the URI by the thing that controls the
the URI that goes in that request is
really what matters in this context is
the attacker if anyone's the attacker no
I mean if evil calm has a sub resource
includes a sub resource from victim calm
its victim calm that has to opt in to
receiving that request from evil calm so
it's the evil calm origin that needs to
go in the origin header okay maybe maybe
this is not the time to talk that
through I don't know if that's correct
because they the expects et header comes
from the victim yes yes but the but
evil.com is initiating the requests yes
our who initiates the request in this in
this context doesn't actually matter
because victim calm is the only one who
has any control over their expects et oh
well the other issues that it doesn't
you're saying if victim calm chooses to
serve expects et than they are opting
into their incidents but the report URI
can be arbitrary so that's what that's
why you need the origin feel that I mean
as as Nick suggested if you weren't
going cross-origin for this if if victim
calm didn't want to send their reports
to CT reporting calm then that and they
would have and they were and we doesn't
like the system such that they were the
only ones that could receive it that
would not be a cross-origin request in
that sense because the victim calm is
receiving reports at victim calm and
it's it's the one setting the the thing
and it's not a cross-origin request
I think the your modeling of this as the
thing that initiates the request that
then that the HTTP request that then
causes the certificate validation to
occur as being the triggering our agenda
is
incorrect I think you need to perceive
this as the thing that sets the policy
and sets the reporting your I as the one
that actually initiated the request yeah
and then it's different and I think we
might have been talking past each other
when we're talking on this just is
literally impossible because we have
this context and I didn't understand
that that's what you were thinking about
I see because to me it was obvious that
the person making the request is the one
that sets the expectation to think about
that a little bit more but I think I
yeah and with that Mike okay you think
about that some more and say and decide
whether or not you you think that the
the carve out the cause is still
necessary because the kabbala cause is
problematic um I I suspect I will end up
thinking that the carve out records is
still necessary for other reasons but
this may be the wrong place to be having
that discussion ultimately being the
fetch back as the as the venue yeah that
sort of thing you guys decided but we
can offer some advice I don't know if we
can get honor involved in this
conversation any more than we have but
that's really what it yeah and and by
the way after after thinking about it a
little bit more I don't actually think
the null origin is that big of a hack
like it doesn't it's fine perspex as far
as I can tell and it is safe as far as I
can tell in the sense that it does
require the server to opt in and like
you know and unless the report
collection server is an internet server
I think it's fine but but I see what
you're saying yeah so that so the
alternative here that that still ends up
with two requests is for the person
setting the expects a T to set up a
resource for reporting on their own site
and they they you never have across a
that's never across origin requests from
this perspective and then you don't have
a have a pre-flight if they do want to
use an external service they can use one
of our wonderful redirects and we'll
we'll post across to the external
service that's that's possible right so
there's a number of different ways that
this particular cat can be skinned
and I think we can we should talk faster
so it seems like the conclusion is to
leave that issue open for a little bit
more time yeah though I mean another way
one could read that is that I mean the
draft doesn't really say anything in
particular right now it says that if the
client is supposed to be sending Korres
the client should send Korres so I'm not
sure that any of these yeah so - Martin
Thompson I would like to see at least a
plan for for a solution whether it be
here or in some other document know if
if it is entirely appropriate for this
document to say basically nothing about
cause then that's fine but I don't want
to ship this thing and then find out
that the conclusion of the discussion on
the fetch spec is that this document had
had to do something I we don't need to
ship it in screaming hurry do we do we
have a specific issue about this open on
a third spec yep it's a fetch pick and
the fax back yep I think did you work
alone um I don't think there's one
specific to expect CT if there's one
about OCSP which is the whole other
because it seems like ona and sleevee
and a few other folks need to be
consulted so i I'd say so yeah let's
let's talk to those guys and then hi
there this is this is important to them
so it should be difficult to get their
time so hopefully you know okay any
other questions or comments for Emily
all right thank you all right thank you
so is Paul Henning with us
silence alright so the next item on our
agenda is about the header a common
structure draft mark is going to do is
best phk imitation and consumptive let
that's quite a bar I don't think we have
a lot to talk about here there hasn't
been a lot of activity on this spec what
there has been is confusion about the
scope of the specification in that I
think people think that this spec is for
different things and my understanding
from the discussion that led us into
adopting this spec and indeed the
discussion about jfv which was its
predecessor was that we were most
interested in something that would
improve the experience for people
authoring new headers so that there were
less pitfalls facing them and they had
something they could rely upon and also
to make headers more reliable to parse
there are some secondary goals in terms
of making headers more efficient or
allowing alternative encodings of
headers but those were not our primary
goals in doing this work and so I guess
from my perspective I'm interested in
what people think about if I've got
those goals right and if so whether
we're still on track for meeting those
does anybody have any strong opinions or
even weak opinions about that
Julie and I see you out there hi I'm
Mike West as someone who is minting
headers
I liked JSON a lot more I think JSON
from a web developer perspective has
tooling everywhere in every language is
very easy to use is well understood by
developers who are going to be setting
headers and reading headers and that
seems to me to be a strong argument in
favor of something that reuses things
that developers know about today thank
you Julian says on jabber we're not
making progress that's the main issue
and I'm willing to get the Jason's back
out as a non-working groupers back right
my response that is I would ask for a
little bit of Julian's patience in that
if we can come to a solution as a
working group it would be nice to have
one way to do this instead of two but
let's let's maybe give it a little more
time Michael for me to echo you're on
the air
well what's up pressing the button okay
so I would agree with the goals as you
stated them I would say that from
discussion with our dev team we really
really don't want to be including a JSON
parser that low in the sack if we have
to we will but I'd prefer we not go that
route and I like this draft a lot better
more in that direction but again making
progress is not there's the issue
so Mike I guess again speaking
personally I look at this draft and I
have a hard time getting from it to I
think where we need to be you know it
doesn't talk about parsing error
handling the author experience any of
that and it does seem complex you know
personally I'm tempted to try and write
a draft to you know offer another
approach do you think that this draft
that we have now is is you know 50% of
the way there 80% is its eligible I
suspected it is salvageable I agree with
you that there are probably some pieces
missing and it would be interesting to
see a draft or a full request but trust
to fill those in okay I might talk to
Paul Henning and I think we need to
huddle yeah yeah my quest again one
thing I would note about the JSON parser
is that I understand that putting a JSON
parser into the net stack seemed strange
and difficult one nice thing about JSON
is that because we have implementations
and because those implementations are
exposed to the web they've been very
well fuzzed
and we have a very good understanding of
the security properties associated with
them given that I even I don't have that
much trepidation about using the
existing JSON parsers in places where
they aren't currently used because again
I think they've been very well fuzzed
I'd love to hear from Daniel Steinberg
but I don't think he's about is he I am
opposed to using Jason since even in the
most popular JSON process we found in
compatibilities that result in different
interpretations and since it's about
headers and miss interpretations or
disagreement between how a for example a
floating number would be implement
interpreted might result in a security
issue
so I'm strictly opposed to using Jason
and
I favored using this HTTP had a common
structure as a basis so Martin Thompson
won I sort of caution against getting
too much into the what we would prefer
to do a or b no I think we've actually
heard a lot of those comments before
about Julian's draft and about this
draft I think part of the problem with
the current draft is that it it
originally came from a place where it
was being a little more aspirational in
its goals and a lot of that legacy
remains in the document and maybe it can
be salvaged but I would I would like to
see those goals articulated first and
that would be that would be worthy of
yeah conclusion as well yeah right and I
think one thing we can do we started the
discussion on the list about these goals
we probably need to finish that and get
consensus on them I don't know that
we're in a place to get that consensus
right here and now because we need to
articulate them a bit better but let's
go ahead and do that
and then see where we sit perhaps right
anything else in this one not for me
okay
cuz you know cache digest yes
screens right let me just find the
presentation
hi so let me explain about the changes
that has been made to the cash next
draft so there has been three changes
and well the first let's talk about the
last one and this intended status has
been changed to experimental as we
discussed in Chicago since a browsers
likely to have support for cash dices in
the news feed future and on instead
we've added definition for the cash
Liars header and considering I'm going
to experiment so the cash that is headed
is emulation of the cash digest http/2
house frame which is not as optimal as
using a frame but it kind of works and
it's already being implemented in apache
h2o and also there is a node module
called chastised immutable and there are
some small scale deployments now that
already have this being activated and
the header looks like this and it's
basically a base64 form of the digest
value and some flags so it's really
one-to-one matching between the frame
definition and the header so next please
and we also have a new feature that is
actually an HTTP to setting that allows
the server to tell the client whether it
supports cash values and the issue with
we thought that it existed but since
Justin just needs to be setting 0 RTD
there was no way to let the server to
notify the client whether it wants to be
chances not however we've noticed that
since the else one points very full
handshakes
let's the server speak first using the
zero zero point 5 RTG data we cannot
fire from the server to the client that
if it wants to see a cash status before
clients has the chance to say me I need
it so this takes advantage of the
approach on the other hand 0.5 RTG is
only a very
available in for handshake so for the
zero our duty resumption the client
needs to remember the remember if the
server supports a cache digest and have
that information associated it's at your
session cache and well while that might
sound complicated my understanding that
terrorists tax would have that kind of a
support that kind of association
I mean associating extra data to station
cash since that that is also a
requirement in quick so we have that we
have this API and we hope their browsers
once they decide to support cache
stylist can use this thing so this so
these are all the changes so the
question is what the next step is maybe
we could go through right and and and so
that's the the I guess the question is
that we've been letting this draft
hangin around for a little while to see
if a browser would implement it and and
we don't seem to have anyone
prioritizing it you know in a native
browser implementation although as Kazuo
mentioned we do have some header
implementations and so if if we don't
get any information about that I think
it makes sense to take it to last call
and go as experimental pkg hi this is
Gigi I apologize that I have not read
the draft does the are you expecting for
the client to remember this for the
duration of the resumption ticket of the
TLS resumption ticket earth so that
that's the explicit duration that you
want that to be cached ah you mean the
accept cash digest header will be
remembered for the duration of the
session ticket of the session to get
okay on the other hand the cache state
is more stable oh I mean the thing right
but this particular header is synced in
it's it's retained specifically
alongside the presumption state yes okay
so does anyone have any any comment
about going ahead to working group last
call with this does any browser vendor
went to shout no no I'm going to
implement that right we did have some
interest but we didn't have a commitment
so Oh Mike I wish I could be doing SH
and doing the shouting that I'm going to
implement this but I think we're still
in the same state of interested in that
but don't have any immediate plans for
it we want to see how it goes
could you remind me though what is the
size particularly when you base64 it
we're kind of sighs do you need four
acceptable false positive rates sorry
what's what size do you typically see
with the header version when you base64
it what to represent a reasonable cash
with a reasonable false positive rate
yes I understand that you know we don't
have we only have very small size
deployments at the moment so loads our
numbers quite small like how everybody's
going to save it mm-hm hundred bytes
Mike firfer but for the very limited
deployments we have now yes when you use
the header I see something like the
serviceworker cache answer you're
choosing what you store in it rather
than doing it full HD right so for a lot
skill site a lot especially with that I
catch that his frame would typically be
one that rings a bell I think that's
what I came up with yeah and you know it
kind of blows due to base64 and it will
have some impact on the HP compressor it
however the size is likely we might be
less than half of the HVAC C so
hopefully we can live with
some hon Thompson you said less than
half the h-back state how big are you
actually making these things I didn't
think it was that I didn't think they
were that big yeah and where people are
advertising pretty large h-back tables
now after realizing that the default is
fairly really small so I'm not I think
part of the problem here is that this is
an experiment backed up behind what is
effectively another experiment and the
success of server push on the whole
doesn't hinge on this but it it is still
in question I think some people would
disagree with that I think some people
see this as necessary to make the server
push successful and I know that that's a
contentious topic but some people have
stated that sure but a lot of the
problem this solves some of the problem
with server push but not all the
problems that we've discussion at some
length up in other venues but to the
extent that it fixes the problem it is
it is also equally encumbered by the
other problems that that are attached to
so proportion and until we understand
more we we can't really say whether or
not this is the right solution and
that's why I think we should publish it
as it experimental and just though it's
been sitting here it hasn't changed in
some ridiculously long time now there
are implementations out there let's see
how the experiment runs right and
explicitly say this is an experiment to
determine whether or not we can fix
heavy push but the one thing we were
kind of waiting for was that a whole
discussion of golden compressed sets
versus cuckoo filters but that seems to
us without more data we can't really
make a decision there otherwise so we
decided just to stick with how it is
so in jabber llansteffan oats that size
depends on the probability you want to
achieve which mic agrees with either
bread lossy Google Chrome just to answer
the question of what our status is we're
interested in this but it's not
prioritized the biggest problem we see
is it's quite hard
to implement within our current cash
implementation so and we're not sure
that this is the right solution
to server pushes problems so if this
doesn't have a high probability of being
required we don't want to put the
investment in to rewrite our whole cache
to support it that makes sense
Gemma and Gugu just came up to Jen
Iyengar Google I just came up here to
can you hear me now yes yes to say that
I agree with Martin in that this seems
like an experimental proposal unless
there's any other way to do this that's
that's the way I would publish it as
experimental right thank you and I think
the worst case is is that if a browser
gets interested but discovers that this
isn't the right approach we burn a frame
type and have cache digest 2 or whatever
it is but it's still worth publishing I
think it's a bit we'll never have again
mark what about the bits we will think
of other bits yes thank you thank you so
mark I have a friendly I have a request
for an agenda Bash can we at least move
the origin frame a little later we have
someone in another in another room doing
a presentation who would like to be here
for this certainly sir
that puts us at random access in live
content we'll find out if dar shockers
paying attention or he thought he had
another 10 minutes and you checked in a
PowerPoint presentation I checked in
when I was sent bad Patrick oh yeah hold
on let's see if I can make this work
that's a of really quick and we
don't even need the presentation ok I
can go we're getting there
I can't guarantee the fonts will be
exactly the same that's all right
so I'm just gonna I'm here to just give
a quick a bid on the random access live
draft that's right so I think at the
last working group we actually had
requested comments or feedback from from
the working group
we haven't received any specific
concerns or comments I'm assuming people
have probably read it and no problems at
all our people haven't read it but then
the other feedback that we had received
was to actually just try out you know
the protocol of the idea and make sure
that it actually works with caches or
intermediaries and doesn't have any
problems with that so next slide on that
note so we are actually just working on
kind of building a test framework so we
have our client and server sort of ready
we are you are hoping to finish this by
before this IETF but we are a little bit
behind so we'll still finish this and
send out our observations of results or
hope is that the answer is there are no
issues with caches and intermediaries
but we want to verify the hypothesis and
that's pretty much it next slide so any
questions and I guess the question to
the working group would be we is it a
good time to issue a last call keeping
it open pending over results or should
we wait once that's the question of
who's read the draft raise your hand if
you've read the draft live access and
random sorry random access and live
content okay succeed can I help
yes I would observe that that you know
we can do a last call fairly quickly and
so if you know what if you were to bring
the data either you know on the lists in
next month or two or in Singapore Wieck
additional last call and have a two week
period and then yeah soft glass call if
you like I mean we are sort of right now
asking for any concerns which is very
similar question through a lens called
indeed in right so I would say if you've
got an active experiment I'd prefer to
see it finish and then we can do you
know just a two-week call maybe yeah
we're hoping you're doing before
Singapore so okay sounds good right
thank you
look forward hearing about it 8gb
replays just keep going on um we can do
that sure so replays this is Martin
ah oh wow that's right all right so one
of the things we've been doing in TLS is
this is zero I'll teach a theme that has
everyone in a flap and one of the things
that that document requires of us is to
explain how it is that you use your
protocol with zero ITT before you
actually start using it full disclosure
we may have deployed this already
without any of the measures that are in
this dart in this document but such as
the nature of the pre-release channels
that has been deployed on that I think
we've probably claimed that you know
there's an experiment out there right
now it just happens to be sort of rather
large next slide please so I'm the
primary risk here is that zero ITT
lights the client make requests but the
TLS handshake isn't done as a
consequence there's no fresh state from
the server mixed in to this and the
request can effectively be replayed now
TLS mandates that you do some Antibes
replay stuff and they're imperfect what
can I say next so this is what the draft
does and says it says that the TLS
connection is modeled as a single stream
there was a lot of debate about this in
in Telos as to whether you would have
separate compartments for the early data
and the other stuff and you were somehow
have some sort of clear delineation
between the two of them practically
speaking that doesn't work for HTTP I'm
not sure that works for many TCP based
protocols it may work for things that
use that data ground protocols but we're
not done with DTLS ones for you just yet
and then the document contains advice
some basic guidance on what to send in
zero RTT and on the receiving end what
you might want to do with it and how you
would deal with it on that end
and then there's some discussion that we
had in a workshop about intermediaries
and we realized that we've really nice
if we had a couple mechanisms from
intermediaries and we defined some of
those next place so the advice for
clients we recommend safe methods in the
document there's some sort of hand
waving with shoots and maize and whatnot
that allows for other things in the
browser context different policies will
prevail depending on your attitude and
what these things the other thing is
that we we actually mandate an automatic
retry of the request if the zero ITT is
rejected and we talk about the fact that
you might decide not to send a request
anyway but in the general case if you
made the request in zero ITT and zero
RCT is rejected then you will make the
request again that would be the default
operation unless someone has used one of
the new methods that we're providing to
cancel the request in the meantime I
think that's probably the only out that
we have one that it's important to
recognize this enables an attack and the
draft explains that but it's it's a 1:1
kind of one time only it's it's it's a
visible thing and we are being very
careful to distinguish between the
effects of retries from the rific at the
effects of replays and the distinction
here is that a retry is something that
the client does with full knowledge of
what's going on a replay or something in
an attacker does with the packets on the
network and this is language that's
being used in tailless as well next
advice to the server's here first thing
is please consider whether you want to
enable zero ICT at all and this is
something that TLS does not necessarily
enable by default you have to turn it on
we have some advice on that one and then
it says whatever you do before the
handshake completes that's the risky
stuff and the assertion in the draft and
the model that we have sort of adopted
for this not formally verified
disclaimer is that if servers always
deferred processing of a given request
until after the handshake group
completes then they will only ever see
that request once that's a that's an
assertion I'm like I said not sure about
that and so the recommendation following
on from that is that if you're not sure
whether something is safe wait and so
this has some performance downsides but
the consequence of this is that when you
get these messages you have some have
some certainty and the performance
downsides aren't it doesn't completely
eliminate the performance gains from
zero ITT the opportunity cost of having
this slot is not completely wasted so
you you can send all the bytes and then
the bytes are ready on the server ready
for processing and you can even do some
basic parsing as long as that parsing is
sort of content agnostics side-effect
free and all the sorts of things we've
talked about
so there are still some benefits to
having the data arrive without actually
doing anything about it we talked about
that as well
next place intermediaries with the
interesting discussion so an
intermediary really can't decide what's
safe just based on the knowledge they
have typically so what we recommend here
is that an intermediary marks the
requests that arrive in before the
handshake completes with a new header
field and that header field signals to
upstream servers that the request may or
may not be safe as a result of something
that happened further downstream on the
path and that origin server can reject
those requests if it thinks that they're
unsafe or it can defer processing on
them or do what whatever other things
that might want to do deferring
processing at the origin is difficult
because it doesn't know when the hantai
completes and doesn't know whether that
that signal doesn't arrive so the
here is that the header field is only
really used by intermediaries if a
request arrives in zero huh tt you know
that the person sending it would have
included this header is basically
implicitly present by default and that
allows us to sort of not worry too much
about annotating every single request
that we ever sent and saves a little bit
space the reject mechanism allows the
server to force non zero RCT requests in
the unsafe cases it means if the server
is unwilling to accept the risk of a
replay it can tell the client hey this
is not cool
try again there's a risk here again that
if this processing is not consistent you
get you've created a side channel so
there's a little bit of advice about
what to do in that circumstance as well
and the important point here that we had
some discussion between the author
authors of the draft for quite some time
is that the combination of these two
mechanisms requires coordination between
an intermediary who enables zero RTT and
the servers that sit behind them because
if these annotations are not understood
by the server's in the back then the
server's in the back will not know to be
it will not be able to reject things
appropriately and so the message arrives
its marked with early data by the
intermediary who supports this draft and
implements it and and deploy zero RTT
but the back-end server doesn't even
know to look at the early data header
and so it processes the message without
knowledge of the this risks that it has
taken and so that could be exploited in
some fairly nasty ways we don't really
know any way to avoid this particular
problem I mean once the request is being
forwarded then it's being forwarded and
there's some things we can do that I
think this is probably the best solution
without making the request completely
incomprehensible so we could we could
rot13 the entire request
if they came in early data and put the
old I had a field up front I suppose
that would be on we could do some some
serious damage to the protocol if we
wanted to do to make this possible
mandatory but I think this is a
reasonable compromise is that all I have
no more just a small clarification which
I think follows from what you just said
this isn't really for all intermediaries
it's just for gateways yes specifically
use the word gateway and the term there
because I don't see this being useful in
the forward proxy case because the
forward proxy enables the it's quite
convenient you know the client connects
with zero ITT it sends a request to the
forward proxy like you're gonna do that
anyway but since the forward proxy and
the forward proxy annotates in this way
but it's got no idea that the server's
are going to be able to accept this you
understand the new header field and I
think there's if I remember there's
still advice in there that if you're
configured to use a proxy you don't use
your RTT correct oh you can use zero ICT
because you're gonna connect yeah right
so that's right you can do whatever you
want it's yeah right I don't think
anyone uses for proxies without this oh
yeah so for xx is one of our we have
this design pattern that with we're
started to use a lot more often which is
an explicit permission to retry
something and improves reliability no
end importantly here it's it's an
automatic retry and no matter what the
request is this means that clients can
be more confident in attempting zero RTT
because any server that accepts zero RTT
will understand this will reject
something if the server blaze it say so
if the client thinks it's safe then they
can attempt the zero ITT there was a
risk with out these mechanisms that the
clients would not do this because if
they don't know that the server's were
able to understand this particularly in
those intermediate ated cases where you
have the CD ends involved you know the
reverse proxy the the gateways and so it
becomes a mutual thing both sides have
to agree that it's safe to do this to
know each other before anything happens
next
example so you can see in the example
you make the zero RTT request its
annotated by the gateway with the new
header field the server goes eh not not
for me right now and sends back a too
early status code and then the client
waits for the handshake to complete then
we try some request pretty
straightforward that's all I have okay
Victor is waiting very patiently the
question so one thing which kind of
feels weird about this design is that we
don't actually have a standardized
mechanism to communicate a between
gateway and server whether it's a
connection was secure or not as far as
I'm aware so Oh early data feels a
little bit weird in this context because
it's like well you don't have early data
you don't know whether it was actually
secure or not so so Victor in the in
this in this scenario typically the the
origin server is completely usually
pretty well aware of the fact that
they've employed a CDN or have a load
balancer sitting in front of them I'm
not sure whether I why you have this
specific concern as a result of this I
mean is it just an observation it's
mostly an observation that just feels
weird
well another thing to feel weird yeah
welcome to http especially with CD ends
it's about it's about anger so if I'm
understanding this correctly the clients
don't send their early header but this
is meant for only intermediates it's
implicit in the case when you put
something you know a data the that the
purpose of it is to signal that
something on a previous hop happened so
as for example as a browser if I'm
sending a request server early data then
is it valid for me to actually include
this early data header but because I
would be really useful since without
that I didn't
is that whatever the the intermediate
proxy has to have a separate API to
receiver Lydia to know that this data
came over early data because it's a
single stream like you said and so
there's a number of reasons
sergeant ones I mentioned and one of the
more important reasons is that it is
often very difficult when you're
constructing a message and putting it on
the wire knowing what the status of the
the wire is when the message hits the
wire and so this way allows the clients
to send the same message twice and and
avoids accidentally annotating things
that are either the handshake is yeah I
think that equal same argument to be
made about like receiving data as well
and some data as between the half there
are two tiered stuff so I've assumed
that like a reasonable thing would be if
I have at least some data on this
request sterilized of a zero ITT I would
include this early data header and that
would help terminating proxies not need
to have the separate API first evening
so RTT data if they want to do something
more fancy they can you don't need a
separate API how the the draft sort of
explains this that the terms under which
we we mark things is is the handshake
complete that is the marker that we're
looking for and it's a very simple
marker to get and every every stack that
I'm aware of has has a very clear
delineation you have a point in time at
which the handshake is considered
complete and a point where you may may
be uncertain but it's I'm gonna cut in I
don't know we've got 20 minutes left and
other things to discuss the focus here
should be on whether there's interest in
adopting the document not on the details
please as a solo developer who has
already shaped a gateway that suppose
you are Tiki I love to have this
document for my eyes early and even
before working group adoption I love to
have that 4x X code space piloting the
sick number so that we can implement it
we had some debate about the number was
less that's already a teapot Nick
yet Nick Sullivan I like this I support
this draft I think it's really good the
only question I had was how are you
going to deal with interactions with TLS
intercepting proxies it's the wild wild
west out there then nothing I can do
about it
this is dkg so the decision on the
server side of when to send the 4xx is I
think the least understood part of this
the part of this that I understand the
least yes I think the semantics that we
want for that are you as a server must
know the complete architecture of your
entire operation and you must be able to
identify as an origin server the set of
requests that are not permissible to be
sent in that that would be damaging if
they were redoing and so when it said
you're effectively saying sort of
permission to retry what you're actually
saying is there's no way that if this
thing was replayed somewhere else we're
not sick it's attempting to read this as
the semantics are ok I receive this but
for whatever reason I I'm not gonna
handle it therefore it's safe to go
ahead and retry which is distinct from
saying the request that you sent is not
something that should have been in zero
rgt in the first place you see what I'm
saying but we don't want to do is we
don't want to we don't want the origin
server to be like okay I received this
I'm not gonna process it because it
could have been replayed therefore it's
okay to go ahead and retry there's
there's two slightly different meanings
there yeah and it would be really bad if
we gave origin servers the wrong
guidance yeah and so this is actually
the critical guidance and that's the
part that I I'm not confident you know
so pkg what it were close is that
something that you think would stop us
adopting it or something that we could
discuss and perhaps no I think it's
something that if we're good I think I'd
opting it is reasonable I see the I see
the if we're gonna have zero RTT I see
the need for this but but yeah okay so
full disclosure so along with Martin and
Willy I'm a co-author on the doc
so determining consensus for this lies
in Patrick's capable hands so we're
gonna seek consensus from the working
group do a couple hums on whether or not
we're interested in adoption of this
document I guess first can you hum if
you have read this document if you favor
the working group oh we got one on
jabber there got to do both if you favor
the working group are adopting the
document that's been presented here
would you hum now and if you oppose the
working group docking the document we've
discussed here hum now okay that sounds
like strong consensus perhaps unanimity
well this reflects at least three or
four adopting hums on jabber five they
keep growing so thank you Thank You
Martin Thank You Nikki mark I think we
should backtrack and reward it Martin is
the person who you were concerned about
now with us I thought that might be the
case I think we should give that party
because that's active work Randy so
let's talk about origin um do I need to
update my classes are now authenticated
there we go I just need to pull it over
they'll be a second you go ahead and get
a pen oh sure they were really good more
chair slides than not personal slides so
is there anything to discuss on origin
other than the active discussion on the
mammals as one of the author's I do not
believe they're primarily errs there is
some discussion that has been going on
regarding a few things that Lucas
brought up and if you want you know Mike
time to address those I think that's
fine but the primary issue in the
document has been this clause other than
that we are I think fairly close to
wrapping up the origin frame extension
so the clause reads clients must not
consult the Dinah's to establish the
connections authority for a new requests
this is in reference obviously to
origins that were in the origin frame
and it of course also involves the
normal certificate checks from 7540 that
are referenced elsewhere in the text
this clause you know it's clearly not
yet reached working group consensus
there are a couple different schools of
thought on this so if you want to move
to the next slide I think there is
consensus that the existing DNS
provision in 7540 is a weak second
factor involved and you know
establishing a connection there is
however disagreement in the group about
you know just how valuable of a factor
that that is and so the discussion has
been leading the chairs to ask you know
this question here is the substitution
of a different more performance and
privacy friendly second factor or
factors you know into the origin
extension you know a path forward with
that if mark which I can make any
comment says you know co-author of that
document not that slide so I mean from
my perspective I'm looking you know has
an editor I'm an editor on that document
as well for a way forward on it and and
as I commented on list in the last day
or two you know historically we haven't
specified the exact spec stack of
specifications that you use when you're
verifying about a new certificate for
htdp that has resided elsewhere the IETF
defines a selection of those mechanisms
but we don't say in HTP itself you must
do this this this or this and so it
seems like we should think about that
before we go and specify specific
mechanisms here but from what I've seen
there does seem to be support for saying
in a slightly more vague fashion you
need some sort of second factor beyond
just their certificate itself and and
and it could be that mechanisms that we
typically use to validate those
certificates could also be used as that
second factor to have more confidence in
it but I'm still looking as an editor
for input from the working group on
exactly how we want to go back to
that mm-hmm comments from the floor yeah
so so Martin Thompson I think the this
Falls kind of into the territory of what
what does a client do to decide that a
given server is acceptable for a given
name and there is there are some
commonality there but there's also quite
a bit of wiggle room our certificate
transparency policies diverse and the
way that we validate certificates is in
some cases a little bit different and we
have different trust anchors in some
cases and so the idea that we mandate a
single thing is I think the point on
which we've actually sort of gotten
wrapped around the axle in this
discussion and I that the the right
advice here is that we we acknowledge
the possibility that DNS is important
and that we're potentially taking that
away recognize that the privacy benefits
of doing so are significant and then say
that and a client or user agent can make
its own decisions about what policy it
wants to apply in determining whether or
not a given request can be made to this
particular server and I think that is
it's kind of weaseling in a sense
because we're just sort of pumping the
can down the road a little bit but with
a lot of these things I think the the
normalization comes with time as we get
more experience with the policies I do
think that there is value in having the
must not DNS statement in here and
retaining that because I don't want
servers to be in a position where they
can't rely on this mechanism for
particular properties and that property
that I care about here is not making
additional DNS queries and certainly in
the in the current environment making
those DNS queries expo
certain information to to others that I
would rather not have exposed so um just
to respond to that I get a little
uncomfortable when you talk about
servers relying on that property because
that's not a design property that we
have and it's possible for you know in
error handling in transients conditions
for a connection to close or foreign or
you know an origin to be popped onto a
new connection and all the sudden it is
exposed to the network and if your piano
and not being exposed to the network
that that it seems like it's a much
higher bar than we've currently designed
a floor it is you probably also need
some kind of an acknowledgement yeah
Eric right so what happens when you send
this origin frame doing an existing
client nothing right so it's already the
case that you cannot rely on this
property right and similarly any client
which decided to it didn't like the
origin the frame would then be made
these DNS requests so as far as I can
tell regrettably you know I mean
regrettably this is a best-effort kind
of situation unless we're gonna create
some a mess we're going unless we're
gonna grate some indication for the
client that says I promise to speak
origin and I promise not to do DNS or
cross those are evidences that would be
a new kind of interlocking we have not
previously but we could put in an
acknowledgment like essentially yeah I
mean we could put a thing where the
client said and right you would think
with a client could it could you say
that those are my semantics it's not in
touch I guess the question then becomes
is how would how would we actually
expect the server behave differently
under those circumstances given that
presumably the situation at hand is the
client is gonna attempted you reference
those URLs and if the client like you
know refuses Jeff I mean like the
server's not gonna send you some content
which causes external linking because
then because you said screw you I don't
like origin I mean I I guess I guess I
understand like I mean I agree agreed
the desire a property to conceal the DNS
requests I just don't understand how
like how is this so we're gonna
dependent that property even if it could
so I agree that I don't
this is dkg I also don't see how without
some
additional mechanism and I'm not even
sure what the mechanism would be that we
can make this a must although I agreed
that it would be nice to make it a must
this statement of the problem that's on
the screen right here I think is
problematic because it says existing DNS
provision but it's really doing about
existing DNS over the local network
provision there are multiple ways to get
DNS data and I think if we're gonna
frame the problem like this we should be
clear that we're talking about the
network path being the additional week
second factor not the fact of DNS data
period so for example I could have some
additional out-of-band channel that
gives me DNS information or I could have
an in band general that gives me DNS
information not to bring this working
group to the question though but the you
know it's not about DNS / data it's
about what came over the local model oh
no the provision of 7540 is about data
we've got two remote people waiting
let's do one or two of those no sure of
course Yoshiko Google sorry we're on
Mike's on or about people yes I'm like
hey so I'm going to echo the concerns
that I don't really want to see this as
a must not because and you have existing
clients that are that already have
coalescing logic and I don't think that
this should depart from that
substantially if we want to say that
it's a clients may do other things may
omit the check and have some guidance as
to what you might look for before you
make that decision I think that's
probably a smarter path I also will
repeat what I said in the jabber that
we're also later today doing an adoption
call for a draft that says the exact
opposite the client must still do DNS so
we need to reconcile this one way or the
other in both graphs
thanks Mike go ahead ekor oh yeah so um
I I guess two things first is um um I
don't I think partially right the the we
second factor is the go deep on the
network path that is allegedly
associated with the DNS and that will be
a weak second factor even if the DNS
were entirely trustworthy mainly say you
got that over DNS SEC like the issue is
is the the issue is the if I thought the
factors are way if all the network
between you and the website right so the
the is attending to give you is even if
we trusted yes entirely is not being
routed some entirely third location
which is not associated with it with the
origin you care about um the that the
second thing I was going to note is that
we actually can take three postures one
posture is the one that's in this
traffic nobody likes very much the other
is to sort of kind of encourage people
to do some other second factor and not
say what that really is but say there
ought to be one and the third is to say
we take no position or are hostile so
that you have a second factor that we
spoke you can so I think like I mean
this is sort of a very weaselly kind of
text um I think it might be better
simply to document exactly what the
assumptions are and say implement we'd
lead off the implementations decide how
to behave I don't know so not place
requirements around them just document
possibilities yeah I mean I mean I mean
my sense was that that may the people on
the mailing list resisted the ID you
should not do a second check and um and
so if we're gonna say is that means me
saying don't do a second check to be
problematic by their hand I sense their
people um you know in a sense there were
people all in the discussion who thought
a second check was silly and then I'm
like that makes me operate enthusiastic
about recommending a second check
especially when there appear to be 84
second checks with extremely different
security properties no okay Victor so if
was there is one saying which my
experience with browsers and socket
poles has taught me is that normally so
they cannot
promise you that they will handle
requests in certain way they will try to
handle it optimal way but God knows how
it will they actually handled so I do
not believe that from perspective of
user agents this is actually a viable
strategy the assumption of not having
DNS queries is viable so I do i side
with occurs that which would document
that there might be a second factor
required by user agent and documents
clearly what happens when the user agent
declines that second factor and whether
it declines its explicitly or implicitly
but leaves the specific policy after
browsers thanks Victor the cheek or a
Google so I would rather see as the site
what should be the second factor
especially since some of the considerate
options would require changes to the
format of origin frame for example if
you wanna staple DNS SEC response and
send it inside of jean-frank that's part
of the draft and it cannot be like hand
wave it and say like trying to do
whatever then Schwartz I agree with that
I it does seem like having a you even
just a relatively open-ended extension
field in in origin to be able to figure
this out later it would be nice let's
hear from Eric no audio working here yes
yeah I think the one of the things that
worries me is trying to well I
appreciate the desire to have a pride
can do someone's for privacy reasons
trying to have something that's not
explicitly designed for privacy it's
just kind of a a piece of an overall
privacy story seems like it could do
more harm than good and it may make
sense to take the design of a a privacy
specific
thing and look at what are all the
pieces needed together and treat that as
a separate draft and have the origin
frame itself just go back to not
changing the existing behavior because
because prior to origin frame the there
already are constraints on what sort of
coalescing is needed in that era allowed
and that DNS needs to be checked so the
the most conservative thing to do would
be forge and frame to not relax that
requirement and then for us to look back
separately at building a better and more
comprehensive story on how we might want
to real relaxed the DNS requirements in
a way that that can be that does does it
could unbuild up a comprehensive privacy
story some of them Thompson I just
wanted to push back against the
suggestion that we that we hold this one
because we might want to make some
changes to the origin frame I think the
if we do want to make some if we do want
to say do some DNS SEC record pinning
and we would find a way to do that
virtually orthogonal to the to all of
this and I just keep coming back to the
the notion that this is really kind of
this DNS requirement is really a policy
decision that we made by accident I
think more than anything else and that
we're relying on it so thoroughly is
it's kind of sad but we kind of got it's
like one of those ossification things we
we ended up here by accident now we're
now we find that we can't remove it and
I don't know what it just makes me sad
that that's where we're at I would
rather leave this completely for the
time being and loans and things maybe
before we actually commit to something
okay so I think the chairs will have to
huddle and sort of you reread the
minutes here but thank you all for the
comments ad Adam wrote are you still
the room are okay well based on that
we're going to do the discussion of BCP
56 bits next and hopefully we'll talk
about HC Beecher as time allows in our
next session we'll try and carve out a
little space for that but we appreciate
out of making time to be here for this
okay
if I can get to it
all right so um this is another proposal
for a document that I've been working on
the background for a little while called
BCP 56 bits and the original BCP 56 was
on the use of HTTP a substrate so
basically how do we use you know HTTP
well when we use it with other protocols
that are defined inside the IETF and it
was done this is from the data tracker
as you can see in 2002 2002 it had just
a couple of drafts from from Keith Moore
and and was published way back then and
this is the abstract which I finally
recently somewhat amusing it turns out
we we now have a lot of interest and
quite widespread interest in using HTTP
as a substrate for other application
level protocols I have a cron job on one
of my boxes that emails me and Patrick
every couple of weeks now and and lists
all of the ITF documents in working
groups that reference HTTP and this is
the current run of that tool there are
lots of people you know using HTTP
different ways and this doesn't actually
list them all there are new working
groups blowing up all the time it's
saying oh yeah we'll use HTTP for that
and and I don't have time to review them
all and give them advice Julien I'm sure
doesn't have time to review all the
header fields that they create
he is our bottleneck for header field
syntax as well as other things of course
it's it's the there's a lot going on
we're seeing an explosion of this not
just in the outer world but but in the
IETF specifically and in the outer world
it's happening as well you know HTTP
api's are used for everything including
cat gifs and the problem that I see or
maybe problems too strong but one of the
issues is that people design a an API
for their own server to deploy to serve
cat gifts via API and they don't think
about the implications of taking that
API design for one HTTP server and
scaling it out to multiple HTTP servers
multiple implantation with different
versions and different extensions and
the coordination problem that that
entails it's it requires a different
kind of protocol but they're still using
the techniques that they've learned
deploying their single implementation
and deployment API on the other hand you
know the it's very easy for an effort to
give this kind of guidance to turn into
a bit of a crusade to to say thou shalt
be restful and and I really want to
avoid that that minefield I want to have
advice that is useful to people based
upon the experience we have as a
community for using HTTP as a substrate
and so that is the the line I'm trying
to walk and it's very embryonic right
now that's the line I'm trying to walk
in this document it's it's very
bare-bones right now but I think the
question I have for the working group as
an editor of that document is are we
interested in in in starting work up in
this area again the the hallway chats
I've had personally are that people
recognize its way past overdue for for
revising this advice because the world
has moved on considerably since 2000 and
2001 in terms of how we use HTTP and so
I wanted some feedback as to whether
people are interested in working on this
and giving feedback
I've already had a lot of feedback
during this meeting that I've started
incorporating the document there's
certainly a lot more work to do but I'm
very interested in doing this if only to
save us the time and the effort of
scaling you out to individual reviews
all the time Jonathan the Jedi and God I
think yeah I think that it makes
complete sense to consider the things
that you would need to do to make HTTP a
good substrate if that's part of the
goal of such of this document and I
think it's absolutely appropriate in
particular when something becomes a
substrate which HTTP has it ends up
picking things into it which people
don't realize that you don't scale
widely to large numbers of applications
latency is one of those things when
there's a tiny bit of latency that's
baked into the substrate things that
build on top of it end up havin deeper
and deeper latency
that's not a good thing to have so being
able to document all of that stuff is
very useful at the same time I wonder if
this is the community that would be in a
position to do that what I mean by that
is the people who are actually using
HTTP as a substrate are likely to be
folks who don't care about exactly what
is going on underneath but are more
likely to simply grab a library which
they can use to talk easily to the other
side and use the surface of it and use
HTTP without necessary caring about
exactly what's going on underneath my
wrist but I think that's true for folks
outside the ITF but we still have folks
come here who want to use HTTP as the
protocol and JE map is an excellent
example of that we spent some time with
Jay map this week talking about their
use of the protocol and for me that was
an exciting thing to do because we
learned that they had requirements that
we weren't meeting and so now we can
start to think about how we could
possibly meet those requirements and
also we can give them at the same time
we can give them some guidance of where
they are able to use existing things in
HTTP we can guide them to make sure that
they're not breaking other stuff or that
they're using it well so I think you
know certainly there are folks in this
working group who this may be too high
layer for more to semantics for but
there are also a lot of people in this
working group I believe who have a lot
to say about this and have the right
experience to do it yeah I should
probably change what I said you're right
of course and I I guess I was thinking
that there are people who are not in the
room who you may want to invite into the
room to talk about how it's being used
sure that's a perhaps a slightly
different point than what I made earlier
as part of the goal also do document
issues that are mean this is going to be
a BCB I don't know the data are in the
document but certainly if we encounter
things that you know are too gnarly to
put in there I would like to resolve
them some somehow yes well Google line
after atom separate document whatever
yeah not until some like like the the
general goals and particularly the way
that you stated them we're going to push
back a bit
against what what Jonah said here one of
the core things that I think this
document kind of needs to say if if not
directly but but sort of at least cover
is that HTTP is not a dumb transport
protocol right it's an application
protocol and the consequences of that
are what the document explores in great
depth and that's valuable to the extent
that HTTP serves the needs of people we
should make it better suit those needs
but I'm not interested in having the
discussion about how you might use it
for a multiplexing protocol or as a
substrate for tunneling and various
other things over the top I think that's
just one of the one of the ways in which
it has been abused and I think we can
talk about things like eventsource and
various other things where they
basically treat it as a transport
protocol right and it is kind of
ill-suited to that I will just add to
that Jonah every time you call HTTP a
transport protocol Roy fielding knows
and he will find you so it's transfer
Ferg in the end it's not Adam Roche I
wanted to end up here mostly because of
all the example of J map is interesting
they're they're kind of you know a
motorcycle with you know relatively
small crowd falling behind it we have a
freight train called 5g that has already
said that they're looking at HTTP for
their you know working between their
services they're basically breaking
their monolithic service it down into
what looked to me like micro services
and they've already strongly signaled
that they're likely to want some changes
here right so we should definitely have
some guidance in place for them before
that happens I think that's probably a
lot more motivating than the current
ongoing efforts inside the ITF Alexei
Alexei as an area director I review lots
of documents that try to use HTTP so I
can't quite understand you as as an area
director I review quite a lot of
documents to try to use HTTP so having a
single point where
you know partially as a checklist
partially where to send people you know
go fix these things now would be very
useful for me thank you until I clear
I'm very excited if you can actually do
this job right I have not at all
attached to the current form of the
document I think it probably needs to
change quite a bit so we were we're out
of time we cut the line down sorry
and we are out of time in the session so
we will do another revision before he
does that
okay never mind I think yeah yeah all
right thank you everyone we'll see you
back here hopefully a 3:24 mostly quick
and HTTP but well if we can we're gonna
sneak in HTTP terrific time as well
and Julian called it Trey and his slides
it's turf
I looked it up it does I like this this
yes I do it's not in their budget