beautifully on my own display of the
slide it says interface to network
security foo and then on the next line
it says auctions I'm Adrienne Linder as
Linda this is I to NSF we have a full
agenda blue sheets have been around once
but I'll push them around a second time
so you can fill in if you're missing and
one thing to add the if all things go
well this is my last session chairing
you I'd like to say it's been a joy and
hopefully you'll be successful going
forward without me though we have an ad
we can we can definitely now we can do
real work thank you very much let's get
started ok first of all is it notes well
so hopefully everybody really well this
is the new version with so please read
it so here is some trivia so charter I
think I don't have to do repeat that
mailing list for newcomers and we have
minute taker and Frank and Sue thank you
very very much
and for everybody else since we have
etherpad
right there there's a link from the IETF
99 agenda please just go there add your
comments or name especially when people
can now record a name correctly and if
they mistaken your notes and please
correct that online so we can all
contribute to the minutes and blue sheet
okay so here's agenda and being posted
and we're gonna get started
Wow so so here's agenda agenda passion
and if there any questions anything is
agenda changing if not we'll just go as
this plan okay
so congratulations to the problem
statement and use case document authors
may finally get one RFC thank you and
the second one to be out is the
framework we have completed the working
group last call and going to be sent to
iesg for review so that two other
working group documents the working
group have decided to leave them current
in the working group until the working
group charter either close or each other
so we'll leave them open as we can move
forward that that's the terminology and
the gap analysis so there's another
working group document on the client
interface requirement and we're going to
decide if we want to move that forward
to the working group last call so here
are five four or five drafts ready for
working group adoption we can't discuss
that further on the mailing list they
are primarily information models and
data models and we have quite a few
contributions on the information models
and data models and so initially there
was some inconsistency among them this
morning thanks to all the ulcers we got
together we had a really productive
discussion in the morning align the
models and decided on the relationship
among all the information model drafts
and data model drafts later on sue
Harris I'm gonna talk about those
relationship and how we move forward
with all those drafts so actually that's
my quotient and so do you man come here
to talk about this morning's discussion
gay people are update
and just to remind people that as a
working group we looked at whether or
not to have information models and made
a decision that they were going to be
useful for us that is a decision we
could revisit if we want to but where we
are at the moment is let's push forward
and have information models to to drive
our data models and so based on that let
me give you a few discussions we had a
model discussion with some of the
authors please go ahead so first I'm
going to give some high-level goals or
ideas
first of all information models we
treated as blueprints for data models
okay and there are two types of
alignment exact door a subset and we
also worked on this based on which is
your core concept or which is your key
model and then you group your models
around the core concept and we want it
to be easy to understand so that we can
provide models which can go to then
vendors and people who are trying it in
academia like our hackathon presentation
which is next with Paul Shaw we want
easy to understand models that's why
yang was written as it is go ahead to
the next one so let me talk first about
why blueprints are the basis for
conflict stripes as you see we're in
Prague and this is one of the largest
structures but when people build a
building like this they start with a
portion of the building and then they
build up the structure and the same is
true of an information model we may use
the where you were treating the
information model like a blueprint for
this large building it's it's got a lot
of structure but maybe we only do so
much in the data model some working
groups that are doing yang models think
that the information model should be
exact there are pros and cons that's
just the way we were sort of talking
about how our
capability models and our capability
model our customer facing model our NSF
final facing model so I'm just providing
some thoughts that we had from the
authors go ahead then it's very
important you invite verify the
blueprint because if you don't like this
building doesn't work so well together
maybe you have a floor sitting out so if
you have the data model equal the
information model then you can check the
data model out with tools if you do like
we do we're suggesting and you do the
information model as a future blueprint
which will guide you in your data models
you must actually take a different
approach there is a downside if you use
the case where you have the data models
equal the information model and you
trust and checking it you go all the way
down to the data model with lots of work
before you actually check it and you may
have a large cost like this building
that's not quite aligned so that's why
we thought okay we're going to use the
information like a like a blueprint but
we have to carefully hand check that all
the information models work together
this is just one approach as I said you
can use the information model equals a
data model and then trust after you've
got all the way through that the data
model checks checkers will work or you
can do what we're suggesting which is to
hand-checked
synchronize look at the information
models use them as a blueprint and
implement subsets that's how people
build large buildings and we thought
that might work go ahead so that's the
recommendation verify the complete
information model that means if you have
five information models you must verify
them by hand and then build a portion of
the model in stages simple than more
complex that's the approach our teams
and development teams have been taking
well well the well the team from Korea
all the people were here at the
hackathon stand up and be recognized at
this point for their work on the
hackathon code so I guess especially the
students so we also have people who are
working on product code we think that
with simple more complex we get an
understanding now this is possible
because of the good work to base
everything on the Keen model of
capabilities
go ahead Linda capabilities is like our
key structure that that you may see in
Prague in of the Cathedral and some of
the castle here that around which was
built all the family models and the
structures in Prague that's how the cast
was been hi Hank glad you're here so why
and how the data model I think I've gone
through that simple set sets help you
get miles accept it now there's a real
benefit in this that this approach fits
right in with the net compressed comp
work in their data catalog and registry
what you can do based on their stuff is
you can say I want this subset to go in
my data store for configuration ok and
these are the model drafts in that come
that will allow this this is why we
think this approach may be successful
for people actually deploying now again
the data mantel catalog and the open
config if I remember a right Hank and
those in the hackathon they finished
their their hackathon version of it so
again there's hackathon early code we're
following early code movements go ahead
to the next one now that was a long
explanation to go to this slide at the
top we have an information model that
goes around and here I'm going to dance
outside of the box I apologize with a
pointer you guys have that thing yeah
that that would be nice too I could use
the spoon
okay one of these makes it turn red now
that wasn't it isn't it okay yes the red
pointer is not oh oh thank you so much
yeah okay thank you um okay so over here
is our key model that key structure like
the castle with the the capability model
then we have a client facing information
model a high-end high-end edge astray
ssin model the monitoring model and then
below the capability model is some
detail from Frank on the security policy
this creates an information model now as
you look and you review this please tell
us what you think now the bills back
here for Kumar but this one and our
group thinks that that was discussing
things this morning really well thinks
that the client facing model ought to
take an approach of intent okay how many
people know what declarative and intent
models are okay very few pardon me while
I I give the rest of you a moment the
clarity of verses descriptive is if your
descriptive you describe how to go to
the store I need to go to the store to
get aspirin I need you to go down the
street over there
find the drugstore go inside pick up the
aspirin bottle pick up the excedrin
bottle and come back declarative says
please go to the store pick up aspirin
okay the declarative model in a client
is much more powerful because the client
doesn't have to know what the interior
of the security model it says secure a
path from these two to these two or
engage in a threat and a levin or some
complete capability so Nabil I hope I
gave a good description we all felt like
this client model should
be declarative we're working on that
these models are still in the info model
here a work in progress but we've made
some progress along that and that's
what's different all the rest are
probably what you expect for info model
now the reason we take this is some of
this is new thoughts and this blueprint
will help us build a good castle down
here we took the build a little so this
capability model that's underneath under
the same point is a subset now we think
this is a workable subset based on the
the hackathon code that works underneath
in the base model it may be an incorrect
subset but this is for you to review and
to work on there is hackathon code so
try it you know this is a build and try
there is the interface data model which
is trying to take it's just not a
hundred percent aligned with Kumar but
was enough to do the hackathon stuff so
you have to look at the Kumar model and
the Kim NSF facing models to see what
you think is a declarative thing here
it's secure connection for this time
this location it's young customer excuse
me I pointed it the wrong it's Jung's
customer facing model that is equivalent
and all the comments I just said should
have said come where I pointed it Kim
Kim is at the NSF facing model which is
the thing that goes between the
controller and the actual NSF discussion
I think we've gone through this type of
discussion quite a bit so I won't repeat
it
how or hands anybody want me to repeat
the substance of what's in the NSF
facing okay no hands no talk okay then
this is the registration model and this
one is new again based on work that's
being coded and deployed uh that matches
the Jean I 2's interface monitoring
model so that's our model discussion and
and why we paired things in this way we
think that the capability model from the
team is ready to go along with this and
as our key model just like the key
building we're going to ask the working
group from the authors to adopt both
then we'll ask you to adopt other pieces
from the models questions on our little
review and and these models and
structure is it after lunch or am i
confusing okay no questions I'm
impressed yes thank you very much and
maybe at the very end after all the
presentation talked about their data
model information model then we can
discuss a little more okay develop this
telefónica on question 2 - so I would
like to remark one thing well well this
morning the discussion this morning I
was thinking that precisely the
capability model is not precisely a
model on on what happens in the
different interfaces is a model so
capabilities can be registered so what
we have is precisely working here is
about an open model in which you can
deal with different set of capabilities
so in the sense that we are open to
registering different kind of stuff and
this is very important because what we
have is a placeholder for the diff for
the other other different models as the
ideas are not that people have to take
their capabilities and go for the
capabilities and and specialize them or
extend them is about that the
capabilities mobile provide the this
support for declaring the capabilities
and manipulating I mean this is
something that we have to be a little
bit careful ok so eventually at the end
of the day we have to develop the model
for the client facing and the model for
the NSF facing so what a B in this one
will be the separate information model
to describe them imprint
both of them should be based on the I
mean if you ask me I think that they
should be based on the capability model
okay okay and whether whether we have
whether we what we make is a general
model that is more detailing one case of
the other this is up to the group and
that's something that remains to be
decide so far okay thank you so that's
our last slide for the chair sorry for
taking so much longer we're supposed to
do five minutes back when little longer
so next one is the hackathon sorry oh no
where is the hackathon
ex oh just this one right this one this
is another one is it the poster I can
sound poster thank you song report right
okay so this is our childhood song from
Sanga University next right please
so the objective of this hackathon is to
show the validity our design of their
attitude driven security management so
this time seven credit student from my
university a sketchy you we prepare for
less than three months us and then this
last the weekend that we tried to tune
our cold and prepare for the
presentation so next slide
so this hackathon is collaboration our
work with the university and Korea
Telecom is I see a vendor major I spend
in South Korea and also a tiara a each
government supported Research Institute
so three organizations are working a
wait for the hackathon so the correct
telecom they provide in the year the
applications for I to NSF services next
slide please
so this portal shows last week an
student and Korea telecom researcher and
I are working also children also trophy
our customers so we work together and
also we presented our work and then this
time we are at first University a world
again
so that year soul meeting we get a best
so indicates our working group are
working very hard
next slide so next you already know the
concept of i-10 instead so the goal of
this hackathon is we tried to show the
first application is if I were the
second one is a content-based security
such as a web filter and then a week
combined using a service function
chaining as I proceed we showed the
according to the frank information model
case the investigate the maquette using
the fiber and then if this content
should be investigated in detail in that
case that factor should be poor word to
the DVI deep packet inspection so in
order to that we implemented the
opposite this time we try to follow the
separation working groups solution next
slide
so contribution orbit is hecka so we
showed that the POC the promo concept
for I to NSF using open sources and also
we showed that the validity of our
simple data models so even though the
data model is a simple but I looked like
at a powerful and then we show the peas
ability of a data driven approach next
slide so those are a bunch of open
sources so we especially this time we
use the x8 XSLT extensible stylesheet
languages and transformations which
means high-level the policy specified I
too and I step user that high-level
policy translated into low level policy
will be delivered to NSF
backslide so this figure showed another
computation so left hand side is
enterprise network right hand side is
service website Facebook web
YouTube so this time we implemented the
fiber and the web filter which means the
paste on the Porter port information
such as a web port is 80 right so if
traffic is from some clients such as
employee the traffic is aware we can
compute out the second one is if the
content of the web the packet contain a
YouTube or Facebook we can peer table
which means we can perform our web
filter next right so this figure shows
the computation next so we can show the
fire
next the secondly this one is repeater
remember we implemented the using I
suppose she so service function forward
and then original only the the foil
packet is forward to the web filter NSF
using SFCC
next please so we unloaded our document
and the open source our code into github
and also we unloaded our the video clip
the explaining how to install and how to
test next slide so this figure should
heat up next light the finally are we
cut are many lessons from the last two
hackathons and we showed a POC the data
model I think it should be the simple to
label for the audience so also we are
sure that the current existing of the
source are in not to implement our eye
to eye to NSF framework and also we
showed the feasibility of our approach
okay that's it
thank you any questions comments thank
you very much they also got an award for
this hackathon thank you just a little
extra note from hackers are so hackathon
is I Kiev work and just recently not too
long ago Linux Foundation start a new
project called - security controller
open source project they're like five
companies currently in there like Intel
our Pato
Huawei I think that's two other I don't
know Kia maybe
in there so I've approached them they
were supposed to come here gave a
presentation but kind wise it's too
early for them to really we come to do
the presentation so next time if we meet
they'd probably be able to give us an
update what they are doing and they are
hoping to use iTunes SF interface as the
API is to to guide their work their work
is mainly for the controller part just
like the the logistics like the logics
of getting the interface from client be
able to translate into and as they're
facing to face Kathleen Moriarty ng so
you're following that work and if we
need to do liaisons and whatnot yes yes
absolutely
okay yeah all right I'm sure it's it
sounds like it's too early for that but
they just started they just form yes yes
please
and Frank shall we uh I have a question
power to how future plane to maybe in
the next i TS meeting to two more
excellent test about new interfaces that
are at the graduating interface although
our clients facing the faces because we
i think after this meeting we have we
have we output song a new new content
about this part so i think if we can do
heck song it will be very helpful yeah
basically are currently we already
implemented arm the monitoring
monitoring on the information model so
and also this time we implemented the
content security so such as a picture so
so information our model are getting the
more detailed information i'll really
plaque the dead one into era model and
then we can implement it of course next
the 100 and the singapore meeting and so
we implemented that once okay tiago have
it's more related to yeah open source
stuff when i mean normally open source
projects are very reluctant to to making
anything that sounds like they come will
tell us what what they are doing and we
can
try to influence them in fact I knew
about this project some time ago because
world it was in the minds of some people
that are working with us well it's
rather interesting and we I try to push
them to use it they join us at five
years and and well in confident they
will be coming here and we will have
even managed to convince that needs a
couple of guys in Intel to participate
in the India to NSF fortunately I am on
it so it's I hope we will we will manage
to have them and well it would not be a
bad idea if you bring some of your
results there as well could be because
this is this is what we're running cold
and this is what they're looking for
okay so we can discuss that offline they
just started like a couple months ago so
they are waiting for some kind of
substance for mass to give to them okay
I'm cold bring the cold okay okay thank
you very much so next one is
applicability oh sorry it's the
capability dress yes you did hello
everyone friendship are we okay I will
give a reduction of our latest I
honestly have capability information
motor shaft since it's a it's a basic
information motor for a lot of vitamins
safety to motor work so I warmly welcome
everybody can give us put feedbacks okay
unfortunately let me let me say that I
think the whole point of the key point
of this information motor draft is that
wait if I are where we proposed an
information model for capability for the
security capability so that's that's a
beginning of of the hosting so let me
explain what is the capability so I
think maybe it's very the understanding
actually for us that ability is a
function that the network security
function can provide
it is not dependent on what is is device
motor or its visualized or it's
physically yes they are there or not
relevant but we want to define the
logical function which which you are
gonna safe can provide and so it is
abstract concept and they it should be
very flexible to to represent the
functionality of the security functions
okay so and in addition to these
particular concept of course we also
need to to define how to operate how to
manager this capability because our
following work is based on how how can
we defined and then we how can we manage
it so then I think if we have the
capability information motor then we can
use it to to to build and construct our
security policy motor so that's our our
way to to push this work okay next page
okay this is a this is a motoring
picture if somebody feed for the time
you may fear not but we're easy to
understand but please read it more
actually it's really it's really helpful
because uh because it photo that you can
see that in we have the so based on this
motor it can be for example it can be
the super information model or it can be
another good information model but it
did provide us some very useful policy
information element that we can use to
construct our security policy motor and
that's a that's a that's a step but it
but that's
otoscope of I don't a safe work that's a
yeah
we can use it and then we have to to
branch to inferior footprint these very
basic or information motor the left
branch is that we we try to define what
is the security policy so the
the security policy that - we could say
that Calgary we use that you see a motor
so it's it's called as a event condition
and action we use this motor to to to
describe the any kind of security policy
so so it means that it means that we we
use different kinds of we went object
condition object and the actual object
to compose our security policy that's a
physical way and and if you can see from
this picture it's very similar like some
class definition we can based on where
is very an initial class and then we
inherited we extended to define our our
model and in the in the in the in the
right branch
it's our capability information motor
definition it's a little bit different
from the security policy actuary that
hability whom each model is about what
what is the function of these and SS so
it is used to to add what advertise what
to this unless it can provide and the
register to the controller so that the
so that the customer can use it so so
that's a different thing so we have you
can you can say that way you can see
that we have two branch of the
information motor okay so in this page
where we want to explain a little more
detail about what they are with the
what's the security policy and what the
capability information they want to
specify okay the security policy is used
to define the behavior so it means that
we we define the security policy and the
tell the tell the security device is
what you should do how to do so for
example when something happened and when
you detect the sound traffic how to
react to it that's what we want to to
buy the security policy but if we're
talking up
if we talk about the capability it's
another story
it's it's how is when because before I
use any security capability I need to
know what we have so I need to some you
can you learn sign information model to
express that which functionality or
which feature that unless it has so
that's we need another way to express it
so you so that's another information
model yeah and but if you see our title
actually the security policy and the
capability information model they are
the two purity they ensure they are the
same thing but the use in the different
objective in the later you will see how
we define them respectively okay so let
me emphasize our way to define the whole
information model actually with to
achieve the scalability and to achieve a
modern driven approach so of course we
cannot defy certifying a lot of security
policy motor and capability model for
every kind of network security function
so other ways that we foster a way to
find several several kind of
capabilities they are the very physical
element and then based on this based on
our define the capabilities we we use
our security policy information motor to
use them to to meet different require it
requirements so everything starts from
the capability information model ok ok
so I I think I have I have already
introduced what is our current model is
the ECA policy motor so event the
condition action policy rule but if you
of course it's a container to contain
all these elements but in addition to
ECA we also think that we need another
we can even to make our policy more
flexible and more useful so we
we added we added the resolution
strategy so it's used to - for example I
have several security policy rule so we
we can use this resolution strategy to
to decide how to use this rule how to
combine the area that they are met with
that to decide my final result my final
action sorry
so so that is very useful to construct a
very complex or very intelligent policy
and also we have the metadata it is also
used by the by the by the resolution
strategy - 2 T Phi also also - to define
how to map to the final actions and also
we have default actions which means that
if I cannot match all the conditions
what can I do so we can do the default
action so that's our country all the
element of the security policy ok and
after introducing the security policy I
want to introduce either I want you to
use the capability information modal so
so so if you can follow my introduced
introduction before so the capability
information order is is I think it's
obvious to you so so it's it's just
another expression way another
expressing way - to define the
capability model so here you can see
that we have those basic element we have
the action set we have the condition set
we have the event set and the resolution
set and default action set so we use
some capability algebra you can consider
it as a set theory we we listed all
these all these information all these
capabilities as a whole to express what
I can provide in the security
perspective to our user for example I
have the our action set which we which
include deny and pass so that means that
this this network network security
function can can
and confer to the traffic oh it and it
can also pass a traffic order or other
actions
okay so so by this way network security
function can very easily to express what
you can do to the security controller or
to the client so so okay and then if we
have this kind of definition we can do
some more some more calculation or some
more operation on then down below we can
do the addition and the subtraction we
can we have to tablet have a period here
they are two to two functions set and we
can do the addition of them so that
means that we can get a more powerful
capabilities and we can do subtraction
which means that I don't need some of
the capability in that motor so I can I
can subtract it in the future I think
that maybe we can add more on this
operation so I think I'm always I'm
almost finished about this inhumation
mode of interaction so about future work
I just want to say that for for make our
document content is short so we move a
lot of for example or specific
information motor at attribute to to the
appendix part so they are trusted for
the example to show how to use it but of
course they they will never beat a
complete set of the security policy
information model and the capability
information motor so our question to the
chair or working group that I think I
think maybe it's not a question but we
just want to say that we don't want to
do I think that cannot finish which
after leaves the some typical example in
the appendix and that's that's current
way we do and and the next next page
please and I think we still think about
another enhancement to current
information motor for example we want to
do in addition to current poor
operations maybe we can do more on the
condition and the event clause for
example we can introduce conjunctive
normal form and the destructive normal
form to apply on the our condition and
our event to make our logic more
flexible and more powerful and then and
also we we're also considering our also
considering we can we can do more things
on our event and the condition clause
such as we can for action we can define
different policies on how to implement
the action we can we can actually the
first action or Exeter execute that the
last action or depending on the priority
execute which action
so I think there are all the details
technical details that we may be needed
to add in the future version we are
considering this and the way where we
can anybody can give us more otherwise
or good suggestions last one is that
about the decorate decorate more pattern
this is a this is a tough decision we
are not yet decided a decoration
decorate motor is a software design
pattern that because ternary we we we
design the class so decorator motor can
provide some of the benefits for example
it can be loaded and wrong and in
England one time so so it is it is
managing in the management aspect you it
is very efficient and it can save a lot
of manual configuration and the menu
modification but it's more complex than
current static inheritance class design
so we are where we are not yet decided
if we should choose this way to
to make some modification to our current
model design so yeah we like to hear
more suggestions I think that this page
if you have time you can see I don't
want with so much time thank you thank
you so much
so we are running considerably behind
schedule if everybody could save 20% on
their time then we won't have to push
anybody off the end of the agenda or if
anybody wants to come up here and commit
ritual suicide that will also work next
one is applicable bility hello this is a
person so destruct motivation is
applicability is the one of our
milestone item so the based on our the
hackathon experience we show out I 2 msf
can provide security services the one
thing to note is the I to NSF provide
empirical TNF and also a physical data
security function also virtual trip
function so in turned out using the Sdn
Software Defined Networking can leverage
the security service next slide
so the combination of AI to NSF Sdn case
s TN s which can perform perform the
simple to firewall services such as a
polar drop mirroring and then the
complicated security services can be
done using the more complicated NSF
learning on top of an Apple II or
physical yeah
devices so and also I to another policy
rule enforcement case we can are using
Estelle suite and an Apple II or
physical devices the net
a function we can using two things to
improve the performance next slide
so today why are we have augmented our
framework which means the the bottom we
can have the STL a network or having a
stern switch so at the resort security
controller and a switch controller
usually a switch controller arm we can
say STNG - controller can talk to each
other using and as a facing interface
next slide so the information and the
data model I to NSF during the our
hackathon we implemented the partially
consumer-facing case partially
implemented by the next the hackathon we
fully implemented but consumer-facing it
is called the kind of face interface
information should to be enhanced in
terms of ECA up the paradigm and NSF a
face in case I think at the mature so we
I think at least security that all
security functions such as the fire is
fully implemented and also restoration
interface case we can register NSF and
NSF capability so we can we are planning
to implement next hackathon so this
applicability case we can show these
three interfaces defined I to NSF can be
used next slide so this figure shows
that the flow so you can aware right so
the high-level policy and low-level
policy configure also low-level first
scan configures the security city
controller and then Sdn switch can
computer the using open flow over I - RS
okay
next slide so this draft
explain the three use cases if I were
for your IP dpi and DDoS attack
mitigation services so due to the time
limitation
can skip you can our leader the slide
over trapped next so you can skip yeah
so use cases I mentioned the three user
cases next so we can skip the use cases
the next next next next next
so our next step we can also include
more user cases such as SFC piss the
spirit of function chaining will be
added such as the fiber and the web
filter and fiber and DDoS attack
mitigation we can combine using SFC so a
separation is also one of our groups
trapped so also we can reflect the okay
Frank
information model so we can improve our
NSF or facing interface considering
content security and authentication next
time okay thank you for attention if you
have questions or comments please go
ahead
so what is next one model information
model monitoring you have the slide you
didn't send me the sign you what happen
you just send them do you have them
maybe maybe you can use your laptop the
monitoring
[Music]
the monitoring yes yes so from you okay
that's one thing I didn't get it
I got a two bucks okay I got it
okay okay hi this is Hank I'm
apologizing for the mix-up of these
lights here okay so we are starting with
the information model for monitoring of
network security functions and yeah
which does give the most important part
here so it is ultimately intended to
deal with the huge amount of information
that will be emitted by functions and
that we don't only mean the I to NSF
functions that will be standardized but
also by the legacy interfaces that are
already pushing a lot of information as
notifications today
so the content here is not only the I to
NFS events that are of interest because
they are already processed by a rule or
some are outputted by the I to NSF
system itself but also raw data that may
be of interest and was not assessed yet
the policy here or the general rule here
is that the consumer of those
notifications decides so we again reuse
the existing model of capabilities are
you see a policy rules and just allow
them to consume notifications that are
coming from outside the scope of the I
to an SF
there is rough consensus in the
terminology team John stress na who was
basically in charge of the ECA logic
agreed to this but we have no text for
this because John unfortunately I was
unavailable in the last few weeks so
unfortunately is also not on site we
skipped the drop the stuff of the alerts
and the alarms there was too much
discussion about an arbitrary definition
of classes here there will be an
implicit definition due to the chaining
of policy rules though so this
escalation of severity or confidence
will still occur but they will just be
named events at the first time and be
annotated with metadata
basically telling what others we at the
hackathon were exploring next at least
the potential solution drafts there are
existing in the scope of the Netcom
realm
so we basically implement its
cutting-edge firmware was deployed on
friday and software the NCC and the NC
client open source office everyone
github on Wednesday this weekend at the
hackathon we were able to do periodic
updates and on change updates from the
USA and the PRC so globally spending
creating a notification flow that was
then consumed by a component this was
first intention was to build a
component and then we realized that a
second component in this scope of first
proof of concept is pretty much looking
like AI to NSF component and also the
function capability semantics are quite
similar so that we little bit saw this
coming due to the convergence of the two
terminology drafts but now whether
running code we can actually understand
this better and the rule used here to
create AI to NSF events was the filter
expression for a subscription on to a or
multiple yang modules and su who was in
the room where you probably love to hear
that we did III as unchanged updates and
also always bf table at its edges okay
so talking about legacy interfaces next
slide yeah this pretty much already
spoiled so we will use the notification
system because notification is this
thing and yang also a life data we will
push via yang probably at least this is
our route that we pursue at the moment
poor mechanisms has very much more of a
legacy thing as are the log files that
are created or in retain we call those
records because it's not only our blocks
it's also databases so a specific agent
with specific rules we create events
from those quick we also have an early
proposal of a categorization system for
information monitoring because how you
get it like if it's a query it was it's
a subscription what it is about is his
life is a record is it declarative guide
and how you should be imperative guys
how it should do things or an assessment
already that the outcome of a rule is it
a raw aggregation or already a complex
set of rule result and then again what
about the function is irrelevant here
its context as introduced by John stress
know he would elaborate on this
unfortunately he is not one side so the
next set is we investigated of course
next to yang subscription other ways to
create telemetry there's an effort going
on with
co-op pops up unfortunately authors meet
tomorrow for their breakout meeting so I
couldn't get updates on that today
excellent hypocrite is under severe
restructure it will be fully compliant
to XMPP and jabs and the XMPP protocol
console is at the moment confirming that
this is a standard or as paconne can
could be a standard as was basically not
violating any XMPP rules so there are
alternatives in the way to get telemetry
not for only for monitoring but also
between functions but this is again
future work so next steps are deciding
on here what to do with the
categorization model you saw a property
here on the sides and we will also have
to focus on intervals of freshness of
information because that might be of
relevance to security so this was how
fast enough so thank you very much one
of the challenges we had in routing hat
was going through the categorization the
fact that you've actually done that in
the in the security piece is impressive
in routing we do it in order to support
high availability and sub-second flow
and failover
security it's really good to see the
same categorization thank you very much
you're welcome
and yeah your input always is appreciate
it the the pieces you throw at me
throughout the last entire but very very
helpful information modern day tomorrow
so make it more consistent so next one
is the sue Harris capability data model
[Music]
again we're taking the approach of
high-level thought for the room case
you've coming into this new we're taking
the approach of implementing like I said
a piece of the the large blueprint and
working on it step by step through
hackathons if you're interested in
playing with us please please download
the code from that that has been created
from the Korean team and please I'm sure
they'd love comments this is to help get
early review early fail on anything but
we're starting to see we think this is
close for some of the product groups
that we've talked to okay
and also the Linux theme the groupings
are what you would think from the from
the original capability information
model we're grouping based on network
and security control the content control
the mitigation control and the
capabilities information remember this
is just should look like
Frank's original thing go ahead to the
next now there's a difference between
the NSF facing yang data model and the
capability model the NSF is used to
configure the rules of policy into the
NSF and the capability data model is
used to retrieve it we're taking the
idea that you want to know what you're
supposed to do and then you put it down
this provides what we had agreed in the
Charter which is to write what we're
doing and then allow flexibilities for
different
people with NSF's to download things the
benefit of having the good open source
that the team did as you can see it
based on the open source filters please
go ahead this I think is just showing
the same thing in a picture keep going
and this shows that you're getting a
directory list interface and this shows
that we've actually been doing the fact
that we've used this for SFC okay in
case you missed the last hackathon in
this hackathon report let me give you a
little background there's two cases that
we're looking at that are real important
phones and forwarding with the
classifier using the SFC stuff really
good and this isn't on the slide so I
apologize information that this packet
de load we've taken a look at it not me
the the good team from and the students
have looked at what happens when you
actually monitor the SFC work from a
centralized pointer if you distribute it
what they found in their initial
implementation is you really ought to
distribute these type of security
functions throughout the network because
it's more efficient so with that
high-level let me go show you that you
know the ideas the packet comes in you
have a query based a capability you
download the information and then you're
able to forward it this allows you if
you have a distributed model to get very
efficient with the SFC forwarder either
for specific functionality such as mail
cleaning or filtering or deep packet
inspection or other things within the
network so please we're giving you this
as a model but we're trying to keep now
improving the contents of this for the
IT resource again work on a little piece
build it test it provide you models
what we really would like some feedback
is if you take this home and try it will
do this will verify the next set of
stuff as we go thank you
sue I saw Paul sent a note to the SFC
working group about another especially
related draft and I'm seeing this I
think we maybe should sort of correlate
all of our SFC related drafts and make
sure that that working group knows what
we're doing
I did take I did take a time and tell
the chair about what I thought was the
high level order I will make sure that I
also go back and correlate that with
that working group but I told him what I
just told him that the important thing
for their working group is the fact that
it looks like in our early thing the
distributed filtering for security
functions was more effective and I'm
sure he'll share that with his team as
that as he wishes that's Joel Halpern by
the way for people as the people there
are too many chairs yes Kathleen
Moriarty ad so a couple of general
comments a few of the drafts some not
adopted yet seem like they are
overlapping enough with other ones that
if they move towards adoption like the
applicability statement she folded into
something else
terminology we may want to fold into one
of the protocol drafts it'll have an
easier time with these formational type
drafts with the iesg
and the other one we've been hearing
about development work which is really
exciting can it also get plugged into
code stands so that we could track what
drafts have info that's really good yep
we'll do that okay great thank you um
Adrian you will help and Linda you will
help guide that because we had kept the
terminology as a standalone draft Frank
did you get that in a note so I make
sure we follow up on thank you hi this
is Hank and this is about collapsing
terminology you of course know that I
have not to speak for John and me at the
same time I think John would not really
like
the dependency onto a protocol or a
specific model because there's an
umbrella they would always include terms
for other drafts and they they are not
at the top of the heap so it would never
align so if there is no extra charge
pressure and reason to do it I would not
recommend to do it there there will be
yeah
so a document passed my review if it's
read if I or even copying a definition
from somewhere else and I think the
point of having the terminology document
is to pull that all together right and
it's fine to combine it with another
document the formational type documents
are not viewed well by the iesg so
there's a lot of pressure and you it
there's a lot of pressure right now on
that
I know Sue's been through it a few times
either a shepherd or as an editor so if
it's I'm suggesting a protocol document
because there's something more support
for those and those do require the
terminology right moving forward so if
it's like a core document that's pivotal
to the working group that you're going
to be referencing anyway from other
documents then it's a good one for the
terminology to be referencing I think I
think yeah sure it might be if we put it
in a protocol document it might be
useful to put it in our key protocol
document the capability for record and
that also makes them it's part of that a
standard struct document and it's gonna
get more review okay good thank you for
that advice we appreciate it
next one is the NSF they think they're
models so this is in compliment to the
capability data models yes so this is
for the NSF of AC interface data model
so these are we report the praetor's
about jumbo that we will deplete the
Franks that the latest version our next
television next please
so the sewer lady is plaintiff
differences so keep yeah next slide
please so this time are we updated the
event component and the action component
using the more concrete data types next
slide so this is showed that we replace
the integer time unsigned integer type
using the immigration time next right
also we previously use the case but this
division we use enumeration for our
ingress action next slide so also the
previously the year
apply some apply a profile axiom or
domestic action context based action for
example we try to simplify the data
structure next slide
so next step we also include the content
security and authentication once the
prank the information model providing
more detailed information we implement a
Tara young motor and also we implement
for next hackathon thank you thank you
in terms of time do you have questions
no okay I'll go to the next one okay so
the next one is the the registration
interface right
hello everyone this is how one young
from something one University and this
presentation is about registration
interface information model and data
model yeah so the major objective of the
registration interface is registering on
NSF and this capability into the system
so our information model and data model
focus on that function and also in some
cases the security controller may want
to request the developers management
system to create a new instance or
district on existing instance which is
underutilized so in this - to document
we designed the information model and
data model to support the following
functions which is registering a new NSF
instance and these capabilities into the
security controller and additionally to
request dynamic instantiation or the
instantiation next one yeah so this
slide is a summary of the update and in
the in this new version of the
information model draft we added the
portion of performance capability and we
also update the updated young data model
to align with the information model
update next one please
so this figure is briefly describes the
registering process through the
legislation interface so after creating
the new instance by the developers
management system developers management
system registers the creative you NSF
instance and his capability
to the security controller so the
existing information model and data
model are used to describe the security
capability upon NSF instance next 1/3
and and we thought in some cases are in
the following cases the security
controller may need to request to create
a new instance or destruct an existing
instance so this is the possible cases
so the first one is in the i-20 a popper
a mock on NSF can trigger on advance the
security action which requires another
type of NSF rapport for further security
inspection in this case for some reason
the the triggered NSF instance may be
unavailable in the system in this case
the security controller to serve
disadvantage security action the
security controller need to request this
DMS system to create the required NSF
instance or if the security controller
can detect on NSF instances under
congestion then the security controller
also need to request to creation of a
new additional instance next one please
this is the summary of the version
update and we have added an additional
portion of the performance capability to
describe several type to attributes of
the type of resources next one please
yes so in the future we will extend our
hackathon implementation to to support
this registry registration process via
the registration interface and we will
also do
some investigation on the feasibility of
dynamic instantiation or these the
instantiation yeah thank you
they're all otters here not willing to
growing time management but I see that
this is I mean looking at what you
intend to do here I see it two points
one is that this is more connected with
a protocol rather than an informational
relatable rights so I mean calling it
information model data model probably
could be a little bit misleading this is
one thing because we're talking about
how you interact with the different and
how you actually retrieve capabilities
and or push or pull capabilities from or
to the NSF seconds looking at the atom
of the elements that appear in the in on
the screen I see a I mean is somehow
very also how it's very much connected
with the hand we're talking about stages
you are talking about memory or the
processing the idea processor loads and
things like that that has to some extent
there well there are events as well or
some kind of telemetry so so I what I
would encourage is that to try to
convert with what hank was presenting so
we have a single set of telemetry data
in general whatever they are events or
measurements or whatever so it would
encourage that you converge with them
when it comes to the for the data model
and the protocol because this set of the
of protocol choices at hand was showing
business it would be very good to
experiment with them in the next seven
hackathon that's thank you very much so
next one is our remote presentation
Gabriela you are you there in meet echo
and can you
you should have a blue microphone button
you can go for hello we hear you we
don't see but okay so hello
let's see you it's right okay
well hello my name is a little bit from
the University of Pavia cheers for Spain
I'm going to present the update of the
draft southward department 14 basically
said flow protection I don't know if I
can move this light solar okay it looks
like well first of all of with reminder
of the main of the dates of this draft
the first one is to describe the
architecture for the basic management of
security Association by means of the HD
and party and also to define in this
case the network ID function facial
interface security controller to you
managed and monitored security
association between our modern networks
objective function for that we have to
define the German models for
configuration and state data for the
management of the next slide please
okay in this drug we propose to use two
cases in case one the network security
function implements both the IPSec can
start and also the management protocol
this case I key in this case the
security controller is in charge of
provide the negotiated function with the
required
configuration information for IP or the
a speeded-up
security policy database and the policy
of penetration database but not the
security Association database with the
security Association are created in run
time by means of a akin oscillation the
table length in case two we suppose that
the network security function only
implements the NSA data bases the
security policy database and the
security Association
database but not run the in this case
the key management protocol so in this
case the city of the controller has to
provide the configuration for both
policies and the security Association
intercept in this case the network
security function sorry
so just to say that in this case the
network security function we have only
support for for a basic and the only key
management functionality to the security
control next slide please
okay changes from the last produced
version we are talking about this drug
is person 0 3 we have focused this
niversity
in the Bodleian hasta los scenarios
the idea is to define the model and to
deploy a test bed to test the Dawson
scenarios and the work for the hospital
in this case the Rottweiler scenario is
worn to be done for next session we also
have improved the discussion among this
one versus case Chile following the
comments received to land in the middle
list and concern in the previous
presentation rolling the main
contribution is the John configuration
data model this case we will provide any
providing the drug just one junk file
providing the model sorry
[Music]
sorry can you just to say that we we
provide the John balloon for the
clicking configuration information for
the HDD si D and D IP configuration and
said before we provide just one file the
gen model in just one file it is up to
the security controller knowing the kind
of scenario to be applying in order to
decide the part of this model to be used
for example if we are talking about the
security controller is deploy in a case
one scenario then it has two main years
of the AIT SPD and in AD
the models but ether controller knows
that has to deploy case scenario then he
has to make use of the SPG and basically
on in order to define this John
certification we have negative analysis
or of the RFC 4301 to describe the
requirements of the security policy with
the Association and pushing the ways we
are also analyzer physicians t26 to to
analyze the configuration required for
the key management protocol the also we
have analyzed open source implementation
like strong one and this one but again
here we call for of the experts to try
to help rule the land and turning out of
this mode next we have also the set up a
proof of concept may be news of well
this this conflict only cover the
security controller and adversity
function plane doesn't cover the
application lawyer yes and we have made
use of that comes like the sophomore
protocol maybe use of the new tubular
implementation and the channel model
including we have tested the horse to
horse inject with a pathway
scenarios with different transport
alternate mode
replication Turkish illumination of
educational options for case one in case
of the network security function we have
menus of train of strong one for the
implementation
and the API provided by strong in this
case I said in order to allow runtime
configuration of IP and for case two in
the case of Manitoba security functional
we have made you soft
beefy Kim Basinger for the SAT
configuration in the network security
function the came station for the SPT
configuration and also the XRF M for a
CDN speaking in sixth system so it is
light and so any question is welcome any
questions maybe we don't have much time
just try to keep well to pressure mask
who so say quickly this is good work
IPSec or the flow protection is good
however in practical cases many cases it
doesn't work when your NSF is with
inside the corporate boundary and there
are policy rules which which won't allow
it
das has been dealing with this the same
issue in dots it needs to be covered and
be taken care of but it's not the sole
solution because it doesn't always be
it's not always employable that that's
all we need to have some caveat and
discussion with that that point in the
draft yes yes well it's true that we
have not analyzed all the all the cases
but that's why we reach for this time
scenario that could write some problem
model just to say that we have follow
the RFP see we have tried to be very
accurate the in the definition
so in theory we are basing on their
feces so of course those the scenario
appears and we want to try to analyze
these cases so next one okay you have
mirror might set it on the mitt on the
IPSec mailing list not and I train a
semi long list well the problems I see
with this model is that in a lot of time
in VPN scenarios your NSF is not in the
corporate bounds but in some kiosk at
the mall somewhere and the network there
is not known to the administrators so
the information about what is behind
what what the address the NSF has and
what addresses are protected behind that
gateway are known only to the NSF at the
start so the information about all that
has to flow from the NSF to the
controller now if we build the model of
where the information only flows from
the controller to thee to the NSF then
we have to have some side channels some
Bachelor of that where people read off
the routing table from the configuration
of the NSF and then input it to the
administrator and that's not what we
want want something automated that's the
point of doing things using SD ins so I
think the there should be a flow of
information of what we usually call
topology information from the NSF to the
controllers in order for the control to
build the big picture yes yes in this
case we have to take into account that
we are trying to apply the HBM already
so in this case the indian our next pass
the worldview of the network
another question is difficult to provide
the administrator with the record
information in order to send the correct
that's a the current high-level policy
to the controller in order to allow the
controller to specify the correct
network security function but we have to
assume that the security controller has
the world view of the network and I
think that is something that where we
are now see that is required thanks to
the deployment of the HD 1 solution and
of course there are a scenario were it
could be more difficult to apply but
there are other scenarios were work
problem we don't have this kind of
restriction and the SDM are I could be a
solution for for for the management of
the security Association right so I
agree that the control has to have all
the information I'm just not sure if
that information should come from the
northbound interface or the southbound
interface but I guess that sorry just
comment because this kind of discussion
also to place in the last meeting so
probably would say maybe I can have a
separate meeting in order to discuss
about this chantix wondrousness love
Alice + I'm very much concerned with I
Clay's piece and option number 2 because
first a security controller became a
really very attractive target for attack
once you execute you control you get all
the keys and the second concern is that
well it's a could you clarify please how
you securities that are distributed from
security control to endpoint because I
hope you you are not send it in clear
yes you if you if you have some
security channel between security
controller and endpoint that you've
already implemented some kind of TLS
icon something some security protocol so
I don't think you you get some again
when you remove likely to because you
you need to have some security some
standard security protocol to to secure
transport keys so I don't think it's a
good solution to remove by well unless
the end are they all the network devices
that say have to have to have a trust
relationship with the shiggity
controller that's one of the implication
and that's why the security controller
hospital to have the wall of view of the
network you know file those network
security function has to be proficient
with this authentication encryption act
area even but in this file name in our
case we make use of napkins with maybe
use of assassins tunnel between the
security controller and adversity
depression but in other solution by
neural control video so the Stalinist
security channel because of course you
arrive information is critical so it has
to be predicted carefully right so I
think you've made a really important
point and could you reiterate that point
on the mailing list please and then we
can we can close on it and actually have
it documented thanks Nabeel and hey
we've got 28 minutes for 50 minutes
worth of so whatever Thanks so this
draft is about the requirement for the
quite basic dance interface to the skill
these are the authors that contributed
to the draft
this is really depicting the reference
model within which we defined the my
place interface provide the ability to
further for a user or application to
express the security policy in a fashion
for the security controller which turns
decide where to apply those security
policies and how to apply them then the
the enforcement point on which bouchard
NSF's on which these security policies
and the being confident by the security
controller applied the policies to the
traffic as with the end points 10
points could be applications or could be
users or could be applications and user
and any combination of these so what has
been updated in the draft that has been
some clarification on the requirement
preferences between the must nays and
what's they based on requirements coming
from the owner what's--what stands for
the open network user group feedback
from them skillett policies that were
added related to segmentation what
people know sometimes as micro
segmentation policies that track
policies as well as compliance and audit
policies and there are further kind of
finally great defiant of different
policy blocks that pertain to source
policy endpoint group the direction in
which the policy needs to apply
throughout the group and finally there
is also update relate to consistent
policy enforcement in cases update to
the policy that will trigger it will
will trigger update on the on NSS
for for the policies that are the user
isn't an accomplice
so what are the design principles behind
behind the the client-facing interface
really the the goal in here is to enable
again a user or application to express
the policies in an abstract way and very
declarative a slash descriptive way
rather than being imperative and
prescriptive meaning asserting really
the what rather than the how things need
to unravel and when they need to apply
and that fashion that means that the
user express them without necessarily
knowledge about the network topology how
then I saw his eyes within elaborate how
they're connected and so forth because
that's really for the for the security
controller to decide about where to
apply the things having said that that
could be cases where the user or the
application needs to express also a
policy of certain affinity by which the
policy need to apply to a practical
device particular in particular a
particular anis a function and that
exists as well can we go to the next
slide please
so there are many requirements there is
no point in going through one by one in
here really what has been covered but
suffice to say really this these
policies are intended to be applied in
multi domain multi-tenant ways so there
is there are these objects that there
are requirements for object that that
identify tenants at five domains ways in
which the policies could be triggered in
/ - that could be event digger that
could be finally triggered there are
requirements on expressing policies that
identify the endpoints to which the to
which the the policies need to apply
whether is application identifier is
user identifier or or traffic identifier
and that does the source for this for
this identifier as well what they could
be obtained from
I think we could go over that again then
so what what are the next steps in here
the the idea is to add examples to the
draft that try to illustrate more via
examples how the requirement could be
applied that is the terminology used in
this left would die to an ACEF
terminology laughs as well as just some
comments on the on the mailing list I
think there is related to here really
can't separate what side of a
requirement this is what are the must
require meant as well as to get
clarification on what is the difference
between what we call in the draft as
construct based policy definition versus
intent based the Tahlia truth in my view
it's really what we're talking about
really is intent based that except that
that intent is big stress was constructs
that are defined by the different policy
objects that we'll talk about in there
and they were formation that and finally
we need to continue soliciting Aquinas
from the working group as well to
enhance it that this this standing was
not your thank you for your presentation
it's very helpful um the indentity that
you're the groups that you're using it
would also be good to clarify whether
using how you're looking at identity
concepts is identification etc right so
let me I think I'll give an example in
here just a brief one so the idea I mean
before there people used to define
policies that says block traffic from
this IP address to that IP address block
user I acts from accessing application
be the idea in here is to really group
things and rather than define them based
on information as such unless you need
to but you could say block traffic
between application a and application B
how many instances of that application
exists really is a Robin that's up for
the really controller to arrival death
and expand that policy to the
application instances that's that's one
example so an application is that the
case could be identified by a name or
attack for example
and how that could the same thing - they
use it you could put a user with
user group and obtain that tag or event
event of that user group from an Active
Directory or LDAP or something along
that line that's kind of the idea so you
define policy between contacts rather
than on explicit identity that exists in
the network that could be variant as
function of time both comes and goes and
also that the kind of explain that I
love
so this is the draft about the
information mark for the client so the
idea I mean as the information on that
model and John what what it is is really
I think so referred to its early and her
presentation has a blueprint to define a
data model or basically finding what
needs to be contained in the model in
other words as really as there is one
our C that says how it should be fine
it's about defining really information
objects what information relate should
be defined in them and the
interrelationships objects and that's
really what the information model that
were defining in here the object models
and the relationships are really defined
in a way to address that Aquinas and the
requirement death as I said earlier
there have been few extensions that we
added to the requirements related to
different policy categories though some
of them are already in the information
while others will need to be extended in
particular things pertinent to the to
their competitive to the to the audit
for example category as well as to the
segmentation category it has to be
explicitly mentioned but Jean drill the
information model is consistent with the
requirement left that the functional
requirements really is applied to
multi-tenancy related objects so that we
have a tenant domain object object the
main object and so forth and there are
just kind of defined in the requirement
what we call the user group and point
the application endpoint and so forth so
there are object models for these
so there is also an object that defines
where the fat information is coming from
the source of it the weather is defined
based on as URL threat threat feed
signature an event map and so forth
there is telemetry collection objects in
the information model draft that says
what data could be collected the
telemetry data could be collected the
sources from which they are collected as
well as the destination to which they
are streamed to if you will or reported
to either via a pull model or a push
model that's also kind of the object
model capture set and there is security
policy objects that are created using
different so really the way you define
the policy instances is he a composite
of the different policy marks or policy
construct that we talked about earlier
and in this presentation next slide
please so the draft is has been updated
if there is any input from the working
group that would like the work group
would like to hear about that on the
manifest and will discuss and update
according to command so this first of
all again I see that there is some
overlap with other end drafts etc so we
will need to have an in fact when it
comes to these the customer facing
interface I was wondering whether can
move it a little bit I was wondering
whether it would make sense I mean
looking at the text the text to me looks
more a set of one hand is extended
requirements that are better formalized
the one hand and on the other hand they
are more about most about metadata I
mean we're talking about the issue the
source dates etc what looks
to me as an envelope for a general
statement and probably I mean and it's
something is something that we will have
to go through this Linda was proposing
this design team in which we are going
to try to steer a little bit all the
drafts we have at hand I'm probably I
mean my recommendation looking at it it
would be probably that we take some
parts of what you have there for the
requirements and some parts of what you
have there try to mix it too with Hank
was presenting as well because we're in
telemetry for example this is one thing
the second thing that that I'm starting
and it's a general command not only to
our to your document in particular is
that is true that we agreed that we
wanted to have information model
documents and that's to me looking at of
what have been presented and the
documents in the UM in the data tracker
etc looking at them looks to me that
this is justified in the case of the
capability model because a capability
model is something complicated so to say
to express and it's a new thing that we
are bringing here in terms of
generalizing the whole thing but
probably in other cases just having data
mobile I mean a data model document with
a justification talking about why that
data model is built probably should be
nothing so we reduce a number of
entities and we apply these outcomes
racer this probably genetic hni comment
to all that for me some of us in the
work group not just this one I think
probably I didn't touch from that bit
earlier that there was a decision to pre
Indian I've been in other working groups
where people had really forgot didn't
see they need to have an informational
model documents they've done in some
working groups were done done and then
we dismiss some data after the date of
all that have been find so they were
just used as guidance if you will to
define the data model I think there's no
there's no requirement to
push every document that started through
to RFC is it when it's useful drop it
when it ceases to be useful yes that
makes a match oh yeah coming back to
your comment that that's really where
the information model is it's really
very kind of separated from the
requirement the requirements talk about
what's driving things what needs to be
done what the information model is
supposed to be they talk about what
information is too deeply complain and
an information model how things relate
to each other and that's really the
information model is so it's not really
requirements we we have no requirements
this is just again from reading it looks
like since since do you think that we I
will have the requirements I will have
the information model we have the data
model then you push certain things that
could be in the requirement you push
them to information is more complex
listen you're agreeing with each other
stop it
okay really quick there's a sink height
the term that I heard already and that I
also wrote on a lot chart on the first
day of the athan is telemetry so my
assumption is that the solution on data
model level will be a yang based posh
subscription subscribe but if occation
based data model a datum also say
they've been stream telemetry stream so
maybe we can converge all the
information items in a corresponding
graph that would make use of this one
method you saw a lot of triggers there
that are beyond event time for example
so we should yeah I mean there is no
need to have multiple graphs talk about
the same thing
I mean consolidating will make sense I
mean sub model is obviously that I think
and having streaming model is that I
think as well because definite means do
exist so be really careful here you have
just five minutes on the agenda and
you've got lots of slides so cut to the
piece that you really want to say
hello Jessica from Huawei I'm going to
present you the latest changes I was a
policy object draft first as a
background recap and the framework draft
I at USF has selected the save a model
for for policy rules and the capability
draft has defined many attributes for
different for different conditions
subclasses the attribute base the policy
rules and phases to possible problems
repeatable configurations for the
creation and the maintenance of the
policy rules is time-consuming and
tedious so a more efficient way is
needed as anyway used as the object
issue to express the condition in the
policy rules so there are two main
benefits the way we provide the reducer
bureau chief for the creation of policy
object can be referenced for multiple
times and also brings simplicity for the
maintenance of the policy rules so next
slide please
there are there are two main changes
from last meeting first we provide a
minimal set of policy objects and
attributes instead of defining every
possible object it's even needed as a
new one will be included in this draft
so here is a picture of the other
objects we define including address
object and service application user and
schedule and and here are some some more
slides about the details of the policy
object I think we can skip it and the
gels are in our draft and the appendix a
has provided the possible values of
attributes
so next slide please next slide we sing
again go to the examples the example a
slide and yes so we were added an
example of the application scenario for
the policy objectives
this is a typical enterprise network
technology which the fair wall which is
an example of the NSF located at the
boundary of the network and we have Chu
department shook hands out departments
the marketing department and the R&D
department next slide please
mmm then we can make different policy
control a code by using by defining and
using many policy object and in this
slide the event the event patch is
missing we were added in the in the next
version and so so next slide please
so we have come up with some questions
and us sausage for comments such as jus
event and action also need objects and
we can build policy object for post
client facing interface and an NSL
facing interface so and other questions
I think we can talk about each in the
mini list
thank you that's all
so yeah I quickly report this time in
hackathon we implemented a VP Iowa
Victor so we try to use existing
information model but it turned out a
shape point of view a little lacking so
I hopefully the authors of a kind of ASA
can include last one yet so the next the
hackathon which we tried to okay this
time we have made our improve the East a
model so hopefully the momentum of the
conspiracy
probably improved next slide so next
please
so we tried to synchronize with the
super information model next time and
also the flag to make is consumer taste
thank you thank you so next one yes hi
so I'm Hank again last meeting we made a
very small very tiny introduction of the
structure moment which is in our way
later document to the HR NSF what group
it is about remote attestation so we are
doing the same thing as Diego well
really of course we are doing remote
system entity characters authentication
this is using RFC 4949 terminology so
this is basically for remote attestation
is this is composed recording it wretch
three activities exists so at the
station actually is only the creation of
the evidence by having one or more
claims about the characteristics of the
business with system entity and so this
claims can be used as evidence then we
convey second activity this evidence to
the verifier the an interconnect
interconnect is a strange term here it
is typically used by people of USB or
bluetooth when you have hard times
finding the the the message pass were
using it can be GI opens and it can be
up to the internet so everything that is
able to transport data can be
interconnect it could be in a small
form-factor SFP interface talking for
the module or it could be a cluster of
super high performance computers talking
to another cluster so the interconnect
is basically just the thing you convey
the evidence with verification then
happens on the other side it's the
appraiser of the evidence against the
electric cloud of guidance defined by
second terminology next slide so
typically this is a challenge response
act interaction model because you want
to know that the evidence you get is
fresh it's just the thing you want it
and the HST just created it so at
creating a nonce and the action model is
tightly coupled timewise - Radhika
bird's this by using trust time some
tokens and set of a month and therefore
allows for a unidirectional interaction
that does not need a return Channel next
slide so there are a lot of objectives I
think I present them last time
basically unidirectional is great
because of rest call me and it is
basically used for constraint
environments and it will be able to be
used with loss of connectivity so you
can basically create audit logs of the
attestation basis the evidence and then
transfer later next slide we're
introducing a third party for this
because these term tokens have to come
from somewhere they are provided by the
trusted by a timestamp Authority there's
an RC for that I forgot to put the
number in by Google so the Tuda protocol
has a nested sync protocol which is
basically encapsulating the time scepter
into two other times Thames and now it
comes that are provided by a hardware
root of trust they're calling that rod
so in essence true there is a read based
on Hardware rod the TSA is required
to create this evidence basically every
scenario so every thing that would
create a secure audit fire audit block
or something that hasn't in the past and
you want to prove it really happened
requires a TSA this is not unique to to
DES we're just making use of it in the
terms in scope of agitation next slide
so we had a lot of feedback for this
already coming in from a lot of
participants of it--when SF I got some
of them more ah past slide previous
slide please because it's the second
question so why using tudi if it uses a
sync protocol and makes things more
complex yeah well there was a very first
question but I think some are answered
there are please look at RFC 4949 the
bill la patrulla and the Biba model both
are specific models that focus on
confidentiality and integrity if you
change trust level zones talking about a
nuclear plant and critical
infrastructure that's kind of important
to adjust the things inside without
being able to compromise them from the
outside just read that up it's it's kind
of yes then second slide please
a question I'm running through these
items because of time
so which environments would be a benefit
from the more complex solutions so we
have a lot of IOT stuff going on in the
ITF space and most of it is coop coop is
restful there is no state so you kind of
faciliate a challenge response protocol
without state on the server side also
there is the idea of aggregating a lot
of requests for two stations with one
aggregated nonce this is an idea that
was published by our lead author
actually 10 years ago and it does not
address restful coop IOT problem we
think next time sorry so doesn't it he
is a introduced new attack vectors here
it will of course as well
every other component that is vampire
require to create security it would
create another service in fact that is
of course an attack vector for example
there's probably a night when s of
component that takes charge of the
security of the service of the software
itself or for example prevents resigning
of anything you create into a night
renders F domain so there will be
security functions of course the trade
secured you into their I to an SF domain
and the TSA will be just another
function like this next slide so yeah we
can broadcast of course you can beacon
it out unsolicited and they are not
encrypted so if we just become this out
yeah those would compromise privacy but
that is not a problem unique to tutor
that is a problem that you chose to do
it but the broadcast and there please
just choose a secure transport for that
so next slide next session was does the
state let nature support incremental
data stations and most certainly it does
it is basically the one point of
creating a partial order locks that you
can create as measurements company with
the evidence so the map shows you a very
good way how to do this via SNMP yang
can do it very more easily but we
started with the most complicated thing
we can find and that was as a simpie so
last question is after this I think so
how and up again and up again please
so how would hardware root of trust and
virtualized environment work because
virtual machine does not have hardware
this is called a virtual hub of trust a
lot of stos are working hard on this for
like I know six years and I think much
at least two SDOs that are not the ITF
have solutions for those unfortunately
they do not do public review on a
regular basis but I basically know for
certain that they will do public review
that one of them will do public review
very soon so this is not a total
specific but an attestation specific
problem
I kept a Moriarty Sega d last meeting
you approached me about doing this work
since it's crossed multiple groups and
another mailing list I don't remember
ever seeing a request I know this was
about the terminology for agitation
because everybody thinks at a session is
something else or doesn't know what
attestation is at all so it is about
talking about the right things there
there is a draft it's an individual
draft with General Electric's and arm it
is posted I can post this graph to the I
to NSF list if you want I was asking
about a separate mailing list the
separate mailing list requires that we
need a draft you said we can talk about
we cannot just start a list please
create rafts first for that list that is
the first draft it was your
recommendation I all right I still
haven't seen the request for the list
no yeah because as I was offended that
we really surpassed two weeks ago so
okay you have to compose a breakfast
also there will be a agitation at an
event terminology thank you okay thank
you and we're done apologies for our
polling time management at this end
you