your love nest yes yes no man who work
too much never has changed so many years
I'm not sure fix it okay
[Music]
that baby's room desk and we're gonna
made a claim later than to it earlier no
places in Germany where people actually
laugh all the time I just I want to go
and see this folks
um what some people have missed the
speakers I'm not just rude
just finish the work yeah yeah but just
you know if you're sitting back there
the sound is really bad this room it
somehow it's here they can't hear so I
will find it all just
did you get under the ticker okay would
anyone like to volunteer to work on the
Ethan's at this will improve your return
on the minutes but I see the massive
number of volunteers I see that's like
you know if you sit back up this sort of
post the sound may be bad if you're
worried about being insulted if you walk
in and out through all friendly about
what you can hear you probably care and
having announced this one more but I got
stuck in the back corner maybe next time
oh yeah okay can everybody hear me how
about the back I had one of the mumblers
at the Mike bend is everything working
okay in the back good
okay they fixed it good news will go
with will go with the tape then okay
we're going to start start is where the
where the meeting that's between you and
bear and dinner so I'm gonna go through
the agenda and then Al and the chair
slides unless you wanted to do it I can
do it oh okay so it's Alex you're up is
anyone seen mark so far okay he may not
make it he had another meeting am I too
loud though okay
so the agenda they've written the note
well again please read it enjoy it
how many people have never seen a note
well okay well then please read it there
online the first thing we're going to do
is we're going to bash the agenda and
we'll go through the church to chair
status being as it's late we may run a
little later into the chair status time
but we have a fairly short set of model
reviews the data models were going to go
through the topology drafts went to the
is Jian came back because the revised
data store issues had not been finished
now that met mod has kindly finished
stuff and and given this good advice and
the thirties group has worked alex will
give a brief update mock went through
his data model in info model to see if
they were revised data stores we may
haven't had it checked on yang models
but if he's not here I will give a brief
check then we will go through some new
models fabric data center and see you
separation models and then most of this
session was to see if we had interest in
a design team for a family data store I
will go through a description of that
and then I will call for volunteers then
at that point we will break out into
working on a design team because I
figured most people the ephemeral data
stores probably just so simple we might
be able to finish it at this time or we
might be able to get a good long way
then our next session was set aside for
a data store to get a room but they gave
us a large room so I'll try if I get a
data center team now I'll go right into
the the chair slides on that because
what's important but I've lost the chair
slides okay okay I'm I so just go right
into the chair slides
what we're doing is we're at the end of
our two major models our major models
are our network model and our game
topology model we think that this is all
done I think the road data model has to
the 25th to make a comment but these are
about ready to go once we've checked
with the aim doctors and officer and
routing der for their cue A's and these
will go carefully we will I will be
asking at least it my input from the t's
working group and people for an early
RFC publication if the ISU approves of
the topology so the t's work can go
through and several others the read
model will probably go through a normal
speed but there are implementations of
large size coming
remember these models can go into
configuration or dynamic data store they
are simply models they aren't designed
to be ready for dynamic data store and
have been implemented in it I think I've
said everything on this slide this
little thing is congratulations to the
working group for having gotten through
the big major models we were chartered
through I know that we've had a lot of
and congratulation to the net modem that
come for all their help
okay now the ADA's request is to adjust
the milestones and plans we can if I
have a design team that's works on a
ephemeral state and work that might fit
in with it then we will keep going if
not we may go and wait for some of the
implementation reports are going to a
short hiatus there's lots of stuff but I
need to make sure that as we plug in
additional models we have a data store
to plug in what and there is a template
for this thanks again to the to the
authors of the revised data store can't
being one and several others that
there's a template so you know I'm going
to go through is the last step the
template and the issues if
have a short design team this because of
all the good work maybe a short form or
we may have to argue with some other
things so looking for that design team
if you're looking for a quick term
that's what we're doing our choices are
again work on the ephemeral state work
on the new models for specific
deployments and wait for week for more
implementations at the end of all the
models I will show the network data
store model actually at the end of all
the models they'll take a pause and ask
for people if they have any opinion then
we'll go into the revised data store
model and for those people who want to
work on it if there's no one that want
to work on it that will take us into the
go on hiatus while we finish everything
questions this is really a time of
choice if the working group says okay
we've done everything and the
information in the revised data stores
is enough for corporations to develop
their own that's great we've done a good
job at setting everything up and doing
the pumps up and getting the push and
getting these basic models I'm sure the
stuff will come back as we get other use
cases and in fact some of the boss have
suggested that might be good good I
can't watch some Juniper Networks not so
much question was the comment I'm still
the assigned the gang doctor for the
topology draft and I'll beat a looking
into it shortly after the conference so
thank you Illya I went through the chair
slides already my apologies now we're
going to Alex it's your turn yet these
gonna do it they're two drafts one is
the basic topology model the second is
the layer three topology model
I'm excited so basically they have been
a fuel updates and so the topology model
went from the zero from the 12 to the 14
and the layer 3 topology model from the
8 to to the to the 10 graphed and the
main update most whoops 20 they're the
most important up it is that we changed
up the model tool to MDM da compliance
and this was Sol's and particularly to
address the mix discovered underlies and
configured over the issue that we had
that we've struggled with for such a
long time this was basically the the
cleanest resolutions of basic and glad
actually that worked out this basically
the structure of the model actually has
remained the same actually the change is
actually very minimal I think we only
change all of the description updates
was that the server provided leaf is is
gone then and then in addition that was
actually was in the in the latest
revision we did add also a state model
for non and MDA compliant implementation
that was a comment that was made I think
it would be a good idea to add that so
we have this actually in there in there
as well we move because there's bidding
just for the non and named MDA compliant
implementations and yeah so the updated
module models have been reviewed but of
course we'll be happy to to get your
review I'm Kent and also I wanted to
mention also that the security
consideration have also been updated and
and and reviewed basically it does
explain basically the fact that we rely
on the other line transport and knock
them to provide security in addition
basically we have added basically
explanation of various exploits that it
could do if you were to mess
configuration if you did not have that
access okay next one and so basically
the next steps are essentially the
network topology draft is done we hope
the tree topology draft is practically
done it doesn't require actually one
more revision with very minor a place
there was also another yang dr. think
Christian hops rise actually the issue
that we have in the example which is not
actually part of the model per se but in
the example we have basically we show
how to apply to do is is and basically
advise that and also there was basically
actually one issue that PT one prefix
needs to be updated to point to the
correct state model the amount we hope
to post them in the coming few days
source by the end of the week okay thank
you so again this is passed it's working
group last call but at any point if
you're if you're implementing you're
deploying it please send comments it
will go to ITF less call fairly quickly
after the yang doctors go so thank you
again to all who've worked on it
okay now we're on to the rip model and
mock if you want to give that one just a
minute okay this is a very brief update
to this I Torres rape even is model and
remodel and Mr Trabb has already tear
for a long time and quite stable Oh
certainly and they stood dragged on line
with each other
and there's no additional changes since
two years or before and the information
model has already passed a walking table
last call and the data model has already
not Co has where I studied and we also
very appreciate their comments and
suggestion to that model and also have
it do a very quick check on the track on
animals react
it's I think a personal thing that
Chavez are
it's capable we always the undie I'm a
DA style so when that's all fit its
wrapped and again we look for again our
gang Gawker has responded it's Kyle's
right yeah yeah and so he's starting to
interact with monkey so we are again
thankful for that okay any questions
about this again it's the same comment
this is going to go rapidly through the
process if you have looked at it or
played with it or have anything to say
please make comments okay thank you
quick you can queue thank you Mike for
all your hard work and big back to
mitten up there in the blue internet
space that we can he's done been so
faithful to keep going with us all these
years
okay now we're going to go through the
new models these have not been adopted
or call to we're going to talk about
them fabric based hello everyone now
here come to the two models focusing on
the fabric based management's for this
internet work the first one is about the
network topology and another is the
service model and these two model have
been presented for several times and so
and they give a breath introduce an
introduction about these two models next
slide please
the objectives the service model is
defined to represent the services for
the users in order to deploy the service
while regardless of the details of the
network such as the halogen technology
and many others while the fabric pays
the topology model is used to define
fabrics topology module to manage the
Death Angel Network in architecture we
give the usage of these two models the
Fabri
service model is used by the
orchestrator to communicate with the
topology manager in order to deploy a
service while the fabric topology model
is used by the department in order to
manage the network next slide please
here is the history of these two models
the fabric to purge model is firstly
proposed in ITF 96 in Berlin while in
ITF 97 we updated the fabric topology
model due to the comments and and the
besides we also propose to the fabric a
service model as the servicing of s 2
users to configure or manage the user
natural fabric topology besides that in
the fabric service model we also define
an architecture in architecture we
explain how these two models come to
cooperate together in order to provide a
service besides that we also add new
orders in order to participate in the
work my last idea in Chikako we resolved
the comments on comparing the fabric
model with the heat polity model after
discussion with the heat policy authors
we both make the consensus on the
difference between these two models
besides that we add some descriptions
and revise the models based on the
comments next slide please
and after the IDF 98 we also make some
actors added on these two models firstly
due to the recommendation by the area
directors we're also updates the models
to natural management database
architecture style style and also in
appendix we provided a noun MD a fabric
topology state module in fact that as
people show more interest in fabric
modules so we remove the contents of the
fabric capable device
at this model is independent with our
two Tomatoes the very fabric our
topology module and the service module
besides that or also make some editorial
changes next slide place after this
after only thing that now these two
jacks are ready for the workgroup
adoptions though we may ask what the
chairs recommend about the adoption and
also we are appreciate for the further
review of these two model jobs and thank
you for that question we will pick it up
after the next model it's part of our
general discussion
I mean you appreciate all your hard work
to refine the model thank you very much
and next is the questions any questions
good we'll go on to the next note thank
you again we will pick up some general
questions I introduced at the beginning
of the session after this next model and
before we go into the discussion on a
ephemeral datastore thank you okay next
model
Michael the children yes
just uncle flipping your slides for you
today so just okay I will conclude this
is Michael from Norway and today I want
to introduce a update for information
module for Co separated in network okay
this is a slides brave introduce
background motivation objective of our
walks the background is still separated
by ng networker use case and the
architectures already assessed by BBF so
Club CEO working groups and relative
document will injuries a strawberry
steps and maybe will be published in
these years and so why we need to say
still separated the engine network is
because it can't get example in when
many benefits for example if we have the
central knives can chew plane that is a
control plane can have the whole wheel
of the network resource and the users
information
so since contributing can distribute as
a real natural resource as a specific
service requirement for example the
second to blink and balanced
distributors the IP and the grass and
session to the user brain that can
improve the utilization of network
resource and another benefit is if we
have the synchronizer control plane that
it can provide a unified interface to
obstacle outside system such as as ms
tcp server and raters system can
simplify as a management also this work
can monistic can't reduce the time to
market because the the in children and
the user can be separated and the device
of them can be extended separated so it
can significantly reduce
time to market so last things we can get
benefit is because some PNG network and
anytime maybe a large number of user
accessing so if we have a dynamic
control plane to handle it either will
improve if usage to the network okay so
how to achieve this
see you separated network in this
document will provide an information
module to present interaction interface
between the control plane and the user
plane this if this world could be
standardized it can help the interaction
work between interwork between different
devices for example if the controller
and devices is from winter a and the
user Briand devices are from winter BCD
and if we have a sender information
modules that can help them to understand
each other and help them understand I
recognize what is attributes table
carried so this information module
basically have two blocks the one is
introduced control plane the interface
it contributed information now there is
in introduced Europeans in information
so came to plan your from the
contributing is take charge of
generation interest tables rules and
it's an essential user plane and its
user plan we are mapping to some policy
and in performing corresponding action
another rules of the user plane is to
report as a traffic statistic to the
user to the king to blame for and next
rise a we provide a example of this
information module okay we can see in
this picture even maybe a user name the
Bob he is assessing and then you can see
the figure it's a user plain view
Barb's information and the traffic a
statistic for example available
bandwidth choose a control plane
controlling receive assistive
information and then searched public
corresponding service requirement it's
in generated Auto generate some service
some tables so for example a users
information table I chose each episode
it's a king user plane okay a set of
tables is a relative choose Bob and
there's a Bob sauce in for ipv4
information and the pubs curious
requirement for window here is provide
examples say R is 6 and be per second
pyaara is it and be per second and then
to use a contribution census several
schools choose European European
receives the troops and mapping and
mapping to corresponding policies and
here is some policy example the user if
Bob is an engineer and the source IP is
in the market and subside and since it
performed cause one action is okay
limited Serbs and ways from from 16 and
be to 10 MB sin so user plain performs
this actions
okay
this page is a provider update from last
night meeting and in the 0-1 version we
write into users information module and
user planes information module
characteristic practice among clerical
errors and improve the readability
here is a figure 2 shows a periphery
introduce user clean the behaviors the
user plan receives rules and the map
into power
say map mapping persons and perform
Cosmin actions and another things we
update is a debt exception to introduce
data model of Co separate the PNG
network here we reuse a steel model
which defunding the RTG JWT working
group so a logical network element and
the logic own that under network
instance module and here we can see this
is a tree structure we use an example we
create an instance of the irony mode you
who can hear the name the name we
assigned an a value of a brass one and
then you can use skim among mesh machine
ISM to assemble different
rattail works such as interface VLAN
para cqs ACL and in this in this meeting
we also want to get some feedback and
thus Macworld can me become toad so
whether this is a good way all right
away to use this in volume to present as
a seal separated did motor okay next
okay so next cyber we want you along
with the PPF rabbit it works and maybe
requires a people have cheers and
applause co-working Google chairs to
since millions into I try working group
and we also want to solicit more
comments in suggestion and we can't
based on this suggestion documents to
prepare another word and to improve our
works
finally if everything works appeal and
the working group think we had to see is
available works maybe we want some time
we can want to walk off adoption thank
you thank you Michael and again we're
gonna cover some of these adoptions in
our general questions so any questions
for Michael
well thank you we will go on to the next
step again I'm going to repeat what we
started out in the chair slides is our
major work item left is to create a
femoral or a dynamic dais or that was an
initial Charter of course with the
dynamic data store we could create one
that's not in our wonderful map mod
provides datastore version 3 there is a
[Music]
appendix which provides a great deal of
the information you should see the
example a federal state that Kent and
other his co-authors provided and
there's a wonderful extension now we can
go through and continue to work on that
but we need a design team so right now
we're going to do what we lovingly call
the hum moment I would like to hear a
hum on people who want to work on this
revised data stores work means be an
author be a revisor
yes right right
from long coat so the chair would like a
hum we'll all those who are willing to
work on the ephemeral data store that
means co-author or revised hum ok that's
a small set of hums the next question is
is our people interested in the last two
models we'll go model by Marvel I'd like
a home on people who are willing to
active the authors have spent quite a
bit of time working on their model how
many people can't watch some cheaper
networks before I get to the hum at
least in the last model I was wondering
is the iiterest working group the
appropriate working group for that work
I mean is it related to ephemeral
dynamic data source again this is an uh
place like our TWG we're models can come
to find a home it doesn't have to be
ephemeral it doesn't have to be dynamic
and simply be a platform wide not a
specific protocol and protocol
independent so in that hat the fabric
model fits so we'll ask that question
and for Michaels we have a secondary
question so I will ask the question
because that will help the ad and I and
Russ and Aliyah and I to direct the
author's to their best next step how
many people are interested in working on
the fabric I've asked the room to have a
hummus you're interested okay so we do
here some interest that's a sort of hmm
well yeah you're hearing it probably
better than I okay for Michael's draft
and his wonderful co-authors that's the
one Michael did you present in our DWG
as well yes okay
what was your feedback there okay so one
of the questions someone asked about his
model and I I want to make sure if we
had any discussion is whether it's
specific is a protocol independent model
Michael makes the proposal that the
split between control plan and user
plain is interesting and a non protocol
specific model other people have
suggested that it may be aligned with
other things such as a BBF because of
his application and the reason why it's
here is not necessarily and it's
ephemeral or dynamic although you can
see the benefit of that for his model
but because it's protocol independent so
I'm going to ask for sense of the room
by the way we will we will send these to
the list as well but as a sense of the
room for the ad and Russ and I how many
people are interested in reviewing this
model I
from heylia you here are our answer was
that a medium or was that a high for the
note taker meeting - that was meeting
okay so that's energized quick okay so
that gives the that is the chairs
because of that we'll get together and
and send the authors what we're going to
do as far as making a working group call
unless you want to yeah so I'm really
happy to hear that there's interest in
additional work and models but one of my
questions is getting the base pieces
done and having the energy and
participation and need in terms of
implementations for instance to do so
and so for that I mean I personally feel
like there's a lot of value in the read
models and apology models one of the
questions is for other pieces of work
that the working groups working on like
the filter based rib you know the
interest level in that I have talked
with the chairs about looking at winding
down the working group if there's not
enough energy and if we're not having
folks actually actively volunteering to
do things like Shepherd and review
documents I know that part of the
challenge in this working group has been
that a lot of the documents are there
sorry I mean a lot of the challenge
[Music]
let's try this again so you can actually
see me and not my column right one of
the challenges has been that a lot of
the documents have been sitting there
for a year or two and we haven't had
necessarily all of the pieces such as
the ephemera some of the ephemeral data
store were
in order to do full implement heat as
for these standards compliant for what
it would be implementations and so one
of the questions I have is how many
people of course now I can't hear the
helmets well either how many people are
willing and interested to seriously you
know work on things like the data store
reviewing documents and and so on in the
next six months if I can have a hum for
that that would be useful okay so that
was a hum for if you're willing to work
and review the revised the ephemeral
data store well I was actually asking in
general for the work because because I
think that what I found interesting is
that was actually different and less
than the people who are interested in
some of the new documents I'm lonely I'm
extremely concerned about the idea of
trying to adopt new documents in the
working group if there's not energy in
the working group because there are
other places if we need to that we could
put them right I'd like to see the work
that's in the working group get done
we've done a lot of stuff when we
started this working group we thought
wow if we could just get data models I
mean just getting the RHIB data model
get some of the stuff done
that would be huge and a big change for
the industry and I think we've seen a
lot of that happen already a lot of the
features that we're looking for to go
into net cons and rest cons are there
it's awesome but the question is you
know at what point do we say that was
great but now we don't have energy or at
what point do we say this was great and
now we're really gung-ho to go focus on
this piece and that's what I need you
all to be thinking about my
understanding is the ephemeral data
store work to actually do that
particularly if we have some productive
sessions this week is not that high but
I really need to have you know what the
question I'm facing is do i recharter or
do i close i who are us and when do I do
it and that's based on you know
interest and energy as is not a I want
to I want to close I to are us this is a
if this is what the status is that's
what it is and I need to know that hey
Phil Phil Schaeffer towers if you're
looking for a more accurate thing you
might want to have people stand up
because there's a diability in a hum you
know but you stand up and actually raise
your hand you know something
sure that's more accurate more
yeah I'd appreciate that so fine who in
the working was right time do you wanna
go first yeah yeah I'm economy so the
working group from the original
architecture document fair it's far away
and the original intent what was you
know in the in the in the architecture
and what is being developed today are
two different things so from that
perspective me personally I have I'm
coming here to see if there is something
coming back but so far from my
perspective you know from the original
intent and what we it when the the the
working group went to our you know ended
up in very you know differentiated so if
you remember you are even the author on
the document you and David Ward's on the
original architectural document yes I'm
very well aware so I would argue
actually the push notifications the
ability to do dynamic pushes and
subscriptions are one of the pieces
there we have an understanding of how to
actually do the priorities to handle
multi-headed control that's there we
have the dynamic data store understood
what needs to happen but not nailed down
yet we have the RHIB model which lets us
provide a programmatic interface at the
right level if you're talking about
speed issues sure that's a concern if
you're talking about all of the other
pieces in terms of sort of dynamic to
the different protocols so challenges so
I will go to that I have
okay so I have a experience implementing
something which is close to my Taurus
yes but it is essentially not compliant
with image with the majority of the
documents one other thing you know which
I ran into it that there are some there
were some issues that they had to go
different ways and different paths so
some of the things are useful but you
know majority of the things are a little
bit you know problematic so I'm I'm
keeping an eye on it but I am NOT you
know again doing active contributions
because you know it's a the path has
diverged it's off a point of
clarification if we had a net mod exist
be net Kampf
Andres Kampf for two initial pieces as
we announced in the last couple things
people with an alternative Fiat binary
BAC bore or whatever you have are still
open are you suggesting something linked
like to see something like that with an
yet another affirmative not necessarily
to be nice but not necessarily because
it's it's more about the interactions
between the app between the applications
between the how I see the address is
useful between the management service
control and data play and some so and
especially with the breaking up of the
data plan and the control plane and the
control plane separation sorry of the
control plane data plan that they define
the service point those who're
interesting part where it some of the
ITRs concepts can be used and you can
use that called fresco or anything
third-party doesn't matter because in
this case like for example the rib model
is a common thing now which transport
you used to to transfer the API between
the point a and B I don't think it's
that the distant it's more about
agreeing on you know on the applications
for example one of them is we were
having that today for example is I want
to do an LSB and from a user's
perspective is how I want to use the LSP
or how I want to use the aqua and then
defined it here how how is it how is it
being used and what API in an or the
what an API to do in order to
communicate that their desire I'd wanna
I'm purposely I want to use the word
intent so your desire to be that being
in essentially through the control point
being established and deployed under the
data play so coming up with those use
cases and saying okay here I might you
know here's my comment el fip here's my
you know common you know rib you know
just that would be a very useful and
then which protocol see using it really
doesn't have it so what I'm hearing just
to reflect that unless you want to
address something else to Lee I just
want to clarify your comments did you
want to go ahead for something to leave
before I and others just fine question
then it sounded like the data plane
application things but that Michael was
looking at was something of interest you
know if you can mention the draft name I
cannot put Michael we - oh okay so I
haven't read their draft so I you know I
can't do a full comment on that thank
you very much that was just a clarifying
question - the question is more use case
but more the point as you say you have
an implementation and what we've been
doing here is diverged are there other
people and I feel free to raise hands or
come up to the mic who are in similar
boats is that are there pieces that are
have been implemented and it just feels
like this is not has not been going down
the right path okay so let me pull that
your contributions are welcome the
intent was not to go down the different
paths
and if we don't understand what the
divergence is it's hard to improve it
running code really matters that said
but then I go back to Phil's point which
is all right raise your hand or stand up
if you're willing to work on documents
in the last next six months to get
different pieces done okay okay cool
thank you so I'm not gonna try it I mean
if if I Taurus were to continue for a
long period of time that I would be
looking at doing things like reach our
Turing to add in some of the pieces that
we talked about in some of the Netcom
net mod recharter to clarify the pieces
that need to happen but we've got you
know an agreement and I'm happy to at
least let things run through the next
IETF and see how things go but we really
need to actually have energy in motion I
know that some of the models like the
apology stuff are things that um certain
projects are depending on and we're not
really seeing folks coming and
participating and saying hey this is
what we need a lot of energy has been
put into the working group by you know
sue is one of the chairs and that's not
something that's fair to depend on and
it doesn't represent the group right I
need you all who raised your hand to be
active reviewers and active drivers it's
it we can't have a single motive force
in the working group that's not
functional okay alia has the input now
the next step we're going to do is for
those who've raised your hands who want
to work on the ephemeral data store for
the model people I think the Lea and I
will get back to you on that I apologize
for this pause here but we will get back
to you within a day or so and if you're
here the rest of the week we'll try to
meet with you individually so we really
appreciate your hard work and
Michael I think you heard that you have
new someone to talk to about it sorry
let me just clarify
clearly there's interested in both of
both of the models and the work the
question is not should the work
proceeded and it - of course I
understood this the question is should
it proceed here or would it make more
sense for it to happen in RT gwg due to
the you know if we're trying to closed
you know work on heading to finishing up
the work and I - RS then it might make
more sense to do an RTG WGS this is a
management issue not a reflection on the
coolness of the drafts or the interest
in them and and that you should see is a
positive thing for your drafts there's
there's actually good interest in lily
and I are being very careful to make
sure Ellie and Russ and I are very
careful to make sure your drafts are
finding a good place because we are
hearing interest so you should hear that
as a positive Thank You Russ okay the
next part of this working group is
really a working session so for those
people who raise your hand come up to
the front we're going to sit down and
talk about the ephemeral datastore the
rest of you are welcome but this is
really this session and we may schedule
another session on Thursday as a working
session so if you raise your hand and
come up toward the front we'll just sit
and start working on this ephemeral
datastore they didn't know there was a
test when they raised their hands yeah
okay come on
so I'm gonna start with the ephemeral
datastore if you're interested come
toward the front if you raise your hand
and we're going to just start to talk
about things okay so you're going to
have two functions here where we have a
ephemeral datastore
this basic by the way
jörgen just so I say thank you you're
one of the authors thank you very much
for the care you did your normal
excellent work here along with Kent
thank you you just did a fabulous job
with this stuff okay folks in this
revised data store and Kent can help us
this is a basic model you know we could
take off example ITF a femoral model and
just simply put weight first let me take
a step back one of the things that that
again very helpful asked me in email is
what about a femoral data store and
dynamic data store I hope it was clear
that a femoral data store is a subset of
dynamic data store not everything is
ephemeral right the the ephemeral source
well sorry I can't watch I thought they
were sending them for each other that we
had just moved from the to the term
dynamic so it wasn't specific to the
question
some people said and this is part of the
discussion part of the model design is
there's a femoral is a particularly brie
boot the information goes away cuff goes
the magic information it is not clear
that in dynamic data stores every that
that is a capability that has to happen
with dynamic data stores you could store
dynamic data store in non-volatile Ram
okay so that's where you laid it out so
ephemeral and and you made it the same
well so the draft says anything is
written to the dynamic data store is
ephemeral it doesn't doesn't the draft
preclude you having a data model where
you can write entries in the data model
through the dynamic datastore and those
are ephemeral and in theory you could
configure entries in that same data
model through conventional data stores
and those would be persistent let's go
with the simple case we're just gonna
say there cinnamons and stop
I had to raise the issue by question so
we're only gonna consider again thank
you for the question it was excellent in
email it is only a femoral okay so this
example that they have we could say ITF
a femoral is ephemeral whatever the
appropriate thing is probably it since
it's ITF it should start we can go with
the namespace we can give a list we can
import the data store we can import the
origin did anyone have any problems with
the origin pieces that were listed in
the revised data store by the way do I
have someone who wants to be a lead
editor on this draft
am I getting a volunteer that's one of
the things Olli is looking for do we
have a theme volunteer so the editing
not seeing a hand that's a little
worrisome Polly and I okay this
ephemeral identity then becomes part of
the data store and the origin can be
from the base of the dynamic okay there
is an argument value and Kent what were
you intending for this argument value I
didn't pick this up am it mont um so
we're actually outside of the working
group meeting now yes I don't know you
don't this is a design team yeah it's
it's this is just right so the four
authors were in the process of
discussing the need for this extension
statement and actually we're beginning
to think that maybe it's not necessary
okay we're trying to formulate a final
conclusion to it but the whole question
is do we really want it to have config
false if they're more true
or could we could the data model just be
a standard config true and I'll you know
and but but it's only available inside
the specific dynamic data store yeah
okay so yeah
second to last or second to top line I
think those they config false affirm all
true
yes so so the that okay so at the time
that this was written that's what we
thought but then in the interim we came
out the yang library biz document and if
you look at that there's basically a
list of modules which could include
standard configuration modules and also
I trust modulus e like and then or okay
and then there's a missile module sets
and then lastly a list of data stores
the data source would be things like
running candidate and then potentially
ephemeral I traverse ephemeral each of
those data source then I have a pointer
into which module sets they're using
which of course then are which models
are using so what this means is you we
you can have a module and a server could
say I only implement it inside the
ephemeral data store and no it might be
very useful right and then of course
then that means that config true nodes
would you know it's obvious that these
are going to reflect the dynamic updates
so this that it then in that scenario
you wouldn't have to have this config
false ephemeral true which in some ways
seems different I mean it would go
against the grain of some basic tools
like being your so we're still in the
process of kind of sifting through
whether or not we really want that idiom
config post ephemeral true versus just
having configured standard config true
but the module is only available in the
specific datastore the question is for
the RHIB info model yeah
oh for the topology model I'm glad you
said that because I was in the process
of reviewing it I was wondering if it
was ready its config true and I believe
the topology model was config true as
well
and and you intend to be able to edit
them dynamically yes okay so then that
kind of
tilts the tilts the hat with your so so
I think the remaining question is is
there any cases you have where you think
there's data that's confit faults sort
of state data like fib entries for maybe
for example there there are five entries
as defined one or two state values that
is high I installed a route oh yes it
really happened
so that's operational that would be if
it was just in a configure so if you
install it if it if if the rib model is
used in the street configuration model
that is obvious what you're really
asking is if you instantiate this in an
ephemeral State what happens right first
application installs the second
application that's like right now right
now the girl working group is something
doing something very like it in in what
wouldn't call not with all the net lot
stuff because I can't do it they want to
its stall out and then they want to be
able to read it back to make sure they
got there and it's in their definition
that's dynamic it goes away so that's an
example of working you've doing it in a
less than optimum thing because this
stuff isn't ready so I think my question
is slightly different it's almost a
seven in it but it's if you have some
data dude naturally in the Yale model
Marcus conflict false is there any of
that date of the
you ought to write to know so everything
I can't think of a one in everything
you're the right to you something you
think is so that could be configured
normally potentially and is reasonable
smarts convict true then that's useful
to me every time we've done something
like that
we've regretted it or configurable oh
yeah yes yes yes ok configurable through
standard data source whereas you might
be talking about available in general
yes night or s models that do not exist
you're not exposed but it's there
writable there right we're not going to
say that complete false but we haven't
already so you take something false with
some other model and found any case
simply don't exist in I think that's ok
and I think I think I'm the option of
having some coffee true stuff that's
only applicable to iOS I think that's ok
it's more the question of semantically
lots of configuration states it's all a
bit woolly anyway but I think the yang
confit trees what people think was
configuration of in Forsyth Sun isn't
and it's just trying to get that balance
is is this stuff that it's really just
state you want to modify dynamically so
something like a some session states
that you'd never be market as
configurable because it's it's it's
dynamically learnt from the running
network so you can't define this
confidence not since so we'll use BGP
and we'll use the LSP example the BJP an
example where you would write over
something everyone who's done that is
usually found a place where it went bump
in the night and caused a bad problem
okay and then I mean there are many
things like easy to do that that are not
configuration that people have tried and
every time I've heard of that I've
usually heard of a a major incident
caused by it so bad ideas just stop it
it's read or write data filled this is a
good time to just sit and chat about
this well this does does I Taurus intent
like obviously you intend to write rev
entries through the ITRs program that's
why n read write do you do n also expect
for those models to be accessible
through stick conventional configuration
interfaces as well
yes persistent they know ok so left
outside the store ok so that's fine but
that's not your intention that I would
still say not be a bit ephemeral
datastore intention if you have those
models and you say to explicitly they
should not be done by conventional
configuration la statistically they
should only be used I Namek Lee because
that's slightly different because it the
moment confiture is looking like
it's for us to say but that's not that's
not our desire yeah if we said that in
the past you sent us home with that
question and we went and did a lot of
discussions and decided nope that's not
a constraint we have to have to work on
so if you hurt me or someone else say
that your questions really got us to dig
and say nope wherever people use our
models these are models then they gotta
define their data stores and define what
they want we've got two basic models
ribbon topology we know that they'll
work with we know something thing the
place where comes down to is this true
has to apply to the entire earth can't
down the middle city state or
traditional grip which is just a
[Music]
it's called there's a math there realize
because you're not going to rewrite the
Mack header from I to RS you might
rewrite the next huh you might rewrite
the route itself right but the primary
tree is going to be config true but
there may be some individual leaf here
and there that simply it's local state
there's no way for a controller to know
what that local state would look like
and there's no reason for that yeah
there's no reason for the loop ever if
the control over writes it you're
probably not doing a good thing when you
took this is why I said we had to talk
about in the my original draft the
defaults case because when you read risk
up and some of the defaults what happens
it reads like the same thing you know
what do you do when you have a route and
this realm is got a next hop IP next hop
but its installed with
mac address that goes out that can't be
must with it's just operational state
that it got put in with a a particular
map that that Ethernet it that Ethernet
interface has a MAC address how do you
handle that in your normal configuration
we can configure next hop but we won't
in many cases be able to configure our
Mac because that's tied to an interface
you can't change it because that
interface usually is tied to a Mac you
got a board you stick it in it's got a
MAC address no we don't think it's
sensible for the basic grip yes yes
that's how we're planning to do it and
that's what Russ is trying to say those
are the things you have operational
state this right that is that as far as
I can tell what you are doing now so so
one thing that came up during the I
guess the routing working group and I
think I sent an email to you on the
working list was was the assumption I
think that when we make config true
nodes in a model that does that
necessarily mean they're accessible
through conventional data stores so I
guess I responded to your statement
about that from your slides and I guess
my my thinking was that just because you
have a data model with config true
doesn't necessarily mean it's accessible
through conventional data stores coming
back to what kent said we can say this
model is only accessible through this
data store this model is only to
supposed to this day of store we can
have models in a router that are
testable through some data stores and
not in others so the ITRs model may only
be accessible through the dynamic data
store so trying to address that model
through a conventional data store you
get so this goes back the decision with
the idiom but assuming that we go that
you know I tress models are
with standard config true then if you
really wanted it only to be available in
a dynamic or ephemeral datastore then
the RFC itself could say so in text or
the yang module might be able to say so
in text or we might be able to define a
new yang statement of some sort that
kind of explicitly states it but I'm not
sure if that's a great idea
do we need to limit it I mean I don't
arrest and say for the ITER for this I
tourists draft it has to be accessible
through the avenues for vendors to make
it accessible I don't want to restrict
it or or imply that a plus P right so
back to that I mean I don't have read
the rib draft myself but in the topology
draft I remember it's not intended to
only be in the dynamic discs or it
actually was intended to be configured
standard and because you want your
overlay is to survive reconfiguration
this is why we came up with that whole
thing with the leaf Roth being required
and since false so that you know if it's
referring to something and it's not the
can't the references and resolved inside
configuration then the system if it's
valid convicted valid configuration but
then the system can go ahead and see
well can I resolve this leaf wrapped
inside operational state and if so then
the overlay becomes active want me to
echo in the recording so it's nice to
try and use the mics when we can we
should pass this around when we talk
okay more questions more thoughts on
this so I still think that I think on
the same page roughly that that when you
write a model you write conflict true in
there that means that you could take
this model and use it on collection of
configuration it may be the author's
intent to say this doesn't make much
sense and you might put a comment in the
model say it's designed to use B to be
using i2s but actually just by it being
conflict true that does say that
something could take this model if they
wanted to and try and use it through
informational datastore so let's use and
and then maybe as you say we use young
libraries the mechanism to they make it
make it particularly whether or not a
particular model is very wound through
dynamic or so through conventional theta
doors right and we find the case what
we've been hearing from people is for
example AC provided an extended rib -
there are t WG and Elise said to him why
don't you look at our to s you said but
that's a femoral only and we said no
that's a data model yes you install it
in the datastore you want it to be in if
you want it to go in the config because
it's got some really valid things then
you need to make sure it works in the
config that in the yang doctors you
might want to you should look at the
model in both ways so that is the case
that Joel mentioned that is some place
you say for this datastore we're going
to accept this if someone puts it in the
config they have to make sure they have
it working so the one thing we want to
be careful of here is to do with
performance I think that to say if it's
a device is choosing which data models
are available in which data stores then
that could be quite difficult for
clients to handle that there needs to be
some way of having right sets of modules
and things like that says all the
packaging in a library thinks that
there's an open issue I think here so if
we have the models that can be either
one don't did you have something you
wanted to say that the thing is we have
only a small a relatively small number
of models and at the moment all of them
that we're doing by definition we're
doing them because we want to support
them in the ephemeral data store and we
certainly while some boxes may choose to
support them in the conventional data
store we certainly do not expect that
all boxes will so from our perspective
in terms of the current work we have to
treat it as if you're supporting this
because you're supporting it here now in
principle you could have a box that only
supported it somewhere else only
supported in the conventional but we're
not trying to solve that but we would
want to have the situation because we
wrote it for a femoral that boxes who
are supporting the model were required
to support it for config that would
overly limit the work and the use of the
work yeah
and that will sounds fine that all
sounds fine and pragmatic and I think
that's even he is just description
statement or comment in the model saying
this is how it's a vision to be used I
think that's okay so we can cook again
that's something as these models are
going through the final Ganga fish you
should say put it in because we're happy
to do that questions before we go back
to the the richest thing on these and
then I'm gonna go to the next set of
pages of questions
it's along these lines I guess one
question I had based on the new data
stores draft so we've defined a new edit
data RPC so this this the RHIB model for
example has our pcs defined for adding
and removing things I don't think the
topology draft has that so if I go to
the the RHIB model you could use our pcs
to add and remove them but I guess it's
a question for the community are we also
intend to use edit data with a target of
our ephemeral or des ephemeral to write
to those data models or just the our pcs
so that's one thing well the topology
model I think is expecting to be able to
do because it doesn't have our pcs right
then I wonder why we're doing our pcs
then for the model
okay and that was based on initial
feedback for some of the winners pardon
and speak right and that's that was the
next statement as the early implementer
said our PCs are going to give us better
speed I can kind of see that as
implementation can go oh this is this
our PC director right bank that's
exactly what of looking at where it
belongs in a data store but that's
something definitely want to clarify is
that okay we're not intending to use the
new the new edit data or that it data is
allowed or whatever like so at this
point and again we're in this
last-minute call bit and mock sitting
there we should say at this point with
this revision
we're intending to do our preseason mock
you need to okay what about reading from
the data store because reading from
operational will give you the
operational values and for sure we
should be able to read this data model
in the operational days yes but are you
intending to be able to read the Oh are
ephemeral data store and read to read
this data the our PCs are only right
yeah they're only right today so I'm
just wondering - do you have your answer
do you want to do a get get data on this
data store or not just something we'll
need to clarify there are you muck the
get to theta it current in conversion
there have d some example the rape a
dripped late and and relate something
like this the question is asking is are
you going to get the results from the
operational data store or from these let
me rephrase a little bit yeah so
obviously you'll be able to query this
data model from the operational data
store and that'll give you the
operational view of everything in that
data tree a config true and the config
false notes for the config true nodes
are you expecting to be able to do an I
get data from the or from the DSF emeral
data store I'm not I'm not sure if
there's a reason I don't know the
protocol well enough to know if what you
write to the dynamic data store I know
but what what you writes the ephemeral
to the ephemeral data store is there
some reason I wouldn't exactly get
translated to the operational or the
other things I could overwrite it or
something well I mean there should be no
lag between the operational the only the
only concern I have is the view
that you need to be able to get out all
of the pieces of data as long as you can
get out all of them I don't think it
causes a problem for us if the reads
need to be aimed at the operational data
store instead of the ephemeral store
make the co2 look a little odd to some
people but that's a perfectly reasonable
thing I had normally simply assumed that
one would read back from the same data
store one wrote two because I tend to
think that way but it doesn't hurt
anything if it well that is what yeah
kind of we're using our pcs to write
it's a question of whether you read ever
read the data store because we never
read it if we never read this today if
we only read the operational for this
data maybe let me back up a little bit
at one point you guys are talking about
panes of glass and resolution it is that
all gone away there's only one there's
only a single ephemeral data so yeah
it's a global that every deaf only one
is a little Danish last rider wins yeah
so they I think there's a priority
mechanism it's not always last rider
wheels but last successful writer is the
only one yeah which means it'll be that
same copy very shortly in the
operational yeah then there's probably
not a strong need to read from this data
store using get data which actually kind
of means to me you have our pcs too
right
you're never gonna read from it I'm not
sure there's a data store there well at
least the way it apology is done if just
to read and write that data store now I
don't I don't have a strong preference
on it okay reason we did this is we're
trying to have a very simple beginning
there is still an open issue depending
on working group effort and desire to
come back to the panes of glass but
right now we're just trying to get there
that was our statement so I'm not I'm
just raising something I don't know this
was this was just simply a clarifying
answer hopefully but so the that get to
the end of your question it's more I
just will have to decide what we want to
do there doesn't sound like we've
necessarily concluded there's a good
point that I
to think about how this might get
extended and also the topology model
doesn't have our pcs so that one's a bit
different yes yeah okay okay so I
thought where Jason was going with that
line of questioning was that you know if
you're going to do get data on the DSS
ephemeral data store
then it'd be asymmetric if you aren't
also able to do the Edit data I mean
there may be our pcs but it'd be a SPAD
I don't think you're going to prevent
the ability for edit data it's going to
be possible the RPC is are just an
optimization and but then I have
question if the value of the RPC is I
mean it seems more like an
implementation detail that could be
optimized you know a way hopefully
enough maybe not enough I'm not the
expert here with your your performance
requirements but I mean it'd be
unfortunate if towards me to define the
RPC to get that last microsecond of
performance does does the RPC data show
up in the database could do that that
was our assumption and that was our
desire that's correct
in the ephemeral datastore actually
seems to be against the common way that
we approach miss that our pcs are really
only affecting the operational this is
the rim for the department no no no in
general for an accountant in breast pop
in general all RPC is only effect
operational it's true is a little bit
funny to have these customers machines
for these things I mean your thing is
the fact that you're writing this data
stores already
doing something special for my
Tourette's so maybe that's gonna be
optimized to that because I have to do
the RPC and then go ahead and create the
thing in the ephemeral database I'm not
really optimizing you know I actually
have to do more work because now I have
to tell it as I'm making the operational
database
don't let that in fact impact the demons
who would traditionally look at the
ephemeral database so it's it's a it's a
mixed optimisation but but but my my
question I thought your question is well
was does does data created by the RPC
show up in the ephemeral database and
the answer is yes so one thing that you
have to be aware of if you write an RPC
and you're hardwired it to a specific
data store it's hot' by it with specific
data store right by doing that you won't
be able to use the same module to
implement it and conventional data store
whatever because the RPC is hardwired to
modify a specific dynamic data store
right so if you look at any data it
passes the data store as part of a
parameter into it um so you don't have
that mechanism that would argue that we
need to have both if people are going to
multiple but again as Joss said our
focus was ephemeral and and the high and
the high throughput constraints for the
rip the topology is if we ever wanted
the our pcs to be used in other data
stores I mean someone could also augment
them to add a target in theory group if
we wanted to change it to be able to use
another resource but if you're if you're
doing this stuff through conventional
data stores are probably not looking for
the high speed optimization anyways why
why should the RPC be any quicker than
an edit data on the dyno a datastore cuz
we haven't I don't even express any
constraints as to what happens I think
just maybe just a preference for some
implement implement technically meant
errors
maybe I prefer to use a PC another way
just a classical gain turncoat
something like that so I think the
recommendation would be to not define
the are pcs in the base rib model but to
allow those to be defined in another
model you know another RFC actually that
you know potentially augments the model
yeah yeah so so the traditional edit
config or sorry edit data and get data
would work maybe not the highest
performance but for you know it would
probably get you off the ground and
satisfy most these cases and then with
experience from discovered our proceeds
are faster you know we certainly could
augment them in yeah although deciding
deciding on our pcs or not I'm not sure
so much yang dr. thing I mean it's kind
of this community has to decide whether
whether there's some reason to have
those are pcs I think I'm King Arthur
urines comment where if you the RPC
would be locked down to specific data
store presumably and you know that's
unfortunate because people may want to
move around to other data stores so if
the base model did not define that our
PCs and the flexibility to move around
would be there but then the other you
know but then the other model module of
either but that's optional to implement
and of course we be targeted
specifically to your
okay smoke is the lead author sugar
you're talking to the yeah I know sorry
maybe before we move to your next topic
I just wanted to sort of live Joel was
talking about the priorities and one one
dynamic or one or thermo data store I
mean I think the implementation details
for how this is going to be done are
still in play and in my mind or at least
the way I was thinking about it there
might truly be a data store called des
ephemeral yes but but then there also
might be in addition to that there might
be something like Dias ephemeral one two
three four five yes where you want those
are representing panes of glass okay I
was gonna say that is actually an
implementation that doesn't really even
need to be in the draft right all right
don't give me that no I tourists would
have to define all this but but they di
tourist documents say you don't remember
it it doesn't come back if you want to
store it somewhere for information
that's fine and the device can store
anything it wants to know but the
important property is the current
property that the application can know
about is this is what's there if my
thing too gets overwritten
I get an error and I don't have to worry
about whether my thing will reappear by
magic at some later point in time
it's gone so there's no if as far as I
torus application to what is in
operation and there's only one did one
pane of glass for that yes yes I know
the reason I went to this slide was
actually that very question no no Kent
you might want to stay there the you
just the the the it's a fairly easy when
I said we had to discuss edit collision
and II did a fairly good job of
describing in the Attic collision
because this is what we're doing we're
having edit collisions right Ren and II
called it said on the stuff cause of
etic envisions the entity tag is used to
handle edit confusions the only thing
that's different with our two S's
requirements is if you have a collision
and you lose you have to send an event
it's it I don't know how to express that
in a datastore but that's part of the
what do we do to design it is really for
rest comp
edit condition I figured if we could get
the rest conf now so this entity tag can
be broken up between client ID and
priority or client reference ID I mean
Andy did you guys thought carefully
about that so that's why this is here so
does that help at all that is one of the
our truest sticking points that we've
long had but I thought in rest confident
so I'm walking up the whiteboard
I guess what I'm trying to draw here is
the subset of the diagram ephemeral
sorry they'll provide safes or draft and
in there it has an error says dynamic
disorders can feed into operational and
and so then you know you would might you
think that it would just be one dynamic
they swear I trust would define but I'm
proposing as an intimate I'm not you
know as an implementation detail you
might actually define let's say you have
eight panes of glass so define nine data
stores eight of them being the specific
one for you painting class one of them
being your resolution area right so so
then you would say okay so you know
however you want to do it use versa
priorities they're actually interacting
with these guys but then behind the
scenes there's logic that does the
distillation and then that gives us
what's the inherent operational the
point I was making is I don't care if
you store it in nine different data
stores or four hundred different data
stores but if a rights the stuff and get
success and then be rights the stuff and
get success and there's a collision and
a gets told your stuff is gone when B
goes and deletes his stuff a stuff
better not reappear don't reinstall now
normally if I see any of those it looks
to me like they're gonna intend to cause
me installation that's why I'm reacting
as long as it doesn't reinstall I don't
care what happened right so that could
be your implementation logic how you're
doing that so if you discover that
collision then some repair logic could
be to remove that in the values from the
data storage so it's gone and as long as
it's gone I don't care how it seemed
right
so going back to the other piece over
here that's why we have both the
definition of the Edit tag and we just
have to pick a number of bits the other
tag is is is currently I guess Joel just
another clarification on that I believe
you would also expect that even if
there's 8 or 9 data stores anything when
you read from operational has a single
origin yes one point is that this is not
actually just an implementation detail
you have to say that which is the larger
data store you want to write and do you
want to say that I write to ds1 ds2 ds3
first personally I would expect to be
writing to DSD
not the astadia one but in the only
reason I'm proposing that you might be
the writing to the 1 2 or 3 is because
otherwise you'd have to introduce
extensions to rest cough or you know how
do you specify the priorities there
would be some extension but it right but
if you map priorities on today's tours
then you kind of get it for free with
the existing protocols and that's the
reason why I'm suggesting I'm gonna go
back to number 1 edit e-tags can store
have the space inside of them to store a
client reference they if you break the
entity a bank just for a minute break
the number of bits in half half of its
stores or client ID half of its stores
priority right you know if the clients
different you prepare on the priority
bits if the clients the same you stay
you know if the priority bits are the
high order you can do the comparison
that that was the discussion with Andy
and in the creation of the entity tag is
if you're encoding that you can encode
it in a way that the priority it's
actually even better than that if you
but the priority in the high order bits
you just compare the two things and the
entity tells the real edit you can't
just serves as the tiebreaker because he
observed that if you really just make
these unique and you don't have a
collision you don't have to worry about
what if two things have the same prayer
effective priority and so we avoid that
and the point is I don't want to require
that people be writing to their
individual data stores that that would
be really a painful requirement I think
I understand your proposal and this
might be workable I think with within
the context of the ephemeral data store
you may be able to redefine the meaning
of the entity tag but I just want to
share with you that it's desirable that
the e-tag value for say running if you
only if your system only supports
running and it gets committed to
operational the e-tag value for running
an operational would hopefully be the
same so a client could very quickly look
of a single comparison of ETA comparison
see that actually you know my system is
completely the applied is in fact the
same as intended I would expect at least
in most cases I want to where there's
not a corner case that they see tag that
was used on the dist on a dynamic data
store would be the one you would see in
the operational the fact that
operational doesn't worry about
collision resolution doesn't cause us
any problem with saying but you can't
use that e tag you can still use that e
tag so I actually don't think it'll be
the same in operational because the
operational data store will undoubtedly
also have configuration from you know
traditional conventional data stores and
therefore the e-tag value will not be
the same as what it would be just for
the dynamic so my poem is actually
different I think in some of the I
terrace drafts I've read about how you
look at the dynamic configuration
through dynamic and it compares to the
stuff coming through attended and has
some sort priority resolution between
those two is that still intended so so
my question is how how is that going to
be handled
well I can't tell how it will be handled
but I know what the last time I was
working closely on that question you'd
have a configured value not an ephemeral
value that was the effective priority of
the config store and so you have
essentially a priority string that
applies to that and so you then compare
the priorities across those two that's
because otherwise you you get this
complete uncertainty about what's going
on so the idea is that yes that the
dynamic data store when you go to apply
something it checks was this created by
conveyance i CRI or similar conventional
config with a higher priority than you
the client has if so you lose you don't
get to do it okay because I'm not a
young person I cheated I said it should
look and it doesn't it can find the the
real data under the covers because if
it's already existing in dynamic then it
doesn't have to look at static because
if the new cling the dynamic thing then
byte under dynamic thing beat config
then transitivity saves money by Lac but
if there's nothing in dynamic then you
have to check that you're actually
allowed to override config dynamic one
to one this is just one example one to
100 and config to 101 to 250 configured
always overwrite right and which case
only if you had a dynamic case without a
config case with a clinton if you flip
it right then yeah and those were the
two cases the architecture tried to
write in
correct yes yep yep data in the ribs
well all the systems do have that but
you can change the next up for a route
of less I've even you could have a BGP
route learn and then you use I to RS to
install a route in the ribs that ever
rides the BGP route or you could
actually do it the other way around you
want to be able to do it the other way
around
which is you want to be able to have the
BGP route override unless the BGP route
goes away for some reason yes but that
examples a rib example where basically I
tore us the information compliment
dynamic data store is the equivalent of
a protocol routing protocol in terms of
it has an admin preference and competes
in the rib for what gets installed based
on the admin preference not based on any
right that's a local admin preference
kind of thing that's it can see that's a
config option on the router that's not
something that's done like on a per
route this just our ribs were I mean yes
it is no it is I don't think there's an
admin distance anywhere and that would
have to not be in the rib model that
would have to be in the config model
someplace right that would be something
that you can figure on the rib itself
can I can't go back to a question phone
what Supertop that yes you've you've
used a range of both those cases is is
not the case for the the conventional
configuration that just be a single
priority value for all that that's my
expectation I suppose somebody could
have an implementation where they had
multiple but I don't know why they would
ever do so so it's a single value and
you know and that's configured and you
know through the diamond crystal what I
value is views a simple checklist or
when you're writing to it whether you're
a bubble blow that buggy that's where
this resolution happens and what data
stores you see the various information
so I assume I assume that whatever is
written to the iOS protocol you're gonna
see if you do a get data on the on the
DS ephemeral even if in and this goes
back to my question earlier even though
that entry may not make it into
operational because config overrode it
or okay so then going back to that we
definitely need to be able to read the
the des ephemeral because you may get a
different value in there then you read
from operational and then intended would
only would only have what's configured
through conventional interfaces before a
resolution of the priorities is it is
this where do we define this different
split is that in the data store is that
in the addition to restaurant there's a
very simple answer but I couldn't quite
figure out where you'd say and our
normal standardized split between these
is this or does it need to be flexible
for customers sorry my first question
would be that where do you carry this
priority information rascal how do they
know what is the priority of that
specific added conflicts
request where is that the information
static give a table that is either
statically configured or updated through
something like radius because that's
secure from some server but it's free
off it's pre setup it's a priori
and so you know client ID the priority
you could simply have client and
priority but in case your client changes
the priority in the middle that would
this is my proposal this is Joel and I
have debated whether you just need a
client the idea where you need a
priority but we need to have that
discussion make a decision and go on but
see if your client if you have a client
ID and it always has the same priority
then you just keep the client the
question is if something dynamically
comes in and changes it what do you do
about the decision Joel says oh well the
next time someone comes in you have a
different priority I'm not as happy with
that I like story well the only the part
I like actually being explicit about the
priority and the client ID even though I
think the priority is stable for any
given client because the prior that lets
us use some nice clean value for client
ID that is not necessarily tied to the
assigned priority which changes if I
have a client it's got the same ID all
the time if the radius tells me what
priority it has and the server checks is
he using this priority he's allowed to
use if he does something with a priority
he's not allowed to use no now whether
we allow a range or the value he's
allowed to use is always one value
different debate back to the datastore
definition this is the entity tag we're
just that the cleanest way seemed to be
split the entity tag into two fields and
say for our chests it's going to have
these two fields or anyone's client
their number integer fields or something
where would you put that if we have it
first of all does it sound reasonable
and second of all where would we define
it is it in restaurant visit in the
datastore so I'm not entirely sure if it
is reasonable if you look to the HTTP
RFC and the definition of the e-tag and
what it means I'm pretty sure it has to
do with the representation of the states
regardless of how the state was written
how it came to be you know and so I'm
not entirely every time you enter to
take you write it when I talk to Andy
about if he said the others region will
split in half it's it's just a number
it's an opaque value if we then go
beyond that opaque value and say by the
way your opaque value has to several
paid values in it
no no what I'm trying to say though is
let's say there's an e-tag value the
data has been written by one client and
I need to eat tag value is calculated
using your approach and then let's say
another the system reboots so it's all
this wiped clean and another client
comes in a different priority and they
write the exact same data in in your
approach I'd be a different etag but I'm
thinking that it's actually the same
state it's the same data therefore I
wouldn't think that maybe I'd be the
same he tagged so that's the thing if we
defined if they have the same client ID
and they have it that's not what he's
asking he says if two different clients
client a wrote it at time one it's got
me tag claim they went away he died
client B came back and tried to write it
the exact same data in fact either
client B has a higher priority or he has
a lower priority if he has a lower
priority even though he's not changing
any of the data he'll actually get an
error if he has a higher priority he is
replacing it with the same content but
it gets his e tag because that's now
actually conceptually the data's change
it now has this priority associated with
it so I think it's reasonable to view it
as
it's not actually the same data even if
all of the fields look the same so I
think it's a reasonable access it's
bending the etags but I think it's a
reasonable stretch it is a stretch but
so are we talking about HTTP EDX
I think they handed out by the server on
their opaque and you shouldn't change a
mess around without you shouldn't know
below this this is the server that we're
telling it's gonna use this e-tec the
point gherkin is we're talking about
what the server is going to use as the
e-tag that he's associating with the
data so that it's a way it all it is is
a hack and frankly if you can give us
another hack and we don't care we know
it's a hack so we can associate the
priority and the client ID with the data
so I mean my understanding of the
architecture is you have a client coming
in the client is mapped to a priority
mm-hmm right and a priority is used once
you you merge conventional config
ephemeral conflict together
it's also your between ephemeral it's
not just with the merger between the
ephemeral clients so you have to
associate the priority with the data in
the ephemeral data store somehow and we
said we want to associate the client ID
with the data in the ephemeral store for
traceability so this is the suggestion
that we were given was to use the e tag
if you want to give us a different
suggestion I don't think anybody is hung
up we just need a way to associate this
with the data yeah we really just want
that's why this issues here if you just
want an example of how you'd like this
to do it and where to put it you know
whether it's an arrest cop or whether
it's an data store definition
so Anton's on the crystal dating thing
should go in the data stores
architecture draft because I think this
is specific to ITRs and not dynamic data
stores in general are down about the
protocol updates is a different question
but one thing on the e-tag that I'm
still confused about is that if the each
item interfere so effectively almost
like a hash what current data is then I
think you might not have enough
information you take your generating
here because it's not going to represent
a hash of given subtree of everything
that's below it
whereas isn't this he tagging I
represent the last thing was written to
that subtree so I think you might have
split it up maybe into if you do this
the scheme of having some priority some
client and some hash of the subtree
maybe my understanding is learn and risk
on the e-tec changes when the content of
the whole datastore changes all right
it's not a specific entry and some rip
that get changed by client XYZ so you
yeah and they you really have additional
metadata to be explicit about it need to
be explicit about when the mapping
happens and what happens if things
change so it's climbed to priority
mapping something that static he takes
won't work then we need something else
we really don't kick grateful because if
if we have to change and it has to be in
the data model or something then that
was it you know we should we should do
something if it goes there a metadata
model so I think this multi-headed
control is the only thing that's
preventing this work you know like this
is the effort that in
how to do the prioritization and how did
this is it right this is the only
multi-headed in the validation
well anyway I'd hold that for a second
but anyway I'm just saying that this is
the hardest part I mean if you were to
take it on as a working group item and
he spun on it for a whole month or three
months or whatever I mean that is this
this is the whole thing the word for
this if you selling straight through so
I mean you're asking that sort of on the
spot to come up with a different way we
just I'm saying check into it I would
say you know let's verify with HP RFC
the definition of e tag and what does it
really mean it's or you know does it
have a wiggle room in it just make sure
we're not violating it anyway
and and if we're not then I think you'd
be okay to continue it might be
difficult from implementations
perspective right because a generic
ruskov server you know you could imagine
the infrastructure and it's calculation
mechanism I guess it would have to be
able to do the same for the dynamic data
stores but then kind of prefix it with
no so does the same hashing calculation
and then and then it doesn't prefix look
you know client and it would just be a
little bit different from the
infrastructure perspective but Jurgen
point is me we read this tag those on a
isn't then rewriting the whole data
store it's just the one thing that's
being rewritten with an e-tank it
bubbles up to the root of the trees you
modify any tag somewhere low down the
tree some some leaf it'll modify that e
tag and everything up to the room much
with every time that's actually not a
that's actually probably a positive okay
because imagine somebody wrote some leaf
at certain priority yeah and somebody
went and tried to do rewrite the entire
data store yeah you would actually like
the fact that oh you're going to see the
same priority from the last guy who won
now there's a little weirdness we may
not see the highest priority it's not
going to produce the right result in any
case I don't I think we don't care how
it ripples up that's because it's not
gonna ripple up right no matter what we
do rippling up you're gonna have to
check all the subfields a container with
two leaves and client a rights leaf a
with priority one recline be rights leaf
you know be with priority to what does
the containers probably be we don't know
why we've defined things it's the
collision is on the individual fields so
you have to check the individual fields
no writing no my question is I know how
to calculate the e-tag assuming where to
go this approach I know how to capture
the e-tag Felipe I know how to calculate
the e-tag relief ii but then how do i
bubbled up to the container that's no I
think the answer it took yes this has to
get answered but I think that is not
going to break whether this works for
this or not because if it ripples up it
ripples up so there is a value that is
well defined so you know what you're
getting but that's not the value that's
used for the comparison to check the
things it will know it will almost never
tell somebody the right thing that they
want to know about is this whole
datastore still the same but divergent
think I just think you back to you
saying where to do where does this get
written to whatever the answer is I say
not the data source draft because it's
dynamic actually everyone's the reason I
think probably not the rest cough
updates an NDA because we want out to
progress quickly because we do that so I
think it's another another draft that's
augmenting risk off probably whatever
the solution won't make up those
solutions whether that's in iOS or in
net confess I don't know it's definitely
an ant or it's working group that's that
that's the discussion that a draft it's
really a risk of crap like they started
out writing this you know you're talking
about that this has to be an
augmentation I'm sorry should is this
are you know what I hear it okay okay
[Music]
so the word accession it says that that
is all semantics and syntax behaviors
including turning on and off protocols
and locks on exams in turn off so we
don't really
I
[Music]