well yes
it's losing one of you cross it says to
serve anymore
oh really it's okay I love corn or
Firefox that will protect their cell
suit our cheetah pet dog boots tonight I
will take the December to you okay yeah
few persons missing something don't eat
up you you like almonds
okay I'll own this one okay we'll be
crossing the blue press in the blue
seats in a minute
Jonathan volunteer subscribe thank you
and Nils will be taking notes as you saw
when you when you speak and comment
please use the microphone and please
state your name before for the notes our
agenda for today shall be very short
introduction a status update and the
rest meeting finalized ice peace
whatever it takes
so as you all know we've been working on
this particular item for quite some time
the doors are now locked okay yeah so
the door is enter only for the next two
hours yeah so this is something we do
want to finish now our last remaining
workgroup item and yeah we have a
proposal that we think could be working
to get the final issues clear in forward
your feedback on that and then let's do
what it takes any comments or questions
on the agenda okay working group status
um go sucked it was a fairness it's in
quite some time already with our theater
it is waiting for ice peace which one of
the reasons why we want to get ice
trickle ice just recently Bronco Blasco
ended we got a few comments and then got
an updated person there's all one
outstanding comment on the mailing list
that it seems at least one plus one was
carried so it seems a reasonable chains
please checkout them emailed on that on
the mailing list and comment accession
issues otherwise we'll be requesting
publication for trickle eyes shortly a
nice piece we will work in group last
call after next update so let's make
sure all the things we care about are in
the person that's gonna be published
after this meeting so the idea for
finalizing eyes there was a very
thorough review and quite a substantial
PR from Peter Thatcher which on the URL
you can see on the on the bates there
it was mostly editorial so it did not
actually change the behavior of ice but
since there were substantial editorial
changes we want to make sure those
changes didn't do any unintentional
changes on the behavior so that's why
the plan for today is to review the key
parts of the PR the PR is hundreds of
lines of code hundreds of lines of text
but um I did Mark twenty-something parts
that are maybe a bit more substantial
and the ideas go through one by one get
your feedback okay does this look okay
she can we go forward with this have it
merged and get this thing published and
then please let us know if there's any
other issues where that are not in the
current PR there's a few editorial fixes
that were discussed on the on the email
list on the next following slides but
this is the plan for today any questions
or comments on the plan okay so I guess
we gotta go then go forward with with
them a few first few issues crystal will
be presenting those and then we go with
the PR meanwhile please open your laptop
go to the URL you see on on that page on
the slide it's in the ice rink group 50
45 bits
github is the pull request 38 we will be
reviewing that change by change so
especially you in the back may not be
able to see all the text in the PR those
who want to be actively contributing on
this system please come to the front you
is for easier if you do see the text on
the on the slides and on-screen okay
with that crystal yes back in April I
sent an email to the list and I had gone
through all these different kind of
states and different kind of properties
we have in ice there's a lot of them you
have different state machines and
addition to that you have properties and
so on and so on and I was basically
wondering whether we really need all of
that there were some feedback about that
now we could change and change however
doing some of those changes would
require quite a bit of editorial rework
and since nothing was really broken that
the approach is really not not to do
that because you know it would be a kind
of optimization but it wouldn't really
it's too late for that the ones that you
see here on on on the on them on the
slide are things which are defined in
the draft but at least when I've been
looking through it seems like it's not
really needed used anywhere so so so so
I'm gonna focus on that for example
first we have the ice state the distaste
of ice itself we have running completed
in a fail and my question really here is
that do you really need is what is this
state machine used for I mean because
for example if if ice fails why should
you maintain it in a state machine fail
I mean you're just gonna quit doing ice
and I don't didn't really see any any
other usage of this I states my
suggestion was to do it do we really
need it for anything yeah I'm okay with
this I mean you're either doing ice or
you've done ice and either succeeds or
fails
that there is these states that might
need to be exposed in a in api's for
instance WebRTC one is probably a
question for that they can resolve more
than anything else I do think the other
the other states are like things like
frozen it is is kind of quarter the
whole thing yeah I come back to this one
thing I forgot to mention regarding this
I said also we had a PR where we
actually define ice session so now we
have a clear definition of an an ice
session e so we know when it starts and
when it ends so I think that's further
removes the need for actually having
this ice state because we know when it
starts and and how long it goes on janux
um what I recall and I think investin I
haven't read the latest version of this
but in 5245 there were certainly
normative behaviors as if something
happens when ice is still running you do
this if it's after it's completed it's
done that um I mean I don't know whether
that needs to because it's state or not
but that's that's sort of if we mean if
that's gone that's fine but if I mean
used I think that's being able to say
this is when it goes from running to
done is probably useful sure but I mean
if you think there could be something we
don't need to decide it nowhere we we go
back and look at it I mean we don't
let's not you know it's and again if we
can keep it it nothing's broken I just
remembered we have formative text on
that name still but we can look into
that I think what it was it's like when
you're running you don't send remote
candidates when you're completed you do
or something like that I don't remember
you know well okay yeah College X um
every all the implementations I know of
whether it's old ice new ice whatever
have this state variable that they
reflect up to higher level protocols
that has sort of these states in it and
so if you remove this and suddenly it
becomes no longer defined in the spec
what the state means or how the
implementations are supposed to set it
or whatever and it just it makes it much
harder for people I mean should the
implementations remove
the state out to other applications or
something it makes it a much more
difficult backwards-compatible plugin at
a software level if you remove this this
state variable and I imagine there's
lots of other specifications that use
the value of this state to report in
statistics and diagnostics information
sure so I mean let's keep it and there I
mean we have more important things than
let's I'm ok with it I'm just too for
these point I mean it's not like you can
remove the states from your code as a
result of this change then what I know
so anyway so can we get into a minute so
we have a document the other thing was
and for for for the checklists there are
actually two things we have a checklist
state with the running completed fail
and this is something that we do need
are not suggestion that we're gonna
remove that but we also have something
which is checklist status which is not a
state it's a separate you know attribute
frozen and active weather afraid
checklist is frozen active and there is
a definition what those mean but I
couldn't find again any procedures in
the spec actually using this information
for anything so if you're aware of
anything then so are you suggesting that
we merge the two states into one where
we have frozen action completely well
basically either that or we just remove
these sir frozen active and just keep
the state machine so the training
complete failed my understanding is that
we don't need the checklist status
because of the way that we've changed
this in support of trickle it's all Maya
I was just to say about to say that I'm
pretty sure in our implementation frozen
was basically a state before running so
and then there was no actors it's like
you go from frozen and then you anything
else
John I think he used to know there used
to be I mean I agree there could have
been one set of states but I also think
that when play we changed the unfreezing
algorithm checklists are no longer
frozen it's just the candidate person
exactly that's part of this emails
ya know these have no changes they don't
think I don't think there's any concept
of a checklist status of frozen anymore
so I can go away I think what we need to
do dump pending double-checking I think
they can go away now so I think we take
the approach to remove it obviously will
true full of check that we don't break
anything but again when I did a search
for for for leasing the draft the only
thing I could find this where we define
what it means but nowhere else could I
find any you know what it's used for so
yeah I want to further add to this that
if we keep that definition we also keep
some confusion and removing it should
help at least a little bit there will
always be the confusion that people have
between 50 to 45 and 50 to 45 beers
we're frozen has been moved but that
that's yeah and that's actually a
background of this because when we
really mean and when you read a spec
maybe it's not confusing both most of
their background is this is from
feedback coming from from the people
actually implementing this for example
and Taylor and annum Peter and Andy's
and these people they you know this is
confusing what what what do we needed
this for I mean SSO that's we're trying
to clean up okay yeah this is something
which came up Peter send an email also
to the to the list when you've at some
point you you calculate this priority
for for or for your candidate pairs and
the spec says that they have to be
unique but there is no scope what does
this unique mess mean and this is
something which comes up Rea often it's
something that for example is Jian
alright if a last call is gonna comment
on so we thought is and actually here I
talked about the the candidate pairs but
what we forgot to put here is that there
is also this thing called the local
preference which is also said to be
unique but we also need to define what
that uniqueness mean but I think it
could be basically the same thing I
think the suggestion that we've had or
on my understanding of it is that the
unique west uniqueness would be within
one checklist for one media stream so
for example you have audio and video
those are two different
dreams it's okay to have the same
priority values overlapping in those
because you're gonna treat them
differently anyway and this would this
would this would be during the ice
session so for example if you do a nice
restart you will recalculate everything
so it doesn't matter if if you get the
same value as you had previously so I I
agree and I think that actually if you
look at the again I don't know how much
of this you've kept but fifty to forty
fives
you know default ways of calculating
priorities they are implicitly unique to
within one checklist only although with
a slight weirdness for components for
some reason they're not there pair think
that makes it be different depending on
which component you're em but I'm not
sure that actually matters yes and also
what Peter asked what was whatever we
need to some say something about
components but I don't think you could
do it because each component is a
different candidate and and and and the
things the fact that they all have to be
unique covers components also so we
don't need to say anything about that
okay yeah I think one more thing we
don't have a slide on that and and I
think it's more editorial but I want to
bring it up anyway just to make sure
because I think it's it's important we
did add some time ago we have text now
saying that before I mean this was
regarding this removal of aggressive and
everything but what we now say is that
until you do nomination you can send
media on any candidate pair I mean
that's something we agreed on and that
and once you've done the nomination you
only use that pair to to send media what
I think it was Peter said that the spec
is a little unclear it now the way he
reads it that means that you need to use
this nomination for for the whole
session he wanted a clarification saying
sure you can do REME ination and then
you obviously you will end up using
another pair so that just adding one or
two sentences to to the
to clarify that if you do a Reno
mination you don't need to do our ice
restart in order to do really mination
you can read Amon 8 during the during
the ice session get all my on the same
topic um do we have any text which
basically says what to do with the
candidate pairs which you like after you
nominated I don't think I've a glee
remember that I was like going through
that and I didn't find anything and it
seems they're like implementations which
basically drop anything after they
nominated and there are other other
implementations which keep that stuff
around and like another interesting
question is what do you keep for example
consent running on these in case you
want to switch in case you want to re
nominate consent is of course if you if
you talk about this continuous consent
that's a course out of scope to answer
your question I don't think the draft
says anything what you do with the other
candidates for example you you must
discard them or anything so maybe that's
a further clarification we should say
that if you think or if you you know
want to be able to do a real amination
at some point you you should you know
keep them alive by by sending this you
know things I'll look into that but
that's a good good point okay exercise
we seem to have a functional mic now it
was in the front so we have a closer
look at that issue but otherwise I guess
we have these no closed we have a way
forward so next step would be to go some
key parts of the massive PR and I said
earlier I recommend coming a few seats
forward we're actually able to see the
screen or at least open the pool request
number 38 on your on your laptop on your
browser so you see what we're going
through here so there's a mention the
beginning there's a bunch of them I did
mark with idea Freud about ninety nine
session in the comments for those that I
think were more substantial that are
change the text you know more than two
subtle ways
but none of these are meant to impact
behavior it's also be at least we're not
changing in behavior just making it more
clear the first one being there the
definition of selected pair and select a
candidate you can see the old version in
the top and the new version in the
bottom and the key part there is is now
tend says sending media instead of
sending and receiving media so that was
the how we actually changed the behavior
what you can do with your valid
candidates already much earlier but seem
to be something else left left over here
but is this something that looks okay
and for all of these I'd like to get a
few notes in the audience when you have
ready you think it makes sense no
comment okay
no not John exam
I mean it's undecided about this I mean
certainly I believe 52:45 normative
behavior saying that you actually
especially you should throw away media
received on the non nominated pair after
after a nomination and I believe that
this was intended as to some degree uh
you know a weak security measure before
you had you know probably if you didn't
have proper you know SRTP running or you
know possibly a denial of service
prevention so I mean so I mean the
question is should you take any media
regardless you take any media from
unknown non selected candidate I think
one of the goals here is to be able to
latch on to the proper path and throw
away anything that's you know somebody
spamming you from you know just randomly
probing courts from an unknown port
that's true I wonder although if this
part hasn't actually impact on that
notice selected pair is the one and use
use for sending cause I guess this
implies that you right yeah and clearly
for saying this this isn't I mean this
isn't the normative
it says it but if we do say that this if
we do still say that and I don't
remember this this description should
reflect that so it maybe could be
clearer to say after nomination or
whatever but yeah so that's probably a
bit different because this is only about
the selected pair and selected candidate
only definition of that and uh and it
used to be sending a receiving but it
can be in the beginning different also
you would be receiving before you select
it yeah we said it's before selection
yes you should receive out any era which
you've got a valid check but an after
selection I think that he is you locked
down and although other people talk to
this I think this is the type of thing
that is like when I was reviewing it's
really hard to decide if this is a
normative change to the spec or not
without going through the whole spec you
can't just read ten lines here on a
slide inside what this means it's really
difficult on this one I looked at it and
I thought okay when you're doing DTLS
SRTP I don't I don't see any changes on
this which i think is probably what what
the people had in their mind when
they're thinking about this but if
you're doing s des we have instances
where we want to do a make before break
connection where we're handing something
off from so other wife like handing
things off across networks and we will
in start using a new transport when a
previous one is currently working for us
now we may be in wild violation of the
spec but nonetheless this is something
that I thought was allowed on the old
one Johnathan's yes but that's a
different ice session if the ice
discovers I have connectivity five
different ways which one I actually send
packets on should be my choice based on
the cost of using that interface and the
quality I get on the interface and we
monitor that and switch and this looks
like I can't switch anymore maybe I
don't like cats how I can do whatever
Swift once you go
selected you were supposed to use that
until you denied restore as I said we
may have been in violation respect but I
don't think we were Krister this is
actually one of the things I mentioned
during the slides that that there have
been a comment saying that we should
make it clear that you can re nominate
during this session without doing a nice
restart if you think that's wrong then
then we need to have a discussion about
that but but but but regarding this
specific text I mean I agree this is
something that for some reason I missed
and I'm little concerned because I think
also once you've done this election you
shouldn't be forced to being able to
receive media and on the other valid
candidates I mean that's the reason why
we do this election right so so now we
know where we're gonna send the media
now and I think there is even text about
that elsewhere in the document where we
talk about we have a we added at some
point the media handling section or
something like that which goes more into
detail about them okay so it seems we
need to have a closer look at the rest
of the text before approving this one or
should we simply reject this change well
I think projecting this if we have this
much confusion about what the spec means
I think we need to do more than reject
this change we need to come to consensus
on what it should mean and write it down
explicitly yeah and I'm sorry the other
point I would make is that what we know
said one of the points of of selection
is once we've done selection but once or
rather what selection has happened both
sides are then entitled modulo you know
leaving them up modulo packet reordering
and the wire to shut down all the non
selected candidates and you want to be
able to do that very you know often very
quickly you know to stop using resources
on the turn or turn off one of your
radios or whatever so that's the point
of selection they can turn everything
else off okay
this has been can the action item you
just wrote down have a name on it I
started by mr. can the action item
you're in the process of writing down
have a name on it that's a very good
idea um no I mean person to actually do
the fix
so I guess what it's from Peter Thatcher
the pull request origin I don't see
Peter remotely so okay Chris Turner is
gonna take this together with Peter and
I got okay yeah and we need to need to
speed up this yeah I guess my question
for the note taker is did you have it
clear in the notes what we thought the
issues were okay okay okay so this may
take a bit longer than we expected but
um other ones hopefully are a bit faster
so this one 8-inch ya then yeah because
the split view is can you guys read this
yeah
that's oh yeah I mean all of these are
editorial I accept the previous one is
supposed to be editorial but it turned
out to be bit more so this is about the
text you see we used to say you have a
single turn turn relay and now we're
saying can be can be multiple so all of
this text goes away but it's super hard
to actually so probably easier to open
on your laptop and take the details
there this is Ben I'm happy to ask for
the author's to just look at editorial
stuff and make their own decision I
don't and unless your things in there
they think have material impact on the
stack yeah yeah I mean the girls already
did look at this they look okay but
there's a risk just like the previous
one we thought it was completely
editorial but it turns out there are
more implications so there's something
about 200 other changes which are okay
fine fine fine fine fine these 20 were
like hmm I think it makes sense if
someone else has a look at this it might
be helpful than to say why it's
something we're looking at another
screen here is a dip so all of them
should have that comment Christa this
ash is the one comment I gave to Peter
when I saw this Peter I said you know
you should give some explanation why why
you have done this and that I mean if
it's just a spelling error that's fine
but but in this case where there's a lot
of text removed I think there should be
a little more in explanation exactly why
it's done because otherwise very
difficult to find out why it's done it
may be easier for him because when he's
doing is he has to speck in front of it
you know and he's reading it but we are
just seeing this true and that's why I
tried to comment on though there's a
more substantial ones like why I think
this change was most requested and this
was about the fact that now we can have
okay
so yeah we are
ah true true so these are could change
but no it's the same James the same
chains there's no similarity with you
oh yeah that's the one sure yeah yeah
actually sorry about that it was the
next one were the multiple turn servers
so this is the one I mentioned so we are
actually these chains is moving removing
a lot of text so how many if you had a
chance to have a look at this before the
session okay
come okay so what's your reflection on
this particle one my reflection I'm
reading this whole thing it was
completely indecipherable and I know
that that's useless like I feel like you
wouldn't did all this good work and I
should you know I mean all the auditory
everything is actually our tutorial and
writing it's like it's great I'm sure
like no complaints about what the any
authors do but having these all mix
together like this it's really hard to
pull apart and figure out what to do
with them so every single one of them I
was like you know what everywhere that
twenty lines of text was deleted I was
like you know it's going to take me an
hour to see what the impact of about
twenty line of text delete and by the
way I've always thought this document
had way too much text in two thirds of
it should be deleted so I should be
doing a little dance that that's finally
happening that someone's doing it but
you know in look like the previous one
that we even discussed it may be totally
editorial I'm not saying this a problem
with it even though it's not totally
editorial I'm a hundred percent
supportive but it's I'm not quite sure
how we're going to review all of these
and get them done yes each one of them
would be better as each one of them's
gonna have success like it first of all
if all the just purely obvious editorial
things were completely separate it would
be less daunting if nothing else true
and what if each one of the other things
was its own PR and we could evaluate
discuss itself so this PR is already the
improved one this one there was they
used to have also technical changes here
now they will remove so this would be
not purely editorial and then I did
another round where I tried to flag okay
like through your changes and more
substantial more substantial ones are
the ones we do now going through so
we're not gonna go through every step
change but I do agree it's a it took me
two afternoons to do I don't know like I
don't want to tell somebody
like I don't like your PR that probably
grossly improves this document right you
put a huge amount of work into but on
the other hand of the how I reviewed it
and think it's okay no and that is not
going to happen in the next two hours in
this meeting or any other way I mean
it's it's major how can we use these two
hours the most productive way that's a
great question because this is the best
plan we got I mean what we came up so
far but very open for it so my yeah why
I gue have con that this is like I also
gave up on reading so the whole thing
just reading this specific paragraph
we're looking at it sounds to me it's
just all justification of the shoot and
like why turn servers are expensive so
that that one seems okay to me to change
to this one sentence this has been part
of the reason I think we're doing this
painful exercise in here is because it
wasn't happening right we we not only do
we have a huge thing of a huge huge PR
that's hard to go through but we've got
all sorts of people that are busy on
everything and are having a lot of
energy for this so whatever it takes to
get that energy going and just get this
done everyone remember that done that's
right probably the most important bug in
this right now is it's not done but I'll
push a little bit back on that last one
when you go through iesg review and
naked shoulds are often questioned so
even and and I'm not saying that every
should should have a long detailed
explanation of why it's there but it's
generally good at least keeping Center
Institute that says why Hawaii you would
not when you might contemplate not
following this otherwise you'll get
a whole bunch of ways and this a must
questions and I asked you review so
maybe another question for consideration
for the group I haven't followed all the
updates and changes that have been done
to for 30 to 45 days over the last I
don't know how many years at this point
probably but I think it's worthwhile
considering
I mean how comfortable are people
putting in a bunch of editorial changes
at this very late stage I mean how well
motivated is it is it really necessary
is it worth the risk
do people actually want to do this is
there a need for doing this little man
um I guess it depends on whether you
want to have like new implementations on
the market or not because quite honestly
like I mean reading eyes is like without
any code base it's like super confusing
the only reason I can I can make it
through the thing is because I can
compare like running code with 50 actual
text and I know it's like working code
so I think there is a need to to to
clean it up yes and do you think that
the changes that are being proposed here
that they achieve their goal as I said I
didn't read that one PR all the way to
the to the end but but the things that
you looked at you know yeah I think
they're like they're improving things
what I've seen so far even I haven't
noticed anything which makes it worse
okay so you think this is justified we
should definitely go ahead and review
everything in here and make sure yes I
think it would if we if we only make the
spec like ten percent more compromising
that's a big improvement okay see more
or less said what I said except that I
understood it because I had seen
Jonathan Rosenberg's presentations back
when he was designing the thing okay
good and I could second that I mean I
think we should keep the bar high for
this late changes but if someone is
gonna do a PR I think it's a it's free
then makes it's much easier for us to us
and do the changes and everything so
those I would definitely consider a
random comment from the bushes saying
hey please but improve this I would be
scarred at this stage
sort of supporting that whole argument
too I think that if we do manage to make
the document success significantly
simpler to understand and comprehend our
odds of getting reasonable real review
on the real technical issues as we go
through this of all the changes we've
made over the past four years are much
higher so there might be some even
though we're going to do a bunch of pain
and suffering to make it more
comprehensible here there may be some
real good
that's about you maybe okay good point
um our way forward shall we go to the
next issue or do you think we have some
better way of tackling this okay so we
keep on continuing until we come up with
a better proposal and here I did note
that okay then Nega should be questioned
so it's probably good to give some sort
of justification for that shoot yeah
okay next issue okay so this was just
about the fact that earlier there was a
bunch of text saying okay you would be
only using single turn server and that
was removed did we reach a conclusion on
the previous one or you going back to
that one afterwards
okay so I guess the distance was
relatively straightforward okay my
little turn servers are fine
that's one aspect now but then again
I'll give you a 30 seconds to read it
through Krister says it's okay so look
for IDF 99
[Music]
okay those who finish reading reactions
it looked okay to me
Krister gives thumbs-up wondering I mean
one thing I'm wondering is the dropping
of the last sentence saying terms should
be well that I gave the wrong term
credential maybe that's more normative
behavior of turn not normative behavior
of ice so I shouldn't be specifying it
I'm just I feel like that's different
than the most of the thrust of it which
is only use one turn server yeah yeah I
think I recommend I agree with that
people should make sure that they've
thought about both things so so this
text seems to substantially change the
behavior in ways we don't want right
like if you learned multiple ones
through DNS rec I mean it removes all
the stuff about if you get several DNS
results back how you should handle it
but what we want in the draft is advice
to implement or so they don't screw this
up it's not that any implement or can do
a random thing and it's all fine so so
if I return a DNS address that has a
hundred and fifty records for different
geo regions of the world and I get 150
candidates sent to me you know from some
other side from an implementation that
that didn't follow this advice for
removing I'm going to be really sad so I
don't know I think that that text with
those shoulds are necessary parts of the
protocol and should not be removed
however these suits leads to a single
torrent server which we we moved away
from we would not allow multiple turn
servers
yeah but each one of those turn servers
has multiple IP addresses and you still
don't want to return a different
candidate for every single IP address
that they have yeah I guess the point is
that even if you're I mean even if you
won't use multiple turnovers as such you
still want to make the same set of
choices both in terms of the names and
the IP
dresses for every candidate in every
every checklist is it I mean basically
you know don't say I think yes okay yes
I can use the turns over over here in
the Hertz or over there
but if threats are over there has five
IP addresses I want to make the same
choice for every finding I make on that
print server so maybe this section needs
to be clarified newtonia so reality is
at least from from WebRTC is that people
tend to put in like a whole list of
turns servers typically people who don't
know what they're doing they basically
will provide like 15 turn servers and
then they they think that makes net
reversal better than if they provide
only a single turn server so there's
definitely room for improvement here and
I mean like on the other hand like
WebRTC clearly allows you to provide
more than one turn server or more than
one stand server but yeah I agree with
Khan that on the other hand like we have
put in some warnings basically saying
like providing more than 10 turn service
is probably not going to help you I mean
like if you can't reach like the first
three it's like that it doesn't help you
right so I think it's the the the
limitation for a single one should go
but I guess there should be then some
advice on like okay there should be some
upper threshold or whatever yeah so
Jonathan I mean I guess it should say
it's a only use multiples of these if
you have some meaningful reason to
believe they have different network
characteristics you said I mean like you
know if you believe there and you know
different you know like ones in your DMZ
and ones on the public network or you
know one is TCP one is UDP or whatever
and then the other thing we do still
want to say is once you've picked what a
turn server makes the same you know well
once you've picked a set of turn servers
use that same set of turn servers across
all your checklists don't make different
choices for different checklists and you
know when you do DNS right we do SRB and
DNS resolution yes or VN a resolution
pick the same actual IP address across
all of them don't spread them across
multiple but don't spread them across
the DNS load okay say that text I don't
know I was about to ask you to update
the PR but if you can formulate
something along those lines that would
be very helpful can i yeah I mean I hope
I'm pretty hope to Alou in this session
before two hours has gone but it doesn't
look very promising right now but if you
manage to do that yes you'll have a time
after session just one thing I was gonna
mention on my belief of why people and
WebRTC are putting in these twenty a
list of 20 or whatever is they don't
really own 20 or have credentials to use
the 20 per se they're run by other
people and there's basically using other
people's bandwidth and often those get
turned off so they just keep adding more
that's on and off so it might be that
really this is probably outside of the
ice spec but maybe WebRTC spec that it's
like look if you have a list of 20 like
try and see which ones seem to be valid
and up and that you have valid
credentials to authenticate with and
then throw out any that don't meet that
requirement before you even pass the
list into the ice-sub system and that
might actually reduce out some of the
problems that yields but that's that's
only going to solve your turn server
problem of stun you don't have any
credentials and they're people do the
same thing
they provide like 20 stun service and
they think it's like going to make the
world better
yeah I mean there's like they're like
famous lists on github with like free
stand servers right and people basically
take the whole list and dump it into
their like JavaScript application expect
wonders okay but it is something we want
to have an ice pack or leave it out
thought that kind of recommend it it's
not a part you see look I think it's
mostly out but what I'm saying is that
the thing that's causing us um there's
something happening in the real world do
the implementers that is causing us
grief here and so we might want to try
and put some text in that tries to
reduce that grief maybe that's not
possible maybe this is wrong spec
whatever I don't care I'm on my real
issue is that I don't I I think we can't
remove this because a bunch of the
normative behavior nothing to do with
the list of turn servers just to do with
the list of IP addresses for a single
DNS thing we still need advice though so
just to clarify what Colin and Jonathan
said before so a lot of people put URLs
and some of them have the same
characteristics I don't know if any
document outside is gonna say like you
have 20 URLs they're different apart
from looking at them and saying they're
different but if some provide turn TCP
Canada or run over 443 in some
situations they would basically be
better if you can't find a UDP route of
it and so definitely need more text here
for solving those kind of situations and
I such as you can take a PR of that I
think that is yes no Neil's question to
current like I mean the first sentence
of that paragraph we're looking at right
now reads to me as if this specification
says you can only use one single stun
and order and server ever and I think
that one
I agree should go
guess we should be no it was already in
the change that their senior will go
well the first sentence do you agree on
that limitation should okay and next one
criterion for selecting typing local
preference values there was a whole
bunch of text about VPN in their faces
and when when to use one etc that was
substantially reduced
I don't know it's not just cuz the
dual-stack fairness covers that now
because if all that if that's all been
superseded by dualistic fairness then we
can remove this that's good we'll a
reference that would probably sell the
issue yes
okay and I guess that's a general
question yeah the I suspect yeah it is
too long whatever you can do shorten
makes a lot of sense but it's parsley
long because there is helpful in quotes
informative text when you would you use
a VPN and such I guess it's about where
do you want to put the balance I have no
idea I can live with this other way but
I mean it you know someone previous is
geez I don't know about the current one
would have said you said you effectively
have a foot here that tells you which
value you should use with no advice or
reasons about why you might use a
different like we're deleting all the
advice that covers why it's a should and
why we leave flexibility to people and
how they might choose really I can live
with deleting all that device just wrote
there was a fairness is referenced here
so maybe maybe that's already covered so
I would originally cuz it to me it's
saying right okay it's kind of useful to
actually be more keep it but let's check
with classic fairness I think we're very
good with that I don't think fairness
explains why those values are like that
I think it explains how you deal with
the v4 v6 specific instance not why you
might make a VPN candidate lower than a
non VP GM candidate and vice versa so
but it comes a question of do you think
people need to understand why they
should set these numbers that way or do
you think they will you know should
always just do them exactly like that in
which case we can change them I should
too a must but if you're gonna leave it
as a should maybe you should have some
advice there about how you change the
numbers I don't think so so pen any
advice general guidance here from an ad
/i use t point of view just to try to
set a precedent as well for some of the
subsequent this has been famous before
right I mean if we're gonna say
shouldn't something like this you're
going to get the oil they're not a must
question that doesn't necessarily you
mean
you know 10 sentences or whatever over
here unless you think you do but it's
helpful to have something that describes
what sort of variation from that should
you are being is being contemplated so
yeah I mean the other thing I wanna say
is the existing text I think does not
take dual stack fairness into a couch
and you know would need to be changed
regardless because most like fairness
changes those recommendations so in
trying to deal with objections we might
get and still make this easy and be
quick and easy to edit my suggestion
would be we keep roughly the green text
we have including a reference to dual
stack fairness that you know is
normative and at the same time we take
all the other text and we stuff it into
an appendix and we put a little note
here other considerations for thinking
about setting these numbers can be found
in appendix of foo and we never have to
read the appendix again and people won't
get confused with it when they're
reading the real thing I like that I'm
thinking about deleted explanatory text
as an appendix for a lot of --dress
might be a good president okay that
sounds like something we agree on
so let's do that and move on so yes we
move the external text text to appendix
keep only the minimal that if that was
part of that change yeah okay yes and I
reference the appendix
I guess the same should apply here lot
lots of helpful Tech's but maybe
appendix material
okay any more comments on this one
let's see so here it's just removing
perhaps redundant details of that so
much part
it's I thought I could put a comment in
but I think all these are good I think
they're a editorial and be help okay
but in general it's improving but that's
not true
okay let's say looks good
Oh
okay then we move on
so then so yes so here's that Walmart
text
really addressed that's right
I think clearly IP address in the new
text is wrong I think he means address
family and I think we help thought we
have nat64 recommendations now also good
question I don't know if we have next
course I think I thought why will I we
discuss having that six four
recommendations they can remember that
and didn't ever get in that's making all
of that
okay any other comments or
I see common very focused I assume he's
reading it okay so for the notes it's
okay
[Laughter]
okay so here it's equivalent pants order
I like that
okay
Jonathan gave thumbs up from number
eight Cullen comes up I see note comes
down going first
a second approved
okay I just remove redundant part and
made it shorter sounds good
so comes up from Jonathan
so the original text had that little
clause unless the sending agent detects
that the candidate pair does not work
and that seemed to be at the essence one
things we were arguing about earlier I
think we still sort of neat that text
let me rephrase that I have no idea if
we need that text not I think that that
is a non editorial change but an actual
significant change Chris I probably need
a text but I wonder whether we we need
it there I mean if we're gonna talk
about this real amination and stuff like
that maybe we should have a separate
section for that and there we can
describe why one would do this and there
we can talk about you know that
candidates no longer work to have it in
one place because I think or already
should at least be in the media handling
section because this is this is really
media handling so I don't think it
should be here these talks about how you
do nomination or then we need to put
everything here but I think it would be
good to have it in one place okay I
guess you will be able to do such a PR
it's very short kind well Jonathan X I
mean I think this is a bigger I don't
think this is actually very well
specified anywhere what you do if you
get a nomination on a pair that doesn't
work that's what I mean you'd have to I
mean somehow I mean I get what it would
have to be your peer is doing aggressive
nomination and you've got one like high
activity that's the only way it could
happen yeah right yeah this isn't clear
if this is if that Clause applies to set
of genomic set it to set it
our said it later that's very much not
clear at all either so I think yeah this
party should be media handling and I
mean yeah I mean sort of the your peers
with aggressive domination your
checklist your check failed case I guess
we don't have got gressive anymore
well I accept it you're still talking
before you could still be talking to 25
ah okay legacy devices but I believe
even those want to use aggressive cause
you have the ice tool option you disable
the accuracy with that so you don't have
a receipt okay
[Music]
well for those who violate the spec
maybe we don't have to be that's the
theory is that you'll never get a
nomination for something where you don't
have bi-directional connectivity I mean
ice tunnel s I have seen things where
yeah so I mean I agree what Chris was
saying this would be better somewhere
else in this back maps Hillary was here
he may say I only removed this because
it's duplicated somewhere else in the
spec so it's fine right so this change
may be fine but this case does happen on
a regular basis where you have a
firewall that allows stun through but
blocks RTP that's I mean there's other
case that can happen too but it's going
to continue to happen with things that
are doing everything new okay so you're
saying we should have some normative
text on this in the media hunting and
that's you cover it somewhere in the
spec we should deal with this and we may
in fact already deal with it okay and
I'm just not seeing it and somewhere and
in this but in this particular part we
can remove those details because they're
gonna be disgusting elsewhere just to be
precise what you just said Colin
basically means that you would nominate
this because none works and then we do
it in the media handling section
basically if you discover any point
during media handling that the pair is
not working any more than 2x yeah okay
so again this is related to what we
talked about the the the real emanation
because even if it would keep the
existing text okay so what does this
what happens if this happens because
there it doesn't describe
he said should be used for media unless
this and that that the pair doesn't work
okay so the pair doesn't work what I do
then so we still need to to have that
text and I'm but I think that texture
shouldn't be here it should be either we
hear in the media as has been suggested
or in a really it's difficult area you
need to look at the draft and see where
it fits but but but the text should be
somewhere but as far as this change is
concerned I'm okay with it
okay so did I even read the
consciousness correctly so we'll merge
this proposal but we make sure that
takes covering this case is elsewhere
given this is one of the things that
probably lots of implementations do and
I don't think the chrome implementation
actually does like I'm okay with the
urging this as long as it gets put
somewhere else but what I don't want to
have happen is this gets removed and
then people decide not to add anything
else later like this text needs you know
what you said yeah for sure
but if that translates to we don't add
any text anywhere else later then I
don't think it should be merged
okay okay and let's hope we have a short
slot at the end of the session three
guys get together and bash some text on
the Reno mination which we could be
merging in a week or so spec so that
this doesn't keep tracking us okay we're
almost halfway through so here's the
text that apparently is equivalent
yes it looks okay to me
it changes the terminology that it's
using from use candidate the nominated
flag but they are essentially the same
okay so but of course we should only so
of course we should only we should have
a bit of the bar that putting changes
that only improve at least with a big
margin even I mean it's not gonna be
perfect but it should be improving at
least marginally because there's always
a risk that we it screw up for neo
mariya
when does the controlled agent set the
nominated flag
I thought that's the controlling agent
oh the flick on the flag on the Paris
set when you receive a yeah basically so
the idea is that you have to order
something to have the nominated flag in
for the control that you have to receive
Lee use candidate and successfully
compete the track I'm not there so
that's I think that's what this is hangs
yeah flag is you know it is the it is
selected pair not every call okay so I
think we're gonna merge this change
so here bit of text about third particle
control was was removed
she's been number 11
Krister I'm okay with this change but
but I have a feeling that this is
something for example wherewhere is G
could could ask you know can it could
you give an example of such so maybe we
could say in certain usages and then eg
third party control or something like
that just previous
so merge with one change putting this
one example there shortly okay I see
nothing
thank you
oh yeah this was the bigger one still
editorial but it's up I'd say a lot of
text I'm not gonna be giving it on the
screen for you to retreat who had time
to read this before the meeting the
whole this then number 12
yeah the one which I'm working to take
offline I mentioned about this in the
email but you may want to read this
before the session so who had a chance
so I had a really a couple of times I
think it was okay but considering our
discussed in the previous things I
thought were okay I'd love to have
someone else have a look at it too so
for this I what I would suggest we take
it later but get a volunteer or two to
have a look at it it's gonna take like
five minutes but I have to read a couple
of times so who would volunteer to read
this and make a comment okay Krister
will do it
Jonathan thank you
there is a what's a github ID and you're
not in them repo yet anyway yeah you're
not a committer yet
so anyway maybe for next round we'll do
that
is that the one
okay so it takes a while okay so okay so
let's go forward
so here again looks at a big change but
um say redundant text maybe what was it
wasn't it not needed number 13 in the
pull request
so um I was just looking back at the
previous one I I do not think its
editorial I don't think it's wrong
change its necessarily but I think it
changes the way you select the IP
addresses I don't I probably you know it
might be worth pulling that out in a PR
itself and trying to break it into some
bite-sized chunks or something like that
but it seems to be I think I think the
old texts and the new texts would in
many canes at least some cases result in
different traffic over the wire
okay thanks and back to number 13 any
comments here
it's the station
good question
i'm nitsana I'm confused about the new
text because it says something about the
the after all minions using that
candidate per our completed so is that
is that meant to say the ice is
completed or like the whole stream is
like gone like I'm cheering down the ice
session of that pair like it says like a
full agent should not stop sending not
stop sending checks and responses from a
candidate until three seconds after all
media streams using that Kennedy are
completed is that the reference to the
to one of the ice states or is that like
does that mean three seconds after my
application on top of it has stopped
using it I so I think this might be a
little bit confusion - between how
WebRTC uses ice and how other things
might use ice so in WebRTC the consent
checks would keep going until three
seconds after all media had stopped
using but I think the ice back in other
uses of it we're just going to use ice
to set this up and you're not doing
consent checks then it would be once
you've got it set up you'd stop and when
ice is completed not when the media is
completed so my guess here is this text
is though matches WebRTC implementations
of ice is wrong for the ice pack
cursor I think the text is confusing
because it talks about all media streams
using that candidate I mean one
candidate is normally used only by one
media stream unless you're bundling much
so so I think that yeah oh yeah sure
okay okay yeah I I smear the stream here
so I think this takes this a little
confusing maybe he meant something else
maybe him and I mean there is no ice
there is no there is no pare state
called completed right so he's probably
talking about the ice state here right
but but yeah so so so and I guess these
three seconds has something to do with
if there is some media on the wire that
you can do something about that but but
but I think that it's confusing it needs
me more clear what what he's talking
about part of the three seconds was to
in handle the to handle aggressive part
of it was just to make sure that you
know other checks get you know responded
to rather than having to wait for the
timeout but yeah I think this the all
media stream is unless you mean you're
doing something clever like we're using
candidates across you know ice sessions
that's fine that's your problem but yeah
I think that all media streams there is
confusing so other than that I think
what you know until the checklist until
the state of the I think it's I guess
the old text yeah I think that is the
question is when the session goes to
complete it or when the checklist is
complete because that's also unclear
okay so should we keep the old fixed um
no yeah yeah I think it
Carlina say for all peers for media
streams using these candidates oh I
think it's trying to handle forking here
also yeah that's probably what's very
easily uh missing here yes
so safer to keep the old text maybe I
know something wrong with the old
texture was it just wordy wordy okay I
suppose a vertex but you know also need
to worry about 14 devil
I started need to worry about it's the
same issue
it was requests 38 and hit split you I
think the old text is also has confusing
bits and pieces in it so I would think
we should try to find a better text John
isn't point out the the completed
there's also not like super clear okay
so Krista will you take a stab at this
okay shall we move the next one Cullen
looks slightly concerned okay so if you
look for one of the keywords in the
comments you see on the screen you
should be able to find them so as you
can see in the screen there previously
valid a fair part was was removed from
the ice crystals because it seems
redundant
move
Jonathan I mean I think the using the
preview I mean the the previously
validated pair I agree is a little bit
but I mean I think using the previous
session so you would rather use previous
session yeah then previous selected pair
now this is all so confusing here
because we're using you have ice session
area media session which is a little
unfortunate the capture right what do
you mean so previous lesson is the
previous if I did there
it's doesn't know that doesn't actually
work why success using a previous media
concurrently to be sent to the previous
body okay I using previously for using a
previous reason for using the previous
sessions okay now the tricky thing here
of course is that it's distinguishing
previous session versus a new media
session which is might be a terminology
issue we distinguish you guys session
from media session I would have to check
because we definitely need to investment
make sure we do we definitely had a word
for you know of you know the entire you
know sequence of ice sessions which i
think is what he's using media session
here for it's a little unfortunate if
that's both session but i would guess
it's a we work quite hard to get these
things explicitly defined that we're not
but we would have to check it to make
sure we have a word for that and make
sure this is using the right word for it
yes cursor remember we had a discussion
about this at some point because we
wanted to have it mainly need a little
more because i think using previous
session sees is confusing if you talk
about previous you talk about the
previous i session it should be using
the you know characteristics of the
previous ice session or something now
say
especially since the text talks about
both ice session and media session so so
when you say previous session what do
you mean do you mean the media session
decison
so maybe these this leads needs a little
this may be one of those things that
yeah we do need to clarify it but but
the way he has suggested it's not clear
enough okay so is that now captured
there so using previous session instead
of using previous valid pair and we make
sure that those different sessions are
explicitly okay
number 15 again details removed creator
particle control and there's a change
okay yeah so ice restarts
I think this is a little more than
editorial maybe because I don't really
understand he says may do I what would
the other way be of doing this I mean if
you want to determine it also really
really terminated yeah so I think I
think what it's trying to get it both
words are trying to get across which I
don't think we quite event word for is
you know the only way you met the only
way you can do this is this you cannot
do this other than by doing a nice
crease tart so I mean that's why the if
you want to you must you know I mean I
agree it's a little bit of a weird
formulation but I'm not sure what's if
there's a better formulation for you
know saying you know saying you you I
mean maybe you may you may do it by this
you must not I'll do it other than by
doing this Krista we can say the
following actions or use cases whatever
requires a nice restart and then we sit
I mean we don't need to add the master
may for each of them we have it in the
beginning and and then we just list
their case Neil's the other thing which
I don't like about the new text is like
if an agent wants want to change its
implementation level I have no idea what
implementation love means for reverses
light okay that's that's defined okay
okay I think to match the meaning of the
old text we need to change the maze in
the new text to muss but I don't think
we need any change other than that let's
train you on board with that there's no
oh this one
it must restart ice to do so
okay
changing mayst musts does that sound
like a good solution jargon yeah
okay any other comments on this moving
forward number 16 again details really
okay but I slightly still in the latest
right well that yeah moving and then
yeah make make it make it explicit where
was it
okay
so again Peter thinks it's equivalent I
think so too
sorry
uh Johnson onyx I think if I if Peter is
correct that that is indeed that this is
indeed a redundant definition of sort of
selected pair then yes except that
there's a verb missing in the second
second sentence this blog over that
candidate media is forwarded
okay otherwise looks good
Crysta : yes okay I'm still iffy on this
why it seems like a lot of I'll think
about more but okay it's not an obvious
to me at all why it's equivalent okay
can we get on deadline what he was
attack on this like in a week or today
okay oh yeah so I guess what we will do
probably will make a version anyway this
week and then we can file comments on
that we can do that is Chris we can do
that Peter but one thing to remember
also is that you can't just to emerge
because I think he has done the PR based
on not the latest version so there are
some there are some merge conflicts that
we will need to take care of so so but
of course if theater can do it fine but
actually this PR should be against
master I mean should be automatically
updated so it should be manageable
there's no conflicts at the moment are
you destro okay then it wasn't
earlier it was merciful
okay
okay well here Peter apparently the
details back so that was after my
comment that seems to be now equivalent
to the older one so we can skip that
number eighteen
so here had some text about RTP relate
things and I tend to agree maybe in the
eye space back we shouldn't have too
much RTP where things cost or some
better handle in the ICSD aircraft so
this is about the jitter control
Jones lacks I mean I think that I agree
maybe you don't want iced arch beast
bait specific stuff explicitly but I
think your might need something like
remor generic you know you know any you
know but whatever for TOEFL you're
running over this needs to reconsider
its you know like your transport level
so like obviously your congestion
control and jitter or dedication things
like that because you know SCTP should
you know needs to you know you know
needs to redo its congestion control and
you know whatever whatever protocol
you're doing over here you know you have
it's a new network path you should reset
your now any network path out of
patience you're using that follows so
what do you such as something shorter
thanks then what was that in previous
one few sentences that okay take care of
these things or what do you recommend
ah sorry you asking me to write
something at the mic no no I'm asking
like do you think we should keep that
keep it fixed no I think we should have
a shorter text so you know that sort of
generically talks about you know
characteristics of your network no
unless we really need the this advice is
very important to people that are
implementing the overall system yes it's
unfortunate it's in this spec but unless
there's another spec we can reference
from this one it needs to stay in this
spec you know and you know ice was
developed and is primarily used for RTP
and this is a very complicated part of
how ice screws up RTP and you need to
interact with the two so I think it's
quite reasonable for this document to
talk about how ice works with RTP
particularly when it means you have to
do something different with RTP than
you'd normally do if you weren't using
ice I don't care if it's an appendix but
my recommendation would be the best TP
because that one has a lot of hard TB
details already on we're referencing it
here say which one again the IC s DB so
nothing to do that suits me there's
about media handling fair enough I mean
maybe it should be in New York to piece
back I'd be willing to take that but I
mean it just like we saw RTP spec
whatever that is
right that's why it's here okay so you
would recommend to keep the whole list
maybe somebody can rephrase it a little
bit but I think that all the advice that
has given in that text every piece of it
is needed okay then there is your way -
yeah this is Ben I heard someone say
appendix if normative text here please
don't move normative takes to an
appendix this one is not normal
oh yeah really this text should have
more normative tech you know it should
have more capitalized words in it not
like this is stuff that you really need
to get right if you want to do a good
implementation so I mean I'm okay so and
if we add more normative ministère we
shouldn't put it the appendix so what
I'm reading here is that we're gonna
actually keep this here and Cohen will
you recommend what should be stronger
language or are you okay with the
current one I'm fine with the current
one but I'm one of these people who
believes that if I write text like it's
super important that you set the X bit
to Y and the protocol will totally fail
if you don't set it to Y that that is
normative text and does not require the
word must in caps for things to be
normative text so I'm fine with this as
it is but many people seem to feel that
if the word must isn't there it's not
normative so I'm on the fence and this
paragraph partly because whatever at the
top of the paragraph is something that
each system needs to each our DP system
needs to cater for that irrespective
wise so and the second bit which is
about the marker bit I think some of the
text already exists in RFC 3550 about
the talkSPORT the
question is is this guidance really
needed in ice for it if you have a
reference we're more than happy to use
that well it does say 3550 recommends
the MA Quebec to be said because at
Oxford and I think that that is probably
already in 3550 in the first part which
says that you know if parts change the
jitter buffer will need to be adapted is
something that every 35 50
implementation kind of takes care of
okay let's try to keep it all let's try
to keep discussing on the microphone so
we have it recorded so what I'm saying
is that the first paragraph it talks
about the fact that the jitter buffer
would need to be adapted because the ice
candidate or Paris might change is kind
of trivial like systems do that
automatically they adapt okay I guess
the easiest way for us here is we just
keep this but that makes sense
and unless someone feels some chip words
should be changed let's just keep it as
such I seen nodding okay excellent go do
that
okay nineteen oh yeah
excellent those number twenty RTP
details so so we'll keep this
and the last one Nathan must not that's
maybe
sounds reasonable change Johnathan's I
mean the it sounds reasonable except
that elsewhere it says you don't change
roles on a restart regardless so we were
looking at that in the previous thing on
the ice restart so now of course
probably he's worried here about the
third party call control case where it
said where the restart is actually
pointing at an entirely new entity which
has no idea what the previous tie
breaker was so I don't know what to do
with this well I think maybe we should
ask whether there was a real reason
motivating this change it's definitely
an not an editorial change and it
definitely does not work with old
versions of ice I mean I don't think we
can really do this because if some old
version of ice changes it on you and
you're like whoa I'm gonna throw you out
now because you changed something that
says must not it's not really compatible
okay so it's not just alignment it is
actually a change that's what yeah
that's gonna be painful here on the
screen if you find it on your laptop it
they ceased
well I think the other section says you
must not change your type you must not
change your tiebreaker value after
you've washed a tie or after you are
after you've won a tie well you know it
says must on so way after you so I think
that's not the same thing as must not
change on a restart okay so we should
not make the change you should not make
the change going back to actually 50 to
45 it says an iced restart causes a new
selections of roles and tie breakers
like very very simple it's one of the
few clear statements in the whole spec
[Music]
Krista I thought we said earlier when we
thought what's the difference between a
nice restart and a new media stream was
that we said that the roles don't change
to your nice restart yeah but I think
what that saying is that the roles at
the start of the restart if you will but
there still might be but a few but
you're pure still might have gotten
confused and so you still need to do the
tie breaker mechanism well this is where
I think what this is really saying is
this problem you know it's less clear
because we've done the separation of STP
but you know the controlling role is
based on who the original offer was not
who the card offer is I think that's
although I think that's what that's
trying to say so
you mean basically if so your default
assumption is if I was controlling
before I'm still controlling but still
have to be the tiebreaker if the other
guys Dixie's control them anyway
because it might be three PCC or
something
okay okay so but sort of for this
particle change we are not going to do
it right correct
yes okay and let's double check that
it's it's actually aligned but this
seems to be something we shouldn't be
doing
okay so that was last one of the ones
that I flagged in the PR there's plenty
of more if you are interested I'm going
through but they are maybe less
substantial so since we have ten minutes
let me throw a bomb which is some bits
do we want to use it have we discussed
that before or do we come to consensus
on it in the main difference is sha-256
rather than shot one for our purposes
good question I don't I don't remember
being six rather than sha-1 for the
Phenom it sounds like a kind of
important change it does yeah and we did
then the backup compatibility is you
know well I should have to define that I
don't see how we could take ask the is
GM to approve a document yeah and have
crypto agility to shot to 36 at this
point in time I mean Fleming you you
know more about this may be a new same
page like okay I was my first reaction
was like I never want all of our stuff
to always have to upgrade to the latest
version of everything if we don't need
it we don't want don't use it but on
this one it seems unfortunately is G is
gonna punt it back to us if we don't do
it would be sort of my guess yeah I got
a same feeling then it's it's late late
in the game but I guess something we
have to do and well those familiar with
that would be how substantial the
exchange yes I agree with Colin that
it's it's hard to get something through
without agility there if for some reason
people decide not to make sure the
security considerations at least Mitch
the decision y-yeah I guess sha-1 starts
with broken okay we've had graphs get
through that would say yeah we're using
sha-1 but we're using it in this kind of
okay way in and it's too much trouble to
change right now we'll change the time
of the future and and that's okay as
long as it's clear and the security
considerations maybe Chris be even
better be agile better suggestin
ask the security ad and have him write a
paragraph of text for the Security
section excellent idea
thank you : okay
Krister can you take an action on that
yeah well we're right in the notes
Neil's if we capture that in the notes
yes okay any other bombs anyone wants to
throw I mean this is really the last
moment we I hope we won't be needing
many more well any more sessions on ice
peace face-to-face will this can be
publication week was done by Singapore
do so so Alan issues raised a long time
ago was does the new timing work with
something doing the old like doesn't
does something doing this new thing
actually Interop reasonably well with
something doing the old thing and have
we convinced ourselves that's true I
think it's the real question yeah I mean
that's that's been our goal and best of
my knowledge we've I haven't seen
changes that at least in my head probe
it but no I haven't been fermented a new
one so Neos looking forward to it that
is one of the nagas idea so I I'm not
raising an issue here but I have I I am
concerned about the timing changing how
that
the ordering and timing changes and
whether that will actually allow it to
find connectivity in a bunch of use
cases I've not gone what Dan York did
long ago of work through the exact flows
to figure out if there's a problem or
not but I sort of I'm not volunteering
to go do that but sure wish somebody had
please raise up on the mailing list
just running email describing the issue
that someone who's maybe implementing
this could have a look at it thank you
come on okay
anything else and I think I promised
yeah we may be able to and early yes we
did almost five minutes ago and Jonathan
now you have the five minutes to figure
out the one piece of text you said you
would do it okay and anyone those who
are interested in this can we do read
emanation or not
Bernard started a discussion on the
mailing list so please participate okay
so with that thank you everyone and I
hope we don't have to see in on this
topic in Singapore
that's see later now it's
[Music]
you