hi my name is suresh krisshnan internet
data director of the IITs reporting -
from prague we're we're just wrapping up
a meeting so we just had a ETF 99 here
and we got a lot of work done so we had
about 1200 participants here on site and
we had about finders participants
registered for remote participation our
decision-making process is rough
consensus and running code and I want to
emphasize the running code part of it so
we had like a fantastic hackathon here
we had more participants than we ever
had in a hackathon we had almost 200
participants and lots of fantastic
projects a lot of this stuff is
implementations of own protocols so we
actually implement our protocols and
give feedback to a standardization
process so everything is like real life
not made in a vacuum the IITs also
participated in this process so we had
this work on HTTP status code 451 which
is talking about legal demands to take
down content so we're actually trying to
measure how much this is getting used
and how it is used across the world so
that was like a fantastic hackathon
project some of the technical things I
want to talk about so we had a lot of
work going on on the Internet of Things
IOT stuff so we had like many working
goes here but like 8 or 9 working groups
that do IOT related stuff all of them
met here we got a lot of things
progressed so we're doing like IP on
these things we are doing like protocols
for application layer protocols for this
the security for this implementation
guidance for this and this we got a lot
of things accomplished on the operations
and management space we had a lot of
work done in yang so we have also had
some stuff at the hackathon the director
yang so like sometimes if people said
like oh can we do that with yang and
then like you know people are actually
coding it right there at the hackathon
and we had results ready to go after so
it's really good to see the energy same
in the IOT space like we had like a lot
of idea to do it demo so this stuff in
the LP ran working group they're doing
some header compression stuff and we had
like two interoperable implementations
like getting done there and we also had
some interrupt testing for some working
groups for example six-stage they
actually had a entropy event with
multiple implementations and they
presented the results right after to the
working group meeting so the running
code part is like working extremely well
and we also had a code sprint where we
do stuff for ourselves so the tools that
we use are done by volunteers here in
at the core and so the Saturday before
the IITs people sit together and write
the code for the tools we use for
ourselves and other things like there's
like some lively discussions happening
in like lots of groups here les we had
like a lot of discussions on what kind
of functionality to like finalized
before TLS 1.3 is ready to go and in
ipv6 we are discussing like you know how
like the addressing architectures like
gonna like go forward in the future it's
also like a new transport protocol via
developing called quake and this has got
like a lot of support from the industry
and we have all of the major browser
vendors here and the operating system
vendors and also a lot of the content
providers like participating here in the
process they all here and they also
participate in the hackathon we had like
interoperation between multiple
implementations and the stuff that
failed it went back to the working group
to figure out like how to fix so like we
are making great progress there as well
and we couldn't do all of this without
our host and sponsor so I would like to
thank our host Comcast NBC News so these
are Nick and all our sponsors for making
this meeting possible and letting us
have a wonderful meeting as for like the
next steps like we're going to Singapore
to have IETF 100 and the work is going
to continue on all the mailing list so
see you later on one of the idea mailing
list bye