[Music]
I think so yeah we have a jabber scribe
I'm a minute take your bio city that I
thank you Melinda
but neither jabber scribe okay thank you
good so I owe you a drink all right
is that okay all right well I think it's
because um boots - so I'm influencing it
to be okay okay well I wanted to first
all say ahoy to everybody because I was
very taken by the hello and check that
we learned about last night and you are
under the note well as a attendee of the
research group so do not do not feel
that you couldn't gather way I was
reading all that boilerplate
and also we followed the ITF
anti-harassment policies which I put up
on the board last night in the plenary
if you were there okay and the agenda
today is I have a little bit of an
update on the IRT F and there's a longer
one with more silly pictures that you
can find in the minutes from Saturday
Sunday Sunday
whoops Sunday and then our two applied
networking research prize talks and I
should warn you that we have plaque
presentations and photographs to you I
you know shaking hands kind of things so
tolerate us during that and then if we
have a little bit more time at the end I
want to get people to just say I'm on a
listening expedition what do you need in
terms of publications if you're working
in the IRT F so be thinking about that
and come up to the mic and talk about
that okay so the for those who don't
know I think you do we have a a parallel
between the IR
Tia and the ietf PIR camp was founded to
kind of take on the longer-term work and
to not have some of the process
strictures and and timeframe that IETF
has so it actually goes back to the
beginnings of the IETF it's not a new
development by any means and we're
organized into a bunch of research
groups this is there's not a research
group this is the area of meaning and
then also there's a steering group with
the research chairs research group
chairs and some at-large members so
because if you are at the plenary you've
heard me say this last night too for
it's very unusual that everybody meets
at the ITF but this time everybody did
so I think everyone must like Prague
because they don't have to meet an idea
they can meet in different ways so that
this is the list of the groups we have
and we also had a proposed research
group the path aware networking research
group pan our G which is our our our G's
are formed in a different way from
working groups they they convince the
chairs with some consultation and then
we give them a year to take off or not
take off so they're not exactly
chartered but they're in the proposed
state now and then we also had some
initial organizing for a meeting a group
that's currently called din that would
be about blockchain and crypto Ledger's
and things like that needs to organize
its thoughts okay and Saturday we had
the annual applied networking research
workshop there's where the proceedings
are and you could also see the recording
if you weren't there so one thing that's
confusing is we have the AARP and the
and our W and so the al RW is this kind
of a standard research workshop
emphasizing applied networking so the
intersection of in of ITF tight style
things that we do and research and so
that's going to happen again next summer
take a look at it let us know if you're
interested in submitting to it and then
we have the NRP which I'll tell you
about in a few moments so this is the
IRS G membership and it also shows you
who are the chairs of the research
groups so you can just run your eyes
over that and then we my cats don't look
very good in green and purple but but I
find it coming to see them and so we
have a discuss mailing list and an
announce mailing list that you can join
and I RTF dot org has links to extensive
information on the research crews but
you can also find the research groups
through the data tracker okay so we're
going to talk about we're going to move
on to the applied networking research
prize talk starting with Philip but I
also wanted to mention that this prize
is a submission of papers that were
already published so it's kind of like a
best paper but Pam internet best paper
award so we ask for people to submit
what they think of as the best papers
they've they've seen anywhere and to
nominate a speaker who would benefit
from experiencing the ITF and the IRT F
so the winners of this receive a trip to
the IETF and some hospitality from I saw
involving attending the the the ITF
fellows dinner I believe and you should
even though we're meeting this this late
you should think about ways that you
might encourage these speakers to to
participate in IETF when you hear what
they've talked about so with that I'm
going to introduce Philip who is just
about to defend dissertation is that
right yeah and then move to a position
with Dave Clark at MIT and has a great
study of a multi perspective analysis of
carrier grade nat deployment so over to
you and here is your download over
[Music]
Thanks all right can you guys hear me
all right also with the okay sounds good
okay yeah my name is Philip Lister I'm
going to talk about or work
multi-perspective analysis of carrier
grade nat deployment I think we agreed
on be presenting us here yeah okay I
think the cameras are all pointing okay
yes I'm going to present our work on
carrier grade nat deployment in the
internet this is a paper that appeared
in our last year's IMC conference and if
you're interested in the PDF you can
also get it using this tiny URL link
here I also want to acknowledge my
co-authors here so this is joint work
with Florian now CEO mark Randy Anja
Christian Nick and burn okay I think
there is no need for a long introduction
of what the problem here is i guess
everybody in the room is aware of the
problem of ipv4 address space exhaustion
it in fact it receives a lot of
attention more recently also in the
media and it is also a long-standing
problem so I just found this quote here
a couple of days ago from IAB from an
IAB meeting in 1992 and already back
then the problem of too few ipv4
addresses was clearly named as a clear
and present danger to the future
successful growth of the worldwide
Internet now that was in 1992 if you
know fast forward to 2017 now we have a
situation in for in which 4 out of 5 of
the regional internet registries that
manage global IP address allocations
exhaust Sedaris pools
currently we have only about 1% of the
globally routable ipv4 address space
that is still under located and usable
and of course the question is what do
networks now do to mitigate their ipv4
shortage issues and the first thing that
comes to mind of course is the
transition to ipv6 which will present a
long-term solution to the scarcity
problem and internet also receives a lot
of attention from the measurement
community so when it comes to ipv6 we
have plenty of measurements and
statistics available I will just show
you two very common ones you might have
seen them a couple of times already in
the last days the first one is from
Google and it basically tells us that as
of today about 20% of the hosts contact
in Google and us are using ipv6 the
second one is from a pinna class that
measures ipv6 adoption on a per country
level and here we can see that we are
doing quite well in some countries but
still also there's a lot of red color in
this in this map
now besides transitioning to ipv6 is
peace can also use other means to
mitigate address shortage issues and in
particular they have two other ways of
doing that now the first one is to buy
ipv4 address on address markets and the
IRS like the registries recently
introduced policies that allow these
transverse and also publish statistics
regarding these transfers also here we
have data available that we can that we
can look at to track how these markets
are evolving what I show you here is
just some data pulled from the our IRS
that shows some statistics of the number
of address blocks that are currently or
where are bought and sold and on address
markets in the recent years and you can
see that this is indeed the markets are
indeed taking off but then there's a
third thing that network operators of
some networks can do and that is that
they can use ipv4 carry a great net to
to multiplex more users behind a fewer
public ipv4 addresses and when we
started looking at carry a great net we
soon realized that there are no
deployment statistics available so it's
really hard to keep track of like how
popular this way of combating before
exhaustion really is you know
so very little is known about how
carrier-grade nets are configured in the
wild and this is the focus of this work
and also of this talk all right now
first we wanted to get a bit of an
understanding of the problems like that
ISPs face when deploying carrier-grade
NAT so we have formed a little survey so
we asked we asked ISPs about their ipv4
scarcity issues and whether they want to
deploy ipv4 carry a great lap so we
circulated this and eventually we
received some 75 answers just want to
quickly show you some of those the
highlights of that so probably the most
important question that we asked is like
did you or do you plan to deploy before
carry a great nap and we were quite
surprised I mean of course 75 hires
piece is a small sample but we were
quite surprised at 38% of the ISPs told
us yes we already do that and another
12% told us that they are in early
trials and they will deploy before
carrier grade nat in the near future so
we went on and asked him also a little
bit more about carrier grade nat
specifics so we asked them what if they
have any operational concerns when when
introducing he for carrier grade nat and
they were plenty so one of the most
commonly mentioned one was that
subscribers might experience problems
with applications that just don't work
well behind carrier grade nat so a
gaming was mentioned several times
another issue that came up frequently is
the traceability of users behind carrier
grade nat and also issues with publicly
facing gateway IP addresses becoming our
blacklisted now we also asked some of
what they see as the major challenges or
caveats when introducing carrier grade
nat troubleshooting connectivity issues
was was frequently mentioned but also
more generally how to how to dimension
carrier grade nodes meaning how to do
the resource allocation like how many IP
addresses how do we allocate IP
addresses and ports to subscribers and
how do I set the right quotas for
individual subscribers one thing that
summarized piece mentioned I and I want
to mention that here because we will
also see some effect of that in our
measurements is that their problem would
be for carrier grade nat is a shortage
of internal address space and it means
basically
they have used the available RFC 1918
ranges already in their management
network and not have problems finding
address ranges that they can use behind
a carry great nut okay
we also get them a free text field where
they can tell us more about what they
think about carrier grade nat and what
we can really see is that most of them
were not really fond of deploying before
carrier grade net as you can see also
from the first comment but a
surprisingly large number of networks
also told us that v6 deployment seems to
be costly and difficult for them so some
of them just opted to first go with
carry a great nap so basically that
really motivated us to study this more
because it seems to be widely deployed
and the networks also voice concerns
like regarding carrier grade nat
deployment at the same time we don't
have broad and systematic studies
available so what we did as we developed
our methods to detect carrier grade nat
presence in the internet and also
methods that allow us to extract some of
the properties of commonly deployed cg
net instances before i talk about our
methods just want to quickly introduce
some terminology so here in this figure
you see a common case of our subscriber
is connected to to the internet so we
have the isp in the center the ISPs some
public ipv4 address space yes with other
networks in the internet towards the
right enhancer or the public IP ad for
address to its subscribers in turn the
subscriber will run a home that and
reconnect these are her devices behind
that mat so that would be the canonical
page here we don't have a CG NAT D
formant now if the size P no decides to
deploy carrier-grade NAT we will have an
additional map box that sits within the
isp and then the isp will hand out
internal address space to its
subscribers and that gives us two more
cases like the first one is the case of
net for for carrier side nut which
basically means that here we only have
one nad box but the network's it's
within the isp and not at the end user
and then we have the third case where
the isp deploys an app box hence our
internal IP addresses to the subscribers
in china subscriber runs another CPE net
so here we have the situation of
net 404 okay i mean this is what harry
great net deployment looks like on the
white or of course like in practice
there are more complicated scenarios are
possible so our goal was to find ways to
detect the presence of these devices
this turned out to be really difficult
because gnats operate transparently
right meaning that if you monitor
traffic if you monitor packets there's
no easy way to tell whether it is packet
was translated at some point on the path
before we can see it so we had a hard
time with that but eventually we found
two methods that allow us to detect um
carrier gretna presence and i will now
introduce them to you the first one the
first method that we found to be working
is what you call detecting cg net from
the outside using BitTorrent we call
this one from the outside because with
this method we don't need any probing
devices within the networks if you want
to test but we can this detection works
by crawling the BitTorrent DHT let me
quickly walk you through i guess
everybody here knows the BitTorrent
protocol and in the in in the classic
way baton would work the way that you
want to download a specific talent you
will connect to a tracker tell the
tracker i want to download torrent XYZ
and turn the tracker will give you a
list of IP addresses in port numbers of
other peers you connect to them you
download your content but you can also
do that without using a centralized
tracker you can do that using your baton
distributed hash table and if you do
that using the BitTorrent DHT then each
the torrent peer that participates in
this DHT will maintain a list of our p
addresses and port numbers of other
BitTorrent peers that had recently
interacted with and actually it turns
out that we can use these deterrent
peers in a baton DHT as vantage points
in our study so in order to do that we
implemented DHT crawler which is
basically a machine that continuously
asks the current peers across the
Internet the term peers participating in
this DHT and we asked him hey please
give us a list of IP addresses and port
numbers how it appears that you recently
interacted with an intern they will tell
us ok
can reach Pierre each beer has a unique
ID I can reach P X Y Z using IP address
and port number now we have to scroll up
we implemented as : we had to scroll a
runny
by the way initially not for the purpose
of detecting nap but it turned out that
we can we can do it partially with that
so we had a scroller running and after a
while we realized that in some instances
we have the time you have the term peers
like this peer here that apparently sit
behind some form of an app and tell us
that they can they have connectivity to
another peer using an internal IP
address so for example sure in this case
we ask a specific peer to peer tells us
I can reach peer 8 h2d using an internal
address so they leak as internal IP
addresses by habit or DHT now when we
realize that this is happening we tailor
the crawler to extract in harvest as
many of these internal end points from
the baton DHT and we can do that quite
efficiently so within one week of
crawling we can learn private IP
addresses from more than 700 thousand
peers in five thousand guesses now the
question is do all these five thousand a
SS necessarily deploy carry a great Matt
and the answer is of course not right
because at this point we just know that
there is some form of mapped but it took
me a carry a great net or it could just
be a home mat with multiple the torrent
clients behind it okay so to better
understand this and also to be able to
resect these small whole nights from
carrier-grade nuts you have to have a
closer look at the leakage relationships
and what we basically do um in order to
what we basically do is that we form a
graph and whenever we have a peer the
term PA that leaves us the contact
information for a peer be like this one
and PB has a private IP address we will
form two vertices in the graph where the
leaking PL PA is a big blue Burgess and
the internal peer to peer with the
internal IP address is a small red
verges then we draw this arrow to show
hey PA litres PB and then we have a look
at these leaking relationships at a
larger scale so namely we form a graph
for each is in which we crawl return PS
now let me
what these graphs look like so this is a
tiny subset of our data of course we
recall many more of these peers and it
shows us to a SS and in the first a s we
did not detect carry a great nap
meaning that here we do see leakage we
see patrol MPs leaking us internal IP
addresses but typically the only League
is one or two and also on that is more
importantly all of these leakage
relationships are isolated so in this
case we cannot say that it are an
indication of a carrier grade math but
it could just be hole nuts but then we
have other a SS like the ones on the
right-hand side where we see much more
leakage and the important thing is here
is that we also see overlaps in this
peer leakage meaning that we have
different the term PS using different
public IP addresses leaking as the same
internal peers which is indicative of a
net that has ranges of public IP
addresses which we use as trigger or
carrier grade nat detection all right of
course I mean there is much more
thresholding involved and we have to pre
post process these graphs um we have
more details on that in the paper but
here I just wanted to give an impression
of what this signal looks like for NAT
inveterate alright so with this method
we can test some roughly at 2,700 a SS
in which we crawl a sufficient number of
the torrent peers and we detected carry
a great nap meaning these clusters on in
one or two hundred fifty now the
benefits are clear that we have a broad
coverage and if we can just do that and
we don't need to put any probing devices
within within these networks the problem
is that first we need a lot of the
torrent activity in a SS so that we can
even they can at least in theory show up
in our measurements and secondly is even
if we have significant baton activity in
a specific a s that deploys
carrier-grade net it will not
necessarily show up here because it kept
the net must be configured in a very
open way namely it must expose internal
IP addresses of the torrent peers to
each other so with this we will only
partially capture the carrier grade nat
landscape so we complemented that with a
second approach which is what we termed
detecting CG net from the insight using
using
metalizer we call this approach from the
inside because here we have full control
over probing devices that are located
behind the carrier-grade NAT so I want
to quickly introduce Naturalizer maybe
some of you folks know that knit eliza
is a network troubleshooting suite it is
developed by XE in Berkeley you can
download it as an Android app or as a
Java applet or you can use it as a as a
command line tool and when you download
metalize done executed it will run a
series of tests regarding the health of
your connectivity and if we also show
you a detailed report showing you lots
of properties of your arm internet
connection at the same time when you run
metalizer you will support our research
because we use that in measurement
studies and in this particular study we
use data captured in more than 550,000
sessions like an accession just means a
person executed Naturalizer and they
cover more than 1500 guesses and the
benefits of this metalizer data is that
it gives us direct access to the IP
address of the client of the router and
also the public IP address in advance
and set alignment cellular networks and
since we have full control over
Naturalizer we also implemented more
customized tests now we'll talk more
about them in a second just a quick
sketch on how we detect carrier-grade
NAT presence with metalizer now here we
have two different cases we have two
cellular network case in the cellular
case detection is straightforward
because in a cellular network the IP
address of the device will directly be
assigned by the ISP so we can compare
the device IP address against the IP
address that we see at our measurement
servants okay it was translation now in
residential networks the situation is a
little more complicated because here the
device IP address will always be
assigned from the home router so what we
do here is that we use UPnP to query the
external IP address from the home router
and again we compare it with the server
side IP that we see turns out that in
practice this is much more cumbersome
because in up to 7% of the sessions we
see cases
that people have to at least two home
routers in cascade in their homes
meaning that the external IP address
from the first CPE router is not
assigned from the ISP but from some
other CPE device and we developed
several filters and heuristics to get
rid of these sessions and if you're
interested in that and that we
documented that in our paper okay that
was a quick overview of detection using
naturalizer until we tested some 1500 s
s and we detected another roughly 200 to
carry a great net instances and also 205
cellular asses using Harry Redknapp now
the benefits here are clear we have much
more control over this measurement point
it gives us direct access to the IP
addressing data that we need to detect
detect area great not the problem here
is again partial visibility this is
crowd-sourced data and we are at the
mercy of users executing this for us
okay now let me show you some key regret
not deployment statistics now first when
we've been talking about like what
percentage of networks do calls carry a
great net of course we need you to
define into what kind of networks we are
interested in and so in this work you
want to focus on eyeball networks
meaning a SS that primarily connect end
users to the Internet so the first thing
that we did is that we define our a set
of eyeball asked by a population of a SS
that we consider eyeball a SS and we do
that using two different data sources
the first is to Spamhaus pv ellis this
is a basically a list where you can
register residential address ranges and
the second one is a data set from a pina
gloves which gives you an estimation of
the number of subscribers in a
particular areas so we use these two to
refine our set of eyeball asses which is
about 3000 a SS and we may have a look
at how many of them like we cover with
our measurements we see that we cover
roughly 62% of them and in addition this
is what an on-set all archives and in
addition we test it in total 218
cellular asses okay now how many of them
do deploy carry a great net
let me rephrase and how many of them do
we detect it for the non-cellular case
we end up with a little more than 17%
and maybe if you know recall our survey
and the surveyed was 35% we measure 17%
so the real number might be somewhere in
between and what is probably interesting
to note here is that if we partition
Vass that we tested according to the 5
different regions we can see that
character at night deployment is
particularly pronounced in the a penis
in the asia-pacific region and in the
ripe region and it's important to point
out here that these are also the two
regions where addresses ran out first
okay now for the subtler cases we see
that hairy right net is just everywhere
so more than 94% of the networks that we
tested we apply it there are only some
very few exceptions in Africa where you
still have a chance of getting a public
ipv4 address on a cellular network ok so
much for the deployment now I want to
talk a little bit about some of the
properties of the Nets that we
identified now the first thing I wanted
to show you is um the internal address
ranges that networks use behind their
carrier-grade NAT deployment now both
our methods allow us to study that and
we showed it here for again for the non
cellular and for the cellular case and
what we can see is that the RFC 1918
ranges particular least 10/8 is still
the most common commonly used one empty
relatively newly allocated 164 which is
specifically allocated for the purpose
of deploying carrier great not only
slowly takes off but what is probably
more intriguing to see here is that up
to 20 percent of the SS already used
multiple internal address ranges behind
their carrier great not now if we recall
also from our survey that it seems to be
an increasing problem for SS to find
usable internal address ranges to use
behind the net now the schools as far as
that in the case of some major cellular
networks they seem to see the need to
use routable IP IP addresses as internal
IP addresses behind their carrier grade
that
and in this figure here I show you some
of the most prominent cases I want to
say here you don't want to do it any
name shaming we see this behavior form
or ESS and we just chose to show these
six because they are like really big so
we have a lot of data and can be
confident in our reasoning here so what
we show here on the x-axis is the
corresponding relative address block let
me here we show the network's did use
them as internal space now what we want
to highlight here is that like for
example let's have a look at the 25/8
address block I recall correctly it is
UK Ministry of Defense and currently if
you go from the global routing table
this address block is not in use and but
what we see is that there are at least
four major networks that use these
addresses internal internally there
might even be more as such this is just
a subset of them and we would argue that
the question is what happens if somebody
wants to finally use this address block
given its scarcity will increase we can
imagine that at some point people want
to buy and use this address block and we
can likely expect it a lot of users
behind these users of these of these
networks will have severe connectivity
issues here okay now that was that was
one of our findings we implemented more
customized tests in our metalizer test
suite to extract more properties of the
carrier great nuts and I want to quickly
sketch on earth or methodology here so
one thing that we do is that whenever
you run metalize or net Eliza will
initiate ten subsequent TCP connections
from the device to our measurement
server and what we can then do is that
we compare local IP addresses and port
numbers to remote IP addresses and port
numbers but that we can study how
carrier grade nads allocate ports and IP
addresses and for some of them I will
show you an example we can also estimate
like how many products in an individual
subscriber receives we also implemented
a custom TTL TTL based nap test
basically what this test does is that it
sends TTL limited probes to first create
state in all nets on the path and then
to retain it in some hops but to expired
in other hops and with this test we can
pinpoint the location of
nets on the path including carrier-grade
nuts and also extract time all values of
the Nats and lastly we also implemented
a stun test which allows us to compare
the kind of map mappings that a carrier
grade map would give you in contrast to
your home router Oki there's probably
not enough time to go into all of these
all of these results I just picked some
of them that I quickly want to show you
one thing that we found quite surprising
is that up to 20% off to carry a great
map instances that we detected use
what's called arbitrary pooling but it
basically means these are these are Nats
that have ranges of public ipv4
addresses and if they use arbitrary
pooling it means that you as a user if
you initiate two subsequent connections
your public IP address might very well
change that this is something of course
is courage in the in several RFC's and
we were surprised that we see it to that
large extent because just think of what
this lets you hosts reputation systems
we also studied in detail of a location
behavior just want to show you a quick
sketch here so Nets have different
strategies on holiday allocate oh it's
true to its subscribers and we were
interested in studying what it is some
sort of a common uniform behavior you
within a specific a s and it turns out
that this is not the case so to 70
percent of the ASA's in we did in which
we detected carrier grade lab never
liked a mixed port allocation strategy
meaning what happens to subscriber a
will not be the same it what happens to
a subscriber B we have more details on
that of course written up but generally
when studying resource allocation we see
a huge diversity um here and we also see
that actually the majority of them shows
like non-uniform behavior and of course
just think of what this can do to your
applications to most reputation systems
are also to attribution I'm going to
quickly show you one case one port
allocation strategy which we really like
because it is very like measurement
friendly some kind of rate notes do
allocate parts in a chunk based fashion
meaning that every subscriber receives a
specific chunk of course then it will
ran
choose port numbers from this shank and
in our measurement system nicely closed
up because for each metalizer session we
can see okay the chunk size in this
particular ISP is like five hundred
twelve ports or it is like a thousand
ports and this in turn allows us then to
reason how many subscribers are behind a
sing an IP address in the most intense
case that we found here in our
measurements is 512 ports per subscriber
or 128 subscribers per IP we heard more
crazy numbers like people told me that
they met like thousands of users behind
the IP I don't know this is the this is
the highest number that we can somehow
empirically back up here okay um I want
to quickly show you one other thing
because I think it matters um we also
implemented the stun test and as
mentioned what the stun test does is
that it measures somehow how restrictive
or how open the mapping types are that
in that uses in first I will not go into
detail of all these different mapping
types but let's first quickly look at
the distribution of filtering in their
mapping and filtering behavior for for
home nets and the only thing I want to
point out is that the most restrictive
way of configuring in that is using
symmetric net bindings and it basically
means that if you are behind such a net
you can't do any peer-to-peer anymore
and even if you use like advanced hole
punching that needs it won't really work
so meaning if you are behind a symmetric
net that's that's it basically and in
the case of CPU devices we see that this
is quite uncommon so only about two
percent of them do that but if you look
at our carrier-grade Nets we see that
these very restrictive nap bindings are
much more common in fact it's about 10%
of the non-cellular deployments and even
40% of the cellular deployments show
this behavior meaning that the mapping
that a carrier-grade NAT imposes on its
subscribers is often more is more
restrictive than what your CPE home
device would do okay and so that was a
quick overview of some of some of the
results what we can generally say
we see that carrier-grade NAT is very
broadly Paulette and it is like a
everyday reality for a lot of users I
think in fact it is even reality for the
majority of Internet users I'm
considering that most of them are in
cellular networks and what we see in
this first study you see a stunning
variety of different configurations we
see that when we compare networks to
each other but we also see that even
within networks and what we also see is
that the degree of resource sharing like
meaning like how many ports for example
does an individual subscriber received
very fastly across different nets
meaning that we can clearly see with
these measurements that carry great Nets
just limit the resources that are
available to subscribers and also it
means very different things for
different ISPs not it raises some
challenges so for example one regarding
regarding measurement and I'd be very
curious also to hear your opinion on
that so for example when we do
measurements to - to measure end-user
performance it should have performance I
mean the common metrics would be speed
are less and latency and packet loss
anything with these measurement with
these metrics are that they don't
necessarily capture the the limitations
that are carry a great not imposes on
you so for example - to capture them we
would meet we would need metrics like
for example what is the maximum number
of concurrent connections that I can
issue as a subscriber of a particular
ISP or what kind of map mappings will
that ISP impose on me that restrict my
connectivity and yeah related to that we
also wanted to like point out that
perhaps give given how widespread
carrier-grade nets are deployed and
given their measurable effect on how
much internet you receive as a
subscriber but it is need for more
guidelines or possibly like best
practices on what is still considered an
okay amount of internet or whether it is
also something that could be interesting
or subject to regulation all right what
I conclude and I'm happy to take your
questions
judge Nicola our one comment and one
question when you're saying about 20% of
ISS doing arbitrary marking that might
be just different devices you have once
again device in one location as a
citizen device next to it you've been
different has different pools and you
just randomly sheet2 an awesome yes yes
and question did you compare your
database detecting v6 only networks
which do in not six four because it
looks like you're connecting to before
destinations yes so actually most of
that is like currently before most of
these measurements the thing is that
baturin the public DHT of the torrent is
not it's very sparsely populated in ipv6
so currently we can't really compare it
there and for Naturalizer we do have a
v6 data available but we didn't include
it yet endless because very interesting
you said you eighty ninety four percent
of mobile is s doing CGA it would be
interesting to share what they doing in
terms of not six five yes just won't
yeah what one quick thing cuz I expect
it of course questions regarding ipv6 I
just did something which is not a great
analysis at this point but just did it
yesterday so I took the a SS in which we
detect carrier-grade NAT and I just
checked where the day at least announced
an ipv6 prefix and here we see it's it's
about half of them hi Alan Jerome
first to follow up on this and then
another question there are two cases you
can have service provider we do ipv6 and
ipv4 Calgary not and some we can do
simply ipv6 native internally in that
six four yeah was that like two
different cases that you may want to yes
some are separate the second question is
about the audible addresses that you
found and for me that was the most
surprising finding in your study and in
very very interesting because you're
right once those blocks are going to be
on the market and chopped off in
smaller blogs when we may see some
interesting behavior so do you publish a
list of actual addresses that you have
seen something that's a finer
granularity than the slash eight because
I look in your paper is you only go to
the slash eight yes looking going
publishing this data to maybe a slash 24
gladden now he was certainly helped a
lot okay okay I mean we didn't do that
yet but if there's interest in more fine
granular data I think we can do it thank
you
hi Anjali from Boston University so you
looked at the deploying different
deployments by different ISPs how many
of these are like complying to the
standards how close are they like what
are their strategies you mean like to
RFC oh yeah whatever standards are yeah
so I mean there are lots of our receives
on on that behavior and some also on
carry a great nuts the thing is they
don't specify all these to my best
knowledge they don't specify all the
things that we measured here but they do
specify for example that arbitrary are
pooling of IP addresses is not an option
so at least 20% were wire like that and
in other measurements which I didn't
present you but we also measure time on
values and we find it pretty much I
don't I don't have the exact number but
there's a large number of the of the
carrier grade nat boxes also by all item
so there's a large fraction of them that
are for sure on what RFC compliant so
there are specifications and RFC's but
these are these other people yeah yes
there are specifications in the RFC is
regarding net mappings and net timeouts
but for example what is not specified in
charin RFC uses how many ports for
example you need or how many sessions
are appropriate so it's both yes okay
Eric not Mike thank you this very
interesting study so I saw one thing you
had two things you had this sort of port
behaviors whether it was you know
preserving or but I forget the term but
and you also had the restrictive Mouse
whether it's a metric or something else
did you actually look at potential
correlation between those two meaning
that there's sort of if you group them
together that things fall in different
buckets no not that that's an
interesting thing to do we didn't do
that yet okay hi I'm channeling waffling
back when Stan was introduced it was
discovered that some map devices changed
their behavior when running out of ports
or addresses so a full cone may become a
symmetric did you observe this with
carrier-grade nuts no I mean III saw
that too I have found that also really
the press if that this can happen
I currently I don't see a way of how to
how to measure how to measure that
because in the end like for one session
we can execute these ten TCP connections
and we can run the stun test once and
it's not that the same user will be nice
enough to run metalizer the whole day
but that would certainly be something
very interesting to study how else to
make it I have a question but also if
there's any more we have we could take a
few more minutes for this so this is one
of the nice things is having a chance to
discuss my question was with this kind
of behavior that you observed why do you
think that why how can reputation
systems work at all is there any way
that you could study that kind of impact
of of this on people's you know
persistent use of addresses for
reputation yeah I'm that I honestly I I
don't really know how a reputation
systems should deal with that or how
they currently deal with that I put I
would be very interested in speaking
with somebody who runs shots such
systems and now there might be people
who have some some hacks ok maybe Dave
Matt Ford thanks this was a really
interesting talk I'm at a question in a
comment the question was did you go back
to any of your survey respondus once you
had the measurement results to establish
whether there were
false-positives turning up in your data
set yes I mean generally validation is
very difficult because no isp writes
that on their website or at least very
very few do we had a all that limited
set off like a couple of dozen of a SS
for which we have like ground truth on
whether they deploy it or not we did not
find false positives so far and we have
several false negatives I mean we try to
readjust our thresholds to be as
conservative as possible and so far we
didn't find a false positive but that
might happen at some point sooner or
later
Thanks the comment was just I think you
made a comment on one of your last
slides about regulation and I thought I
just observed that I was just looking I
know there's some regulation in Belgium
related to this now I was looking for
that and the first thing I found was a
press release from Europe all with lots
of text in it about how alarm how
alarmed they are at the growing use of
cgn and the impact it's going to have on
their on their law enforcement
capabilities and they cite your paper in
that press release so I thought that was
that was awesome and I've also heard of
subscribers of ISPs using CG and having
problems getting two major pokemons go
is there's another thing that came up
high up in my search results and Xbox
there's there's all kinds of breakage
this is causing for a subscriber so it
curves to me that given the impending
regulation or it seems likely regulation
and the effect this is having on
subscribers continuing to measure this
over time you might start to see this
stuff goes away as well thanks Philip I
you and I have talked about some of this
stuff before so I'll echo one of the
questions that I have for you but I
don't expect you to be able answer it
but I'm fascinated by Phelps working in
that there are clearly a whole bunch of
kinds of commercial devices out there
that do these things and no one says hey
that's the J box 1 that's the C box 1
that's the Linux one somebody must know
so if you know somebody in this
community could tell us about what they
are that would be fascinating to know
they also have a cost in the capacity
presumably and I don't understand why
this market place isn't described in the
open right oh and they just have a four
color glossy that says
that does this the the question that was
asked before about reputation and it
cross for instance the world wide web
client space not speaking for my
employer because I've just not
authoritative about what exactly we do
in our reputation product but I can tell
you some of the things that you can do
there are pieces of software that have
unique identifiers in them and you very
often see tens or hundreds or even
thousands of those unique identifiers
show up behind one IP address in a day
or a couple of days so clearly that's an
added address the other thing one of the
most interesting ones that were pursuing
in our nascent research is about finding
v4 v6 address pairings sort of the way
that a APNIC does where you you force a
web browser to connect back with both
protocol versions and and over a very
short amount of time you'll see 1/24
associated with tens or hundreds of
thousands of slash 64's and v6 so it's a
it's an interesting way and that the
unit is temporarily unique identifiers
in terms of the identities of sign in v6
multiplex on to v4 addresses and you can
find the the nets that way and then the
last thing following to what Ellison's I
mean she said like I think that just it
was how in the world would you do this
it's a huge problem it's a huge like
record-keeping problem because you have
to continue continually monitor this and
the other place we're seeing it is
people adding through cloud
infrastructure
so like the cloud right they have a nap
that's infinitely scalable and people
are putting commercial enterprises
behind a cloud and so we see a cloud
address one day and it's one machine
doing some service but the next day it's
a company behind it with a thousand
employees it's a really difficult
problem and I'm glad that's not my job
thank you for the great talk
Steve check away is a professor at the
University of illinois-chicago
and this is a really interesting talk
for the security folks and all of us
good you know good thing to pay
attention to so thanks and again we can
take extra time at the end so think of
good questions to ask him okay great
thanks so as Alison said my name is
Steve chuckwei I'm at the University of
Illinois at Chicago and I want to talk
today about the incident involving
junipers use of Julie C so if you don't
have any idea what I'm talking about
I'll jump I did so in late 2015
juniper made a pretty surprising
announcement they had an out of cycle
Security Bulletin that said that some
unauthorized parties had gained access
to their source code and had managed to
introduce two backdoors
so the first was an unauthorized remote
administrative access and the second was
the somewhat cryptic message that a
knowledgeable attacker who can monitor
VPN traffic can decrypt that traffic so
this is what I want to talk about it
this work is all about how did this
actually happen what was it that the
attackers were able to do what the
consequences of that are and then I want
to end with a couple of lessons that I
think that that we've learned from this
that are applicable to protocol
designers so first these are the devices
that were affected these are the
junipers secure service gateway
combination firewall and VPN devices and
the affected versions of the software
were a variety of screen OS 6.2 and 6.3
versions so let me start with the first
one this was actually from my point of
view the least interesting one
although it was a little bit clever here
so basically what the attacker did was
they introduced a hard-coded backdoor
password that affects telnet and ssh and
so this is the the password right there
and you can see that it kind of looks
like if you can read this it kind of
looks like some other format strings
that you would be using for logging
information and it turns out that you
can see this is being passed right here
to store compare and so if you if you
log in with this this password it it
lets you log in that with administrator
access and it leaves some some tell-tale
sign and the log which one could could
actually remove so this was found really
quickly by HD more and was able to test
it and and sure enough it worked so the
next one was more interesting from my
point of view because it was really
cryptic it just said there's this
knowledgeable attacker who could do
something and so once this security
bulletin was put out researchers around
the world including me and my colleagues
decided we were not going to spend
Christmas with our families and instead
we were going to spend a bunch of time
reverse-engineering stuff and the
question is well where do we start with
this well HD more again was very very
helpful here he he ran strings over one
of the one of the the versions of the
firmware that had been known to have
been changed and also ran strings over
junipers fix that they put out and ran
diff over that and this is almost
entirely the full death there's a few
other things but this is the the key
point here and so this is kind of
interesting if you are a big crypto nerd
you might have looked at this and said
oh I know what these are immediately if
you're like you know most people you put
them into Google and see what comes up
and the first five of these long hex
digits long hex numbers here are
parameters to this
elliptic curve P 256 so these you you
google them and they they come right up
and so the question is what does this
change here what what change from 9 5 8
5 etc to 2 5 or 2 C 5 5 etc and to
figure that out we had to reverse
engineer the the binaries and it turns
out that these two values are rather
this one value that was changed were for
the x-coordinate of a non-standard
elliptic curve point which was used for
dual EC drbg
if you haven't heard of dual EC drbg it
was a or it is a pseudo-random number
generator that was designed by the NSA
in the early 2000s and then they made a
push towards standardization so it
appeared as part of an ANSI standard I
think it appeared in some other
standards eventually NIST standardized
it in special publication 800-53 C their
default random number generator it
doesn't actually do anything else in
this for this particular work but it's
an interesting thing to note here but
the key point sorry I couldn't resist
the the key point here is that in 2007's
Microsoft researchers sumo and Ferguson
were able to demonstrate at a crypto
Rumph session a theoretical backdoor
attack against dual EC and sort of after
this people thought well okay we know
this is bad it has some biases that the
we we probably shouldn't use it and it
turns out it's really slow no one would
ever use it so let's ignore it in 2013
there was some renewed interest to this
when a New York Times article was
written as a result of the Snowden
revelations that revealed that the NSA
was trying to tamper with some
particular crypto
and that dual ec was perhaps one of
these and then the following year some
of my colleagues and I showed that in
fact that if you use dual EC as your
random number generator for TLS then you
can actually break TLS so fast forward
to you know 2015 and we see that once
again we can actually do this with with
I so let me talk about what it means to
have a backdoor to random number
generator because that's kind of an
unusual concept but basically the way a
normal random number generator works is
you start with a seed so you have some
seed value s naught to which you apply a
pair of functions so you apply F of I
compute F of s naught and you get s 1
which is your new state you compute G of
s naught and you get some output or 1
and then you can just repeat this as
many times as you need subject to some
theoretical or I guess practical
constraints on how many times you can do
this but you can do this to keep getting
more output now where the backdoor comes
in is if someone who has some sort of
secret knowledge is able to start with
say some output r2 and apply some other
function to it using this secret
knowledge and recover one of the
internal states of the generator and the
reason that this is really bad in a
crypto program protocol is probably
pretty obvious once the attacker gets
the internal state of your random number
generator well then they get every
subsequent random pseudo-random number
that will be generated until the P R and
G is receded now Dulli see the the EC
stands for elliptic curve and so just do
a quick primer on elliptic curve math
don't need to understand most of how
this works although it is a pretty neat
ear pretty neat area so basically a
point on an elliptic curve is a pair of
x and y coordinates that satisfy a
particular equation it's no matter what
the equation is here the for our
purposes x and y are going to be 32 byte
integers although there are larger and
smaller elliptic curves that one could
deal with and sort of the the key
properties here are that you can add two
points on the curve in this sort of
geometric fashion and arrive at another
point on the curve and you can repeat
this process over and over so you can
take an integer in and a point P and you
can compute n times P which is just
adding P to itself at times and finally
the key to this whole scheme is that
given a point P and a point in P it's
hard to come up with n so this is the
elliptic curve discrete logarithm
problem so let me describe dual EC here
so this is sort of a somewhat simplified
version of how this works
but we start with a 32 byte state s
naught and we take s naught we treat it
as a big integer we multiply it by some
fixed elliptic curve point P which is
the generator for P 2 5 6 and then we
take the x-coordinate of that and that
gives us a new state s 1 we take s 1 we
multiply that by a second fixed elliptic
point Q take the x-coordinate and that
gives us R 1 which is not quite our
output it's almost our output so what we
do is we take the least significant 30
bytes of R 1 and those become the most
significant 30 bytes of our output and
then this process repeats so take s 1
times P you take the x-coordinate and it
gives us s 2 multiply that by Q take the
x-coordinate that gives us R 2 the next
30 bytes are the least significant 30
bytes of that are the next output bytes
and so on so the really cool thing that
Schumer and Ferguson noted about this is
that if an attacker knows the
relationship between P and Q in
particular if the attacker knows the
integer D such that P is equal to D
times Q
and it turns out that such a d-- exists
and the attacker is able to see output
from dual EC then it's actually possible
to recover some internal state and so
the way this works is pretty neat you
start with the output and you set r1
which you don't know except you know the
first 30 bytes of it just because of how
dual EC works then you need to guess the
two most significant bytes of r1 or in
reality what you do is you just try all
65,000 possibilities so that doesn't
take very long and you find an elliptic
curve point R that has all one as its
x-coordinate this either succeeds and
you find two points or it fails and you
find zero points in which case you would
just try the next most significant byte
and now you take R you multiply it by D
and you take the x-coordinate and if you
Oh indeed so so so you take the
x-coordinate and that gives us 2 and if
it was not immediately obvious how that
works you can read this string of
equations here or you can just take my
word for it all right but most of the
time you're you're not going to get a
value that works so how do you figure
out when you've actually recovered the
internal state well it's pretty simple
you just walk dual EC forward so you
multiply your assumed s2 by Q take the
x-coordinate and then you check is the
least significant 30 bytes of r2 equal
to the remainder of your output and if
it's not just go back to step two and
pick a new value for orange and try
again and otherwise you have recovered
the internal state of the generator and
so what is it that an attacker needs in
order to do this well obviously the
attacker needs to have this secret value
D but the attacker also needs to see a
large amount of output from a single
block of Abdullah see output so say at
least 28 bytes and the fewer bytes you
have the attack becomes exponentially
more difficult so if you have 30 bytes
or more it's it's basically free to do
if you have less than 28 bytes you
actually have to spend a lot of time
working on and next you don't actually
need to see raw output to do the
comparison step it's sufficient if there
is some public function of that so let
me give you an example imagine a network
protocol that has a 28 or larger byte
nonce that gets sent in the clear and it
has a difficulty that also gets sent in
the clear so here we don't know what the
the private key for the diffie-hellman
public he is but that's okay we can use
the Shuma Fergusson attack on the nonce
to recover some proposed internal state
of the generator then you compute what X
would be just by following however X
would be normally generated in this
protocol and then you compute G to the X
and see did that match the the proposed
sorry did that match the actual public
he or not and if it did then you know
you've got X and you have basically
broken the protocol so you might wonder
how can one learn D and I've got 4
methods that one could use to learn D
here the first is you could solve the
discrete logarithm problem the second is
you could be the entity in charge of
picking the official Q value in dual EC
and so either way you do this is you
just pick a large integer e you multiply
e times P you set that to be Q and then
D is just the inverse of e modulo the
group order so some simple math and
you've got D 1/3 you can use a
non-standard point Q you don't have to
use the the nsa's Q value and just do
the same thing as in step 2 or you can
gain access to somebody else's source
code and substitute your own Q point
just as you would have done in step 2
and it's worth pointing out here that
solving a discrete logarithm problem is
too hard we just can't do that
picking the official point was done by
the NSA
but they're not saying how they picked
it so so who knows screen OS that was
used in these these juniper boxes
actually use a non-standard point Q and
finally the this incident that I'm
talking about came about because the
attackers replaced their the Juniper
skew with their own cue and so now we
can sort of answer the question what was
it that the knowledgeable knowledgeable
attacker knew well the attacker knew the
discrete log D so this was actually
pretty surprising because there's a 2013
knowledgebase article that says that
although some of these screen OS
versions use dual EC it it doesn't
matter because dual EC is not the
primary PRNG and in fact it takes the
output of dual EC feeds that through an
ANSI PRNG X 931 and that's what gets
used as the main output and so in light
of this we had my my college and I had
five research questions that we really
wanted to answer so why doesn't the use
of X 931 defend against some compromise
Q value why does a change in Q actually
result in VPN decryption because this is
just a random number generator perhaps
other things should be able to defend
against this what is the history of the
screen OS PRNG code where two dual ec
come in and and how did that lead to
being able to decrypt traffic and then
are their versions of screen OS that are
using juniper skew that are vulnerable
to the same passive decryption and
finally how did juniper actually
generate their their Q value and so we
were able to answer a subset of these
questions the first three by drawing on
a body of firmware revision so in this
table on the right here this is the the
list of revisions of the firmware that I
reverse engineer to sum greater or
lesser extent in order to answer these
particular questions so we can answer
the first three questions
letting for
if we want to figure out the answer to
the last two we're going to need some
other body of material that we just
don't have access to although presumably
juniper knows the answer to five which
as we'll see will answer for so let's
start with a screen os 6.2 s
pseudo-random number generator and let's
start by looking at the the PRNG
function over here on the right and so
keep in mind this was decompiled code so
any of the names that you see here are
names that I came up with not names that
appeared in the firmware there probably
very different in junipers actual source
code and so this function has a couple
of key features here the first thing is
you'll notice that there is a
conditional reseed so it seems pretty
standard some condition is met the
receipt happens second we can see that
it's always generating 32 bytes of
output at a time using the ansi x9 31
PRNG if we look over on the left we can
see the the receipt function and the key
part points here are that we're using
dual ec drbg
to generate 32 bytes of pseudo-random
values the first eight bytes of this
become the new x 931 seed and the
remaining 24 bytes
let's sorry the remaining 24 bytes
become the X 931 key so at first glance
this looks like exactly what Juniper
described we have dual EC here but its
output is being fed into X 9 to 31 so
there shouldn't be any problems with
this particular use but let's take a
closer look here because it turns out
that's not true so the first thing that
happens over in this PRNG function or a
PNG generate function here is that we're
setting this index global variable here
to 0 then we call this one stage RNG
function which it turns out always
returns false which means that
happens every single time this generator
is called so then if we look over at the
the receipt function it's generating 32
bytes from Julie see the index global
variable is set to 32 for some reason
and then back in the main generate
function this loop never execute because
index is 32 so the loop guard is always
false and thus at the end of the
function what we have is 32 bytes from
dual EC left in the output array this
global output array which is the output
of this particular function so what's
going on here well we've got these
global output and index variables and
the they're being reused for different
purposes so the output variable is being
used both as a temporary 32 byte buffer
for the receipt function and it's also
being used as the main output for the
PRNG and this index variable is global
for some reason that doesn't make any
sense and will actually come back to
this later when we look at the history
of this like why is this global and I
should note that the the a bunch of
people were looking at this code and
we're saying well I don't understand how
anything could go wrong with this
including me until Willem Pinker's on
Twitter pointed out that that when the
receipt happens the the ansi generator
is in fact not being around so he was
the one who figured out that the key to
this whole thing and so from this we can
answer our first research question why
doesn't the use of X 9.31 defend against
a compromised Q well X 931 is never used
so it can't possibly do anything so to
answer the second question which is why
does a change in Q lead to passive
decryption we somewhat unfortunately
need to talk about the internet key
exchange so Ike is used among other
things for establishing traffic keys for
VPN sessions and there are two major
versions of Ike which I'll collide v1
and IP to
and both of them have two phases which
is at least seem to me coming from a TLS
world somewhat unusual but the first
phase establishes keys to encrypt the
second phase and the second phase
establishes keys for use for IPSec or
some other sort of encapsulated protocol
and in both cases these are basically
classic diffie-hellman protocols
so let's if we if we take a look at at
one of the ike phase 1 packets that gets
transferred we can see that there's a
header and a series of payloads that
follow it so there's a payload that says
which crypto algorithms are we going to
use there's a key exchange payload which
contains a diffie-hellman public key G
to the X and there's a nonce which the
standard says should be between 8 and
128 bytes long and in screen OS the
private key is this 20-byte value X
which is generated by dual EC and the
nonce is always a 32 byte value which is
also generated by dual EC now in an
ideal world and ideal for the attacker
world I should say the way the attacker
would attack this is by applying the the
sumo Ferguson attack basically directly
so if the nonce is generated before the
private key then the it looks something
like this so we have to run dual EC a
few times we get a nonce and we get this
this value X and so what you do is you
run this you will Ferguson attack on the
nonce which gives you this internal
state s2 and then you just generate X
compute G to the X and you check did
that work so basically what I described
before
unfortunately what appears to happen if
you look at the code and you look at the
protocol is that the nonce appears to be
generated after the diffie-hellman
private key is generated and so the sumo
Ferguson attack doesn't actually recover
X right so you could you run your attack
over here on r2 you get s3 but you've
missed
on X because X has already been
generated and you can't try to run your
attack on X because if you had accident
there wouldn't be anything to do so so
that doesn't work so initially I was a
little disheartened when I saw this
because it seemed like you would have to
deal with multiple connections but it
turns out that the reality is somewhere
between the ideal case and the apparent
case screen OS contains cues of
pre-generated Nantes and diffie-hellman
values and the reason it does this
presumably is to speed up VPN
connections these boxes are not super
powerful and you know computing G to the
X could be an expensive operation and so
critically the the nonce q is always
filled before any of the other queues so
there's a timer that fires and once a
second it will say I'm going to generate
one value and either I'm generated nonce
or I'll generate it if you Hellman
public key and it always has the nonce
is first and the consequence of that is
that in many cases the ideal attack
really just works the nonce was
generated before the private key and so
you look at one transfer you look at a
transcript of a single VPN connection
and what do you see well you've got the
nonce and you've got G to the X and you
can run the attack on the knots and get
X and I guess I should point out that it
is in fact possible for the nonce is to
be generated after X for example if you
make a bunch of connections quickly you
can exhaust the nonce Q before it's had
a chance to refill and then in that case
you have to deal with multi connection
attacks and you can see the the paper
for all the the hairy details about that
one interesting thing about ike is that
at least for Ike v1 the authentication
mode that is chosen and for I could be
one at least there are four
authentication modes actually has an
impact on the the traffic keys on the
the encryption keys not merely on the
authentication and so if you have
authentication via digital signatures
then the attack works exactly as
described there's nothing more that you
have to do if you're using Ike be one
with pre-shared keys then it turns out
that the pre-shared key is actually
mixed into the traffic keys so the
attacker needs to know the pre-shared
key in order for this attack to work and
for the two modes involving public key
encryption
well the nonces are encrypted and
there's just no way to run the attack
and it doesn't work at all and
interestingly in Ike v2 the
authentication modes don't affect the
traffic keys at all so the attack just
works and that's actually that's that's
kind of sad we would like later versions
of a protocol to be more secure against
attack than earlier ones but in this
case that's not snatcher so what about
phase two well phase two some more
nonces are exchanged optionally another
diffie-hellman exchange happens and to
attack this it's actually pretty easy
you can either just rerun the Schumer
Ferguson attack or even easier is you
could run the dual EC generator forward
to just get the the new values you care
about and the proof of concept that I'm
about to describe here we actually just
ran the Schumer Ferguson attack again
because it was fast enough and it it
meant we didn't have to bother dealing
with with values that were sort of
generated far apart so to test that this
actually works
we bought a net screen SSG 550 m which
you can see over on the right and we
replaced the Q value in the firmware
exactly as the attackers did with a Q
that I generated so I knew the discrete
log D and then we set it up to do to
have VPN connections with a variety of
different configurations and sure enough
the attacks worked as described I could
be one with pre-shared keys required the
pre-shared keys using an RSA cert it
just worked fine and for Ike v2 the
attack just worked fine so that gives us
the answer to our second research
question why does a change in Q result
in passive VPN decryption well
the dual EC output is right there on the
wire we just run the Shema Ferguson
attack and at least for some VPN
configurations that's sufficient alright
so we figured out what the attacker did
and we figured out why it works but now
we have this question of of why does
screen OS do this is this something that
was there from the beginning probably
not and in fact one of the things that i
did was i reverse-engineered a whole
bunch of other versions of the firmware
you saw on the table and we can see that
there are a number of differences
between screen OS 6.1 and 6.2 in
particular 6.2 added dual ec in this
cascade with ansi x9 31 it moved from
reseeding on every 10,000 calls to the
generator to reseeding on every call
there was this bug with the index
variable that was now global so that it
it exposed the dual EC output even more
interesting than Mike Knotts has changed
from 20 bytes to 32 bytes and 6.2 added
a nonce pre generation cue and so this
the set of changes actually raises a
number of questions why why were these
changes made so I want to go through
them quickly and sort of offer my
thoughts on them from an engineering a
cryptographic or a standardization point
of view so why was dual EC at it I don't
know this is a this was kind of a weird
thing I can't think of any engineering
reason that would require this and in
fact in 6.2 as far as I remember the
only thing that the elliptic curve math
was doing was doing dual EC so they had
to add a bunch of custom code to their
OpenSSL version in order to use dual EC
so it seems like a weird trade-off to me
and I can't think of any standardization
reason for doing this a screen OS was
had was Phipps certified 4x 931 already
so they didn't need that and in
they never got it certified for dual EC
so I'm not really sure next
why does screen OS 6.2 reseed on every
call so on the left you can see 6.1 and
on the right we have 6.2 here and you'll
notice that this reseed counters global
receipt counter was retained in 6.2 but
it doesn't do anything it gets
incremented and then when X 931 reseed
gets called it gets set backs to 0 so so
the receipt value doesn't do anything
anymore
so why does this happen well I can't
really think of an engineering reason to
reseed every time maybe there's a
cryptographic reason maybe they were
trying to add backtracking resistance to
X 9.31 I don't know maybe a
cryptographer could could enlighten me
could just be a buck next there's the
receipt bug
so in 6.1 we can see that output was
initially a parameter to the PRNG
generate function and index was a local
variable then when they moved 26.2 both
of these become global variables for
some reason I I don't know why I can't
think of any good engineering reason for
doing this I can think of kind of a bad
one but it's not we're talking about it
could just be another bug but it's a
really strange one I don't think I've
ever changed a global there a local
variable to a global variable
accidentally so I don't know what's
going on there next we have the ike not
size increase so 6.2 as I mentioned
increase the nonce size from 20 bytes to
32 bytes again I can't think of an
engineering reason to require this I
can't think of a good graphic reason
although I will note that the Department
of Defense had some bizarre to me line
about how you wanted the public
randomness to be at least so big and so
they wanted to do this and TLS maybe
this is the reason here I'm not sure but
I will note that at 20 bytes the sumo
Fergusson attack would take about 2 to
the 96 scalar multiplications which is
completely infeasible
would never be able to do it we're at 32
bytes it takes two to the 16 and finally
there was this nonce pre generation Q
that was added to the diffie-hellman pre
generation Q's so in 6.1 there was the
the diffie-hellman Jenner pre generation
Q by itself and this is actually
reasonable as I mentioned these are not
very powerful devices
so perhaps computing G to the X mod P
was sufficiently slow that they decided
to do it ahead of time that makes sense
to me in 6.2 they added the nonce pre
generation Q and the only thing that I
can think of here is that when I
measured this on my laptop dual EC was
about 125 times slower than using X 931
and so I suspect that what they did was
they switched to dual EC and they tested
how long it took to establish a VPN
session and it took a measurable amount
of time and so they said well here's
where it's slow let's just generate this
in advance so I don't know that at our
adding a nonce generation Q to handle
the fact that you're PR and G is slow is
the right move to make but it at least
makes sense from an engineering point of
view and so if we look at the changes we
can see that the first four of them were
actually required for VPN for passive
VPN decryption if you didn't have these
then the attack just doesn't work at all
and the last change enables single
connection attacks whereas if you didn't
have that you would have to do this
multi connection attack all right so
that's the the history of the VPN and
that sort of leaves us with the final
two questions are there versions of
screen or less that are vulnerable
well maybe it depends on how Q was
generated if Q was generated in a safe
way and I can describe one way of doing
that then then no the answer is it's not
vulnerable if Q is generated such that
somebody knows this integer D well then
yes it's vulnerable to whoever knows D
and so that leaves us with the final
question of how was junipers q
generated and I just can't say I I don't
I don't know and it's impossible to tell
with the data that we have and so I want
to end with with a couple of lessons for
protocol designers that I think we've
learned from this so first and this is
sort of banal PRNG is extremely
important for cryptographic protocols
and so you should pay a lot of attention
to what's going on with your PRNG
so one thing you can consider doing is
hashing the output of it before you put
it on the wire if you have a good PR ng
this is a pointless step if you have a
bad one maybe this will help you I don't
know it would have in this case perhaps
more important is you should look very
closely at any proposed changes to the
amount ya ng output that is being put on
the wire we've seen instances in the
past where the NSA has tried to increase
the amount of random bits that go on the
wire and TLS and they didn't really
explain why and we should be very
careful about Allah knowing that a one
idea is to use separate PRNG instances
for your public random values and your
private random values and if all you
need from your public ones is that don't
repeat then this seems to work pretty
well if you need them to be
unpredictable then maybe this doesn't
help you so much next is we should think
carefully about the nonces that we're
using in our protocols for example we
should not allow nonces that are too
large or that are variable length
anything that's too large for example
Ike's allowing up to 256 bytes is is
unreasonable it's just too long you
don't need that and it just invites
implementations to expose secrets either
intentionally or unintentionally by
using bad random number generators and
it's worth pointing out that variable
length implementations allow you to
fingerprint implementations so perhaps
don't allow that one thing that was
really interesting to me from the from
comparing Ike v1 and Ike fee to
as i mentioned that i QV 2 was less
secured against a bad random number
generator and so maybe we should
consider whenever we have some low
entropy even low entropy secrets we
should consider hashing them into our
traffic and authentication keys and
finally I just want to end with talking
about this this concept of no bus so the
NSA has this notion of nobody but us so
these are things that they don't feel
like these are vulnerabilities for
example that they don't feel like they
have to reveal because the because
nobody but us would be able to exploit
them and dual ec is indistinguishable
from a building block of a no bus
exceptional access mechanism and I think
that this is a pretty clear warning of
what happens when we include exceptional
access mechanisms either in our
protocols or in our implementations that
can be co-opted by third parties and
that's just really bad and so I think we
should be very clear here in the IETF or
I RTF that we should really not be
building exceptional access into our
protocols okay thank you
[Applause]
hi Steve
Kenny Patterson let me just start by
saying I think this is really amazing
work and you probably didn't tell us
exactly how many hours you spent in the
lab ruining your Christmas to do all the
reverse engineering and congratulations
that's really amazing thank you I have I
also have a question and what public
statements to Juniper make about the
penetration of their software
development entity or section that led
to this right so what public statements
did they make I I think they they had
the the out of cycle advisory that
started all of the this work and then
they eventually decided to remove dual
EC from their products altogether I
think they made an announcement about
that I'm not sure if there's been any
other public statements so they didn't
make any public statements about the
mechanism by which they were penetrated
or their mediations they took in
response to that or anything of that
same nothing that I've seen I've been
contacted by a number of reporters who
have asked me if I had any insight in
town that it that happened and the
answer is no I have no idea how how that
happened okay
thank you thank you i Stephen Feil yeah
I totally agree to ask but I thought you
might your honor I think this is a fine
lesson a demonstration of the detail of
exactly the crap consequences if we did
go so stupid I hope I hope everybody is
listening I'm not just me what question
yeah he said on your previous slide you
kind of recommends yes before putting on
the wire so there's two people who are
interested in the quic protocol or
probably on here they're meeting that
but they're having like fun debates
about in a new transfer protocol what to
leave in the public header that might be
visible on the wire versus what to put
in ciphertext including things like
packet numbers which may not be
sequential and may hence be efforts
around us yeah so I guess that's all
a question if you thought about if there
are other kind of places and protocols
that we might be exposing randomness you
know in ways we haven't really thought
about the possible attacks like this
it's a good question
I'm actually not sure all of the places
that one might be exposing randomness
and the obvious ones are nonsense that
we that we send but I hadn't thought
about sequence numbers I I guess I
haven't looked at quick in quite a while
but I would have assumed a sequence
number was sequential but you're saying
that's not true so I don't know so I
haven't been involved with details quick
but there was one male earlier today on
the list is suggesting that you could
randomly pick higher bits and then just
have the lower bits differential which
may give some better properties in some
way but I guess just we need to think
about being careful about that kind of
thing yeah absolutely I feel how big
yeah
I'm just amazed that anybody would want
to do this in the first place because if
you go back to your original slide when
you doing the Dooly okay it's not like
they're using the curve 255 1 9 curve or
whatever where yeah it's pretty close to
the power of 2 I mean these are you know
the NIST curves and so on and so they're
gonna wrap is it even an embarrassed
random number generator no absolutely
not it is biased and one of the reasons
that that it only uses 30 bytes of the
32 byte output is precisely to deal with
that there's some analysis and SP 800 -
90 about about why that is a that was
the right trade-off to use and I admit I
didn't totally follow why that was the
case but but there is there is a bias I
tried measuring it and there's some some
numbers in the the paper about
distributions of values you get and it
was pretty hard to distinguish so the
bias seemed fairly low to me yeah but me
like you're going 125 times slower and
you know if you just fiddle around with
merkle-damgard construction you can
create yourself one that's unbiased with
the free
sure yeah I don't know why anybody would
use Dooley see it in that nist special
publication there are three other
pseudo-random number generators one of
which was designed by the NSA the other
two by i think john kelsey at nist and
or others at nist and all of those are
much much faster than dual ec there's
there's no reason to to use it okay well
thank you to our a and our p awardees
and i'll come up again for a moment
thank you I'm gonna ask you so are there
any folks who are in the the miracle
queue who wanted to ask questions so
either of our speakers now since I can't
see it you guys will have to tell me if
anyone moves okay all righty that um
it's really hot in here
so I think that I'm going to spare you
I'm going to have a really long
discussion now so use up every last bit
of our time now I'm going to spare you a
further discussion but I will ask a
request some some interaction on the IRT
F discuss mailing lists about some of
the directions of publish out the the
overview that I gave to the EDD team and
asked you guys to give your your views
and so thank you very much for being at
this IRT F open maybe you can go get
some drinks be set early on and deal
with your dehydration and thank you so
much to our speakers you guys need this
day so we can photograph you getting
your plaques sorry oh yes yes and if
anyone wants to stay and applaud the
receiving of the plaques you're welcome
to stay all right
till next time we have two more awardees
for the next ITF so hold your breath
till I announce those
[Music]
you