so yeah wellness okay so on so let's
think of the meeting so this is new
version not well it's very important to
be well this for any ITF meetings and
thanks from heat for the to be the
meanest takers and he's going to edit
our notes on the ether pad and okay we
also have some okay great not a poor
number okay I will change this you know
I think it's on the agenda now Larry's
coming so we also have a github page for
our working group with our draft so this
is some updates of our status of walking
boo right now so we have the energy
efficient routes which is in ad scan
right now or else we she's not here
right now so I think he's catching up
with Oh sweetie come so we I already
started
so we have an agenda we we miss to
milestone right now including the Quinto
draught and crypto draft and the Co app
drop so but yes I I think we do need
some good pushers of this draft in order
to get it down to be some into to the
iesg I personally read the cooperator
again I think it's pretty good draft and
but anyway release some somebody to make
some edits before I can ship it to the
ISD and we have some green ones which
will be discussed today which is the TCP
draft and also TCP guidance raft and
also the ESP garden draft so suresh
krisshnan has ad
so the energy efficient stuff just came
in to me like couple of weeks ago it's
been a request at i/o to do review of
this so they're taking a look at it so
hopefully we'll get a review for that
and there's also in the review going out
so like once that is done I'll do my
eval and send it to ITF class cough so
hopefully like in a month month and a
half it'll be in front of the IES you
okay thank you second series here's our
agenda so so we all talked about
basically so the first three drafts will
be wheezing our count walking charter
and we are going to discuss it and the
main object of the meeting today will be
asked for the option and for further
steps of this draft and the forest for
the last one on the agenda is going to
be asked for the interest of the draft
so how to get impulse for our group so
any question regarding the chain okay
pretty good so I can move to the first
prison thing
yes yes so basically this draft
providing some recommendation on how to
secure machine to machine communication
with IPSec ESP and is believed to while
IPSec ESP history is believed to present
some significant advantages for small
devices especially regarding
interoperability VPN its transport layer
independent its key management
independent and it has a lower overhead
than TLS the presentation has already
already be made in Berlin in the ITF 96
during the six low motivation remains
the same and so the problem is that the
standards face standard espy is likely
to be implemented by many different
small devices and well this document is
intended to make sure that these new
implementation light implementation
still be compatible with the standard
one so basically we described how can
what are the mandatory features as well
as where other feeders have they can be
implemented in light waste depending on
the context and the the use of those so
overall these though we already have an
IKE a minimal Ike v2 in this working
group so this document is continuing the
effort for ESP so we had a presentation
during the building meeting and the
document was
believed to need more reviews from the
IPC Kimmy working group so we had I
think it was last ITF from such another
physician but a good review of the
document and we received a significant
amount of feedbacks so now we think we
it's relatively mature which doesn't
mean that we well we expect a few more
reviews and process and back and forth
the document is clearly handled between
the two groups so it's not that we're
trying to hide the document and the the
updates from IPSec Amy there are still
heavily involved and we're going to
require them to review in detail to the
document so what are the changes since
the last version so we probably spent
some time clarifying the purpose of
minimal implementation and from the
presentation it was thought that we were
designing a ESP v2 which is not the case
so it is the two bits so we clarified
the text on the SPI so we detailed on
how it can be handled with multicast or
anycast communications we detailed in
detail how we can use a fixed value for
a spi or limited number of values for
SPR in case of some devices would not we
could hardly generate a random divider
andum SP all right
we also clarified that it doesn't mean
that you don't need randomness because
for crypto you need randomness so it's
just a way to avoid generating new SPI
we clarify the padding so our padding
was correct
I mean it was I think it was wrong
statement and we clearly mentioned it as
mandatory and we also clarify with well
ESP got some mechanisms so that you you
can provide some additional padding so
that you don't leak any information
about the size of the packet so well for
a minimal version we clearly mentioned
that these kind of features are not
mandatory or not expected to be part of
such implementation next header
well we clarified the meaning of the
next header and also define that that
was a missing part in the last version
that you you have to remove to to be
able to disk out some dummy packets ICV
while it was mostly a clarification
because the text was suggesting you can
cut some part of the ICV or make some
ICD optional which was really not the
case so that has been clarified in the
current version and that's about all
would you eat we received some
additional comments we will address in a
further version and we would like to
continue this draft I mean in this
working group but in collaboration with
IPSec I mean we have well there are some
known implementations user load library
in C Python and we have some supporting
Kentucky riot and you will see later an
implementation of this minimal I for
group sorry for a group key so at the
end of this session so this is where we
are and we would like to look that work
for what
can you see a little bit more about the
implementations like bison
implementation that hard leads for IOT
devices but it was mostly for testing
the specs and testing the
interoperability with so which which of
the ESP the IOT OSS implement that so we
have one in Kentucky okay and I I have
heard that some in realtor Tobias from
LMU the implementation for Kentucky is
very old that's done by Shahid Raza this
group and we are currently developing
one in riot so um Hannes again so I
think we should not do that work it's a
terrible idea
we IPSec provides no benefits the
motivation that you a percentage is just
nonsense it will it will if people
actually use it it will actually add
another security mechanisms that people
don't have to support which adds
fragmentation it I think it's a terrible
idea it doesn't do as a service it's
just bad
so this is an opinion but we have a few
vendors that are quite interested in
using IP sex the eternal communion one
of the good things about you know losing
IPSec we said you can ask use also use
the I curse and to to generate the keys
for the 15 for layer which you can't use
the TLS because 15 9 doesn't support TLS
because there was nobody to write the
traps for that so that for for if you
want to have one crypto algorithm you
and one encrypted protocol you can have
I person to an ESP and nothing else you
don't need to Ellis at that point so but
actually I guess in most of the cases in
this kind of confronting basis you pick
one and you talk to whatever is your you
know cloud or whatever service you have
there so if you use TLS use TLS
everywhere that you don't support this
if you use IPSec use IPSec everywhere
and you got super TLS so it's you know
whatever you pick and you pick what what
is suitable for your there your needs
wait so are you implementing I and I be
sick for a 15 or 4 foot and this type of
stuff in your products as I don't work
any better anything but anyway so so 15
4 has you know I'll Greenwich that
allows you to carry to prepare barsky's
and I person is one of those is that the
15 so I'm not totally familiar with some
of the that I Triple E work but is that
the I Triple E work where it basically
standardized hip as a key management
banner or and everything you can imagine
[Laughter]
so are you are you guys going to use
this in your products in you are like
black we are making things up a little
bit well we we know some some some
customers that are gonna use that yes I
you Erickson going to use this stuff in
your IOT devices
I can't probably detail what for you're
gonna implement
well I don't think I'm here to to
detailed what is too broad mass for
Erickson as a vendor so so I'm not
asking for roadmap but he be are
standardizing something they are
providing implementation guidance so
presumably you have done something we we
were to standardize something as
guidance from implementations that
Hutt's has actually been done rather
than something that we may or may not do
suresh krisshnan so Hannes just hold on
a second
the thing is like it's like an early
individual draft right at some point
he's gonna go for an implementation I
understand right like nobody's requiring
implementation for adoption it's a good
thing to have right so yeah so if I
understand you correctly your questions
should be right
maybe I'm paraphrasing it's like why do
you see a need for this is that the
right way to put it okay so he's saying
he has a need for it right like and
we're trying to figure out if somebody
else has a need for it I think that's
where he's at so if if somebody's trying
to see need for it then we'll go forward
if not like this whole discussion is
moot right we just move on right say
Daniel go away and that's it right so I
I fully agree with your point at some
point we need an implementation like as
a personal draft I don't know I think
it's a bit early for that
anyway they recognize he's not going to
try trying to standardize anything new
this is standard ESP it's going to it's
already standardized it has been out
there for a long time he starts
describing what kind of tricks and
things you can do to make it's very
small so you don't have to implement
that you don't have to read the whole
OSP and this is same thing made it mean
minute amount in a more like I mean
there is Ike is almost already at what
is at that point but the problem was it
was you know 150 page 100 100 pages and
had all kind of feature that you don't
need you don't need not trouble or
something you don't need that kind of
things and so on in most of the minimal
cases you don't need those
we were actually documenting just what
we don't need this is the same thing in
ESP I Hannes again I think also it was a
bad idea to standardize this minimal
Ikey
since the reason is what as some feature
is really useful or not depends on what
your environment is like the natural
bristle if you talk to like previously
mentioned you talk to some cloud a
service probably you will have
naturalism um
and so on so you just stripped out up
sort of random things and busy
I bring if I remember correctly it was
you focus on the BSK version of course
that gets the code size small but that
may be a right thing to do
in some deployments in some use case and
not in others we never had any
experience with those use cases and
that's why it feels arbitrary for
example the 15 459 I question 2 is using
the minimal one because it does it
doesn't need not reverse or because it's
perverse keys between two devices it
actually doesn't know most of the
features of a person - it just uses the
key generation given it said so so yes
there is you she said yes this will of
fragment no environment but that will
happen anyway and it's actually already
happening because I mean there is
thousands of you know implementations
using their own proprietary stuff and as
long as they use anything from here it's
much much better than 10 proprietary and
if they're prepared the requirements are
that they need to be you know sending IP
packet they don't want to do TLS they
don't do anything like that this might
be shooting better for them than 10 the
TLS if it doesn't they used to tell us
it's it's you know they've been they are
breaking their product table decide what
they are going to use I don't think it's
our your point of view say oh you go you
must not use this or because they will
use anyway whatever have but what they
want I know so Hannah's first first I
think we will Shepherd the minimal I
document we asked for your opening and
you said this is a good document we
should share it as soon as possible
I mean when we share for the minimal I'd
document we ask for your opening and you
I think I think I will still remember
the email you said you said we should
publish it as soon as possible okay
and the secondly and secondly currently
even for the FC for the 78th 25 25 so
for the minimum item is is nothing
normative right this national team is
informational so it tells people how to
implement a minimal client of the IKE
you know you know your protocol you know
protocol compliance way so I don't want
to continue this discussion I just
started suggestions RFC 7 9 mm son how
to improve awareness of implementation
so since you do have some some
implementations it would be good to have
a section documenting them which of them
are open source where I can get them and
so on that working definitely help so
now I go at the draft and I I don't know
about the implementations yeah that's
something that can be easily put added
so so then you test one thing I I was
are not clear right now so because you
say that you want to continue to have
this document in L week as well as IP ii
e so that's that mean that you don't
want to ask for call option today no no
I when I ask for adoption today okay so
so because of because of the hanys
comments I think we should first ask
questions like these so how many people
think that this is the question we this
is the valuable question we want to
solve it in this working group please
please raise your hands so if it's our
so yeah if you think that this is the
right problem that we need to solve in a
week walking group please raise your
hand
like 10 so so you feel don't sing that
or if you don't think that this is the
right play this is right problem we need
to solve you know it please say so hands
okay we got is so let the minutes not
that Hana sauce in the rough in the room
Hana sauce in the rough in the room okay
then we excellence
everything is green you know right here
we simply do some video I thought it
some more like flashes like that he used
ok hello good afternoon my name is
Carlos Gomez and I'm going to present
the last update of the draft entitled
TCP over constrain node networks by the
way we are pleased to have Michael sharp
as a new member of the author team and
would like to help him Troy well thank
you for the contributions that he has
already made so far so first of all a
quick reminder on the motivation for
this document so nowadays we have
several application layer protocols that
are being used for IOT scenarios for
example we have the constrained
application protocol co-op which was
originally designed over UDP however
there's also an ongoing co-op over TCP
specification in progress that's mostly
motivated by the need to overcome
problems with middle boxes that appear
not to be very friendly to UDP traffic
also we have that HTTP 2 and even HTTP
1.1 have been used and are being used in
some IOT scenarios and then we have
other application layer protocol such as
XMPP or MQTT especially the last one is
very popular which rely also on TCP at
the transport layer so we have that
despite that TCP has been quite
neglected and even unfairly criticized
as a protocol for the IOT TCP is being
used and will be used in many IATA
scenarios so the purpose of this
document is to offer simple measures for
suitable TCP implementation and
operation over constrain node networks
so let's look at the status of the draft
the initial version was presented in
Berlin one year ago
in both elegant eCPM sessions then the
document was subsequently updated the
was 0 1 & 0 2 which represented in Seoul
and in Chicago respectively and today
I'm presenting the last update which is
0 3 where we have addressed comments
received in Chicago and also we provide
details on the riot and open WS n TCP
implementations by the way thanks to
Simon rumor and avi village asana for
kindly providing details on these two
implementations just a quick note to say
thanks to everyone who has provided
comments and feedback and input for this
draft since the initial version so
thanks a lot everyone so let's go
through the updates in this last
revision of the draft the first update
is in the subsection titled maximum
segment size there was a related
discussion in Chicago about nodes that
use technologies that support an MTU
which is greater than 280 bytes
according to RFC 1981 those nodes should
support path MTU discovery by the way
there's a note in that RFC that states
that a minimal ipv6 implementation may
choose to omit implementing path MTU
discovery and the date in the document
also based in the based on the comments
received in Chicago is that unless
applications require handling large data
units that meaning leading to an ipv6
Datagram size greater than 280 bytes it
is desirable to limit the MTU to 1280
bytes by doing this we avoid MTU issues
along the end-to-end path and also we
avoid the need to support path MTU
discovery
so another update is in subsection 4.8
which is about delayed acknowledgments
so we have that constrained device will
be in some scenario sending data to some
peer and the peer may not be a
constrained device so we may recommend
we can be giving guidance for
constrained devices but a problem is
that sometimes the peer device will not
be a constraint device and usually those
unconstrained devices have delayed
acknowledgments enabled so that means
that acknowledgments may be delayed by
typically 200 milliseconds it could be
even up to 500 milliseconds and if
traffic is of transactional type which
is quite common in constrained known
networks that would contribute a
necessary delay so if that's possible at
all disabling delayed acknowledgments
would be recommended for example that
might be possible if the peer is
administered by the same entity managing
the constraint on network however in
some scenarios that may not be possible
yes it confusion if the traffic's is
transactional type and if the server is
not responding very slowly then you
don't the the delay that doesn't matter
at all because then the acknowledgment
acknowledgment transmit the response as
piggybacked so if the server for example
replies between 200 milliseconds to read
or acknowledgements that don't have any
meaning yeah but if you send that data
message and that's all then the
acknowledgement will be triggered will
be transmitted by the the other endpoint
if the server is sends the response so
they come back within 200 milliseconds
or whatever is their delay a climber
then the response the the ACK comes back
with the response so there is no delay
ik mechanism in such a case
you mean if this piggybacking but what
happens if it is the the sensor is the
constrain device that's sending a data
message it's expecting an acknowledgment
without any data so it's a pure
acknowledgment in that case that's just
adding some delay which mail order
that's no transaction oh that's that's
kind of all you need erection of them
well yeah so I've seen the transactional
terminology used in some places but well
let's maybe try to clarify the
terminology so that it's clear thank you
okay so another update is in the annex
of the document so if you remember
there's design acts where we are
collecting details the main features of
constraint TCP implementations so now we
have other details on the riot disappea
implementation so this is an
implementation design for class one
devices targets are 8 and 16-bit
microcontrollers the implementation is
based on single MSS window so this
simplifies the implementation and by
default there's only enough memory for
single TCP connection so at this point
so far it might seem like riot TCP
implementation is quite similar to my
creepy however it is not as minimalistic
as my creepy because for example the
memory locate that can be increased to
support multiple parallel connections
and then there's an independent buffer
provided for each connection and also
retransmission is handled by TCP itself
as opposed to what happens in micro IP
where it is the application developer
who needs to take care of
retransmissions rather I mean I beg to
differ here even in case of you IP even
in case of micro IP the TCP buffers are
handled by the TC I mean it's not
application handles only for UDP it
works that way participate won't work
that way because there are other
sequence I mean I
mentioned this in my review comments as
well yes it's impossible for application
to generate the same sequence numbers
the data part if you see yeah yeah so I
agree with you
and the point is then the application
needs to have some reliability so the
application layer cannot rely on TCP in
this case for retransmissions I mean I
agree that you cannot create like the
whole TCP segment with the header and so
on so I definitely agree but that means
also that the application cannot rely on
TCP for retries in this case I just want
to sorry yeah I just want to make one
statement the current micro IP
implementation has multiple connections
every connection has one buffer and it
handles three transmissions so this is
what I have already
okay so then possibly there's something
to clarify about the versions so also
even if you have input we would
appreciate very much this thank you okay
then we have also added details on the
open wsn discipline tation although this
subsection is fairly shorter than the
previous one overall it is that open wzn
is according to the details we have
received is mostly equivalent to my
crappy implementation it is really
minimal and as in micro P there is a
problem with not performing
retransmission so the application
developer needs to take care of of this
so this is the summary table where we
are trying to summarize the main
features and mechanisms of the different
TCP implementations for constrained
devices so as you can see we have filled
in most of the details for the riot and
open WSM implementations and we have
also added the rightmost column for tiny
OS this is currently just a placeholder
so tiny OS has been relevant
in several IOT scenarios so we plan to
add details on the TCP implementation of
tiny OS as well in future updates of the
document so at this point the author's
understand that the document is quite
stable also it is getting more and more
complete with the successive updates so
we would like to ask whether this would
be a good moment for working group
adoption of Agincourt Acharya actually I
have a very generic question the matter
is that closer to mic I have a very
generic question that is when the www
this worldwide wave that came into
picture then a classical problem emerged
for TCP which is short flow on TCP and
there has been several work that has
gone through it so it is I mean only a
few segments maybe few kilobytes of data
that has to be transmitted and one
problem that is the slow start and the
condition control that actually created
that was actually not giving the optimal
performance both in terms of utilizing
the increasing bandwidth that the the
the network was offering so will it be a
dimension that also needs to be
considered here because there has been
work like limited transmit and this kind
of work limited transmit was actually
dedicated for I think it was arrested
three four zero two so it was very old
RFC but these works were a limit
actually for performing these or
improving TCP performance for these
things so because I am currently working
on something similar to that and I'm
facing some I had to do the study so
that is what a just a general proposal
whether these dimensions can be taken up
yes so I so the you read any version of
these forecasts and I haven't seen the
mention that is I am commenting
very good yes so uh I understand we can
consider this so in a way we are
considering that for example in many
applications that would be a sensor that
is going to be maybe trying to send one
data message per hour for us as long as
possible so that's different from the
use case you are explaining then I'm
wondering if maybe TCP first open might
be a good solution here for the use case
you are yeah I've seen that actually TFO
is in the draft because I rather have
seen scenario so thanks for that yes so
we can revise the document and see if
maybe we could we can more explicitly
refer to those kinds of situations
possible yes I think that will be good
yeah thank you thank you so my name is
Michael Shara from a course or row but
I'm actually speaking yours ttpm culture
I would suggest this work and hope to
adopt the document it's very clearly
understood that work is needed and but I
think it's heading into the right
direction I'm not sure if the milestone
day that I've seen earlier in the chart
is realistic because at least in TCP
n/bar a little bit slow this reviews but
in general I think this should be
adopted by this working group
okay good so any more comments questions
okay so first let me ask if you have
read any version of this draft please
raise your hand so if you think that
this if you if you are supportive to do
a top this draft in a week please raise
your hands so if you are now supportive
of adoption please raise your hand
[Music]
so it's pretty clear
yeah thanks use your sticker
sorry oh yeah hello everyone I'm Rahul
shadow from War II technologies so I'm
here to talk about neighbor management
policies for 6lowpan so some background
the note so why is this this kind of
worker actually required so in case of
multi-hop networks the node density is
it can be anything it's it's hard it's
hard to pry it what the node density can
be and the neighbor cache size in case
of a constraint node can be really
really small it can be small even if you
can allocate more in F memory it would
be suboptimal so the point is no density
is high what to do the neighbour cache
is going to be really small so how do
you prioritize the entries here how do
you prioritize the entries here and
ensure which ensure the entries that
remain in the neighbor cache would
result in least churn of the network so
when I say churn what I mean is that it
should be possible to to enable proper
routing adjacency so that such that the
network paths don't keep on changing now
the reason why this this this work is
important is because and if you're
playing with two or five or ten nodes on
a table till that point everything works
out okay at the moment you go to 50
nodes hundred nodes and you have a
neighbor table size which is like 10
you're going to need to you're going to
have you're going to have to have
neighbor management policy in place so
some of the popular implementations so
right implements
FCFS quantity used to implement least
recently used entry so what it does is
it just replaces the least recently used
entry I had in case of riot it it
populates the whatever comes on on the
first come first serve basis
the problem is in case of ripple based
Network or in case of multi hop Network
you you will have a DI of storm or a
Taoist storm and your or your neighbor
cache is going to be populated with the
same with all the parent entries and you
won't have any space left for child
entries so there's one typical example
mentioned by yo Keem on the this was
mentioned on the mailing list but from
my perspective I work for a metering
solution and the node density can easily
run up to hundreds of nodes in the same
vicinity it's in sub gigahertz mode and
it can easily cross hundreds of nodes
this so how do you manage them neighbor
cache entry so that is what this draft
tries to solve the problem so the
considerations here are it's a security
enable 6lowpan ripple Network for the
sake of explanation I have used ripple
as the routing protocol pana as the
access protocol and of course neighbor
disk out is there so three places where
primarily the neighbor table update
happens is the initial to really be
signaling so before the network
formation comes into picture you have to
authenticate the node to the network and
that's where panic amps into picture
second is the repose parent selection
algorithm third is when the check when
the routing child load advertises itself
to the network now there's one thing I
have to mention here that even though
I've mentioned pana because I have used
banner but the the problem is also
present in case of six stitch we're
currently there is the PRI element the
prev the panel element is called as a
join proxy there I mean the same problem
statement exists in 60 shell as well so
these are the terms that are used in
case of six station animal working group
so the neighbor management operation I
will be real quick here it's the three
operations broadly insertion eviction
and reinforcement
and the primary problem with any
insertion is you have you will have so
the way routing protocol works is you
you have a storm going down spiraling
downwards downstream and then you have a
Down messaging which comes upwards so
this is how the downstream and upstream
paths are established so if all the d io
messages are accepted by a child gets
like 10 euros from ten different parents
then the table is going to be full in
the first place so there is no space
left for the child entries so how do you
handle this case eviction in case of
eviction if you end up everything a
childhood entry it will have a ripple
effect on all the other child sub charts
as well so it's it's it's not very easy
to evict a child entry well this is true
for storing mode of operation only but
the good news in case of eviction for
eviction for parent entries is that you
can actually evict a non-preferred
parent now this I'm talking in I'm using
very specific terms to ripple all right
so if you have it the non-preferred
parent it is possible to evict it
without much implications and I'm going
to we are going to make use of this
particular intelligence in in the
routing policy in the neighbor
management policy as well the
reinforcements the link quality
estimation has to be updated over a
period of time if you can use an active
or passive mechanism quantity has an
active mechanism in the form of active
probing of neighbors passive mechanism
can be you over here the D IOT's or the
other messages in the network and you
can update the link estimation clearing
unused entries now this is also very
important because you want to release
the neighbor cache entry as soon as
possible so as to so that it can be
allocate to something else so in case of
storing mode of operation route
invalidation is is important because
routing entries are directly mapped to
the neighbor cache entries in case of
knowledge non storing mode of
implementation you've got to deregister
using NS with lifetime of 0 while not
many implementations do that currently
and in case of PRA neighbors there is an
interesting question actually I'm not
sure whether whether six station has a
way to handle this but there is no way
currently in Penner to know
for the relay element to know whether
the authentication has been completed so
that it can ever or it can it can just
delete the neighbor cache entry so that
it can be used for something else so
what we propose is a reservation based
policy where few few amount of so the
reservation is done for routing child
entries the parent entries and the PRU
are sessions or otherwise we call it
other other sessions basically one good
thing about this reservation policy is
that if if the routing child entries are
unavailable or not present then the
parent and seats can still occupy the
whole table because like I mentioned
before non-preferred parent eviction can
be done so this is what we try to do to
optimize the usage of the records in the
neighbor cache entry in the name of
cache table the insertion reason needs
to be kept as part of the neighbor cache
entry because obviously it's going to
help in the eviction process now well
whatever mechanism I've mentioned just
now is or reactive what I mean by
reactive is that if the table space is
actually not available you send a
message for example you send a down
message the parent is going to reply
back saying that I don't have a space
just check on with some other parent a
parent node and it's going to fail the
problem with this kind of approaches
after some time the same previous parent
is going to send this d io message and
since the child has lost its taste
information there's no way for it to
know that you know it can't go to that
parent so in case of ripple right now
there is no way to know that the table
space is all utilized so as of now
whatever we have mentioned in the draft
is all reactive but it has its
limitations that that's what the slide
talks about so in a way what we want is
want is a parent node to signal in some
form to the child node saying that I
still have table space available now
six-stage does this there's an ask
beacons which has this bit which says
that I'm still the join proxy I'm still
the router you can connect through me
but
this kind of information is missing in
in the ripple and I feel it might be
useful there as well so this is what I
mean by the proactive wave but having
said that this is clearly out of scope
well wig and we would like to bring it
to the role working group or six row
working group for discussion so if it
was purely fewer this is by Michael
Richardson
yeah I'm Michael Richardson so if it was
purely implementation advice then of
course it would be very there any
critical action here and I actually
think that that my advice is maybe this
I want to say that maybe this belongs
somehow in neighbor discovery messages
and yet we can run ripple networks as
Carson hates without ever actually doing
router advertisements and so because it
really matters to leaf nodes right that
they hear several router advertisements
that they better pick one that actually
has space in his neighbor cash for it
and it really matches for for new
joining nodes so it'd be really nice if
that was actually in there at that level
too and maybe we have to put it in both
in the DI oh and in the name in the
router advertisement and of Carson has
an opinion of it where it goes but it
mean there's a protocol action here
about this and if you pick wrong then
you know poor little unpowered devices
that turn on once a week are screwed
because they're never in they're never
LR you'd into the cache so it's not only
about rippling six low here so in case
of key management protocol this benign
world as well a story not just moment so
Michael asked specifically whether I
have an opinion I do have an opinion if
it's for hosts it goes into Andy if it's
for out us it can go into Andy or it can
go into the routing protocol
but okay um well if it's needed by both
and then it's enable discovery because
Deborah discovery is received by both so
Costin now scoot two questions first
could you keep your comments related to
the do you have any comments with a
reactive way
rahu just discussed and the second
question is also related so for the
proactive way which working with the
best place to discuss I definitely know
layer my question essentially is try to
decide between role in six though and
given the three clothes working on
neighbor discovery to me it seems that
this is something we should fix in the
six seven seven five update process that
is going on in the system yet yet
buh-buh-buh-buh here today I really want
to listen was your comments to the
reactive way which is definitely
redeemed the scope the shadow of the
work it's probably still good to have a
document that explains how you use it I
mean if this is all explained in
wonderful detail in six seven seven five
this yeah but I think it's better to
have a document that actually reflects
implementation experience and so on so I
think this is a useful document to have
okay great yeah Michael Richardson II
and I think I would agree so I would
suggest all of the advice okay in this
document be it maybe needs to update six
seven seven five okay I don't know I
don't know you guys let's say that's the
list maybe but that but that the
proposal for it for for the additional
metrics that we need should be a new
document in six low and four or a a
proposed text 265 775 this should be
working
last call comment on 6775 this yeah so
our rationale was you know we keep this
draft here we specify the requirements
towards all the changes and then we take
on the actual changes in there okay
let's quickly ask how many people have
read these drafts any washing with
disrupt I think there's only one which
okay select five so how many how many of
you think that we should a sorry so it's
not a question so if you think that is
we should adopt is documenting yeah we
please see us raise your hand so if you
think that we should adopt this document
focusing on the react okay okay so how
many are you so if you don't think that
we should adopt this document please
raise your hands no okay prickly thank
you
hello can you hear me okay okay so I'm
here to present a bit more of a research
work it's not really an ITF document but
I'm presenting here it's about an
implementation we did on a group I
client the group Ike is another draft
which is going to be standardized
I guess quite soon the authors are here
so yeah so the motivation of doing this
work was kind of because we didn't find
any useful group key management protocol
which is deployed in IOT I know of one
DTLS which was going to be standardized
but it's or in ace that was kind of the
motivation to start this with just a
question I'm the dice work at the detail
s stuff yeah it was actually done in a
separate working group and then we
decided to abandon it because it may
change us to the DTLS that people didn't
want this document is not the one is not
your document the standard crew bike not
the minimum but have you written a
document on your stuff as well okay
that's what I'm saying okay so I just
quickly want to tell you like this also
follow up on minimal Ike because it's
pretty much correlated so what group Ike
does so the first two exchanges the
first exchange is setting up a secure
channel between client and server this
is completely standard Ike and it's also
minimal Ike so minimal I really helped
in this implementation the second part
is actually just to request secure keys
from the group server which is also
mostly the same as to I guess a I calls
in with you it's just that you don't
negotiate a key because you get from the
server that's the main difference so you
ask for a group key and you get one it's
not a negotiation of a key and three
King is basically the same we
implemented this in riot we figured out
that we need around six kilobyte of
memory to run this including
yeah the ciphers to be stored for them
actually doing group message like
securing group messages for example with
est or Aeterna to 15.4 or whatever and
we tested this on three different
devices with jars three Arduinos so it
works on every m0 device which has the
arm in Syria
Michael Richardson touch clear you need
six kilobytes to get to the end of the
process at which you have 40 bytes for
the SPD left and that's all you need to
keep afterwards sorry sorry so you need
six K to do the whole the whole time
sequence you just described no no right
it's the whole that's the whole memory
we need for the system in right there is
the right Colonel included there's 56
class okay well no no I don't mean dump
the kernel I don't mean that I'm trying
to I try and understand how much of of
the pieces that you accounted for
persist after the the the the the so the
I guess a and the bottom thing so okay
thank you and yeah we we run this code
again still names and implementation we
found it's just a Cisco Rooter the
results I think are pretty good the big
chart here is the diffie-hellman which
the elliptic curse to mention that so
the crypto we use this a s for
encryption to hot hmx for integrity and
PRF and what if you have we use a
elliptic curve you know that's what I
was wondering which is missing in the
table of paths and it relates to the
comment that Mikey had or a question
mark yet because if you use it if you
ham and you need the big lamb bignum
library that typically were if you want
to have any reasonable performance that
will require a fair amount of RAM which
is only temporarily but you did needs to
be there otherwise stuff would not end
that's sort of missing so you need
that's why the 32 kilobyte brand device
was able to handle this but for example
if I remember the numbers correctly
there was about 10 kilobyte for Rhys
Ram for reasonable protocol run before
elliptic curve cryptography right if you
want to optimize the point computation I
have to look up the number here but I
think you have to take that into account
as filing the estimate yeah yeah but
then the RAM numbers don't sugar I think
that's part of the kernel right okay
let's take these to the list yeah so
yeah that's and what I want so this
thing only happens once at the beginning
of the session
so yeah that's reasonable amount of time
I guess for establishing your group
communication so yeah what could we do
for minimal minimal ization for this I
think pretty much everything is done by
minimal Ike already except that there is
a bit of modification from the I cost to
the GSA arson tegu cheers Araki just
because it has another meaning here and
what would be also helpful to have
recommendations on like how to configure
the server so that the actual group sa
auth message is kind of minimal as well
so yeah the question though we have an
implementation available for iOS I know
that there is an implementation or I
heard that there is an implementation
for Kentucky which is going to be Lee's
released soon I don't I've not seen it
and yeah the basic question is is there
interest in the working group to do this
kind of work here or just Mon I'm trying
to understand when I would use this so
this is essentially I open a secure
channel to our server yeah and then I do
a get on a key yeah I know today
it might be because we are running out
of time we're running out of time so if
you have technical questions I suggest
you bring in to the list yes we can
discuss the technical so wish you have
come earlier because we actually have
work on going and group communication
security in the ACE working group an
extremely painful process um and they
are we had you if you could have
implemented that one it would have been
such a great sort of benefit for the
community and unfortunately been for the
wrong thing um I think for foot for a
couple of reasons the first one is it
refers to a document that apparently is
an individual document I don't know what
the status of that other document is
whether that will actually be adopted in
the idea of and then the minimum
actually doesn't do you a favor here if
you look at the discussion that we had
in is there's a fair amount of interest
to also add the authorization
capabilities and to add public key
cryptography to the whole equation to
make it resistance against certain
certain attacks the last the last
comments Brian wise answering the first
question so the other graft is is still
being formed there is at least one
implementation commercial implementation
yeah we the authors are would like to
take just the right piece that give me
but we haven't asked the where who
haven't been ready yet to ask the share
yet so that's but the if there's
definitely implications this is a thing
that's happening no I think I would say
it's probably a little Tara normal
comments not fry a CV but I would say
that I would say it's probably a little
too early to be asking if this what
groups interested in a minimal version
of that but the meeting I think it's a
few soda-lime Estero if you want to make
a shot point take like eight seconds
okay so they're on me there or for a
long time it was m/sec first and m/sec
shut down and that's why i get less
you know orphan and idiotic there is an
ad support for that so it's too big true
as an individual craft or we can go to
the epitome thank you all go and enjoy
your evening muster yesterday while this
is not here she's having a baby