[Music]
ah ah okay that was a good idea right
thank you
good morning everyone welcome to
multipath TCP part two the blue sheet
has started going round now it's the
noise from out oak somebody shutting the
door thinking so we need a note-taker
please can somebody volunteer and the
jabber monitor
you take notes Thank You Brad somebody
able to keep an eye on my arm Jabba
which is very easy at least if you're
confusing let's see do Gavin thanks me
the note well of course so we had a good
time on Monday talking about or Tuesday
where I'll be talking about the
implementation updates the Biss and some
proxy stuff so I thought since there's
been a lot of discussion on the list in
the last couple of days about both the
converter draft and the Sox draft I
really wanted to give people a chance to
follow up all in you know in a
face-to-face session on those two drafts
so does anybody on us there was kind of
a burst of discussion which is actually
died down in the lost day which
[Music]
mmm-maybe implies we have some consensus
on it or perhaps just implies that
people have got other things to do at
the moment does anybody want them not
allowed some time an agenda basically
now for people to follow up on on either
of those the convertor draft or on Vlad
Sox the six draft see people are still
coming in so if if the if there's a
moment that people have to follow up
anything
so I'll tell you what my my
interpretation and the way forward I
think on this on the Sox v6 one it you
know that's I think that will will not
be honed in this working group and it
was great that we we heard about it so I
think we will continue to hear about it
and I I'm assuming that it will go
forward in interior or somewhere similar
so that's that's great and I think it's
good that we remain in in the discussion
but I don't think it's unlikely would be
the working group reading it on the
converter thing my read of the
discussion that happened for coming on
Tuesday and Wednesday in particular was
quite promising and that that people
seem to quite like the approach and the
people who'd had issues on on previous
approaches which was particularly Joe
and Tom Joe touching Tom Herbert and it
was great that they made lots of
comments and I I think they were
probably reasonably okay but oh and we
have to to confirm that and give people
more time to and to read it and for
others to chip in so unless anybody
wants to make any further comments and
follow up any of the points my
suggestion is that the authors of that
draft do a rev a new version taking
account of the comments which were lots
of clarification things
Durov do revision will ask for comments
again on all the relevant mailing this
and then will work out with Mia what the
right working group is to do it because
you know obviously should be the
corporate call for it to be adopted as
to say what working group will work on
it so
that's my suggestion of how we're going
to go forward with it okay
so if nobody wants to chip in any more
on on the proxy work we will move on to
topic
- so topic 2 today is this is a new
security attack which Xeon and sorry
apologize for mangling your name
Xion and colleagues raised a couple of
days ago on the mailing list and this is
really great that they brought it
forward and notified us and there's been
some nice discussion in the last couple
of days of it so that for those of you
who haven't caught up I've tried to
extract some points from the email now
that we just look at me technically I
don't think the authors are on meet echo
so I will attempt to summarize the
problem that they raised so this
concerned the MP prior message which is
sir and that and the problem is that it
seems to allow a man-in-the-middle
attack err on one path to divert all the
traffic onto its own paths effectively
hijacking the MP TCP connection and when
we were designing the MATC protocol
there was a security assumption knew it
would be equivalent to roughly
equivalent to TCP security so on path
attackers our vulnerability for that the
TCP but this is this is probably a bit
worse than that and there's a little
explanation there about why you would be
why you might be interested in sending
the MP prior message on and
the sub connection and it might be that
the first one you've got is already
congested so it's you know you can't
really send it on that the MP prio is
about indicating with one of the sub
connections one of the sub flows is kind
of to be used as a backup path or or or
not so that's the kind of mode in which
you're using it so the issue really is
that the MP prior option has no
authentication required so that's that's
the vulnerability if you like that the
this proposed attack is exploiting so
that the solution that seemed to that
the Xion and others have suggested is
the possible solution is to remove the
address identifier from the option and
my read of the discussion that was on
the list is this was seen to not have
very many down sights and that he would
cure the issue so we ought to have some
discussion so I will throw open the mic
Alan Alan so just to summarize a little
bit more MP prior is a backup bit for
use on as a sub flows predates the fact
we can do the pro a bit in the MP join
so that that's pretty much negated the
point of this signal anyway so as far as
I'm aware there's no problem with
removing this as regards the actual
attack itself the spec the scope of it
is very very small in that it requires
only only enough bandwidth and so on and
relying on the policy of the other end
to apply backup in a certain way and
requires it to be an on path attacker
which is as I said on the list pretty
much equivalent to a TCP level attack
anyway having said all that not a
problem to get rid of it as far as I can
say so the real question to everyone is
is there any reason to change your
priorities of a sub flow from another
sub flower and if there's not then we
see I feel we've cleaned clear to get
rid of it
so Allah given OTO I think the attack is
is important in practice because you
have let's consider one case where your
you have a smartphone and you are
connected to a Wi-Fi access point and a
cellular network if you control the
Wi-Fi access point then you can tell
with the attack that the cellular
network should not be used to transmit
data so you move all the traffic over
the Wi-Fi access point and the reason is
that in the NP prior option and I don't
remember for which reason we have placed
an address identifier in addition to the
bit and this address identifier should
indicate that you would put as a backup
all the sub flows that are used that are
using this specific address identifier
and this is a really strange use case
and as far as I know no implementation
is doing that so I would support the
removal of the address identifier from
the NP prior option and if you remove
the address identifier from the MP prior
option then you are forced to use the
MPI option on the sub floor that you
want to change the backup status which
means that you need to be on path to
attack this particular sub group and I
think this solves the problem and we
keep the protocol simple and usable
any more comments so let me ask the
question is there anybody unhappy with
this proposed solution if you're unhappy
with this proposed solution please can
you hum okay so I heard nothing and if
you're okay with this proposed solution
please can you hum and if you would like
more time to think about it say another
week please can you hum okay so for the
notes I heard some humming on the happy
to remove it and none on the other to
none nobody was unhappy we're moving it
and nobody needed more time to ponder so
Alan has editor can you go ahead and
make the change thank you right that's
great
so this is good we're well ahead of time
so Marcus is up next to talk about this
proposed NPT robust session
establishment so let me see if I can
[Music]
yeah good morning my name is Marcos from
the company with a magenta color as you
can see it's a telecon and yeah today I
want to talk about real existent and
annoying problem we were faced with into
the field and yeah my my goal for today
that I can gather them feedback from
your site because it's the first time
for me at ideas and I'm not pretty
familiar with process here so please
support me during you know the
presentation or afterwards so can we go
to the like I think that we can skip
directly and okay so I have an example
where I try to explain the problem you
have faced first we start with the
standard empty TCP and we have a you see
a smartphone and we assume that it is
system-wide enabled with standard MP TCP
and as you know it's not fun today it
has a Wi-Fi interface and a cellular
interface and if it tries to connect MP
capable receiver it will work like that
that it first tries to open initial flow
over or through the default default
route and if it is successful then
afterwards it can open subsequent flows
so I think most of you know this process
and yeah as soon as a to succeed point
succeeds so you have a subsequent flow
then you have multi path capabilities
which means resilience and possibly
event with a cognition yeah but first
you need the first point the initial
flow and then you need the second point
the subsequent flow and to have multi
path capabilities that's again the flow
diagram for what a session establishment
here you see again on the left by the
two interfaces a one and A two from the
smartphone on the right side the host B
interface from the server and first we
started the request with an MP capable
for the initial flow and if it succeeds
then on a two we can start with mantich
on next ok what is now the our problem
or the motivation for or a proposal for
a robust establishment what happens if
the default route is not able to
transmit or succeed in reaching the
server in establishing an initial flow
and the answer is pretty simple nothing
will happen even if you have another
working path you know for example the
cellular network you can not reach the
destination and that's it's it's a
problem so the question is always where
do you put the default route should it
be on Wi-Fi should it be on cellular we
don't know and at the end at the end it
it could happen that we will never reach
the destination or we need some
mechanism which tries to detect where we
have to put the default route - okay and
now our demand is or our approach is if
there is at least one functional path
the connection must be possible that is
our idea and that I want to present now
the idea is mainly based on introducing
potential initial flows so do not have
any more the concept of one initial flow
and then subsequent ones you want to
have potential initial flows using all
paths available during the establishment
process and do not rely any more on one
half and that is what you can see here
now we directly start on both interface
potential initial flows and even if on
the default a default route it cannot
succeed it will work over the cellular
so any path can be used to establish a
connection the idea and for that we
developed three different proposals I
want to present now maybe there are also
some other ideas but but we try to to
make some yeah to develop some some
different proposals which have different
kind of aspects in kind of robustness in
kind of other benefits and that I want
to present now and maybe then you can
afterwards
give me some keep the feedback which one
fits best on from any of you so okay and
that to directly say let it the
preferred proposal from from our view
and it's pretty simple so what we are
doing there is we establish over each
path from the very beginning identical
since that means we copy the the arbiter
placate the MP capable but he sent him
to host E and the first flow that
returns a step little connection which
at the end resembles the initial flow
concept and in the second flow and that
what we called on credit approach if we
directly use and down credit as a
subsequent flow that means that at the
end guarantees robustness and overall
latency reduction why overall latency
reduction we have two things in respect
to to latency first the quickest path
and Abel's communication and secondly we
have the path all the flows earlier
available and can use them for example
earlier for bandwidth I could
and and the last point we do not
Institute with this concept any kind of
network overhead the second proposal is
pretty similar to the first one so we
start again with applicative the soon
requests for all paths available but now
there's a change on host B side during
the handling of the last acknowledgment
which will arrive at was B so we reset
all but one that means the first flow
which returns on host B will be the
initial flow and all the other ones are
reset and then we can proceed with a
standard empty join procedure yeah that
guarantees robustness as well we have
some nitrogen reduction so it's of the
same s and through the don't write
approach so the quickest party in game
determine the the handshake latency and
second emergency but then we reset all
the other one and again we have to use
the MP join so the sub flows will not be
there earlier as in the don't write
approach
yeah it's then like standard MP TCP and
we cause a business network overhead
because we have a lot of handshaking
which at the end we reset yeah and the
last proposal that we call the time
solution we don't like it but it has the
benefit that list Falls then they're
compliant but compared to the two other
proposals we have already seen it is
less efficient and of course it
guarantees robustness as well what we
are doing and that is pretty like the
happy eyeballs concept from RFC six five
five five we start with a normal soon
request
over the first interface it will the
default route interface and if after
some time we do not have success in
establishment a connection to the
receiver side then we tried on another
interface and if you could assume that
can introduce a lot of delay because we
have to recognize that one or several
paths will not work imagine for example
if it has eight paths available and only
the last one work then we have to try
eleven paths before we read the path
which is working and I'm not sure this
is a good solution but I say it again
it's full standard compliant from from I
feel okay again a comparison we start on
the left column to the downside approach
so it's most efficient in in terms of
robustness overall latency reduction and
I think that is a huge benefit also
compared to to the standard MP TCP and
do not introduce any additional network
overhead for such such an approach but
it needs sender and receiver
modifications possibly some standard
extension and there are pretty sure that
we meet some standard extension for such
an approach and yeah at the end it's the
most challenging one in terms of a send
that extension and of implementation now
to the middle column right before make
it it also provides for Buster's it had
the initial flow latency reduction so
compared to the don't read it's a little
bit less efficient yeah again it needs
something that we see by modifications
it will need some standard extension I
guess it's challenging as well and
introduce some additional network
overhead because we have to reset all
that one and then we have to proceed be
the empty throne again on the right side
on the right for now the the timer
solution so it provides through buses as
well that is why we are doing that the
implementation is pretty easy because
you just have to do it on on Center side
it's full standard compliant yeah
but as already mentioned less less
efficient in respect to to latency and
network overhead probably yeah and we
have possibly latency increase by the
you define a question no no okay so we
defined some some criteria to evaluate
our own proposals we we made and
obviously the important point the
important point is robustness and all of
them fulfill this criteria then compared
to MP TCP as well to a standard MP TCP
the network overhead should be minimized
and that is true for proposal 1 and
proposal 3 but not for proposal 2
because we we said all the unnecessary
initial flows or potentially initial
flows the latency also compared to to
spend a template if you should not be
increased and in the best case we can
also reach use it and that is fully true
for proposal born because there we we
can or we will reduce the overall ED
latency before the cricket path over the
quickest potential initial flow will win
and establish a connection and yeah for
proposal to we will not increase the
latency and we will have some little
reduction just hi my name is Uma from
Huawei
very good draft hi quickly skim through
it I didn't understand why you didn't
put mbb
kind of Sena make before break is it not
applicable at all in this case or a
little people are symptoms we have this
mbb right make before break was very
heavily used in a rama routing
background guy so why not this is
applicable here first you make the
connection then break it so it if I
understood you right that that is a
proposal from from us but we that is
downgrade that is the proposal one D
prefer the proposal one that is that is
just our view on that but right before
make it also a proposal and if you like
it why not so that is why we discuss it
today okay I will take it offline now
how specific and proposal do I have some
comment on that yeah yeah and propose
three people most probably have some
latency increase in the case if the
default route is not working and yeah
they were not reach use the latency
compared to standard mpg CP and the last
point is standard a standard compliance
that I have to explain a little bit so
we assume that for all proposals either
we can directly incorporate with the
existing MP TCP standard or we need just
a little mini just minor updates of the
standard but it's solvable from you so
it's all of them true okay
we decided to investigate a little bit
more the preferred approach the
preferred approach for the dark right
approach and interested first in an
environment so we developed a prototype
we implemented in the standard MP TCP in
version 0 & 9 and he feels like a lab
setup where we casted it first so we
have a host a and host B both are multi
path capable and host a has two
interfaces where a one at the default
rod and a two is a secondary path
yeah the in the first test the part that
are both following introduced some
variable packet loss on the reform fraud
we had no packet loss on the secondary
part and the latency was the same on
both paths and what you can see now in
on the left side we show the average
handshaking time over the packet loss of
the default rod and you see for MP TCP
the ever attend shaking time increased
tremendously over the packet loss and
with 100% it's not possible to establish
any connection and with our preferred
approach mptp Rob we call it the blue
line there you see normally it should be
a stable every change taking time but
because of some imperfections of our
current and prototype it's not really
stable but it shows a good indication
that we are much better than with the
standard MP TCP in case if you have a
problem on the default rod now again the
same test but now we want to show the
latency benefit and the default rod that
we introduced 40 milliseconds one-way
latency so no packet loss anymore trust
the 40 milliseconds one-way latency and
on the secondary path 20 20 millisecond
one-way agency so from theory the
handshaking needs three times the one
when agency and that you can see now in
the in the figure so for every TCP we
have around 130 my 120 milliseconds and
shaking curation so it fits to the
theory and for every TCP rob we have 60
milliseconds because there we benefit
from the secondary path
which is faster in respect to latency
now real-world setup then we have on the
on the left side MP TCP capable client
with two interfaces which is connected
to an application server in the public
Internet hosted by us we're transferring
TCP Fox is running and we try to reach
the destination in the public Internet
through this application server and in
this setup we try to download the 10
most popular websites and and see what
what happens again be introduced on the
default route an additional 40
milliseconds one-way latency so that
means of the route the default route
between the host a on the left side and
the application server and on the
secondary part be introduced in 20
milliseconds one-way them can see ya and
what you can see now on the figure it
the loading time over the different
websites and the different approaches
the MP TCP or entities here oh and yeah
you see in 9 of 10 websites there is a
benefit by entities of Europe it's just
in the case of vk.com yeah there's no
benefit but I assume again that is
because of the imperfection of our
prototype but the indication is clear
from from my view it's much better with
MP TCP rogue in respect to the overall
agency and also the bandwidth because we
have earlier the flows well yeah first
some general effects MP TCP rope can
protect MP TCP against network auditors
during the connection establishment it
can improve the user experience in terms
of reliability and latency under most
circumstances learning times can be
shortened by having
maximum throughput earlier available and
we already did some reference
implementation based on mt tcp version
0-9 and now the important point for me
that question I want to discuss with you
if they are generally need for us to
stablishment if yes there should it take
place so I had already some discussion
with Ollie bein on the mailing list and
there was one proposal from his side to
do it in the application layer so in the
responsibility of open developer I
personally don't like this approach I
think it should be in the MT TCP layer
know that we have multipath capabilities
from the very beginning I was an MP TCP
session yeah the next question want to
benefit from only robustness or a won't
we benefit from robustness and latency
reduction yeah which approach in general
fits best in future so is it any of the
proposals I present today or there any
other approach which can be bit can fit
how to integrate the MP TCP Rob into the
MPEG key standard or the implementation
and yeah how to develop or improve the
existing reference implementation and
make it available all of the process if
you if you're interesting about and and
so on but before I hopefully get some
answers from your side if the next time
and then we will return I just you know
there's some detailed discussion about
the tomcod approach I prefer because
there are still some looks like unsolved
problems but there are some relevant
points we have to discuss yeah in the in
the Dawn Treader proto it the same for
the pret before make approach the
application the third request special
the especially the
the MV capable so at the end we be
duplicating the key a which is very
important and can you go that sounds
like inning yeah dick stop so I know to
the don't teleport stop okay so this as
I mentioned we be duplicating the key a
and here you see host a and host B so
it's pretty simple but what happens if
at the same time there's a host C which
try to reach host E and by accident or
by intention its uses to that the same
key a what happened then then we have a
problem because key a X in the approach
as an identifier that flows belonged
belongs to the other and there we need
some solution to handle this so so we
have some ideas how how we can mitigate
the problem so we cannot fully use it
but you can mitigate it I guess
so we can reduce the time frame where we
allow allow use and request with the
same here or we can use some remaining
space in the m capital options for
example to introduce some additional
identifiers that that flows belongs
together also we have to solve the
problem of the SSID
because from the fgetc key standard
normally the atrocity is 0 for the
initial flow and for all the others it
is it then negotiated and may be that we
can
solved in the same way that we
introduced some additional information
into the NP capital in general there's a
question if there a need to negotiate
rope support between client and server
can be solve it in another way how is it
that a fallback mechanism you have also
there are some ideas but it would be too
much for the presentation but it's it's
an important point and that was also
part from olivier so in the best craft
there's not any more TA in the capital
which he sent with the soon the last
days I had the chance to review the
trust a little bit and I think we can
also succeed if we don't have a key a in
in the empty capable but that has to be
discussed and there are also some other
approaches so there was from the NRC T
at ikf 97 a proposal which is pretty
similar to our afraid before make no
sorry for it approach and I had already
the chance two days ago to discuss with
a Qian on from Nick and realized that we
have the same focus and maybe work
together on on the traffic or whatever
yeah and we have the API balls which can
be implemented in the application layer
this is a possibility but not preferred
preferred from our side so now we can go
back and maybe we can discuss the
questions or internal rodeo protest I
thought if we could go forward to slide
please because this basically covers
everything I was going to say which is
good to see you for pick up on it or for
example the IETF 97 proposal which match
long list but the biggest killer means
of course there's no key in in people in
the base but the semantics of the key
simply aren't
aren't the same as what you're using you
know it's a key that the pair of keys
for the entity is once they're involved
once it's set up have a semantic meaning
but you simply can't assume that two
keys on the wire from two random IP
addresses are the same thing as you say
you have identified that as a risk but I
as far as I can see it's pretty much a
showstopper more than anything else but
64 but but we are firmly especially for
a malevolent attacker wasn't an accident
so that's a concern but how I'm most
curious given you've identified or less
there's no point
rehashing it but I'm most concerned
about how you see it working without the
key on that last point you said you said
you had a way around that okay so if you
don't have the key a from the very
beginning so it's missing in the first
soon yeah obviously then we don't have
the information and you cannot use it
and that identifier but in the last
acknowledgment we have both keys
available and I think then you can make
the decision on receiver side for
example because so but I assume the
handshaking with you like that
you would allow any key you wouldn't
have sent the same key BAE sorry you
wouldn't have sent the same key BAE
right so then we would then be what
replays all right if you talk about not
sending the key a in the soon then we
are not aware of it and Ho speed the
receiver will answer with different keys
yes but at the end if knowledge month
arrives again the host P then he can
identify the flows belong together
because of the key a for example or some
other information and then he can be
replaced internally
security alarm bells are going off all
over my head on this and I can't point
to one just one thing but I feel very
very uncomfortable with that's why I'll
leave it for just now Thanks divya
bharati I think I totally agree with the
use case so there are there is a good
motivation to do that but my feeling is
that looking at what has been done with
a pea eyeballs because when you have a
queue before and ipv6 is the same issue
you don't really know whether you should
connect over v4 v6 there is similar work
being done in the taps working group so
in the taps working group there are
there is work on an API where you can
let the the library or the API selects
the good source address or selects the
good transport protocol and this is the
same problem and I think the advantage
of doing that in the application layer
is that you can have something which is
generic for many applications running on
the same system so if you look at smart
phones for example applications do not
connect directly by using the socket of
the socket API they have an underlying
API which is provided by this wonderful
vendor and it already takes care of you
selecting which source address to use
depending on whether the Wi-Fi is
available or the LG is available and so
if you decide to use both then you can
use both in the API and you can use a
timer with whatever value you want but
that would be part of G and this is
completely hidden from the application
so there is a shim layer that does this
for you without requiring any changes to
the protocol so I think the use case is
really valid and I encourage you to
continue to work on the use case but I
would focus on looking at the
application level solution because you
get almost the good benefits that you
want and the just the cost that you have
is that you might open connections that
are useless and that you reset already
but this is done by many applications so
this shouldn't not be an issue and the
advantage of the library is that you can
remember what you have done in the past
easily and then you can avoid sending
too many duplicate scenes while if you
put that in the kernel and the kernel
would always always send duplicate
things then I would be concerned from a
scalability hue part on the client and
on the server side
I completely understand what is that and
that was also some lucky IQ acumen Tizen
you you have on the made in this I know
but then it's only the case of
capacitance we we handle there and we
don't benefit somehow in but then it's
it's up to the library to decide whether
you want to have low latency because if
you want to have low latency then you
just open over the parallel pass and you
get the connection that you have hmm you
are right you are right yeah okay but
then maybe we have several requests and
all that won't be enough to reset yeah
but you can learn what is the network
gives you the best latency and so you
have some over at at the beginning and
then or you have some over at on a
regular basis from time to time you just
do the probing but you don't have to do
it for all connections and you also need
support and all the socket libraries you
need it for you need it for
yeah but whatever as I said applications
will interact with the shim library
anyway and taps is building this kind of
library and you should look at the neat
project they are writing this library
which allows to select transfer
protocols and this is more complex than
just selecting the source address so
this is a shoot they are doing a
superset of what you need and all of
them has to use it but then there's an
unsaid we have the security issues and
the fact that there is no engine and
then it guarantees robustness and but it
is supported from standard itself and
every person of this robot ever matures
MT TCP add functionality if you only
implemented and in some libraries then
we rely on the support in the libraries
yeah but if I OS and Android decide to
put it in the rubber East and by default
everybody is using that okay
Chrissa posh apple I also want to say
this is really important where we're
basically it's really important to get a
robust connection establishment and in
iOS we have something that is called
wife Isis that is basically doing the
timer based approach and to kind of
reiterate whatever Olivia already said
the advantage of the time of its
approach is that as it's sitting inside
the library it's also independent of the
transport layer protocol so whether it's
MP TCP TCP whether the server supports
it or not it just works like the
application doesn't need to do anything
and another point also were at the time
of is approaches curved it's a timer
you're not constantly erasing Wi-Fi
versus cell because you want to favor
Wi-Fi and only you cell if Wi-Fi it
doesn't really doesn't work and you
really want to avoid bringing up
cellular at all cost because it has huge
power implications but also implications
for the carriers because they need to
maintain stain and so on yeah thank you
thank you for your comment but for me
it's the same it's it's depending on on
the library and yeah I know about what
my assistant you you already presented
on Tuesday and do you need some time I
think to detect that the Wi-Fi is not
working well I don't know how all your
algorithms work and maybe be introduced
a lot of delay to recognize that there
is a problem that is the the negative
point of the timer based approach from
from ICU but the question is what you
want to have at the end is it just a
bastard or is it more crying brain
Trammell I really like proposal one but
I share Alan's sort of security
heebie-jeebies when I look at it um
we need actually to have serious
security people throw some cycles at it
to say that it's okay the other thing
that makes me less enthusiastic about it
is that I don't see a partial
implementation or partial transition
solution
do it it's like we put it in a standard
then it's magically there um you need to
have some negotiation as to whether or
not you're a modified receiver that can
support protocol one so that adds a
whole lot more complexity we have an
enormous amount of implementation
experience with option three racing and
timing it's a little bit slower but
looking at the cost-benefit analysis on
okay we get a little bit more latency
for this much more complexity would this
be done before impe quick is done I'm
not sure it would be um with respect to
implementing thank you with respect to
implementing um the timer in the
protocol itself in the MP TCP layer it's
worse than that it's worse than just
saying okay well there's some efficiency
problems because you're going to be
doing the other racing anyway right so
now you have two different layers also
racing stuff so you're gonna raise v4
and v6 at the library layer and then you
have it balance the MP TCP layer which
is also going to be trying to race
different paths on v4 and v6 and it just
seems like that's a really good way to
get extremely confused so if you're
going to have racing the racing stuff
probably belongs in one place and I'll
reiterate Olivia's pitch for the work
that taps and the knee project or do we
know that thanks thanks thank you bonus
ok lost comment another instruments that
have been on the mic already I just
wanted to add one thing and that's it's
also not the latency trade-off it's not
so simple so it's not necessary that you
know using both the paths is always
going to give you the best latency
because if you want to have them both
for robustness you want to have the most
for short flows once you get into the
path being heterogeneous it's not
necessarily always a win so what I was
saying was that when you have two paths
and they're heterogeneous also if you
just say you know I want to have both of
them because they all
is gonna give me less latency that is
not necessarily true because when the
paths are heterogeneous you may not want
to use both of them it may actually make
it slower because you may get traffic on
the short path and it could dominate the
completion time yeah right depends on
the scenario where you want to use it
sure but so I think you need to separate
the robustness and the latency in that
sense I mean it's not at the end I think
if you have both you can decide whether
to use the path from the schedule of you
or not for example so if a power returns
first but you don't want to use and you
don't use it that is yes but then you
still have to wait to see if the other
one yeah yeah it's tricky but thanks
Marcus we need to move on because we're
behind yet shaken up cranky
so ello everyone I'm Kanta from UC lugar
and this is a proposal for fastest of
procreation so so why do we propose this
is fact that for instance current of
implementation typically initiate a
connection and then they create sub
flows on all pairs of IP addresses and
this is great for bandwidth segregation
but in the case of for instance Matt
phone this is not useful and in fact it
can be worse than what we can we want in
the sense that you will establish the
flows that might be useless because you
don't have enough data to send or
because in fact you don't need contra
segregation instead in the case of the
smart phone you rather want to have a
low latency and yeah seamless network on
the earth so when you leave the the
Wi-Fi you want to switch on the cellular
in the same lightweight and useless up
flows useless tell you lots of flaws
consumer energy conception and radio
resource allocations so for instance
where with the smartphone use case
suppose that you start with a smart
phone which is in a Wi-Fi network that
works well the the connection establish
and so on and then and then you decide
to move and you reach you as you are in
a in a zone in an area where you are
losing your the Wi-Fi which ability and
so it becomes lossy and then in this
case you want to have an additional sub
flow in that case that will use the set
up and you don't want to use the
cellular if you are on a Wi-Fi that
works well and and you don't need both
with education so next so
in fact this work come from a technical
report of a stress Aunty published and
so we have three a mechanism to enable
this on smartphone in the case of the
ITF will focus only on the last on the
last proposal because it is the only one
that affects interoperability and so so
if Y we will present the multi pass
option to do that excellent so the idea
is in fact we want to either break
before make approach at the subfloor
level and we want to delay the creation
of backups of flow in your case the
cellular sub flows
so yeah this nice for from the office
allocation for energy consumption but
yeah it's a kind of reactive approach
and so you if you need some time to
detect if you really need to create a
cellular acid flow and so you can have
larger latency and yeah you don't want
with to a latency and this is annoying
up in the sense furthermore establishing
stop flows in multiple CP takes some
time right as shown here actually when
you want to us your smartphone that
that's data to be sent and you want to
create a new subfloor you have to wait
to RTT before actually sending your data
and so yeah if the latency of your
cellular network is quite high you will
wait which you have an increased latency
which is annoying and so yeah if we
could create sub flows in a one RTT or
even in as 0rt
fashion it would be nice if we could do
some kind of TFO but at multi pass CP
level using multi pass
connection information to establish the
subfloor it would be great because you
can send that
in the sin and then you can have the
answer or just a total cynic and so in
it's just a latency of using sending
data on the cellular if in this case so
it's like so if you take the case of
liquids response traffic here we made
simulation with me I mean the topology
and so we look at the Latins experience
but by the application when you use the
first pass and then you try to send your
data on the second pass backup path and
we see that compared to the classical
joint way of doing things you around at
least one acity you save at least one
entity when requests are quite large and
if the request fit in the syn packets in
fact you can save towards the to RTT of
the establishment of the so flow which
is which could be nice so next slide so
about the proposal except the concrete
proposal we want to wait - Alicia -
additional multiple City auction a first
one that would create a Sapru when you
want to send data so typically when you
have requests based on traffic and the
client detects that your Wi-Fi stats and
so you will send your data directly in a
when creating the Sutro Oh another
option when you want to create a sub
flow but the clay on earth not to send
but it knows that it has that are to be
received for instance you are in the
middle of a build up route and for some
reason this is the subfloor definition
which you are receiving data is lossy
and you want to say okay i think i will
open the cellular and see if I can
continue my transfer on the cellular and
this is the case for the other one so
next so this is kind of proposal like we
we implemented it in a in our technical
report
so this is the option we will shoot use
in the scene option to create to create
quickly and user flow so compared to the
multi pass and picturing option
here are the four you change the first
one is that we will include the data
sequence number because you you need to
know which that as you consider the data
goes onto of course you need to add a
data level length like in the DSS and
because of security consideration you
want to adjudicate in some way your sub
flowing so you use IH match don't get it
to 4 bytes we will discuss this a factor
that and so to compute the the H Mac you
can use the token of the connection and
the DSN of the data you want to send
next and it's an ACK in fact can
directly send H Mac computed over at the
DSN and the attack that that is present
on the connection
so next and we are in a similar way
after I think with when you don't have
that that you sent then you use the
attack itself and you can compute ashmac
using the data and the token of
definition and similarly with with the
syn ACK we used at the SN of the fuel so
next so of course this introduced the
critical Z direction the first one is
that in this in the MP John I think it's
a bytes and then 20 bytes of the H max
here we we shortened especially in a the
fashion out option the H back to 4 bytes
because of CP space tipsy be options
based on situation of course we can
modify it but this is mainly to fit in
the Linux implementation of TCP and as I
don't think we we should give our office
about sin we prior at
when you have the DSN you have the data
you have the H Mac so you can replay the
packet on another subfloor and create
additional sub floors with the same
packets if you have seen this packet in
the network which is quite annoying and
so we can say ok the server should limit
the number of supports that are created
for a specific DSN over a specific
connection this is a possible way of
mitigating so next slide and so to
conclude in fact this is a proposal to
tune will T pass itself to fit a
smartphone consideration because because
of the case of the cellular and and the
mobile nature of the smartphone and we
are we actually implemented this
solution with inside MP TCP
oh that 91 and within Android 1/6 6.1 on
Nexus 5 and so is there any interest to
follow up this work at least at the ITF
is there a need follow-up for this
proposal this is the main question in
fact hi this is Maha we are looking at
low latency applications for couple of
these cases in Fiji and related Phi G
requirement is 1 milliseconds but we
don't go that far but you know the low
latency is very very important topic I
just wanted to ask what is the
comparison after sub flow creation and
with your changes yeah what is the what
is the gain you got with this with your
approach with the classical with the
classical and with your additions ok
in fact this we mean that in the paper
we showed that for kind of interactive
traffic can reach similar performance
yeah a slightly induce a tansy but not
much more than classic a motive as with
the backup mode
so the reduction is significant or not
significant latency for the sub the the
latency remains quite the same it's just
that you don't have the cilia which is
establish useless okay so if you SW
cellular it's only when you need to use
it and actually you use okay thank you
any more comments Alan Ford I'm a little
I may have just not followed it as
you're saying it had pointed in your
options when you send them in the sin so
before there's any data yeah what are
you actually signing with the HVAC as
you mentioned signing data acts and data
sequence numbers and so on but there's
no data in that packet just sign the
data comes later mature agent data
doesn't come till the third ACK if
you're sending data out the first scene
doesn't have data in it presumably in
the in the fashion in on the phone out
as in you're the one who wants to send
data yeah so the idea is to use the data
English Maki or we can use the other
mm-hmm what's the data sequence number
referring to that the data sequence
number of the connection of the data you
are saya sending the same okay but are
you sending data to the same yeah okay
so yeah that was a bit I wasn't too sure
like I see how it worked in the leather
diagram for the other way not this way
okay cool I'm a rinse from so I'm
curious about the impact on delay
between your detection mechanism that
you actually need to establish your new
sub flow in relation to the the cost of
setting it up because I guess if yeah
the the magnitude of those two are kind
of important I guess to see the whole
picture on the latency or yeah in fact
the the impact will be clearly visible
if you have your main network which has
low latency and your additional network
which is
I let and see we have a much more much
higher impact because in fact the time
we will have to create your sub fro will
be saved somewhere but yeah when when
this is comparable yeah the all all is
about being a good data detection system
which is yeah we proposed one in our
work but yeah yeah you have Indians
Latin T because of the detection and
yeah I will stand up so would this be a
change to the base psychosis an
extension that could be done later from
into the protocol base for me it's just
adding two two option so it's like an
extension yeah an extension you can it
but it would change the security
properties by having this reduce
statement yeah for that option yeah um
Chris off - I think it's important too
that we speed up their handshake and
that we can send data early but for this
particular use case like when when cell
is down and aisle it takes a very long
time to bring it back up again and then
basically the handshake is kind of from
the noise so I'm not sure if the gains
that we see we would really see them in
the real world deployment and then maybe
a little bit more technical question is
it seems like we are missing the DSS
checksum here maybe oh is the data level
length able to cover middle boxes yeah
we didn't include the DSS section but we
could
okay thanks going to this sounds like
this is something that needs small time
for people to think about and discuss
but I've taken the message that we can
go ahead with the bits without worrying
about this because it's something like
that it's an extension if that people
think that's wrong then we need to come
to conclusion on it with book so we're
up to Christophe talking about some
thoughts about documenting interactions
between empathy screen tear though now
do you have sites would are you going to
show yourself
[Music]
so apologies this one is not uploaded
but will did sing
[Music]
hello so um this is basically more like
a request to revive an old or draft it's
basically the draft that Sebastia
Gregory and Olivier wrote a few years
back about the interactions between MPTP
and TFO the draft is not suggesting any
wire format changes or MPCP it's mostly
documenting how one would implement an
entity's PNTR for amputees P stack and
it basically boils down to two
recommendations one is on the TfL cookie
size because if we have MPT cpt fo and
all the regular TCP options then we need
to make sure that the TfL cookie is
small enough so that everything fits
well inside the sim and the second
recommendation is about the data
sequence mapping for the data that is
inside this in because it basically
suggests to have the data that is inside
the sin to not be part of the DSS
mapping and the details are all inside
the draft MPGs P plus T fo has been
implemented in Linux for RFC 68 when t4
by Gregory a few years back and it has
been used as far as I know by many
people when I did the implementation of
the the base draft I made sure that it
works with empathise p+ t fo as well and
in iOS we have it invented also so my
request is kind of can we maybe revive
this draft or even maybe even include it
inside this document
allenford I just wanted to say that I'd
love to see this in the base but that
requires someone who isn't me to write a
text that requires what sorry okay we
will help so any comments on the idea of
including it Roberson who's going to do
some writing
what so this is Michael speaking as TCP
ensure I have not ended multiple City
for quite some time I just think we have
to think in TCP M about whether we
should move this at some point in time
to standard strike and I'm not sure if
this would be of interest with the
multi-faceted City working group so far
TF always experimental so if there's
input on on that from the multipath TCP
working group that would be something we
anticipate what are we interested in I
have actually been discussing with
fusion of moving DTF o RC to standard
strategy I know
I've also had acquired a number of
discussions it hasn't happened so far as
a personally I think this is what should
happen but we have to think if we make
it happen but as I said for this working
who is mostly if you have input on that
then please raise it on TCP n so we
heard one commenting by group including
this in the basis of any other comments
and favor or gangster or concerns
how many people feel ready oh sorry I
just saw there's a question from Yoshi
in the Java saying to service use
different cookie sizes for TCP and MB
TCP that is completely implementation
dependent in the Linux implementation it
just decreases the cookie size to four
bytes for all GFO connections we could
simply change it to make it dynamic
based on whether mptp has been requested
or not
I think there are two different dilemma
elements in the in the slide Kristoff
brought so the first one is there is a
recommendation on TFO cookie size but
this is related to the size of the TCP
header in the scene and so as we move to
68 24 bits the requirements on using
shorter cookies will be less strict than
what it was with 60 68 24 that's one
issue but the second issue which is
really specific to MP TCP is the
importance of looking at the data
sequence mapping for sin theta and so we
might say that the TFO cookie size could
be in or out of this document and could
be in another document it could be in a
generic a TCP M document where they
recommend that when whatever size you do
should fit with the options that you use
in the scene because that's basically
what what needs to be done and then
there is a data sequence mapping which
is very specific to MP TCP and I think
this part should be in the RFC 68 when T
for this document the cookie size is
just an implementation detail on a grid
in the base we actually really don't
care anymore in the base we have less
issues because the Imperial option is
only four bytes yeah so is is anybody
against trying to include something on
these lines in the base the Argus sorry
please hum a few our games
please hum a few it's too early to make
a decision you need some more time to
think about it and please tell me if you
be in play we're including something on
these lines so there's some noise on the
on being in favor and not on the other
two so I suggest that Christoph you and
Olivier work on on some text and then we
can discuss some specific text and if
you can try through that in the next
couple of weeks something that'd be cool
oh jeez excuse me Julia scrubber time
just a quick
clarification there was a question I
don't remember who at the mic saying
that since that GF o is experimental and
MPT CP standards track is that a problem
or not yes so did that the intention is
for the base to be standard strike yeah
and TfL being experimental is that not a
problem Mike who is Mike who's
approaching where I'm not the best
expert for these kind of things but as I
said I think I think there is a certain
interest in T CPM and thinking it is
about a standard strikes things so if
MPT CP would require a standard strike
specification that I think TCP M could
do something so so we saying that if MVC
stands tracked here though remains
experimental that causes a problem for
some of this or I think other server did
your initial thing is just your initial
comment is a plea if you think TF those
should be standard spread please come
and say no no I think the if there was a
problem we could fix it in T CPM I
thought I'm aware there wouldn't be a
problem with this well me I can probably
answer but it's informative in this
draft so should be fine yeah I mean you
says that's correct
okay okay so I think we have a plan
thanks guys
[Music]
so Quentin you're back on
this one
so it's so just before we start there's
anybody not sign the blue sheet is
everyone signed one in the one in the
back corner thank you
remind me we do to finish at 20 past
yeah okay so perhaps five minutes so due
to the ability of the ATF not 64 era at
at the IDF we decided to play a little
with it yes so let's take an example in
fact of you have a client which is
behind on the check for and is a Sonya
ipv6 address and a server which has both
ipv4 ipv6 address given by two different
networks so you can start initiating a
connection on the v6 so we will do the
DNS request you have the ipv6 address
you send us in to the ipv6 then receive
a cynic then you receive the address in
before and and so what should the plan
to equals today there is no real way for
the client to detect the embedding of
the before slide so the in fact the
client receive an eye before but this is
only and the commercial of the embedding
of the v4 address into v6 is actually
done by the DNS resolver at an active
form and performing the commercial in
the of the address in the Nazis for is
probably a very bad ID because we don't
want to have Middleburg additionally the
box is doing funny stuff and you could
have additional program due to the TCP
or option space because I am a PB six
addresses that rather than being for
others
so what we can do instead is to try the
clan could try to infer the embedding in
some way so for instance here we we are
using at the idea the well no prefix
which is error so when we were sieve an
ipv4 address it's quite easy to try to
assign to that embedded address and it's
implementable it's it was done it it
works it's nice the only issue is that
not 64 can have the window perfect but
also the need for specific prefixes and
the inferring that was specific perfect
is quite art and it's quite a key in
some sense and may be a way to sort this
is to to rely on a draft that is
currently done which could allow the
that is for 2 and by Avaya other idea
should be to communicate the embedding
of the neva specific address no that was
with big projects and
yeah this is my okay yeah yeah this is
actually this is a a genetic problem for
each time about protocol in which you
have referrals so there used to have
RFC's which are we have defined already
means to discover the proxy which is
which is used by the net 64 you can see
France that an extension of the defined
for the protocol PCP that we list for
instance to forward to interact with you
not 64 and then you learn the list of
all the prefixes of the nat64 bit
because we may have multiple not 64 in
path and then it gives the ability to
provide this kind of prefix to a to the
host and then you will do the the other
synthesis bit under RFC 60 50 if if it
turned on the house itself so this is a
generic problem the the DHCP one is not
is not an option because there is a
recommendation from the behavior working
group to not go with that with that way
that means that yeah because various
issues with DHCP itself it does not
allow you to discover for instance if
you have multiple not 64 in a single
network with one single DGP option we
don't have this limitation and there is
actually one RFC which go through all
this list of alternatives to discover
the prophets and the disappear option
was discarded by the behavior working
group so the only proposal the only
RFC's in this no track which we have
today in is the the PCP and this is
really a problem which is shared by all
the application in which you have the
address records through the scrubber
track I'm going to use some strong
strong vocabulary here so I would like
all the miners in the room to leave
before I do there is one possible point
of view that nat64 is a hack that
doesn't belong in the internet and I'm
still hoping that more read that there
will be some a sudden outburst of common
sense and people will be using things
like map II that don't have the problem
that nat64 has I'm wondering about the
wisdom to accommodate for nat64 broke
for nat64 with an MP TCP
just one quick command to wear to
jealousy had you you seed map
II had not it returned at in the CP
itself the only difference there is that
there is a fortress fix it not in that
CP and you have the same problem two two
two bit in for the communication for a
host which located behind the CP even if
you have the map in the network side so
the nut will be always there you have
fair walls and the problems are there so
I don't think this is the opportunity to
to to say this is bad or not this is the
situation we have today and the nat64 is
really declarant in meaning networks and
multiple customers millions of customers
are enjoying the service to have the
ipv6 and the ipv4 service continuity so
that you can also join to the majority
of the servers which does not support
ipv6 so not 64 is something which is
really helpful for this for these people
and this is really a good a good problem
to be solved so what the comment is how
this sort of it it is not specific to in
PTC but that's another way but this is
not something that we should to say
against Notts except for and so on but
anyway how do you even not you agree
that not is a mess
but if we believe that one day we will
have our P v6 only networks then we will
still continue to use ipv4 and so not 64
is one way to get that and the message
from vendors and from network operators
is that if you deploy it not 64 please
use the well-known prefix and there is
some hope that we can cope with that
with MPT CP if you use any of the prefix
then I guess nothing will happen and we
won't use the not 64 prefix in NPC
so if I get it right this has no impact
on the best protocol document this is
sad not just due to a large issue with
not watching or just very much them yeah
Frank good that's Christoph um I just
want to cover confirm like that this is
a really big problem where we am when
the device is on an ipv6 only network
and previously we were on an ipv4 only
network so we only have an ipv4 address
how can you establish a subfloor over
the ipv6 only network and we are doing
in iOS we are doing a lot of
synthesizing and dissenter sizing off of
the IP addresses to basically extract if
we started on ipv6 only we extract the
ipv4 address out of it and the other way
around and so even if they are not using
the well-known prefix we basically
figure out what the prefix is by
resolving might be before only about
alpha and that way we can basically use
use MPGs p on whatever network there is
so I I think I maybe even think that
this could be documented in the base but
I'm very happy with this and it's kind
of an informational thing it doesn't
have any warrior actors it you know I
mean that sounds great if you if you can
go is something that people like in the
near future then that's that's great
yeah okay so I think we've got about one
minute left so I'll just summarize where
I think we've got to today so if I
remember right we're going to we've at
least here agreed to confirm things of
course that the MP prior which is we're
going to make that modification we
talked about Chisholm wire change we're
going to have this TFO interruptions
stuff's more informational and maybe
something on what Quentin's is talked
[Music]
and we're going to try and try and get
the bits in it sort of we thought it's
been in a stable state for a while but
we keep making the odd change too
so when hopefully this will mean it
really will be stable in the next month
I guess all of these bits of text can be
done and then we're going to work out
how to push it up into is G land and
wider review we have to do working great
last call first
I'm assuming Mir do you want to make me
for closing comments last minute you're
happy okay right thank you very much to
everybody we've used to our time up it's
the end of the idea congratulations see
you or hear you in Singapore bye bye
thank you for all the good discussions
and contribution and if anybody didn't
get a blue sea snake
you