Nakia earlier this year and he announced
that he will be stepping down as chair
of net Khan working group after Prague
so I wanted to take this opportunity to
thank mammoth thank you for as many
years of service thank you very much
at IETF ambition of course all the best
in his retirement rather than give a
long speech I put together a slideshow
of pictures that were taken by him and
his friends on his many trips to the
many different ideas locations but
before I run that slideshow I wanted to
announce that today after bits and bytes
we are getting together for a farewell
beer bash for mammoth it's a surprise
for him yes so if you would like to join
us in wishing him in his retirement
please meet in the lobby at 9:15 we are
going to head to a place called locale
Hamburg it's about 10 minutes from here
and please make sure you bring your wife
along so she can meet all your merry
friends after the slideshow bird who was
co-chair before me you would like to say
a few words so let me just quickly run
the slideshow
shall I say the words during the
slideshow cause this feels like a
funeral to me that little grad so Mehmet
thank you very much
you know I've also been co-chair with
you and it was great to work with you
and you know normally I do a Dutch song
but I looked up the words for an English
song so that you know it's not that you
can understand what I'm saying but also
as a matter of fact so that people can
participate and it goes like this
I need to read the words for he's a
jolly good fellow for he's a jolly good
fellow for he's a jolly good fellow
that's all say all of us that's it
that's and so say all of us and so say
all of us for he's a jolly good fellow
for he's a jolly good fellow for he's a
jolly good say all of us and so say all
of us thank you so thank you very much
this is indeed a touching moment to
leave net converting group after nine
and a half years I was doing a lot of
wrong and bad things it seems I was
unsuccessful I appreciate very much your
words it was indeed an honor to serve
for net converting group and the ops
area
I am indeed very happy to have worked
together with Netcom folks and
especially the authors of the drafts who
indeed spent a lot of time very engage
in many discussions and helped to
publish those documents I especially
would like to thank Bert Wyden and dan
hromas cano for their guidance and
mentorship from the beginning it was
indeed a real easy
alived having birth as a co-chair so I
was just following what he was saying it
was indeed a really good start and help
from him but I also would like to thank
to Boehner for his support all the years
and Mahesh in the last two or
two-and-a-half years so it is a good
time thank you very much to all for your
support and getting net Kampf documents
done thanks and that we bring the
meeting to order
okey doke so this is the net conf status
slide set can you go back there is a
reason why I can is here in parenthesis
I will come to this in a second we need
a JavaScript and and many takers is apat
is actually for everybody
please enter your notes there from this
session but we have as far as I
understand Ignace and maybe Bala I don't
know as main minute takers this would be
helpful any JavaScript please okay
thanks nada
so with this please enter in is a pet
whatever you think it should be put into
the minutes the link is on the slide and
you can find it from the net
working group status page also okay this
is the new note well the the co-chairs
are keen of copying the newest not well
into the start of slides any submission
to ITF intended by the contributor for
publication as all or part of an IETF
draft any statement made within the
context of IETF is considered as IETF
contribution please be aware
that all contributions are subject to
the rules of RFC 53 78 and the new RFC
81 79 which I didn't yet read yet but
you need to take care of it
go ahead okay this is the one slide
status since Chicago the working group
has been rejected after some long ish
discussion but also IES she needed a
longer time to approve it now it is
available please look at it on the link
last call for RFC 6531 alized
we will now go to the next step 0 touch
and keystore drafts were in workroom
class call we will check the status
today secure shell TLS and net compress
compliant server models are in workgroup
last call we might discuss one or the
other issue today
yang subscription push drafts which are
supposed to be ready for working class
we will check this Martin raise some
issues on the mails but Alex and others
addressed them mostly I assume there is
one remaining this will be discussed so
I am stepping down and now the
introduction also which has been made on
the main list but officially in the
session Kent Watson will be the new
co-chair starting after IETF night
planned meeting please welcome him
together with me
okay the agenda you have seen we have a
package for items which were or are in
vertical glass call go ahead charted
items ready to go to work last call this
our main leader yang push drafts go
ahead
we have drafts fitting the Charter they
are subject to adopt we need to check
whether there is already substantial
amount of content available before we
can adopt go ahead non chartered items
as it is important for net conf and EMA
data store architecture it'll be shortly
presented here it has been already
presented and discussed in net mode
sessions what we need to go through it
if somebody has a question it can be
asked and we can address those questions
you didn't tim carry any okay if I could
ask a quick question on on the status of
those elements that are of those drafts
that are in the working group last call
now is there any chance of any of those
drafts being published this year just
trying to figure out what what the next
half the year is gonna look like in
terms of publications it is actually the
aim to publish if the vertical glass
code is successful if there are issues
we need to solve and and if they are
substantial and take more time to solve
it can be delayed but the aim is to
publish as soon as possible okay so
these four here that we're talking about
there's we're gonna try to get those out
this year is that accurate yes the yank
push draft set is also in the queue for
last call this will be most likely if
the issues are solved on time after this
meeting in a month time or so yeah let's
see how it goes is there a particular
set of traps that yeah the client/server
modules in the earth are the
are some of the big ones that we were we
were trying to track a bit closer so we
were just trying to figure out what the
next six months Michael I mean the last
call is going as far as I know after
this meeting still one week time and and
yeah please raise the issues during the
last call if possible provide a way
forward if the issue is accepted and
yeah it needs to be solved before
publication yeah okay I figured that
much but not less so Tim don't go away
so this is like a BBF question sure no
no I mean that makes a big difference so
okay there is like my personal opinion
that if we don't publish this in six
months it would be like a real concern
right but now whenever we've been
dealing with different as do sometimes
you have deadlines because they're
meeting at cetera and I would like to
know about those I can't remember these
are part of the BBF comma module piece
to be honest with your they're just a
Nokia track I just like I said I get old
I'm next in line for the retirement
package okay there are three go ahead
again despite there are three documents
accounting Netcom proxy and udp-based
publication channel for streaming I hope
it will time for them I assume they will
be good enough to let them present
that's it
so the first presentation is from Kent I
think
good afternoon working group so this is
one presentation for the collection of
drafts that are all in last call at the
moment so there's one slide per drafts
so if you have any questions or comments
on you know draft make sure you ask it
on the slide that it's showing on screen
so zero touch is the last call actually
completed there were four comments
received potentially one technical
change and actually I view this is a
sort of soft technical change because it
doesn't really change the the the the
content of the data significantly or at
all really it's just a matter of
structuring of the gang module itself
but the issue regards whether or not the
top level choice statement is okay in a
yang data structure I think a couple of
tools piaying and and Andy's tools
flagged as an issue though technically
the document being data structure says
that it's okay so long as the top-level
node always resolves to a container
which it does so I don't know it is
actually currently on unless being
discussed but if we want to discuss in
the room right now anyone have any
comments on this issue ok so again there
is a thread on the list right now and I
did actually just poke it I think a
couple a few days ago so I could pick up
on that that'd be great
next is the keystore draft again last
call completed three comments were
received potentially for technical
changes are looming I mean so so there
are also editorial changes but I mean
I'm just calling out the technical
changes here because these are the ones
that would potentially cause a need for
another last call
so first is defined a separate module
for some algorithms for the algorithm I
dented identifiers so currently the
acute or drops is has you know base
identifiers and then I don't know about
ten sub identifies for various public
key algorithms
you're gonna had a comment about
potentially moving those out into
another
gang module I don't know what we call it
an algorithm crypto algorithm identifier
module it be nothing but a bunch of
identifiers so we could but my concern
is that if we were then we'd probably be
tempted to you know not just to public
identifiers would want to do symmetric
key identifiers and other kinds of
identifiers and it couldn't become it
could grow right so that's that's the
concern but I understand it might be the
right thing to do I don't I don't think
Juergen is gonna be in this session so
but but maybe someone else has a comment
on this all right so this particular
item is actually is I replied to uragan
comments yesterday last night and so
hopefully we'll pick up on it there next
is how should various lists of lists be
named I don't really think we're gonna
be able to discuss this in the room
right now there's a few ideas floating
around but just be aware that there's
some strangeness in the naming of the
various containers in the draft and
again not sort of soft technical change
because it won't dramatically change the
structure of the data next is how to
normalize the data fields in various
lists a similar comment to previous is
soft technical change next what type
should be used for host keys actually
okay so the draft currently says it so
something called a one asymmetric key
but you know ultimately it's an ASN that
one structure which is kind of uh normal
for SSH implementations which are
typically textual base this once
resolved already what I did actually if
I realize the ITF system module also
defines SSH house key the same way so I
just copied and pasted how it does its
definition into the reporting replace to
the one asymmetric key here okay so next
draft the reducers yes so just to
understand next steps for the two drafts
which head already workgroup last call
so you mean zero-touch is mostly done
with an update it can be verified on the
mailing list and can go
next step yes okay and keystore needs
some changes defining a separate moment
is kind of big the first poll points the
largest and and as I understood you
already suggested to have another last
call after these changes are prepared or
provided depending on the okay it's
depending what we do the first bullet
point if we decide to keep the
identifier in the current draft then
obviously nothing no change there the
remaining three changes I all said they
were kind of soft technical changes so
yes they're technical changes but
they're not dramatically changing the
nature of the data if you have a
separate module and rearrange the whole
draw yes that's the first item if we do
that a new last call would be needed for
talking so go ahead okay okay so the SSH
client server draft is currently in last
call as are all the other client server
drafts so far I think it's what a week
and a half and so far there's been zero
comments posted a little bit concerning
but that's the current state same with
TLS client-server 0 comments have been
received so far for the Netcom client
server draft we've had one comment
received so far which potentially has
one technical change in it actually it's
not a technical change it's an editorial
thing I think but the design
considerations section should we remove
it altogether or move it to the appendix
or fix it currently that design
consideration section talks about the
motivation for you know for instance why
do we do call home and why do we support
multiple call home endpoints and you
know the justification for all that that
whole justification is as it applies to
net kampf
it this draft it also applies to the
restaurant client server drafts so if we
keep it then I think we'd want the
identical design considerations section
to also show up in the restaurant client
server draft which then seems redundant
but you know I don't I wouldn't
necessarily recommend moving it out into
third draft but perhaps we should any
comments on this okay so this actually
is being discussed unless this is Tom
patches comment so I replied to him
already last night and on the rest come
client-server draft so far no comments
have been received so far and that is my
status for this all the straps now the
last four are still in last call so we
need to wait until deadline and prepare
an update if necessary for those which
need an update and we will see how
decide without me now you're asking for
concerns that concerns me there is not
much comment right I keep hearing all
the time that need to be rich faster but
we don't provide comments the last call
so maybe the thing is that we've got a
set of documents in last call right now
and we have a next set that will be in
last call next right so some how can we
just stop thinking about our own
documents and the people who want to
have last call sooner that provides
feedback for this set there and and
we're going to help the process here
otherwise I mean zero comment what is it
mean right so it seemed that we've got a
discrepancy we want to British fast but
we don't provide feedback if you read it
it's fine just tell it it's fine so can
I have a show of hands of instead of
saying all the documents a show of hands
on anyone has read any one of these set
of documents Oh
fairly decent set so I think it would be
helpful to indicate that because I think
and even if it is saying plus one or the
plus one is not the best of opinions but
saying that you've read it and you have
no concerns even that is helpful to the
authors so would encourage you guys to
on the mailing list the last call is
still open say yes you have read the
draft and you you believe that the
document is either either you have no
opinion or you have some opinion okay
thank you thanks Alex
good afternoon everyone so this visit
concerns the yang push the related draft
so you see busy the the four graphs
which are yeah which are in this package
basically here so it's push updates the
subscribing subscription for
notifications and then the net con for
respective the rest convent HTTP support
for the for the transport
so one thing perhaps to mention upon
decay there was there was a hackathon
earlier this weekend busy where which
basically showed actually
interoperability a yang for Hughes case
security use case concerning basically
yeah a security gateway for use case
discussing the second working group
involving different vendors yeah
different vendors implementations of
this so I just wanted to mention is
there's a there's a link here to the
where you can see busy the details of
that in terms of the drafts themselves
we've had just a few updates actually
most of its rank push itself there was
one outstanding issue regarding filters
concerning busy whether or not it's a
note selector with a match on values and
so forth so this video has been resolved
clarified basically it's a note
selectors simpler semantics and and the
permutation is basically the the concern
that was that was essentially addressed
to that security considerations have
been updated we have also a clear a
distinction between a data source of
action and the stream subscription that
was a little bit books not clearly
enough delineated earlier now basically
it's pretty much done but there are a
few items which are next which are
basically next which are which are this
it up here one minor updates will be
updated within within a week and the
main thing basically what also made
mentioned earlier there were speech was
raised to are really basic editorial
issues which are being addressed but we
have actually where we're getting some
text text updates one concern basically
how two concerns the context for X
powerful that is being defined the
second one is a clarification regarding
that we don't want to have replay
capability when you have the data store
push the third aspect and this is busy
the third basically the the the open
minor issue but it is a it is a major
concerns where they how the stream is
designated currently basically this is
done to identity and Martin suggestion
was why don't we use string for that so
there's a trade-off between these be the
reason basically why identity is chosen
right now it's all that you have a set
of the busy each stream has an identity
they have a well-defined semantics it is
part of the model and defined as part of
that you can also if you want to add
additional types of streams that you
could subscribe to you can add
additional identities you can also have
build your hierarchy obviously if you
have a classification sub categorization
of that and if you want to have an ad
hoc stream and I think this is busy
where Martin's concerned and essentially
come from then you can have something
using a custom identity so that's one
stream that is custom and and that would
basically any other stream and if it is
so desired to actually also distinguish
between different custom streams and one
could do so or one could potentially
also bezzie added conditional custom
stream name or something along those
lines anyway so that is basically well
this believe what we have there on the
pro string side is busy just the easy
you can be ad hoc
to introduce new new string names and
you're not tied to busy having these
predefined in the models and there's a
busy one thing where it would be good to
get feedback from here and Barash is
ready to get you on your lyrics on I am
actually put speaking about the other
topic replay we have been using a known
very similar solution we don't change
updates tones used for configuration
mirroring with replay so I am upset
don't really want to take as replay for
I agree that for periodic subscription
it doesn't make much sense but for own
change notification unchanged push
updates I think it is meaningful okay
thank you Jason Stern I had a comment
about the stream names I kind of like
the string idea in a way and I was just
thinking like back in I think it's 50 to
I think it was just a string and they
just defined a name that was a standard
name so we could do a string and reserve
some name I guess reserve some names for
the standard ones you want to have
well-defined semantics in the spec it's
one option well yeah I think that that
is busy but wouldn't be required to have
bunch of yeah well defined names yeah
are there any other comments
yes just one Eric go ahead Eric I guess
he left
Oh Erika's online and he was I mean
right is this the only issue remaining
Alex that I'm aware of yes okay so as
the go ahead please stay tuned
yeah I'm going Jim from Hawaii Alex I
think as a issue which is cast that just
no we should confirm each before last
call for the go home parameters and for
how to state the unchanging and you know
how to define the unchanged model for
Zeta to issue so what was the second
issue sorry the first the first one is
basically call home buddy that you save
it for the configured subscription maybe
when you define the transport clarifying
that busy you would use column to
establish this subscription air and if
you use call home basically to establish
the connection is this what you're
referring to
yes ii 84 which which except to support
as their own changes of solution you
know just not with this colorful
unchanging you know now is defined that
one by one for a duration young and you
know for that just now we discussed
whether can you use metadata I think I
can confirm yeah but I think is a should
make clear
okay thank you so before a lotta you go
on yes I have one message from second
okay so I do see it's a message for you
about some pressing big red button only
once I turn it okay on that goes
otherwise you will accept and really the
floor at the same time oh he was just
there again military I thought I pressed
it once only
yeah I guess he it yeah so
you might wanna try coming back again or
just send the question on jabber
alright so so why don't we in the
meantime let's let's move to the well to
the other drafts so requests here is
discussed this may be one quick question
to give Eric time to to join but in what
case picking our Strang to quickly
quickly check is this one an NDA
compliant actually no it is not so there
it so that is yeah so so busy this it is
not an it is not an NDA compliant the
question is basically whether an MVA
compliance would be needed here because
we don't have interplay between between
things which are configured which are
non configure tense of every nominee
have to have those dependencies so there
is basically so we do have currently
basically state that if that does define
missing which curve which subscriptions
are in effect versus beta subscriptions
which happen which have been configured
so tool to follow the nmda guidelines
that would actually require updates okay
thank you so in MDA compliance is always
needed if you are using something from
an MDA you need to be complying well but
the the thing is okay you can use it
also you know can you you can use it
with the nmda architecture but basically
the guidelines that you should collapse
the that you should collapse a bottle
and that you therefore basically
optimize the model because you save some
mods which you would you save some
objects which are no strictly speaking
no longer needed that is basically the
valve unless we are near to last call
yang doctors review will be started and
they will take care of an MVA compliance
okay Bob Wilson Cisco so just quick
comments on that I think you could just
name your container without a - - state
so I still have a state only container
but just remove the - state at the end
of it because they knew you had
configuration in the future you can
change things being conflict true you
don't have conflict true stuff under
contain
it's got a - stay to the end so just
rename the containing problem okay
thanks Lada
so again relaying Erik white on Jabbar
parabolas previous comment on the replay
I am replying to his question on that
conf
mailing list presumably basically real I
should have a notification ID so there
is not close duplication in replied
items and my opinion is that a new RPC
should be added as part of a new draft
in conjunction with not notifications to
let God answer your question so in so
basically angle Ericsson we used
notification based on time so when and I
don't know when we say new RPC will that
go into these set of drafts or a
complete new RFC later there isn't
there's a new draft that this will be
presented actually later in this which
concerning notification bundles and that
one actually does have the facilities
for your for instance link to where you
can point actually to the previous
message so you can find some detect and
so forth if there if there are any
updates that you missed and so for
picture which should address those
concerns but they are not in this draft
right is this busy the other this is the
notifications to draft I think not but
still replay can be done based on time
stamps not just on message ID or a
notification ID I just want to state
that we would okay we need a solution
where you can replay at least on change
notifications okay alright so there is a
result so there is an update anyway and
after this meeting once the update is
available
Mahajan Kent will decide whether it can
go to
okay I mean based on the available
issues and how substantial they are the
decision needs to be taking all right
okay so let me get get to the other
three drafts actually there are
hopefully less issues and actually they
update their happy to update as well and
but the updates have been more minor
minor nature's basically it so the the
Netcom subscribe notifications this had
essentially a number of text weeks
clarification text again regarding we
play we etc and the transport routes
have just general general general
cleanups that we have here actually this
is the on the last item this is
information not quite correct we had
actually conversation before that being
regarding the whole working hard working
group last call we would actually
request to go to working group last call
because this issue is actually not
specific to the notification drafts is
more general issues regarding t RPC an
HTTP compatibility happening having
where the question was but he can we
have G RPC kinds which are automatically
compatible with with rest conf and
there's a there's the issue and there's
an issue concerning the support of the
get operation and G are physically but
it's somewhat orthogonal for those
lights it sorry there was an update for
the slide set where this last pallet has
been removed
yes okay I mean the dependency with G
RPC is not between gr PC and Netcom push
drafts it might be a depends between GRC
Andres conf but I or the co-chairs
would like to hear more on this issue
and discuss whether this issue is
relevant for us or not so I don't know
very much the details of such a
dependence between G RPC and rascal at
the moment we would like to hear more on
this
at some point I mean whoever feels
responsible should bring in a few slides
or bring it to the main list okay thanks
so that's it please provide an update
for the drafts you are mentioning and
Netcom co-chairs will guide and we will
see whether a last call can be started
soon so next is Rob no still Alex on the
bundles we seem to be on time good so
this is the other draft that that was
just mentioned
so this basically a new draft but part
of the earlier package did they follow
on work concerning concerning is any
providing the ability to bundle multiple
notifications into a single notification
having become defined in common headers
for that and you've seen earlier busy
another revision or another version of
this of this diagram that shows how the
different drafts relate basically with
their with the with the transports and
etc on the bottom and then be the
subscription and the push updates on the
on the top so essentially there this
this essentially would sit right above
the notification is so right above the
the transfer updates because this
defines basically the message headers
they would be food in the in those
updates so the purpose is to be able to
bundle multiple updates and notification
records into a single notification
message and essentially define the
header parameters and so forth that
would go into that and we distinguish
between what would go into the record
and what would go into the overall
button so basically it's about
distinguishing the the record contents
from the wrapper that the record is
basically ending and busy having the
refere be able to bundle multiple
notification messages essentially this
well at the corpus is
the yang model and Betty this defines
basically the notification messages
first for predict Li a single
notification message but we have basic
message header with the field that you
see here record time type subscription
identifier and so forth
one item perhaps to point out here is
the is the object on the message
generator idea it's a second from the
bottom and this basically is to deal
with the possibility of distributing
subscriptions where you can have
different notification or streams that
come for that originate from what
appointed from different line cards that
you want to distinguish where they are
from here as touch points with another
draft that general and Walker are going
to present her later on that he goes
action born to monitor those issues
anyway so that's that's basically the
notification message containing a single
record and then there is the bundle but
you see here so there you would have a
bundle notification message but you have
busy various information that is valid
for the for all records set which are in
a bundle from the individual records
which wasn't busy be contained
underneath that and that's okay so next
steps to that is to you know basically
to reveal revise the data data model
there are a few fields that which may be
a little bit over specified so we will
take a look at that and we want to also
basically align this with the concept of
having multiple message generators for
subscriptions of this is something which
is currently alluded to within this so
that you can have one subscription you
have multiple message streams originally
originating from different line cards it
seemed like a somewhat orthogonal so
maybe this is something that will be
pulled out potentially also combined
with the we had some conversations with
Cameron and Walker regarding the other
graphic might actually put it better
there so this very some of the ongoing
discussions if we should pull it out but
anyway so this is where we are that's
that's what I happen the crush is also
busy if the working group is interested
in this work alright so let me ask that
question so you before I do that tree
you believe that the document is ready
for work Rupert
yes so that's what we want to request
yes okay all right so with the show of
hands please indicate whether you
believe that that the working group
should take up this particular document
okay
a fairly decent show of hands so I think
we will then issue a call on the mailing
list or a group adoption Thanks okay
next is Rob giving a summary is a bridge
between NDMA and Netcom rafts so I'll
try and not bore you to death with this
because I mean an MBA you've heard a lot
about it so I'm in fact this is very
quick intro to three draft you about to
hear from from Kent and feel presenting
them so to tie this together
so this will just remind what N&B a is
the key points are the operation of
state datastore and splitting to the
operators are asking device to do this
what it's actually doing and if you look
at the implications for that we know the
data models are changing has been lots
of discussions this week about that and
how to modify the data forms to be an
NDA compatible we're talking about
potentially deprecating net confident
get but not at this stage over time but
there needs to be new net confrim risk
on four dishes to support operational
data stores and this is the picture that
I've shown in net modern is in the in
the draft and you'll see obviously what
we've now got here that's different from
what was there before is these new data
stores but the intended datastore we've
got the operational data store and we
potentially got dynamic data stores as
well I'm sort of a ITRs so we need to
add a protocol extensions to net conf
the audience handle States was fairly
cleanly so there's extensions there rest
Gulf has to have similar extensions to
that that's a bit trickier because they
have a sort combined view today so can't
explain how I plan to handle that
but the key point I really want to pull
out here is that the scope of both of
these drafts is trying to do minimal
changes and extensions to Netcom from
restaurant to support nmda so we're not
trying to go any further we're trying to
get these documents just done as quickly
as these pragmatic in in this
organization and finally it's worth
mentioning that your library is also
going to be updated that's used by both
protocols and yeah and this the solution
there effectively works in the same way
for both of them so that's what I had to
say I think questions are probably best
and directed both to Kent and fellow
appropriate thank you no ok so as
promised the update to yang library or
the proposed up at the yang library so
the motivation for wanting to do this is
first that existing RFC is don't provide
an ability to suppress all that's needed
RFC
7950 which is yang 1.1 and 80 40 which
is rest huh say that all net conf and
restaurant servers must support 78 95
which is the yang module library sorry
yes this is a question to graph outer
and net mod co-chair is it allowed that
net comp draft changes or updates yang
language RFC shouldn't it be decided in
net not working group ok yes good point
I'm not sure exactly how we should move
that forward but yes yes and and to be
clear the update to 7950 isn't so much
to the yang language itself for the
syntax the yang it's more having to do
with the statement that it says yeah you
know because 7950 describes the xml
encoding then
for knockoff and it's really regarding
the statement that it says that the
Netcom servers must support gang
libraries so that's that it's not really
- yang language itself it's just to that
statement about the conformance for net
comp servers if you actually I don't
mean if you want to pop a stack there's
an even a bigger question about you know
the gang next and wanting to factor
those things out of yang 1.1 and and you
know moving those conformance type
statements into some net controlled
working group document but at the moment
you're right it is it is a net mod
working group document another comment
um yeah a Behrman we already have
capability urs for candidate writable
running and startup so how does this
proposal interact with them is if I
advertise candidate am I allowed to put
something in here that says some
configure holes true node is is not
supported in candidate no but maybe the
potential collision or confusion or any
value at all in listing modules that are
only used in the conventional data
stores so this this might be a better
question answer on the next slide but
quickly the the one issue might be if
you connect to a hello to an Netcom
server and it sends a hello and it says
it supports the Canada Day store but
then you go to the yang library this
will the pros proposing library and it
says the Canada Day store is not there
right that inconsistency but I view that
more as a bug on a server that it would
even provide that inconsistent data view
another coming not a much Kaimuki
addressing issues it was raised by by
make meant my personal view is that we
should antagonize too much over it
because so first of all process wise I
believe that it's no rule that says that
an RFC as it was worked by one working
group cannot be updated but an RFC that
was other working group and for all
practical purposes is the same people in
two different rooms and actually you can
just run the last call copies a net most
working group and we are fine so that's
my opinion
thank you for that
balázs Daniel Erickson it is strange
that some data stores will be advertised
as capabilities well I don't know if we
in intend to have a capability for
intended or operational also what does
it mean that let's say I support
intended if I just copy over in the
running to intended does the is that
support already so please make some
statement what does it mean to support
such a datastore sure okay so first off
it again it's not an exercise a tree
diagram but but the proposal is that
there's a list of data stores in each
data store has a list of properties and
those properties are closely aligned to
capabilities so you'll find property
names like writable running and validate
and whatnot so so there is this ability
also to provide that the comparable
support it's not for Netcom for abundant
but for a restaurant that's necessary
there's no other way to describe these
things second thing regarding the
support what does it mean I think in
part the definition of the intended
datastore is defined inside the revised
datastore draft so it's really to be
taken up there but also I mean it's what
it means is that there exists a data
store a resource that you can get views
from it's read-only resource so it's a
set interesting question
yes okay let me continue again with the
motivation we're still on a second
bullet point here so these two RFC's say
that 78 95 must be supported regardless
if they support nmda or not and so we
want to leverage this requirement so
that you know this this yang module
library 78 95 is already it's got the
hook it's the must thing that all
servers implement but then if you look
to 1795 what does it say
it says that there's a mandatory to
implement module state tree that a
server uses to advertise all the modules
it supports this module state tree
assumes that all modules are in all data
stores there's no ability to
differentiate which modules are where so
there's not actually the case with nmda
right some modules may only appear in
the operational data store so if you
think about foreign
since the neck network topo modeled in
the ITRs working group where they talk
about underlays and overlays it could be
that a server only supports presenting
the underlays I know the the topology
it's discovered from the network without
any ability at all to configure the
overlays so here's an example or a
module would only appear or a server
might only support it in the operational
datastore similarly some modules may
only appear in the dynamic datastore if
you think about for instance the in
iiterest a femoral rib where it's never
expected that it would actually be
configured and anywhere else another
example of some modules may only appear
in running when a server hasn't yet been
coded to support the op state yet night
and actually have a slide that touches
on this more but it's sort of a
migration a graceful migration phasing
strategy that we're suggesting and
lastly there may be variations in
features and deviations between these
data stores so you know in the running
or a conventional data stores
traditional features and deviations are
there but then if you were to look for
instance to a dynamic or operational
there actually might be a variation in
the features and deep-end deviations
that are being in effect at that look at
that that data store
okay so summary of changes to 7890 pi
that are being proposed so first off
it's renaming the document title from
gang module library to just yang library
this is because the tree diagram is no
longer just about modules it also is
about data stores and furthermore we
want to sort of it's a hedging bet to in
case there's any future extensions that
are desired being a server metadata info
this is now providing a place where that
a future metadata could be augmented in
it deprecates the module state tree
because that particular tree assumes all
modules are defined in all data stores
and we have a comment to the mic please
I'm not sure that this change going from
yang module library to yang library only
is really useful because I believe the
semantics is slightly different and this
can even more
become confusing with the normal term
that we use the libraries usually are
some software libraries that use we have
already libraries that are called yang
lip and labia and and so on
so perhaps III personally don't like
this term library for this purpose very
much if native speakers could come up
with something that's we already have
Yin catalog unfortunately used for other
purpose so and I I don't know this yang
module library really means that it's a
library of yang mode use Faris yang
library I don't know it I I'm not in
favor of doing this change exactly
although of course in many cases it's
only used as yang library without the
module number two
so it's not the best name but in defense
I think everyone refers to this yang
library and no one actually probably
even knows it's called the yang immortal
library another comment that was gonna
be one comment it's it's everyone in
common parlance calls it yang library
there's really we're actually helping
people because when they go to when they
want to find out what yang library is
there actually a document called yang
library instead of finding a document
called yang module librarian wondering
where the definition of yang Yang
library is I understand your confusion
you know I would the developer would
look for Lybian a if you said yang
library so I understand the confusion
but it's just commonly use my experience
is that any person that just comes mu to
- yang and read some stuff about that
becomes confused especially they are
software developers they always ask
people what kind of library is this and
so okay so this one's easy to take to
the list and resolve there the last
sorry okay sorry okay another comment
coming anywhere we sold the original
module state that's completely cut and
pasted and cut and started over actually
says nothing about data stores your
additional data structures
that point into this say something about
datastore so the the idea that we need
to deprecate
the original thing because it it it
doesn't support this new stuff thats
added years laters seems rather extrange
to me
okay that's a fair point I can just make
your leaf riffs point it the thing
that's already there instead of the cut
and paste that's a fair point
um so we did it we kind of went back and
forth but in the end we felt like the
simplest easiest thing would be to use
the existing grouping which is why it
does look like an exact copy paste and
since we did in the end your we could
actually just not deprecated module
State and point to it and of course
module state has the - Dayton in it to
be in MVA compliant we might want to
take this opportunity to back out of it
but I I understand what you're saying
Robertson Cisco I thought those tear
eases we did this one was because at the
moment module state redefines that all
modules defined in all data stores and
we're changing that doesn't it okay the
the other point was we wanted to
actually put an extra layer into the
tree so that when you're accessing this
information from a client you could all
get it in one request and I think of
accessing this existing module state
tree that would be more a hassle so
certainly the second comment is true
going back to the first comment you're
right it doesn't actually say that but
the semantics that are understood when
people go to module state if a legacy
client were to go and and you know ask
for the yang library it would get module
state and think that all these models
are implemented in all data stores so
perhaps by even though it's the same
it's still a list of modules it's in a
different location and that location
doesn't have the semantics there's
there's Lexie clients can't reason it to
mean anything other or you know in in
the old legacy way so we can take that
to the list
updates to 7950 and 84-84 t these are
actually they are they're updating these
draft in the same way in both cases
there's a section in those drafts where
they're claiming or stating that yang
library I'm sorry we're module state
module must be referenced and we just
want to change that to instead point to
the new path yang library modules module
so here's the proposed treated Graham
and um you know again underneath the
module list is actually the it's just
using the grouping from the existing
yang library so that block of you know
descendant nodes should look very
familiar to so there is a list of
modules and then there's a list of what
we call module sets so each module set
is having an ID so this is what
restaurant sort of refers to the module
set ID or it could be used as that for
that purpose and then the module set is
pointing to a list of modules so what
are the modules inside this module set
and then and that's in there being
referenced by ID not not by the two
tuple of name and revisions so this
actually is a little bit cleaner and
then lastly there's a list of data
stores which is pointing and each data
store is pointing to which module sets
it supports I know that it says actually
it's off or not it's not mandatory true
but it should be mandatory true in
addition to which module set that data
store is pointing to there's also a list
of properties so this is where we were
saying before about how some prep like
running datastore you could say it's
writable running it would have that
property
you see there's anything else I want to
say here yes the last point is that all
the conventional data stores would be
expected to point to the same module set
so you know there'd be datastore entries
for running and intended and and Canada
startup but all of them would are
expected to be pointing to exact same
module sets so there's no inconsistency
between the modules that are being
supported and specifically with regards
to the very features and deviations
right okay flex
provided so with this servers can state
how they support models per datastore
NMDA implementations can phase in
operational support on a module by
module basis I think this is very
important as servers go to implement
NMDA it would be massive if they
suddenly had all modules you know with
the applied view you know instrumenting
all that back in logic to provide to
provide the operational view of all the
values but being able to do it on a
module module basis have sort of allows
for graceful migration and just so we
hear about the config false nodes don't
count because config false nodes would
always show up in operational so when
you say that you're supporting a module
in for instance only in running it
doesn't detract from the fact that
config false notes still show up in
operational last well point to the nmda
implementations may only support the
operational view for specific modules
server only supports providing oh so we
talked about this one before
some more flexibility in enables
deviations and features per datastore we
talked about that as well and of course
all conventional data stores would point
to the same module set hamster be no
inconsistency between them and that was
my appreciation or comes so you want to
be able to say that's that medium and
even so the foo node is type in 32 in
the running game store and in its type
string in the candidate datastore and
it's type decimal 64 in in the
operational datastore that's why you
want to put deviations per datastore to
allow the implementation to have a
different data type and in whatever in
each data store that seems rather I
don't think it's specific data type from
it's not a feature in an example but
maybe it could find of this is it was
actually pushing for this sure because
that's not what the deviations are for
deviations are for the for the
implementation say I'm breaking the
rules I'm doing something wrong
you know in the past we've been able to
just say Oh everybody follows the rules
deviations are a way to express that
ability to say I'm broken or for
somebody else to say he's broken and and
and be able to express that in a
programmatic way that an application can
take advantage of it's not saying yes we
want to break all the rules because that
makes a world in which we don't want to
live but we want to live in a world
which where we understand which rules
have been broken and and and you know
the expectation is you go to your vendor
and you say here's the list of rules you
broke go fix them vodka
I believe it it could be opportune to
integrate scheme amount information into
this because for one it's not clear if
we have if we have a mount point in in a
module that's in multiple data stores
whether the schema mount is supposed to
be applied to all data stores or not I
don't know but maybe a second more
important point is that I believe this
young library information it's not only
some machine-readable data that that it
doesn't matter whether it's complicated
or all simple I believe this is some
kind of metadata that mean we might want
to use for other purposes we have
earlier today we discussed how to how to
validate instance data again some data
model so this might be useful to specify
in some way before you know it was
really just a collection of modules
because here we didn't have any other
mechanisms to do it more complicated now
we have the adjusters and we have schema
mount and I think it's really important
that we think about all this and try to
come up with something that makes sense
that people can really understand and
and use
Tim Karen okay I do have a question so
by changing this and adding the data
stores in the libraries you you made a
statement that said you can now provide
a migration path where you know some can
be old you know use the old way some
using the new and could you just expound
on that just a little bit further
because I'm trying to understand what
your thoughts behind of how that might
be used for migration sure so the this
draft says that a server implements nmda
if the operational data store can be the
resources available or if the this
module is present or if you yeah okay
blurs will basically the two things it
says but what does it mean that the
server supports operational does it
suddenly mean that all the modules are
present and in operational and we don't
think that is
I mean necessarily immediate immediately
true you would have the the server a
code would have to be modified in order
to provide that operational view it the
back end logic has to be modified in
order to actually look to line cards and
hardware to collect the applied state to
populate that response we just believe
it's going to take time and so for
servers that implement you know dozens
or hundreds of modules you know they you
could imagine them you know prioritizing
those over a year or two or three but it
wouldn't be immediately so so this is
what provides them an ability to sort of
you know present some applied State in
operational well you know over time and
more more well as Daniel Erickson I
thought that the simplest way of
migrating would be just if you get to
get data for operational you just copied
over the running and whenever you have
the code for really noticing the
difference is then you modify it is that
compliant but this is an option that we
could take up if we did do that then I
think that the response should somehow
have a flag or an attribute
indicate that that's what it did what
the server did but maybe that's the
that's what we did that's why I think
clarification of what support really
means is the intent is there I think we
all agree with the intent how we satisfy
that intent is sort of watch that issue
so I'm okay with if we want to consider
alternatives they're not clear on a sin
top on the same topic sorry and trying
to understand what unda mention is that
the ITF yang library does not mention it
a store right so if it doesn't then we
don't need to update it meaning that we
could just command if we want to refer
to data stores a plashy schema right
which means that potentially we don't
need to update 79 50 and 80 40 this is
this correct in my response to nd what I
was saying because imagine you have a
server that exists today and then it's
updated to support in MDA but it's still
we're not deprecated we're not removing
the existing module state tree and the
server wants to continue to support
legacy clients so I have a mix of legacy
clients plus in India where clients the
legacy clients would go to the module
estate to get to see all the modules
supported presumably those that are in
running would be present but but but the
server would potentially also support
more modules may be for instance and
dynamic data stores right but but if
those new modules that would also show
up in module state then the legacy
client would also see them and probably
assume that they're configurable through
running even though that's not the case
why I assume because that's how they're
coded today they they they go to look to
list of modules and module state and
just as there's no way there's no
indication or a flag to specify that
which data stores that are available in
the existing module state that's right
so they have to go to the new module
there to discover it the legacy client
wouldn't do that that's right but what I
mean they can do that today
so I'm
I still do that today anyway right I
don't understand the question right Phil
Schafer are you sick then why are you
saying deprecated in place make this new
thing that people go to and just kind of
without explicitly deprecating the
existing modules hierarchy yes is there
a place where we can argument because I
thought it didn't have a root it module
states the top-level container and we
want to get away from we'd like to have
a separate top-level container that we
could target to retrieve all the server
metadata info in one response okay okay
I agree with what you're saying so a
legacy client sees the new module
it says config equals true but it's
really I to RS and it's not going to be
writable and in candidate or running and
they will try to write it in candidate
or running correct unlikely but it's
scenario but yes I guess it's safer to
not confuse the legacy line so we can
continue the discussion on the medes or
offline also I'm disposed in the I mean
it is covered by the Charter it has been
asked for to prepare so it is good that
we have it just a question do you want
to add something before adoption or do
you think it is ready to adopt I think
it's ready to adopt of course the once
adopted it becomes a working group
document and we can edit it and modified
any way we need to so there is nothing
substantial missing now okay so go ahead
Marsh
all right so the usual question for
adopting show fans for people who
believe that this document needs to be
adopted
all right sizeable size so I guess we
will make the call again on the mailing
list
okay next is Phil on nmda for net Kampf
my presentation is short we want to add
in my presentation is short we want to
add an NMDA support to net comp we do
this through tuner operations get data
and edit data which are essentially get
config and edit config pulled over with
a new target leaf that is of that
supports the the new data stores get
data supports the origin attribute so
that you can figure out an operational
data where your data comes from it
codifies a hierarchical persistence so
that for any parent for any child you
you can the the a child's origin
attribute defaults to its parent in
addition we augment three operations to
add a new datastore leaf and that's it
how's that for easy Jason's turn here
can you go back to your first slide and
just something just triggered me on like
on the get should that be a source leaf
or a target for the get I believe it's
called target in the existing today
forget config we do we make it a target
its source okay so maybe that maybe
should be source okay and it may be
source and I wrote the wrong thing so
this might be a question that Andy might
ask again but let me prompt him by
saying in the last meeting in Chicago
the question on what happens to get came
up does any thoughts on is get gonna get
deprecated is it going to be augmented
replaced my failure is to get should be
def kept get should be deprecated
because it's poorly defined and there
were some people who were feeling it
should be kept so I mean if people in
the room are in favor of deprecating is
fine
and we they can see people in favor of
keeping get need to speak up mm-hmm
anywhere man I don't have any problems
with this draft or the restaurant it's
it's all fine to me it would just like
one clarification in the nmda
architecture because this is an identity
ref I don't have to actually support the
operational data spore I could support
Bob's operational data store and I want
to make sure that for conformance
purposes a server must support the real
operational they may support additional
operational x' but they must support the
real one and I think this is something
Balazs also brought up we want to know
do you you really support this data
store and we'd like to you know see that
conformance that that an NMDA device is
going to support the real data the real
operational and the real and intended
the identity ref allows anything that
uses the same base and so for
conformance like to say these mandatory
ones you have to support and you may add
your own but you may not you know for
conformance versus replace the standard
one
so the yang library should give you the
information on what it device supports
and what it won't
I hate putting that kind of mandatory
language into it into any definition
because it prevents future evolution
let's say let's say in in in you know in
the same way that that the language in
the yang spec that binds it to yang
library rather than just to a particular
RFC rather than just having that
information external requires us to
update that particular RFC I rather have
flexibility and health standards are
used even though we only see how they're
used today and and which always remains
like that that that one would expect
your your Lang Lang library request to
return the operational data store and
what module sets are
are supported by it right now we we only
had three standard data stores and and
this server implementation is not
allowed to make up any new ones okay so
that that is useful for the client to
know who would like to code to an
architecture rather than an
implementation and I actually see it the
other way it's limiting in terms of in
terms of the implementation because if I
want to come up with but I want to have
a standard that has interoperability
value I don't want multiple massive
flexibility so that's my opinion could
you go to the next slide please
maybe I made a mistake the next one down
the validate one yeah um the lock/unlock
invalidate is per day distorted and this
is a this is a clarifying question the
validators per data store that's what
that that means there yeah the current
the current spec for for lock and unlock
has a specific set of data stores that
one can lock we want to make that
generic by by saying we supply an
identity okay so so can I into is
validate also for all the data stores or
is it just for the intended so you can't
request a validate of intended because
intended you already know is valid you
can't have an invalid addendum but it
would allow you to to validate running
or startup or dynamic or dynamic okay or
whatever we come up with in the future
that's what I was I'm focused on dynamic
I me then ask my thank you that was the
first part of my question and this also
allows you to lock and unlock dynamic
this is that's wonderful that's really
great now on the specifics of what you
do if you don't have the standard
validate that's something you define and
the data store where'd is that so if you
have additional validation let me be
really specific for the ITRs ephemeral
by the requirements we described there's
some
validation you can go from a femoral to
config as far as constraint or to ops or
a couple other bit but you can't have
something go from config to ephemeral
that's that's a validation piece that we
sent as part of our requirements I'm
assuming that's what that validate does
or is it's supposed to do something else
just just this clarification it done how
you envision that envision is doing the
the validation operation for that
particular database if you have rules
for your sorry to not database datastore
if you have rules for your free
datastore that say here are the rules
for validity for I to RS datastore then
that operation would enforce that would
would inform you of validations of those
okay well we're aligned in that thought
okay thank you very much Marshall
Eriksen I was missing two things from
the guarantor get data operation
I thought we will be able to filter on
origin and I'm definitely missing and
I'm needing a filter that allows me to
get only the config force data is that
intentional or will that be in we don't
have that now we can certainly add it
please do some of course origin itself
is is a feature so so that would be
optional can't just respond to that
question arm I do if we'd Ward add that
that'd be a separate RFC I mean how do
we do filtering on metadata generic RFC
it wouldn't it's not necessarily
specific to in MDA so does that mean oh
so you don't want to filter on config
through config force because I think
that was one of the main reasons why we
had the separate state three sub trees
in originally so the rest cough protocol
already has the query parameter for you
know content so you can do that in
restaurants I'm not I don't think
there's no reason we should couldn't add
it to but even then that that's
different than filtering and metadata
which is what the origin is
and state yet state AG golfing force is
my main need I just thought and of
course even though you're doing get
false you actually all your identifiers
will be config true so yeah I just like
to echo that I my gut is that some sort
of way of getting config true versus
config false separate from being
interval filter on metadata might be
might be useful um back to validate I
thought there was still a bit of an open
issue we were talking about validation
what it means I mean this drat the the
nmda or actually the data stores draft
talks about templates I know even though
we don't define them we talk about
template expansion between in I guess
running and intended camera where the
expansion happens so and that template
expansion can change whether something
valid or not right like well since it
ends up and intended it has to be valid
so I mean so I could take I think it so
with templates before expansion
sometimes configs are not valid right
like relief refs may not be completed
etc until that templates expanded right
so you could ever running that that is
in fact that doesn't validate and then I
would North candidate I'm working you
edit the candidate you fill in a
template okay yeah so they so Kennedy
gets copied running running gets the
template mechanism run against it fills
in a a complete intended and then that
yeah so I can see Oh antenna would be
valid but does are we now saying that
implementations that have a template
mechanism no longer have valid
candidates yes
we're running I guess it's not really
related to this draft suppose early
accept this draft is the first one that
kind of has language around template
expansion
yeah and that's that's part of why we
tweezed all these apart so that you can
have a template mechanism that affects
your candidate are running you know
imagine something imagine imagine a
template mechanism that fills in you
know you haven't you your your
you have a mandatory field and yeah
exactly and your and your template
mechanism fills it in all the time is
false yeah so I mean I can I can I can
see how it completes and intend to keep
it can become valid am i more worried
about now that where is this draft is
the datastores draft almost kind of
telling us now that implementations of
template have invalid candidates which
is not really a concept where you really
kind of well it's kind of a concept we
face we fudged over so this puts it in
in in a more stark contrast that's why
you see it more but like under chinos
yeah so would you guys the can return
failed to account to see your candidate
now someone runs a validate well part of
the part of the validate operation as
opposed to the so if a client comes in
fetch and fetches the candidate
configuration they'll get the raw data
yeah that mandatory field will be
missing that's right if you do the
validate operation on the on the
candidate it will succeed because the
template mechanism will be run in place
to generate the full configuration well
if you're running validate under
candidate the contents the candidate
itself is not valid because those aren't
that's not expanded until it's in the
intended but again the purpose of the
validate operation is to is to see you
know when this is committed will this be
valid we can take this discussion also
to the main list or okay you guys can
continue discussing later yeah I'm not
sure whether it's fair to put this on
the datastores draft but it's I mean the
Davis or drafts the one that brings up
this template expansion so we may want
to figure out like I said what we want
to say about it we left a lot of
fuzziness that which we have yeah sorry
for interrupting Laden I don't actually
I want to sort of second Jason said I
had a very similar comment during the
net mod session I think we have to be a
little bit careful here because I mean
what validate means because yang spec
says that some properties have to be
satisfied in all data trees and some
properties need to be satisfied
invalidated trees I can imagine
templating mechanisms that break even
those properties that are like they
types for example you put an asterisk
instead of name aside like that so I
really think this needs to be clarified
what template because it's its templates
are only mentioned in a very and waving
way in in the nmda draft as you said
basically but in in terms of what what a
schema means whether really it can be it
can be broken in candidate or in running
even that that's quite an important
point I believe we can certainly so I
don't I don't want at this point to have
to specify what it what the with what a
templating mechanism is or any sort of
standard thing but we can certainly say
here are rules templating mechanisms
cannot break you cannot break individual
datatypes you cannot break Keys you
cannot break hierarchy you know you're
all of this for the for the candidate
and running have to be in place okay we
need to move on please quick last
question the yank standard contains the
sentence the running-config
data store must always be valid if we
have this templating managed is this
Center still true that is that is not
true in a tenet have for many
implementations hasn't been true which
is a start maybe if some updated for
that yeah are you done yep just the
question is there anything substantial
you want to add before adoption or is
everything you mentioned here or it in
draft filtering an origin was not in the
draft rules for templating was not in
the draft and that was first one there
was a thorough knee I personally would
be in favor of having those things in
the drop before adoption but I let my
heart speak well also the question on
validate I think there's quite a bit
right so I would second moments opinion
that I think we probably might want to
put that in before we make a call for it
up
even in a draft state we would need such
text a little bit at least Thank You
Kent in the MA for a restaurant so this
was again a draft covered by the Charter
and it'll be just adopted once it's
ready okay so introduction this solution
is backwards compatible with the
existing restaurant servers factors
compatibility is achieved by only adding
new top-level resources
rest comp defined slash data and we're
introducing a new top-level resource
thereby leaving all the semantics for
all the existing resources alone summary
of updates as just mentioned we're
adding a new top of a resource this was
/d s I know we try to we shy away from
acronyms but after looking at datastore
slash datastore many many times it
became obvious that it was just gonna be
too long and ugly
so /d s we also add a new query
parameter with origin this is to enable
the filtering on on data based on upper
origin it also it states that section
three five four paragraph three doesn't
apply for all the new des resources this
is the one that says that if he--if a
particular leaf is being referenced the
resources being referenced and its value
is the same as the value of the default
value then the server must return an
even if it's a server that has the
explicit a basic mode we believe that
the server should you know be allowed to
continue to use as standard with default
behavior I even in that case so this
actually isn't specific to nmda in
particular but we're kind of addressing
and what we think is an oversight or an
issue with the rest contract and we get
to do it because we're defining a new
resource so we're taking advantage of
this opportunity again this draft does
not deprecated the slash data resource
and but maybe it should I mean something
that we could
right speaking some more about the /data
Deus resource datastore is encoded as an
identity as was mentioned before so for
instance we have the standard identities
which are defined inside the revised
datastore draft in a net mod working
group so they're all prefixed with the
module name ITF - datastore but then
other RFC's can define their own
identities so for instance an example
des ephemeral draft could define a deus
ephemeral datastore and yet they all
show up because our identities we did
this in particular it because we income
in lieu of having a anima defined
registry this is much more dynamic and
flexible this is why the motivation for
using identities instead of just a flat
list of strings some conformance
verifications so clients can test either
if operation will exist you know how do
they how does a client know if the
restaurant server supports nmda they can
they can do a head the head operation
HTTP head operation on that URL just to
see whether or not the resource exists
or if the yang library container exists
others being that the new revision so
here you could either do a head or a get
operation oh by the way I guess in
theory you could do a get operation on
the on the operational but you would get
back all the data which is ridiculous
right you would never want to do that
that's why I didn't show that as an
example but if you're you know the
resource is actually targeting the yang
library get maybe you know appropriate
because in the end one of the very first
things a rest client sorry a restaurant
client would want would be the yang
library so so you know in one step it
can boast check to see if the server
supports an NDA and get the contents of
the yang library so probably preferred
would be one of these latter it shows
here that you could the client could
either check for the yang library in
underneath the slash the new top-level
resource or the legacy top-level
resource right because both would
provide the same content but at the end
at the bottom here we we prefer the end
we're clients not use the /data resource
so that resource could be deprecated
more easily someday protocol operations
for the most part all protocol
operations defined in at44 the slash
data resource are apply to the new data
source with some exceptions though these
exceptions are one dynamic data stores
are excluded as each dynamic store
datastore definition needs to be
reviewed for what protocol operations
it's the force this actually goes to the
revised datastore draft where it talks
about dynamic data stores and
specifically calls out that you know
each dynamic store source datastore
specifies the protocols and and even if
it says it supports neck huh it may not
support for and locking in that conf
with it like an ephemeral data store
there's no notion of Netcom so so so
surely that that name data store
excluded from that comment some data
stores are read-only by nature the for
instance the slash intended and also
operational so any attempt to modify
those data stores would fail also as
mentioned before the paragraph 3 of
section 3 5 4 doesn't apply and of
course the new query parameter with
origin that's it
what is now actually the meaning of the
unified datastore in rest conf isn't it
that it's now more like a candidate if
for example an implementation has the
applied datastore so that I can somehow
edit this unify datastore but does it or
does it mean that it will be immediately
the stuff edited will immediately appear
in applied if it works this way I mean
if it's applied immediately so the the
unified datastore is the slash data
resources and in underneath /d s we have
a new data source specific resources
where they take on the more
traditional or dates for specific
interpret X and so they're no longer
unified there is no way there is no
unified datastore underneath the /d s
datastore that said if you.we we were
cognizant or concerned about this that
you may have an NMDA aware server that
you know maybe someday only wanted to
present the new resource without
presenting slash data and so with the
properties remember in the yang library
presentation I mentioned each datastore
has properties one of the properties I
think it was called Auto commit
sometimes like this and it was meant it
was intent if you read the description
statement for it it's intended to be
used for the running datastore and and
what it gives you is essentially the
unified data store like behavior where
you know whether or not the server
actually implements startup regardless
if you write to running it's going to
auto commit so the there is a
incantation of properties that can be
used with the new data stores that give
you the Universal datastore like nature
enter a related question could this be
used for introducing a candidate beta
store in the restaurant it could be so
the the revised datastore draft in the
DES sorry the ietf datastore yang module
it does define identity for Canada and
this draft doesn't preclude the ability
for that identity to appear but at the
same time at this moment we're not
defining any operations like copy or
commit we could but we were not at this
time defining those operations and then
also I think if we were to wanting
wanting to do that we wouldn't right
because let's shared candidate I think
it's a known issue that's the problem
and and we prefer doing private
candidates so I don't think we should do
that we if we were interested in doing
candidate data source at all we should
probably think rethink how we do them we
actually have an implementation that
uses a per-user candidate so that in my
view makes a lot of sense so you would
like to have some standard mechanism now
to query
these exactly
two questions the first you know I asked
at our dress about the entity tag did
you get a chance to act as an t about
that we not know okay we'll do that
offline then Andy it just it was whether
we could use the entity tank for the
client priority split prior to us for
the dynamic ephemeral so for people that
are online Andy just said that we should
double-check with HTTP people yeah and
we'll do that thank you Andy that's
helpful
that means we probably have to have
metadata I would like to not double use
things okay second question is Section
three dot go back up to the sections at
work not Section three dot v dot four is
that where you're defining the roll back
I thought it was on a different section
don't know it's not it's not here
this section is regards what the
behavior of the server when a leaf is
being targeted and that Leafs values
happens to be the same as the default
value mm-hmm and and what it says that
the value must be returned all the time
regardless those could regardless of the
server supports explicit mode or not and
the reason why this is concern is
because if it's returned all the time
then the client doesn't actually know if
it was there if it's configured or not
yep so wherever the rollback is defined
part of the requirements were there were
you had to have a restriction on the
roll back for the ephemeral so I don't
know if we need to add an augment that
says we don't have to do it all the time
we could only report the requirements
State at all or nothing and you roll
back I think didn't give me that option
either we augment it as an option or we
go forward that was one of those
requirements
in different estate okay some I'm trying
to think what you mean by robach so with
resk off you your it's pessimistic
locking right so we're using etag or or
the if modified and it's all-or-nothing
either the server takes or a doesn't ok
so there's nothing to go but but but but
then there's a second thing which is a
rollback on error right the traditional
Netcom and that is addressed in the yang
library data store so each data store
has a list of properties one of the
properties that we've defined is called
rollback on error which you know has
that semantics i'm if you want to have
rollback on an error on it it is it is
it is the rest comp base functionality
so what you're telling me to reflect
back just to confirm rest comforters the
thing will block all or roll back if
there's error the rollback at all of
this error and the other part if someone
wanted to use it they could put it in
the egg libraries that would then affect
the federal data space and that would be
the implementations problem yes just
that so i as i was going to ask my
question the thing about the rollback on
error just triggered another one so
rollback on error in net comp
has two slightly different meanings
depending which data story working in if
it's on the candidate it's the scope of
that edit config because the rollback on
error is a attribute of the edit not of
the commit versus I guess with unified
or running rights it's intended to apply
to the action of actually applying the
config or not well there's two things
there's there's the error options that
can be passed on to an edit config for a
Jenny there's actually the RPC call
rollback on air right so if you're doing
a sorry it's an RPC it's it's a it's in
it's a it's a flag that's inside the
commit operation so as you're doing
commit you can pass a flag to say
whether is that look okay I wasn't
familiar with that part yes so it's in
6241 I think okay the the the other the
other question I had is we talked about
library how we're adding now we
we had modules before now we have to add
datastore information discussion about
rest comp just made me wonder our this
is the list of data okay so we have the
single new tree that describes data
stores and their properties are those
properties gonna be different for rest
comp versus net comp so if us know that
the remember these are views the
particles are views onto conceptual data
stores the properties are with the
conceptual data store yeah which is the
protocol so the protocol needs to
support the properties but the
properties won't vary by protocol I'm
more thinking about an implementation
that has different support for different
data stores on different types of
interfaces so you have a rest comp
server and a net comp server on your box
you're not necessarily gonna support the
same data stores on both those
interfaces are you should and three the
dynamic data store are you necessarily
gonna offer it on I don't know if sure
if we need to I'm not sure if we should
say that when you advertise it
necessarily means you have to support it
on all possible interfaces that access
data stores well if you can come up with
a strong use case okay we can take it to
the list well I mean the use case use
case I can think of is like an
implementation who's maybe gonna
implement I char s they may do it over
one interface to start not multiple
sorry may support over s compa start
really calm but again I trust as a
dynamic data store and per the revising
is for draft each dynamic stays for
defines its own semantics like from
scratch so whatever you support in the
properties you know may not I mean yes
so when I describe the datastore in the
state tree is fine but that stage that's
the module state or the new library tree
is gonna be presumably it's the same
library tree you're reading through
Netcom for s cough so then you advertise
the dynamic and that is only one place
to advertise the dynamic datastore okay
an impression that you support okay I'm
sorry I think I now understand your
question right so it is in the yang
library draft it says that the
the response that comes is actually with
respect to the server or less responding
so so the response could vary by a net
confident remember we are over time so
I'm sorry a lot that this out so based
on the questions I I'm gonna assume that
I think we need some more clarifications
before we ask for what group adoption
mm-hmm
actually I thought I was handling all
the questions where if there was
anything else to ending there are less
the quick question were you intending
how do you know what's valid inside of
the library ie how do you know which
modules might be valid for the dynamic
data store is that going to be an I in a
registry you know so in case someone
says here's my catalog is this really
true are you trained yourself generated
or you're trying to buy registry so this
is in the yang library action and so
that the the the data store entry for
the dinette for the ITRs ephemeral
datastore would have a pointer to a
module set which is those modules that
are supported inside that dynamic day
story okay so you're asking for because
I I see questions here and you said
you're taking it to the list that's why
I was we can consider we're going to
continue the discussion unless no matter
what I believe the working group should
adopt the straps even with questions
outstanding we have a milestone for
bringing this to last call in the
November time frame so all right just a
procedural thing as to whether or not we
push for adoption adoption now or a week
from now okay
so a short answer from people that they
feel that the document is ready for
workgroup adoption okay a fair number
all right so before we get off this film
if I can ask you to take one more
Akshara action item and to close on that
whole discussion of what to do with get
s ResNet confess concern the get
operation
okay now we have a slot for nama
architecture and guidelines
it'll be just summary actually we had
this summary today right
so questions can be answered quickly we
have less than 10 minutes time all right
so does anyone in this show of hands
again want Robert to go yet again over
guidelines as far as nmda what they need
changes they need to make the oil to be
NDMA compliant I guess we got that thank
you thank you for watch so now my coach
he has more time okay now Mahesh will
present on the accounting draft these
three yeah our I mean we need to go
through them and and discuss how can we
adopt or whether people are in favor of
working on those topics alright so I'm
going to talk about the three version of
the draft as a quick introduction this
draft is essentially addressing the last
a in triple-a accounting and defines the
yang model forward the changes since the
one have been and I know I skipped 0 2
in between but that was because I
submitted a division is I change the
accounting record a little bit and I'll
talk about that the addition of default
deny all China Claire clarify the
interaction with Chappell a server and
two additions so let's not in that same
order that I had listed there so I added
default deny all just like makam does to
protect records so you need an explicit
rule to be defined if you need access to
the accounting record
as far as modifications of the record
are concerned so I had a start/stop code
accounting start/stop code that was used
if you wanted to fragment the accounting
record as you were transmitting it I
dropped that simply because I think
that's going to be implementation
dependent depends who you're
communicating with and whether they need
that kind of fragmentation so I'm going
to leave it up to the implementations
that need to fragment an accounting
record to add that if it has need be I
also added a message ID with session ID
simply because there can be multiple
messages within a session and if you are
trying to key you would need that I
there was a question on what happens to
any values that you might want to
capture as part of the counting record
so example and I get is what was
requested so if there was a filter
parameter that was asked for
we will probably want to try to capture
it in the accounting records so he'd
know what was requested but there is at
the same time it tries not to capture
the entire response because that would
be just huge and especially with get or
get data so just to make sure that
that's true and same it-it-it config
again values for what was being modified
as part of the edit config also added
some examples in the appendix 3 examples
particularly on edit config get and how
to set the maqam rule considering that
there is a default deny all what a rule
would has to look like to for even a
user like root to be able to get access
to the accounting record so with the
change in record this is what the tree
diagram looks like
and as
mentioned the next step is to ask for
workgroup adoption questions any
comments questions on this draft who
read actually dissolved
I saw Andy I mean it has been already
presented twice this is the third
presentation I I mean what I remember
from last meeting there were some people
saying in favor
others were uneven or uninterested some
were saying I remember Kent stating that
net converter should start such work
later not now
but yeah after getting comments from
Jason for example I just need to know
again the same question who is in favor
of working on this topic in net
converting group theirs so Jason CERN I
apologize I've only skimmed through the
draft but I just want to confirm my
understanding I think it's not intended
to instantiate data in the node this is
just like a format you're proposing it's
like a so you're putting as a container
but it's just to represent a format of a
message that would go on a wire towards
a triple-a yeah and I guess that format
i I don't know is it something we know
that these triple-a servers will
recognize and be able to terminate that
format right so one is that there is no
format of what an accounting and it
could looks like today I mean it's kind
of free format in today so one is to
normalize that well there's tax and
radius accounting that probably has some
sort of yeah but what standard so I
think radius is statement somewhere that
is that they don't care what is in the
payload
so this is to formalize that payload
what is exactly in constitutes an
accounting record so I for example I
asked the operators what would you like
to see in an accounting record and so we
went back and forth on trying to figure
out what is an important piece of
information for them and based on that
feedback we came up with and if I define
what an accounting okay so I mean
there's one part of it one part of this
I think is is particularly useful is
that I guess you know defining what's
gonna get captured up in those
accounting records you put an instance
identifier just to say okay here's a
piece of data and yang tree and here's a
value I guess I'm just a little bit more
concerned about whether this format is
gonna properly inter work with some of
these other servers like you mentioned
it's the payload but you have like
start/stop fields and other things but I
think are part of the standard actually
radius accounting message aren't they
they're not just part of yes so in case
of yeah so radius when you're
communicating with radius and because it
at least used to require fragmentation
because it had a size limitation you
needed that but that's particular to
radius if you're doing this say just
doing a get over net come and doing
accounting I could get you won't need to
do the fragmentation so that's why
attract accounting code out of there so
I I have to interrupt you this is only a
five minute slot you need to be fair to
the next two presenters please go ahead
can very quick person my only question
is is this the right working group for
the work and is there another work group
like diameter radius working group that
that could take a set instead only
because I mean I guess from a counting a
meaning a triple-a perspective since we
were dealing with maqam so let me ask
them the question quick because we need
to move on so we got the sense of the
in other meetings but I have to ask
again who thinks this work should be
done in that convert of show hands
please I did not did you show him I did
not see any hand so we need to note this
and that come co-chairs need to decide
can there be an option to say we might
need some more discussion to figure that
out first
yeah I mean the mailing list is open for
discussion I was trying to ask people
several times to raise discussion on the
mazes so this is also the measure for
the interests of the working group okay
so let's go ahead with the next one
Netcom proxy so you've got five minutes
I working group this is Michael from
hallway and today I want to introduce
update for an account proxy and that is
document already present in a staff
meeting and I have received similar
comments most important thing is we need
to address is to show zapped and set
this machine ISM need to be done in the
application layer are not in the
transport layer so it prepares another
version to address as a comments either
on section to introduce use case and
it's narrows and you can read the
document section 1.2 and I also will
introduce this scenarios and use
guillotine next to side okay this right
aisle please remember on time management
you've got now for me yes yeah okay so
first scenario says using a comma or say
too many means and every instance ended
we can see a picture that shows that
after use it Yama's can actually I met
through the published network and within
them halfway network the private
protocol
such as at LCP Iranian through that may
have instance and this recipe we will
provide the data choose to the knock off
too many mental have way instance so yam
as we all connect to that operates
through sir
knock on proxy and the proxy locally and
we FM reasons we have management we have
within the only half man network the
country that we are transported from the
proxy to that we are instanced through
now come over to ICP and we have for
instance will report their ID to the
proxies the proxies can report us
support can restore amines touch
released and then the EMS can using the
statically statue management it says
there are free in every instance this is
the second scenarios if this introduced
using the knockin proxy to management is
non key element and showing this figure
so Yama's connect who's a gateway admin
destroy public public network and within
the updates which network some private
protocol such a queue s protocol Iranian
services network element and reasons and
SH network
queue as protocol provides a teacher
choose an alcove and notice that this
object switch Network natural element
may be not some IP devices that so
innately cannot be used to report their
IP to the an account crunch and to
management is none Kidwai element the
EMS can connect to the in on k2m and
through the nikon proxy and the proxy
locating the gateway element within SH
network within the owners network and
back home now comes later will be
transported from the proxy choose an
anchor element and non kiev element will
repose ID to proxies
can restore the means at least then the
Yama's campus on the attach agrees to
management is 9kv element okay I need to
ask necessary questions just you you can
say one or two sentence and we need to
go on okay last okay so let this trolley
please show hands who thinks net count
working group should work on this topic
okay so as we I assume much things the
same this is not in the current focus I
mean in the focus of the current charter
we need to come back to this later
please update as you already wrote get
more commands and update it and
especially raise a discussion on the
made list to get support okay thank you
so this is important before coming back
to the next left comm session thank you
very much thank you thank you okay the
last one is the UDP this might be in the
focus of the current charter because it
is related to the net Kampf
I mean notification set up drafts so
please go ahead okay I need to go work
faster the udp-based publication channel
for human telemetry and there are
several young casuality working IETF and
our work is based on them the problem
we're going to solve is to collect a
large amount of data from devices with
maple and line cars there the existing
solution consider only one push so er
in the main board as you can see from
the figure the data cracked here from
Lanka's and aggregated to the main board
so the Mabel can easily become the
bottleneck
especially when management of data so
what we are proposing here is the
distributed data collection mechanism
that can push data directory from nine
cars to the tractor and then why UDP mmm
the yum push mechanism supports the
separation of subscription control and
the transport for data stream that means
we can use different channel for
subscription and publication to existing
transports are not confer and the rest
come for both of them are tcp-based if
we use the TCP based transport for the
distributed data correction then the
collector will suffer a lot of
connections and UDP is lightweight so
high frequency and the better transit
performance can be achieved which is
important for you mental metric and the
scenes no connections they need to be
maintained the UDP in capsule
encapsulation can be easily implemented
by hardware that can further improve the
performance here's the brief overview of
our solution thus the subscriber send
requested to the via the subscription
channel and the subscription server
welcome host request and distribute the
damage to the agent and then the line
cards can push data to update to a
cracker
there are several technical points need
to work out firstly we need to define
the subscription model and then in
interaction between
subscreen server and the agent and also
the udp-based the message header and
also the retransmission procedure if we
want to apply or consider the reliable
subscription and also congestion control
here's our preliminary design on the UDP
telemetry header and you can see the
flag indicates the supportive features
on reliability or sanitation encryption
so and there are also many other fuels
defining in the draft and that's all and
the music feedback and cooperation okay
as I said this can be seen in the
current focus of the Charter Phil no no
I'm sure coming first I need to ask some
questions but go ahead we don't have for
time for more comments but we should get
your so so I support this work this is a
stuff that we do in generous as well I
think it's very common you know a lot of
work needs to be done on the particulars
but something in the space is we're
standardizing in the space is certainly
very important thank you okay so who
read this draft more than 10 or
something nine to ten
who thinks udp-based publication channel
for streaming telemetry is important for
net conversion and we should work on it
same amount or even more 10 to 12 okay I
am NOT going to count everything it's
more than 10 in any case so people are
in so I was not in favor of starting and
immediate adoption but I'm Kino asking
Netcom co-chairs now I include Ken
because you guys need to decide when to
go for adoption yeah I think we'll be
taking it to the so you want to start
the call for adoption on the list
yeah okay so it'll be done soon
somewhere so that's it actually fill the
other option is
designed him and getting the folks
together on that so you mean this should
be done in the so called design team
together with other yank push drafts I
don't know
so this will be then discussed with the
co-chairs and write one last thing all
the problem you're mentioning that's the
one we've been going from net flow to IP
fix Nick bottom right car so there's a
lot to learn over there okay okay so
that's it for today thank you very much
hope to see you in Singapore then I will
sit together with you in the room yeah a
party in honor of you tonight there are
some information available you can get
location info from Mahesh we don't have
a slide for this you can add to it so
these are together yeah you can send it
to me if you want to look at it or just
for the summary on on greatest yeah