okay okay we're gonna get started you
don't mind shutting the back door it so
it sounds a little loud still out there
from the break thank you
welcome to net mod in Prague I'm Lou
burger this is Kent Watson we're chairs
obviously and we have Michael Wang who's
helping us out as have been helping us
out a secretary as usual this will be
shown again as usual we on our slide we
show where you can find the different
information on the tools page and that's
the easy way to get to it you'll find
that there's a jabber I'm sorry there's
a etherpad link and if you could join
the etherpad and help us with collective
note-taking we'd like to take you that
before we get into the session we have
the usual note well but it's actually
changed slightly the this was just
updated based on RFC 81-79
being published some folks may have
noticed the blog entry talking about the
changes it's a new updated IPR policy
for the IETF it clarifies some things
the from my reading of it the most
significant thing it does is clarifies
what a contribution is and isn't
basically if you say anything in a
meeting or in a forum or even give any
indication of your opinion that's a
contribution the other thing it does is
it points to an RFC the number of which
I'm forgetting which talks about if you
don't follow the IPR process what are
the steps a working group can do based
on that
that really goes to late disclosures
this is a pretty fresh change it was
just published in may may not have
noticed that before you might want to
take a look as usual we have neat echo
we have audio and we do have some
participants who are remote this time
blue sheets are going around please sign
sign them and again here is another way
to get to the ether pad this is the
longer form if you get to the tools page
and click under minutes that's the sort
of the easiest way to get there our
agenda is posted we don't have any
changes right now we did have some
requested changes but we're going to
just stick with it we have a couple of
sessions so um at a high level the
agenda is meant to be rather than going
through all the working group documents
first on in the first session and then
on chartered working group documents in
the second session we're breaking it up
so the first this session is primarily
nmda focus with some other documents
sprinkled in they may or may not be
working group documents and then
likewise the next session will be
primarily focused on schema mount with
some other documents sprinkled into it
and this particular agenda has been
ordered with the ACL draft being
presented first so that the QA for the
nmda would get at the end gives us
flexible timing so if we're running at
it short on time you know less than 20
minutes but if we have more time we'll
be more
okay from what's changed what's changed
since the last meeting so we have one
document that is sitting with the iesg
although our ad looks confused by that
maybe not so we have one document
sitting with the iesg that's working
through the process we have sixty eighty
seven bits which is the guidelines
document that's been returned from the
IAS G primarily because of the update to
NMDA guidelines that document that's
come out the intent is is and we're
going to hear more about this the intent
is to take the guidelines and produce a
distilled recommendation that ends up
replacing the current section in sixty
eighty seven bits and once that
replacement is agreed to by the working
group will submit resubmit sixty eighty
seven for this we have a couple of
documents that are in last call be good
to take a look at those the last call
was extended because it's overlapping
with this week one of them the one in
green is on the agenda the second one is
not but please do take a look and send
comments we have a bunch of other
updated working group documents that
we're going to be talking about over the
next couple of sessions I already talked
about sixty 87 this I think we talked
about all of these except for entity so
this document has been sitting out there
for a while the authors thought the
technical content the the hard part was
complete but that it might be impacted
by NMDA and and in fact it has them and
the authors in github have a partial
update already completed but it sounds
like there's some work still left is
there any of the co-authors in the room
Martin who I think currently has the pen
is not Andy is is a co-author but I
think he's ducking Andy if you want to
say
about this all right you would co-author
an entity it's alright you don't if you
don't want to say anything that's okay
no I think the current status is that it
it was checked by a couple people that
it had the new objects that they wanted
and I think now we have to look at what
needs to be done to meet the new nm
guidelines yeah and - Laura Martin we
started editing and already push submit
it so it's probably close to being ready
okay that it'd be great if we could see
an update in short order so we can go to
last call because I think I think all
the issues had pretty much been resolved
at this point other than you know and as
you know City sitting business we talked
about that already we do guidelines
about
so Tim karaoke can I just get a
clarification sure please net so it
looks like then entity will probably be
the first draft that will see the data
store guidelines if you will include it
in are you talking about firsts a
publication requests their first
published I guess it will probably be
the first publish then right or is it
gonna be a small so there's been a whole
bunch of internet drafts that have
already been refactor to the format that
MDA and so we're getting other working
groups so that that work is like running
ahead okay uh so I think we have good
examples if you're looking just for an
example and ones that are far more
complex than this one this is actually a
pretty simple model in terms of what we
submit into the to the is G for
publication I certainly hope that this
is out very soon so yeah it would be the
first one submitted by this working work
okay thank you sure don't want less so
actually it might be a good to some
liaison statement to a different as do
is doing like young models to explain
our nmda right that's actually an
excellent idea
the one question I have a little bit
maybe for you is is do we wait till we
have agreement on the recommendation
text from the working group which we
don't have yet or do we go just based on
the ad recommendation that's been
distributed and maybe some other folks
who work and other SDOs might have a
view on this I know we have some folks
from PDFs and folks who work in I Triple
E where I can give us kid can't make a I
Triple E statement but they still work
there so I think we could do both right
for example get an I Triple E iesg
meeting this week and I forgot to
mention that we could have an informal
email because we have the contact then
one of our good text ready then we
mentioned that so basically it's like
okay warning it's coming that's a good
idea
so one thing I failed to do is to go on
to etherpad and make sure we actually
have people taking notes and etherpad we
have just people raised hands if you're
in on etherpad taking notes alright we
need some people to jump in on etherpad
please and take notes I am watching
jabber though so I think Jim wants me to
say something really I'm lettin you
start by saying your name ya William
Lupton representing the broadband forum
um so yeah absolutely we unwelcoming
liaison telling us about an MTA but
equally of course we're aware of it
already and we and it's interesting that
the maybe that it'll be applied to
entity very soon because actually you
know that is one of the the drafts that
words are actually referencing okay
great thank you I see we're up to eight
in etherpad thank you for joining please
feel free to join in
and if you could put your sign and sign
your name an ether pad in the upper
right hand corner just so we know which
name is which color so with the last
comment I think that was a set up for
the first bullet on this slide thank you
we've had one in Kim coming on the A's
on it came in just recently and
basically it's letting us know that this
other organization the broadband forum
is interested in reusing the work we're
producing in the IETF and it called out
entity as we just heard it also called
out the alarm module the alarm module as
it's been discussed a couple of times at
the IETF privately it's unlist
that one has gone over to see camp and
we expect that work to be done there if
you have any this this one is not asking
for a specific response but if you have
something you'd like to discuss based on
the noise on please just send it to the
list
with that we're gonna wrap up with
milestones the I'd like to highlight
that one we have a few things are done
we have a few things that are a little
late but we're close and the entity we
really need to figure out how to wrap up
and so I'm happy to hear that the
authors are working that we might see
soon see an update and with that we're
gonna move to the next slot which is
first presentation ACL okay so Mahesh
and I have worked on the enhancements
from draft end to draft 11
so these Oh
so so these includes basically support
of combinations of ACLs of different
address families and types and will also
allow to state the reason why this was
done there's also been inclusion of more
match and action parameters and this was
taken from after we got input from
Netflix and there were also a lot of
open issues that we found based on the
review of a various Native models in so
so these were opened up as as issues
then with it and we documented it and
we've taken a eyes to implement this
okay
so why did we include support for if
you'll address families so in the
current model in graph number 10 if you
see ACL type is not strictly checked so
in an in an ACL you can have aces of v4v
say
and l/2 so this doesn't work for vendors
who want to who can only support ecl's
of a single address family type now this
leaves if we haven't have a model like
this this means that a vendor has to do
strict has to do strict type checking
and for most vendors this is not
acceptable so what we did was to create
so basically the model becomes very
error-prone and we needed a way to fix
that so what we did is that we took we
focused on l2 l3 and l4 and we made
different combinations of these types
like different ACL types so when you
have the exchange message you can
specify which type the ACL conforms to
and you'll only see part of the yang
model that conform to that ACL type so
there's no room for error anymore so
[Music]
okay so so what we did here was that we
created so what I have on the right hand
side are the identity feature and
container statements for a particular
ACL type and this is extended to all
different ACL types that we support now
the benefits of this enhancement are
that you have very strict type checking
so for example if you support only be
for ACL you will only see the header
fields and ipv4 header fields that
pertain to v4 ACL there is no way you
can now configure a v6 ace within a way
for ACL or an l2 ace so this also makes
the model easy to extend because in case
you want to extend it to have ACLs I
don't know like an l7 ACL all you need
to do
is write the identity feature and
container statement and that extends
your model right away and you don't have
to make changes to the main body of the
model like you wouldn't have to do
earlier so these are the identity and of
these we have eight new types so since
we focused on l2 and l3 you have a v4
HDL v6 the Ethernet ACL then you have a
mixed v4 ACL I'm sorry you have the
mixed l2 and v4 ACL you have mixed l2
and v6 and then you have mixed l2 v4 and
v6 and then you have something so we've
added something new for the any ACL so
the ending ACL is basically a presence
container that allows you to override
your default routing policy so for
example if you have a policy that says
reject all packets coming in from I
don't know some source you can have an
any ACL that can say accept or accept
only a certain subset of packets that
come in so it's basically a presence
container that lets you override any
default policies you have on the Box ok
the inclusion of match and action
statements so this was nothing new so
this is this was added after we got
feedback from Netflix on because they
apparently used these matches and
actions so one was adding TCP UDP icmp
and they also needed logging so this was
just a small subset of matches and
actions that we've added there are there
are a lot
that are actually not present in the
current native model that we have taken
as an open issue some of the important
items that we have as open issues are
currently the model allows only a single
address and a single port to be
specified in the address and port fields
for source and destination addresses and
ports and this is actually not scalable
and it's not a good design because
you'll have for one if you have only a
single ace you have to have multiple
aces representing a particular network
that you want to accept packets from so
most of the bigger vendors when I looked
at their native models they support
lists you know so so they will support a
list of addresses or a list of ports and
they'll support like a not equal to
equal to or a range so this is something
we are we are thinking of adding another
bigger enhancement that we have in the
open issues is stats collection how do
we want to collect stats in on an ACL
model so for example you have ingre
stats and egress stats so currently the
track number 11 it doesn't address this
issue very well because you can even
have stats that come in that are
aggregated over interfaces stats that
are per ace or ACL per interface
depending on how much resource you have
in teakamp
vendors have different stats that are
allocated so stats collection is one big
issue containers for addresses and ports
is another big issue the remaining
issues are basically leaves that we
don't have for like ICMP off or
precedence things like that that we see
in various native models so if we want
to get a model
that's you know that looks good and
that's similar to a lot of the native
models then we need to we need to add
this in into the IDF model and make it
competitive with other major models out
there so so regarding the open issues
there's going to be technical changes
yes
and actually adding the Santino's that
needs some thoughts on how we want to do
that yeah but I've already gotten some
ideas I've spoken to various people okay
so this one be the final version okay
still how many people have read this
version of the draft it is in last call
so how many people have read this
version a few okay and for those who
haven't you know again please try to
read it and provide comments and there
will be another version well yeah we
might at this point sent a message to
the list saying that well we'll probably
send a message to the list saying that
there is gonna be another version
because it doesn't make sense to force
folks to read it who would otherwise on
not read it and then do another last
call and try to get them to do it again
so well let people know that doesn't
mean don't comment don't read it's just
that we're not gonna have a successful
last call on this at this time and we'll
do another one I'm sorry Ben was asking
when will the next version be available
November November draft it 12 my history
and Ani I think we should be able to do
a little better than number I want to
say within the next month or so we
should be at least able to come out with
an updated version and you're speaking
as co-author yes this guide make sure
everyone knows that's great yeah I mean
if it really was November I know I
be inclined to say okay is this one good
enough but so that's good to hear that
will have something you know a month
thank you
so I'm not with them and I'm going to be
various talks it's worth cursed ones and
updates on what changes we've made to
thee just let's go make it is that
better yeah okay so so I want to give an
update on on the datastore architecture
draft what we've changed there we think
it's very close to completion actually
so we would request people review it I
know there's been some comments on the
ATIS today I'm not a chance to read
through all those in detail but thank
you for those and so weird lights are
trying it finished fairly soon if
possible
so the quick reminder what we're talking
about the whole purpose of the nmda
architecture and the problem we're
trying to solve is this separation
between what an operator is asking your
device to do I their intent the intended
configuration and what is actually doing
so the desire here is to very accurately
reflect the operational state of device
and to align the namespace of those as
close as possible so that you can easily
correlate between both the intent and
the actual operational value as you've
probably all aware we spent a lot of
sessions discussing and time different
solutions this problem I've been
invaluable ITF and we've converged on
this is the solution and the solution
defines a new operational state
datastore this has implications on the
structure the yang models and they're
not being simplifies simplified for nmda
and I've got a separate talk on on what
that looks like and how it affects you
and will also effectively be updating
Netcom from restaurant as well that's
what the pressure state datastore and
there will be talks in the networking
group covering those extensions
effectively for those so we've updated
our canonical they doors picture and the
the lines in rail effectively show you
what we've changed and there's nothing
really this that's very significant here
that's changed we try to align where
information is feeding in with the
origin metadata so
the origin metadata is a way of
annotating where data has come from so
whether a values come from your intended
configuration or whether it's coming
from the system or is coming from a
dynamic datastore or you come from a
protocol so and we've tied this up a bit
and we've tidied up the fact that
dynamic data stores can feed in here as
well and it could be one of those or
multiple of those and they'd be defined
separately so this is summary of what's
changed and this is since the - oh one
version was presented in Chicago we also
published an O - in the interim I feel
that what we've done is we've improve
the definitions of configuration of
State and we spent a long time on this
we've pulled in clarified some the
existing definitions of the existing
data stores that defined in the net conf
RFC so the intent here is this is a
canonical definition of them we've
clarified the semantics of the
operational state datastore in
particular and got some refinements
origin metadata and clarifications and
XPath usage that wasn't in there before
so I'll cover each of these four areas
in more detail so as we've said a long
time trying to come up with good
definitions and good terms but what can
what configuration is what state is
or the different types of configuration
are and we spent many hours discussing
this to try to come up with terms that
are both accurate and fairly concise and
it's very hard tasks to define what some
of these things are so as part of that
we defined the term conventional
conventional configuration data store
which is like the start up and running
and kinda that we have today and
intended is also thrown into that
category as well because it's sort of
logical exists today even you don't see
it we've added a definition for learned
configuration now that one is probably
worth again I come a bit more detail and
is worth thinking about bit more a bit
more because some people have some
concerns about definition so we could
discuss that today and we got rid of the
term static configuration which is good
because none of us none of the authors
liked it it was a bit misnomer because
it could change yes as I said before
we've pulled in the definitions of
startup candidate and running and I am
here
just to have them all in one place
rather than to change the meanings of
what these dates are so we've tried to
clarify them provide extra text more
accurate describe them but we're not
trying to change the meaning of those
existing data stores I ask you please
you can to review these definitions
carefully because once this has been
published then hopefully there's be
reference for quite a while going
forward so getting getting good reviews
that we appreciated so it's been first
things discussed on the list one was the
term of what configuration is and there
was a concern about that the definition
we were using differs from the one
provided in net conf I think so we've
now tried to align that to be more to be
more closely based on that and as you
can see the text here the first sentence
is based on the same as the net conf
definition and what we've actually
really clarified here is that for in
yang a configuration node is modeled by
something that's conflict true and that
configuration came from different
sources the way I sort of like to think
of this is the conflict true on a node
means it can be configured rather than
it it is going to be configured so
something that could be configured
through conventional mechanisms is how
we are defining it the other one that's
been more contentious is definition of
learned configuration and this has been
defined as configuration has been
learned by a protocol interactions with
other systems that is not conventional
dynamic configuration so we're trying to
find the label for the configuration
data you might get from BGP or from one
of your other peers systems in the case
where they're overriding a leaf or a
node that's in your configuration tree
so an example of this might be a timer
value you could statically configure or
it might also be acquired through a
protocol negotiation and so we're trying
to identify your name to that sort of
configuration comes into the system and
also to make it explicit that it's not
dynamic so the dynamic configuration is
defined as what comes through any
dynamic data store this configuration
isn't coming through a dynamic datastore
it's just coming elsewhere through the
system
and then a an open issue that we haven't
quite resolved here is whether the
learned origin can also apply to state
note as well as so needs to be discussed
my hunch is the art will be yes it can
be that that the origin data is only
about where data comes from and so it
should apply there but that's the open
question ma'am it also what is your
proposal for the handling of the term
configuration in that compared at C are
you proposing to replace it revise it
delete it I don't know I guess we're
going to supersede it effectively that
this would so we have here a new term
definition we should be interested to
decide how we want to handle the old
term definition it can be deleted I mean
in Netcom this RFC or
the same can be used there too but copy
and paste is not good
which RC are you thinking about the
Netcom protocol RFC so I think then it's
a good question for the Netcom working
group yeah but I assume you would have a
proposal how to handle it so one option
is that this document lists is updating
that RFC and we can identify that the
soul update is in the name the other
option is that the documents that are
headed the supporting documents that are
going on in Netcom could do that so I
would sort of defer to the negev chairs
on how they would like to do that so
there needs to be a discussion in Oetken
for sure exactly it would be probably
consistent to remove this term from
Netcom this RFC and refer to NDMA RFC
that's a fine solution but BK and then
when you do the since that Biss will
replace the other one that fixes the
document sure that's perfect I
you I don't think the semantics here is
changing though so that's great yeah it
sounds like a part of the plan proposed
presumably as the net conf co-chair is a
good one thank you and also add to that
many times in drafts when they're
importing terms from other drafts they
specify which draft that are importing
the term from so you know for the term
configuration they could indicate
specifically it's the old or the current
Netcom RFC or the new revised Davis or
I've seen so it wouldn't be actually
ambiguous in the terms of the draft
ourselves so the second second set of
changes is a refinement to the
definition of the operational data store
and in particular we wanted to clarify
how defaults work in that data store
because our intention is that we don't
carry on using with defaults operational
our aim here is to try and simplify
devices and clients so the rather having
this mix of different defaults you might
support to try and converge and just
have one one definition that everyone
uses because it's a new datastore we're
hoping everyone for work on the same
thing so the idea here is that the
defaults in a way don't apply to the
pressure of state they'd store the
operational data store always gives you
the values that are in use by the device
so if the device is using a value
whether it's a default always come
through configuration or some other
mechanism then it logically exists and
is a part of that operational state data
store and hence normally if you query it
you would get that data yeah David Lamm
Patrick so I've thoroughly hit my head
on default values in schemas because
it's not only the device that needs to
be aware that the absence of the value
is something different from the default
value but it's also the client libraries
and every single thing it passes through
in the middle so I think there's a
requirement here to kind of maybe not
even have the default of the schema in
the best case because otherwise you're
still trading on thin ice yes
so to answer in the particular case
you've got configure
then a configuration node often has a
default value associated with it and
that configuration knows exists in the
operational State they store as well so
you have it often in the schema but
Inlet what I'm saying is in this case
you would return that value if it's in
use yes well I've shown you Ericsson
that's why we have the home with before
sir draw RC because we couldn't agree
how to handle defaults may be an
operational we can well hope so because
it's new it's a new date store nobody's
got implementations of this thing most
discreet Andy Biermann yet the reason
for suppressing defaults was to improve
the transfer efficiency yeah so if you
have a whole bunch of stuff that's in
the default value and you're wasting 60%
of your packet with stuff that's
redundant yes you don't get that
efficiency so so now you're saying we
don't care about efficiency we're gonna
send all the values all the time no not
quite so in terms of I've said here we
want to clarify what in use means I
think we want to get a definition of in
use that doesn't mean that we throw back
a lot of irrelevant data but we try and
find that so scope sensibly that the
default values you get back ones you
might be interested in
so not a load of so if OSPF is turned
off you don't return all the default
values for OSPF that aren't of interest
but it means that your nose gets turned
on then you do return those values so
that's I think we're trying to do is get
up come up with definition use that
allows well it seems that explicit mode
is clearly not useful because you're
talking about read-only data so it can't
be explicitly set to the default value
so only trim really matters which is if
the nodes not there then it must be
using the yang default and I think that
definition is rather clear and yang 1.1
I don't understand why it needs to
change now
so the the other concern that I have is
this ambiguity that if you don't return
of
you does that mean that the device
doesn't know about it
what does that mean the device is using
the default value now in the 19 yang
says that if it's not there yeah you're
claiming conformance to it yeah then it
is using the default value no exceptions
so if you're if you're well I want to
get to this later but I think you part
of the architecture that's that's
completely lacking is a concept of
conformance for data stores so I'm
reading a gang module I want to know
what is a server that is conforming to
this model supposed to do and you
completely failed on on providing that
information for data stores before we
used to know this is candidate running
and startup there were only three data
stores there's no way to add new ones
like the Acme operational data store
which is now allowed so so really think
it there has to be something in the yang
module that that tells developers what
the conformance expectations are and and
the defaults as is it could be
considered part of that but the problems
that I've been hearing about from
customers with operational data is is
how to make it more efficient
you actually have not been a fixed yet
because the problem with get is is if I
get an entire list my NMS freezes while
I'm getting 10,000 entries
okay so we've had to add operations that
make it much more responsive to iterate
through a list and of course you need to
iterate through a list without knowing
the keys because operational data the
keys change all the time so so I think
you really should focus more on on
efficiency because it especially with
you know large routers which you have a
lot of the getting lots of operational
data is it needs to be efficient ok
David Nutter again so unfortunately this
being a completely new data store
doesn't help with the defaults either
because it's gonna be accessed using the
same existing libraries and that's where
the problem really is so
if that library doesn't allow me to act
even figure out whether the value was
specified or it's coming from a default
which does exist our library is where I
can't tell if I had a default had it had
a value or whether I've got the default
value then I can't actually access this
bit of information so so I think your
suggestion is better to return a value
even it's the same as the default I'm
saying that if if you want to signal
this bit of information whether the
value is actually in use then you need
to put that bit of information somewhere
that isn't the existence of the value
because the existence of the value is
not something that you can reliably test
for I'll chat with you after it's gonna
show you a question yeah well angle
Erikson and I don't think even the
absence of the value doesn't really mean
that the default is enforced maybe some
other protocol remove the default value
and that's why it's not there can't we
have that situation I mean the case our
thinking of is if one of your demons has
crashed and it's not returning any data
then then effectively that doesn't mean
that those values are now and turn into
the default values that just there's no
data to be returned there and either you
hang the whole response or you've got to
compromise so that's why I think it's
sort of nicer for a semantic point of
view to always return the value it's in
effect and I do take Andy's point and
that's what we try to find the balance
between is you don't want to then flood
the messages with a lot of a lot of
noise stuff that you don't care about so
it's trying to find that a reasonable
answer we can I think part of the
problem is that yang tries to cover
default values both in configuration and
operational state and in fact in these
two cases the semantics of the default
values is quite different so yeah that's
why it might be difficult we'd like to
come up with some reasonable definition
and and handling of defaults I think in
terms operational we regard the default
value and yang models being guiding
to the reader rather than meaning
anything else so rather than affecting
the actual date is returned so just a
piece of information for you and for the
working group or now it's actually
taking some of the QA time but that's
okay cuz this is Q&A so it's okay with
us if it's okay with you and the work
group you have to what you've had 20
minutes what okay I think that's okay so
the third of the four sort of major
changes we've made on a major changes or
refinements is to origin metadata and
here we've refined with and to remind
you your enjoy metadata is about where
the values come from so the idea here is
that you can differentiate that the
operational values come from
configuration or it's come from a
protocol or the system is instantiated
that value like a system created
interface for example or maybe it's been
overridden by i2 s so that's the idea
here is you can identify where this data
is coming from and this applies to all
the a nodes in operational and currently
we're focusing our the thoughts Westing
operational state datastore but it's
possible it may apply to other data
stores as well so with intended there's
the thought that we may standardize some
templating mechanism and again this same
sort of idea of annotating where that
has come from might work quite well with
that to say whether a values directly
the configuration or its templated
expand it for example and finally our
intent is that this is optional to
implement because we appreciate that
this could be quite expensive so so the
new set of origin metadata identities
expanded so we've got intended dynamic
system learned default and unknown and
these match the definitions we've got in
the only part of the dock intended is
from the intended datastore dynamic
means it comes from any of the dynamic
data stores and these are identities
so there's multiply dynamic data stores
of IRS has different levels for example
then they can be using separate
identities underneath dynamic to
identify which one of those potentially
the system identity represents
effectively configuration or state
that's coming
from the system itself so you're
automatically configured protocol or a
loopback zero interface that always
exists for example would be system
learned is this one that we discussed
earlier that's slightly more contentious
about theta it's learn from a peer and
this is essentially stuff that isn't
dynamic so it's anything that has come
from another system it's not
configuration it's not dynamic default
value is a value that comes from the
schema so either an explicitly for value
in the schema or where you might have a
description stain that describes what
that value is
circe fault and we've got a catch-all
unknown so the systems that can't
identify where piece of data that comes
from they can at least actually indicate
that there is still some open questions
I think in terms of what the best way of
encoding this information is how to
optimize for that I think one of
suggestions at the moment is to mean
that when you report a given node it was
the same as the parent you can omit it
for example rather than having to report
every day for every tree and the last
one to cover is refinement to XPath
context and in essence I think what
we're suggesting here is the fairly
intuitive interpretation that if you the
XPath expressions for data this in
operational will resolve two nodes in
that data stock they won't resolve two
nodes in the configuration data sort of
example XPath expressions are run in a
configuration datastore will continue to
resolve to the same datastore that
they're in and the last interesting one
is that we're saying that input output
parameters for notifications are PCs and
action statements again they evaluated
in the context of operational so that
doesn't mean that those operations
necessarily have to just apply to
operation they don't and we're saying
that when parameter is evaluated that's
the scope that they'll be evaluated in
and the alternative to that is we don't
even you don't like that would be to
have datastore specific semantics for
those those operations to identify and
they apply to different particular data
stores
okay so open issues there's been as I
said there's been a few more nailless to
discuss about learned effectively origin
and meaning of learned data and this
conversation about defining in use these
two refinement in terms of what that
means and also how to optimize the data
return so we don't turn to too much
noise there's been a question about
guidelines should they be in the body
this is for the guidelines for writing
new datastore should that be normative
text or not I think there was in the
body before ban why we moved it to the
appendix so I think he's meant to be
text rather than a normative statements
see could you go back a couple slides
there's one thing I didn't like since I
certainly expel sexist me thank you very
much name is sue Harris I'm interested
in except for the drive identities I
didn't find that when I walked through
the text this morning dynamic data
stores except for derived identities can
you explain that maybe I just don't
understand what you meant when you were
running through that legs I'm not sure I
do understand either so I think is there
might be a typo effectively what its
meaning here is the dynamic identity
itself is probably more likely to be
abstract and that rather than returning
that at your dynamic data store you
derive from that you and your eternity
right value okay in your yang model
that's the generic I found thee they
never get anything good stuff it's it's
a generally defined identity it's it's
not specific to a dynamic data store
it's just specific to those identities
so so the so the dynamic density that's
in that file yes is generic yes you had
a dynamic data store you would augment
those identities well right from them
effect so derive from those identities
and with your base and you'd end up with
those being you know
different young module associated with
the only datastore I mean that's good I
just didn't find you asked me to read
the draft carefully I'm reading it
obviously with the IRS background with
dynamic in mind and I never found that
second sentence or the exception it is
in it is carefully laid out in the
appendix in the appendix for a femoral
data source was very helpful and very
useful and the XPath I think if I
understood it also is generic and can
work with dynamic data stores as well as
yes I think so yeah so I didn't find any
problems
nicely done thank you thank you David on
Twitter this is actually a good solution
for the earlier key fault problem to
make it similar to this I think because
if you move away from whether the value
is present and actually make it an
explicit metadata on the item then you
can just put have the bit there whether
the values in use and then the system's
actually using it and then you're done
so and then you're saying that if no
value is returned by definition means
it's not in use it doesn't matter
whether you're returning about you the
question whether it's in use is gonna be
answered by the metadata so obviously
you should return the value if you're
using it because that wouldn't make
sense otherwise but if you're not using
the value it doesn't matter if you
return one but you should put in the
metadata better it's not in use okay so
Tim Curry Nokia I think the problem with
that is I think one of the reasons for
the the default value as stated by Andy
was that you were trying to save space
yeah yeah so if I'm sending metadata
back must send the value back right I
just want to clarify that that wasn't
actually a purpose the purpose of the
way we allow flexibility how he'll
handle defaults was for configuration
because we had implementations that
handles handle it very very differently
under iOS if you set configure of a
configuration variable through the
default value it disappears from the
configuration
under that's sorry Phil Schaefer Gino's
900 you know it's my baby if you put it
there if you put a default value if you
can't configure default value you remain
because we think you knew what you were
doing so so there you have two very
different models of how to handle the
fall baggage and that was actually the
reason the space savings was less
mission well angel Erickson actually we
had three different methods of handling
before the the other method is that if
you have a default it gets there and you
don't care any longer how it got there
so 3-day different handling and I think
if we have with defaults on get data
that would solve the this capacity issue
so why not handle that way the socially
free and the the issue with that is that
the operational the operational data
store is to show you what the box is
actually using and so if it's if there's
a value in use you want to see that you
can decorate it with origin default to
know where it came from but you really
care that it's that it's there in the
same way if it's not in use you you
don't want to see it regardless of
whether it's the default value or not if
if there's a if I have an interface and
there's a default MTU and the interface
isn't there I don't care about the
default I'm to you if the if the
interface is down I don't care about the
default into you it's not in use so
that's that's really the the the value
of having the operational datastore give
actual in use values and I think that's
really key
vodka I have another question that I
already asked before but it doesn't seem
to have been resolved and it's about
templates the draft still mentions
templates several times very very
lightly but I understand that validation
is to be done on the intended datastore
but young also requires some constraints
to be satisfied on all data trees and I
don't know if if the idea is that uh
none expanded templates or the data
trivet on expanding templates which is
supposed to be in running probably
whether it is really necessary that all
these constraints are also satisfied and
if so I think it should be mentioned in
the drought that only this kind of
templates is under consideration or
something maybe well Shannon Erikson I
think this compacts what Andy says that
if you are not forced for example to
implement intended or some of these data
stores and if you choose a set the
specific combination of data stores that
you are actually implementing each of
the for each of these combinations what
is compliance needs well which parts are
validated how that the flow of
information goes true for example for us
the related question is that if we if
have a model coffee to and conflict
falls mixed up we don't show the called
operational versus running differences
so in that sense we don't implement the
operational as a separate but still we
will implement the config falls in
operational do we implement this model
or not so I think that to answer that
question whereas before you're comparing
like running with config faults you
actually can you can return that is in a
single get operation you returning the
intent the configuration the operator is
asking for the device is allowed to do
nothing with and the operational States
what is actually doing
point in time so if you had a large
company that had a system running a
large amount of configuration and a
large config change came in in your
running you'd see the new configuration
and all the operational leaves the
config for sleeves are actually related
to what it's currently doing and those
nodes that they need that need to exist
for it to be able to to be as returned
the data might not even be there in the
new configuration so you sort of stuck
with the existing model whereas with
this one the operation of state they so
it's obvious you the configuration is
the applied configurations what's there
and running in the system so the
structure always logically exists I like
your model so I like what you have done
but you have to describe what it means
if I'm implementing part of it only
because okay it will take time okay
so the other question was about intended
for example the intended datastore just
degenerates back to running if you don't
have templates support or you don't do
conked out conflict so whether you allow
people to a get operation on that or not
it should be relatively simple to code
to just point to the same data as in
running I take the question about in
terms of models but about validation of
templates I think that needs more
consideration as to exactly how you
address that Chris snaps those Telekom
so Phil you just said something it
confused me or maybe confuse me and
maybe I so if the interface state is
down do I lose a lot of my operational
like I'm thinking if I change it because
we change our come to you is that
something I'm gonna run into where I'm
only gonna see it and intended if the
interface is down no sorry that was a
comment on operational it's always an
intended intended is your intended
configuration in operational you'll see
what's in use yes if it's not being used
you shouldn't see it so so it's clarify
I think it depends on the implementation
so I mean one implementation may say yes
interest exists it has an empty program
it's down another implementation may say
well no it's not not part of the system
and so that returners or more
you know in a square box the problem is
we don't have a definition for in use
which was one of my previous slides so
that's what I think leaning to the right
please
oh is empty you you know a value that's
active even though the interface is how
I okay so that yeah that's and that's
and that's not a clear statement that's
not it's not it's not clear right now
because we don't have a fixed about a
fixed definition for use Rick Taylor
I'll try and keep this quick I've become
confused about the difference between
dynamic and learned I'm really sorry I
can't think of anything that has an
origin of learnt that isn't basically
just dynamic it may only get set once
right at the bigger you know your
protocol may negotiate some value
overriding your conflict intended value
gets overridden by the negotiation
shorty that's just dynamic but it only
gets updated once so this this identity
really means dynamic data store so maybe
the name of that identity should be
dynamic data store all one of those
dynamic data stores so so what's learnt
then learns is coming from a protocol
that's not not one of the configuration
protocols and not through a dynamic
datastore so something that like it's
your BGP peers or your therapy peers
things when they return values that
override your configuration that was
what when we be marked as learned
configure eight known values yeah I do
understand that but it just seems like
that's another not particularly often
changing dynamic data store you could
express your I perhaps I'm drifting into
I I to RS and Susan way off there
entropy so the idea is that is that a
dynamic data store something inside this
this ecosystem that we're building and
learned is somebody else it's that it's
that sort of division so learned is
actually external something outside of
your whole config model has set this
value outside the box outside the
outside the the
system we're defining so DHCP you know
DHCP you could conceivably make a DHCP
daemon that that takes data and puts it
into a dynamic data store and it comes
in that way but you probably won't
because you're gonna use the IC you know
so so if your dish if you're a DHCP data
comes in through a dynamic data store it
should be tagged as dynamic because it's
under this whole ecosystem init
understands the rule to me I think if it
comes in from from a traditional DHCP
implementation it'll come in as learn
because we want to say you know here's
data we got yeah ok by the way that was
Phil Shafer and Rick Taylor at the mic
going too fast to say their names
constantly this is Christian ops again
so I do have a suggestion on how I would
like to see that resolved the interstate
interface down State thing it came up
earlier in routing working group about
failures being failures that happen
later on after the system was said ok
I've taken that value right and I
replied back everything went ok with
that config value but later on I would
have to detect a failure by looking into
operational state to see if it changed
right and that would be one way of
detecting a failure another way might be
a notification which was the case I'm
not working so as a suggestion for how
to determine whether something is in use
like MTU if it's not available condition
I kind of expect it to be applied right
so in other words if I if I even if I
interfaces down if I change the MTU to
9,000 and and there's just no case where
that's never not gonna work when the
interface comes up then I want to see I
think change it apply right because
there's no reason for it not to yes yeah
I think that that's probably a
definition will end up so you know as
long as the system is saying ok it has
taken the 9,000 value and as soon as the
interface comes up it's going to have an
empty of 9,000 then I want to see it
apply yeah yeah
Jason Stern I just had a question back
for you how about then the case if that
line card is physically unplugged from
the router
it will expect to see any guy who's
Leatherface now then it be removed from
applied configuration Isis doesn't drop
so if you're up or down you'd still see
it but if the thing is unplugged and you
couldn't possibly apply it it's gone
from applied I mean you mean anything
that's creatively up or operationally up
Chris Hobbs well yeah I mean Mike
particularly cuz I'm thinking I was that
I'm gonna you know keep interface a lot
of different vendors and stuff you take
interface down and change some values
and bring it back okay but not if it if
the fiber is unplugged I think is still
down I still want them to you all right
before we leave this draft I know we are
cutting into other time wins
whoops one yeah now that we have open
issues and maybe heard a couple more
here what do you think is your timeline
for resolving all open issues I don't
know I mean the other office my lights
comment as well I I think the job is
quite close I think there are some
things of these discussions we need to
go through and revise those but I still
think it'd be good to get comments for
everyone so I thought was to aim for
last call in September yeah and we have
August with vacations and July to do you
think that's still an attainable goal I
think there's a baby that's grateful I'm
not sure what that means
[Laughter]
okay so hearing otherwise I'm gonna say
as chair we'd like you to continue to
aim for the goal of resolving all your
issues by September so that we can do a
last call in art not by September in
September so that we can do the last
call then and be ready to send over to
the is G in October Phil Schafer I think
it's important that we keep that
deadline because being lazy humans we
will make it if there's not a deadline
so I'm all for keeping a rigorous
deadline thank you
do you want to move on to the next one
yes target not deadly
so the second presentation is guidelines
effectively how do you migrate to the
nmda architecture this is the same
presentation I gave in your routine
working group earlier today so you've
seen that so you can tune up with that
problem definition or skip over that's
the same as I've just presented today in
terms what yang models look like in
various drafts and different bodies
there's really three fundamental
categories they fit into we've got the
ITF split config state top-level style
and that's like the interfaces classes
interfaces state RFC 7230 has that style
and the the interface is the the config
tree as all your configuration the state
tree has may have the configuration
replicated again it may be slightly
different it may also have the other
config fall sleeves as well so in this
particular case ideally they would marry
up but they don't necessarily do that
the second style of modeled structures
we come across is the open config style
that they've been pushing forward and
they're they have explicitly config and
state containers directly above wherever
the configurational leaves are so as
soon as you have some configuration
leaves in one of those models you create
a config container and the UK create PA
state container at the same parent and
you put both the config nodes there and
the state nodes there as well that uses
a single tree structure and then the
third one that's obviously I've talked
about here is the combined structure as
well as the nmda style is a single tree
but without any replication so as an
example to try and illustrate this I'm
using a subset of the BGP model I'm got
for global leaves I'm considering two in
blue our configuration the ace number
the reach ID and two estate leaves the
total partook of prefixes I've got for
labor labor leaves as well and trying to
put those that in to illustrate what a
list might look like in these two trees
two of those these config
two of those are in a container and
state notes so what does that look like
so I start with the ietf split
confidence state tree that's what this
subset of bgp would look like on the
left-hand side you've got in blue you've
got the configuration tree named bgp
with all the configuration on the
right-hand side you've got the state
renamed bgp - state and in this case
I've copied all the configuration leaves
across to that configuration nodes and
then in the shaded orange boxes you've
got the config false notes from the
schema so although the whole of the BGP
state trees config faults the ones that
are liked are the ones that copy for
configuration and the ones that are
shaded and those real sort of derived
data operation state and in terms of how
you produce this model generally you
either have to replicate that structure
by hand or you have to use groupings so
you get the same structure between the
beach piece are the the configuration
side on the state side and in my
experience the models I've looked at you
find that sometimes these state trees
start to deviate from the configuration
trees they're not an exact one-to-one
representation so you can't always know
exactly where a state Leafs going to
exist and what we want you to move to is
this so effectively you taken those
config four state leaves ie the ones
that aren't a duplication of the
configuration and you've merged them in
into the appropriate place in the
configuration tree so you can see like
total paths and take the prefixes have
just moved into the same place and
configuration tree under the same parent
would be and likewise with the ones
limit out so this this has the advantage
that the structure is guaranteed to be
right because you've only got one
structure in the model you can't there's
no separation to go wrong and it's and
it has other advantages that the India
model that you produce is generally far
shorter than the other examples either
the split convict state tree or the OSI
model yes
vodka so here in this example one
interesting case is this router ID
because if I remember correctly in the
routing data model base
feature that makes this router ID
available at the global level or
something like that but some of course
if this feature is off it doesn't mean
that the router that doesn't have any ID
it only mean that there is some
algorithm that the idea becomes assigned
automatically somehow so it means that
basically in in this case so or some
routers will have both outer ID in
configuration and in Stata but some of
those will have it all in stay later but
if we keep this a feature for example on
this router ID we need to distinguish
somehow that this if you want to have
just one they tunneled for both
configurations data it means we have to
somehow distinguish that this feature
does is not does not hold for the state
data version so things like this will
will come up very often so I really I'm
not really big friend of this join join
tree but yeah so say feature yes that's
something you had a difference between
the config and States then clearly you
would that's other things it's the
default value for example right but
we're saying so effectively in this case
we're saying that honey in blue saying
it's confiture doesn't mean it has to be
configured
only that it's configurable and a and
we're saying that if you configure a
value and you end up using a different
value then in your in the operational
tree you'll see that different value and
your seed origin that says it's a
different value camera system whereas
who's comfortable configuration will be
see see this marked with the same values
come from the intended configuration so
I think other than the feature comment
you've made I think you could still get
away with one node here and that's the
desire that you look at it on the same
path and you can then resolve with your
configuration taking effect or or if not
you can go and look as to why it's ten
minutes yeah clarification question on
that last answer
the reason the router idea is there is
because sometimes people configure on
the BGP peer another router ID
why they do that that
different subject so there is the
initial one that lotto is pointing to
very nicely and then there may be a
different one by understanding that's
those are two facts my question and
clarification because this can be set i
believe it operates in the way that is
expected in the BGP configuration
whether the that it's it's unique
variable how its populated can it be
populated from the base or what are you
are you saying
are you and a lot of saying something
that has to be there from the data
stories that just general logic you're
trying to provide I'm not sure I fully
answered your question so I melt down a
tree as well these things are bad for
your pair for the roots ready some
people want to play with the router ID
that they announced to the peer a fine
long story so they want to actually
configure it that's why sometimes it's
there so to answer your question then
this is one of the cases I think the
Phil described a sort of complex default
so in the description statement of the
data model under the router ID that's
for the peer you would say if there's no
value configured here you would pick up
the value that is assigned to the global
Brewster matter ID effectively okay and
I said that the texture is that the
default text that you were commits that
would be in the description text because
I think and I know the draft makes it
quite clear that I still a default so
that's still origin default would be
reported back it's just that it's too
complicated but in single statements
okay so if it came from the origin from
the base you would have an origin or and
the other one you'd have configured it
be it would be origin default if it came
from the base I was at the origin and
configured okay that's very precise
think of them three minutes okay so the
other example I'll show you very quickly
is what the open config model looks like
so that's this again it's the same
leaves here as I was mentioned before
under or above each configuration leaf
like the AAS and the route ID you end up
putting in a config
container and then as appear to that
conflict containing you create the state
container as well each level and then
you put the state leaves underneath that
state container as a copy both of
learning configuration leaves and also
the ones that are traditionally conflict
falls today or derived so your
additional state with this structure
there are some limitations because it's
sharing a conflict raise any one tree so
in elements that are created on the
system like I mean a system created
interface you have to sort of bend the
rules of yang to make that allowed
because you can't actually it's not
configured but it exists in a conflict
tree in terms of a get operation for
example so advantages of nmda I don't
know it's worth skipping through the
rest of this slide deck I'll bring this
yeah I think this group is convinced of
anyway so how to migrate obviously we're
saying everyone should migrate their
model is in Indian architecture and all
the ones that currently published will
be revised or one ones that need to be
revised to nmda and in essence what
you're doing as I said before is you're
copying the config false leaves in the
state tree into the conflict tree and
then you remove the food state tree it's
an unpublished draft you mark as
deprecated it exists and then you need
to check the descriptions for some of
these cases where a value the configured
value and the description refers to a
configured value and it needs to be
massaged a little bit to be applying
better consequence state and then the
other thing I just want to cover is well
can these modules be used on existing
Netcom Prescott servers and the answer
is yes but there's two conditions where
there's a problem one is where you have
there's no way of reporting the applied
configuration value so if you had some
protocol configuration like the MTU on
that Chris mentioned earlier there's no
way of reporting that IMG value is not
in effect but for many cases like the
MTU example it doesn't actually matter
what you put in is normally trivially
applied over some period of time so this
isn't necessarily a breaking thing for
people today and the other case which it
can't handle as the system crated
objects so this new combined tree of
interface and interfaces States for
example you
be able to rate represent an interface a
system created interface obviously when
you have the nmda that comes along
that's fine so we don't Lisa problem for
most modules but for the case that there
is a problem then you can easily
mitigate this by creating a separate
config false version through States
version of that module so you just take
the same module file the chef - state at
the end you mark it all conflict faults
and you reuse the type deaths to save
having new types and then that's a way
to something you can use until such
times nmda implementations available but
i like to stress that we only expect to
be used when necessary
put in the appendix avoid if you can and
it waited over time yes sorry England
with skin quality so I had this
situation when I say when we migrated
from basically I don't know how to
handle without nmda situation like make
before break say I configured something
and and it succeeded so I can see if
there's a applied configuration right
then I decided to modify it and this new
configuration failed okay so with the
nmda architecture I can see the intended
configuration my laid configuration and
applied configuration which is currently
in place right so if I'm not using MDA
right architecture so I don't know how
how can I see this Delta what is
actually configured versus what what was
intended to configure and has failed so
the answer is you can't that's point one
that's effectively mentioned there
unless you create this duplicate
separate tree but in many cases you said
there you can tell that when when you
got a response back neck home you know
the configurations applied you don't
actually know that all you know is the
system's accepted the configuration will
act on at some point in the future it's
not guaranteed so there's lots of
ambiguity as to what the actual
semantics of net conf operations say
today people interpret them as meaning
the configurations applied and some
operators are some devices act that way
others don't so
no consistency there where is what we're
proposing here will be consistent so the
problem is that when I try to do this
make before break I don't know
immediately that it will fail
I learn about this in in sometime okay
so they saw I actually accepted this
configuration but during signaling for
example their problem was detected
that's no different from today and this
device they could behave that same way
it's up to the implementation to decide
whether they delay replying until they
checked it can be applied or reply and
easily it doesn't it doesn't specify the
existing specifications this was the
same issue that came up earlier in the
routing working group so we should come
up with a good answer whether it's to
take the approach being taken there
which is to add specific notifications
or something more generic yes also we
have a question on Madoka so go ahead
and actually we're gonna need to cut the
line because after the meet echo sorry
because we're really over and we worried
we're gonna steal some time for the next
one so this question and then okay we've
seem to have lost Eric yeah so if he
shows back up we'll give him that in the
interim I actually want to ask the
question is share that the their key
from all this is not only us getting in
sync which is hugely important it's also
getting agreement on the language that
goes into sixty eighty seven bits what's
I have an understanding of what the plan
is should I relay it or should can you
tell us what what the plan is among the
authors how we get there
well I think we need to have some
definitive text just saying these
instructions are saying this is how you
mobile ads so my understanding is that
the authors are gonna propose some text
on the list that for what will go into
sixty eighty seven bits yeah yes do you
have a timeline for that what Ken
posters well I'm gonna my co-authors do
it I'll do it in two or three weeks yeah
okay that's great because we want to we
want to get to some agreement obviously
without text we don't know if we agree
so once we have the text we can discuss
it on the list and and hopefully in very
short order have an agreement on what
they recommend
patience are and then be able to
resubmit 60 87 vests yeah Andy Biermann
I wasn't going to go to the mic but you
started talking about this maybe I can
talk with camp this week about the text
but what are the guidelines for someone
who's going to say well I want the the
keys for this list to be different in
operational state than they are and
config I have one more key to add or
they say the operational state value
leaf is a different value set are we are
we discouraging people from that and
forcing them to to use the same keys
everywhere or and not expose a key that
they wanted to put in there or so what's
the guidelines for when the model is not
this simple okay I agree we'll put the
five guidance and that's it yeah so
there there was a slide deck with some
QA in it that's good to look at also
there was a couple of questions that
came in through jabber that didn't get
it to the mic because we were cut I will
copy in the jabber questions into the
ether pad so that become part of the
record and actually jabber is always
available as part of record either way
and sorry for not getting to the jabber
people okay so I'm William Lawton
representing broadband forum I'm the
broadband forum Software Architect I've
got ten minutes and so I just want to
give a quick update on broadband forum
and what we're doing with the yang and
sort of what principles were applying so
I want to cover all this very briefly
you know what do we regard as being in
an out of scope what are we currently
working on and what have we published
how do we publish what about draft yank
obviously where I remember organizations
so our work is not all publicly visible
and what about the yang catalog and then
finally a little bit on sort of best
practices and well dependencies on
external young and best practices so our
emphasis is on addressing our own
requirements rather than on general
solutions I mean we don't actively avoid
general solutions but that's what's
driving us which i think is you know a
contrast force with Korres do such as
ITF where I think the emphasis is more
on providing something generally useful
and our current emphasis is on
we will call broadband access nodes so
the equipment sort of between the home
and the and the internet for example
those of two of our main standards that
are providing the requirements that are
driving our current work and so will
define in BBF yang where it's for things
that we've defined or yang where it's
for things other people's have defined
but they have defined but the
organization is not interested in
defining it so for example some of the
first yang we did was four so ITU
unphysical our standards and we will
reuse yang from other organizations
whenever it's possible so these are our
current projects substrain the areas on
the Left and sort of internal project
names just quick description then you
can see that the top right to the ones
we've actually published which I've got
a little bit more information on in the
upcoming slides and then you can also
see in bold there's one project for
which we published draft yang and I'll
also talk a little bit more about some
draft Yin
so I wasn't too good has up the blue
sheets well okay this slide has actually
lost a picture of but I think that's the
next one give me an error message okay
well okay it's lost a picture um it was
a beautiful picture but I was never
going to go through the picture in
detail anyway so these were the first
ones we published back a year ago so
these were the ones I just mentioned
actually the itu-t ITT physical our
standards for video cell 2g that fast
and also some sort of associated sort of
like for example handshake handshake
protocol there that I've got more of on
dependencies on ITF but they're the main
dependencies was was on the interfaces
model and we're now working on some new
features and I'll giving you some
examples they're bonding in Reverse
power feed then there would have been a
picture that just showed the modules and
their dependencies lots and lots of sub
modules here actually these are quite
complex standards but only a small
number of module or I press the button
too far below this is the other one
which are what we call the common yang
modules for access networks these have
also been published so the idea is that
these are applicants
it's a little bit analogous with net mod
I think these are these are modules that
we expect to be widely applicable and so
similar arm dependencies but also ITF
system an RTO I tip Hardware there it's
a draft obviously we're aware that we're
going to have to think about how to
apply the the data stores here so thank
you for that we're also working on some
new features there and I've listed some
there and no alarm management that's
another dependency there I don't expect
you to be able to read what's on that
picture there but it's just showing you
those are all modules as opposed to sub
modules and it's showing import
dependencies and it's also showing areas
and it's also showing external
organizations there are the various and
containing boxes and colors so how do we
publish it we have a software release
registry which is a grand name for just
a wiki page that lists everything we've
published including both draft and
standard yang it all goes into this
broadband forum area yang repository in
github with separate areas for draft and
standard and then it's also all
available far the sort of de facto
standard young models yang a repository
via a sub module which just points to
the above BBF owned module there's some
examples in the background slides draft
yang for some projects in fact only
really one sorry we've made draft young
available for study purposes does have a
different license and that's in that
area of the of the github but we are
currently working on making sure that
such draft yang is available across the
board for all projects and will be
updated recently frequently I mean we
wouldn't expect every commit to be
visible we would still expect there to
be some sort of decision to make it
available but we want a very low bar on
making that decision and also just as a
plug really all the all the bots draft
and standard yang is available in the
young catalog so I'm going to flip
through these at the rate of about one
every two seconds so you could go into
the catalog and you could do a that's a
cunningly constructed regular expression
search that only matches one thing
and then you would get this and then you
could click on the impact analysis and
you would get there this from which you
can see that some there's a draft BBF
module which is is it green I'm not sure
I'm Cala blonde which is dependent both
on some published BBF yang Ananse and
published IETF yang and you can see
there are even links to the to the
corresponding documents which is which
is all quite nice and that's all enabled
by the metadata so ok just to put it all
into one place back to external Yang's
so we do have a policy that that our
modules must use external particularly
iron and IETF young yang modules
whenever possible I reduce or to said
that but we did this isn't just this is
intended to be letter adherence to the
letter and the spirit you know we really
would do want to be using these modules
as they were intended to be used
I'm just to pull it all together those
are the ones were currently dependent on
directly and then I also mentioned this
already but we the pub the the stuff
we're working on at the moment I'm also
very much
we intend to depend on the ITF alarms I
mean this is actually a very active area
at the moment that we're working on
internally and then just finally we also
have our own sort of version of our own
sort of young best practices which is
based on and adheres to sixty eighty
seven bits as much as possible I mean in
the future it could also equally refer
to other SB o--'s but right now it's
it's ITF so it's a mixture of
qualification two and extensions of
guidelines that are in 687 bits but also
there are some additional BBF specific
guidelines we do plan to share that with
you guys because haven't got around to
deciding how best to do that yet and
also there are some more detailed
examples of guidelines in both those two
categories in the background slides and
that's it
I'll going to fall snow a little bit
we're left with two extra minutes but
wait we have an ad coming to the mic so
speaking so thanks for this so you heard
about NMDA right so I guess at tomorrow
we got the NMDA question answer by a rod
where he's going to show the different
RFC you know actually we did that today
we used it rather than do it as a formal
Q&A session we took it just during
discussion time so we we used all our
Q&A session our Q&A time this session
right but there is a list of RFC that
will need to be updated right I'll bring
that up right now
okay maybe it's for tomorrow my point no
it's not for tomorrow okay now the
question is you know about an MDL right
so it's a difficult question but you
meet plans there well right now no there
is no this is not something we've have
raised in BBF yet right but we must and
I think I mean off the top of my head
our plans will go along the same lines
as I mean I think the guidance that Rob
presented I would think we would apply
that guidance to our modules just in the
same way that you're asking other eye
you TF working groups to do that the
particular implications for us will be
the two IETF modules that we're
dependent on that have this split which
would be the interfaces module and the
hardware module and we're just going to
have to deal with it and I presume we
will do it in the same way that we will
I mean I know there's some discussion of
exactly what deprecated means at the
moment but we will I presume I'm not
sure which should be the core one the
state one I think is the proposal so we
would I guess is that right we would
deprecated the config and and bring the
config into the core or the other way
around okay we're doing the way around
we're requested to do it and just to
take the hit on on how we managed how we
decide to publish that and and so on I
don't see that we have any option we
weren't we won't ignore it all right
perfect and one last thing I want to
mention in the catalog we're going to
have very soon I guess a week or two the
the metadata on what is the three type
that we have is this like an mga open
config so it will how to see
okay yeah so happily will support some
additional metadata to go into the
catalog yeah yeah back to the Q&A we
actually while we use most that time or
all that time this time we have a talk
that was supposed to be given that Alex
isn't gonna be able to give tomorrow no
no you said you are gonna give it never
mind I was gonna steal your time
oh well good thing you're sitting here
now protected it alright we have 10
seconds left so we're not going to
change conformance things like things
that stuff like net comp state that was
published as just monitoring now we're
going to be configuring things so why
would we move something that's purely
monitoring into like make that a
configuration module so so i guess this
this slide needs this was right this was
for discussion this is things that need
to be looked at so Rob had looked went
and identified some RFC's that bear some
investigation this isn't our list as
chair saying we are absolutely doing
this this was input for discussion it
the slides are there they were intended
to get discussion going let's get the
discussion going on the list all right
with that thank you very much and we
will see you at the next session which
is Wednesday at 1:30 right back here
[Music]
you