okay good morning and we are organizing
this workshop here on measurement based
for ready the six so we started
originally with looking only at NetFlow
wall or maybe six space and we sill for
two year four to the upper two years
we extended it to general measurement
base so this is a we call it a rug shop
so we have six speakers giving insight
in the current work on using networking
right few measurements for network
management and of course this is not a
conference yet so we hope that there
will be a lot of interaction we have
asks its because to give enough time for
some questions and for discussions first
of all I want to show you this knot
slide here which you probably already
know but
oh I got some one I got from the annuity
chairs from the energy okay for our
agenda is yeah come to be a black home
speak with our speech would be I mean
this two and half hours are not so but
we plan to have a me will have sweet
presentations before the break then we
make a break
raishin we choose ourselves and after
that three other presentations and
something I pop up tell you so this
workshop is organized by me today and
energy okay
you know all the quests I I want one
more thing there is lava energy meeting
on Thursday on different topic so if you
are interested of this joint
though so I would I would suggest that
we start this course people who is
deeply from penalty for sin so in that
long trip
so good morning everyone I'm Orchestra
Kelly from says neither Brunel
University of Technology and the PhD
student and I'm here to speak about our
attempt to accelerate IDs systems for
high-speed networks as I as I already
mentioned I'm from chestnut more
specifically
so as I already mention up from sasnett
Czech national religion Education
Network most Bisset more specifically I
work for my broader group and our main
goal is to monitor the perimeter of our
network and to guarded perimeter from
external or internal attacks that we can
detect from monitoring these these lines
so we have vast tool set to do so from
Network probes so the data acquisition
from metro grinds through collection
detection storage visualization and
remote configuration of the whole in
this presentation I want to speak about
network probes and how we collect date
on how we analyze the packets so the
standard approach to monitoring probes
is you have a network interface card
that provide packet capture and on those
capture packets you do some software
processing on a CPU of a host server
this is the standard approach we have an
accelerated approach when the probe
itself has a accelerator in FPGA and
each accelerator can somehow eight the
processing of the packet so the software
performs only very specific or very
advanced processing tasks and the card
can accelerate the total throughput of
the system we call this concepts of 35
monitoring the concept is here on the
right you have your processing
applications your flow exporter that
that exports NetFlow data in IP fix or
net four formats it receives data from
the card and in the card the card
received packets from the line and don't
send only whole packets to the software
applications but the software
applications can instruct the card to do
some processing it can either parse the
packets and send only headers instead of
whole packets or we have flow cash in
the hardware so some kind of net flow
records or aggregated records for flow
can be also sent to the software
instead of whole packets and as I said
this is all controlled by the
application so it's flexible depending
on application you can have different
requirements how this data should be
pre-processed so we measured the
achievable speed ups on various network
monitoring tasks and we proved to first
under a net flow we have like 5 times
beta for application layer processing
mainly HTTP processing we have speed up
to like 3 times compared to the standard
monitoring probe but when the software
need to process every packet we already
publish those results at infocomm
conference and in our three fully
transactions own computers journal so
now the question is can we use this
system this software-defined monitoring
system to accelerate also IDs so not
only network monitoring but IDs so our
assumptions are that a current IDs
systems are not fast enough for current
high speed networks also that before
discarding method that they use
basically blind discarding when you have
an input buffer and if the ideas is not
fast enough these buffers start to
blindly lose packets is not good for the
detections of IDs and informed
discarding can be better and perform
better so another assumption is that
usually the attacks or the threats are
present in the initial packets so
usually you don't find a threat insider
in the middle of a let's say long video
stream but somewhere in the beginning of
each network connection so in the last
assumption is the heavy tail character
of flow sizes of network connection
sizes when you have a very few heavy
flows that carry mate majority of all
the network traffic so by dropping only
the middle packets of these few heavy
flows you can get a pretty decent
reduction of total network traffic that
is processed by the CPU so these are the
assumptions using SDM basically to
accelerate IDs we use as
as a pre-filter so we don't need a flow
kitchen hardware our application is IDs
but the system stays the same basically
so it's only a different use case so we
don't need to modify the SDM concept we
just use it for new use case so our test
setup was we have two servers sorry we
have a traffic generator with a large
pickup files on an SSD drive which we
replayed but using TCP reply over a
standard network interface card these
were these are pickups collected from
our network so that it's a real traffic
it's not synthetic it's real traffic so
the reply traffic was then delivered to
our acceleration card in that card we
have an SDM firmware so the hardware
acceleration part that's for valid
packets - IDs software and the software
instructed the SDM to do the pre
filtering we tested to idea systems su
ricotta and snort the testing server
just the quick stats we've got to
physical Intel processor V with total of
16 16 cores at 2.6 gigahertz a lot of
RAM and of course our acceleration card
with Sdn firmware as I already mentioned
so with the acceleration with the
accelerator on the FPGA on the cart so
for some results first of all it's snort
over a standard bleep backup interface
now to describe the graphs on the x-axis
of both we have a speed of the input
link so here it's from few few hundred
megabyte bits per second to do gigabit
per second and on the higher graph we've
got buffer overflow percentage so
percentage of lost blindly lost packets
on the input of the ideas system due to
its lack of performance on even speed
and on the lower graph we have number of
detected events on that speed the recap
was the same
so the number of detective events should
be same if the detection is hundred
percent correct but due to we can see
from the graph that due to blind lost of
decades the detection the number of
detective events is decreasing also so
if we take a look the Green Line is the
ideas snort without our acceleration so
pretty quickly even at the two hundred
and fifty megabits per second the drop
rate starts to rise and therefore the
detection rate drops using our
accelerator the drop is around zero up
till three times larger speed so up till
750 megabits per second and then start
to slowly rising as well so the
detection rate is better then without
SDM so this is what we want to achieve
better detection rate so the ideas need
to process only packets that are
interesting and therefore can detect
more threads another similar graphs but
this time for suricate are already
picked up we can see the same trend
basically without SDM the drop rate
starts very quickly with SDM the drop
rate is not not so significant and also
the detected number of detected thread
is not declining so rapidly so we can we
can use this ideas on even higher speeds
with more precise detection rates now
the leap back up has a problem with
performance that is known so we try to
use our our own driver instead of lip
backup which bypass the kernel do zero
memory copy and so on so basically the
car delivers packets directly to the to
the application to the in this in this
case to the sericata ids and the results
are better the performance is now in a
in terms of gigabits per second and
again we can see without the
acceleration the drop rates start to
increase very quickly and the detection
rate starts to drop according
and with SDM sorry with SDM we've got
better results
we've got more detective threats more
detective events even at higher speeds
and the last graph is basically just a
surrogate are the same IDs but with
smaller rule rule set for the previous
test we use all the rules that are
available for the Sarika tights like
13,000 rules but for this test we reduce
it only to know their detection so the
number of rules was only 1,000 or
something like that and the performance
is even better even more than 10 gigabit
per second up to 20 and we can see
basically the same trend as the drop
rate is increasing the detection rate is
decreasing and again with SDM we've got
better better performance better
detection right
so to summarize ideas can be accelerated
using our SDM system with reduction of
packet loss we increase the accuracy of
detection so from the other side the SDM
is applicable not only to network
monitoring but also to network security
specifically IDs acceleration and we are
preparing in another infocomm paper
about this duration so this was just a
parallel preliminary results for this
paper so thank you for your attention so
any questions please go to the
microphone
and present yourself and your
association no this is from Ethernet and
I signed us look you drop the middle
packets yes so tell how many packets do
you need and is it very we have a
variable threshold on which packet which
we start to drop and it's usually around
like first 20 packets are analyzed and
then we start to drop or 30 or 10 but
usually it's between 20 and 30
okay the decobray around with this
parameter and that's it
if we play around basically after 20 or
30 the number of drop packets is
basically the declining but the number
of detective events is staying the same
okay okay so but it does download with a
bunch of files yes and the second file
is maybe with malware then yeah maybe
but but as I said we try to play with
the parameters and look at the graph or
look at the data okay the results and we
kind of wasn't able to see that kind of
behavior in our later okay so it's okay
no tell is it another detection is it
more like web traffic wave detective or
is it mostly large large downloads where
this effect is most of the traffic on
our network is HTTP or HTTPS so it's
usually read traffic websites and
good morning thanks for the presentation
our chunk of a check of speaking for
purity what you've just mentioned that a
lot of traffic network is HTTP what does
the resolution has to do with encrypted
patterns I don't actually know the
insides of the both tested IDs so I
don't know if they do some or what kind
of analysis they do we just you know
take take those ideas and as per snort
it doesn't support going to the TLS
session but I believe they're amateurs
and ciphers I think that some some
threats can be detected also under the
parameters of this traffic
mistaken okay okay see Thanks
I have a question from from remote he
was asking how easy it is to program
programs offering API or well I
mentioned the Snowden's ricotta snort
has a limited limited support of some
extensions that's why we only tested it
so far with withstand a really backup
interface but for sericata you can
implement your own plugins basically
input plugins or some different kind of
plugins that can take the data for you
and do some reprocessing with them so
using the plugins using the API that is
already in there we was able to extend
the system with SDM acceleration let's
say you are you are a few own ideas how
hard would it be to adapt it well our
SDM system has its own API so basically
you just have to call a function to
connect to SDM and then call a function
like I don't like this flow drop it for
me for each flow that you don't want and
that's all
any other question okay thank you again
[Applause]
then I would like to ask the next
speaker to come
it's abacavir Foreman here
you mean why'd I go to one of you take
care of the jabber rule and see whether
there are questions coming up from
remote participants everybody you left I
I find it with my Windows PC but it's
hopeless
[Music]
the work is about topological analysis
and visualization of networking data
where we use the when we have a case
study which was the dark netra
presentation first ever-present
motivation of the work second divide
reasons and background and related work
the methodology that we applied in this
work some experimental results regarding
the scanning activity and did those DVDs
darknet and the finally conclusion
future worked
so the the context of the work is where
we are focusing the network monitoring
data which is usually used for security
forensics and anomaly detection the goal
is to notify malicious activities
regarding traffic patterns behind that
and the alerts have triggered this
Masha's activity we focus on specific
but this modality which it ibf that work
background radiation basically data
could have this data is coming from
networking scopes like net usually it's
noisy traffic but important source of
forensics data we have many information
that we collect thorough list at work
disk up Santa and magnets the data is
will consider a volume and wide range of
services and sources the extraction of
structure and compose of this data is
difficult because it's noisy and then
complete information we have all the
packets we are with not closed because
it's passive so we just receive packets
from the internet so they usually the
GAO learn to study this kind of traffic
to predict and model internet malicious
activities basically large-scale scallop
order or the dose the I don't see the
night observe ourselves
so to show an example of like net so
usually it's a perfect sound and you IP
addresses we haven't serves behind it
just that idea that net so there is no
productive traffic knowledge made
traffic we are in our lab we will stink
like net so we select on and coming back
pockets without to play from there we
show this example use of that's so the
Otakon will control the bikinis we start
sending some packets and an IP address
connector to connect all the packets and
then we are able to visualize them and
so the our goal is to which is usually
nosy but contains some useful
information regarding large-scale
scanning or that's a unite of self
the problem that we addressed in this
work was - what are the compounds of the
patterns of the darknet traffic and how
to filter this traffic to extract types
formation with basically to attract did
those activities and to obstruct the
scanning get me some work was done
before many more that didn't under
guarding this issue mainly to
characterize internet background traffic
the first work was done by paying the
oil for where the character is a ideal
traffic become basically the composition
of the observed protocols and ports in
this traffic another work was done by
more efforts in 2006 where they studied
the probability to observe it was
attacks within military scope and
withdraw and co-authored in 2010 made
another world to characterize internet
background traffic over multiple
darknets extract environment features
and level of pollution of the station of
the addresses this is the first bug
report regarding military
characterizations idea more works where
they focus upon BACnet the data
basically the world to first first care
about identity and other work regarding
DNS queries in 2015 by absolute the same
authors regarding facilitation was that
basically the way we find some tools
regarding mainly in a twist which was
like net data from 3d scatter plots or
some 3d visualization tools to monitor
and visualize historic network is little
bit different because we applied new
technique this technique is based on
topological topological data analysis
its
TBA or today it's a branch of
mathematics where the goal is to study
high dimensional and complex data by
extracting
invariably emetics feature from this
data to discover relationships and
patterns so the goal is to study
large-scale data
multi-dimensional look stacked ovarian
agility and money the PDA has some
fundamental properties very interesting
which are coordinate which coordinate
invites some tennis that does not depend
on coordinate system analyze which our
case interesting because we can analyze
data connected from different platforms
it is the formation of ice so we so it
is less and insensitive to noisy even
the data is noisy there is no problem
with this beta we can apply to DA and it
is able to handle approximate data and
the third form that we obtained using
PDA the compressive version of the day
press the presentation
so basically will it take so here our
example is not related to that working
but we take CD shape which is Rabbitohs
first alpha and here we have as input
data a 3d point cloud which with many
many number of points in this case we
used the photonic function which is
example X and recipe so this function
will allow us to add another dimension
to the data and this dimension will
filter the data its filtering function
they will explain later switcher and the
output will be in at work paragraph 18
edges that represents drop so this is
the polished beautiful representation of
this 3d chain and the colors represents
the filtering parts we filter in here
and the colors of the filtering function
applied to the points
so this new part but the other part this
is the last part of the object but about
the top of the ears of the Yap so this
is the main idea so here we have 3d
shape and we want to apply the same
technique for the network packets that
we collected from exactly
so they to apply to be a our use case so
we extracted some noisy traffic
monitoring data from the darknet that
used our lap and we apply the one
technique from the DDA which is the
Moffatt algorithm the algorithm as
explained before will allow us to obtain
this particular graph this graph
represents the data instead of linear
many points so the the processing step
so we have the darknet where we extract
some features related to the packets
basically the issues the address
destination of the address the ports and
TV stuff compute the distance between
the packet filter function same as the
eccentricity for example but we can use
another one split this function so we
speed the values of friction using many
intervals car history technique like the
beasts can Lester each data which are
combined this graph which represents
representation
so this is the details of the mapper
algorithm so the input is the feature
vector it's contained the feature of the
packets from the back yet
basically in this case we used that the
timestamp the source destination IP
address and the parts of the protocol
TCP parameters of the algorithm are the
ones that we used to split the values
for the filter fraction percentage over
this afterwards because we can define
can you define a overlap between the
other ones which represent something
like azuma when we walk to zoom the the
graph they will obtain later using this
underneath in this case little function
which is the identity so from but the
technique is really flexible so can use
and other types of reflection the data
our data from the trench and the package
for future packets this OVA deployed
over the intervals that we define on the
filtering function and then last but
each using the bisque and clustering
technically we can use another one but
in this case we used the bisque and what
each vertex is a pastor of a be the
cluster the containers using to the
discard and LG
represents a non-empty intersection
between clusters so good bye when we
apply this technique we obtain the graph
where each vertex is a cluster obtained
from the discard and the link between
them means that there is no ambition no
update per section this technique using
the Nabisco so each each hunter viola a
function of its points projected on this
interval we applied the be scan which
requires two parameter
no but I need you to discover just any
technique
many lips alone in the same cluster
number of neighbors that the point you
have to be considered as Augusta and the
distance function that we use on this
world is the difference for time stamps
for the time stamp which we take the
difference and IP destination the
difference and for the parts and the
protocols use the quality which means
equal or not we apply that this
technique over 6 for example 1000 like
it's this is the parameter and we
extracted some patterns for example this
that we expected result scanning
activities but we check if this money
and we found that business can get and
the success active access some sparse
cuts and some randomized and those
discounts but
then we applied the Technic in some day
some scanning activities probably like
that and we applied also Sirica tap on
the same data and we observe that we are
able more than sericata only five so
first can I get DVD but for scanning
activities using this list the
parameters are estimated using an error
method so we have tried when we find
something interesting and but when we
find them
it remains them so we can apply them
more data sets and we find the another
example of activity that detective is
regarding Windows so we apply this some
would it be the UDP packets DNS you use
these parameters epsilon some others
because to extract them directly from
the dock game and what's the destination
and the approach so we for example for
one thanks yes than one second to
analyze depth using the map Berger
agrees to analyze three millions of
packets that we received for one day
requires eleven eleven minutes so which
is reasonable so we can analyze whole
day one specific attacker sent today
it's two minutes so we can know exactly
what the specific article sound
throughout the darknet and on that idea
is in short type but we need to increase
some this performance because here we
are using a single machine so we can use
more computing power and also paralyze
the tool enhance the performance of the
analysis
so as a conclusion and future work so in
this work we presented this new
technique that we are using to extract
potatoes from a darknet traffic
basically this technique used to
function the first one is this filter
function who represent one or more one
or more dimension dimensions to filter
this data and apply the number of
intervals and the never an overlap from
our recent advance and also a partial
clustering using the Biskind technique
the goal is to extract some activities
basically scanning activities or DDoS
activities and as a future role we want
to include more packet targets and
applied this to net flow for example not
only in the packets like that and
extract more activities and action and I
signed up to have him so why didn't you
use statistical feature extraction like
principal component analysis our
singular value decomposition instead of
the day usually question the first point
that we want to validate this thing this
is the this work and we know that TBI
was applied different data and 3d shapes
and the goal was to apply this technique
very day
how to apply decent qualitative is
technical different types of data
basically data from networking and we
want to know more on this variety how
basically it's cluster data but it is
more because we clustering in each
interval it's not the global clustering
so also this one for the reason that we
want to validate and obtain the good
results but I agree that we need to
compare this to other peoples my
accessibility techniques what as we have
even can use or just discard this is one
what one of the reason why we applied
the DBA to know the validity another
question is are the datasets available
datasets is most of them I collect from
our deck depth area to access the data
we have to sign but so it is a
possibility but thanks Jochen Sabini
technically universe between Justin oh
so dark in this case is used by dark
space is that is used in literature
correctly and if you search about dark
space and you will find that Qaeda is a
class a network is doing tasks talks
this research there's a lot a lot of
work
yes just one point yeah the direct net
is not the the GAO voice this is why we
have the term darks yes yes yes
so it's mainly pills
thank you
my uncle is on it so you look at the and
address space the top space what do you
think if you use other address space and
apply the technique to it like services
and lines I think we can this is one of
the future work that we want to do is to
apply the same technique for I mean
protective networks the packets or even
that flows of looks track some some
patterns that will be abstract some
services but we need to find the good
parameters for the ability or extract as
some scanning activities target replies
the network so the technique is opening
we can apply this I could just imagine
that you you find traffic patterns in
production traffic which are closed the
things you discover now which is
occupied or which is asked by many
clients then you have something that he
does scenario so it could be you may end
up in more false positives I guess yes
but then this in this case for this
specific world we haven't we haven't in
average about we check it manually that
this is for the doors scanning
activities but if you apply this to real
traffic liability item and then we I can
check if this force protection but here
we received this now
exactly what kind so yes this case the
validation photographer got space it's
quite simple the validation because
there will be no katachi
and isolated events and if you have
traffic it's maybe a small much more
complicated and complex to isolate but
the check yeah the comment is faster
this is this is an ongoing work we're
working on this yes goodbye
any other questions no okay thank you
very much for the break
Michelle Oh Santos right and if I wanna
security form stimulus provide
but one question is the blue shade is
still circulating everybody writes in
the name okay
okay morning my name is Michele Santos I
am a professor in Brazil and the
objective of this presentation is
talking about some as the end placement
challenges so probably everybody here
everybody heard about at the end the
objective is not it a class about a.cian
but he a briefing reveal about us and
it's important to have in mind that we
have a separation of the photo plane in
the data plane in stage we have any
cheat codes as in controller and it's a
centralized Inglot in a nutshell Sdn is
a paradigm that the cop of the photo
plane from the data plane so we have
this famous figure in a summary we have
three layers the network elements the
data plane the Kanto Plain Jane
controller means software's like parts
not good light of the life and so on and
some Sdn applications that will run over
the controller so we need to have a
different view about how to treat
scenarios of optimization when we take
when we think about Sdn we have now a
single point of failure ease and we
needed to think about dependability and
knowledge in a different way we will
have overhead mainly in the SDN
controller and we need to think in a
different way about planning and
provision and we have some problems like
the flows at a time flows at a time and
we need to think about well place the s
can control it in the best way because
probably probably most of the people
here know that but when you have a
switch and a new flow arrived in the
switch
if you don't have that specific girl to
this new flow we need to consult the
Assam control and it took some time some
additional time so we have a lot
research question related to this
scenario for example what is the best
placement position for each Sdn
controller
what is the curse of each controller
what should it be the capacity of each
controller what should it be the
capacity of its controller how to manage
the rules and the network policies in a
centralized way how to deploy virtual
light as in so how to categorize this
problem in each way we propose in this
presentation and probably draft three
men placement problems about Sdn as in
controller placement problem has been
ruled placement problem has been
hypervisor placement problem
I was trash-talk talking about Sen
controller placement problem it's a
famous problem problem and in summary a
steam controller and placement problem
all CPP deals if the allocation of a
theme in trollese in a network it seems
easy question but it's not when we think
about this problem we need to decide how
many controllers are required to support
a network where to place each Sdn
controller and what is the controller
demand in other words in this trigger in
the right side we can see the controller
1 and we have a lot of switches switches
assigning it to this controller and it's
Adam and so when we think about
optimization and the objective function
it's not polynomial problem it's an
np-hard problem and we have several
papers about this problem like
if we quick search for Ashley and
control placement problem in scholar
Google we can find hundreds of papers
about this problem one of them like in
the first result has more than four
hundred citations and it's not a new
problem like this paper is from 2012 so
the second problem is as the SDN roll
placement problem it seems similar to
the last problem but it's not when we
have applications running over the
controller and when I talk that it's not
one application but several occasions we
needed to run the conflicts we needed to
to the science the best path and it
seems ok old problem but you think about
that with a simple with same controller
with at the end paradigm we can think
about how to do the load balance at the
same time save image turn off some links
and aggregating some flows and a
specific link and everything in our we
have time it's not a user problem that
you're solving a real time when you have
a huge network and several nodes so we
have different types of rules like
access control world policies track
shaping thirteen-year load balancing and
we need to do everything in a real-time
and have the conflicts and policies so
what do you think about this problem
like optimization problem and use some
techniques like
integer linear program of some areas so
the last problem is Sdn hypervisor
placement problem in summary hypervisor
placement solutions deals is how men
hypervisor instance
are needed and deposition it's very
similar to the SDN controller placement
problem the first problem that I talked
to two minutes ago so here is an example
with a visor or I can talk about slow-mo
we have a hypervisor and the hypervisor
will create abstraction for each
controller in the infrastructure like
you we can have Knox and open the light
and like you walk in parallel oh and
it's similar to the controller placement
problem but the placement of the
hypervisor demands detailed
investigation because some question will
arise like wire to the fly the Sdn
hypervisor we need to think about
hypervisor reliability and fault
tolerance because we will have another
layer of software and the Skibo
hypervisor design and you okay
I talk to you about some problem in
there and I tried to define some
problems about
relatedly to at the end but the question
is how to solve these problems what is
the best technique to solve these
problems and the answer is its there is
not a best technique because it will be
its depend of the objective and the
complexity of the network how many nodes
do you have and what how many model so
in summary we have two categories two
categories exactly resolution methods
that give as optimal solutions and we
have a time consume well a high time
McCracken some examples technically is
Brenton about dynamic program and linear
and entry program we have here a
trade-off because we have exact methods
to solve these problems but
to retake time on the other hand we have
a rich fish with quads ultimate solution
reasonable competition times like some
techniques like Jeanette Jeanette
Jeanette algorithms simulated annealing
and ant colony optimization so one
normal question that arrives from this
presentation is okay
I have a iesson placement problem what
is the best techniques to solve this
problem that's not the best here is the
example we have a paper published in the
pupil I communication error and it's
paid this paper is from 2012 and to use
a linear program to solve this problem
we have a model and here we have another
paper and this paper dynamics controller
provision and software-defined networks
and they're all of autos proposed the
risk is Bayes it simulated annealing for
the same problem but in this case we
have dynamic placement so we need to
have quick solution we need generate a
quick solution most in real time because
it's a dynamic I analyzed the load in
the network and decides where to put my
to create Sdn controller dynamic so the
proposes creates an informational
information of their FG didn't find at
the emplacement problems challenge and
solution directions and that is thank
you
okay so this was a presentation quite
different from the Odyssey also
represented solutions while you are
presenting a problem
so maybe the really good idea to from
question offer more for what do you
think is anything missing we do the
efforts on some feedback to give some
hints where to how to start and so on
using anything how how the problem has
been looked at what what what you see is
is it a good idea to look to look at the
problem with the three placement
placement of the control of his from I
ask the audience this is a good idea is
there to handle the problem
often you know where it's from it's
really quite interesting because
actually yes this is a this is a Florida
Sdn lesson but this is the sole program
we find in in other topics related to
network management for instance in my
company we work in optimizing you know
that's a monitoring infrastructure based
on containers which is also you have to
do quite the same thing you have to
optimize the way you locate resources
and in place them and this is also
problem for I guess you know indebted
centers with VM so there is a lot of
problems with the same background
optimization issue so it's great
interesting to tackle such an issue in
in an emerging I think yes
so I'm just relaying a question from
Carter Schmidt um is asking how cannot
work measurements help in solving
problems you raised in this presentation
and where the measurements should come
from yep
so how can network measurements help on
solving the problems you raised in your
presentation and where shall do you
measure those it's depend help to treat
the problem we can treat the problem
just in an analytic way the measurement
of the network can be an input in the
problem and how to measure that after
the solution is generated it's the end
of the problem it's problem we need
different treatment thanks
okay more remarks or questions okay
thank you
we will have now a short break off
around 20 minutes so we will continue
5:00 to 11:00 so you see we have a very
precise time plan and then we will
continue with some screen X
presentations you will notice that the X
representations are from from industry
from from companies and institutions why
the first three were from universities
so let's see what will come up
interesting thank you see you in 30
minutes
yeah
[Music]
so I come back to second half of the
author workshop
thanks again to Giovanni who is taking
care of the Jaguar so let's start our
next speaker our necks because marco de
Witts from SI DN and he's gone everyone
everyone in the back to okay okay better
like this okay hi everyone everyone
seated hey my name is Martha Fitch and I
work for Italian labs and we are the R&D
team of the Dutch registry the country
code top-level domain and I may be
representing the industry as Roman said
so nicely but we are enough profit
organization yesterday make things clear
and today I would like to talk briefly
with you about our spin projects the
spin project stands for a security and
privacy in the Internet of Things
it's a project we started recently at
Pasadena labs and it's about the intent
of things now I could argue with you
about what the definition is of the
Internet of Things we have been
struggling with that internally quite a
while there is a great definition of the
I Triple E organization it is only 86
pages long so you can have a look at
that if you like but I like the approach
of rc7 452 but whatever the definition
is of the internal things we all agree
that there will be plenty of it there is
a lot of IOT coming towards us both in
our homes as well in the enterprises
there are many research activities
trying to estimate the growth here is
one made by garden the figures may
differ but everyone agrees is going to
be a lot of IOT and
and with that we will also see quite a
number of problems because all these
devices entering our networks all many
of them has their limitations like for
example they are cheap manufactured
cheap at for security they have standard
passwords hard-coded fess or it's telnet
ports being open sometimes you can
bypass security but just going to a
direct link so in general there is this
is this agreement that it's it's a bit
of a mess and also a security nightmare
and we have also seen evidence of this
this is the famous mirai botnet that you
may have heard of last year targeted
against time we were particularly
worried about this because Dyne is a DNS
provider and we also run a DNS
infrastructure for Cottonelle and this
attack brought many important services
down such as PayPal for the finest let
Romania and since we also run this DNS a
DNS infrastructure for Darnell this
particularly triggered us so we came
together we had this little brainstorm
session and we thought like what could
be the solution to this problem
shoot manufacturers deliver better
products or should we have legislation
or international policies or maybe even
certification programs for devices or
should we make the user more aware
through the security become a feature
that sells that people that there is a
market demand for for security or should
be empower the users give to give the
user tools to to be aware of the things
that are happening in this home network
and give him control of what he can do
within the home network so yeah we came
to the conclusion that there is no
silver bullets actually you have to do
all of these things to solve this
problem but for this spin project we
decided to focus on the empowerment of
home users
we particularly targeted home users
because we believe that in the
enterprise world there's already already
a lot of things happening with intrusion
detection systems and stuff like that
but if you look at the home using his
router all ACP device or a home browser
basically has is a simple manner of
finding some firewalls so that's how the
spin project was born spin is a research
project from our lab steam and it
attempts to research the user
empowerment part and that means that
with our spin box or spin system or spin
device we hope to detect anomalies and
however just to give you an example it's
not normal if you refrigerator starts
sending our millions of emails all over
the world that's not typical behavior
for a refrigerator and it's also not
normal if your IP camera starts scanning
for 22 or less that's unusual then what
we would also like it once these
anomalies are detected that they are
automatically blocked so suspicious of
the traffic from empty Intel things
devices we hope to automatically block
them and we also want to inform an
average user about them I mean not every
user is spec setting like you are many
users who have very limited knowledge
about how these things work is that we
want to conform them and also give them
the ability to define some sort of
security preferences for network so
these are the research goals for this
project
our main motivation for starting this
project because it's a little bit out of
our league perhaps is because we want to
protect the infrastructure of operators
or DNS operators and other operators in
particular of course our own
infrastructure United direct benefits if
if this problem gets tackled in one way
or another we also have this booth of
the Internet's mentality so we would
also like to give users more control
over their in-home Internet of Things
network and by doing these things we
hope to preserve the trust in the
Internet and that's more or less a
indirect goal and will benefit us all
and also know ourselves we decided to
choose for what we call a user centric
approach that means we would like to
allow users to easily deploy a solution
and I'll get back to that later we want
to protect the users privacy by keeping
things local as much as possible what I
mean by that is we do not want to
connect to any cloud servers for to
transfer all the behavior that's going
on within the network because we believe
that is a privacy in Figment so we want
to do as much as processing on the box
itself as possible and again as I said
earlier we would like to allow the users
and average enough affects everyone's to
configure a system at 40 to certain
security preferences and what we are
also thinking about is to initiate some
sort of collaborative initiative to work
together with a group of maybe security
related people to define perhaps certain
security profiles think of a security
profile that matches a smart TV for
example a smart TV has a certain
behavior and it would be art it was
smart in view to sending out these
emails so maybe we can define templates
that a music and load into the spinning
device for specific devices maybe I can
important in a way maybe in a manual way
but the collaborative event is also part
of this project here is a brief overview
of the spin concept it's hard to see I
suppose but what this figure represents
is partner defines that you install in
your home network it has in common
trafficking as outcome of traffic and it
has a number of modules the three main
components of this thing is are the
three modules on the Left a module to
visualize threatening to let the user to
make it user aware of what's happening
in network and also there is a control
panel that it allows the user to
configure certain settings there is a
module that is supposed to monitor
devices for our behavior and there is a
module to control traffic basically
viola
what this figure also shows is this
group of people on the left and the
right these are the communities feeding
the system with knowledge about certain
devices like for example your
refrigerator all your television what
happened and again as I said the
processing is done locally so the device
is not sending behavior of the user to a
cloud service of any kind it's processed
locally and hopefully we will manage to
make this largely automated first this
is I mean this is a provocative thing
I'm aware of that is tricky to have a
device have things blocking
automatically but maybe if the profiles
are mature enough you can achieve this
goal as well yeah
at the moment that the spirit project is
both it is both a concept and running
coat we decided to write start writing
running code from the start so we have
at the moment of prototype running it's
based on open wrt and it is also
currently bundled with our belly box
device that is an earlier project of a
setting and labs it is this piece of
hardware on the left
it's a GL I net small cheap kind of home
looser device and with the family box
project we implemented a validating
resolver on that thing with trust anchor
management etc and we took that project
to an able spin on it so we have
announced the value box after it's been
functionality and one of our
architectural principles is to focus on
IOT devices with a what we call a
predictable behavior so we clearly
distinguish between a home computer a PC
or a laptop for example tablet because
the behavior of such a device is pretty
unpredictable I mean my behavior at my
laptop is totally different from the one
of my wife for example I do weird stuff
she just visits a nice web sites but
there is also a privacy issue info there
because if I would be the manager of the
spin device in my home I wouldn't even
want to know what my life is due so we
left that out of the equation we are
focusing on IOT devices because IOT
devices a regular IOT device at least
the ones as we envision them they have a
predictable behavior like for example
the refrigerator again it's it may visit
the manufacturers site maybe for a
firmware update of something but it may
also visit the grocery store to order
something if you could notice that
you're out of milk I don't know but
that's about it it's not going to scan
the entire internet and for 22 or do all
kinds of other stuff so we envision that
we can define templates for these
particular devices that's why we focus
on on them so as you can see the
computer traffic is directly forwarded
to the Internet
and you can have your internet things
network or internet things devices let
their traffic pass through the spinning
box here is a picture of an early
prototype of the visualizer it's a bit
simple but what it does is in the center
is the IOT device in this case it's a
Samsung Smart TV of one of my colleagues
and as you can see it already makes a
lot of connections if you turn it on to
the Internet and in the very first
prototype these where IP addresses so it
showed the IP addresses it was
connecting to of course that's not very
useful for the efforts user so we build
a kernel module in the spin box that
monitors DNS queries and when it can
correlate a DNS query to one of the IP
addresses it connects to and it shows
the name rather than the IP address and
we notice for example that this Smart TV
was connecting to Facebook now mycolic
has nothing against Facebook but he
didn't configure a Facebook account on
that smart even so he was surprised to
see but his smart miss Marchant he was
connecting to Facebook the next thing
you can do is you can click on the
balloon of showing Facebook and you can
tell the spin device to block traffic to
Facebook that's also currently working
in the current program now we have this
little IOT lap within SIEM we're testing
various devices smart speakers and most
Amazon echo for example and we have
noticed that a few starts walking to
empty and to adjust a key then of course
at some point in time the device will
stop working so it's that's why we are
thinking of building up this community
effort of you know templates that you
can load that belong to certain devices
you can load safely and let the device
do clever things without breaking things
but anyway this is the current situation
speaking of current status as I said we
have this running prototype on our money
box open wot platform we started with a
focus on privacy
we hope to extend that to security
related things likely we are hoping to
scan devices within the network for
example to see if they have open ports
or whatever our philosophy was to design
a vertical slice that's kind of narrow
kind of functionality that works top to
bottom and once you extend that
functionality it becomes broader so we
have more modulus as time progresses we
have this visualization module we'll
have this blocking module but again it's
still on many will and we are now
working on more automation being able to
detect malicious traffic within the
network anomalies etc the software is
free so you can have a look at how we
progress a target upside if you happen
to have the same hardware that we use
then also install firmware images
straight from the valley box websites so
feel free to have a look at that but
remember it's all been through research
so don't expect the vision for the
further future is it would be great if
we would get the spin concept and maybe
even spin software deployed into regular
home devices we are aware of some
similar initiatives apparently the
industry has picked this up as well but
this is all proprietary stuff and it is
cloud based mostly and we hope to come
up with some kind of an open standard
that vendors might ultimately implement
in their home Reuters for example we
have it running on the torus which is a
big thing that bill colleagues awfully
Suzette and our spin software is running
on that route we foresee also some
standardization work in regard to this
we foresee that for example there should
be interoperability amongst into the
things devices I can imagine that if you
plug in an Internet of Things device in
your network its identifies itself in a
secure manner to maybe do router
so that the roots are can download
certain templates belonging to that
device
so we foresee a standardization work in
that area
concerning protocols data formats and
for the near future we are working on
refinements and improvements of the
spinning software we also have one huge
research question and that is how to
protect the protector how to make the
spin device safe itself so challenging
again we have to initiate this elaborate
collaboration effort it best form for
sharing device information in a
standardized way that's interesting I
came across a draft that seems to touch
this matter it's the draft ITF pops
aw nut that more or less resembles the
things we're thinking of so that's
interesting that there is already some
ongoing work happening in that area as
well and hopefully ultimately I can tell
my TV to only go to Netflix and not
nowhere else to Facebook in my case if
you are interested in celebration please
feel free contact me I'm here all week
we have also written a tech paper about
this there's a lot more elaborate than
what I can share in 15 minutes you can
find it find it on this URL so I will
have a read if you want to know more if
you want to discuss this with me you
know and that's it questions just a
remark as the slides would be soon
online where he was the white person to
URL for example Dharam ashkani
unaffiliated you mentioned the
standardization and I just wanted to
point to me maybe you are familiar
already but there is a working group
called second mission and continuous
monitoring they truly does something
like that
eating in architecture and the data
model for profiling
security
pattern or normal behavior of your
network and kind of holding out as
exceptions so that could be something
that you would like to work at least it
was talking for me absolutely excellent
feedback thank you I will look into it
Tim carreño yeah I will say that you
know this is actually great stuff
because you know search organizations
like we brought in forum we actually
were developing a new protocol you
talked about you know there's in
translation going on it's a new protocol
called Universal Services Platform which
actually has a Patrol or an agent it's
focused in the home area network and so
you know your ear affect your your
device is actually would be a controller
there they've got the discovery of
vocational and stuff are taken care of
the other thing was is that an L map
right you know if you look at the
diagnostic piece within these devices
whether it's an IOT device rather the
router that that's also a possibility
because really looking at a diagnostic
test this is this is actually great work
because we're we are very interested
thickly I was brought to inform how we
how do we troubleshoot diagnose and
react towards the events that happen at
home so we're looking we're thinking
along those things up a line so you know
I'll be interested talk to me oh that's
for to maybe see what we did is this is
great great great confirmation that we
are on the right checking one way or
another
thank you
oh are you question my life away maybe I
would remember later okay thank you
again those were interesting oh by the
way it's there is there anybody here
working maybe for manufacture before
manufacture of some such devices nobody
here has a week great to hear a feedback
on on this idea okay
so our next speaker is young cougar from
is from Ethernet okay and the bottom
line sorry
so we have two tickets okay so this is
actually from in distillery industry we
are from SONET and this is about
indirect as it measurement of the three
sticks in the Ottoman project I will
give the introduction how this route is
linked and Sebastian talk about the
indirect measurement paths where we have
this passive sample measurement that's
which is currently broken progress send
it and maybe you get some and here or if
you can tell us some pointers or
feedback on it will present some first
results and any confusion and so briefly
Ottoman project the project goal is
automated performance monitoring so
bringing more automation in the whole
performance measurement and monitoring
things it's funded by the German
government and it's a program for small
and medium enterprises we are one of
those timeframe is 2016 until 2019 so we
are at the beginning and you can visit
the website if you like now to get a
better impression of the project it's
maybe makes sense to tell you or the
partners we have some application
partners which are directly interested
in the results we have and they provide
problem statements use cases scenarios
they have unless we can get the network
data these are legible in IBM and we
have research partners which university
and to enterprises so Japan
so it's a service provider for the
German railway and autoblog logistics so
everything which is connected to the
Japan and then there's IBM and it's IBM
Network one services they provide
connectivity and services to Airlines of
enterprises formerly belonged to the
transit systems now it's basically if
they use the platform and solid wire IBM
and they're not part of IBM then there's
a column then for small medium
enterprises it's acid ice on it we have
a network monitoring solution called ISO
flow many Lopez but we do all things
like loves kale and the rice network
measurement and monitoring and we also
have a second department which does the
very very knowledge based company in
Munich and we have our customers in
Germany there's not a small company it's
sensitive medium is from preschool and
they have something which is for data
exploration that just expire and get it
for Tyra in entire country go to the
news content management system so
they're really use of century and UI
based so it's 24 weeks in the consortium
to have either two companies here or for
research completes for application they
try to put together and I guess ok so
what is the idea of project why we think
we need more to make today's challenges
in a circulatory is that network
infrastructure is business critical part
it becomes more and more business
critical that we in enterprise networks
so if there's something program and
production stops yeah or whatever units
you can do with your bank transfers
whatever and at the same time you have
fewer and fewer people operating
increasingly large networks so men power
is declining but you still have to be
able operate large networks and
additionally you have high dynamics in
networks to to authorization
like Sdn and all of automation things so
the network becomes more and more moving
part so this makes the automation of
network monitoring mandatory because the
network rules and is automated and so as
the network monitoring 2ps well of
course there's always the discussion
thus is it only monitoring so that we've
stopped at monitoring always also the
configuration of the network that's also
discussion with our Asian partners and
with our customers in terms of liability
and what if the automation breaks the
network because your monitoring system
sets we want to have to change Network
who is liable for that trust something
which is in discussion um
the vision of Ottoman is basically well
you have some users in a data center in
between you have wide area network and
there might be interfering traffic and
you want to detect this happens quite
often in network operations and what you
do to name is you have basically the
monitoring system which collects the
data metering and export by our IP fix
or other mechanisms and then you have a
med monitoring system here and that you
have to configure initially you
configure the router then you have to
manually interactively to the problem
analysis you to the drill down to
through several charts and entire crimes
and in the end you have an analyst
report compilation compilation but this
is typically done manual by the
operations people then you link it with
other ticket from the ticket data and in
the end you have the management reposes
your management tells you well this
application broke down what's the reason
for it you have to to lots of these
things manually today in order to end up
with the solution and the report and the
autumn on in autumn on we want to
automate the whole process so we want to
start a configuration of the network
infrastructure and the network
monitoring system we do the problem
analysis mostly automatically and we can
then do adaptive adjustments in case we
need more fine-grained data from the
system or from from routers we are
aiming towards the traceability in
visualization
so that you already get the result
presented that you would otherwise to
manually by by drilldowns linking with
other data if you get some insights
there as basically expert in the loop
the user which can feedback to this one
and in the end we have the automatic
generation of the management report so
this is the vision of the complete broad
project and we have now one specific
case where we get a little bit more
down-to-earth and the problem of
unobserved parts so this problem just
came up in a meeting we discussed some
approach and this is for example the
used to the scenario deutsche bahn you
have a van which is monitored you have
active measurements there like see so at
core IP SLA to all locations you
continuously know what's going on there
but then you have the access network out
there and you don't know what's going on
there and if an application breaks or is
slow and the issue is somewhere over
there you may not know so you have an
observed path and you even don't know at
any time which client is over there and
this could be for example hi queuing
delays exist network issues hi
processing delay in the routers because
they are mostly software based here or
there can be any error that you cannot
imagine yeah so this is why we measure
we measure because we want to see the
performance of the network and that's
why we think it's important to look into
this and observed path and the idea we
got is we could sample packets in here
and we can do some times them analysis
from the traffic this goes into this
direction and this came up when we
discussed the paper on school based
sibling detection based on TCP time
stems from Technical University Munich
so this is basically the TCP and flow
time stamp analysis that we are
currently looking at of course and it's
not possible it's a coarse-grained
approach so it's not possible to get
really the cheeto take it by packet but
generally we are interested in bursty
Network conditions so if in general
a network conditions become worse and
then they impact the interactive
business applications for example these
are some charts from round trip times
where round trip time suddenly increases
from 300 to 400 or we have a piece of
even 700 millisecond round-trip time so
these are effects observed an enterprise
network and you want to know if there
are such effects that can take your
application so it's just we just want to
know is the network becoming worse
because then we can say well it's in the
better condition then we trigger further
automated investigation by our ottoman
mechanisms and if it's in a good
condition and application users
complained and you know nothing changed
and you're still safe and this network
is still the same as before due to
measurement and now the research
question is how well can we passively
message it off and delay increases in
those large scale delay variations and
that's our current work and I will hand
over to Sebastian to explain it thank
you
ok so in the following I'm going to
present our technical approach to a
little bit more in detail and in
particular how do we do this passages
passive monitoring in principle well as
you often indicated before we rely on
time stamp information now what time
stamps are typically available to us as
you can see here in this simplified area
we assume that we have hosts which
communicate with some servers and we
have some TCP communication including
the TCP segment with time stamp option
set which is usual for most current
Linux host implementations and also of
most current Windows operating systems
so this is the first timing information
we get the time of the host system or
the server the second time information
which we collect is the time at which we
do packet sampling on the router so what
we do is we take every hundred thousand
packets and we take a snapshot of its
payload including the time stand option
we also know what time was it from the
perspective of the router when we took
the sample and then we try to establish
a relation between these two times times
and based on this equation which I'm
going to show you on the next slide we
are attempting to detect delay
variations of course with this approach
there are some challenges in particular
how accurate are clocks in the router
and in hosts how much TCP traffic with
TCP timestamps option is actually
available in the network and how many
samples do we need in order to get some
valid measurements but our basic
assumption is like this the first step
will assume that clocks they don't jump
they don't drift so we live in a perfect
world and we can establish a linear
relation between the timestamps of the
host and the timestamp of the router so
we assume that we can take the TCP
timestamp of our measurement sample
related to the packet timestamp sample
in the router and do this for several
samples and we will end up with some
sort of a linear equation like times
them of TCP equals some slope M
multiplied with the packet sampling
times them plus some option now of
course there are two unknown variables
in here the slope and the offset and I'm
going to show you in the following how
we try to gain some insight into the
correct values of these for the slope we
get a very simple approach we did
appliance analysis so we collected
packet samples of our TCP flows and in a
after in second step we analyzed how
much is the Delta of the TCP x times
compared to the Delta of the packet
sampling timestamps and we did this for
each consecutive packet sample which we
got now of course we are aware that
there is probably a lot of noise on the
packet sampling times then because we
will measure the delay jitter processing
delay in that but still our results
showed there are distinct peaks for
different values of M and we got two
insights first of all well even with
this noise there is a way to the guessed
the most
slow at least if your sample size is
large enough and second of all there are
two typical Peaks for Windows host this
peak is at 0.25 and for Linux host is 1
but in the end this means that we have
to do this slope information estimation
I'm sorry for every flow which we
observe now with this knowledge we still
missed the second variable the offset
beam and we try to estimate the value
for it like this first of all we start
with our initial packet sample we now
know the slope M and we know the
observed packet sampling time stamp and
the tcp times them and we just calculate
an initial value for B or the offset and
for every constitutive sample we use
this B value and try to calculate what
time would we expect to at what time we
expect to observe a particular TCP time
step now if we should be wrong with our
estimation for instance we see that the
measured times them for particular TCP
is x then actually arrived much sooner
than predicted this means that the
sample which we currently process
probably expected less processing or
queuing delay or whatever and this means
that our current estimation for B was
wrong and we have to adjust it take the
new minimum maximum and by iterating
over all samples of a TCP flow we will
eventually get the offset which reflects
the minimum processing and packet delay
so now we have suitable values for the
slope and the offset and we can start to
actually calculate the delay variation
and I'm going to show you in the two
last slides some preliminary results as
I said before we did offline processing
but we did it with real traffic in our
intranet so we have local area network
as well as wide area network in this
however we don't have any well known as
traffic we don't have any one on delay
or jitter and but still we see some
interesting results even if we don't
have any one let's say
lab setup conditions in the first
picture you see a flow which has a
duration of about 2 or 3 minutes and as
we can see here the calculated delay
variation is typically around 1 to 5
milliseconds and the first glance there
are no outliers at all and so we assume
that this was local area network traffic
that our measurement accuracy is
probably around somewhere between 1 and
5 milliseconds so in the worst case 5
milliseconds so not too too bad the last
result slide this is a flow which was
measured for a IP address destination in
the internet so this is wide area
network traffic and it was quite a long
flow we see here that this is going on
for 12 hours and we see here an
interesting sawtooth pattern we don't
see this sawtooth pattern for every flow
which we observed in our measurements
but only for sound and hence we assume
that this is probably an issue with the
clock on the host which drifts and
eventually it's corrected again I don't
know maybe MTP or something like that
but which means in the end that for our
approach we will have to consider
clock drift and other clock effects in
the future now how does this fit into
the big picture
what does delay variation mean does this
boil down to a most valued no can you
make any statements about voice quality
with just as well you know again it's
useful for us as a first indicator for
anomalies in the network so if we see
that the delay variation is typically
around 5 milliseconds and then at some
point we see some weird Peaks which can
be done with this passive approach this
is an input for Ottoman control loop to
trigger additional and more fine-grained
monitoring as we intend to do in the
Ottoman project ok so it jumped to the
last slide so as we have seen the
positive
the passive monitoring of the day
variations using TCP timestamps seems
feasible at least for the scenarios
which we look at and we assume that the
assumption that the clock drift is like
little didn't old
however the timestamp accuracy of
routers has improved a lot
so actually now it's feasible to do
measurement in the order of magnitude of
small number of milliseconds our future
work includes that we set up a task lab
where we have delay jitter and
everything under control
so that we can have a further look at
how accurate we actually can measure and
second of all that we do more
measurements in the network of our
application partner in particular
document systems the stuff at least we
also want to redesign our approach so
that we can migrate from offline twats
online processing and also taking into
account the clock drift okay this
concludes our talk thank you for
attention and we are happy to take your
questions
you'll cancel bidding well at the moment
our router is capable of ipv4 and ipv6
for the measurements we did so far we
relied on the ipv4 okay just because for
conveying timestamps many people have
similar problems and there's now and the
draft in the idea editors queue it's
about IP version 6 performance and time
Gnostic metrics destination offices so
they have a destination destination of
extension header field in IP version 6
where they exactly put these times them
sequence numbers and so on nan the track
or for conveying this is quite
interesting because at the moment we are
limited to TCP traffic and only TCP
traffic with the times the option set
and this is some fraction of the the
overall traffic and with IP public all
this would be much more interesting
because the visibility would increase of
this for ipv6 search so you can go wait
thanks for your call
Westfair to Curry University of Southern
California um a fantastic work so things
for bringing is interesting to look at
the data
have you looked at if you considered the
effects of mobile devices as they change
between say different access points and
things like that which were distance
from the access language might cause the
saw tooth pattern or other stream gene
artifacts this little Bismarck work
though I don't necessarily mean cell
phone network even we should see some
mobile devices in original because well
of course everybody fastest in
smartphone but indeed I didn't have a
look at the mobile so far so the results
which we have a look at word just
business okay so these these effects
complete what interesting but we didn't
have yes and I think also I don't know
yeah well we have I think we're past
typically though though a wireless love
device in the price daily from separate
subnets I think yeah I'd love to see a
graph oh that's that's what drilled my
curiosity a second real quick question
is have you looked into turning any of
these data sets into sort of
notifications no issues with too many
false positives and things like that
with trying to actually detect real
problems using the data to come up with
on you you come up with a whole bunch of
interesting data sets they have talked
about how to turn them into something
useful right at the beginning so no we
keep going right relay in on the
question here so the car Schmidt moly
his ask any field plan via plan and
standard drafts are even on artsy on
this work and if so which working both
integers we have not thought about it
yet but if we maybe have your picture of
the provenance loser space
ability I don't know maybe it's people
publish measurement but let's see what
it will be about
thank you God Jesse okay well speak up
just over my dog to our remote
participants as you can see you can ask
questions you can even buy all you also
this new feature I don't know words
otherwise just write your question down
to Jabba
we are following you and on the chat
Giovanni is doing that
okay hi everybody my name is Thomas
green and I started my PhD a few months
ago with orange and telecom PI tech my
talk today is different from what you've
seen before but out you'll find it into
interesting so my thesis is on
entitlement routing and security so
let's dive into it so a bit of context
first so BGP has been there for a few
decades now so I guess most of you know
how it works to summarize it provides
kind of a back end complex environment
for example you can have limited
visibility of the topology you have
limited portion of information to you -
the best path selection and of course
you have questions of legitimacy and
integrity this means that you have a lot
of steal a lot of incidents and attacks
ongoing and that's why in 12 2015 7 10
years Theo PhD thesis including mine on
subject so the main idea behind this
work come from the fact that AAS
relationships I made by business
agreements which one negotiated few
times a year and this also inferred the
idea that the inter domain structure
must be stable at least on a large or
large part about the methodology so a
bit of overview of the definitions and
synoptic of the process of BGP dynamics
and Rises so first definition of primary
path we basically want to feel
referential of a stable structure of BGP
so the internet and so we build a
referential of what we call primary path
which is the most useful for each router
perfect spare and from this we want to
interpret the flow of
incoming updates messages into primary
vas and availability so to compare it to
the primary bus referential that
revealed since the Soto event is a
primary pass in availability period so
is quick overview on the synoptic of BGP
damning analyzes so this is where we
take place and at an extent we want to
after that be able allows these VP
dynamic analyzes to extract and detect
events and be able to mitigate them
eventually a bit sorry a bit more
precision on what is episode of event so
basically as I said we're transforming
the the stream of updates into a stream
of set of events which basically groups
updates together messages together
following a primary pass for so yeah you
can expect from that to see two types of
total events so so they weren't that are
the what we call transient which
translate into events that go back the
lose the primary pass and then after
some past expression phenomenon go back
on to the primary but again we expect to
see those kind of events fight often and
with with a lot of with short duration
sorry
also you expect to see from those kind
of events to see structural so that ends
with basically our survey events where
you switch from your primary paths that
you have in referential to a new primary
path which can be due to a change in
policy business policies for example
also yeah this is the two types of event
that we will see and we want to take a
look at the term Poland artistics
of those events to analyze BGP dynamics
so let's take a look look at the first
result
so for this work we took data from one
monitor from the right right price
project on the three months very good so
that is that is pretty really relevant
because you had several vantage points
but for free to work we intend to extend
those monitoring forms so first what
we're going to look at is the first
thing we look at is the turnover of
primary path so basically it's entering
the question of stable our primary path
over long period of times so to do that
we computed primary path calculated on
April 2 a 16 and compared them to the
primary path that we would find on
different months following this one so
you can see that primary paths are
pretty stable over time so after one
year you almost have still 50% of
primary path still the primary path that
you sign one year later but it does
definitely it is definitely a decreasing
over time so you need to identify the
structural changes and to incorporate
them into your referential and be able
to update this referential periodically
to have a meaningful view of the
stability second thing we look at is the
prevalence of primary path so do they
exist and how are they stable okay so we
have DCF figure on so the complementary
CDF of the primary path Sujit for all
pairs at the data set on the three-month
period so you can see that first ipv6 is
a bit more stable than ipv4 so basically
you have a large part of set of primary
paths that I used for long period of
time almost all the three-month period
but you have also some that are really
unstable and not used so far police
exists
even more up here yeah so second thing
we'll look at is take a closer look on
primary on pseudo evidence so this
confirms our first assumption so you can
see that you have almost observe the
events that we find our event that come
back to the primary pass that we
calculated from the referential and you
have a few of structure of today that we
wonder on the top x-axis you can find
more friendlier human friendly units
than seconds right you can see that for
transient to the events they basically
have short durations most of them so
under a minute for about 50 of ip4 only
12.9% are longer than one hour and for
ipv6 it's almost a new trend about the
structure of the events you can see that
they on the contrary have way longer
duration so only one 11.5% less than one
week for ipv4 so yeah this again
disconfirm was at our assumptions of
expected properties of the observer and
so so how do we benefit from those of
the events and how do they help us to
analyze bgp dynamics so you can see that
first you gain with those new two events
objects you gain a factor in term of
volume again about almost one order of
magnitude for ipv4 and ipv6 which mainly
comes from the fact that remember the
soul events include all upset during the
past expression following a from a past
fall you come from the fact that you
group up there together and you can see
that for a lot of transients 11 at least
you have only one path that you switch
on the past expression before you go
back again onto the
primary path and about most of them are
at maximum sight but from the bass
exploration in the trends of my p4 and
ipv6 the Subang benefit that we are from
this is that it is semantically rich so
to do that so the tables are beeping to
get it to understand it first so I'm
gonna explain them so we compared a BGP
mounted net which is a public service
that we do I Jack sand any kind of event
detection on BGP so we wanted to compare
our methodology and apply it on a use
case to detect outages in Ajax compared
to the BGP man so you can find the
reports on BGP stream but coming down
there public website so first on the
outages type of events so out of all
observable event that we could see no
data set meaning that we have at least a
one update related to the prefix and
that they say is impacted by the T
outage we can for most of them they take
them at the same time so basically what
we look at is do we have a super event
corresponding to a starting time
announced by BGP money that translates
into observe even domain so the answer
is yes for most of them and even for a
non-negligible part about fifty percent
we can detect in the eleven domain we
detect them before than they do so we
said there is observing that translated
primary person availability before them
and actually out of those 236 early
detected events there is a significant
detection phase about one hour before
what they announce or about 90 percent
have done nothing and only for about one
per nine percent of the events we didn't
find any event related to this outage
another type of events that the report
is our Ajax or just which most by Jack's
multiple origin si Jax
so you just want to look at the origin
yes I don't think yeah see I Jack so out
of the observable event we can say so
the table may be a bit confusing at
first because we appears to be missing a
large part but actually when we manually
inspected the results it seemed that
there was only due to one prefix which
was illegitimate
less specific graphics which was in
Egypt similarly announced which
triggered a lot of hijack events because
of all more specific announcements so
explicitly this might mean that we found
in the when we compared to the in the so
driven domain and the primary pass
referential when we compared that we saw
that there was a primary bus for this
specific event and that for us the I
Jack was not a hijack because the
original yes was the one we had in
calculated in the primary bus
referential and for those events
inclusive legitimate means that for is
perfect less legitimate the less
specific yes sorry good find events yeah
implicit illegitimate means that we
could find an event due to a less
specific prefix so for us we didn't find
any primary well CSV we didn't find any
primary pass for this those events which
means that we cannot say that you see
the I Jack because we don't have any
primary pass to this value right so to
conclude on this those first results we
can safely say or confirm that the
entitlement are is pretty stable for the
most part and that settlements are
useful and compact objects EPP dynamics
we have excellent work of course in
progress for now with more data as I
said before so more monitoring points
more meaningful view of the Internet and
we also going to include new results for
example to better analyze the structural
events are they what are their
properties really and also to be able to
remove all the bgp noise so the
recurrent there so the events that
receive for example the transient so the
events to be able to remove all that
noise so and if you have any suggestions
on new interesting result like any good
you know I guess that will conclude my
talk thank you for your attention and if
you have any questions or remarks you
know
yeah nice presentation I just have a
question uh Giovanni Italian by the way
there some people use IP anycast which
just allows you to announce the same
perfects from multiple equations across
the globe yes and some people use the
same eternal system some people use
different autonomous system so how that
would play out in your methodology he
was different on on system numbers this
is true
so actually we want to refine a bit of a
methodology to take into account such
specific cases because you can have a
lot of cases we're really looking at
primary path from a router and a Naas so
I wrote her below me Rheneas - a prefix
so indeed it those kind of network
practice and in fact and we gonna look
into that to make sure you know when you
see the primary tabs on the theory that
he had in the beginning and the kind of
a 50% remain stable over one year yeah
yeah it's very interesting but it could
you elaborate what a little bit cuz I'm
also curious about that little thing
were the reasons for that and why 50
percent change yeah yeah yeah so yeah so
basically for us mean that you have
other business equipments that change
providers for example so you can add a
different as pass you have also some
engineering practices that can impact as
well because we look really the primary
path is the entire path that we look at
not so you if you have one new AAS or
one less a yes so as fast you can add a
mismatch of course so we want to refine
this methodology to include such
specifications and our more precise and
defined definition of the yes if people
do prepending like adding the same
internal system number does it count as
a change in the primary yes for now yes
the
because we think it's legitimate us all
right thank you also questions okay well
thank you guys thank you again for
coming so we are planning to do this
workshop next year again provided we get
big enough time slot it's meeting I
please consider joining Selma humouring
list again remind us that s in northern
what you need you not polite to this one
on Thursday evening and a gentle will be
published soon by Alessandro okay and is
not a meeting of the energy yes yes yes
Friday Thursday at 6 o clock or
something okay thanks if you have not
yet with and and for the speakers who
have not yet sent me your slide set
please send it to me
Otto Lisandro or Ricardo
yeah it was