we start white with you right plug-in
you may have to hi hello can anyone hear
me except for the front row interesting
I don't know that um we're not sure we
need some help
does this microphone work no I think
this one doesn't
yeah none of these are like oh maybe
it's when maybe someone was meeting in
here and turned off the sound wow this
guy seems too
[Music]
I think I was trying to do about it but
I'll take a look screen on Pocket take
whatever I'll just speak live do we have
a volunteer jabber scribe it's the only
thing we can be great Thank You Ted and
thanks to the two minute taker
volunteers
Joe and you're on and before we start if
you're not here for SAG that's what
we'll start doing as soon as we have
audio
let's talk yeah Mike hello
okay hi welcome to sag I'm Arabella
Kathleen Moriarty so yes we're starting
with working group reports ah she's very
we know well I forgot you all to be
familiar with this if you're not
familiar this well I guess you can read
it or read it later right so we'll start
with some working Barry did you have a
yeah okay good enough if you bring them
in order always I know we already in the
order turns out ace we met Monday
morning and we have lots of different
proposals floating around and how
to carry these different tokens around
into the authentication authorization so
we had lots of researchers coming along
and providing input we unfortunately
didn't make that much progress on the
already charted items so we need to
improve on that but there's a lot of
ideas thank you so act me sent the
report hurdle thank you I also sent the
report dots thank you for sending the
report I to NSF so we met
Thursday we actually have two sessions
why is the procession and then the
formal session so this time we had lots
of contributions on the data models and
information models so this meeting
mainly is to make sure they are lying
with each other so we reached a really
good result on that thank you thank you
so I piece tucked me sent a report Thank
You kitten sensory port Thank You lamps
oh okay I missed that thank you
miles sensor reports yes so no I'm
saying you sense a report Thank You Olaf
I didn't see one Hannes it seems to be a
pattern yeah actually the final session
is tomorrow so in the first session we
talked about wrapping up some existing
working group documents and we also had
Mike Jones present a best current
practice on a JWT after we've some
researchers found attacks
so we documented those and we did a hum
and the group wanted to work on that
document so that's something we will
confirm on a mini list so if you use JW
T's that may be a good document to look
at or if you implement them
all right thank you and open PGP open
PGP has had quite remarkable success in
not getting anything done and that has
resisted all attempts from both chairs
to talk talk to people offline and try
to poke things and so we have asked Eric
to close the working group whenever he
is ready to do that and told the working
group that and hope that that might spur
some things and it it spurred a few
words but no actual action Eric any
comments I think I'm happy to do so I
suppose thank you for your service and I
would say happy to do it isn't quite the
right characters right but I know I
understand I'm just saying I'm sad that
we could not get it done but we in fact
we cannot so as the as the co-chair this
is dkg I'm also bummed that we didn't
manage to get that done
there is continuing work in that space
probably and if I can manage to get
people to document it I'll try to get
them to submit drafts and if they
actually start submitting drafts that
are actually functional then maybe I
will come back and ask for more but we
have we have not had any luck in getting
in to move we don't have enough
implementers in the group right I think
it's certainly open PGP is a protocol
people use so if it turns out to be a
case that you have activity it's worth
your standardizing we can figure out
some way to recreate a new working group
open PGP to I think three all right
second thank you for sending the report
second I didn't see one oh it is sent
okay thank you my mistake and TLS thank
you for the report and the nice
management of a tough working group
session talk lines
yeah and in send a report we met on
Monday core documents are in last
working a blast call we're playing area
bring playing around a little bit in
proxy hell with a draft that may involve
some help that we are stating some help
from the HDP working group will see
think we yes we did get one from trans
so thank you so now we're going to go
into related working groups we're going
to do a little interrupts in the middle
of that for one of the related working
groups lino thank you great he's going
to talk about a need that we've brought
up before and zag and we have a request
okay thank you so in the dime working
group so we have the base protocol and
initially in the previous version of the
protocol we have an end-to-end security
staff and when we we publish a new
version of this one this end-to-end
security mechanism was deprecated it was
based on CMS and and nothing was done so
we are still looking for a solution for
end-to-end security basically it could
be between edge edge agent between a to
two different two different networks
anyway you will go through what we call
a roaming networks or you have a bunch
of agent in the middle so or you may
have end-to-end real end-to-end
communication between edge two clients
client and server so the idea to have a
solution to be able to protect a VP's
next slide yeah so the status is that
the end-to-end security requirements is
now an RFC so we have existing
requirements coming from the mobile
community so for roaming especially but
also by operators that would like to
protect their diameter signaling so what
we have done is to reuse a previous
draft called end-to-end security but no
work was done on this one so there is a
lake lack of resources and also like of
expertise because we also died metal
part but we have also the security
aspects next slide please
so we have in the existing draft we have
a basic solution where it's possible to
have integrity and confidentiality
so what we're defining its specific AVP
where were you able to sign and another
one where you are able to group all the
sensitive EVPs and to encrypt them and
to put this in this in this what we call
a group AVP so it's it's how to be able
to convey to convey this information so
the solution was based on Jason so using
the Jason Webb signature for the
integrity protection and Webber Kishin
for the confidentiality we were thinking
about maybe there is something new to do
in this area maybe instead of Jason
using support cozy or if there is any
other alternative so next slide please
so I'm here because we are a crying help
yes sorry I added the note / other
feedback I think it just threw you off a
little and so I think that the proposal
is quite simple just to be able to have
a solution so I know that people in the
room are aware of this issue so we I'm
looking for some guys that could help on
this work so we could create a kind of a
design team and so on just to be able to
have a solution
done so any any volunteers would be
welcome so you can contact a katrien
myself and are there any volunteers in
the room that are interested in helping
on this okay please help yeah this is
Jim Mahoney have been in the time
working group and yes this is just
lingered it's been pushed off where
we're losing energy and we're realizing
we don't we can't do this by ourselves
so would like some volunteers thanks
Phil hon Baker I had to generate
something very similar for my meshwork I
it's written up but not separately from
the other stuff but I can pull it out I
did notice the problem with you with
applying Jose encryption and rolled my
own based on Jose but doing things in a
more sane fashion for doing end-to-end
encryption within a web service so so
you're willing to help okay hopefully
you have a few more people thank you and
we'll move on to the an eye chart from
here we'll move on to the rest of the
related working groups so anima I saw a
report I don't have a nice list marked
up so I may not know all of these D
bounds oh okay dime we just got that
dispatch anything for dispatch okay d
mark do you mark met this morning and I
guess the main thing that it's
discussing right now is whether to put
out the document as experimental first
or go straight to standards track we'd
originally been figuring standards track
but Dave Crocker pointed out that we
don't know the operational effects of of
what we're doing and could use an
experiment with that so the working
group still hasn't decided that and
we'll figure it out otherwise it's
almost ready for working group last call
that's the arc sorry that's the arc
spec the D mark spec itself is
informational and it's on our cue
sometime to think about moving that to
standards track and whether we will do
that or not we don't know yet
thank you
deep prise HTTP
quick Netcom ntp
i just wanted to give one quick update
the network time security
Kayson is gonna go to working group last
call this week or the current draft is
going to work in crib last call and last
time when we sent it to working group
last call the security community was
very responsive and we're hoping you
will be so again thank you can I jump in
about deprive please so the big two
topics that we talked about when we met
were we had a bunch of fun and games
talking about D K G's proposal to D MUX
DNS and HTTP traffic on port 443 to the
same server that's that's good what
change go back and look at the videos we
also had a really interesting
conversation about D and I said quick
within the context of privacy so I think
we've got some really interesting
feedback on that draft as well and we
touched again on how do we move forward
to look at the recursive to
authoritative problem but we haven't got
anything concrete that yet lines are
good I caught you a quick um we are
monitoring the situation in TLS with
interest perk and radix perk is getting
around some of the issues it had with
its double context encryption for RTP
that's getting to a point where it would
benefits from some more review well
probably in a couple of weeks once the
new draft is out would benefit from some
review from folks who are
cryptographically minded and have some
enthusiasm for real time protocols so
like I said I expect there will be a new
version of that double encryption draft
in a few weeks then I'll maybe ping the
cyclists for some more juice okay and so
for radix they'll just say they're going
to close soon they are going to work on
I think one more draft and get that
through the working group and likely
close so thanks to everyone for their
work on that cider TCP ink I think sent
one and Utah
we're meeting later tonight and we can
sort of start to see the light in the
end of the tunnel so by okay talking to
somebody else
so right now we've got our the the core
documents that we were charted to do
they are in they've been overseas for a
while we're working on a few specs
related to the best best practice of
using TLS in in email various forms and
shapes but after that we can't really
see any other work so if the security
community has stuff for you ta you
should bring it to our attention before
Singapore because after that I think
we're gonna be done thank you
okay see frg no you forgot the crop okay
we did yeah
colonel for Deakin we have three
documents almost done deprecating sha-1
and 512 RSA using edy to 519 and I
forget what the third is but we'll
probably be done really quick and not
meet in Singapore alright thank you and
sorry about that so see frg okay thank
you
ir TF open proof sec so we've we've
changed chairs it's it's actually Martin
now but I'll give a quick report that
per sec is currently looking at
developing a traffic analysis document
the catalogs different forms of traffic
analysis and provide sort of guidance to
the community thanks said I RTF open one
of the two talks is Steven tuck away on
breaking junipers EC drbg H drbg so for
those security people not going too
quick they might want to go here one of
the research surprises all right thank
you and w3c
we didn't have any buffs so now we're
going to move on to presentations oh yes
sure so we have boss from the previous
one where there is work going in a
report was sent but both cheap and fun
yep
for deep we had a tutorial on Sunday
which I think was well attended
describing on how Trust song works and
and the scope of the deep effort and
Wednesday we we met to discuss the
Charter and I posted it to the deep
mailing list and we will also continue
with the webinars so that would be in
webinar from the Intel guys about the
trusted execution environments hopefully
maybe next week or the week afterwards
I'm still talking about the exact date
and I would send a doodleball around and
we'll make the announcements for fat
which is about the firmware updates for
IOT devices we actually met today and
sort of a site meeting to talk to those
who are developing operating systems for
IOT devices were the potential customers
or the potential guys who are impacted
by this and there are two new documents
out there posted on the mailing list
describing what the standards effort
could look like and so please join that
list if you care about firmware updates
and or IOT devices thank you and we are
hoping to charter those at least and
then soon before the next meeting or
after of off at the next meeting
I thought give you w3c update thank you
sorry I didn't realize I was on the
agenda this is Sam Euler w3c is web
authentication working group is making
interesting progress bringing token
based device based authentication up
into the browser but I think the thing
they'll be of more interest to the room
is we're reaching out and trying to get
more eyes doing security and privacy
reviews on our specs if people in the
room have interests in that space and
are interested in reading some w3c specs
with an eye towards security and privacy
and maybe stopping our working groups
doing stupid things please get in touch
with me all right thank you so now we
move on to presentations and Kenny
Patterson's up first with a presentation
on post quantum crypto so we're just
gonna switch laptops here okay good to
go
how long do I have okay so 30 minutes on
post quantum cryptography and I promise
you there are no equations in any of my
slides so if you are thinking of making
a run for it because of the possibility
of equations you can stay stay in your
seats I'm gonna start by looking at
something that's manifestly no post once
I'm going to start by talking a little
bit about sha-1 and talk about the
lifetime of sha-1 so we go back to
deepest darkest history the 1990s sha-1
was published it was actually a tweak of
a design from 1993 there were various
attacks on Shia zero in the 1990s which
validated that switch then char 2 was
published by NIST in 2001 nobody used it
we had the first collision attack for
sha-1 and 2005 except it was an attack
that didn't provide any collision it was
an estimated complexity of 2 to the 63
hash operations there's a famous
breakthrough paper by wine get out it's
maybe worth remembering that wine was
denied a visa to come and present our
result in United States at the time
things some things don't change very
much then between then and now there
were lots of claims and counterclaims
about improvements to this attack and
you know reactivations of the complexity
in 2006 NIST took the chef's the the
step of deprecating sha-1 from 2010
onwards for all federal agencies for all
new applications requiring collision
resistance or a limited set of
applications and use cases in 2013
Microsoft gar
to doing something about showering
deprecation from 2016 onwards for new
code signing certificates 2014 still no
collisions this is now quite some time
nearly 10 years after Wang's paper
Wang at Al's paper I should say the best
estimate at this point in time is to do
the 61 hash operations to computer
collision due to mark Stevens and his
collaborators in 2015 something really
interesting happened we saw something
called three star collisions which are a
precursor of food collisions against
Taiwan not quite there yet requiring
moderate computation ten days on a GPU
cluster with sixty-four GPUs 2017 sha-1
is still widely used there's lots of
activity in the C browser forum maybe
some of you have seen some of that
lovely controller state happening over
there resisting the removal of sha-1
trying to extend this lifetime is gone
and then finally we got the first
collision since sha-1 in ferry this year
I joined research activity between the
researchers at CWI led by Mark Stevens
and by Google
they finally actually exhibited sha-1
collisions q much press coverage and
then lots of researchers like me saying
well you knew this was coming this
should not be a surprise six point six k
core years of competition so 6600 cores
running for a year some permutation
combination of that kind of resource so
pretty serious work required then what
well we'll see what happens I think
sha-1 will be with us for some time to
come
indeed here here's a related graph that
shows the uptake of sha-2 in browser
trusted certificates on the on the
public Internet and you see a sha-1
search which is the redline suddenly
started decreasing in around early 2014
and then sha-2 started to shoot up an
md5 is effectively reached you which is
a good thing anybody want to guess yeah
by all means support but let's make this
as interactive as you like
except please don't throw things so
anybody want to guess what happened in
in in early 2014 to make this thing tick
up horribly
the first vulnerability with the logo
not the last only the first okay so I
think what's important to say here is it
was not a cryptographic attack that led
to the switchover from sha-1 to sha-2 in
certificates it was a computer security
vulnerability in a very widely deployed
piece of software open SSL
okay what about progress in quantum
computing we've seen sometimes something
happening and in the kind of classical
world I apologize for the very small
font in this slide I think the slides
are online if you want to have a look at
them and follow along so there were so
many things to put in here there's been
so much progress that I had to make the
font very small so it's interesting I
got all of this from Wikipedia because I
am NOT an expert on on quantum computing
or quantum physics I actually missed
that class in physics so pre-1994
wikipedia says that there were these
isolated contributions by various great
physicists people like Stephen Fry's
nah-ha level Charlie Bennett etc lots of
interesting little nuggets but nothing
no kind of connecting theory no kind of
concept of quantum computing as a thing
that really changed in 94 and then 96
because of Shor's algorithm and Grover's
algorithm so short algorithm basically
breaks discrete log and factoring
problems in with poly many gates and
polynomial depth polynomial in the size
of the numbers that you're working with
in other words all public key
cryptography deployed on the Internet
today is broken if you could build a
large-scale quantum computer they could
implement Shor's algorithm in Grover's
algorithm in 1996 basically gives you a
square root speed-up for search problems
and the effect of that is to have the
effective key size of your symmetric
primitives so some would say that's why
we have aes 256 in the first place as a
hedge against quantum attacks and
Grover's algorithm in 1998 a two bit
quantum computer was built and three
bits using NMR in 2000 we got to five
bits and seven bits using NMR in 2001 so
this is great the number 15 was factored
oh no no no no seriously on Iran a
quantum computer I'm not I'm not making
a joke here this is significant progress
because it means you have to build a
large enough computer and run it for
long enough to find out that 15 is
three times five the cube eight was
announced in 2005 if I have no idea
whether I know it means but it's good
good good publicity in 26 2006 we got to
12 bits 12 quantum bits 28 quantum bits
and now you start to see a runaway 2008
128 quantum bits this stuff just got
real this got really worrying except
this is d-wave so there's some
knowledgeable laughter from the front
for those of you further back what D way
we're building is a quantum annealing
machine so it implements some kind of
annealing algorithm in a quantum way
it's not doing general-purpose quantum
computation you couldn't use as far as
we know one of these T wave computers to
do to run Shor's algorithm for example
we do know that Google bought a dua wysz
een anybody from Google here willing to
confirm that and then tell us what
you're doing with it I have been told
that they dismantled it and rebuilt it
in their own image so some how to do
their own stuff so they have those kind
of people okay yeah true okay so back to
the real world of actual general-purpose
quantum computation fourteen qubits in
2011 and then in 2012 the number 21 was
factored as three times seven then
actually between 2013 and 2017 there
wasn't a huge amount of kind of publicly
announced progress in factoring and I've
been told by experts in the field that's
because factoring is the wrong problem
to focus on we should be looking at
other things than factoring I think it's
because they find it hard to scale their
quantum computers beyond the number of
bits needed here there instead focusing
on more fundamental technologies trying
to get them in place before attempting
to fight for larger numbers um in late
2016 onwards the physicists did a pivot
I believe is called the pivot in the
tech world towards focusing on something
called quantum suit primacy which is
actually a phrase I find personally
objectionable it has a lot of really
ugly overtones the use of the word
supremacy here and what this means is
building a large enough quantum computer
that you could solve a problem that no
classical computer could solve in a
reasonable amount of time with a
reasonable amount of resources think of
gluing all of Google and Akamai and
CloudFlare servers all together
trying to solve some computational
problem not being able to do it but
being able to do on a quantum computer
something like some kind of corns from
chemistry simulations for example and so
now there are rumors there are
circulating around in the research
community that quantum supremacy will be
announced at a conference in Berlin last
month Google announced that they would
achieve quantum supremacy by the end of
the year but I think that's using one of
these well who knows exactly what that
means let's let's not speculate too much
in 2017 d-wave launched the two thousand
queue which has two thousand quantum
bits in their simulated annealing world
that reminds me of the story of Hewlett
Packard whose very first product was
called the Hewlett Packard 200 okay
because it sounded good to start with
something that had a large number and a
small number it looked like you were
more established
I guess D Way have been a p-wave have
been around for a while now IBM unveiled
a seventeen bit quantum machine sorry a
seventeen qubit machine and Google and
Microsoft Research are all doing cool
stuff in this area so there's a lot of
energy going in a lot of money going
into this progress hard to judge for me
so what I'd say is that to draw these
two things together is that the threat
of large-scale quantum computing is kind
of weakly analogous and go with me on
this it's pretty weak analogy to the
threat of a breakthrough in sha-1
collision finding and the breakthrough
might be imminent but then again it
might not
and we know do actually have sha-1
collisions so this is slight really
should have been updated but for a long
long time people were speculating well
we can do sha-1 collisions but nobody's
done it yet because the reward is not
high enough or because it's actually
harder than we think we didn't really
know whether it was going to be possible
no we didn't really know whether those
algorithms would scale or not to the
size required it's hard to quantify the
risk that something will happen and hard
to put a timeframe on it happening but
meaningful results in this area we'd
have a substantial impact and lots of
smart people are working on it and
there's been a tremendous amount of
research investment on the other hand
maybe quantum computing is a bit like
fusion research if any of you tracked
fusion research over the years it's been
very interesting there's been tokamaks
and there's been no kinds of plasmas and
firing lasers at pellets and none of it
really works
yet okay so here's some conversations
I've been party to with people in the
quantum computing world large-scale
quantum computing is only a decade away
but he's been saying that for 25 years
okay
in terms of fundamental physics were
pretty close to what we need there's
just tons of engineering work and this
is a quote from Evan Jeffery who is now
with Google was with UC Santa Barbara
and he was he and his team were acquired
by Google and this was in a really great
talk that he gave a very cold head it's
sensible talk ly he gave about a quantum
computation a real-world crypto in 2017
and you can find that on the real world
crypto Google as for a YouTube feet and
he estimated also in that talk that to
break a 1024 bit RSA modulus would
require something like 250 million
quantum bits to be held in a coherent
state for long enough to do the to do
the computation I'll just remind you the
current state of they are is 17 so
there's a gap but apparently it's only
engineering work okay we should get him
to come and say that to the IETF see how
you guys react to that yeah okay so is
there a coming crypt apocalypse I should
never put a word on a slide that I can't
actually pronounce I find apocalypse
very hard to say I've done it twice
correctly now and I think I'll quit
there we don't know whether there'll be
a scaling breakthrough or not if it
comes it would be pretty catastrophic
for the internet and for internet
security so as I mentioned before shor
Shor's algorithm would mean that all
currently deployed of a key cryptography
on the Internet today would be broken
without exception okay you can break
elliptic curve cryptography all discrete
log based cryptography based on finite
fields all RSA base cryptography and
that's pretty much what we have in
deployment today interestingly because
of the key sizes and the sort of scaling
properties of quantum computation
elliptic curve cryptography would break
before an RSA so lipton of cryptography
is weaker for the same key cipher for a
smaller key size and I see and and one
of the one of the things to think about
here is that an attacker a well
resourced attacker think nation-state
adversary NSA could capture
trusting okay you're catching up good
okay a nation-state bursary could
capture interesting looking difficult
exchanges now okay so from my email
server to Eric's mail server where we're
discussing this talk and what am I going
to say I think was a question yeah just
a quick question on the ECC point um it
seemed Richard parts is this been is
this been a point with that is it gotten
actually gotten some analysis besides
the hand waving keys are longer need
more cubits because there are like
time-space trade-offs that apply here
and so even though you might be able to
get by with fewer cubits you might need
a longer coherence time is it similar
walls I think a detailed how all of this
analysis of this was done by some
colleagues of mine when I work for HP
back in the in the 90s HP Labs I think
if you look for the name Tim spear you
might find a little white paper that
describes this phenomenon yeah Paul
happened here there was just a paper
like two months ago on this which
actually says that maybe ECC is going to
be almost as hard for equivalent strikes
the last thing I heard was you need many
more registers so you need a bigger
computer I believe the answer is there's
not agreement yet there probably will be
agreement on this within the next few
years
thank you very much for that
clarification poll okay I'm as I said
I'm not an expert so if people here know
more please come and grab the mic and
give the rest of the presentation that
would be really great I could sit down
okay so we really expect some warning of
impending disaster we would hopefully
see in research papers published
research but of course you don't
necessarily know what's going on inside
the government research lab and we know
that replacing kryptonite scale takes
time okay it took a long time to get rid
of max and encrypt and TLS they're still
hanging on there I think we kind of
killed our c4 but still it takes time
and you'll still see it in either normal
corporate data centers where they don't
really keep that up to date with
security oh sorry I didn't say that I
didn't say that okay
replacing crypto at scale takes time and
of course as I mentioned traffic capture
now it could be broken later so if
you've got data that needs to be kept
secure for decades and you think there's
a risk of large-scale quantum
computation then you need to apply some
kind of precautionary principle and
think about migrating your crypto sooner
rather than
later okay there's even a conference for
this it's called katha crypt it's a
pretty doom-laden conference but you
know if you you could go okay okay so
how should we move forward from here
well this is not the way to move forward
let's think about post quantum
cryptography instead what is pqc post
pontipee of geography is cryptography
based on conventional techniques so
conventional public key cryptosystems
these would run we would compile on your
computer and run okay on a classical
computer in a reasonable amount of time
and we believe to the best of our
knowledge that they resist the known
quantum algorithm so Shor's algorithm
and so on so this area is called pqc and
sometimes it's called quantum safe
cryptography sometimes it's called
quantum immune cryptography if you work
in the area of quantum key distribution
and you're a physicist and you want to
embrace post quantum cryptography then
you call it quantum safe okay so we are
bringing other things into your fold and
extending your reach and so on so
there's a little bit of politics here
we're going to call it post quantum
cryptography the main candidates for
this and this is what I would have had
the equations had I been braver our
lattice based cryptography which has
been studied for twenty years now I
think code based cryptography which has
actually been studied for much longer
the michaelis code base scheme uses
gompa codes these are error correcting
codes and it was already in the late
1970s early 1980s being proposed and
explored
there's newfangled stuff based on
nonlinear systems of equations they have
a pretty patchy history there's been a
lot of schemes proposed and then broken
we're still finding out what makes these
problems hard and then the latest
greatest thing is elliptic curve isogen
ease if I was our tech investor I would
not invest and let the current isogen
ease right now we're extremely new and
we're still really figuring out what
kind of security they offer so there's
four main approaches that the
researchers are currently exploring and
these different approaches they could be
vulnerable to further advances in
quantum algorithms so it could be that
tomorrow Peter shor comes up with a new
algorithm that solves hard lattice
problems
we simply don't know what we do know is
that smart people in the quantum
algorithms community have been working
for a long time to develop new quantum
algorithms and so far with one exception
we have no applied to lattice based
schemes or to these other schemes and
the exception is this paper by Elder and
shor that was published much earlier
this year and then almost immediately
withdrawn because it was a bug in the
paper it was a very unfortunate thing
because this was the first time that
somebody of Peter short stature had
something interesting to say about
lattice based cryptography and this was
kind of a wake-up for the classical
cryptography community this was a very
interesting piece of news it turned out
that the the the parameters that he was
able to attack using his quantum
algorithm were not the parameters that
we would use in cryptography but still
it was maybe the first quantum chink in
the armor for lattice based crypto so
this was a significant thing but as I
say that they were was withdrawn but
maybe he'll come back with a new idea
with working with Eldar in the future we
just don't know there was also a paper
published by GCHQ in the UK now renamed
as NCSC called soliloquy and this was a
explication of their failed attempt to
build a lattice paste crypto system that
was continum in they found a quantum
attack against their particular scheme
so with another data point there for you
that maybe this stuff has some ways to
go before we really understand in
security against quantum algorithms even
the conventional security of these
schemes is not well understood in all
cases we have a pretty good handle on
the security of hash based signature
schemes for example X MSS which has been
working its way through CF RG and is
close to being an RFC now there's a
later scheme called Sphinx which is
developed by some academic researchers a
couple of years ago and we have a pretty
good handle on how to choose parameters
to make these kinds of things secure
they rely on pretty standard properties
of hash functions which we believe are
not really susceptible to quantum
attacks we even have some lower bounds
or the strength of quantum attacks
against these things but for things like
lattice based crypto and code based
crypto and nonlinear systems of
equations the academic research
community is really no digging it's
digging its its hands into this area and
trying to figure out exactly how we
should set parameters and
tax and so on I'll just pause there
because I see Steven coming to the mink
Steven seemed so for the hash pay
signatures I don't know if this is true
for all schemes but for some that the
more mature ones at least you only get
to sign a relatively small number of
times and then you have to change
private key that correct parole it's a
question of parameter selection and yes
and no I mean there's trade-offs between
the number of signatures you can sign
and the size of signatures and the cost
of signing and so on I'm I think on the
next slide I'll come to this point talk
about some of the characteristics of
these schemes and maybe maybe I'll try
and address it there okay yeah here we
go
so it's true and this is really what
Steven is hinting at that the current
post quantum schemes that we have are
not as performant as the pre quantum
schemes we've all got very used to it to
curve cryptography not really consuming
that much power on our servers or you
know not that much bandwidth on our
networks so typically what you're going
to find in the future is larger public
keys and larger key exchange messages
larger cipher texts etc I don't have
hard numbers for you here we can discuss
that later if you want this this field
is still very much evolving and on the
flip side you actually often get much
faster cryptographic operations to
actually do an encryption with some of
these lattice based schemes is just a
matrix multiplication and adding some
noise vector so encryption is much
easier than some kind of finite field
exponentiation for example this is good
news the performance may suffer as we
refine our understanding of how hard the
hard problems are in this area as we
refine our understanding of how to
choose parameters for security so better
attacks which will emerge over time as
people tweak their code and come up with
new ideas imply that larger parameters
are needed for the schemes and that can
also lead to a particular approach is
just being completely abandoned so we've
seen that a lot with some of the systems
of equations approaches people had ideas
they tweak them you tweak them interpret
them and eventually they said okay we
give up we can't make this secure using
this current set of ideas and
parameter selection this area is a much
more complicated question than it is for
RSA and ECC we've got used to magic
numbers like 2 or 4 8 bits for RSA or 3
or
two bits if we were crazy about security
or two five six bits for ECC there are
more parameters to play with in the post
quantum schemes and it's harder at the
moment to figure out exactly how to set
them put another way we're roughly where
we were for RSA in about 1982 okay I
would say I wasn't around I mean I was
born then but I wasn't doing
cryptography then I was just out of
short trousers but looking back in the
literature there was a lot of debate
about exactly how big or ISA should be
our RSA number should be can we choose e
to be small or can we choose D to be
small to improve the corruption etc etc
okay so we're kind of in that phase at
the moment in the research community
okay
I'm not doing for time eight minutes
okay I'm gonna speed up a little bit so
where are we right now with post quantum
cryptography we are still doing research
lots and lots of research and we're
progressing from research toward
standardization and appointment at a
fair rate of notes there's a couple of
examples here there's something called
the Internet defence prize which is
awarded at using execute each year and
it was given to a lattice based key
change protocol called New Hope in 2016
so the industry was like noticing this
stuff was happening and rewarding it new
hope design experimentally deployed by
Google last year in SSL TLS you can read
about that on Adam Langley's blog it's
been switched off now it was a limited
time experiment to understand the impact
on bandwidth and processing time and
there's a huge amount a really an
increasing amount of mainstream crypto
research going on at the moment in this
area but we're not there yet and on the
standardization site NIST last year
announced a process for standardizing
post quantum public key algorithms
starting announced in 2016 the closing
date for your submissions if you're
planning to make one is November the
30th 2017 and I know there are lots of
academic and industrial research lab
teams now getting their proposals
together fine-tuning them I'm going to
be involved in one myself so for full
disclosure I have a I have a dog in this
particular fight the process is going to
run as I mentioned up until 2023
ish
and the evaluation criteria our security
naturally cost and then there's kind of
mixed bag of other sort of secondary
criteria flexibility simplicity and
adoptability and you can go read on the
nist web pages to figure out exactly
what this means and here's a rough
overview of the process and i don't want
to go through every single one of these
tests i just want to show you how long
the process is expected to run for so
thank back to the days of
standardization of aes and add an extra
two or three years to that and then at
the end of that we may have a portfolio
of post quantum algorithms that we can
use or nist have reserved the right to
make a decision but further evaluation
is needed okay so it's going to take
some time Haemon you're thinking i've
heard about this thing called quantum
cryptography and quantum key
distribution why are we not using that
instead of post quantum cryptography
well let me let me destroy quantum key
distribution that destroys too strong a
word let me let me critique quantum key
distribution okay so this is great right
this is the physicists will tell you
this promise is security based only on
the correctness of the laws of quantum
physics and the correctness of quantum
physics is not in doubt it's been
verified to ten decimal places maybe ten
decimal places is not very large when
you're thinking about security
parameters for crypto okay we considered
an attack at a level like two to the
minus 120 and then we scrapped your
block cipher so ten decimal places
doesn't really cut it anyway okay and
this is often contrasted to the security
offered by public key cryptography we
always said that public key cryptography
is vulnerable to quantum computers and
and quantum key distribution would not
be etc etc I got some quotes together
here this is from Brian loans dr. Brian
loans from kinetic quantum cryptography
offers the only protection against
quantum computing and all future
networks will undoubtedly combine both
through the air and fiber optic
technologies okay here's another example
all cryptographic schemes used currently
on the internet would be broken that's
not actually true this was said by you
bizarre who is an IEC our fellow and ex
editor-in-chief of the Journal of
cryptology
so he's a pretty solid cryptographer and
he said that too at a lunch meeting of
some Institute this is an early example
of alternative facts
here's MIT technology review as early as
2003 this is 2td is one of 10 emerging
technologies that will change the world
even Burt cholesky who many of us know
and highly respect said back at this
time if there are things that you want
to keep protected for another 10 to 30
years you need quantum cryptography
these are examples that I gave at a talk
10 years ago this year at the fuse
Institute at the University of Toronto
so these are all 10 years old so what's
the big holdup why we're not already
using quantum key distribution but I'll
give you four reasons and I have backup
slides so if anybody wants to debate
this with me let's list it in the coffee
break after and qkd doesn't actually do
what it says on the tin it doesn't
distribute keys it expands existing keys
and if you already have a key in place
you can expand it in all kinds of ways
and build as many keys as you need to
using things like key derivation
functions ok qkd has significant limits
on both range and rate range is the most
fundamental one you may have heard about
the Chinese quantum key distribution
network running from Beijing to Shanghai
it sounds very very impressive but it
does not provide end-to-end security
it's a sequence of links join together
and each intermediate point you can read
the traffic in the clear ok if you want
end-to-end security qkd is not going to
give it to you until we have quantum
repeaters but they require a quantum
computers and I think I've told you
about quantum computers already security
in theory does not imply security and
practice in theory they're the same in
practice they're not
I think Yogi Berra said that I'm here
the idea is that we have to build
devices we have idealized models of the
physics but the devices will have
weaknesses they'll have side channels
you can shine laser beams into single
photon detectors and cause them to go
haywire etc etc etc okay so proving
secure systems is different from
designing secure systems and finally
quantum key distribution does know
offer significant practical security
advantages over what we can currently do
at low cost with conventional techniques
by which I mean symmetric key
cryptography ok check me later if you
want the details on exactly why that's
true ok it's not just me this is this is
my government this is the view from
ncsc or GCHQ as was quantum key
distribution they actually took the
unusual step of publishing a white paper
about two years ago outlining their view
and here's what they say the summary is
that Q KD has fundamental practical
limitations does not address large March
the security problem and is poorly
understood in terms of potential attacks
by contrast this is wonderful is his cat
net for someone like me by contrast
postpones on public key crypto or
appears to offer much more effective
mitigations for real world communication
systems from the threat of future
quantum computers in other words invest
in P Q C naught Q key T ok coming close
to the end now what should i etf do so
CFR g is on this to some extent we're
looking at developing internet traps for
hash based answers we've got two drafts
in development at the moment one is very
close to being finished and as I said
before this is a very mature and West
risky area but I think that all the
other post quantum schemes are still in
that kind of difficult teenage phase
right where they're kind of okey you
know kind of gawky and awkward and
likely to lash out at any moment
so and that's in the research community
nevermind standardization and actual
experience of deployment so we have a
long way to go here and my view is that
NIST's process is where the action is
going to be so in this has the resources
the secretary at the experience needed
to run a proper process you might think
back to things like the Julie C fiasco
and maybe NIST is not the body that we
should trust the developer crypto
standards but I believe that isn't a
significant concern here because of the
very heavy involvement of the academic
community we'll have I hope that and I
believe that the academic community can
keep the process honest I'm the
scientific experts will all be
concentrating their efforts they are
with NIST and not with IETF or other
standards bodies at least in the next
five to seven years that's where the
action is going to be
so I think my personal view this is
known as CFR G view or anything else
just my personal view we should wait for
an s processor on its course we should
be ready to rule over once those
algorithms are finalized we should
continue to avoid baking in any
algorithm so we should have algorithmic
flexibility and you know the ways that
we can get that wrong for example are
having maximum fuel sizes that are
rather too small for most quantum
algorithms so we should avoid doing
things like that we should keep an eye
on the kind of flows and the protocol
exchanges that are involved in key
exchange algorithm Squad some key
exchange algorithms they're not as
simple as straight-up elliptic curve
diffie-hellman would be so that cuz
that's going to have an impact on
protocol latency and road trips so we
might need to design carefully to avoid
impacting on those things we should also
maybe do some work and see if our G
could do this understanding how best to
combine pre or classical crypto systems
with post quantum schemes to so that we
get a hedge against the failure of
either type and we should also identify
and resist any efforts to do the kind of
sto shopping that you sometimes see
where people go to multiple standards
bodies until they get one that that
takes their stuff and we should we
should allow this to do its work with
the help of the scientific community
okay so final slide it might be coming
or it might not be I'm not going to try
and say that word it's possible that
post quantum co2 is a massive
misdirection of the scientific community
designed to distract us from things that
really matter like we could if he helm
and parameters or I don't know maybe
repeated ephemeral values in the TLS
protocol or something sigh I makes me so
sad makes me so sad folks I'm channeling
Donald Trump there and we can so we can
hope and I believe that in this process
will proceed in an orderly fashion they
were actually in some sense taking their
cryptographic reputation on it they have
to get it right and they have to put
adequate resources into it because
they're still in the process of doing a
repair job based on what happened with
Julie C and that whole that whole fiasco
so I think at the end of it we will see
a very sensible and conservative
portfolio of algorithms of options for
that will suit ITF needs
I mean time those things ietf can be
doing as I mentioned on my previous
slide to make the transition as smooth
as possible so that when we we get those
algorithms for an S we're ready to start
using them okay so that's everything I
wanted to say please form an orderly
queue of the mic I don't have to be
happy to talk to you thanks a lot
[Applause]
see thanks video you can is Richard
Barnes um I will +1 the suggestion on
your previous slide that we that CFR did
you take a look at this question of how
you combine classical and post quantum
algorithm work free quantum impose
commonalities if you will because I
think that's gonna be critical to
transition and I think it was one where
we're developing a solution with some
degree of generality I think it would be
really useful in facilitating that
transition I think it made that request
cfrt before I make it again now if
anyone has ideas there can be interested
I was wondering if you had any thoughts
about like how if there are ways that it
seems like you've kind of parsed out
kind of in this process and I ATS I see
FRG processes and fairly separate stacks
here there's wonder if you have any
thoughts on how they could maybe support
each other if there's things that see if
are G or IETF could do that would be
supportive in this process in terms of
the different perspectives evaluating
proposals or doing Interop testing or
something like that okay yeah thanks for
that suggestion that's an interesting
idea
maybe we could have some ITF folks
attending the NIST workshops that will
take place and feeding in requirements I
mean the sort of requirements gathering
phases somehow passed already there's a
requirements document that's been that's
been published already last year but
they're probably still opportunities to
influence if new requirements are I so I
encourage everybody here to go find the
NIST call for proposals document at this
website let me find the did I go back
past it already I'm trying to find the
URL well you can find online anyway and
there you can see the call for
submissions and there it talks about
these kinds of requirements so something
is missing then ITF people should should
get involved more generally and I'm not
sure um off the top of my head I don't
have any grace
for how we can we can compliment what
they're doing I aside from the things I
already mentioned I think the I know for
a fact that all of the key players in
the research community in this are
really focusing their efforts on the
noose competition maybe getting some of
them to come here and give updates on
what's happening could be useful you
want to come back yeah just a quick I
think that's a good insight I think
maybe that we have a little bit more of
the industry players here and so perhaps
this could be a way to make that
connection between the academic
researchers and doing some more kind of
operational testing and in my systems a
little closer direction thank you Paul
Hoffman two things that are related one
when you said well I don't know how big
the keys or the signatures might be just
for the people in the room current
estimates are they're going to be at
least an order of magnitude larger so
we're talking about 50,000 bit keys and
suchlike that depending on signature
sizes and such obviously this is one of
the things that NIST is considering on
trying to minimize that but if you've
got a protocol running over UDP or where
everything needs to fit in one packet
you should be very concerned about keys
or signatures which leads to the next
one so as Kenny gave a presentation for
me yesterday and CFR g because i had a
conflict
i've got a document called draft hoffman
c 2pq which is classical to post quantum
where it has nothing to do with what
will be chosen but we have to sort of
get an idea of how many i'm looking for
people to help if you look at the draft
you'll notice it's completely full of
holes and requests for for input this is
not something that's at all baked we
need a lot more work done on it we're
going to be talking to other people in
both in the physics side and in the
crypto side but in this room we are
going to want to know when should we be
making the transition and you gave a
couple of examples of soon longest term
never and it would be nice if if we as a
group could have some parameters on that
so please take a look at that and talk
to me if you have any ideas thank you
for let me second what posing I actually
forgot to include it in my slides and I
meant to mention of the draft that would
be a great place for people to start
contributing thank you right but and
again just to be clear it's super super
early in the draft so lots of room for
for if you were looking for something
contribute please do thank you I feel
huh maker a couple of points I do have a
degree in nuclear physics and I don't
think that quantum crypto is going to
work because the sorry quantum key
exchange will work because the
engineering parameters are too hard but
I wanted to one point is that we do have
Lamport signatures and they work and it
might well be worth baking in Lamport
signature roots now because that is one
thing that we can trust and we don't
need to do any more research but going
back to your original bit about the
whole sha-1 piece
CAS actually started moving to char to
in 2008 some of them did yes and Russ
helped me push one of them to do just
that the big problem was that the rest
of the infrastructure wouldn't accept
them until much later
and as a CA I can't issue certificates
the other people won't be able to read
sure and the other side of the argument
is that they wouldn't update their
software because no one was issuing
chateroo certificates I mean yeah we
know this chicken and egg situation is
often the case in crippled appointment
and I did come up with a bunch of
proposals to transmute through that
deployment cycle that were rejected by
the same people who then when they could
see the writing on the wall come back
that oh we got to get rid of this right
now and we've got to cancel certs that
are already been issued so I mean like
the issues that were you reporting to on
cab forum that's actually got to do with
the financial networks and they have a
bunch of stuff that they have put out
and haven't been listening to anything
and so we've had to take a bunch of CAS
offline they're not part of the web PKI
anymore to make use of that and that's
been a multi-million dollar backwards so
it's been a lot of fun right so
yes we would have a deployment plan for
this and we can start working on the
deployment plan before we actually have
any crypto hmm thank you I think that's
very much what Paul Hoffman's draft is
about - it's about starting to really
strategize about that stuff well in
advance Thank You Steven
good great okay thanks so comment on the
questions the comment is I think another
thing the IETF could do is look when
we're dealing with data items that might
still be sensitive in the far distant
future and not do that so rotate
identifiers don't have long term things
etcetera a lot of this is the
application space maybe more than in the
ITF space but I think it's still
something the ITF could be doing is
knowing that if we're creating new long
term identifiers and those can be
correlated with things maybe we
shouldn't do that okay I don't think
it's just identifier stores also the
plaintext right and yes but because the
plaintext probably isn't in an ITF
contacts roof okay
and then the comment was so you had a
nice time line and that said you know
sit back and relax for seven years
oh yeah the question is what's the kind
of IPR situation here and are we really
have we got 27 years to sit back and
relax that's a great question and I was
reading the draft just that the call the
other day what does it say by IP are
it's definitely a consideration I mean
this is obviously aware of it
I think they don't require IPR
declarations it's not like yeah I won't
say anything because I'm not sure but
it's certainly something that's on their
minds maybe somebody knows yeah just
couldn't want to come and say something
about IPR and mist if you can cut it in
front of you Nick that would be great I
think
really quite the AAP ought to be
declared okay declared but not given up
yeah not that we we hopefully prefer now
yeah okay but you see impractical Wars
they'd have to thing the same and one
will I PR and one without then yeah I
know that there are teams who are
targeting than this competition you're
making their proposals as boring as
possible from an IPR perspective that's
what my team is doing so hopefully
there'll be some proposals that are no
IPR laden we can hope how can you Nick
Sullivan thanks for the investment
advice on sergeant II base crypto but
I'm something to point out that actually
is pointed out by I Sasha new base
crypto is that the key sizes don't have
to be extra large you can actually there
are post on to seed schemes in which you
trade a lot of computation with small
key sizes for quantum resistive quantum
Fourier resistance right I think that's
a great point and and I promise to not
put any equations on the slides so I
didn't get into that level of detail I'm
but my comment about so Geneva's crypto
was mostly about the novelty of it the
newness of it it really isn't in any
sense battle-tested
still very new technology Tamiya has
gone Renoir Wayne so when it comes to
the timelines I feel like in a quantum
state it may it may happen in 2030 it
may happen in 25 it may happen in 35 or
it may never happen
we will only find out once the quantum
states have collapsed so however like
when you mentioned your point with the
Kepler data now and read it later I
think that's one element you could you
should add one more thing the devices we
design the protocols we design they have
lifetimes of 10 years plus so I think
that kind of leads us to this maybe
crypto agility plus that we need to
design the protocols in a way that we
can update them without too much
breaking our necks in let's say five to
ten years time if
that state actually happens and I think
that's probably a requirement we need to
consider now just so we can manage the
tail and if these incidents happen
earlier than we expect them to would
that be a fair yes absolutely I think
that's a great comment thank you all
right thank you very much Kenny okay
thank you okay so now we're gonna have a
talk on pretty easy pretty easy privacy
not as easy to say by Volker Brooke have
this in a second if there will be Flint
I won't be bringing them up just very
shortly what else okay
I can introduce myself because I'm new
I'm for Co for pretty easy privacy we
approach it trying to solve ok this is a
mic but ok very good I have testing time
ok ok again my name is Coco I'm from
pretty easy pretty and we are trying to
solve a quite hard problem it's the
problem you users don't need to get
involved with crew to details at all to
use crypto and that on open standards
thank you
so yes here we go yes we also could you
go back please
we also applied a draft here or supply
draft here where you can read some
details welcome later to that next slide
please
the problems we are facing I think is
quite clear unfortunately there's way to
less proofs in Internet and really
I think this is a big issue because the
network could help a lot for civil
rights but if it's still like this then
we need to improve there and what we're
actually watching where it's going to
encrypt offer users is either it's going
to propriety platforms which build some
system which works quite well but it's
closed source no one else really what's
behind the curtain
and on the other side we have open
standards which are yes basically for
email some others and which are quite
hard to use so that's the situation we
found and that's where we want to
improve and another one is we really
believe that jabber deserves gaining
more users okay next slide please
so this is an just an example of things
we're actually working on and we need
answers for I will not go through all of
them but basically you can say there is
lots of missing interoperability here
which gave us the idea to talk to you
guys if you want to help you and there's
also things well we have basically
either web of trust idea which as a
privately activist I really dislike
because the web of trust means
publishing in a social graph and this is
exactly not what privacy wants and on
the other side we have the hierarchy of
x.509 which is enterprise you way better
that which ends up with rest anchors
which make issues so our idea is that we
start to do everything peer-to-peer and
not server based and this is the core of
the PAP idea having a peer to the
implementation of everything and we also
want to add things we are already
working on it which is hiding metadata
supplying absolute anonymity and
anonymity into our implementations and
into other implementations so this means
extending formats extending protocol
sense of
and one really important thing which is
totally underestimated in my view is we
we never managed to find a real stand of
Identity Management so we have very
different ways to manage identity and at
least we need a mapping or we can even
define what sin immunity means in a
technical way so yes so what we want to
achieve is a common concept to exchange
keys and signal trust until the user the
users PAP is a very user centric project
we compare that with what with web
browser guys - that means we end up with
something like a traffic light semantics
next slide okay so what are those guys
already doing we already have an
implementation of automated key
management locally and between devices
that's automatic key management we mean
completely peer-to-peer we mean
generation revocation of keys we call a
key reset which is a little complex
thing so I need your keys because and we
already implemented a three-stage trust
rating concept we implemented as many
open PGP because open standards highly
important for us we want to be as
comfortable as possible we implemented
message formats which have a little more
privacy properties we implemented a
first version of what we call peace in
which is synchronizing of keys between
the devices one user is owning that
means I have let's say a pad and a
telephone and the laptop and I want to
share the same keys on all my devices
but no one others should have the keys
of obvious reasons so we implemented
that and we created adapters so you can
use the implementation because all what
we are doing is free software in common
languages where applications are built
next slide please
what we also did is we just implemented
applications to show that this is
actually working and you can just
download and try it out so we did it for
couple of platforms and what is still
missing is we have a deal with the new I
think it was first time in history that
new actually is giving out property and
instead of techadon and first guys they
did it is us we actually co-owning now
we have ownership on unit as pet
foundation and we are building me that
the DHT base onion implementation based
on the subsystem of new net which is
coca debt and yes we have way more work
to do because we need to synchronize
more things so for example we already
synchronize keys would be nice to also
have to trust synchronized if you trust
something on one device it would be nice
that it's trusted on the other device
for obvious reasons thanks light so this
is an example of that key sync topic how
it's working basically we yes we are
using isn't one and you will kill us for
that I already heard that there's a very
good reason why we need pair because we
need it as small that it fits in a
Twitter or an SMS usually that's really
the boundaries and that's the thing we
found which actually works there and we
are doing kissing with such device
groups also already multi-platform the
green box is what we are already
implemented and now we'll want to
propose we will write there after it as
internet standards and the missing
things is what we're actually doing work
next slide so we can you guys help us I
hope or we can be a new member of the
family which I hope more this is of
course there is a draft for man based
message formats which is from the ITF
and we already implemented that for
being compatible in our engine but
unfortunately this draft has nature
issues in our concept and yes let's say
we are not very happy on it that is the
reason why we will do another one and
let's work on that and we have the hope
when we design at work protocol families
which could be helpful not only for
pepper from
many protocols like doing a peer-to-peer
kissing implementation we have the hope
that we can make a standard that this
really works over platforms and
protocols yes
also the mappings you know we are using
email and travel for in inland
communication of things like that
kissing and so we want to standardize
that so and we don't get into the mess
that the different implementations will
not be comfortable and there's even
things like UI schemes we design because
internally we are using your eyes for
addresses and next slide please
there's also a lots of future topics we
have hope to find people being
interested in the ITF which is identity
mapping kalenna mapping as already
mentioned and also what we call key many
key mapping which is we have text
message transports we call them transfer
to email isn't transport for pep which
means we have such things where a PKI is
just a huge and you cannot use it on
such small things think of SMS ism a
primitive example and so we have
automaticall mapping onto symmetrical
temporary keys and of course we're also
working on non mind message formats i
already man
I mentioned Java I don't know how much
they love it next slide so what is our
hope to find here yes we really want
interoperability and and I think this is
the right place to ask for it and of
course we need lots of critics we need
your heart critics because we are just
doing it on our own and just put an
implementation on the table here and it
would be nice to hear the opinion of
experts in these fields where we are
right and may be wrong right and what we
also hope is that foundation is way too
small to offer a management of of open
standards so we have to hope that the
ITF wants to jump in and because I have
no clue of the ITF I'm very happy right
people help me it would be so nice if we
get some guidance furthermore how to
achieve something like that
next slide please
leave that the comment that just came in
- yes please
would would reflect now that we're in
zone R has the pepper nation ever taken
a look at the work in the Utah working
group with regard to email security
reporting and UI / security improvements
as far as I know pep is implementing a
kind of overlay for popular clients
based on either s1 or jpg the PGP Utah
meets later on
please join so I believe he's suggesting
that that would be one place that meets
the requirement in your last slide last
bullet okay that's where would this take
place
Utah appears to be one set of place well
that's great input thank you I think
we'll do that okay so because I only
have four quarter of an hour I know the
approach is way too complex to explain
it in a quarter of an hour I would love
to end my people we do a bob off in room
Terrica this evening and if you have
time feeling lighted and this for sure
will end up in a bar I can guarantee
event thank you hi pal voters so I'm not
exactly sure what you're proposing are
you is this an effort to strengthen a
whole lot of protocols within the IETF
to do better security or are you
suggesting that this is a whole new
federated area that we're building or
are you some new centralized phone book
that has all these privacy and anonymity
features inside like that I'm really
confused okay first we never centralized
we do only peer-to-peer and there's no
central infrastructure and the pet
foundation is managing nothing okay so
then hi I'm Edward Snowden here's my
identity yes
which is possible because we don't
manage identities I talked about mapping
of identity management of other people
which they do in different ways into
each other so there is interoperability
it's not meant that pet foundation will
not provide a namespace where you can
register
that's not what you're doing I
continuously even more oh well okay so
mutton comes and that actually helped a
little bit
I read your draft I've looked at your
website in some detail and I have to
confess that neither of those things
helped me that the slightest bit
understand what you're trying to do I
saw some statements about grand
principles and I saw some code but I
didn't see anything connecting the two
of them well I didn't see an
architecture or anything I think you've
actually got a lot of things that you're
asking us to do and this presentation
was really quite helpful as well in
helping me sort of understand where you
you're going but I that what you're
going to need to do is talk to a few
people here this week and and I think
unfortunately I'm occupied otherwise for
the barb off but I would love to come
but you need to ask those people for
help because you're actually asking for
a number of different things yes and
what we what the people here would like
to see is how the what your goals are
and very in a very concrete way how
those goals fit together if you have an
architecture what that architecture
looks like and how the various pieces
fit together and where you have
identified deficiencies in the
individual protocols that you're using
what those deficiencies are and how you
propose they would be fixed and this is
a massive project I have to say the
number of things that you had on these
slides is frankly frightening and it
would be a respect if you can make any
progress on this at all
there's working implementation already
which we can download and try out so um
my caution that there's there's a very
big difference between implementing some
code and shipping some code and actually
getting to the point where you have
interoperability and that's a long hard
battle and I roundly congratulate you
for even attempting that thank you well
thank you
and you are so right that it's really a
hot petal help to the home Baker yeah I
I been following this for quite a while
now and I like it
and I just like to point out at the
moment there are a lot of usable secure
end-to-end messaging mechanisms around
you know we've got signal whatsapp's and
so on there are two problems of that one
is that they're all single silo models
so in order to talk to somebody whose
arm signal I've got to get signal yes
and so that that immediately cuts down
the community I can talk to the other
problem that you have is that they're
all being sold as ways around government
coercion and the thing is that if you
require everybody to run the same app
from a single provider the application
is a point of coercion even if your
crypto is end-to-end secure yes and so
if we're going to get to the point where
we have a system that is resistant to
government coercion it's got to be based
on open standards such that they can the
implementations can be audited and the
protocols have to be designed in such a
way that when you are dealing with a
messed up version of the a coerced
version of the application that tries to
talk to a non coerced then it's got to
become apparent and one of the things
that I had when I talked to somebody
very senior in one of the agencies
formally his advice was Nobis nobody but
us in that the thing is that they're
very willing to mess around with crypto
and applications or whatever but they
are very adverse to having their messing
up being detected sure and so that's the
thing that we've got to work for whether
this is I've got problems with this
particular implementation I think that
maybe we need to go to a consensus
algorithm
that allows us to centralize without
being centralized but it could work
Thanks thank you so next up we have
Dimitri and I don't want to try to see
your last name on certificate limitation
profile yep Mike slip this I will speak
about my proposal to sanitize
application level application supported
list of certificate limitation next
please current state offer test is the
in decay world is mostly divided by F
CEO 5 to 18
we have binary model of trust we have a
set of processes we have Sorrell and
those is P validation and we have say
Draven revocation the sada even
revocation does not always fit the
purposes of real world for example here
at the link to a presentation made for C
browser forum next slide please
and one of the most significant cases of
not fitting current model to the real
world is the case of Google versus
Symantec when Google found that Symantec
misbehaves the company suggested to
limit certificates issued by Symantec it
suggested to reduce the accepted
validity period
the to get the distrust to current us
that the cemetery shield certificates
and so on and so forth and even to
remove their recognition of external
validation status for Symantec issued
certificates next slide please
now when application wants to limit
trust it has in fact thought a options
well application can specify which
processes are valid for in its context
it can turn off Sorrell and SSP
validation and we have problem what
shall we do when SSP is not available
and in case we have flex availa we need
flexible limitation in for example when
one of say is too big to fail week and
we have to have poured them next slide
please
I propose a solution certificate
limitation name the certificate
limitation profile it's a list that can
be distributed with the application or
by the application as a part of
application bundle if it should have
sailor-like syntax it should be
cryptography designed and if this
proposal finds interest and implemented
the users application can use code base
instead of application level hot coding
this will allow to avoid some some
common mistakes in validation next slide
please
so what can be stored as examples of
such limitations at first we should say
whether the limitations are applied to
certificate itself or its descendants on
the chain of trust and for example we
can say
we should not trust if agates issued
after this other date we should not test
their certificates matching the profile
after the concrete date we can limit
develop definitive certificates that we
can say which expire and extension
should be ignored we can say which they
which extensions should be quite
difficult for example for replica it's
the common case is silica transparency
related extensions we can as it was
suggested many times limit my name's by
the essay like name like name
constraints next slide please
implies changes to the verification
process after building change chain of
trust we go through it and apply
limitation to the matching sets and if
specified in the profile we apply them
to is the sandals if we find that the
certificate should not be trust that we
stopped verifying and return that it's
entrusted next slide please and so
instead of hard-coding many a limitation
at the application level we can limit
very small set of check that we have
cell P in use that the selfie you
operate is a fraction of that cell P is
signed by correct answer
thank you very much
[Applause]
I'm on Thompson and that the agenda
doesn't have a link to a draft sorry my
thought I will provide the link up was
requested the chairs on yeah so I don't
know what this is but having said that
why exactly at the mic I I certainly
haven't read this but you're describing
a number of things that has a
significant amount of overlap with a
number of his existing deployed
mechanisms like public key pinning and
we implement a thing called one Sorel
must have been a proposal to use
recursive bloom filters in combination
with the certificate transparency log to
have an exhausting exhaustive list of
certificate revocations why would this
be superior well their certificate the
serial profile is say drivin for example
sorry I'm the CRL I see drivin less al
should be should buy see this profile
can be issued by the application of that
this is something that once they wrote
us yeah yeah yes so the there are
application then Richard Barnes there
are application vendors doing this today
so a chrome google for chrome produces
here l sets which are basically largely
overlapping with kind of the limited
subset of the functionality you
described and mozilla produces a thing
called one crl as Mark mentioned for
Firefox and so the question is those are
proprietary things about there between a
vendor and its applications so I'm
curious like what's the value of
standardizing this and adding as all
this additional functionality well yes
it's a similar one do you describe its
just try to formalize that proposal
syntax from all over the syntax
hi this is Daniel Kang Gilmore with SEIU
I'm also work on the Debian project I
don't know if you're aware of the p11
Glu project which has a storing trust
policy specification they've been
working on that fits what you're doing I
think almost exactly and the use case
Richard is that there are a bunch of
different things that actually check
certificates and the rules are subtle
and so if you can actually build this
particular API then you can encourage
people to not rewrite their own so it is
it days I think definitely merit in this
kind of work but there is existing work
that does this and I'd be happy to like
try to point you to it and connect sure
if it's useful so thank you very much
it'll be great
rich Sol's I guess open a cell
affiliation yeah it's great that two or
three programs on the Internet can do
really fast and really precise checking
of revocation but I'd like to see this
extensible to all sorts of things so not
just the browsers but there are many web
PKI programs out there so I support this
would be interesting to come up with a
standard data format I've had some
discussions with some of the Linux
vendors about doing that so yeah I
encourage this yeah
mutton Thompson as someone involved in
one of the projects that has one of
these things we'd certainly be willing
to participate
we already collaborate with Google who
runs one of these things opening up a
standard for this wouldn't necessarily
do all that onerous and I think we'd be
open to that so there's Richard Barnes
again so that thinks TKG for the
clarification there I think yeah I can
see there could be some value to this I
think at least a soft prerequisite for
this work is going to be well a
prerequisite for the work to be
successful is going to be some notion of
who is trusted to distribute this
information in the you know vendor to
its application space it's kind of clear
because you trust Google for Chrome you
trust in Mozilla Firefox it's not clear
what you would do for say open SSL or
Debian
so it seems like there needs to be some
work done on that aspect of this problem
as well if it's gonna be worth
developing a format Eric rajala for for
someone else one of those projects the
there actually are two problems to solve
one problem is the policy problem of
indicating like which anchors you trust
and which intermedius to revoke and the
other was to address the problem of any
certificates and the and the problem
there is data compression because the
number of road initiative is far too
large to actually send over in any
format books like this at all so um so
just have an entire problem you gotta
solve that problem as well I'm very much
work on that but well for the first
problem I expect that that Accenture
will be distributed with the application
that implies using cell P for example
hard coded and exempt but yes it's a
common problem distribution center and I
hope we can use common method for it
sure that's a little bigger problem is
actually harder in at the affinity the
visually they were hard coded a she is
terrible person is it very very - you
see eight at the market so and almost
exactly as I which is always working
immediately not interesting cause I
might actually produce a second one or
her than the first
okay so Thank You Dmitry could you send
a link out to sag and I will update the
agenda to include it as well I will send
the SAG thank you very much thank you
I now we have 20 minutes left about for
open mic it could be something different
hi Steven Farrell
so there was a bit of an out force
yesterday in today's session and
hopefully we killed off one one more bad
idea
so what I without getting into the
details of that which I don't think are
right here and the TLS working group are
continuing to beat them more bad idea
ferries I guess if the TLS work we went
crazy I think that wouldn't be in their
Charter and what they would need to
rechart her to do the crazy thing and
also I think he heard from Lars and from
Kenny that clearly such such changes TLS
would have big impacts outside one
working group and outside the security
area in the other parts of the ITF so
I'm just wondering what you guys think
about it so nothing's been adopted yet
there's still discussion I think it
remains to be seen what will happen if
new proposals will come to the table
that maybe are better and maybe they
have nothing to do with to us as one
thought I had if there's something
specific to the data centers perhaps hey
that's one thought that I had after
listening to some of the conversations
and you know so you know cueing off of
other people's ideas and thoughts you
know maybe there's an opportunity for
something data center specific and then
you could design just what you need and
it would interfere with TLS or you know
our internet level applications for
encryption I know this one thought I had
yeah I think make sense as well yeah but
on the issue of the working group
decides right so it's still happening so
I guess the question through the
specific question for you is if they
adopt something like this do you
consider that within their current
charter yeah I do go back and reread the
Charter I'm sorry I will I can suggest
an answer what would that be
I mean I would have to go back and
reread it carefully as they do so and
obviously you know we follow what the
working group wants to do so we'll see
what they ultimately decide right so the
more conversation happening sorry after
I said yeah
no speaking not his ad I don't believe
that Draft cream would be within the
tails working group Turner um yeah I
present right okay so which means that
if they did try and do something crazy
like that it would need a return because
of the reason I ask is because at that
point the ietf gets to have a say as
opposed to just the people in one room
or the people on one marinus the reason
paralyzed but this is as possible some
other thing might be within Turner
ground I don't think I don't think dr
green however would do inter right okay
any other questions sorry
probably less interesting but still back
it back to Kenneth's presentation there
was a quantum random Oracle mentioned in
CFCF og and you guys need a theoretical
models to prove security so I wanted to
ask probably your personal opinion on
whether these models exist I reliable
and something that that NIST can base
and the evaluation on I don't know think
about this Kelly yes yes and yes is the
answer so yes they exist what was the
second part game but there was
definitely three yeses I was stable
reliable well the quantum random welcome
well was something we're still getting
our heads around there's a few experts
in the world who know how to work with
it but the group of people who can is
growing your time
it's basically an extension of the
random Oracle model which is some kind
of abstraction we used for modeling hash
functions and security proofs taking
into account quantum capabilities
anniversary so it should become a
standard tool for the analysis of all
the NIST proposals and is it something
that NIST can rely on and used and yes I
think so
hope that helps
anything else all right
enjoy the rest of your day thank you
thanks I appreciate the usual I'll talk
generally so I I my