and even Scotty over tottering say what
[Laughter]
oh you gotta get volunteers huh okay
okay this is fine no it is morning
shall we get we've got a post there is
people hiding behind the post that's
okay
they're not really paying attention to
me so I'm dick Hart
we have our own chauffeur we're chairs
of second events first slide of course
is no well everyone wants to read over
that
so we'll start with some administration
we need a minute taker and volunteers
for a minute taker yeah so this is where
we stop until we get a minute taker we
actually do need one
it's your first time in the working
group people are supposed to say their
name could it take minutes boss thank
you very much and we need the jet
ascribe to channel people from the table
room thank you and the blue sheets are
going around everybody is a blue sheet
moving around where is it now thanks
Tony
are you gonna let other people have it
too so our focus we still have one
working we have a single working group
draft we have a couple of IDs that were
we will have presentations are and that
are at a higher level and we've got some
use case discussions going on and you're
on drew this pretty picture which you
want to talk about your picture so for
people who are new to this working group
and actually also for people who are not
new it can be confusing we all the time
we have a zoo of the internet drafts so
this tries to put the stuff in order at
the bottom we have the working group
document the set format which is related
to their job best common practices that
were working on in parallel on top of
that we have a single a set delivery
over HTTP draft that will be presented
today and then we have two ways to
manage those HTTP streams one is with
REST API and the other one is with
scheme the REST API will be presented
today scheme will not be present
and presumably it's just using scheme at
the top we have profiles which will be
done by external identity management
organizations stos and we have use cases
and people will be presenting to use
case documents today so that sort of
covers a plan for the day which
obviously is a very busy agenda
so let's segues into doing some agenda
bashing we of course are doing that
right now
then we'll have set token the token
delivery the management API which is the
REST API and then we'll go through the
risk in scheme use cases any feedback on
the agenda not I guess we can get
started with Mike figure out how to go
on
oh good morning all I'm Mike Jones from
Microsoft and one of the editors of the
security event token specification
I liked the airplane better deck okay Oh
how do I make that fullscreen where's my
there you go next so we currently have
the third working group draft of the
document the functionality has actually
been stable for quite a while most of a
year we bashed it out when it was still
draft hunt ii vent and the edits since
we last met together in person in
chicago have been to address the issues
that were discussed and raised there and
have subsequently been discussed on the
mailing list and i do thank people on
the mailing list because there has been
vigorous and i think well informed
discussions so i think this has been a
productive few months next so what have
we done since ITF 98 those of you who
are following the list know that most of
the discussion has been about how to
prevent confusion between security event
tokens and other kinds of tokens that
attackers might want you to confuse it
with and in particular the open ID
connect ID token received a lot of
discussion and i'm happy to report that
we did develop a recommendation or
practice to prevent confusion even if no
ID token implementation is ever modified
to know about the security of that token
also as part of the preventing confusion
discussion we worked out a way that had
been discussed in fact in Chicago and on
the list for explicitly typing the JSON
web token which represents the security
event token and that being using the
existing header name type typ which was
already in the job and really those
jason web signature spec for that very
purpose so the new things in our draft
are just to register the content type
and to describe when and how you might
want to use it also partly in response
to some discussions that Marius had
helped lead we put a note in the spec
explicitly telling people using set spec
that some types of events and profiles
might choose to put subject information
not at the top level as a jot claim but
inside the event body in particular and
this may be esoteric or to some of you
but it matters to other use cases the ID
token and I think some access tokens
define what's being acted on in the ID
token with two claims the issuer and the
subject where we're naturally using the
jaw issuer of the set to say
who issued the set so if you also want
to have a claim to represent an issuer
that's the thing being acted on you
would put that in the payload and we
explicitly say that oh and if there's a
subject related to that issuer you might
just want to put that in the payload as
well for consistency finally we added a
new section on requirements for set
profiles which is not actually new
content because it's been widely
discussed on the list for most of the
time that we have had the mailing list
even before the working group but it
tries to write down as guidance so that
people get it right when they're
defining an event or a profile with a
set of events not just that you have to
define the syntax of how your event is
represented which is kind of obvious but
just as important it talks about needing
to define the semantics and the
validation rules for the data carried in
the event and in particular one of the
most important pieces of semantics that
any actionable profile is going to have
to define is how to validate that the
issuer of the jot controls the keys or
key used to sign the jot indoor
encrypted why does that matter and this
is kind of crypto security 101 that if
you don't know who controls the keys
anybody could be doing the crypto
operation including parties that you
might not want to place a lot of trust
in and so this is not a new set of
requirements this is just writing down
in the draft what any
same profile is going to have to do to
make it work and so that recipients of
the set
no both syntactically and semantically
what they need to do to safely process
it and use it next so drilling down on a
point I mentioned on the previous slide
the way that the draft now says that a
set is to be distinguished from an ID
token is by not including an expiration
claim which is something that the
previous draft already said it's not
recommended now we're just saying if
you're in a context where there could be
ID tokens never do it is this a hack
maybe but I mean my ass and others were
good advocates of saying practical
problems could result if existing
systems with ID tokens are extended to
ad sets and a set which is from a
legitimate issuer could be captured by a
malicious party and presented as if it
were an ID token with mayhem possibly
resulting the reason this works is it's
required in the ID token validation
rules to look at the expiration claim
and so if it's not present any correct
ID token processor is going to throw the
result away because it's malformed all
now following up on some previous
discussion in Chicago and on the list
that this is actually defense-in-depth
because already in any normal context
for an ID token it's impossible to
confuse it
because the set wouldn't have a valid
nonce claim with the correct value which
is also necessary for the ID token to be
accepted but you know now we've got two
ways both of them are fully effective
that should do it for the short-term
next and we also added the ability to do
explicit typing that's something that
among others are two chairs in a
different role and I had worked on this
preliminary jot BCP which Kathleen had
asked us to do apparently because of the
discussions in the set working group and
some related discussions
in OAuth and while the BCP does talk
about confusion there's a gob of other
stuff in the BCP talking about ways that
people might implement things wrong ways
that people might fail to do checks so
that'll be discussed in the Roth working
group later today but we invite you to
read that the reason I bring that up now
is the explicit typing is something
that's in the draft jot BCP and the
first use of that is in the set spec at
this point next
so as I said in my introduction the
functionality both syntax and semantics
have been stable for most of a year I
believe that the draft does and already
has met the needs of all the known use
cases that have been discussed the
possible issues with the previous draft
have been vigorously discussed with the
results being incorporated into the
current working group draft and while I
have a half hour this is the end of my
deck I'll just say that now I think the
right discussion to have or any other
discussions that people want to have at
the mic is is it time for working group
last call I'll note that after this
draft was published that addressed the
known open issues that about a half
dozen people spoke up on the lists and
said yeah it's time and I personally
concur it's time to get this done
because it already works and it's
already in use thank you yeah questions
good morning smiley scooter school so
there's a couple of issues so let's
start with the easier one was a
discussion on one of the email threads
about explicitly identifying the profile
in a set because it's sort of implicitly
identified by the event types well it is
explicitly identified by the event type
that gosh sure so you can have multiple
events now if the set is not if the set
is mixing events from different profiles
which it shouldn't but it could right
then a parcel it might be not
deterministic because it depends which
type it picks up to check the profile
also it's not clear how do you map map
the type URI
to a profile so those things are I think
there are concerns I think it would be
much better to explicitly identify the
the profile so I just want to raise this
as an issue and the fact that there was
a discussion around that so and there's
a couple more things but this is the
first one okay and that's something we
could describe in the draft more
explicitly I will say that there's
profiles for which there's only ever
going to be one event and so adding
extra data is just superfluous rhythms
use case well there's no fuss we look so
far maybe there might be but most
profiles will have multi pretty but I
agree
many profiles will have multiple events
and I think rather than having
duplication of semantic information what
I would recommend is for a profile that
wants to have a gob of events that it
come up with a naming convention where
there's a prefix on the event name so
for instance the risk working group I
know in open ID has discussed having a
prefix something like
schema static open ID dotnet slash
events slash risk and then the event
names and so for a profile that you
wanted to do profile identification it's
easy to do that with prefix matching
without needing duplicate information
one of the problems I have is a protocol
designer with adding redundant
information is it introduces the
possibility of an inconsistency that was
previously impossible what if for
instance a malicious or just badly
written party was to use the event URI
and then say this is in a profile but
one that's not related to that event URI
because you have this duplication of
content there is an inconsistency and
error processing code that you're gonna
have to have whereas if you only have
one an unambiguous way to determine the
information you've designed the
possibility of those mismatched errors
out of the system you're in so I'd much
rather do that
I think you have the mismatch problem
anyhow right because you can have
multiple events in a set and technically
the URIs could come from different
profiles so this mismatch issue is there
to begin with the prefix that you
suggest it's practically the profile
identifier right so maybe one solution
is to ask each profile when did they
define your eyes to have a common prefix
I'm not sure but I think is something we
need to try we we could describe that in
the draft if people are interested right
but I think's also considering adding a
top-level claim describing their profile
it's a valid requirement so we should
discuss that as well again adding the
top-level claim I think introduces the
mismatch possibility that's currently
impossible it's possible we have
mismatch possibility the draft
I think I know what you're saying the
draft already says that if you have
multiple events in the set that they
must be from the same so compatible no
from a compatible set of events using
common you know syntax and semantic
conventions listen whether you call that
one profile or whether it's a set of
profiles all adapting the adopting the
same conventions is sort of semantics
but practically we normatively say that
you must not mix events for which
they're representations are not
compatible okay so yes you could still
violate that but we already have
normative text saying you can't do that
sure you could have no motifs text
saying that the profile identify should
match the URLs like it's the same thing
right well the other thing is uh not
sure how how is solving the key
resolution issue because I think
profiles have to define how the key is
resolved right that's right on which
case in which case because there is only
one signature we do have only one
profile per set it's a hard requirement
there is no way around that one issue
are per set but it should be only one
profile too because it should be one way
to resolve the key right again I'm gonna
quibble with wording because semantics
matter like that they all have to use
the same means of resolving the key that
doesn't mean they're from the same
profile it means that they're sharing
the structure of the list of the set
Jori I say this because I think there's
going to be some identity related sets
that you know some are from risks some
are from other working groups some might
be from other identity contexts but all
of them might for instance do the key
resolution in the same way that
an ID connect does where you look up
from the issuer a place to get the jwk
set and in fact that's not just open ID
Connect now that's also specified in the
oweth metadata document right so part of
why I wrote down the requirements for
profile writers is to capture things
like that very point and I call out that
determining key ownership is one of the
most important semantic things that you
have to say how to do that said there's
going to be profiles that do it in
completely unrelated ways just like jaw
is now used in some non identity
contexts including for caller ID for sip
calls and whatnot which I only learned
about because I happen to be one of the
designated experts and they registered
the claims and Shawn Turner and I talked
about it and I said okay that looks
great but their key management is
completely different which is fine and
so sets from that world or from worlds
that may not yet exist can and probably
will do key resolution in their own ways
I just want to note one concern
consequence here which I think we have
to live with is the fact that we won't
be able to write a generic set parser
and validator without having intimate
knowledge of profile without having what
intimate knowledge of profiles because
that's actually going to be that's
always correct because you must
implement the validation rules and the
processing rules defined by the event to
correctly use the event so I think
anything that tries to be a generic
parser can be written but what it will
actually be is a big case statement that
you know may share a bunch of branches
for stuff in the same profile but you
have to know what you're processing
there's there's no sense in which you
can generically
an event or for that matter a jot
without knowing the the rules
syntactically and semantically for how
that application uses it your own
chauffeurs participant so so I'm a
little bit confused because what I had
the model I had in mind for a recipient
was to have one big dispatcher that
would be able to do some initial work on
each and every set including validating
signatures and then dispatch it to the
different profile plug-ins for for lack
of a better word so is it only my my
personal model do people not share it I
think that there will be use cases such
as the risk one where you have a whole
bunch of different events processed by a
common recipient endpoint but it still
is the case even for recipients that are
intended to process many kinds of jots
as a baseline they have to understand
the conventions for securely and
correctly retrieving the keys that's
explicitly outside the scope of what a
jot does it's explicitly outside the
scope of what a set does and so to write
that general purpose processor you have
to build in knowledge of the key
management regimes for all the sets that
you intend to process otherwise you have
no security and you don't know how to
get the keys
right so I think a lot of us maybe
without realizing we have assumptions
only route open ID Connect use cases
which simplifies things but if we if you
don't have that assumption then many
things don't know as a practical measure
I would encourage people in the identity
world to write a set profile which
describes the things that are going to
be common for our digital identities
such as how to retrieve keys and you're
at the JSON based world so awesome so
abet I don't think that belongs here
that's part of a common profile that
might be used by a bunch of identity use
cases right I don't even think that just
because you're doing connected you're
gonna have the same key management
scheme yeah we're looking at like full
mesh key management schemes based on
like expect explicit sort of signed
signed bags of keys use cases which will
certainly not fit into the download your
key from from HTTPS so I I don't even
think that you will be able to do a
common profile just because you're doing
connect FairPoint let me expand on that
just using a little personal knowledge I
have of this talking with Roland Hedberg
in Sweden has been very involved in
academic Federation's in the saml world
and now connect one of the things that
they're doing with this open ID
large-scale Federation draft is defining
ways to manage the keys where you're not
necessarily dependent upon the web PKI
for the security of them where the jwk
set thing is explicitly counting on the
security guarantees provided by web PKI
so life is actually raising a great
point that there's people who want
different ways to do key management even
in identity context
sure but you could still have like you
could have a common profile which
defines one way and then wait and I
encourage yes people to write that down
right but you can't assume that just
because it says connected that you will
do the same key management I think that
was the point are Michaels making right
key management is a is a thing that
varies even within profiles I'm not sure
I understood the lasting key management
varies within profiles so which work
prefers it so if you if you're doing if
you're doing connectors this thing
called um is a mobile connector
I think the TSN a yes made mobile
connected my understand is that they do
key management in slightly different
ways then then like this what is sort of
the the the received way of doing key
management if you're reading the connect
specs right so it might be you might be
tempted to write a connect profile for
Sept key validation that just sort of
looks at the specs and do what what your
what your sort of said what is suggested
that from from those pegs on the core
specs but that would certainly not cover
a number of use cases that could still
claim to be doing open early connect
open early connect is simply too too
broad to include a unique key management
it's become a big world out there sure
no no I hear you but you could still
write a base open ID connect profile and
then you might need other ones for that
do things differently right well if
honestly yeah you could do a connect
profile that validates the content of
the the this the set token right but you
you wouldn't be able to figure out how
to validate its authenticity
okay maybe we disagree here but so my
main concern so the second thing I
wanted to raise is that most of the use
cases that I've seen so far come from
the identity space right what people are
trying to survive in a wedge space
identity space right and basically we're
writing a draft which requires all of
them to undo some things and do them
differently so from the get-go we are
writing a draft which is not going to
work for basically everybody who showed
up to do something that can I can finish
okay and the thing which is not working
I'm not talking about the the the the
second issue I'm raising is the top
level single issuer and sad right so for
basically most identity use cases that's
not going to work and one of the
solutions as you suggested is to push
the subject down to the event level
there were other proposals to push it to
some other nested level another solution
I was proposed is to use two different
issuer top-level claims one for the set
one for the to give context to the
subject but basically we're creating a
draft which from the beginning is not
going to work for most of the use cases
that people are the big right now are
trying to solve right so I can see two
solutions as you said maybe we have to
write a common profile for identity use
cases to cover key management to cover
how the subject is treated and maybe it
has a solution or maybe we have to make
it flexible enough so we don't
contradict all these use cases from the
beginning I think it is flexible enough
now I take exception to your language
and it's probably just wording saying
we're writing something that's not going
to work it's not going to work until the
event definitions write down where their
claims are and how to validate them and
that's true of all claims it's not just
true of issue or subject it's true of
every claim and data value in the event
so there's nothing you know special
about subject other than in the
particular case the case is derived from
ID tokens subject is paired with issuer
and if you're going to have an issue or
a connect like issuer in a set you would
put it in the event body which we've
already said I think a lot of the sort
of angst that I've heard on the list and
I'm hearing here will be solved if we
write down sort of the one page this is
what connect identity sets that are
using the JW KS URI key management
discipline sure would do and I'd be glad
offline to like write a first draft of
that with you I don't know where it goes
I don't know that it goes here it might
go in the connect working group it might
go in the risk working group and we
could set that later but I think the
parameters of how to do that are pretty
well understood and I suspect that risk
already actually has them written down
probably by you so okay so let me
rephrase that because here is my concern
we write a draft which says that we have
only sure and one subject at a top level
and every profile that I'm aware of
will have to override that and say no
subject is not at the top level it's in
this other place right and we are at the
beginning when we write such a draft
that is not naturally like solving the
use cases for all the the profiles that
we are interested in at the beginning to
me that that says okay we're not doing
something right there that that's that's
what I'm trying to say I hear you
let me give an analogy which again it's
been discussed on the list but it's
probably worth talking about here as
well John took an intentionally very
light hand about what's required we
to find how to do the cryptography and
how to represent claims but there are no
required claims in a valid judge that
means that of course you're going to
have to have a profile to understand
what claims are present and how to use
them this is a good thing that's why it
was possible for for instance the
caller-id people and the sit people to
define their own claims and their own
key management to use jots in a way
that's pretty different than an ID token
if we you know the same people wrote
jawed says route ID tokens we could have
just said well all shots are going to
pretty much be ID tokens and make a
bunch of rules in but if we did that we
would never have gotten that
unanticipated uses in completely
different application domains and I want
us to also be able to get these
unanticipated use cases from people that
you know we've never heard of using sets
because they've got the flexibility to
likewise match the claims to their needs
so don't let other people interact here
and you guys are talking past each other
you know I think Mike you're making a
valid point which is we don't want to be
overly specific in the token
specification but I don't think that was
the point that Marius was making which
is that he thinks if what is specified
is something that other profiles would
need to change Marius I think would be
useful if you as opposed to making those
sort of general positions of saying that
it doesn't seem like it's useful the way
it is would be for you to like call it
exact you know precise use cases where
you think that the profile will need
your override what is in the spec so
it's clear to that and I'm curious if
anybody else feels similar to Ameri us
about that
I don't think it's over right I just
think it's sad I'm using Maris's words
which overriding it William Dennis say I
was actually an ask a clarifying
question of that I don't understand why
the the profile would actually to
override it because the way I understand
how John works is that you don't have to
include the claim and the event kind of
market of claims lets you put whatever
you want in there so to me it seems like
if a profile wants to define something
they can don't really have to undo
anything all override anything so well I
think what Marius is saying is that
those things that are specified as
required and set that profiles would not
want to use if I'm in my phrasing that
correctly means we require some no this
is that that's not required well the
subject sorry the subject is not
required you can use it or not if it's
just like any other claims committed but
not required so that's why I don't
understand why it is be overridden it's
just that you're just opting not to do
something that is optional so that's
your right to do and then your option to
add something which is also your right
to do in the in the event there anything
required in a set events yes
there's the issuer an audience and some
time related parameters um the second
kind of finishing I wanted to make is
that Marie she said that that there were
no specs that currently defined the top
level sub no profiles but there actually
is a profile is the only connect all the
aspect that that is using that so I
don't agree that that no one is doing
that okay so maybe override is not the
right word but basically you write a
spec where you say issue is here subject
optional is not it it's here right and
now maybe not to logout but pretty much
all the other profiles will have to say
oh actually no subject is not there it's
over here okay so technically you can
argue it's not an override maybe but for
somebody reading these things right like
it's an override basic saying no it's
not here it's over there and it's not
like saying that everybody can define
their own claims these people are not
defining new claims they are just
repositioning an existing
claim which is a different thing right
and yes logout might be fine with it at
the top level might be I'm not convinced
that for all use cases that we work
actually but many other profiles will
not just not gonna work for them see if
I understand but I think I think this is
you know what I would do if I were to
define full mesh key management for a
pro I would take the Kinect profile and
say you know ignore everything that it
says about key management and key
validation and just do this instead
right so I don't think it's necessarily
that far from what I hear you wanted to
do MERIS window so I guess if someone is
implementing like risk is that a problem
if they're just reading the risk spec I
go and I don't quite see that as a bad
thing I just like if that was your
reference document and it tells you how
to do it
so anyway I'd like to make a general
comment I think it's slightly to this so
as one of the co-authors I just want to
kind of highlight one of the reasons
that we actually wrote this spec almost
two years ago one and a half years ago
and that was that I think when you're
using jot you need to ensure that all
your use cases are mutually
unintelligible with the same issuer so I
so job provides you know you can you can
partition on the issuer but if you don't
you have to make sure like every
particular type of job is mutually
unintelligible and I think we achieve
that here with event and I think the
real value of this spec is then allowing
all of those subclasses of event like
risk and like log out to kind of coexist
with ie tokens and I think that's a
valuable achievement I think it's also a
reason to get this done soon because if
if we kind of dally around too long then
all those people that are thinking of
profiling this may just move on and
profile themselves and then we lose that
benefit of kind of having this world
where you can have you can have an
issuer that only knows about a tokens
and events and is happy that that that's
a secure and safe environment so that's
that's kind of the value of doing it
this way um just want to make that point
decorative
participant so one of the values of a
framework would be to enable
implementations to people to implement
and do some piece of code that's going
to be common that other people can reuse
right so we've got that for jots the
idea first set would be there would be
another layer that we'd go and do some
things to require too common there i
worry a bit if there's a bunch of things
that are optional and if they're in
different places that then you can't
have a common implementation that does
all of that so people don't have to
worry about that I also have a concern
with methodology aren't signalling which
profile a particular set is for and in
you know as I've participated in some of
the profiles at a higher level it seems
that at times you could have messages
for different profiles potentially mixed
into some of the same place and so I
think it's key to have a clear way of
knowing which profile particular set is
with and I think parsing the start of a
of a event in some sort of hand-wavy way
of saying how you figure that out is not
nearly as robust as a clear signal of
which profile is set belongs to him
potentially as opposed to having the
type field be first set the type field
could be for a particular profile of set
and so that you've got a clear signal at
the type level as opposed to you in the
event and that way the event is really
orthogonal to the profile which would
allow different profiles to use the same
type of event type but responding to
that particular point which I've thought
about since you talked about it with me
in person yesterday the problem with
that is if people like like the risk
people or others want to have a common
processor you actually want them to have
a common type otherwise they'll be using
the type and rejecting things that they
actually want to include if they want a
processor so it's going to consume more
than one profile and they can see is it
one of those two profiles that seems
fairly straightforward right this
hospital nice nice easy string compare
and I'll note well I thought I would go
under time the discussion has now taken
us over first so if you want to time
manage this but we thought it was useful
discussions continue on okay now just
one more clarification I'm not sure if I
it was understood where I was trying to
see yes
it's okay for a profile to override
where sub is it might not be an override
maybe specification I understand that if
there was only one profile doing this I
think it was fine and maybe it's gonna
be end up ruining one profile my
suspicion is there's gonna be lots of
profiles which will have to do the same
thing that's that's the only thing about
having lots of profiles to me as a sign
that we did it right well in Dennis
second but sub is also defined a job
right so in any case your quote
overriding job but we know we have
profiles that need it so like like
logout is using I think conceptually
though it makes sense um if I didn't
hear more as he was saying that logout
he's doing it that way but doesn't have
to but but I didn't see the Pythian
conceptually it's you it's using jot the
way jot was defined it's using sub the
way sub was defined in drop which to me
makes sense yeah having a discussion
cross the rooms not can be productive
for people that aren't here I'm sorry so
how many people in the room can get a
show of hands everyone looking at their
laptop pay attention who all's had a
chance to read and review this fact
okay if you can't see me I can't see you
okay so about Tanit looked like beeps
sorry lift your hands again now we know
is that kind of half a hand it's about
nine yeah yeah yeah yeah we're kind of
wondering we're kind of on the edges
whether we're ready to do last call on
this or not be useful if there's more
people that had sort of read it to get
more feedback and so can I make us so
yes you know so it sounded to me on the
discussion there that's some of them
sort of bigger push back is sort of on
the the overall aims of an architecture
of the document I mean it whether you're
gonna focus on the profiles or not right
and if if that's the kind of pushback
that you're saying maybe it would be
better just sort of ask for more that's
not us that's not detailed edits right
that's not you know give me text right
that's a complete rewrite that's a
refocus of the drafts if you're gonna do
that right and I think if you're gonna
do if you're if you're seeing that kind
of pushback I think that shouldn't come
with text that should come with a
separate draft I think if you're if
you're in the camp that thinks we
shouldn't be have to rely on profiles as
much no those people should actually
produce a separate draft because I think
that's a major rewrite that wasn't what
now that wasn't the conclusion I had but
I would agree we had a statement but I
don't write but I don't think it I don't
think necessarily you have that much
pushback but if if you sort of have that
kind of pushback I think that's a major
rewrite to the draft like this
and it that does that it doesn't really
help you whether you go to last call on
this draft or not right you're gonna
have to do somebody has that kind of
feedback you know go and write two
separate draft and then we can talk
about it I think what agreed if this
isn't solving somebody's problem then
potentially there needs to be something
else that solves a problem this is the
wrong tool for the job yes
Kathleen Moriarty area director so I
think once you make the decisions you
know what they are already ten reviewers
is fine it's all I wanted to say so I
don't think you need many more people
but ten is fine in terms of what I see
across other working groups okay as long
as they actually review and and it
provides a feedback so for me it was it
was clear from the get-go that we will
need profiles that we will be relying on
profiles to fill in details for each and
every use case so so at least what I'm
hearing from the from the mailing list
and from this discussion is that there
are some points missing but not at the
level of complete we architecture well
we got us one one can we just on the
timing I think we've sort of been going
around for a while the drafts been
pretty stable I think for a while and it
has means to these lingering questions I
don't want to see that uncertainty
persist for years and us never getting
complete so I think if the decision is
today not to do a working group last
call I'd really like to see a decision
on what the plan is to get there because
if we just punted another four months I
just don't think I think we'll be back
back here arguing about the same points
again and we'll have the same indecision
and in fact indecision is used as the
reason not to go working group last call
will just opechee having a decision
well I on the plus side weren't talking
about completely different things in the
last meeting the core thing I'm I see is
sort of the signaling are in which
profile the set is aren't and there
seems to be some discussion on that I
sort of
of what I've captures being the outside
thing I'm clear on Mario's points as to
how those are not something specified at
the profile level versus in the set
level but when we get a consensus in the
room what do you want to do I will be
asking two questions
whether we do want to go for working
group last goal or not
whoever is in favor of working group
last call on this graph please hum if
you are opposed to working with last
call at this time on this graph please
hum that's kind of clear thank you okay
I just give us a thumbs up yeah so we'll
run that over the list those were the
two I think yes okay thank you Mike and
next up we have Marius Arne and thank
you again all for the vigorous
discussion on the list it's been really
helpful to refine stuff and we are 15
minutes behind
right son - go to school we'll be
talking about delivery of sets so we're
going to the result we have a draft
which looks at two ways to deliver sets
one is push initiated by the transmitter
and a pole initiated by a receiver and
also defines a verification process for
for events themes I have some
definitions I'm going to skip through
them if we need them we can talk about
them during them later on the other
slides so the event delivery down there
all right thank you so first of all the
way the sets are defined and how the
streams are assigned to sets is out of
Scotford for this draft the event
receiver has to register with the
transmitter delivery mechanism and
that's how they are delivered in the
stream there are two define one is push
as I mentioned an HTTP POST to an
endpoint defined by the event receiver
and Paul where the transmitter is cueing
the events up in a buffer and then the
receiver is doing a periodic pole to
retrieve them and also has to be noted
that other methods of delivery can be
defined outside of this draft another
important note is that the event
receiver has to acknowledge receipt of
the of the events and a transmitter is
not required to store the events after
they have been acknowledged
so the first
mock metal is the push delivering it's a
very simple HTTP POST to a configured
endpoint
we have the content type the accept
header to the response content type it's
important no there's only one set per
per push per request the defined HTTP
status code 202 it's also the
acknowledgement that set was received
and in case of an error there are other
HTTP status codes to signal that he is a
very simple request example and then
there are two response examples a
success one which is trivial and an
error response which is a JSON blob also
important is the 400 status code in this
case and then the JSON blob with two
fields there and description and these
are defined in enough slide further than
the other delivery method is appalling
so the receiver is to English deep
opposed to both acknowledge and get more
sets and this to an endpoint which is
defined by the transmitter you ever
defined the content type pot request
response a JSON in this case multiple
sets can be streamed at once as opposed
to only one and also in the request
there are some polling parameters we are
going to look at so there are two so
these are the request attributes so
there are some processing parameters max
events and return immediately
max event zero means that the receiver
is only acknowledging sets received in a
previous request and it's not requesting
new sets and return immediately allows
for long pole and also the request can
have two arrays and AK array which
specifies Olga says the heavy success
will receive
and then a set errors which is another
array which defines all the sets that
had errors and then there is a nested
JSON object they are describing the
error which each other says the response
has a bigger set which contains all the
new sets that are to be delivered to the
receiver and then there is a boolean
flag signaling that there more are
available playing with the request
attributes the receiver can have work I
know variations on how it's polling so
it can pull only so that means it just
request new add new sets and it's not
acknowledging anything it can
acknowledge only or have a combination
of both and here is an example of a
combine request where it acknowledges
some of the previous ones seen on some
errors and it's asking for Ron Paul and
the response it's sending the list of
new cells these are the error codes
split and split into pages next page
yeah also the draft defines a way to
verify events basically the receiver can
trigger to the control plane which is
outside of out of scope for this day but
it can request the transmitter to send
the verification certification message
and in that request he can specify both
to confirm an announced value and as a
response to that because the transmitter
will deliver a verification event and
here is an example the URI for this
event app has to be defined but it's a
very simple event it has nested
attributes for the confirm announced as
they were sent by the receiver
just a few knows the Chicago I think it
was mentioned it's important to specify
authentication authorization and it's
just standard methods used by ATT HTTP
and some examples are given but it's up
to the transmitter and receiver to the
transmitter probably - for the
transmitter to document which
authentication authorization minutes
using and the client the receiver to
support that so can I ask a question on
the error sure so duplicate is an error
but it also says it has been ignored so
why even make it an error that's a good
point I don't know maybe just a signal
to the yeah I'm not sure
III would doesn't matter I mean if
you're doing if if they're if the sender
is duplicating stuff and you don't care
right
why even that I mean you could you could
have a another class of feedback saying
you know hey you notification or
something a informative message or
something right but but if it's just a
convenience log it and let the suicide
and figure out why are you sending
duplicates but you don't have to sort of
throw your error on the client-side on
the other side I think yes we can look
into it I don't know like it's it gets
interesting because the the transmitter
has to keep events queued up until they
are acknowledged if you keep ignoring
them and they keep sending them then
maybe you should send an error here it's
useless to keep sending them to me
because absolutely but if I'm if I'm
sending them twice it's because I didn't
sort of get their ACK right possibly
unless I have a serious bug in my code
right right but you know I can figure
that out from logs too I guess
fair enough I think debugging should be
out of scope fair enough ok yeah I think
so I have questions so two quick
questions you said in passing that you
say who you are please
Iran Shaffer you said in passing that
you can say send multiple events at the
same time with the poll facility but not
with push why is that why is that
because you know push you can signal
that you can act easily with an HTTP
status code if you send multiple at once
then you cannot rely on the start HTTP
status code anymore you need to send
back a JSON blob and it complicates the
the way the the acknowledgement work and
for example for a server sending for a
transmitter sending pushing events the
way they do monitoring and alerts is
going to be affected because they cannot
rely on HTTP status codes anymore it
gets way more complicated if I have a
good a reasonably good the network and
I'm just concatenating ten JSON
structures into one
body one HTTP body and just send the
whole thing why wouldn't it work
I'm nothing he's gonna not gonna work
the problem is we had this discussion on
the mailing list the the transmittal
will have a harder time to do monitoring
and alerts in this case right because if
you if you keep pushing individual sets
then you can have your alerts and
monitoring based on HTTP status codes if
you have multiple in one payload then
you cannot rely on the status code
anymore you need to be able to parse the
JSON and extract multiple error levels
from a lower level right it gets more
complicated okay but the question behind
the question is we're moving the
complexity into this whole whole thing
right which I think it's is much more
complex than we could have done with
just using push with post so the the the
the need for a poll is because there are
receivers were before behind a firewall
and they cannot be contacted with HTTP
right so they need to reach out the
transmitter cannot reach to the receiver
in that case so there are use cases
which require poor push is not gonna
work for them okay actually the firewall
thing is not very convincing to me
because you are expecting to receive
events from the outside so you should be
able to set up an external IP but well
that that was a motivator some people
had a use case where they the receiver
was not yes okay yeah all right maybe
the document could call that out more
clearly why Paul exists in it that's a
good point
okay Annabella Beckman the few questions
we have and comments building on the
earlier comment about the duplicate
error code it's not clear to me what
we're expecting a transmitter to do in
response to these error messages are the
the error codes that is receiving from
the receiver looking through them most
of not all of them
like the sort of errors that are not
going to be remedied through some
alternative code path at best the
transmitter is going to resend the event
which is going to result in the same
error that the only other alternative
really is for them to log it pipe it
into a messaging or a error logging
system something like that I'm not sure
how valuable that is versus alternative
existing out-of-band troubleshooting in
essence right fair enough so from
practical experience I think yeah I
think logging is the only saying the
thing that the transmitter can do at
that point but having a detail of what
went wrong from the receivers point of
view it's very valuable later when you
do troubleshooting I think would be
helpful to in the spec make clear what
the expectations are what expectations
are a seer should have about what a
transmitter is gonna do in response to
these error messages should make sure
the implementers have a reasonable
expectation of what the behavior is
gonna be at when they implement that
there are other errors will retry might
actually work
there might be some overlap when a key
rotation is done and for a while it may
not verify the signatures and then
starts working again I don't know but
there sure yes the other question I had
is we have the pull and push mechanisms
defined are in the same draft if I
understand correctly the expectation is
that an implement a transmitter would
implement both in all cases is that
correct maybe it's not spelled out
explicitly we would have to check that I
think the expectation is a transmitter
implements boat and then receivers what
whichever works for them is it necessary
to do that do we need to hold them
together like that
to be compliant you need implement both
or can you decide which one you want to
implement or choose between something we
have to discuss I think it came up
before and the conclusion was the trust
or so further
we say the transmitter will have to
implement both to be compliant but and
it maybe we shouldn't go there the pull
mechanism it involves a lot more
complexity on the part of the
transmitter which may not it may not be
worthwhile if in a particular use case
there are not going to be any clients
III could be wrong I'll have to
double-check maybe right now the brass
dimensions that it's on a similar note
the more available per response
parameter it also adds complexity on the
transmitter side I don't see the value
of it given that a client is a receiver
is always going to have to handle the
possibility that they make a request and
there are no events returned i kind of
agree the only case where it's kind of
useful is if the receiver let's say
paused every five minutes but if it's
more available stays in the loop until
exhausts all the events but yeah the
receiver could do the same thing it can
pull until you sees nothing and then
waits for a minute so I agree yeah okay
that's it
thank you Tony nedelin we have
definitely used cases for polling only
and so we would definitely like to see
it as two separate things all right we
don't have to implement poll we don't
have use cases for poll very much make
sense so two separate ones means
splitting in two drafts or the drafts
should specify that one by one or the
other I don't want to see him I don't
want to see the draft split right I'd
rather see it as one but this just be up
either one be an option but you have to
employ one of them straight well the
point is not to save our time with the
specification the point is to have an
interoperable draft and in my opinion if
we split it in two we're not going to
have an interoperable draft
so if we say that the optional for both
senders and receivers we're not going to
have interoperable implementations so
it's an issue for me why because we will
have some that only do this one and some
that only do this one and they will not
interoperate with the other guys okay
thank you so given that this is on our
Charter and most of this has been around
already and we just cut it out and
massaged it we would like to to call for
working group adoption of this draft so
we will we will have a ham on that I
will ask Kathleen acoustic thank you so
I would ask for yes some and no harm
people who are in favor of adopting the
HTTP delivery draft as a working group
document please hum now people who think
we should not be adopting this as a
working group document please hum okay
we're adopting the draft Thank You miles
[Laughter]
all right Thank You Marius next up we
have Annabelle
oh right do we have sites think we have
slides cool okay hey good morning I'm
Annabelle back men I'm going to be
talking about the other side of the set
space that is the management a simple
management API for events treatments
excuse me event streams specifically
what we're talking about here is
codifying the way that receivers can
manage this stream of events that
they're receiving from a transmitter we
and discussions have identified four
specific operations that receivers are
going to need to perform those are what
the spec is currently focusing on you
can see them listed there we have
querying the status of a stream adding
subjects to a stream removing subjects
and requesting verification the other
side of the verification event that
Marius mentioned in his draft to be
clear when we're talking about adding
subjects and removing subjects what were
or talking about there is a receiver
indicating to a transmitter that this
particular subject is one they are
interested in receiving events about or
not interested in receiving events about
what we are not focusing on in this
draft is anything relating to
registration of the receiver itself with
the transmitter any of the credential
management key resolution kind of
problems that that Mike discussed things
of that nature
next slide the the big key here is we
realize that these profiles are going to
be implemented not in a vacuum
they're going to be implemented
alongside existing mechanisms or
existing protocols like skim open ID
connect that already define ways to do a
lot of this stuff registration
authentication identification of
clients we can't reinvent that at the
set level and expect people to follow
that so we ultimately need to leave a
lot of that up to the implementing
profiles to define next so briefly we've
thrown out the term set event streams a
few times just to be get everyone on the
same page we're talking about a
relationship between a transmitter and a
receiver or there's a flow of events
from the transmitter to the receiver
over some delivery method such as the
ones that Maya's just presented that's a
quick comment there this both the word
feed and stream are being sort of
bandied about in various drafts it might
be good to harmonize the terminology I
like stream better agreed I think
there's there's been a lot of
back-and-forth in the past on
terminology here I think there's
starting to be a consensus around
streams but there are likely places and
drafts that have not been updated to use
that terminology well to be clear that
feeds and streams were actually
different but that was confusing because
people thought they were the same thing
at the other thing to note about event
streams as a relate to the management
API according to this spec we're saying
that there is one event stream between a
given receiver and a transmitter next
the other
one object that or one entity that the
specification has to define for us is
something called subject identify our
object this gets to some of the earlier
discussions of the various ways that
subjects need to be identified by
different profiles in open ID connect
logout they are going to be defining
subjects using issuer and sub in risk we
might be using that an event might be
using a phone number and email address
other profiles could be doing all sorts
of things so if the management API is
going to be dealing in adding and
removing subjects we need to define ways
to say what are those subjects how do we
how do we know who we who that subject
is so what we're we're saying here is we
have a subject identifier object that is
a JSON object considering containing a
set of claims that uniquely identifies a
subject and that profiling specs are
going to define for us so if risk wants
issuer and sub as a subject or phone
number or email as subjects then the
risk profile would would define those as
different subject identifier objects for
use with the management API next step
add some kind of clarify what I'm
talking about here you're a couple of
examples that you might see from risk
events so talk about the actual API the
transmitter implements an HTTP set of
HTTP endpoints that the receiver calls
again these are event stream management
which is the query endpoint ad subject
remove subject and request verification
the spec states that these are
independent URLs they may be the same
URLs for multiple streams or a
transmitter may define separate
endpoints or
each of these for each stream that is up
to the implementer next reading stream
configuration it's just a HTTP GET next
you'll see the simple example there's
really not much to it next in our
response is a JSON object containing
claims describing the delivery method
defined for the stream as well as an
optional events claim that lists the
event types that may be transmitted over
the stream this is a may there's a no
guarantee that the transmitter will
actually send any of these events to the
receiver
they are just possibilities next adding
a subject and removing a subject are
likewise pretty straightforward HTTP
posts containing a subject identifier
object in the body and expect to get a
204 no content back on success next we
see here with an example using an email
address based subject identify our
object next next
like I said remove his basically looks
the same next we're just posting to a
different endpoint next verifying stream
configurations again simple HTTP post to
a verification endpoint this contains a
the JSON object that may contain a state
parameter it looks like there's going to
have to be some harmonization between
this and what's in the the HTTP delivery
spec as far as what's required for a
verification event and what we need what
the receiver needs to send in this
request since we need to change
important thing to
about verification there is that it is
expected to happen completely
asynchronously a receiver is going to
make a request to the verification
endpoint to ask for a verification event
and the transmitter will be expected to
send that event at some time in the near
future the receiver should not expect
that that will happen before the the
transmitter returns a response to the
verification endpoint request here we
see another again simple example request
and response
lastly yeah good next lastly the error
reporting is just using standard HTTP
error codes next okay any questions on
that your on show for two comments and
one of instead of the for explicit end
points I would be I think it would be
nice if we had the director in point
from which I could get a JSON with a
foreign horns and then my other comment
is if we end up with an explicit profile
claim or profile signal I think we
should replace the list of events here
with a list of profiles that would be I
believe cleaner and easier to handle
so just to make sure I understand your
first point it sounds like you're
talking about discovery type of
mechanism for the for the endpoints yeah
I think that's I think that's worth
discussing to your other point the my
only concern about that would be if
there is a use if there are use cases
where a transmitter will only be sending
a subset of events that are defined
within a profile over a particular
stream and if there's a need to be able
to
indicate that up off the top of my head
I'm not 100% clear that that use case
exists so be interested to hear if if
anyone has that in mind looks like good
topic for the list yeah yeah there are
different use cases were only some
events would be said but yeah we can
discuss this oh I will look forward to
the email fad right just as a note so we
have to decide which control plane
approach we are gonna use either this
one or one based on scheme just
wondering how are we gonna move forward
at that move with this one when are we
gonna decide or how are we gonna do that
is there a requirement to have only one
control plane that's a good point yeah
so we want to have multiple ones to
define one well it seemed the skin
people were keen to use scheme as a
control plane and the non scheme people
were thinking that didn't work for them
okay um that may be more clear as we go
through the risk in scheme use cases as
well alright and then we're gonna keep
the draft separate like the delivery and
from the control plane I think as
opposed we decided I we're gonna have a
separate draft just for the control
plane is that correct we've got an ID
from on the control plane or you know
the management API and we have an ID on
that you just presented on delivery
right but the ID working group document
now of course right but the ID for the
control plane and because it's just a
temporary one and could be merged back
into the drafts
there was one possibility we discussed
it already but potentially it makes
sense for skin people to have a
different control mechanisms there have
a comm and delivery mechanism alright
thank you I think given that were
looking at having n number of delivery
mechanisms and M number of control
claims potentially there's value in
keeping them suffer
Kaplan Moriarty area director just a
request if you do if the working group
does decide to go ahead with multiple
control planes
I think documenting the architecture and
applicability for each of these might be
very helpful and what I would suggest is
just starting out simple with the you
can use the data tracker working group
wiki and keep track of this and then
maybe when the working group is closer
to final taking what you've pulled
together there and putting together an
overview document overview documents
seem to be well received in the iesg
right now as opposed to some other
formation documents and you know that
would be more towards the end where you
have all of this stuff defined and you
can show how everything fits together
but if you use that as a collection
point to guide the work and prioritize
it especially with multiple options it
could be useful good thank you yep thank
you I was gonna ask where should we put
that and then you answer the question so
if only the history provided the tool to
convert my architecture slide into ASCII
art that would be great there's no other
questions do you wanna thank you really
yes
so the distribution had been sort of
part of something been in this working
group for a while and factored out of a
previous ID the control the management
API is a relatively new piece of work
looking to get a sense in the room as to
whether we're ready for this to be a
working group document or whether we
need to do more work on that that's what
I do and that's two questions
you you found at every time this is my
first time okay I'll ask two questions
one a hum for who would like you to be
you oh okay okay okay
so first one on Hama as to whether we're
ready to adopt this as a working group
document and another home for no we're
not ready for home if you're ready to
adopt this as a working group document
and how many of you think we need more
work on this okay so looks like we need
another turn on that and so in I guess
whatever we need to fix on that if we
make sure clear on the well there's a
different question which is should we
have this as a document should we have a
control plane
as opposed to not right like should we
be doing this yes I mean it's in the
Charter but is is it worth another term
should we continue to do work on this so
how much we should continue to do work
on this if it wasn't clear from their
presentation can maybe Anabella Mario's
stand up and say in a few words why this
is important why you're spending the
time on this why we should have it as a
draft sir
so okay can I just ask I mean you're
doing this is an individual draft at
this point right you working you doesn't
need to make decisions on the individual
dress right no just keep working right
sure wouldn't be useful to know whether
you're beating your head against the
wall or it's something right that's a
different question right that's a sort
of almost a shorter question do you
think the working groups the working
group should be focusing on this type of
problem right that's a that's a valid
question right and if I was at that mind
Kathleen Moriarity area director it
could also be at this time right you
could take honest work later
this is Barry leave us the question then
is if you hummed for no should should we
reconsider that after a turn or two of
the document or not you know is your no
not yet but maybe later or is your no no
let's forget about it
that's really the next question right
well then why I'm asking that as there
wasn't a bunch of negative feedback
about the document but there was a hum
for no right so that that may mean that
nobody want nobody cares about it and we
should just they should just go off and
do whatever they're gonna do on their
own but it would be better to ask the
working group would you consider
adopting it in the future in the near
future right you know so they know right
so we're good make me do it again all
right so I will ask two questions
whether you think this could this
document could be adopted after say one
or two revisions and review on the list
and possibly in the next meeting or
whether you think this is work that's
inappropriate or uninteresting for this
group to work on later could I make a
suggestion for a simpler question just
also working group whether they think
that management API should be should be
in scope for the work Europe fair enough
then you know then if that's an that's
an that's a baseline right you know yeah
but I will still qualify it a little bit
so so I will ask the group if the
management API is exemplified in this
draft is in scope for the group or not
so if you think this management API of
the sort we've just seen is in scope for
the group please hum and if you think
the management API is not in scope for
the group please hum okay in scope but
not yet ready thank you
okay hues kisses so we're going to look
at risk use cases the once we identify
so far and the reason we're looking for
these use cases it's to have a set of
requirements for for the other drafts
I'm gonna skip over the go back just
from most of the definitions I just want
to highlight the definition of an
explicit IDP to RP relationship and
implicit because it shows up a lot in
the use cases and I think here on
pointed out that if you don't understand
that the use cases don't make sense so
an explicit IDP to RP relationship it's
where when the RP is register will the
IDP and the user is going to an or to
flow so basically the IDP has an aura to
grant for the user and photo for the RP
and the implicit use case is when the RP
is using an identifier like an email or
phone number and the IDP is the one
controlling it and that identifier can
be used in a recovery flow so implicitly
the implicitly you have the IDP rerp
relationship it's not explicit through
some odd grants alright so first use
case it's the simplest one when you have
the explicit IDP to RP event flow the
transmitter is the IDP the receiver is
DRP the our IDP connects expose the
control plane and the RP can make or the
management API can make API calls to it
and it can authenticate it access tokens
because CRP has those the second one is
the reverse one where the RP is sending
events back to the IDP just
make a note in this case this is what
the use case when the aware we have the
issue a conflict
he also one requirement for this use
case were nice to have feature is to
make it easy for for our piece to to
participate in the interaction without
complicated crypto if possible because
the RP can identify itself with an
access tokens we are exploring the idea
that maybe in this case the sets don't
need to design would have to look at the
security implications of that the IDP
can document the endpoint for the data
plane and RP can simply start posting
events that to that endpoint of course
the RP can have a full transmitter
functionality that's that's another case
now we have the use case of an implicit
IDP to RP so the the first point is that
the the two entities need some legal
agreement because the user is not clear
to the user that there is a relationship
in with them just because I logged into
a website and I'm using my email address
it's not clear to me that the email
provider should send risk events to the
to the website where I logged in also
these cells requirements for the
management API so the remove subject
operations are coming from from this use
case because the RP needs to make these
use cases in order to start receiving
risk events and there is an assumption
made for this use case that the RP is
registered VIP as an auto client even
though the users don't participate in
the dance so for the control plane we
access tokens can be used yes okay can
you jump back one slide
alright there are
I just wanna note there that in yes in
the in this case the since the Opie is
registering with the RP that sort of
adds save significant potentially add
significant complexity for the for the
RP because you have to manage manage
date for for well you have to manage a
lot of these relationships right am I
missing something and so in this case
you already have an relationship
established between the write the RP
it's an or to client to the IDP and all
that yes now you're onto turning this
around right in this case the IDP needs
to be a client or client of the office
no no no that's not in there okay so it
so that may be a mystery so you're right
so testing the last paragraph so yeah if
the RP wants to have a full transmitter
functionality then that needs to be
happen exact that's why in the first two
paragraphs said he said the requirements
to try to make it easier and not have
that require right and I what I was
trying to get to is that part of the
work on key management work that we've
been talking to to Mike about right is
to get away from the need for a lot of
symmetrical so symmetric crypto so it
would be nice if we if one could sort of
call out in some of these Q's cases
where key management sort of comes into
the profile right because it or where
you know the complexity trade-off
between push and pull might come into
this right because I could so naively I
could say that in this case maybe it's
in it maybe it's worth doing whole
because you don't then don't have to
have this this sort of reverse security
relationship I push for it should be a
good one I haven't thought about it yeah
I mean it's one of those things where
you're sort of Paul might actually be
worth it if I if then I don't have to
have the IDP registered as a as a north
as Ana was kind to the to the right
already a few of these considerations
maybe might be worth putting into the
use case document to sort of because it
actually informs sort of the your
implementation choice yes thank you
one more okay so open questions for the
implicit one what are the implications
of unverified identifiers like
unverified email addresses that's an
important one and the other one is
discovery how does the RP find the
correct IDP for a given identifier so if
you have an RP and in some cases might
be easy to map to email addresses to who
the provider is but in other cases is
not easy and we might need to so these
are these are these are problems to be
solved for this use case sure but those
are at the risk levels post at the shot
level right and then the the reverse is
the implicit RP to the IDP in this case
no enrollment call is strictly necessary
because the RP has the user identifier
already so it could simply notify the
the IDP directly but still the open
question is easier among our Mountain
norman necessary it might be based on
the implementation like each RP or IDP
my decide on that and also again we have
the assumption that the IDP is
registered with the RP as an or to
client and can use access token and this
is the reverse one again so there is a
purely implicit uski so you have two
different websites and they happened as
an example and they have they both use
email addresses as main identifiers and
technically they could do cross
discovery to see if they have common
users and then starts and agree see
that's between them obviously there's
legal agreements and there are open
questions about legal and privacy
implications for this identity as a
service use case so you have identity as
a service so you have one entity
managing many RPS at once so this
identity as a service could technically
automatically do the configuration with
all the corresponding IDPs on behalf of
the RPS and the Assumption for identity
as a service is that the identity as a
service provider can impersonate the RP
at an IDP so it can obtain access tokens
on behalf of the RT very similarly
security as a service the main
difference is that in this case the
service provider cannot impersonate the
RP and just head there are some
delegation rules so the IDPs will accept
some requests but they know that they
talk to a different entity and not to
the RP so this complicates all the all
the use cases although I'm sorry all the
control planes and the whole the scenery
would work because now the management
API will have to explicitly become aware
so I think what currently we have
proposals for a management API are not
covering this use case I'm not sure if
this is a use case we will want a
service or not but it's it's one is
important to note and on-premise are
paid so this is the one that is
requiring polling because they are
sitting behind a firewall and push to an
HTTP endpoint is not possible questions
sorry could you clarify again what
security as a service means what is
happening alright so maybe the name is
not right but you have a service
provider which provides services for
many RPS in one case they can
impersonate the RP in the sense they in
an or two terminology they have the
client ID and secret of the RP they can
obtain I access tokens or some other
means they can get access tokens and
that management API endpoints they show
up as being the RP right
maybe a dozen all the difference in the
other use case at security as a service
maybe it's not the right name but the
number seven they just they don't
provide full IDP or RP implementation
but they provide other security but they
do still manage a large number of RPS
but in this case they cannot obtain
access tokens on behalf of them and in
all case when they make an API call they
have to identify them as themselves as
being I'm the service provider and the
IDP will have to or whoever manages that
eight management API they have to
understand that there are some
delegation echoes there and they are
allowed to make calls on behalf of the
of the RP so in other examples of this
fuel has examples of this the
requirements comes from Oracle and few
hansel so I'm not aware of this example
is directly but I just can't let it
sounds like in general there are
examples of delegation when you make API
calls when you make an API I have clear
examples where you make an API call and
you say I want to make the API call as
if I was the card but I'm not the card
and then the receiver would have to make
sure that I'm allowed to make those
calls on your behalf so basically the
delegation it's clear to the implementer
of the API right would it be correct to
call it risk assessment as a service or
something like that right side is it
that different from security right maybe
security it's too wide
okay yes sure
thank you any other questions okay next
up is one of our favorite presenters
Tony
okay I'm just gonna present this is
draft zero zero and this is the skim use
cases for scenarios there are some pre
assumptions here which is we use skim
triggers and they are things that we use
to make sure that we can we can keep
track of all the things all the events
that go on within within skin processing
we also listen the skin security model
that's documented in the in skin and
then we also have a privacy aspect to it
to make sure because we are sending
information trick we are sending updates
security information around around the
net here okay and so we have to we
actually have three use cases the first
one is a push use case the second one
will be a poll and the third is a mobile
SMS and stuff like that but there are
pretty simple use cases basically the
skin client we have down there it's
going to issue commands over to the gym
service provider we assume that all the
security and tokens have been set up
correctly this is we believe out of band
stuff that needs to get done and then
what and so so the skim client skim
processing client controller will send
skim security commands such as update
users and things like that and it will
also do the the event commands at the
same time so we may want to not be
notified of you know things that have
changed with a particular user or stuff
like that so that gets also done through
that aspect and then the skin event
stream is going to kick off push events
down to the down
back to the skin client if if it detects
that the triggers have been pulled and
and you need events to be set and then
we also need a a polling in this
particular case because we have a we
have a firewall situation here and we
also may only want you you know we may
also want to have the client tell it
when it wants to receive updates it's
not it may not be advantageous to have
it pushed all the time so there needs to
be there needs to be a pull pull
mechanism here but the but the use cases
you know the flows are the exact same
same situation and the last one is just
is basically the same go ahead go ahead
next yes that's what I said and so the
last one is just we have a we have a
mobile situation and in the events may
come over SMS or some other mobile means
instead of instead of coming over to
HTTP types of events so those are the
three basic skin.skin cases that we that
we have we've implemented the second
case where the long hope where the long
polling and we do directory
synchronization via that comma
you're on Shaffer comment to both drafts
actually there's a major mismatch in
terminology and so someone coming from
the outside will not in my opinion be
able to know whether the specific use
case is appropriate for this solution
for this solution and maybe both so
could you add to these three use cases
in some wording using the terminology in
the other draft such as implicit IDP ERP
and so on and on the other hand could
the authors of the other draft please
say whether stuff is appropriate for the
cloud for the enterprise for mobile yes
Tony
yes Turk if I was an author of this I
would you're just the straight man just
the straight man here I have a question
identify your I'm sorry I'm dr. Michael
B Jones I work at Microsoft I actually
have a question about control point
aspects of the delivery of messages
through skin and the related events as
you're viewing the architecture is that
already implicit because of the skin to
context yes so you wouldn't need a
distinct control plan as Annabelle
described because that's that's already
and that for free so you get that
because we in the skin service provider
that's what we've got so you have to
implement that skin okay thank you
and about Backman or a clarifying
question so within the mobile scenario
you're actually looking at transmitting
events via SMS not just via mobile push
yes correct I think that that's our it
could be expanded to to the mobile push
but that's our current usage and the
reason I ask is the way we've discussed
delivery of sets and packaging those it
does not lend itself very well to being
transmitted directly over SMS so some
interesting questions that are gonna
come up over what that would look like
perhaps a great topic for another
delivery method would there be another
spec for SMS delivery of set if people
would if it's if that's a use case I
would assume so well but your will be
for SMS you are presenting the use case
no I'm just saying Annabel was talking
about mobile push and my question about
mobile push was just to clarify whether
whether the slide was correct and
referring to SMS yes since you said it
is then then we would correct okay I
thought you were I thought Nick was on
the mobile yeah I think as long as if
skim has the use case for events via SMS
then I think there potentially would be
value in defining that delivery outside
of the skin specific contacts agree
okay thank you so I'd like to thank both
groups of authors and however right now
these to use case documents are not in
charter for the working group and we do
not expect them to become working with
documents unless does massive demand for
that so that's the end of our formal
agenda we're at the any other business
if there's anything else no other
business yeah thank you everyone thank
you in Singapore
everyone signed a blue sheet that's
right