yeah okay I'm like Hello okay hi welcome
to sag
I'm Air Force pro-life Kathleen Moriarty
so yes we're starting with working group
reports Australia we know well I forgot
you all to be familiar with this if
you're not familiar this well I guess
you can read it or read it later right
so we'll start with some working very
did you have a report yeah okay good
didn't you up if you dragon live in
order always I know we are doing them in
order turns out ace we met Monday
morning and we have lots of different
proposals floating around on how to
carry these different tokens around into
the authentication authorization so we
had lots of researchers coming along and
providing input we unfortunately didn't
make that much progress on the already
charted items so we need to improve on
that but there's a lot of ideas thank
you so actually in Center reports curdle
thank you I also sent the report dot
thank you for sending the report I to
NSF
so we met
Thursday we actually have two sessions
why is the pre session and informal
session so this time we had lots of
contributions on the data models and
information models so this meeting
mainly is to make sure they are lying
with each other so we reached a really
good result on that thank you thank you
so I suspect me expense report Thank You
kitten sensor reports thank you lamp oh
okay I missed that thank you
mile sensor report yes so no I'm saying
you sensory for it thank you
ooofff I didn't see one comesss seems to
be a pattern yeah actually the final
session is tomorrow so the first session
we talked about wrapping up some
existing working group documents and we
also had Mike Jones present a best
current practice on a JWT
after we've what some researchers found
attacks
so we documented those and we did a hum
and the group wanted to work on that
document so that's something we will
confirm on the mailing list so if you
use JW T's that may be a good document
to look at or if you implement them
alright thank you and open PGP open PGP
has had quite remarkable success in not
getting anything done and that has
resisted all attempts from both chairs
to talk talk to people offline and try
to poke things and so we have asked Eric
to close the working group whenever he
is ready to do that and told the working
group that and hope that that might spur
some things and it spurred a few words
but no actual action Eric any comments
and I think I'm happy to do so I suppose
thank you for your service you're
welcome
and I would say happy to do it isn't
quite the right characters a story but I
know I understand now I'm just saying
I'm sad that we could not get it done
but we in fact we cannot so the other
co-chair this is dkg I'm also bummed
that we didn't manage to get that done
there is continuing work in that face
probably and if I can manage to get
people to document it I'll try to get
them to submit drafts and if they
actually start submitting dress that are
actually functional then maybe I will
come back and ask for more but we have
we have not had any luck in getting into
move we don't have enough implementers
in the group right and I think it's
certainly open PGP is a protocol people
use so if it turns out to be a case that
you have activity it's worked your
standardizing we can figure out some way
to recreate a new working group of them
DGP too I think three all right sockem
thank you for sending the report second
I didn't see one oh it is sent okay
thank you my mistake and TLS thank you
for the report and the nice management
of a tough working group session token'
yeah I didn't send a report um we met on
Monday core documents are in less
working a best call we're playing area
bring playing around a little bit in
proxy hell with a draft that may involve
some help that we are speeding in some
help from the HDP working group will see
and think we yes we did get one from
trans so thank you then we're going to
go into related working groups we're
going to do a little interrupts in the
middle of that for one of the related
working groups lino thank you great he's
going to talk about a need that we've
brought up with foreign sag and we have
a request okay thank you so in the
diamond working group
so we have the base protocol and
initially in the previous version of the
protocol we have an end-to-end security
staff and when we we publish a new
version of this one this end-to-end
security mechanism was deprecated it was
based on CMS and and nothing was done so
we are still looking for a solution for
end-to-end security basically it could
be between edge edge agents between a to
two different two different networks and
you will go through what we call a
roaming Network so you have a bunch of
agent in the middle so or you may have
end-to-end real end-to-end communication
between edge to the clients client and
server so the idea to have a solution to
be able to protect a VPS next line is
yeah so the status is that the
end-to-end security requirement is now
an RFC so we have existing requirements
coming from the mobile community so for
roaming especially but also by operators
that would like to protect their
diameter signaling so what we have done
is to reuse a previous draft called
end-to-end security but no work was done
on this one so there is a lake of lack
of resources and also like of expertise
because we have the diameter part that
we have also the security aspects next
slightly so we have in the existing
draft we have a basic solution where
it's possible to have integrity and
confidentiality so what we are defining
it's a specific AVP where you are able
to sign and another one where you are
able to group all those entities a VPS
and to encrypt them and to put this in
this in this what we call a group a VP
so it's it's how to be able to convey to
convey this information so the solution
was raised on a JSON so using a the json
web signature for the integrity
protection and webber efficient for the
confidentiality
we were thinking about maybe there is
something new to do in this area maybe
instead of JSON using sibour cosy or if
there is any other alternative so next
slide please so hi I'm here because we
are a crying help yes sorry I added the
note para other feedback
I think it's threw you off a little and
so I think that the proposal is quite
simple just to be able to have a
solution so I know that people in the
room are aware of this issue so we I'm
looking for some guys that could help in
this work so we could create a kind of a
design team and so on just to be able to
have a solution done so any any
volunteers would be welcome so you can
contact our katrien myself and are there
any volunteers in the room that are
interested in helping on this ok please
help yeah this is Jean Mahoney um have
been in the time working group and yes
this is just lingered it's been pushed
off where we're losing energy and we're
realizing we don't we can't do this by
ourselves so would like some volunteers
thanks Phil hon Baker I had to generate
something very similar for my meshwork I
it's written up but not separately from
the other stuff but I can pull it out I
did notice the problem with you with
applying Jose encryption and rolled my
own based on Jose but doing things in a
more sane fashion for doing end-to-end
encryption within a web service so so
you're willing to help ok hopefully we
have a few more people thank you and
we'll move on to the O's and I chart
from here we'll move on to the rest of
the related working
groups so anima I saw a report I don't
have a nice list marked up so I may not
know all of these d bounds oh okay
dime we just got that dispatch anything
for dispatch
okay d mark do you mark met this morning
and I guess the main thing that it's
discussing right now is whether to put
out the document as experimental first
or go straight to standards track we've
originally been figuring standards track
but Dave Crocker pointed out that we
don't know the operational effects of of
what we're doing and could use an
experiment with that so the working
group still hasn't decided that and
we'll figure it out otherwise it's
almost ready for working group last call
that's the arc sorry that's the arc spec
the D mark spec itself is informational
and it's on our cues some time to think
about moving that to standards track and
whether we will do that or not we don't
know yet thank you
deep prize HTTP is quick Netcom ntp i
just wanted to give one quick update the
network time security specification is
going to go to working group last call
this week or the current draft is going
to work in crib last call and last time
when we sent it to working group last
call the security community was very
responsive and we're hoping you will be
so again thank you can I jump in about
deep rise please so the big two topics
that we talked about when we met were we
had a bunch of fun and games talking
about DK G's proposal to D MUX
DNS and HTTP traffic on port fearful
three to the same server that's good
watching she'll go back and look at the
videos we also had a really interesting
conversation about DNS
quick within the context of privacy so I
think we've got some really interesting
feedback on that draft as well and we
touched again on how do we move forward
to look at the recursive to
authoritative problem that we haven't
got anything concrete there yet
Klaus oh good I caught you a quick um we
are monitoring the situation in TLS with
interest let's see
perk and radix oh so perk is getting
around some of the issues it had with
its double context encryption for RTP
that's getting to a point where it would
benefits from some more review well
probably in a couple of weeks when Cindy
drops is out I would benefit from some
review from folks who are
cryptographically minded and have some
enthusiasm for real time protocols so uh
yeah like I said I expect there will be
a new version of that double encryption
draft in a few weeks and then I'll maybe
pingas iagnosed or some more juice okay
and so for radix I'll just say they're
going to close soon they are going to
work on I think one more draft and get
that through the working group and
likely clothes so thanks everyone for
their work on that slider TCP Inc I
think sent one and Utah all right
we're meeting later tonight and we can
sort of got to see the light in the end
of the tunnel so bye there isn't okay
talking somebody else
so right now we've got our the the core
document that we were charted to do they
are in they've been overseas for a while
we're working on a few specs related to
the best best practice of using TLS in
email various forms and shapes but after
that we can't really see any other work
so if the security community
has stuff for you ta you should bring it
to our attention before Singapore
because after that I think we're going
to be done thank you okay see frg know
you forgot D crop okay we did yeah
curdle for Deacon we have three
documents almost done deprecating char
one and 512 RSA using edy to 519 and I
forget what the third is but will
probably be done really quick and not
meet in Singapore all right thank you
and sorry about that so see FRG okay
thank you
ir GS open proof sec so we've changed
chairs it's actually Martin about I'll
give a quick report that per sec is
currently looking at developing a
traffic analysis document that
catalogues different forms of traffic
analysis and provide sort of guidance to
the community thanks dad
at IRT F open one of the two talks is
Stephen tuck away on breaking junipers
ec drbg h d RB g so for those security
people not going too quick they might
want to go here
one of the research priorities alright
thank you and w3c we didn't have any box
so now we're going to move on to
presentation oh yes sure so we have off
from the previous one whether his work
going in a report was sent but um both
deep and Fudd yep four deep we had a
tutorial on Sunday which I think was
well attended describing on how Trust
song works and scope of the deep effort
and Wednesday we we met to discuss the
Charter I posted it to the deep mailing
list and we will also continue with the
webinars so there will be in webinar
from the Intel guides about their
trusted execution environments hopefully
maybe next week or the week afterwards
I'm still talking about the exact date
and I will send a doodle ball around and
we'll make the announcements for fat
which is about the firmware updates for
IOT devices um we actually met today and
sort of a site meeting to talk to those
who are developing operating systems for
IOT devices were the potential customers
or the potential guys who are impacted
by this and there are two new documents
out there posted on the mailing list
describing the standards effort could
look like and so please join that list
if you care about firmware updates and
or IOT devices thank you and we are
hoping to charter those at least on it
soon before the next meeting or after of
off of the next meeting I thought I'd
give you w3c update thank you
sorry I didn't realize I was on the
agenda this is Sam Wyler w3c is web
authentication working group is making
interesting progress
bringing token-based device based
authentication up into the browser but I
think the thing they'll be of more
interest to the room is we're reaching
out and trying to get more eyes doing
security and privacy reviews on our
specs if people in the room have
interest in that space and are
interested in reading some w3c specs
with an eye towards security and privacy
and maybe stopping our working groups
from doing stupid things please get in
touch with me all right thank you so now
we move on to presentations and Kenny
Patterson's up first with a presentation
on post quantum crypto we just kind of
switch laptops here
Yogesh yes for you
okay good to go
how long do I have okay so 30 minutes on
post quantum cryptography and I promise
you there are no equations in any of my
slides so if you were thinking of making
a run for it because of the possibility
of equations you can stay stay in your
seats
I'm going to start by looking at
something that's manifestly not post one
so I'm going to start by talking a
little bit about sha-1 and talk about
the lifetime of sha-1 so we go back to
deepest darkest history the 1990s sha-1
was published it was actually a tweak of
a design from 1993 there were various
attacks on shall zero in the 1990s which
validated that switch then charter was
published by nist in 2001 nobody used it
we had the first collision attack for
sha-1 and 2005 except it was an attack
that didn't provide any collision it was
an estimated complexity of two to the 63
hash or Asians is a famous breakthrough
paper by Y natal it's maybe worth
remembering that Wang was denied a visa
to come and present that result in the
United States at the time things some
things don't change very much then
between then and now there were lots of
claims and counterclaims about
improvements to this attack and you know
we estimate of the complexity in 2006
nest took the chef the the step of
deprecating sha-1 from 2010 onwards for
all federal agencies for all new
applications requiring
collision-resistant so a limited set of
applications and use cases in 2013
Microsoft got around to doing something
about sha-1 deprecation from 2016
onwards for new code signing
certificates 2014 still no collisions so
this is now quite some time nearly 10
years after Wang's paper Wang at Al's
paper I should say the best estimate at
this point in time is 2 to the 61 hash
operations to computer collision due to
Mark Stephens and his collaborators in
2015 something really interesting
happened we saw something called three
star collisions which are a precursor of
through collisions against sha-1 not
quite there yet requiring moderate
computation ten days on a GPU cluster
with 64 GPUs 2017 sha-1 is still widely
used there's lots of activity in the C
browser forum maybe some
of you have seen some of that lovely
controversy happening over they are
resisting the removal of sha-1 trying to
extend its life time is gone and then
finally we got the first collision since
sha-1 in ferry this year I joined
research activity between the
researchers at CWI led by Mark Stevens
and by Google and they finally actually
exhibited sha-1 collisions to much press
coverage and then lots of researchers
like me saying well you knew this was
coming this should not be a surprise
six point six K core years of
complications so 6600 cores running for
a year some permutation combination of
that kind of resource so brief serious
work required then what well we'll see
what happens I think sha-1 will be with
us for some time to come indeed here
here's a related graph that shows the
uptake of sha-2 in browser trusted
certificates on the on the public
internet and you see the sha-1 starts
which is the redline suddenly started
decreasing in around early 2014 and then
sha-2 started to shoot up an md5 has
effectively reach you which is a good
thing
anybody want to guess yeah by all means
support but let's make this as
interactive as you like
except please don't throw things so
anybody want to guess what happened in
in in early 2014 to make this thing tick
up heartbleed the first vulnerability
with the logo not the last only the
first ok so I think what's important to
say here is it was not a cryptographic
attack that led to the switchover from
sha-1 to char to in certificates it was
a computer security vulnerability in a
very widely deployed piece of software
open SSL okay what about progress in
quantum computing we've seen somehow
something happening and in the kind of
classical world I apologize for the very
small font on this slide I think the
slides are online if you want to have a
look at them and follow along and so
there are so many things to put in here
there's been so much progress that I had
to make the font very small so it's
interesting I got all of this from
Wikipedia because I am NOT an expert on
on quantum computing or quantum physics
I actually missed that class in physics
so pre-1994 wikipedia says that there
were these isolated contributions by
various great physicists people like
stephen Weisner her level Charlie
Bennett etc lots of interesting little
nuggets but nothing no kind of
connecting theory no kind of concept of
quantum computing as a thing that really
changed in 94 and then 96 because of
Shor's algorithm and Grover's algorithm
so Shor's algorithm basically breaks
discrete log and factoring problems in
with Poli many gates and polynomial
depth polynomial in the size of the
numbers that you're working with in
other words all public key cryptography
deployed on the Internet today is broken
if you could build a large-scale quantum
computer that could implement Shor's
algorithm in Grover's algorithm in 1996
basically gives you a square root
speed-up for search problems and the
effect of that is to have the effective
key size of your symmetric primitives so
some would say that's why we have aes
256 in the first place as a hedge
against quantum attacks and Grover's
algorithm in 1998 a two bit quantum
computer was built and three bits using
NMR in 2000 we got to five bits and
seven bits using NMR in 2001 so this is
great the number 15 was factored oh no
no no no seriously honor on a quantum
computer I'm not I'm not making a joke
here this is significant progress
because it means you have to build a
large enough computer and run it for
long enough to find out that 15 is 3
times 5 the cube ID was announced in
2005 I have no idea what that I know it
means but it's good good good publicity
in 26 2006 we got to 12 bits 12 quantum
bits 28 quantum bits and now you start
to see a runaway 2008 128 quantum bits
this stuff just got real this got really
worrying except this is d-wave
so there's some knowledgeable laughter
from the front for those of you further
back
what da we're building is a quantum
annealing machine so it implemented in
our ger in a quantum way it's not doing
general-purpose quantum computation you
couldn't use as far as we know one of
these d-wave computers to do to run
Shor's algorithm for example we do know
that google bought a d-wave machine
anybody from Google here willing to
confirm that and then tell us what
you're doing with it I have been told
that they dismantled it and rebuilt it
in their own image to some how to do
their own stuff so they have those kind
of people okay yeah true ok so back to
the real world of actual general-purpose
quantum computation 14 qubits in 2011
and then in 2012 the number 21 was
factored that's 3 times 7 then actually
between 2013 and 2017 there wasn't a
huge amount of kind of publicly
announced progress in fighting and I've
been told by experts in the field that's
because factoring is the wrong problem
to focus on we should be looking at
other things when factoring I think it's
because they find it hard to scale their
quantum computers beyond the number of
bits needed here
there instead focusing on more
fundamental technologies trying to get
them in place before attempting to fight
or larger numbers I'm in late 2016
onwards the physicists that did a pivot
I believe it's called a pivot in the
tech world and towards focusing on
something called quantum supremacy which
is actually a phrase I find personally
objectionable it has a lot of really
ugly overtones the use of the word
supremacy here and what this means is
building a large enough quantum computer
that you could solve a problem that no
classical computer could solve in a
reasonable amount of time with a
reasonable amount of resources think of
brewing all of Google and Akamai and
CloudFlare servers all together try to
solve some computational problem not
being able to do it but being able to do
on a quantum computer something like
some kind of quantum chemistry
simulation for example and so now there
are rumors there are circulating around
in the research community that quantum
supremacy will be announced at a
conference in Berlin last month Google
announced that they would achieve
quantum supremacy by the end of the year
but I think that's using one of these
well you know
exactly what I mean but let's not
speculate too much in 2017 d-wave
launched the two thousand queue which
has 2,000 quantum bits in their
simulated annealing world that reminds
me of the story of Hewlett Packard whose
very first product was called the
hewlett-packard 200 ok because it
sounded good to start with something
that had a large number it than a small
number that looked like you were more
established I guess do you a have been a
d-wave have been around for a while now
IBM unveiled a 17 bit quantum machine
sorry a 17 qubit machine and Google and
Microsoft Research are all doing cool
stuff in this area so there's a lot of
energy going in a lot of money going
into this progress hard to judge for me
so what I'd say is that to draw these
two things together is that the threat
of large-scale quantum computing is kind
of weakly analogous and go with me on
this it's pretty weak analogy to the
threat of a breakthrough in sha-1
collision finding and the breakthrough
might be imminent but then again it
might not
and we now do actually have sha-1
collisions so this slide really should
have been updated but for a long long
time people were speculating well we can
do sha-1 collisions but nobody's done it
yet because the reward is not high
enough or because it's actually harder
than we think we didn't really know
whether it was going to be possible or
not we didn't really know whether those
algorithms would scale or not to the
size required it's hard to quantify the
risk that something will happen and hard
to put a timeframe on it happening but
meaningful results in this area would
have a substantial impact and lots of
smart people are working on it and the
subpoena tremendous amount of research
investment on the other hand maybe
quantum computing is a bit like fusion
research than if you tracked fusion
research over the years it's been very
interesting that's been tokamaks and
there's been no kinds of plasmas and
firing lasers at pellets and none of it
really works yet ok
so here's some conversations i've been
party to with people in the quantum
computing world large-scale quantum
computing is only a decade away but he's
been saying that for 25 years ok in
terms of fundamental physics we're
pretty close to what we need there's
just tons of engineering work and this
is a quote from Evan Jerry who is now
with Google was with UC Santa Barbara
and he was he and his
team were acquired by Google and this
was in a really great talk he gave a
very cold headed sensible talk that he
gave about a quantum computation
real-world crypto in 2017 and you can
find that on the real world crypto
google saw a youtube feed and he
estimated also in that talk that to
break a 1024 bit RSA modulus would
require something like 250 million
quantum bits to be held in a coherent
state for long enough to do the to do
the computation I'll just remind you the
current state of they are is 17 so
there's a gap but apparently it's only
engineering work okay I we should get
into come and say that to the IETF see
how you guys react to that yeah okay so
is there a coming crypt apocalypse I
should never put a word on a slide that
I can't actually pronounce I find
apocalypse very hard to say I thought it
twice correctly now and I think I'll
quit there we don't know whether it'll
be a scaling breakthrough or not if it
comes it would be pretty catastrophic
for the internet and for internet
security so as I mentioned before shor
Shor's algorithm would mean that all
currently deployed public key
cryptography on the Internet today would
be broken without exception okay you can
break elliptic curve cryptography all
discrete log based cryptography based on
finite fields all RSA base cryptography
and that's pretty much what we have in
deployment today interestingly because
of the key sizes and the sort of scaling
properties of quantum computation
elliptic curve cryptography would break
before RSA so the trick of cryptography
is weaker for the same key size for a
smaller key size than RSA and one of the
one of the things to think about here is
that an attacker a well resourced
attacker think nation-state adversary
NSA could capture interest think okay
you're catching up good good okay a
nation-state adversary could capture
interesting-looking diffie-hellman
exchange is now okay so from my mail
server to Eric's mail server where we're
discussing this talk and what am I going
to say I think there's a question yeah
just quick question on UCC point on it
soon
Richard points this then is this been a
point that it has gotten actually gotten
some analysis besides the hand waving
these are longer need more cubits there
are like time-space trade-offs that
apply here and so even though you might
be able to get by with your cubits you
might need a longer coherence time and
had similar walls I think a detailed
analysis of this was done by some
colleagues of mine when I work for HP
back in the in the 90s HP Labs I think
if you look for the name Tim Spiller you
might find a little white paper that
describes this phenomenon yeah Paul
happened here and there was just a paper
like two months ago on this which
actually says that maybe ECC is going to
be almost as hard for equivalent strikes
the last thing I heard was you need many
more registers so you need a bigger
computer I believe the answer is there's
not agreement yet there probably will be
agreement on this within the next few
years thank you very much for that
clarification poll okay I'm as I said
I'm not an expert so if people here know
more
please come and grab the mic can give
the rest of the presentation that would
be really great I could sit down okay
so we really expect some warning of
impending disaster we would hopefully
see in research papers published
research but of course you don't
necessarily know what's going on inside
the government research lab and we know
that replacing kryptonite scale takes
time okay it took a long time to get rid
of Mac then encrypt in TLS it's still
hanging on in there I think we kind of
killed our c4 but though it takes time
and you'll still see it in either normal
corporate data centers where they don't
really keep that up to date with
security no sorry I didn't say that I
didn't say that
okay replacing crypt where scale takes
time and of course as I mentioned
traffic capture now it could be broken
later so if you've got data that needs
to be kept secure for decades and you
think there's a risk of large-scale
quantum computation then you need to
apply some kind of precautionary
principle and think about migrating your
crypto sooner rather than later okay
there's even a conference for this it's
called katha crypt and it's a pretty
doom-laden conference but you know if
you
you could go okay okay so how you should
be moving forward from here well this is
not the way to move forward let's think
about post quantum cryptography instead
what is peak you see post quantum
cryptography is cryptography and based
on conventional techniques so
conventional public key cryptosystems
these would run we would compile on your
computer and run okay on a classical
computer in a reasonable amount of time
and we believe to the best of our
knowledge that there is the known
quantum algorithm so Shor's algorithm
and so on so this area is called PTC and
sometimes it's called quantum safe
cryptography sometimes it's called
quantum immune cryptography if you work
in the area of quantum key distribution
and you're a physicist and you want to
embrace post quantum cryptography then
you call it quantum safe
okay so way of bringing other things
into your fold and extending your reach
and so on so there's a little bit of
politics here we're going to call it
post quantum cryptography the main
candidates for this and this is where I
would have had the equations had I been
braver our lattice based cryptography
which has been studied for twenty years
now I think code based cryptography
which has actually been studied for much
longer
the McAleese code based scheme uses
gulper codes these are error correcting
codes and it was already in the late
1970s early 1980s being proposed and
explored there are newfangled stuff
based on nonlinear systems of equations
they have a pretty patchy history
there's been a lot of schemes proposed
and then broken we're still finding out
what makes these problems hard and then
the latest greatest thing is little
curve isogen ease if I was a tech
investor I would not invest in elliptic
curve I so Jenny's right now they're
extremely new and we're still really
figuring out what kind of security the
offer so there's four main approaches
that the researchers are currently
exploring and these are different
approaches they could be vulnerable to
further advances in quantum algorithms
so it could be that tomorrow Peter shor
comes up with a new algorithm that
solves hard lattice problems we simply
don't know what we do know is that smart
people in the quantum algorithms
community have been working for a long
time to develop new quantum algorithms
and so far with
one exception they have no applied to
lattice based schemes or to these other
schemes and the exception is this paper
by Elder and Shore that was published
much earlier this year and then almost
immediately withdrawn because there was
a bug in the paper and it was a very
unfortunate thing because this was the
first time that somebody of Peter short
stature had something interesting to say
about lattice based cryptography and
this was kind of a wake-up for the
classical cryptography community this
was a very interesting piece of news it
turned out that the the parameters that
he was able to attack using his quantum
algorithm were not the parameters that
we would use in cryptography but still
it was maybe the first quantum chink in
the armor for lattice based crypto so
this was a significant thing but as I
say that they were was withdrawn but
maybe he'll come back with a new idea
with working with Eldar in the future we
just don't know it was also a paper
published by GCHQ in the UK now renamed
as NTSC called soliloquy and this was a
explication of their failed attempt to
build a lattice based crypto system that
was quantum immune they found a quantum
attack against their particular scheme
so there was another data point there
for you that maybe this stuff has some
ways to go before we really understand
in security against quantum algorithms
even the conventional security of these
schemes is not well understood in all
cases we have a pretty good handle on
the security of hash based signature
schemes for example X MSS which has been
working its way through CF RG and is
close to being an RFC no there's a later
scheme called Sphinx just developed by
some academic researchers a couple of
years ago and we have a pretty good
handle on how to choose parameters to
make these kinds of things secure they
rely on pretty standard properties of
hash functions which we believe are not
really susceptible to quantum attacks we
even have some lower bounds for the
strength of quantum attacks against
these things but for things like lattice
based crypto and code base crypto and
nonlinear systems of equations the
academic research community is really no
digging it digging it it's hands into
this area and trying to figure out
exactly how you should set parameters
and improve attacks and so on and I'll
just pause there because I see Stephen
coming to the mink Steven soon peril so
for the high spec signatures I don't
know if this is true for all
but for some that the more mature ones
at least you only get to sign a
relatively small number of times and
then you have to change private key that
correct for all it's a question of
parameter selection and yes and no I
mean there's trade-offs between the
number of things you can sign and the
size of signatures and the cost of
signing and so on I'm I think on the
next slide I'll come to this point talk
about some of the characteristics of
these schemes and maybe maybe I'll try
and address it there okay yeah here we
go so it's true and this is really what
Steven is hinting at that the current
post quantum schemes that we have are
not as performant as the pre quantum
schemes we've all got very used to
elliptic curve cryptography not really
consuming that much power on our servers
or you know not that much bandwidth on
our networks so typically what you're
going to find in the future is larger
public keys and larger key exchange
messages larger cipher texts etc I don't
have hard numbers for you here we can
discuss that later if you want this
field is still very much evolving and on
the flip side you actually often get
much faster cryptographic operations to
actually do an encryption with some of
these lattice based schemes is just a
matrix multiplication and adding some
noise vector so encryption is much
easier than some kind of finite field
exponentiation for example this is good
news the performance may suffer as we
refine our understanding of how hard the
hard problems are in this area as we
refine our understanding of how to
choose parameters for security so better
attacks which will emerge over time as
people tweak their code and come up with
new ideas imply that larger parameters
are needed for the schemes and that can
also lead to a particular approach is
just being completely abandoned so we've
seen that a lot with some of the systems
of equations approaches people had ideas
they tweak them to tweak them they treat
them and eventually they said okay we
give up we can make this secure using
this current set of ideas and parameter
selection this area is a much more
complicated question than it is for RSA
and ECC we've got used to magic numbers
like 2 or 4 8 bits for RSA or 3 or 7 2
bits if we're crazy about security or 2
5 6 bits for CC there are more
parameters to play with in the post
quantum schemes and it's harder at
to figure out exactly how to set them
put another way we're roughly where we
were for RSA in about 1982 okay I would
say I wasn't around I mean I was born
then but I wasn't doing cryptography
then I was just out of short trousers
but looking back in literature there was
a lot of debate about exactly how big
our RSA should be our RSA number should
be can we choose e to be small or can we
choose D to be small to improve the
corruption etc etc okay so we're kind of
in that phase at the moment in the
research community okay how am i doing
for time eight minutes okay I'm going to
speed up a little bit so where are we
right now with post quantum cryptography
we are still doing research lots and
lots of research and we're progressing
from research toward standardization and
deployment at a fair rate of knots
there's a couple of examples here
there's something called the internet
defense prize which is awarded at using
executes each year and it was given to a
lattice based key exchange protocol
called New Hope in 2016 so the industry
was like noticing this stuff was
happening and rewarding it new hope does
then experimentally deployed by Google
last year in SSL TLS you can read about
that on Adam Langley's blog it's been
switched off now it was a limited time
experiment to understand the impact on
bandwidth and processing time and
there's a huge amount are really an
increasing amount of mainstream crypto
research going on at the moment in this
area but we're not there yet and on the
standardization side NIST
last year announced a process for
standardizing post quantum public key
algorithms starting announced in 2016
the closing day for your submissions if
you're planning to make one is November
the 30th 2017 and I know there are lots
of academic and industrial research lab
teams now getting their proposals
together fine-tuning them I'm going to
be involved in one myself so for full
disclosure I have a I have a dog in this
particular fight the process is going to
run as I mentioned up until 2023 ish and
the evaluation criteria are security
naturally cost and then this kind of
mixed bag of other sort of secondary
criteria flexibility simplicity and
adopted
and you can go read on the next web
pages to figure out exactly what this
means and here's a rough overview of the
process and I don't want to go through
every single one of these deaths I just
want to show you how long the process is
expected to run for so thank back to the
days of standardization of AES and add
an extra two or three years to that and
then at the end of that we may have a
portfolio of post quantum algorithms
that we can use or nist have reserved
the right to make a decision but further
evaluation is needed okay so it's going
to take some time hang on you're
thinking I've heard about this thing
called quantum cryptography and quantum
key distribution why are we not using
that instead of post quantum
cryptography well let me let me destroy
quantum key distribution this draw is
too strong a word let me let me critique
quantum key distribution okay
so this is great right this is the
physicists will tell you this promise is
security based only on the correctness
of the laws of quantum physics and the
correctness of quantum physics is not in
doubt it's been verified to ten decimal
places
by the way ten decimal places is not
very large when you're thinking about
security parameters for crypto okay we
considered an attack at the level of
like two to the minus 120 then we
scrapped your block cipher so ten
decimal places doesn't really cut it
anyway okay and this is often contrasted
to the security offered by public key
cryptography we always said that public
key cryptography is on two quantum
computers and and quantum key
distribution would not be etc etc I got
some quotes together here this is from
Brian loans dr. Ryan loans from kinetic
quantum cryptography offers the only
protection against quantum computing and
all future networks will undoubtedly
combine both through the air and fiber
optic technologies okay here's another
example
all cryptographic schemes used currently
on the internet would be broken that's
not actually true this was said by
hubris our who is an IAC our fellow and
ex editor-in-chief of the Journal of
cryptology so he's a pretty solid
cryptographer and he said this too at a
lunch meeting of some Institute this is
an early example of alternative facts
here's MIT technology review as early as
2003 this is a QED is one of 10 emerging
technologies that will change the world
even burt cholesky who many of us know
and highly respect said back at this
time if there are things that you want
to keep protected for another 10 to 30
years you need quantum cryptography
these are examples that I gave at a talk
10 years ago this year I'm at the Fields
Institute at the University of Toronto
so these are all 10 years old so what's
the big holdup why we're not already
using quantum key distribution well I'll
give you four reasons and I have backup
slides so if anybody wants to debate
this with me let's let's do it in the
coffee break after and qkd
doesn't actually do what it says on the
tin it doesn't distribute keys it
expands existing keys and if you already
have a key in place you can expand it in
all kinds of ways and build as many keys
as you need to using things like key
derivation functions ok qkd has
significant limits on both range and
rate range is the most fundamental one
you may have heard about the Chinese
quantum key distribution network running
from Beijing to Shanghai it sounds very
very impressive but it does not provide
end-to-end security it's a sequence of
links joined together and each
intermediate point you can read the
traffic in the clear ok if you want
end-to-end security qkd is not going to
give it to you until we have quantum
repeaters but they require quantum
computers and I think I've told you
about quantum computers already security
in theory does not imply security in
practice in theories are the same in
practice they're not I think Yogi Berra
said that I'm here the idea is that we
have to build devices we have idealized
models of the physics but the devices
will have weaknesses they'll have side
channels you can shine laser beams into
single photon detectors and cause them
to go haywire etc etc etc ok so building
secure systems is different from
designing secure systems and finally
quantum key distribution does not offer
significant practical security
advantages over what we can currently do
at low cost with conventional techniques
by which I mean symmetric
key cryptography okay check me later if
you want the details on exactly why
that's true okay it's not just me
this is this is my government this is
the view from NTSC or GCHQ as was
quantum key distribution they actually
took the unusual step of publishing a
white paper about two years ago
outlining their view and here's what
they say the summary is that Q KD has
fundamental practical limitations does
not address large parts the security
problem and is purely understood in
terms of potential attacks by contrast
this is wonderful this is catnip for
someone like me by contrast post quantum
public key crypto of appears to offer
much more effective mitigations for
real-world communication systems from
the set of future quantum computers in
other words invest in P Q C naught Q key
T okay coming close to the end now what
should i ETF do so C FRG is on this to
some extent we're looking at developing
internet traps for hash based signatures
we've got two drafts in development at
the moment one is very close to being
finished as I said before this is a very
mature and West risky area but I think
that all the other post quantum schemes
are still in that kind of difficult
teenage phase right where they kind of
all keep you know kind of gawky and
awkward and likely to lash out at any
moment so and that's in the research
community nevermind standardization and
actual experience of deployment so we
have a long way to go here and my view
is that NIST's process is where the
action is going to be so in this class
the resources the Secretariat the
experience needed to run a proper
process you might think back to things
like the Julie C fiasco and maybe NIST
is not the body that we should trust the
developer crypto standards but I believe
that isn't a significant concern here
because of the very heavy involvement of
the academic community we'll have I hope
that and I believe that the academic
community can keep the process honest
and the scientific experts will all be
concentrating their efforts there with
NIST and not with IETF or other
standards bodies at least in the next
five to seven years that's where the
action is going to be so I think my
personal view this is not a CF RG view
or anything else just my personal view
we should wait for this process to run
its course
we should be ready to roll over once
those algorithms are finalized we should
continue to avoid baking in any
algorithms so we should have algorithmic
flexibility and you know the ways that
we can get that wrong for example are
having maximum fuel sizes but are rather
too small for post quantum algorithms so
we should avoid doing things like that
we should keep an eye on the kind of
follows and the protocol exchanges that
are involved in key exchange algorithms
force quantum key exchange algorithms
they're not as simple as straight up
elliptic curve diffie-hellman would be
so that because that's going to have an
impact on protocol latency and
round-trip so we might need to design
carefully to avoid impacting on those
things we should also maybe do some work
and see if our Jie could do this
understanding how best to combine pre or
classical crypto systems with post
quantum schemes to so that we get a
hedge against the failure of either type
and we should also identify and resist
any efforts to do the kind of sto
shopping that you sometimes see where
people go to multiple standards bodies
until they get one that takes their
stuff and we should we should allow this
to do its work with the help of the
scientific community okay so final slide
it might be coming or it might not be
I'm not going to try and say that word
it's possible that post quantum crypto
is a massive misdirection of the
scientific community designed to
distract us from things that really
matter like weak difficult parameters or
I don't know maybe repeated ephemeral
values in the TLS protocol or something
sigh that makes me so sad makes me so
sad folks I'm channeling Donald Trump
and we can so we can hope and I believe
that in this process will proceed in an
orderly fashion they've actually in some
sense taking their cryptographic
reputation on it they have to get it
right and they have to put adequate
resources into it because they're still
in the process of doing a repair job
based on what happened with Julie C and
that whole that whole fiasco so I think
at the end of it we will see a very
sensible and conservative ative
portfolio of algorithms of options or
four that will suit ITF needs I mean
time those things the ITF can be doing
as I mentioned on my previous slide to
make the transition as smooth as
possible so that when we we get those
algorithms Furness we're ready to start
using them okay so that's everything I
wanted to say please form an orderly
queue of the mic and I'll have to be
happy to talk to you Thanks
so thanks to the ever you can is Richard
Barnes
I will +1 the suggestion on your
previous slide that we see if our do you
take a look at this question of how you
combine classical and post quantum
algorithms are pre quantum and post
content elements if you will because I
think that's going to be critical to
transition and I think it was one where
we're developing a solution with some
degree of generality I think it would be
really useful in facilitating that
transition I think I've made that
request to see FRG before I make it
again now if anyone has ideas there
should be interested I was wondering if
you had any thoughts about like how if
there are ways that it seems like you've
kind of parsed out kind of in this
process and IETF 5cfr G processes and
fairly separate stacks here as wonder if
you have any thoughts on how they could
maybe support each other if there's
things that see if our G or IETF could
do that would be supportive in its
process in terms of different
perspectives evaluating proposals or
doing Interop testing or something like
that okay yeah thanks for that
suggestion them it's an interesting idea
maybe we could have some ITF folks
attending the NIST workshops that will
take place and feeding in requirements I
mean the sort of requirements gathering
phases somehow passed already there's a
requirements document that's been that's
been published already last year but
they're probably still opportunities to
influence if new requirements arise so I
encourage everybody here to go find the
NIST call for proposals document at this
website let me find the did I go back
past it already I'm trying to find the
URL well you can find online anyway and
there you can see the call for
submissions and there talks about these
kinds of requirements if something is
missing then ITF people should should
get involved more generally than that
I'm not sure the top of my head I don't
have any great suggestions for how we
can we can complement what they're doing
i aside from the things I already
mentioned and I think the I know for a
fact that all of the key players in the
research community in this are really
focusing their efforts on the NIST
competition maybe getting some of them
to come here and give updates on what's
happening could be useful you want to
come back yeah just real quick I think
that's a good insight
maybe that we have a little bit more the
industry players here and so perhaps
this could be a way to make that
connection between the academic
researchers and doing some more kind of
operational testing and by systems or
locals reproduction thank you Paul
Hoffman two things that are related one
when you said well I don't know how big
the keys or the signatures might be just
for the people in the room current
estimates are they're going to be at
least an order of magnitude larger so
we're talking about 50,000 bit keys and
such like that depending on signature
sizes and such obviously this is one of
the things that NIST is considering on
trying to minimize that but if you've
got a protocol running over UDP or where
everything needs to fit in one packet
you should be very concerned about keys
or signatures which leads to the next
one so as Kenny gave a presentation for
me yesterday in CFR G because I had a
conflict I've got a document called
draft Hofmann C 2pq which is classical
to post quantum where it has nothing to
do with what will be chosen but we have
to sort of get an idea of how many I'm
looking for people to help if you look
at the draft you'll notice it's
completely full of holes and requests
for for input this is not something
that's at all baked we need a lot more
work done on it we're going to be
talking to other people in both in the
physics side and in the crypto side but
in this room we are going to want to
know when should we be making the
transition and you gave a couple of
examples of soon longest term never and
it would be nice if if we as a group
could have some parameters on that so
please take a look at that and talk to
me if you have any ideas thank you Paul
let me second what posing I actually
forgot to include it in my slides and I
meant to mention all the draft a great
place for people to start contributing
thank you right but and again just to be
clear it's super super early in the
draft so lots of room for four if you
were looking for some can contribute
please do thank you I fell hard Baker
a couple of points I do have a degree in
nuclear physics and I don't think that
quantum crypto is going to work because
the sorry quantum key exchange will work
because the engineering parameters
are too hard but I wanted to one point
is that we do have Lamport signatures
and they work and it might well be worth
baking in Lamport signature roots now
because that is one thing that we can
trust and we don't need to do any more
research but going back to your original
bit about the whole char one piece
CAS actually started moving to char two
in 2008 some of them did yes and Russ
helped me push one of them to do just
that the big problem was that the rest
of the infrastructure wouldn't accept
them until much later and as a CA
I can't issue certificates that other
people won't be able to read sure and
the other side of the argument is that
they wouldn't update their software
because no one was issuing char to
certificates I mean as we know this
chicken and egg situation is often the
case in critical deployment yeah and I
did come up with a bunch of proposals
trans move through that deployment cycle
that were rejected by the same people
who then when they could see the writing
on the wall come back next oh we got to
get rid of this right now and we've got
to cancel certs that are already been
issued so I mean like the issues that
were yuri pointing to on kab forum
that's actually got to do with the
financial networks and they have a bunch
of stuff that they have put out and
haven't been listening to anything and
so we've had to take a bunch of cas
offline they're not part of the web PKI
anymore to make use of that and that's
been a multi-million dollar backwards so
it's been a lot of fun right so yes
we've got to have a deployment plan for
this and we can start working on the
deployment plan before we actually have
any crypto thank you I think that's very
much what Paul Hoffman strat is about to
sapote starting to really strategize
about that stuff well in advance thank
you
Steve well good great I'll carry things
so comment on a question the current is
I think another thing the IETF could do
is look when
we're dealing with data items that might
still be sensitive in the far distant
future and not do that
so rotate identifiers don't have long
term things etcetera set of this is the
application space maybe more than in the
ITF space but I think it's still
something the ITF could be doing is
knowing us if we're creating new long
term identifiers and those can be
correlated with things maybe we
shouldn't do this
okay I don't think it's just identifiers
so it's also the point axis right and
yes but the most of the plain text
probably isn't in a narrative context
true okay and then the comment was so
you had a nice time line and that said
you know sit back and relax or seven
years oh yeah
the question is what's the kind of IPR
situation here and are we really have we
got 27 years to sit back and relax
that's a great question and I was
reading the draft just the coal the
other day what does it say about IPR
it's definitely a consideration I mean
this is obviously aware of it I think
they don't require IPR declarations it's
not like yeah I won't say anything cuz
I'm not sure but it's certainly
something that's on their mind maybe
somebody knows yeah just wouldn't want
to come and say something about IPR and
list if you can cut it in front of your
neck that would be great
I think that we requires the API to be
declared okay declared but not given up
um yeah not given up but um we we
hopefully people it not yeah but you see
impractical worlds they'd have to think
the same and one were IPR and one we
would out then yeah I know that there
are teams who are targeting than this
competition you're making their
proposals as boring as possible from an
IPR perspective that's what my team is
doing so hopefully there'll be some
proposals that are no IPR laden we can
hope I can index holes and thanks for
the investment advice on sergeant Li
Bais crypto but I'm something to point
out that actually is pointed up by I
Sasha you base crypto is that the key
sizes don't have to be extra large you
can actually there are post con
see schemes in which you trade a lot of
computation with small key sizes for
quantum resistive quantum computer
resistance right I think that's a great
point and I promise to not put any
equations on the slide so I didn't get
into that level of detail
but my comment about it so Geneva
scripta was mostly about the novelty of
it the newness of it it really isn't an
any sense battle-tested so very new
technology
Tobias governor marwene so when it comes
to the timelines I feel like in a
quantum state it may it may happen in
2030 it may happen in 25 it may have
been in 235 or it may never happen
we will only find out once the quantum
states have collapsed so however like
when you mentioned your point with the
capture data now and read it later I
think that's one element you could you
should add one more thing the devices we
design the protocols we design they have
lifetimes of 10 years plus so I think
that kind of leaders to this may be
crypto agility Plus that we need to
design the protocols in a way that we
can update them without too much
breaking our necks in let's say five to
ten years time if that state actually
happens and I think that's probably a
requirement we need to consider now just
so we can manage the tale and if these
incidents happen earlier than we expect
them to would that be a fair yes
absolutely I think that's a great
comment thank you
thank you very much Kenny okay okay now
we're going to talk on pretty easy
pretty easy privacy not as easy to say
by Volker Berk house in a second pilot
error if there will be Flint I will be
bringing about very sure what else okay
I can introduce myself because I'm new
I'm photo for pretty easy privacy we
approach it trying to solve okay this is
the Mike that I can even ignore okay
my very good I have testing time okay
okay
again my name is Hawkeye I'm from pretty
easy privacy and we are trying to solve
a quite hard problem it's the problem
you users don't need to get involved
with crypto details at all to use crypto
and that on open standards um you go
thank you
so yes here we go tells when you wanna
change myself yes and we also could go
back this we also applied a a draft here
or supply draft here where you can read
some details welcome later to that next
slide please the problems we're facing
I think is quite cleared unfortunately
there's way too less privacy in the
Internet and we really think this is a
big issue because the network could help
a lot or for civil rights but if it's
still like this then we need to improve
them and what we're actually watching
with going to in crypto for users is
either it's going to propriety platforms
which build some system which works
quite well but it's
no one knows really what's behind the
curtain and on the other side we have
open standards which are yes basically
for email some others and which are
quite hard to use so that's a situation
we we found and that's where we want to
improve and another one is we really
believe that ever deserve gaining more
users okay next slide please so this is
an just an example of things we're
actually working on and we need answers
for I want to go to all of them but
basically you can say there is lots of
missing interoperability here which gave
us the idea to talk to you guys if you
want to help you and there's also things
well we have basically either web of
trust idea which as a privately activist
I really dislike because the web of
trust means publishing in the social
graph and this is actually exactly not
what privacy want and on the other side
we have the hierarchy of x.509 which is
enterprise view way better but which
ends up with rest anchors which make
issues so our idea is that we start to
do everything peer-to-peer and not
server based and this is the core of the
pipe idea having a peer to the
implementation of everything and we also
want to add things we are already
working on it which is hiding metadata
up supplying a platinum 'ti and
anonymity into our implementations and
into other implementations so this means
extending format extending protocols and
so forth and one really important thing
which totally underestimated in my view
is we we never managed to find a real
sign of identity management so we have
very different ways to manage identity
and at least we need a mapping or we can
even define what tune immunity means in
a technical way so
yes so what we want to achieve is a
common concept to exchange keys and
signal trust until the user the users
type is a very user centric project we
compare the result with web browser guys
do that means we end up with something
like a traffic light semantics next
slide okay
so what are those guys already doing we
already have an implementation of
automated key management locally and
between devices let's automate the key
management we mean completely to be
women generation revocation of keys we
call a key reset which is a little
complex thing so I need your keys
because and we already implemented a
three-stage frustrating concept we
implemented as men of BGP because open
standards highly important for us we
want to be as comfortable as possible we
implemented message formats which have a
little more privacy properties we
implemented a first version of what we
call key thing which is synchronizing of
keys between the devices one user is
owning that means I have let's say a pet
and a telephone and the laptop and I
want to share the same keys on all my
devices but no one others should have
the keys of all these reasons so we
implemented that and we created adapters
so you can use the implementation
because of what we are doing is free
software in common languages where
applications are built next slide please
what we also did is we just implemented
applications to show that this is
actually working and you can just
download and try it out so we did it for
a couple of platforms and what is still
missing is we have a deal with the new I
think it was first time in history that
new actually is giving our property and
instead of techadon and first guys they
did it is us we actually co-owning now
we have ownership on the new net asset
foundation and we are building with it
the DHT base onion implement a
based on the subsystem of new net which
is cork added and yes we have way more
work to do because we need to
synchronize more things so for example
we already synchronize these would be
nice to also have to trust synchronized
if you trust something on one device it
would be nice that it's trusted on the
other device for this reason next slide
so this is an example of that key sync
topic how it's working basically we yes
we are using isn't one and you will kill
us or that already happened
there's a very good reason why we need
terror because we need it as small that
it fits in a Twitter or in desmos
usually that's really the boundaries and
that's the thing we found which actually
works there and we are doing key thing
with such device groups also already
multi-platform and the green box is what
we are already implemented and now we'll
want to propose we will write the wrap
so it as internet then and the missing
things is what we actually doing work
next slide so we can you guys help us I
hope or we can be a new member of the
family which I hope more this is of
course there is a draft for mine based
message format which is from the ITF and
we already implemented that for being
compatible in our engine but
unfortunately this draft has nature
issues in our concept and yes let's say
we are not very happy on it that is the
reason why we will do another one and
let's work on that and we have the hope
when we design network protocol families
which could be helpful not only for
pepper for many many protocols like
doing a peer-to-peer kissing
implementation we have the hope that we
can make a standard that this really
works over platforms and protocols yes
also the mappings you know we are using
email and several in england
communication of things like Laki sync
and
oh we want to standardize that so and we
don't get into the mess that the
different implementations will not be
comfortable and there's even things like
URI schemes we design because internally
we are using your eyes for addresses and
next slide please
there's also a lot of future topics we
hope to find people being interested in
the ITF which is identity mapping
kalenna mapping as already mentioned and
also what we call key many key mapping
which is we have text message transports
we call them transfer the email isn't
transport for pep which means we have
such things where a PKI is just a huge
and you cannot use it on such small
things think of SMS is a primitive
example and so we have automatical
mapping onto symmetrical temporary keys
and of course we are also working on non
mind message formats I already mentioned
Trevor I don't know how much they love
it next slide so what is our hope to
find here yes we really want
interoperability and and I think this is
the right place to ask for it and of
course we need lots of critics we need
your hard critics because we are just
doing it on our own and just put an
implementation on the table here and it
would be nice to hear the opinion of
experts in these fields where we are
right and maybe a wrong right and what
we also hope is a pet foundation is way
too small to offer a management of of of
open standards so we have to hope that
the ITF want to jump in and because I
have no clue of the ITF I'm very happy
right people helped me it would be so
nice if we get some guidance furthermore
how to achieve something like that next
slide please
actually I believe that the comment that
just came into my yes please
would would reflect now turns owner has
the pet foundation ever taken a look at
the work in the Utah working group with
regard to email security reporting and
UI / security improvements as far as I
know pep is implementing a kind of
overlay for popular clients based on
other as
or TB genes of PGP Utah meets later on
please join so I believe he's suggesting
that that would be one place that meets
the requirement in your last slide last
bullet okay it's where would this take
place
Utah appears to be one side place well
that's great input thank you I think
we'll do that okay
so because I only have a quarter of an
hour I know the projects way too complex
will explain it in a quarter of an hour
I would love to end my people we do a
barb off in room Terrica this evening
and if you have time feel invited and
this for sure will end up in a bag I can
guarantee that thank you
[Applause]
hi paultalkers
so I'm not exactly sure what you're
proposing are you is this an effort to
strengthen a whole lot of protocols
within the IDF to do better security or
are you suggesting that this is a whole
new federated area that we're building
or are you some new centralized phone
book that has all these privacy and
anonymity features inside like I'm
really confused okay first we never
centralized we do only peer-to-peer and
there's no central infrastructure and
the pet foundation is managing nothing
okay so then hi I'm Edward Snowden
here's my identity yes
which is possible because we don't
manage identities I talked about mapping
of identity management of other people
which they do in different ways into
each other so there is interoperability
it's not meant that pet foundation will
not provide a namespace where you can
register that's not what you're doing I
confused you even more oh well okay so
Martin something that actually helped a
little bit I read your draft I've looked
at your website in some detail and I
have to confess that neither of those
things
me that the slightest bit understand
what you're trying to do I saw some
statements about grand principles and I
saw some code but I didn't see anything
connecting the two of the militancy in
architecture or anything I think you've
actually got a lot of things that you're
asking us to do here in this
presentation was really quite helpful as
well in helping me sort of understand
where you you're going but I that what
you're going to need to do is talk to a
few people here this week and and I
think unfortunately I'm occupied
otherwise for the barb off but I would
love to come but you need to ask those
people for help because you're actually
asking for a number of different things
yes and what we what the people here
would like to see is how the what your
goals are and very in a very concrete
way how those goals fit together if you
have an architecture what that
architecture looks like and how the
various pieces fit together and where
you have identified deficiencies in the
individual protocols that you're using
what those deficiencies are and how you
propose they would be fixed and this is
a massive project they have to say the
number of things that you had on these
slides is frankly frightening a bit and
it would be a respect if you can make
any progress on this at all there's
working implementation already which you
can download and trail so um
I caution that there's there's a very
big difference between implementing some
code and shipping some code and actually
getting to the point where you have
interoperability and that's a long hard
battle and I roundly congratulate you
for even attempting that thank you well
thank you and you are still right though
it's really a hot petal up to the hand
Baker yeah I I've been following this
for quite a while now and I like it and
I just like to point out at the moment
there are a lot of usable secure
end-to-end messaging mechanisms around
you know we've got signal what's at and
so on there are two problems of that one
is that they're all single silo models
so in order to talk to somebody who's on
signal I've got to get signal yeah and
so that that immediately cuts down the
community I can talk to the other
problem that you have is that they're
all being sold as ways around government
coercion and the thing is that if you
require everybody to run the same app
from a single provider the application
is a point of coercion even if your
crypto is end-to-end secure yep and so
if we're going to get to the point where
we have a system that is resistant to
government coercion it's got to be based
on open standards such that they can the
implementations can be audited and the
protocols have to be designed in such a
way that when you are dealing with a
messed up version of the a coerced
version of the application it tries to
talk to a non coerced then it's got to
become apparent and one of the things
that I had when I talked to somebody
very senior in one of the agencies
formally his advice was nobis nobody but
us in that the thing is that they're
very willing to mess around with crypto
and applications or whatever but they
are very adverse to having their messing
up being detected sure and so that's the
thing that we've got to work for whether
this I've got problems with this
particular implementation I think that
maybe we need to go to a consensus
algorithm that allows us to centralize
without being centralized that these
good work
Thanks thank you thank you
so next up we have three trees and I
don't want to try to see your last name
on certificate limitation profile yes
next places all right on my laptop I
will speak about my proposal to
standardize the application level
application supported the list of
certificate limitation except this
current state offer trust is in picker
volt is mostly divided by RFC five to
eighty we have binary model of trust we
have set of trusted sees we have serial
and the civilization and we have sage
rave and revocation the say driven
revocation does not always fit the
purposes of real world for example here
at the link to a presentation made for C
browser forums next slide please and one
of the most significant cases of not
fitting current model to the real world
is the case of Google versus semantics
when Google found that semantic
misbehaves the company suggested to
limit certificates issued by Symantec it
suggested to reduce the accepted
validity period the to greater distrust
to current trusted semantic issues
certificates and so on so forth and even
to remove
a recognition of external validation
status for semantic issues certificate
next slide please
now when application wants to limit the
trust it has in fact two or three
options
well application can specify which
processes are valid for in its context
it can turn off serial and SSP
validation and we have problem water
shall we do when SSP is not available
and in case we have flexible we need
flexible limitation in for example when
one of these too-big-to-fail we can we
have to record them next like this
I propose a solution certificate
limitation named certificate limitation
for a file it's a list that can be
distributed with the application or by
the application as a part of application
bundle it should have serial like syntax
it should be cryptography designed and
evil this proposal finds interest and
implemented the users total application
can use shared code base instead of
application level hard coding this will
allow to avoid some some common mistakes
in validation next slide please
so water can be stored as examples of
such limitations first we should say
whether the limitations are applied to
certificate itself or its dependence on
the chain of trust and for example we
can say that we should not trust
difficut issues after this other date we
should not trust the certificates
matching the profile
after the concrete date we can limit the
validity period of certificates we can
say which x.509 extension should be
ignored we can say which they wish
extensions should be required to trust
the certificate for example for replica
is the common case is a certificate and
parents related extensions we can as it
was suggested many times limits that my
name's by the essay like nay like name
constraints next slices if the employer
the opposite implies changes to the
verification process after building
change chain of trust we go through it
and apply limitation to the matching
sets and if specified in the profile we
apply them to is the standards if we
find that the certificate should not be
trusted we stopped verifying and return
that it's entrusted next slide please
and so instead of hard-coding main
limitation at the application level we
can limit the very small set of checks
that we have self in use that the Selphy
you operate is fresh enough to avoid
rollback attacks and the SLP is signed
by correct trust unsure thank you very
much
[Applause]
I'm done some time that the agenda
doesn't have open link to a draft sorry
my fault I'll provide the link of those
requests to the chairs oh yeah my fault
yeah um so I don't know what this is but
having said that what exactly at the mic
I certainly haven't read this but you're
describing a number of things that has a
significant amount of overlap with a
number of existing deployed mechanisms
like public key pinning and now we
implement a thing called one Sorel
there's been a proposal to use recursive
bloom filters in combination with the
certificate transparency log to have an
exhausting exhaustive list of
certificate revocation zhh why would
this be superior well their certificate
the the serial profile is say drivin for
example sorry I'm Anderson the CRL are C
drivin the CRL should be shipped by C
this profile can be issued by the
application author this thing the one
serial does yeah yeah yeah so there are
application then Richard Barnes there
are application vendors doing this today
so a chrome google for chrome produces
crl sets which are basically largely
overlapping with kind of a limited
subset of the functionality you
described and mozilla produces a thing
called one crl as Mark mentioned for
Firefox and so the question is those are
proprietary things but they're between a
vendor and its applications so I'm
curious like what's the value of
standardizing this and adding us all
this additional functionality well yes
it's a signal from functionality so the
one you described but it's just the try
to formalize that proposal syntax so
from all eyes that centex hi this is
Jane you can do more with Asia you I'm
also working the Debian project
I don't know if you're aware of the p11
glue project which has a storing trust
policy specification they've been
working on that fits what you're doing I
think almost exactly and the use case
Richard is that there are a bunch of
different things that actually check
certificates and the rules are subtle
and so if you can actually build a
particular API then you can encourage
people to not rewrite their own so it is
it there is I think definitely merit in
this kind of work but there is existing
work that does this and I'd be happy to
like try to point you to it and connect
to it it's useful so thank you very much
it's all the great rich solve
I guess opener cell populations yeah
it's great that two or three programs on
the Internet can do really fast and
really precise checking of revocation
but I'd like to see this extensible to
all sorts of things so not just the
browsers but there are many web PKI
programs out there so I support this
would be interesting to come up with a
standard data format I've had some
discussions some of the Linux lenders
about doing that so yeah I encourage
this yeah Londyn Thompson as someone
involved in other projects that has one
of these things we'd certainly be
willing to participate
we already collaborate with Google who
aren't who runs one of these things
opening up a standard for this wouldn't
necessarily deal that onerous and I
think we'd be open to that so there's
Richard Boggs again so the thanks dick
is you for the clarification I think
yeah I can see there could be some value
to this I think at least it's soft
prerequisite for this work is going to
be well a prerequisite for the work to
be successful is going to be some notion
of who is trusted to distribute this
information in the you know vendor to
its application space it's kind of clear
because you trust Google for Chrome you
trust Mozilla for Firefox it's not clear
what you would do for say open SSL or
Debian so it seems like there needs to
be some work done on that aspect of this
problem as well if it's going to be
worth developing a format Eric Ries
Carla from the floor somebody else works
one of those projects
the there actually are two problems to
solve one problem that the policy
problem of indicating like which anchors
you trust and which intermedius to
revoke and the other is to address the
problem of energy certificates and the
and the problem there is data
compression because the number of road
initiatives is far too large to actually
send over and any format books like this
at all so so in order to solve the
entire problem you've got to solve that
problem as well very much work on that
well for the first problem I expect that
the trencher will be distributed with
the application that implies using
selfie for example hard coded and the
checksum but yes it's a common problem
of distributions on the trust anchor and
the I hope we can use a common method
for it sure what's a little taker
problem is actually harder in the
identity the inner be distributive
hard-coded actually is terrible it makes
it very very hard for a new ca10 to the
market so I'd almost rather had to solve
undecided i which in solving revoking
your mediates and adding trust anchors I
might actually further the second one or
adding the first okay so thank you to me
cheering could you send a link out to
sag and I will update the owner to
include it as well
I will send the tag thank you very much
thank you and now we have 20 minutes
left about for open mic Wow
what could be it could be something
different hi Steven viral so there was a
bit of an outfit yesterday in the
devastation and hopefully we killed off
one one more bad idea and so what I
without getting into the details of that
which I don't think are right here and
the tls working group are continuing to
beat them more bad idea fairies I guess
and if to tell that's why we went crazy
I think that wouldn't be in their
charter and what they would need to
reach Artur to do the crazy thing and
also I think you heard from Lars and
from Kenny that clearly such such
changes TLS will have big impacts
outside one working group and outside
the security area in the other parts of
the IDF so I'm just wondering what you
guys think about it
so nothing's been adopted yet there's
still discussion I think it remains to
be seen what will happen if new
proposals will come to the table that
maybe are better and maybe they have
nothing to do with TLS as one thought I
had if we're something specific to the
data centers perhaps that's one thought
that I had after listening to some of
the conversations and you know so you
know cueing off of other people's ideas
and thoughts you know maybe there's an
opportunity for something data center
specific and then you could design just
what you need and it would interfere a
TLS or you know our internet level
applications for encryption I know this
one thought I had but I think make sense
as well yeah but on the issue of the
working group decides right so what
patients still happening so I guess the
question is the specific question for
you is if they adopt something like this
do you consider that within their
current charter yeah I do go back and
reread the Charter I'm sorry
I will I can suggest an answer what
would that be
ami I would have to go back and reread
carefully as ad so and obviously you
know we follow what the working group
wants to do so we'll see what they
ultimately decide right so there's more
conversation happening right after I
said yeah no speaking not as ad I don't
believe that draft cream would be with
details working group turner um I
present right okay so which means that
if they did try and do something crazy
like that it would need a return because
of the reason is because at that point
the ietf gets to have a say as opposed
to just give people in one room or the
people on one madness
the reason was very precise about this
is as possible some other thing might be
within turn ground I don't think I don't
think Drive green however will do any
charter right okay any other questions
sorry probably less interesting but
still back it back to Kenny's the
presentation there was the quantum
random Oracle mentioned in fear fearful
tree and you guys need theoretical
models to prove security so I wanted to
ask probably your personal opinion on
whether these models exist are reliable
and something that that NIST can base
and the evaluation on I don't know think
about this Kenny yes yes and yes is the
answer so yes they exist what was the
second part again but there was
definitely three yeses our stable
reliable well the quantum random Oracle
model is something we're still getting
our heads around there's a few experts
in the world who know how to work with
it but the group of people who can is
growing your time
it's basically an extension of the
random Oracle model which is some kind
of abstraction we use for modeling hash
functions in security proofs taking into
account quantum capabilities anniversary
so it should become a standard tool for
the analysis of all the nist proposals
and it is something that this can rely
on and used and yes i think so
hope that helps anything else all right
enjoy the rest of your day thank you I
appreciate a usual I'll talk generally
so I I really like people to get it