good afternoon I hope you have recovered
from your lunch
yeah at the think you thing research
group summary meeting right now yeah I
have to it's not working I have to go
through the usual things the note well
applies and I hope you cover all the
administrivia we need a Java relay you
can do that somebody who is on Java
Thank You ginger listen so maybe the
most important part of this slide is we
tend to have repositories for every
meeting and this is the repository for
the the summary meeting so this is where
we put things of course there are also
the meeting materials but the repository
sometimes has additional
information in it so you may want to
note down that we are 2017 - ITF 99 this
is weird
I think there's so much 2.4 gigahertz
activity I have a slide on that later on
so what we want to do is give a quick
update of where we are with a research
group also give a quick report from the
workshop we had over the weekend and
then go into a two subjects that we
started discussing in Chicago into
breakout groups and we want to see what
we got achieved in the meantime and if
we have time at the end then maybe we
also can talk about future activities
okay just to remind everyone the thing
to thing research group is an IRT F we
serve food so we are not the ietf here
right now we're in the IRT F and what we
are trying to do is look at research
issues that are coming up now that we
have all these wonderful I would be
standards that we created and the vision
behind all that is to get an Internet
we're low resource nodes things
constraint nodes can communicate like
any other node on the Internet of course
they cannot do all the things that the
big powerful and power-hungry nodes are
doing but they can do their job as
foreign fully fledged citizens of the
Internet and of course within this we
are focusing on issues that have
opportunities in IETF standardization so
just to give an overview of what's going
to happen next
we plan to meet on the weekend before
the riot and I see any cluster that is
happening in Berlin this September
so we are going to have a work meeting
they're looking at various activities
that we are moving forward but one
single topic topic that we are focusing
on and on November 10 we are meeting in
Singapore with OCF ocf was kind enough
to actually put their face-to-face
meeting in collocation with the IDF so
maybe we can get even more and even
closer collaboration going on with ocf
but of course ocf was represented at the
workshop the week ended I think we have
a lot of useful interesting discussion
we are also starting the planning for
2018 we haven't really fixed anything
yet maybe a workshop at a security
conference that is being planned by w3c
web of trainer things is also an
opportunity for us and it also looks
like Montreal will be a good place one
year from now to have another working
meeting but yeah what what other
opportunities we find out really we'll
have to see
the meeting will be hosted by the Free
University and I read my other
photographer yeah it looks like a really
welcoming institution here I've been
there so I know how it was like really
but anyway it's a pretty nice building
in particular the two days they have
sunshine there and yeah it is nice okay
so the reason we have put this on this
date is that a lot of people are already
meeting for the riot summit which will
have happen the next days right is a
operating system that is quite popular
in several communities including the
research communities for IOT and the ACM
ICN will happy after that
so one thing we might want to open up as
a new topic in Berlin is coexistence
we had a breakout group in Chicago that
discussed coexistence and we can
probably get a few research
contributions on that in Berlin
basically the the problem is that most
people who think about IOT networks
right now think most people who work on
those think that they own the landscape
but in reality of course we have all
these various networks both sharing the
common resource of the spectrum and
sharing common infrastructure for
instance common IP and works on which
they might want to send multicast
messages and things like that so it's
just interesting to see what happens
when we put all these IOT networks and
those 50 billion nodes out there will
these IOT networks be friendly to each
other so it's really like like the first
people who build cars they empty
Rhodes essentially to get these cars
going and now of course cars have
seatbelts and so on so yeah how is the
more crowded landscape going to look
like and how particular can we avoid one
network presenting catastrophic
interference to a different network
without having intended to do so so this
is a topic for Berlin and those people
who were in Chicago and discussed this
topic maybe are interested in
contributing to that now next item on
the agenda a quick report from the
workshop this workshop was follow-on to
the iaat CI a B workshop that happened
in March 2016 and we try to get together
the experts that work with instead of
developing organizations that
standardize data formats for IOT
interchange so this was not a formal
meeting between standards organizations
this was a meeting between experts who
want to get something done in these
standards organizations and and it was
surprisingly good meeting thought it
wasn't like everybody had the lawyer
sitting beside them watching that they
didn't say too much and so on which
which we all also have seen in meetings
of this kind of the materials from this
meeting are in another you'd have
repository again under github.com /
teacher TRG 2017 - or 7 - wish we had
basic common understanding after the IRC
workshop last year but we had no not
good idea how we would turn this into a
working collaboration and this meeting
the underlying theme of this meeting was
to look closer at what are the areas
where it's worth collaborating on and
how much we actually get this
collaboration going so was mostly
technical but we did talk about ways of
working so the first thing you need to
do in this space because there are so
many organizations that do something
that is of interest of impact in this
area you you need to understand what
these organizations actually do and they
are all different they all are covering
different parts of the landscape there
of course also overlapping but it's also
interesting to see that a group that in
their marketing materials of courses we
group that this everything IOT in
reality has a certain focus and is very
very much interested in working with
other organizations that have a
different focus and so they can be a
mutual contribution so we actually
started collecting these safes
inscriptions you can find a snapshot of
that on the wiki Vettes that comes with
the workshop repository and of course
you also can fix that because it's a
wiki so a second thing we decided we
wanted to do but we didn't get very far
with and the one and a half days was
collecting a corpus of use cases and
examples now interestingly many
organizations have such corpora
but to actually pull this together and
structured and so on you need to solve
licensing problems so that actually is
something that we also we have started
putting together a glossary of relevant
charms and want to put together
references to relevant tools of course
this is
environment in which foods play a big
role and anything that is available for
facilitating the the work that was
needed here is a health and another
thing that the research community often
this is neglecting a little bit is we
really want to collect things that
didn't work so well and maybe also why
they didn't work so well so we can avoid
falling into the same trap again yeah I
talked about licensing so we to
understand licensing terms and the
impact in collaboration and in
particular for data models which
essentially need to be merged to get an
overview of what's going on in one
I or T environment those licensing
whether those models usually have
license terms which are a little bit
opaque and hard to find out so maybe one
result here could simply be a
machine-readable taking of those license
traps now there are taking schemes for
license terms that are used in other
environments and we have to find out
which are the properties of such as
taking steel that we actually want one
other thing that also is important here
is not everything has to be done by
everybody so there is a lot of
protective by and trilateral
collaboration going on and it would be
useful to know what is going on and how
this is being done so other
organizations that are interested in
computing contribution there can can
find that out and I can do that
yeah there are a few technical goals
that maybe are a bit more work than just
collecting things so one aspect that
came up repeatedly is that applications
often are interested in the composition
of various information resources
available that is not exactly what has
been defined by standards so far so I
have this environment sensor over there
and I really only need the humidity and
the temperature but I'm not so
interested in the co2 level right now
how do I get this information in a way
that is reasonably efficient and yeah
you want to be fine these compositions
and then of course you want to have the
protocols for fetching it observing
those compositions or service objects or
however you call them so this is
something that there is underdeveloped
in in the current productions we also
found that things that are called
metadata often only get second-class
treatment well that starts with the term
we had approximately twice as many
definitions of metadata then we had
participants so we need to define what
what metadata actually means or what
kinds of metadata of interest here and
find good ways to express and deliver
those metadata and it's interesting that
many metadata actually are contextual so
they are not necessarily created or
maintained at the same place where are
the data for those metadata are created
or maintained so we find also have to
find ways to plug this yeah and there's
lots of other things we can do to
facilitate
operation and one of those is for
instance just doing experiments in
module translation and in translation of
data between different models into
different kinds of translation now how
do we get there
well first of all as with every such
workshop where you bury a little bit of
common infrastructure how we have that
github repo we have wiki's we probably
will define further wiki pages and
repositories but you will also collect
other tools for instance one I authorize
it will for collecting models and while
this is a tool that is closely
associated with ocf one of the
participating organizations it actually
has a wider scope and we want to
exercise using that word or find out how
that works and we may want to have other
tools and one thing that repeatedly came
up was registries for identifiers of
course there is INR but there's also and
every organization has their own
registry and sometimes those are too
heavy weight so how there may be more
lightweight registries 520 fire
self-interest to make this happen we we
will have monthly phone conferences so
the next one will be end of August and
of course the objective is to get to
common plaque fests that are about
plugging things together that conform to
the various specifications at play here
now to talk a little bit about the
technical content of the discussion it
seems that there is something like
a three-layer model that everybody uses
in one or another variation and one item
of work will be to define this model a
little bit more with a little bit more
precision than we have at the moment so
there is something that can be called
semantic interoperability which means we
understand what the data mean so when
when you have a mass probe and give it
some some trajectory data you understand
that it's in food and not a meter or
something like that that's a simple
example of semantic interoperability we
have structural in turbidity we are we
have data that is complex that is will
together in different ways and where the
various parts of the system understand
the structure of the data or also the
structure of any actions done and third
we have the syntactic interval ax T so
we actually can interchange these things
we cannot only understand them on a
theoretical level now as with most
layered architectures we in reality we
have recursion so for instance if you
look into the special interrogatory
layer you actually find that there are
structures that are more on the semantic
level which we typically call
information models there are data models
which are really about structure and
then there are something like generic
data models or serialization frameworks
which reach down into the syntactical
left so we may have a little bit of
nesting here which is always a little
bit difficult to understand but it helps
in getting this model actually be useful
yeah so this is terminology work is it's
not the only set of charms that we came
up with that I wanted to focus on one
specific here there's also a number of
areas where we are just trying to
understand the diversity of the
requirements so for instance when we are
modeling data we are not only modeling
the data themselves we also have data
that are needed for security purposes
and there are the obvious ones for
anything what data do you need to
actually get on the network and so on so
lots of stuff is happening in there that
maybe not the area where we have to
focus on but yeah there is management of
trust relationships where it's not
always here with the people who talk
about trust relationships in reality are
talking about authorization and not
about trust that contrast is probably
one of the worst terms we have in this
space but relatively unexplored are the
the other four areas this is from from a
list from a fellow it will probably will
add more precision to this but this is
the state of Sunday 4 p.m. so we need
metadata about security of data so there
is there are authorization requirements
only certain people can read certain
data can write certain data but how
exactly do these metadata look in an IOT
system I took the IETF about four
attempts to define security metadata for
network management so those who have
followed the development of SNMP
probably will remember that this is not
easy
that's very easy to process
confabulation here which means you build
your metadata are true an ideal version
of what should happen but of course in
reality things do happen in a slightly
different way so this is an important
area and then the next point here is of
course if we have all these metadata is
flying around how do we maintain privacy
so because these metadata may contain
more information than you actually want
to divulge so maintaining privacy in
particular within discovery processes is
a problem and of course there are also
related problems like fear printing so
even if you think you have all the
privacy you have done all other privacy
the metadata may still reveal too too
much like with browsers which funds you
have installed case you're not about who
you are that the metadata about privacy
of course is a special case and it's
probably important to look into the
changing legal framework here as well so
in Europe we are all watching the
remaining months until the general
direction on privacy regulations
whatever are becoming the law of the
land and things are changing very
quickly here and finally that there is
one area in which I think the idea
already has done some work but more work
is needed which is the privacy of
identifiers so we still have these MAC
addresses that are are feeling used and
that are beacons and so on which tell
you a lot about who is in the building
things like that and one particular
thing we are interested in is getting
progress on an area that we are calling
secret handshake
product cuts or the year here is that
you for instance can have a mug coffee
mug that you carry to a coffee machine
and the coffee market the coffee machine
find out whether the coffee machine is
authorized to give you coffee now this
sounds very easy but when you add the
requirement that the mug should not
really divulge who you are and the
coffee machine doesn't really want to
divulge all the contracts that are there
in the background about giving out free
coffee then it becomes interesting
because you need mutual authentication
without either side giving away who they
are except two people who as we can can
authenticate and I always get that
information so this actually requires
some some crypto primitives that we
don't have workable standards for right
now and this is also an active area of
research after the workshop they Feiler
dug out a few papers so there was a
seminal paper in 2003 that essentially
defined the problem of course framed in
terms of CIA agents but even non CIA
agents of clearly privacy so you want
two sides of a communication to
authenticate to each other without
giving away who they are and these
people already start by defining this as
a TLS cipher speed so they were thinking
about implementing it and other people
have then later come along and we think
this is a requirement that is very
important for the Internet of Things
because we have all these unplanned
only for between devices and people and
devices that devices
we're just would be nice if a device
that find out where that's supposed to
talk with somebody else or not we
imagine that there are actually other
areas that could make use of this as
well and for instance one of the areas
where we also have found that they need
to do this is in detail s session
resumption where also what we use for to
be able to initiate a session resumption
without already giving away who you are
okay so the research is ongoing it's not
exactly happening at a high-powered rate
and we might want to help accelerating
that energy so this is a pretty spotty
summary of the workshop of course it's
hard in couple of minutes to summarize
it two-day workshop but you can find the
materials online and hope we will
actually be able to write out more of
the things that happened in the room
there's also a 30 page minutes document
so if you want to know all the details
you can can find that any questions
about that and also since many of you
were there in the works of so if you
have any reflections so set of issues
that are chairs wanted to highlight from
the works over as Carson City also to
day works off with a lot of topics so if
you the ones who are participating have
any issues who would like to highlight
from there we can take them now or maybe
at the end of the end of session either
way in Vegas
[Music]
let's go to the dear Jenny way ahead of
you
so Dodge is kind of says something about
the work since Chicago right okay all
right so this is essentially summarizing
our little breakout discussion on edge
computing in IOT that we have in Chicago
so who of you was actually in that
breakout dispassion team okay thanks so
this is basically the result of of your
work so if Sheila and I put this
together there is a kind of rapport I
was in the meeting minutes from from
last time
and so this permutation is summarizing
this and pointing to some additional
ideas activities that happened in the
meantime so in this presentation and
also in that we thought you will see
many say questions I hope they are
interesting you will you won't find any
answers to be honest but I think was
actually quite a productive discussion
and so I think yeah let's do some like
interesting or potentially interesting
activities that we thought this group
could be looking at how are we doing
with the slides
that looks good all right so next step
is and yes so there's a little structure
that we made up a talk at the meeting so
it was trying to understand a little bit
what do we actually mean when we say I
would teach computing soul actual
knowledge and right so firstly questions
why would you actually you know do edge
computing in IOT so what is it why are
people thinking about this and so what
we said is okay and I mean they are
they're like certain set of motivations
so sometimes access to data is delayed
sensitive so you want to have some like
network locality listing of often so in
like industrial IOT for example you
generate lots of data and so the high
volume and you need to think of three
processes before giving into it
somewhere else these days I mean many
applications are you know developed in a
you know cloud centric approach
sometimes you actually don't want this
where like trust sensitivity issues some
IOT networks are intimately connected
like like via cooler networks for
example sometimes there is yeah they are
energy conversion constraints or just
cost constraint in transmitting
continuously large amount of data to
some like centralized processing unit so
we take a whopping next
okay so thinking about technology so you
could ask I mean what what is actually
what that the term edge really means so
is there really a saying network
topology edge so something like an
access network edge is it maybe also
sound like an organizational edge there
is the immediately slightly foggy term
called computing so this seems to
imply like a mighty T attached computing
approach you have different say levels
of processing for example so one notion
that was brought up is okay so we
nowadays we have all these you know
established architectures tools in data
centers for big data processing for
example or to see to the application
design and so bringing these things to
the edge you could actually see this as
re imagine say infrastructure for DC
beautification reimagining the data
center moving computation but also
storage control management out of data
centers one interesting question is so
what are actually the dynamics talking
about so there are you know ongoing
activities for example things like Etsy
mobile edge computing so like an idea
that you say install VMs on base
stations so this is a kind of
coarse-grained se approach so you may
have other use cases and IOT where you
need something with more fine vanilla so
question is how dynamically what you
create edge compute functions or
instances that execute functions so how
the memory need to also adapt to
different events in your local edge
so yeah this a mainstream or legacy idea
of edge computing is often that okay you
have some you know I would see your car
Gateway that you know that some
preinstalled computation doesn't always
have to be the case right I mean
especially in this group we are also
trying to you know investigate say your
disability approaches like thing to
thing communication so that this will
may also mean that you want to be able
to delegate computation but we gave way
but then adjust to another thing okay
next slide please so a couple of
questions that came up so so in so in
the cloud I mean they are established
ways to program distributed applications
they are kind of tools for stream
processing and so on so how would you
say in a same or disability edge
environment actually develop
applications so that can could leverage
those actual building resources so yeah
what would be good abstractions for that
so assuming there is some you know set
of tools executing functions maybe
storage caching and so on so how much
how do you control this from a
programming but maybe also from an
Operations perspective yeah especially
if you think about enterprise or
industrial T of course you have often
also weather managed networks and what
would be the management orchestration
requirements for that so like one
nothing that was put up is so ideally it
wouldn't so the things you have to do
for each company wouldn't differ too
much from like already existing
enterprise orchestration management
systems and then yeah if you think about
your computation on say maybe also third
he platforms maybe also concurrent
computation processes perhaps
multi-tenancy how would you achieve
isolation maybe also famous questions
could come up especially if you think
about not only like one Edgecomb
platform but a say set off yeah like a
tiered model of different platforms that
provide a larger application that is
disability right so you may have heard
of certain edge computing approaches so
I mentioned the etymological quitting
activity there's stuff like you know AWS
green dress for example that's basically
Python function execution I would say so
what is actually the unit of a program
of a function is by a VM or container
it's like a simple step function so what
where do we actually keep this state
that you need for maybe sequent of
invocation of those functions so in ICN
we have a certain idea I can focus later
yeah so this whole topic of you have
multiple applications multiple tenants
yeah was for hours as a potentially
interesting topic to discuss further in
this book right so I think I alluded to
this in the beginning so if you if you
look at the existing set of tools that
already exists an API is so it's
actually possible to run kind of reuse
some of those and cannot just extend the
number and nature of the platform's a
little bit without coming up is
completely a new more
yeah so how use it the whatever system
really be so considering that there may
be some unpredictable Network
disconnections or say over also load
problems so how can you can we develop
disability systems with a slightly
challenging in essence a challenge
environment also in IOT in general I
mean so if we if he gets scared up so I
mean we are talking about billions of
nodes we won't be able to take care of
each node individual so we're so moving
from a pet to a cattle model and so
assuming this would also apply to - yeah
this will be computing you can imagine
that security could could be an
interesting challenge right so these are
could be trapped like execution
platforms that you create dynamically at
a high rate so this better should not
you know screw up too many things next
night right so so in the say hype ask a
data center environment they're
established you know architectures set
of tools you know how to build highly
scalable systems like rack scale for
example and so you basically are able to
you know ya put resources together
automatically scales up automatically
and so on so doesn't make sense to
develop it's like comparable set of
concepts and tools for each computing so
also what would we say the network
control and telemetry approach so I mean
we have technologies like
software-defined networking at some
point you may also want to control your
breathing
I've had from the better
yeah from and one from a networking
perspective so yeah the question is yeah
how would actually actually maybe also
affect the way that we communicate in
IOT
so you could imagine if you you know
have like programmable systems somehow
for example sitting between a a thing
and maybe some cloud back-end well you
need to think about how does this you
know H computing or like this computing
function actually gets to the data
I mean someone needs to be maybe in the
security context in the path so
hopefully we don't have to invent men in
the middle of attacks to make this
happen
so that's presently something that not
savvy ICN guys are discussing so how can
you combine like secure access to name
data with triggering dynamic computation
in a sub maintaining the security okay
let's move on so what also happened in
the meantime that could be say related
to this discussion so yesterday we had a
iot F site meeting on the topic that we
caught this routed Internet
infrastructure that's the idea of
decentralizing infrastructure so
becoming have less cloud dependent yeah
for IOT so edge computing is would be
one of the use cases where this could be
of relevance so if you're interested
there's a wiki page that does not yet
but we'll soon enough list the
presentation from yesterday so it was
actually quite good discussion on on
these topics and so I mention ICN if
which there could be an interest in
technology to enable edge computing
world like in network computing securely
so ICN in general is about accessing
authenticated named data and so this
could be static data but it could also
be that is dynamically created and so
they are there's a kind of ritual
Nativity in ICN that it's working on is
a really lightweight dynamic function
invocation idea and so there was a on
the next slide you see there was a
workshop on informations and for
computing it I said
networking next slide that discussed a
few of these topics so the papers and
the presentations are available at this
link and next that I have a kind of
brief overview of the program so so if
did a really interesting keynote on the
topics which ready for like ICN in the
wireless edge and so like the first
block off of presentations actually
dealt with like enhancing or documenting
coop was ICN concepts or ICN underlay so
fill out like an initial deployment idea
and so in the second session there were
two papers about this named function
networking idea that I mentioned earlier
so this is the idea that so in an ICN
requests you what basically he specify
not only the name like it's a data item
but actually even the likelihood
function expression and this can be
evaluated by the network in different
ways
depending on the actual dynamic network
resource availability so for Tinley you
could say I want to you know apply a
certain function on a larger data set so
you could say okay I fetch all the data
items and then run this locally on my on
my gateway but it will also say okay I
actually move this expression to data is
and then they have further ways to
reevaluate this expression so that's so
kind of really interesting activity
that's currently going on in committee
okay let's move on so yeah we are
thinking so there is actually really
good opportunity to rethink IOT edge
computing with a slightly more
decentralized approach that is less
cloud dependent enables more local
functionality so it's not known about
saying okay actually we don't need like
cloud backends anymore it's just perhaps
a good idea to design the systems in a
way that are not a cloud appendant and
so potentially this could could mean
that so like why a lightweight execution
approach would be useful and so like
enabling the formation of that modern
and dynamic formation of local educating
clouds so even i were thinking that
could actually be documented nicely in a
draft so maybe also spending a few more
cycles on actually saying what the
problems say of studying more mainstream
approaches are and like trying to
develop a few concepts for a more like
thing to thing inspired educating
approach and finally maybe this provide
a more solid description of the details
challenges so yeah we are kind of eager
to put this together if anyone wants
wants to help with that
please speak to us and we're happy to
work with you so that would be the
summary of the discussion so far I'm
sure miss something let me know if you
have anything urgent to it so just to
make sure that everybody stretches after
the lunch who has heard about edge
computing so who thinks that the IOT
actually is a place where we will use
this kind of functionality a lot so we
seem to agree on that and and who
actually thinks they will be
contributing to this field over trying
well that's quite a few so that maybe
just remember the people who just place
the hinge so final question who actually
wants to help okay would cars did it was
a leftover question on the jabber I
forwarded it to you by email about one
of your discussions and the wishi
presentation okay if you can take a look
at your email you can answer the
question it's about the socialist
millionaires algorithm and whether you
guys consider that okay okay well so I
sent it to Ari - it's a it's a it's a
long message from one of the jabber
participants okay I can read out the
question out loud so the question is are
any of the secret handshake on the
casein mechanism proposals related to
the socialist millionaires protocol
Iligan well I thought that was it pretty
well as that was a way to do that sort
of secret handshake thing as used in OTR
good question no I think that that's a
worried you just probably know the
answers I hope it works better than the
other one so we didn't go in part of all
that along the details during their
wishes as sunbath will take this offline
thanks thanks for the question
hello everyone I'm Mohit and I will be
presenting what we discussed in Chicago
and what has happened since then so here
is the outline for my talk we will first
look at what what does authorizing
network access for IOT devices mean what
are some problems and challenges we will
also look at one possible deployments in
however the authorization decision is
delegated to the cloud we also look at
what are the challenges in bootstrapping
security between IOT device and the
cloud and I don't want you to leave just
hearing about problems and challenges so
we will also look at one possible
solution which is EAP nope so what does
authorizing network access for IOT
devices mean it just basically means
once I have a new IOT device how do I
authorize it to connect to my local
network and to the Internet why would
these devices need to connect to the
internet well they would possibly use
some vendor or third-party services so I
have this Wi-Fi weighing scale at home
and it keeps a log of my weight and BMI
and then recommends me a diet plan so
that's that's one example but even if I
don't use any of these services they
would hopefully connect to the internet
and receive some software and firmware
updates so a couple of other examples is
this smart doorbell which lets you see
and you can already buy these things
things online so the smart doorbell lets
you see who's at your door and I have
this smart clock at home which lets me
control my appliances remotely so what
are the problems when I want to
authorize network access for for my new
IOT device
just bought well first is discovery and
configurations I bring it home how do I
tell like this is the access point that
you should connect to or this is the
ZigBee gateway that you should connect
to and and and so on to reach the
Internet and not only this discovery but
it also needs some kind of identifiers
and credentials to connect to the local
network first and then then to the cloud
on on the Internet so how do i provision
these credentials and identifiers and a
device that I just bought and has no
information about me as an owner so to
solve those problems we have some
challenges many of them are fairly
well-known and well-understood so of
course these devices don't come with a
keyboard or a mouse with which I can go
and say this is the SSID that you should
connect to and this is the passphrase
that you should use for connecting to to
the access point scalability is of
course a challenge so if my daughter's
Barbie doll is connected to the network
and my Wi-Fi weighing scale is connected
to the network it's no longer just one
or two devices that will be at home and
as more and more devices get connected
scalability will will be a big challenge
and most of the existing tools and
protocols that we have such as WPF or
Snow ZigBee and btle rely on a network
wide shared secret and that is very hard
to scale once the number of devices
chrome and of course usability remains
always a challenge so we need something
that not only works for you and me who
are more or less internet experts but
for naive users at home who don't
necessarily understand everything so if
you look at what are the current
solutions for network access
authorization they can be broadly
categorized into two so there's a manual
configuration which basically means I
somehow managed to tell this new IOT
device my for example Wi-Fi SSID and
password and this might be through
forced pairing it over bluetooth through
NFC or
what some would call Wi-Fi unprotected
setup where I press two buttons at at
the same time the other categories the
managed solutions which use uses 802 1 X
code based authentication and this
basically requires you you to have a
back-end triple a server and then have
certificates installed on all your
devices so this is something that we
discussed in Chicago was a possible
alternative deployment model so where we
delegate the network access
authorization decisions to a remote
cloud-based service so to give you an
example sync sync the thing that you
just have bought a new IOT toothbrush
wouldn't it be nice if the IOT
toothbrush service could somehow tell
your access point to enable internet
connective connectivity for it I know
this looks very easy on the slide very
nice if you have something like a radius
server and Triple A and all these things
running in the background you already
have these tools to do but there are
still many research problems that exist
so the first challenge is of course not
everybody understands what radius is and
what a equal to 1 expose code based
authentication is so you cannot expect
them to configure radius if if we can't
expect them to understand radius so that
that's a big challenge going back to the
previous slide if I delegate to this
device vendor to enable internet access
for the new IOT device how do how do I
then limit his power so I don't want the
IOT IOT toothbrush vendor to control all
my network access and all my devices in
the network so I need a way so that he
can only enable network connectivity for
his devices but kind of not influence
the rest of the network and if I'm going
to buy devices from multiple vendors how
how do this how does this delegation
work and how does interoperation happen
between multiple delegates also
isolating devices is kind of necessary
and also challenging so once I have
these devices and maybe some of them
have
reasonable security and some others not
how to make sure that one broken one
doesn't break the whole network there
are several other remaining challenges
so how do I monitor the behavior of my
device I just bought a new TV how do I
know it's not listening to me watching
to me all the time and sending some data
back to the vendor so that's that's of
course would be a nice feature to have
but challenging to solve in practice and
multihoming mobility multi owner devices
so I won't be the only one using the
Smart TV at home there would be other
users how how does that work out so this
was a rather short introduction to the
research questions and challenges and
I'm the one who causes all the problems
so I'll ask my colleague Thomas to
present one possible solution so I
wonder if there were any questions or
comments for Mohit at this point so
we've been working on this EAP method
for out of that authentication and it
can address is not all about some of
some more of you of those problems
mentioned earlier it's of course just
one approach there's an internet draft
and there's code on github uses has been
updating very fast in the recent days so
this is an EAP method and idea is to do
out-of-band authentication but it's
rather special EAP method unusual in the
sense that you don't have any
pre-existing relation between the peer
device and the authentication server and
also don't know authentication
credentials actually no identifiers and
the user is what the what kind of where
you bootstrap the Securities or the user
as he assists in this out-of-band
authentication and that creates the
association between the pier and the
authentication server so what would we
use this for or why did we start
developing this well the idea is that
the it's for connecting this smart
appliances to cloud services and then
when you buy such an appliance like the
ones in the example they often have no
know these credentials or names or
identifiers or addresses where to
connect to at least if they are kind of
interoperable and and not completely
under one vendors control so here is an
example of the user experience that we
aim aim for and so you go and buy lots
of displays and start hanging them on
the walls and maybe this number of this
place is such a large that you want
would like to make it as convenient and
this play also has very limited user
interface it just has a display and
possibly a power button and so once you
nail the display on the wall you power
it up and in this case it looks for the
network's around it and finds one that
is the our University Network and so she
shows a QR code that is dynamically
generated the user then picks up any
mobile phone with a QR code scanner
scans this QR code and gets to a webpage
on this on a server somewhere in the
cloud and now of course the user needs
to have an account on that server or
could sometimes create that on demand
but but usually will will have at least
after the first display will have or the
second one will have an account there
and we login or or maybe already is
logged in on the web browser on the
phone and once the user has logged in
the display is now connected to the
cloud and start showing content that is
then sent to the display
or selected by the cloud servers so them
so we kind of record network access and
also associated on the application level
the the display devices with a cloud
service and so and there was no previous
password no previous accounts except the
user had one but so how could we do this
network access and registration to the
backend in the cloud in just one step
well what did we do there was a single
user assisted out-of-band message that
went from the QR or scanned as a QR code
went through the phone and then through
a secure HTTPS connection to the cloud
server and that is usually not enough
for I mean usually not possible but but
of course we use the this Triple A
infrastructure and EAP to help us so
here is a picture of the architecture
that is there is there are these IOT
appliances that have either input or
output capability and then they would
like to connect to a wireless network
and that wireless network is now
infrastructure mode network so it's
managed by a local Triple A server
radios in our implementations and then
there is a trust relation between that
local server and the remote radio server
in the cloud which is then the other
endpoint of our protocol and the
communication channels here are the
inbound communication that we actually
put through the EAP panel so that's how
we managed to do the cloud registration
at the same time registration to the
authentication server in the cloud at
the same time as or B actually before
getting network connectivity and
the security comes from this single
out-of-band message which goes either
from the cloud server to the IOT
appliance or the other way with the help
of the user so in in this case that is
well kind of typically it's a smart or
some kind of mobile smart device and
then HTTP or TLS connection to the cloud
server so that kind of explains how we
manage to manage this so that how is it
possible with one message to get network
access and register the device well I
already said it but maybe to summarize
we had so we had to have the inbound
communication possibility through an EAP
tunnel between the peer and
authentication server before the device
is registered it's just you know we can
put anything through that tunnel and we
put the what is necessary for our in
this case for our now EAP method and
then the user actually has an account
already in the cloud server or creates
one and has secure connection over with
from the web browser or HTTP there or it
could be an app on the mobile device and
then a secure TLS connection and then
the access network has been configured
the trust the Triple A server or in
other words the radio requests are
forwarded to the remote deploy server at
the same server where the user has the
account so then if we look at the kind
of cryptographic that goes on in the
background
or the messages there is actually two
EAP sessions in this process there first
and initial what we call initial
exchange that happens in band it's just
an authenticated and opportunistic TV
Hellman elliptic curve diffie-hellman
key exchange and then the out-of-band
methods authenticates that in two ways
there is a secret sent in that out of
and methods as well as hash of the
of the data and then in the completion
exchange we authenticate the the
elliptic curve diffie-hellman using the
data from the outer band mess it's and
dukey conformation and that's where
that's how we have created the
association between the pier and the
cloud server so the security really come
from this in-band difficult man and then
out in the case amount of man there are
some details there but I won't go into
that and we happy of course to explain
in detail what what kind of security we
get maybe the one thing that you should
mention is that that with that outer
band channel needs to either provide
confidentiality or integrity of that out
of band methods but not both and also
the outer band methods can go in either
direction so that's that's kind of what
has been the challenge in designing this
protocol to take into account all these
possible cases make it as Charak as
possible the outer band channels that we
have been thinking about for example
this dynamic QR code or dynamic NFC tag
on or NFC can also be used from this
phone server to phone to to the peer
device communication and audio cable was
one example of another type of outer
band channel then the association
becomes persistent once it's been
created so that we don't ask the user to
redo this for the same device but
rekeying then after this happens without
user interaction and who could this
cloud-based service providers we well
organizations can set up their own
Triple A servers sure but we would maybe
more likely expected to be device
vendors or the network service providers
or content providers in case of this
place or some concern parties who just
like to register stuff and the protocol
could also be used for device to device
security bootstrapping but it's not as
optimized as the device pairing
protocols for that purpose roaming is
possible after the initial setup in the
whole network if you want want to do the
initial setup some elsewhere the user
interface becomes a bit complicated and
this is maybe the kernel for this
research group more for the interesting
slide here so that what did we learn
from this so the well one thing is that
the security bootstrapping is actually
it could call it also device
registration or the user taking
ownership of that device then when
designing the protocol we have to
remember that there's no names or
identifiers for the device and or if
there are they can't be trusted it could
could be conflicts or intentional
conflicts then probably the most
important thing it will be paid spend a
lot of time working on this protocol
specification is that we want to avoid
rerunning the user assisted out of hand
step at any cost
always so you can't just some failure
happens you can't fall back to the
undissociated mode and start from stress
and ask ask the user to do this again so
you know that no I guess from experience
that for your personal device is one you
if you had to ask create the security
Association third time or every time
like my camera bonds you know after
three times as I stopped doing it and
then if it's a business or industrial
setting sensing you're sending a support
person or engineer on site possibly by
aeroplane or just walking to another
floor in the same building that's
expensive and it doesn't scale when the
number of such devices grows to to maybe
thousands or millions and and one fails
every minute
and then also the protocol needs to
recover from various malicious attacks
on certain points that don't compromise
the security of the authentication but
actually try to put it in a state where
it cannot recover so it has to try its
best to recover from anything that
happens then because user is part of the
protocol we have had and I still had I
guess quite big difficulties with
deciding the timeouts and how often the
retry how long the retrial how to back
off off because it if it was just
computers and just the network we would
just define this but now it's the user
that is part of it and and is expecting
something to happen very fast so that's
kind of one challenge that the usability
puts some conditions on on the protocol
and of its parameters something I found
quite interesting is the influence of
this kind of ad hoc Association or or
creating new associations and the
algorithm agility so we want to be able
to support upgrade of crypto algorithms
but normally you have some kind of
initial credentials that are so let's
say you have a Sloane shared secret that
you start with and you use that for
generating your system keys and if
that's what you do then when you're
let's say your diffie-hellman curve
needs to build needs to be replaced
you just go back to that original strong
secret and use a new curve but we can't
do that because we created the original
secret in the Association or the master
secret was created by us with this
crypto algorithm with diffie-hellman in
the initial Association and that mate
makes it a little bit hard we need to
upgrade the master secrets when
upgrading algorithms and also I guess
there's a the typical question people
ask well do I have to kind of how can I
use this at home because I don't have
EAP there or WPA
enterprise well I would think on that is
that everyone should have that and the
complexities for the average user can be
hidden in case they want to use a shared
key you could still use the same
protocol and then it would support such
speed extensions here's the final slide
so it kind of repeats some of the
lessons that mojito already mentioned so
so one now that we have this method of
delegating to third parties like some
cloud server device vendor the control
over access to our network then that
makes me a little of course a little bit
worried and I would like to monitor what
this device is doing the network I would
like to be aware of who which devices
are they're active what kind of
connection what are they what are they
doing so some kind of situational
awareness I think is important for the
network owner and then it would be nice
to isolate these and virtual LANs we
tried it and it works but then there's
only so many virtual LANs and access
points currently support only so so many
societies and virtual LANs for them so
it becomes a bit complex to to isolate
large number of devices with the current
current even networks and then any way
we would like to limit the power of that
third party to to whom with it who is
the triple-a server running the triple-a
server and if there's multiple such
parties they need to somehow work nicely
together
so so those are kind of the challenges
that arose from from this work on EAP no
that's all I had questions Carsten not
sure this is a question but maybe it can
become one this all sounds vaguely
familiar when we set up at your own 15
years ago we of course had the same
problem how do you run the interactions
that are necessary to establish net
access before having established network
access and we all know how this is done
today with radios and so on but we
actually were looking at IP based ways
of doing that as well and what what we
actually came up with was a form of this
isolation you are talking about so we we
achieved this isolation at the time by
simply identifying a part of the ipv4
address space that was available through
nodes that were not indicated yet and
that could be used for running the
authentication mechanism and then when
everything was done of course one would
get access to the whole network now this
was very crude and and how to scale and
so I'm not recommending that that
experience is repeated but maybe the the
basic idea of using isolation a lot more
and still using IP and not not using a
special internal protocols like EAP or
yen in this case the having to actually
put that since we we wanted kind of we
started from that direction and the high
layer but but then there's the question
how can we communicate with the backend
therefore we could maybe use DNS or
something for tunneling stuff but but in
the end the EAP is the standard protocol
for tunneling things before you have
authorized for internet access paneling
to a specific destination I understand
how the world works today I'm just
wondering whether word in which we
actually could identify traffic
classified traffic as to its security
posture iSchool yeah help us I think it
would be it would be nice to have some
kind of limited network access for
specific purposes only so at the time we
when we did this we of course had to
harden those places that were exposed to
unauthenticated users also those people
who actually put systems into this
controlled address space kind of
designed that that they were making sure
these detectives are so using the IP
addresses for isolation within the local
network like let's say I can devise
these access each other that is tricky
because the communication actually on
the access point goes through unless
unless the devices are different SSID
then it goes down only through the
access point and not through our boxes
so we had to take learn open source open
wrt an access point and hack it so that
it would send that all the data to our
router which then sends it back is it
goes to another wireless modem and
that's kind of you could so you can't
with the current hardware you can't have
this IP layer control over there the
device is a tiny wireless network there
was maybe the take-home message is that
we actually have to think more about
putting isolation features in our
networks yeah so we can do things like
these are things like the one we did 15
years ago without having to come up with
these monsters and the special
implementations hi my name is andrew
sullivan so actually i want to pick up
on on that conversation a little bit
because the challenges that you listed
here it seems to me are primarily about
either the LAN or the device within the
LAN or else the device and its
relationship to some sort of cloud
provider and so on but of course there's
the rest of the internet that is
threatened by these devices as well and
so the same kind of the same kind of
isolation discussion that we just we
just had could also be used to address
that other problem or maybe something
else could be could happen here but we
actually tried a little bit that we have
found about that okay was that we
actually
actually I had a header version that we
are done it well
the firewall router and then on the
local network at tunnel the corner
isolated device in such a way that it
created a bpn tunnel for its device and
tunneled it back to the cloud server so
all communication went that way it's not
optimal routing but sometimes that may
be the right solution well non optimum
routing would be just fine for the
purposes of at least of the rest of the
internet but the there is this new
difficulty that that introduces of
course that then the vendors of these
things are going to want you to have
their kind of gateway and so then you're
gonna have and and also also I guess the
bigger you know the immediate problem we
had then is that we don't actually want
well so once we do this association the
network access then we want to hand over
the cloud side control to when it's a
display we want to hand over the control
to some display management service and
and not keep it at the Triple A server
right I mean I think I I think there's
something really fetching about about
this line here taking and I like it
but it I just want to press a little bit
to make sure that the importance of you
know um you know it can connect to these
things that it's been allowed to and not
to everybody else because that's you
know that that's maybe it's because my
employer but I'm slightly nervous about
thanks Eric so if you were to do this
for your sort of house right you have
some privacy concerns about these
devices 'im and whatever metadata that
might be registered in the cloud with
them and it would be nice if this could
sort of only live in my little cloudlet
over there and I control that thing so
have you thought about how you can sort
of redirect it to this thing will
actually end up pointing only to Eric's
you know repository in the cloud and not
be accessible to the big giants out
there that want all the data well maybe
I had to I I see that that's a new
you I guess our concern at the moment is
still that we are running our own server
and we would like some big bender to
take over and implement the server-side
and provide that service personally a
third party that that kind of but of
course they that would provide this
service to any device that then
implements the beer end but I'm not sure
how that right now so how do you select
which server this goes to you have the
application level date that there
certainly will be the privacy issues but
that's kind of on that depends on the
applications I mean with the displays
our main core one concern is that if you
hand over control of your displays to
someone some third party they will also
start putting advertising on it as part
of the deal
hi my name is Michael Richardson I look
forward to reading your Oh to draft I
see you posted new information and I
hope to see what kind of responses yet
because I know you've discussed new been
quite a number of other working groups
over a couple of years just so the room
knows the anima Netcom and six Tisch
working groups got together to deal with
a lot of this problem of how do we
connect to IP to get to connect to IP
and we have a number of solutions which
are approaching either working group
glass calls or sometimes for the voucher
document which essentially authorizes
the fact that you are the owner of a
particular device has passed working
group last call and expect an RFC soon
so there's a lot of other work that's
happening in this and I would be
interested to see how your document
could interact with some of those things
as to the problem of limiting the path
the access to for the device should also
be aware of some work that's happening
kind of an anima but doesn't really have
a home I think at this point which is
Elliott Elia has been working on
essentially I believe it's called
mud and it's a it's a specification
where manufacturer would say essentially
to your own firewall your home firewall
it
this device to do this this and this if
it does anything else there's a problem
right and so this is a kind of thing
that again the authorization server
would pull down a specialty magic URL
the device would provide with
appropriate authorization and
authentication and would say hey okay I
see that your printer and really nobody
should ever talk to you so if I ever see
a talk and it's a problem but you can be
on the network till 10:00 so you may
want to look at that doc work because I
think that me
I think healthy things are kind of do
you know Endre sees the last bullet yes
there how do you yeah so I think that
was helping you a lot for a lot of
things other things and so there's some
other complementary work that I would
love to interact with you to work on
Thanks okay thanks very much so this is
the end of the prepared talks for this
agenda we are head of schedule there's
one thing I would like to draw two
people's attention there is documentary
that made this slide fun that I'm sorry
a document called security
considerations draft IRT ft2 TRG seconds
that is nearly done and it would be good
to have a few more people look at that
the idea with this document is that
other documents that might want to
describe their security considerations
can actually refer to this document so
they don't have to repeat all the common
aspects that IOT security considerations
usually share and so it would be good to
have a useful document out there and it
would be good to have a few more
reviewers for the stock image so those
of you who occasionally write documents
here that might be a good document to
look at and also to see you which
part of the document you want to cite in
your next document so you can save some
writing so other people in this room I
have motivated enough to maybe want to
do a review of the document Michael
wants to do one very good I cannot see
you against the window but good one more
thank you okay that completes our agenda
so unless you have any other business
rhythm so if you haven't signed the bull
seat please come in here in the front
and sign it now and where is the other
blue sheet okay thanks
I still have a set of comments from you
on the a sector structure that's left to
act on so that's why I remember you so
if you want to look at the other yes
thank you