the Muslim wait we have to turn on the
machine
okay so let's get shot at
welcome to the first session here at the
IHF and so this is the TCAP meeting so
if you're not interested in TCP M point
TCP this might not be the right working
group for you and before we get started
let me introduce let me introduce
Michael so as you might have seen we
have the new co-chair and I think this
is the first time where Michael is
sharing on site so let's all that come
home
[Applause]
so next yeah baby still grew up on the
name collusion issue so if you think of
Indiana which is for your size your hair
so it's an unfortunate name coalition
and so you open it so this is the note
well so for those of you who are the
first time it in IETF meeting please
read carefully the note well for those
of you who know it you probably know it
so this is not yet meeting and
everything that you say here is governed
by the note well some logistics for this
meeting we have a note-taker
at the quarry and more or less as usual
so thanks a lot to Corey for his
volunteer for volunteering for that we I
will look myself at Shepherd if somebody
else could look at Shepherd that would
also help but ladies I will take care of
it if nobody else does it whenever you
go to the mic as a please say your let
me say your name and it also it might be
useful if you check afterwards in the
easier is a pet if we correctly spelled
your name if not please correct it so
that's the easiest way to fix the
minutes and in general whenever you
submit an internet traffic that is
somehow related to what is working who
does that is more or less TCP then
please use the TCP mm in your traffic
name so next slide so this time our
agenda is not fully packed so we have
time for heated discussions this week we
will start as usual with the working
groups teachers and then we have three
working group items on the agenda we go
and discuss the alternative take off we
will discuss the acquisition and last
but not least we've all discussed the
generalized ecn draft and then we
received requests for two individual
presentations the first one is located
latency option so this is presented for
the
first time in TCP M and then we decided
to have another presentation on the 24
140 days and so and as the agenda is not
really full we really have some time for
discussion this meeting stall I mean we
will probably have to extend some of the
slots a little bit bigger see the
request is a little bit short on but
still I asked the the some of the
presenters to be quick even if this is
not quick on the status of the documents
so we don't have any RFC but we are
working on getting here so the data
center TCP draft is at the moment in in
the final phase of addressing the iesg
comments so I think there was an update
this morning and we are getting close I
think to adding all comments so this one
should be you should get into the IRC
edited queue relatively soon we had a
working group last call on topic and ye
there was an update I think last week so
at the moment Yoshi for me is working on
that so the document shepherd run on
topic is usually for me and we will come
back with the next steps
once we've analyzed the the new update
then as usual our quick overview of the
active working group documents so the
three ones that are shown on this slide
here are all discussed in in this
session so I will not comment too much
on the alternative peg of the accuracy
and a generalized ecn one the cubic one
as I have mentioned has passed the
working group last call and we currently
look into the new version other than
that we have a couple of working group
items which are not presented here on
the right one I think there's ongoing
experimentation as we've not received
any update on that one but it was
discussed quite a bit in the last
meetings on the 793 this vest is
currently working on an update so
he actually told us that will probably
be an update this week
unfortunately bass is not here so so he
can't resend it and but there but there
should be an update this week on our geo
to consider there is no news after the
last meeting and the same also applies
on an idio so I think Joe is not in
office this week so that's why he can't
comment himself on on video and that's
actually the state rish so are there any
comments any questions on the state of
affairs in in TC p.m. okay if there are
no general comments we would head on to
the first presentation and that's Nayeem
on the alternative pickle and as usual
as since this is Monday morning please
stay into the this boxed area I mean
this is your cage as a presenter okay so
I'm in the square I'm gonna be fine so
the alternative back of it is you know
as we call it eight so we have submitted
the version zero one so basically the
changes that in zero one compared to the
version zero is that that we improve the
text we have lots of comments from
Stuart Cheshire and we incorporated all
of those comments into the document and
also we basically did some minor changes
including changes changed to the
reference that we made to the technical
report that shows our results now it's
published so then we reference the
published version and also we kind of
work on and get sorting out the
terminology throughout the document so
for example we always use the term AQI
mechanisms
we also make provided clarification on
the intent intended purpose of the
experiments or what we mean by the
experiment in this draft since this
graph is a right now and in the
experimental status basically all the
changes there were basically the wards
meeting an inch and clarifications there
were no major changes so almost no
changes to the technical contents of
their slides that the draft then when it
comes to implementation we had some
early freebsd implementation of it which
is a patch available online this patch
was brought up by Tom Jones from the
University of Aberdeen and last week and
we have submitted this for the free
beastie upstream and waiting for the
results also we've got patches available
for Linux when we are planning in the
future to submit it to the to the Linux
so next what we are trying to do because
this draft initially was focusing on TCP
and then we decided that we basically
generalize it to the congestion control
mechanisms that are window based there
was a discussion right now as the
Dreyfuss stands is that it promises that
it would do an sctp basically condition
control based on Abe using the ACN but
what we are suggesting here is that we
do we won't add the CTP ape support to
the draft that we have rather we provide
the general guidance to say that
basically we recommend that the tape
will be the part of the design of any
transfer protocol that implements the
window based reduction to ACN mark
congestion so basically that's the
general statement that would be written
in this draft instead of going to
specifically SCTP related stuff and how
something happened so then since the
city a city piece a congestion control
spec is not defined yet we leave the
detailing of the how to react to easy
enter to any future draft that basically
defines that congestion response in a
CTP and just
stay kind of generic in this draft about
it so that's basically the discussion
that I would like to bring to this
working group and also I have a question
and that is should we address these two
things is there anything else we should
do so that this draft basically proceeds
perhaps to the working group last call
so Michael Jackson from the fall I think
taking out the setp stuff and and just
saying whenever SCTP has a specification
for ACN we'll take this into account
it's fine with me
the other comment is that in the
description of what you are doing is
you're assigning flight size to flat
ties n plus on equal is flight size
times the factor and I think you can't
Wi-Fi flight size since this is just the
number of bytes which are outstanding
and not Q max so you can't change this
variable you can observe it and use it
but not change it I mean why it's
outstanding and now you say oh only 500
which 500 are you revoking to have ever
sent that doesn't make sense so this was
this is a long history of initially it
was lucid looking at the ceiling and
every night EF there was somebody saying
that all this has to be flat size then
we change it to the flight size you can
change it to window you can change it to
how you update it but it's definitely
not the flight size because the fight
size is the number of bytes you've sent
and you have not come act so nothing you
can have on the left side of an equation
or an assignment so is there any
parameter you recommend to use there I
will go with save and if it was all mine
with me if somebody else in the idea of
hadn't said that you should definitely
be using places they are the RFC had at
the congestion control RC defines flight
size ha
No TCP congestion control RFC defines
flight size as something being the the
bytes which have been sent but not
correct and you can't have that on the
left side of an assignment changing this
receiving yeah I looked at the patch so
changing that it's a minor thing to
change them in its from it's an
editorial change right right these two
things every should be changed okay so
as it's I think it's clear that an
update of the document is needed but
still for our educational purpose could
we have a show of hands how many have
read this document recently because we
definitely look forward to on web use of
this document so and can you give me a
show of hands how many have read this
document so I see off the order of five
people before I would say five six
something like that so yeah whistling so
okay better question so who is willing
to read you at the current or the next
version okay I see Dave I see one out
okay
okay guys I think we have enough
reviewers for the note-taker can you
please write down the presence I think
from a process perspective you have to
await this this document until the easy
and experimentation and has passed
through it is vwg but if this is
happening soon and if you have enough
review is here I think we can move this
document Forge
the black editor of the TSV WG e to
experimentation draft that dress basic
basically through its completed working
group last call we've as will be
discussed tomorrow we've figured out
what to do in that draft about the one
remaining open issue of and talk about
here so that draft is basically through
th vwg should be going to IETF last
column in the near future
okay
so then I think we're done we hope
really that we get some revenues on that
and you noted on the name so we all if
you don't see them we will get back to
the people and as I said then hopefully
in may be in the next meeting or
something like that we think about last
call
okay so the next one is a Christian so
I'm not sure who will present this baba
hi I'm Bob Briscoe the authors this one
was adopted about nineteen months ago
been some major changes carry on
yep just a quick recap of what it is or
what the problem is trying to solve is
am i near enough to mike without coming
out the box yep
[Laughter]
right so conditioned notification just
for those of you don't know there's a
table on it there
the problem was that when ACM was added
to IP and TCP both in the same document
it it only allowed one TCP feedback per
round-trip time of an ACN mark so if
there were many it only allowed one and
some experience since then has shown
that with that more information you can
do a lot better particularly on latency
but at the time we only had a TCP that
reacted once so there was only one
feedback and the way it worked is for
reliability it set the ECE flag in the
TCP header repeatedly until the sender
set the CW our flag so it was like have
many you had you only saw one of them
because of this repetition right so this
is a the idea is to change the TCP wire
protocol to change the ecn feedback and
instead of using them as Flags use the
three bits which you're only used when
when you're doing capability negotiation
of the handshake but once the handshakes
finished use it as a three bit counter
field and just repeat a counter in there
and every time the count the counter of
the number of marks you've seen
increments then eventually the the
sender will realize that it's updated
even if there's been some drops of X
because the problem is that you've got
no reliable delivery of peer acts in TCP
so you need some other reliable way of
getting your congestion notification
back then obviously a 3-bit field is is
a bit limited but that's all you can get
through middle boxes we've discovered
from measurements so there is a option
as well that gives you the information
in by it's not packets and you know that
that will supplement the this revolving
counter in in the ice field if you've
got it but it should work even if you
haven't where work is it doesn't you can
get cases where you get a string of aqua
pure at losses where it gets confused
because of the rap unless you have the
the option to give you more information
but you need quite a long string right
okay just just to explain where it fits
and I've been told that this diagram
doesn't help anyway but it's in it's in
text as well so first thing is the
accuracy n has to be agreed by both ends
because it's changed the wire protocol
all right so what I've done I've split
that in the diagram I'll split the
layers between the wire protocol in in
the transport layer and the congestion
control and accuracy n is essentially
the extension to the feedback wire
protocol so it does all the things the
previous ones did as well it doesn't you
know you don't need the other ones that
this is it like not a fork in the design
it's just an extension yeah and you
could use accurate ec n for bbr as well
as for other other protocols that need
more information than once per round
trip time like TCP prog that we're
working on and I believe it's you chung
here I haven't seen him he mentioned
that he's interested in in when he adds
ec n to be BR to jump straight to
accurate easy and and not not go through
the old feedback mechanism so and and
yes for DC TCP Acura ecn also gives you
benefits that we talked about years ago
and we don't need to go through again
right so that's where it all fits I did
this because one or two people putting
Stuart we're saying can you give me a
road map of where all these bits of ecn
fit and as I say it's not clear that
this helps but it might do I guess what
it does do the next talk I'm giving is
about a draft that's got the file name
generalized ecn but we've now decided to
call it a TN plus plus and that also
fits in this it's a change to the sender
depending on what things it's set in the
IP ecn field but it's only applies in
the TTP context it these are all
basically updates to the TCP way of
doing ACN which was a sort of missed out
on the experience that all the other
protocols got from it and they did it
right whereas TCP has sort of got behind
because it it had all these problems
with it so there's all these bits need
to be added to it to make it work or
make it work well alright so once you've
got the feedback in accurate ECM then
you can have sender base changes on top
of it
sender based congestion control changes
or sender based setting of more ACN in
the IP layer okay all right so the next
few slides go through technical things
we've updated in the last cycle or few
actually because we haven't talked about
this for some time in response to a
number of reviews we've had and our own
thinking and experience one of the big
problems with ACN as it's there
is that if there's bleaching of the ecn
field which means wiping it to zero and
that we will talk about a bit later in
this er ITF when found it's quite common
in mobile networks we think it's a bug
related to bleaching of the diffserv Co
point right and so the problem with rst
31 6j Li has no way of even detecting
that it doesn't detect that let alone
any way to feedback that it's happened
and so there can be some really
dangerous situations for instance your
home router has a 3g or 4g dongle in it
or you know and so your you've got say
fq cuddle in that that's easy n marking
packets and then that those ECM marks
get wiped and so both ends think they're
talking easy n but this this thing
essentially just pushes the cue right
right through to tail drop until it does
anything so you get this sort of
oscillation between ignoring ECC N and
then tail drop going on so inaccurate ec
n the feedback on the sin and sin AK we
are proposing to replace what was just
feedback of whether it was CEO or not
with feedback of exactly which ECT there
was there as well so he David to your
honor hang on I'm confused suppose I've
got something in the uplink that's
that's uniformly bleaching the EC n bits
to 0
yeah how on earth do I get TCP to think
EC ends working in the first place if
that's happening because you're doing
that at the transport layer this is
bleaching I'd know it right at the IP
layer I've got to set each ET in the
shin and a calf those get bleached no no
no the ECM negotiation is in TCP
irrespective of what set in the icon I
checked this I think you wrote the rst
[Laughter]
so I'm pretty sure I'm right David so
we're proposing that we have four
possible states on the feedback of the
scene and the syn/ack so we can both
ends know what he's getting through and
what isn't getting through based on the
two-bit field in the IP header all right
and with we've got just that many spare
states in those three flags given to all
the previous uses they've had for
negotiation and all the broken
implementations there are and all the
rest of it so we've just got enough
space to do this right and we've had a
bit of discussion on that so I think
we'll move on or David thinks about that
right so the next the next point that's
the in ray is particularly by Praveen
who's not here from Microsoft is he's
unsure about whether he wants to
implement the after ACN option he was
you know what so no can he just do the
icefield part of it the essential part
of it and not the optional part and the
spec actually allows him to do that but
it's sort of please don't you know that
wasn't the intention in other words the
spec says you must not put the option on
this sin because it's not necessary
because the the flags implicitly say
you're going to support the option
okay thanks David David just said I'm
right by the way for the record then the
on the on the three-way handshake
there's assured and assured for the
option and on the first day two packet
those assured because the act before it
isn't delivered reliably so this is just
a test where the options getting through
all right and then after that once
established it's all you only need to
put it on
it's change triggered and even then it's
optional Cossack takes precedence
because drops more important than ecn
right so the upshot of all that is
there's no musts there there's only
should optionals and must not which
means essentially for being would not
have to put this option on however it
does say that you must implement it and
you must try to use it because the idea
is that it's useful and this isn't meant
to be a get out for an implementer just
to do less work next I is there a
question sorry did you have a question
were you sneaking feedback about this
always just informational I'm just
telling people yeah I suppose I hadn't
imagined that people might want to
discuss that baby yeah maybe just one
more point say original we saw it also
you can use this for example for data
centers where you might know what your
setup is and you might know that you
don't need the option but for example if
you specify some kind of mechanism that
wants to use the accurate information
and really really needs the option you
can specify in that document that it
should activate the option yeah yeah and
that example you gave in a data center
if you think I don't need this option
you may well find that if you get long
strings of loss due to in caste then
your counters do get out of sync and you
do need this option and supplementary
information to deal with rack of that
three bit field yeah because the three
bit field isn't isn't much to get wrap
on especially in with large windows
right now coming on to the subject
that's got the process wants going for
the last few months we need to use the
flag to the left their mark ie that's
currently the nantes flag for this
negotiation that you just saw and also
for this three bit counting field and
the nonce as we've just been explaining
David's easy and experimentation draft
as well as enabling Abe and enabling the
next talk also makes the easier Nantes
historic and what we've agreed to do
this too I on a process is needed there
one is to unassign the Nantes flag from
the TCP header in David's draft which is
more about relaxing requirements because
this the the registry for this this is a
process problem the registry policy
requires and proposed standard RFC to
change it and then the accurate Sen
draft where in thinking it's likely to
be experimental but we are going to
assign that flag from a registry but the
policy saying it has to be a proposed
standard RFC but we're going to or mayor
is going to raise an exception or
Spencer is going to raise an exception
and say there's a good reason for this
it used to have an experimental IC on it
we're not going to try another
experiment on it we will have some
discussion after after this regarding
this procedure thing okay so just go on
you mean after the talk after the target
just go under yeah can I just check out
all the points on there yeah yeah I
think that's about it so the status is
it's implemented in Linux Mayer's
implementation the URL is there we've
been waiting for this flag to become
available officially before it can go
any further we were also waiting for ECM
plus plus to be adopted which is my next
tour actually Marcello's next talk
we're co-authors
because there's some things that
accurate easy and allows ECM plus plus
to do better but you couldn't really
refer to it when it wasn't even adopted
and then finally we've got a few pizzas
I want to open up for discussion in
appendices at the moment in the draft
the first one is what I've just been
talking about feeding back for code
points on the cinemas in AK oh sorry on
the sin focus the fall code points were
that were on the scene feed them back in
the syn ACK and opens is an alternative
B is about feeding back or for EC anchor
points that were on the syn ACK in the
first act yeah so you know the sin goes
that way you have to feed back what was
in the IP header back in the TCP header
and the sim on this the IP header in the
syn ACK you have to feed back in the TCP
header what it was decently so you go up
one layer at each of each way of the
handshake that second point is a bit
more difficult because the first ACK is
not delivered reliably so if you're
trying to use this as a food as a
fallback mechanism and some middle box
doesn't like it and drops it you've got
no way to detect that the third act of
the handshake has been dropped and so
what we say in the draft is that
assuming you have some data coming from
the client you don't have to you repeat
that on the first data but then we also
have to say that the other end only
looks at it if it's the first one
arriving so I think we've sorted out the
problem if there's any discussion needed
on that or if anyone's read the draft
and doesn't like that we'd certainly
like people to look at that some TCP
expertise to look at that to check that
we haven't forgot any cases you know I
don't know simultaneous opens and things
like that we have thought about all that
but maybe not in all all the possible
cases right now this the sorry the open
issues I wanted to ask people about
particularly the day
and the people here at the moment we
have we have had a little discussion on
this before at the moment we we only
send the Acura ACN option on when a
different ECM code point changes so if
the counter is continually updating
you're getting lots of ECT nor you don't
have to send an accurate ACN option
unless all right you got to seee so it's
like when something happens you have to
send a macro ACN option that's what we
call change triggered now that means
that potentially if you've so got
alternating ACN marking you'll get a lot
more acts than if you've got constancy
and marking and so that alters the rate
at which your the rate of your acts
through your data center depending on
the traffic
I see Andrew shaking his head a he might
not like that because you're getting all
these small packets at certain times and
not at other times is that a problem
because what we'd like to do is make
that a must because if you don't make it
a must you can't rely on the timing
information because you don't know
whether the other ends doing it all the
time or not so it made it assured at the
moment because we know there's a concern
about it yeah and I think a reasonable
option there is if the RTT is very small
and so you can't trust the timing
information anyway because you're
beating your timers just but the
receiver doesn't know what these senders
time resolution is sure but it knows
well its own time resolution is yeah see
the thing is producing that many acts is
going to cause problems further for both
stacks in a very short RTD come in with
an environment just because you're
constructing more packets and you've got
to go around that loop so many more
times
yeah okay um and also the switches
themselves the average size of a packet
in the network matters and access small
so you pushing it downward and no GPS
capability problems yeah
on longer ITT connections not a problem
I see no no problem with doing this
halfway around the world or you know
tell me nothing it's not physically the
same building but across the data seeing
it fabric it's likely to break things
but then traffic across the data center
fabric is a special case because the you
know where the destination is anyway so
mmm just maybe a night to say it's okay
to do that if you know for sure that the
destination is inside the building yeah
something like okay so maybe we could
put some put together some sort of um
I'm more concerned that we put together
something so that the thing that's
receiving this feedback can know for
sure when it can rely on the timing
information of the acts yes so it needs
to be something deterministic it not
just sort of if the round returns a bit
bigger you know yeah or or else have to
have the receiver mark that it did this
yeah we've I have argued for an extra
bit to say whether you're doing this or
not that we haven't really you know
that's just awkward
and really got a bit yeah I understand
yeah we have we have done option
actually what one one possibility is we
did consider the possibility of than the
initial number you put in the option to
start the counter we can we can put
different numbers in depending on what
your mode is if you like we could do
that maybe a mere
Michael Ivins I'm not convinced that
would really need it because if you put
a shirt and in most of them but I should
do it then you can just make a stronger
assumption that it's done that way and
also you can probably detect that it's
not done that way if you just you know
see every second peg attacked and
nothing changes ever and charming
information anyway that has Issei it's
it's anyway not very precise say I'm I'm
not I'm not seeing a strong need for
doing it
I mean I understand your point that if
we don't do it now it will be too late
and we cannot change it in future
but I also not convinced that we need
any any additional yes the other thing
is about this that you the time when you
most want this timing information is
right at the start of your flow when
you're doing a slow start or whatever
you want to know and that's sort of not
enough time to her istic me check what
the other ends doing when you start a
flow you usually I check every packet
anyway usually yeah yeah yes and so the
same sorry Andrew McGregor again if the
receiver transitions into doing a
compressional later and the flow then
it's not very harmful and actually
having accurate timing information
during slow start even on a 15
microsecond Artie tears is possibly
useful yeah yep okay so maybe we can say
if you're not going to do it make sure
we do do it during slow start or
something like that even those receiver
doesn't strictly know when slow start
ends it sort of Bailey knows so I would
like to limit the discussion right now
for everything except for the assignment
of the NS I mean before we go there okay
from the to the fun part was the one
comment I'm speaking and I called
speaking from the individual Mike I read
some statements in the document on the
TCP M consensus and my recommendation to
the authors is to review that because
there are some statements on the success
criteria of that experiment which I find
a bit surprising so to me an extra
Herman can even ami what I was like I
remember the diverting is the success
criteria
for the experiment is that the TCP M
working group team is the protocol
stable or something like that and let's
be clear the success criteria for
everything that we do here is getting
things deployed in the intranet getting
it running it's not the working group
thinking about I don't know okay so it
might be as an implication is needs to
be made explicit that it's being
deployed and the working group considers
it stable it is to be honest I think it
the working group consensus doesn't
matter because if it's getting deployed
and things like this we well anyway the
publish appears so I think the the
purposes of the experiment is
implementation that feat getting
feedback improving it whatever so but I
don't see why this document has to make
it major success criteria that talks
about the tcp and working group and the
consensus here I don't see that why
that's needed well if it's gonna get yes
the TCP working group has to agree
that's it yes exactly but you don't have
to write it in this document any course
it's obvious any other questions
comments not related to a bit so nothing
further only nonce process that's done
yeah no I have a slide for that okay now
so I stay here oh you can say there so
if there's no other comments then we
move do that so that's a procedural
thing and in an earlier version of Bob
slides there were some alternatives
listed so we had a discussion with the
working group chairs of TSW G and the
80s about how to deal with this
reassignment so it was agreed that in TS
bwg arm the unassign 'men of the NS bit
is triggered so that's that's agreed and
so the open crash I mean not the open
question
what had to be discussed was the
reassignment and there were a couple of
options the first option is that it is
signed within the tea CPM working group
by the accurate ecn document there are
three variants of that the first one is
the document itself it's heading for
experimental status and the registry for
these bids requires a standard strike
document so that's why an ad has to it
has to be involved to to say this is
okay and it was indicated that that's a
possibility um the other one is that the
document is not going for experimental
but for proposed an it so then we don't
have that problem the third one is that
the registry for that registration the
procedure for that registry the
registration procedure is changed so
currently it requires a standard strike
document so you can change that to
something that requires only in RFC or
something like that
however the registry covers six bits so
you would change it for not only for the
three which are now currently assigned
but also for the three being unassigned
so this is also a drawback and another
very end of the third option is to have
to change the policy only for the NS bit
but that would mean you have to add a
registry for one bit so it's also
getting very lacking another possibility
is that it is um assigned in a TS w TS
vwg document with or without it so in
two variants however they the chairs of
that working group indicated strong that
they don't want to do it in that working
group and i mean we're just checking if
there are any other possibilities so one
generic possibility would be to to have
a
standard document assigning assigning
this document
assigning the spit and then are saying
whenever and experiment wants to use it
it has to negotiate by itself that it's
being used and then it can use this bit
for whatever experiment it wants to use
this is a generic solution but doesn't
fit into the the current way of of the
accurate ecn document so these are the
options we are aware of how any other
options good come on heaven I mean if
you look at this I mean you can you can
just because I'm standing here like it's
not just so not too accurate easy n but
I guess that's not an option that's an
option
I missed that so I just want to ask or
point out that the we really need to be
thinking are there any problems with the
one that the working group chairs and
abs are happy with and otherwise we
don't need any other options I just we
do we talked about this and we just
wanted to make it transparent for the
working group why they the result of the
discussion was use one a which is
everyone is fine with it and all the
other solutions have some other topics
well I could describe the drawback with
one a if you want which is shall I do it
now you mind me a cool even say there's
actually one more option one is we don't
assign it right now you could open until
the extra mind is closed and then it
sign it as soon as we have a proposed
standard but I think the reason why we
have the registry is because we want to
use this as a mechanism to make people
aware that this experiment is happening
so I think the outcome should be that
the RFC number for the experiment should
be mentioned in the registry
Gouri wants to say something
hi gory fur has had trouble gig item
right place for our sitting in Barton I
got here somewhere already said it all
but one a was what we what we suggested
I could ask another question while we're
on silly questions oh and it was from a
conversation with the man behind me but
and the NS field appears in textbooks
and on some people's web pages like mine
it might be nice to keep it called an S
and rename it because that diagram is
exceedingly well distributed where you
where you see the header fields of the
TCP header change something else it's it
means but still call it in it so
changing our semantics how about making
the same signal so I just want a
backward or reset so I mean the TCP
header is well documented in many
documents outside the IHF and while it's
clear that we want to have this
experiment here it's still an experiment
and I'm a little bit concerned about out
dating every single text book that is
written on TCP by an experiment and as I
said there might be ways to deal with
this and one way might be to use another
name for that date or somewhere else but
I'm a bit a little bit concerned not
about the experiment but the impact is
experiment has on all text books out
there and there are good reasons why
that flag is actually and in other in
other ways we know that but in that
specific age it's the first figure in
the text book that gets outdated as I
said I think we should think about that
we certainly don't want to prevent that
experiment but maybe let's think about
for example having individual
michael jackson from the floor sir
personally I think it's it's better to
make clear that the document that the
diagram is outdated because you see it
so you name the flag differently but
compared to stick with the acronym that
the semantics has changed completely so
people think it hasn't changed but it
did change so break it as soon as
possible I mean if this is your main
concern then in the bit shouldn't have
been assigned in the first place of an
experimental draft but like that was
done so we can't change cannot change
this part anymore so I take the action I
come to update the German Wikipedia page
[Laughter]
during pictures ahead it comes second on
Google David black ain't not completely
flippin suggestion we could change the
bit name to not specified like it so I
to me the most important thing is the
first bullet or at the UH assignment
um I don't actually care about any of
the rest right because in the good old
tradition of squatting on code points
your fire by the time you get so
successful that we will need to deal
with this we will deal with it so it
seems like we're doing a lot of thinking
here we leave it unassigned use it for
the experiment and you know if it's
successful we will we'll know what we
need to do right so just to clarify so
what you say is well when the experiment
document I mean obviously an
experimental RFC once it's successful
progresses possibly to PS and then
assign that bit okay so I don't think
that's the worst option we discussed
that and we sought if we have a registry
it should also reflect what the current
state is that's why we were rather in
favor for signing it
but that leads to another option we
could also remove the hope registry so I
think say between the small group we had
yesterday we we kind of agreed to go for
option A or C where a is the default we
can do right now and see something the
working group could decide on the can I
comment on losses point given this
negotiate a new feedback protocol for
TCP I think we really bad if we allowed
other experiments at the same time with
that bit so that your negotiation you
think something's happening and it's not
like I got an iron registration doesn't
stop any of that no but it helps no it
doesn't oh I guess it does it doesn't
know you it does not help the bad people
but it helps the good people so yeah the
amount of good people that will actually
look at the registry before they do
anything is probably the people in this
room and probably not all of us no no
that's not true
that's not true I don't think we should
not do something that's correct just
because a lot there's a lot of incorrect
people so this is Michael that's
individual contributor I've seen a lot
of vendors squatting on court points no
matter what the honest at Saudi whether
we reach a registry of this Yana or not
that doesn't matter to those
implementers that's quote-unquote points
of course we can agree that it's this
the right thing to do but it will the
thinking of bad implementers is a non
concern at that conversation my opinion
yeah I just can I say what I what the
problem is with I just in the it
essentially is a circular dependency
with the if the I see don't agree it
because we're assuming they will agree
this process exception if they don't
then with there are two experiments in
the ECA an experimental patient draft
that depend on echo ACN and that will
have gone through and and then the ice
you throw this back
and say well you can't have accurately
CN yet or whatever David black Bob I
think you're way off they're way off
into the into into the hypothetical but
I think you're way out the point is the
is G do he is you if the is G does that
eating experimentation bounces back to
the TSV WG with the on fire process with
a with the on fire process flying ahead
and will sweat out no no I'm not saying
if the is you don't approve is in
experimentation I'm saying if they don't
approve the process exception that comes
later without curry CN Mia Coulomb is a
member of the I use G I don't think
that's a real concern and even if and
even if that happens then we just
published a documents without the
assignment and then it's unassigned and
then we can think about it later it's
really nothing to worry about right now
I would just explained to everyone what
the problem is and why we might need
other options but I don't think I'm
happy with a I'm just explaining to
everyone but that's there's two branches
in a flow diagram when something needs
approval yes and no okay
we go
so could we ask for feedback in the room
arm about if you think if you think it
is good to assign this bit for the
experiment I mean a different way so we
can assign the pit so that that's clear
but I think the first question where
you'd like to get a feedback from the
room as weather for this experiment
there would be value in assigning it in
the IANA registry by one way or another
it could be the one a option or maybe
something else but as a the key thing
that we have to know first is is there
if the working crew believes that we
should assign it and my proposal would
be to have a hum on that one and this
two options first of all yeah so just
want to go back to the first bullet so I
assume we're all clear that that's know
as a we are or we are only talking about
the second step here as a better B we
are W we assign on this bit for the
acquisition experiment and as I said my
proposal is to hum on that this two
options as the first option is that we
figure out the process to assign it
again to the aggregation the second
option is probably what lost a proposed
that we keep it on our side for the
moment logic and and so I'm probably
gonna hum fully letting it be unassigned
but I do think we should do the
experiment right so this is not a hum
against the accuracy an experiment okay
let Vicki I mean this this document will
move forward and TCP and no matter what
the only humming so it's gonna be
awkward
[Applause]
okay so I think are the two options
clear to the room so that the first hum
is other whether you believe that we
should assign it to this experiment to
this experiment so if you think that
that's the right thing to do and please
hum no so what note-taker this was a
decent huh and and the the the second
option is if you believe that we should
keep this bit under shine for the moment
and still continue the experiment and
please her know as a for the note-taker
this we're probably two persons I think
as I mean there is relatively clear
consensus in the room towards assigning
it this it's not unanimous but there are
certain consensus in Russian so we will
figure out the next steps but at least
the feedback from the room is okay to
figure out next steps
next presentation actually walk
Marcela's coming out with spot Brisco as
Mia pointed out the last time this was
presented I've been trying to get this
done since 2005 but that flag hi I'm
Marcelo Angela and I'm going to present
our draft or latest version of the draft
regarding
having EC Tec and support to TCP
congestion to TCP control packet sorry
so a current currently RC 3168 prevent
from ECT marking the TCP control packets
and the retransmissions actually for
cynics error see 50 55 60 to actually
allowed marking the syn ACK
alright with some so-called ec n + try
ones approach what we're doing in this
draft in this document is to enable the
marking of oil control packet and also
retransmission whenever the marking ECT
marking of all control packets and
retransmission so what we do in the
draft is with the two things we specify
how this gets done and we go through all
the arguments that represent an Ori
originally in 3168 and we try to deal
with them okay so we have several
revisions of this draft we have a
several very total reviews from media
from david black from gory and from
Padma and thank you very much for these
reviews actually they were very helpful
and very in detail actually they they
provided a very good excuse for Mike
offer to completely rewrite the draft so
now we have this is new version and it
was recently adopted us as a working
group item so
I will this next I will I will describe
what more what is in the current
situation is so why are we doing this
well actually not enabling marking off
of this of all the TCP control packets
results in performance penalties but
this has been reported in different
scenario especially when you have a high
amount of marking then these control
packets tend to tend to get lost I mean
deploy getting low inter of dropping
them is it's much higher because the
other packets are getting much and that
actually results in performance tendency
basically what you have there in this
graph is a flow completion time graph
and you see that the those packets there
that that takes those flows there that
takes about one second to complete a bit
more than a second to complete this a
log scale right it's basically because
because the scene got lost right and and
this is one second time timeout that it
takes for the scene to to be resent
right so actually you see that that
actually getting the scene loss actually
perform a harms performance II severely
right so way to go would try to is okay
so we mark these packets so they they
are likely to get marked before getting
loss hence the performance will will
will improve next slide please
so what we are doing here is basically
enabling the marking of these packets so
we have two flavors of of EC and
feedback at accurate ECM and 3168
feedback we really don't don't know
which is the which is the sender when we
start with the connection right and what
we are defining that what we're
currently defining the draft is that you
can set the ECT marking in all packets
in all control packets and we
transmissions for when you know that the
I mean when you try it the accurate
vision protocol basically when you try
the accuracy and sim and after the the
accurate decision has been negotiated
and when you're not sending accurate DC
and when you're sending 3168
sim in order to to negotiation at that
point you should not mark the ECT but
you can actually use a mark all the rest
of the packets the reason for wrap is
because accurate ecn already
incorporates the means to feed back the
the echo
if congestion has occurred in the sim
but it's very hard to accommodate that
if you have 3168 receiver on the other
end all right so for this reason we're
only proposing to support DCT marking of
the scenes when you're trying to
negotiate equation okay so that's that's
the current state thanks next so now I'm
going to go through each of the
different types of packets and explain
you what situation is what is approach
the GUI what we were proposing so in in
when we're sending in the scene the
problem is that we don't know if the
other end actually supports acquisition
in particular if it supports
ecn plus plus the soup the marking of
the of the packet the ECT marking of the
scene packet so if it support is
actually the same is great because you
you get the the the see echo back right
in case it was marked the problem is
what happens if when you send the scene
you get a reply that it doesn't support
acquisition so it may happen that the
scene got CE marked or it didn't right
so what do you do at that point so what
we what we're proposing to do is in that
case we conservatively reduce the
initial window to one where we assume
that it was marked okay
and we optionally cache the fact that
this was marked that that sorry that the
the server doesn't support accurate is
yen right so we don't try it again
this actually puts you in the position
that if you try to use this if there is
a large number of servers that does
support this you get you you get worse
performance because you get the penalty
of reducing the initial window even
though it did it was in a mark which is
the most likely scenario right and so
there are two arguments why we still
think that's the right thing to do
the first is because a you cache so you
only you only suffer this once
and the second is actually a feedback
varietal by YouTube that is that usually
the client actually doesn't really need
a big window in the initial what who'd
really need to will be window is the
server right so to send a get with one
packet you're good enough
alright so it's not that you will you
will hurt your performance in large
number of cases severely so that's why
we are proposing this okay next okay so
as I said before the ECT marking in
seeing acts was already defined in ec n
plus in the fifty five sixty two however
what it's in there it's really weird
actually
so actually the behavior described in
there it's actually some attempt to
completely mimic what will happen if the
packet get lost right so basically if if
you get this if you get a see mark in
the Cenac what 5560 to set that you
should do is you should reduce the
initial window but also you should
resend once a second scenic without the
ICT market right so not actually we find
that that this is very weird and sorry
it's a five way handshake yes right so
actually we we don't think that's the
way to go actually we think it's
probably by simply reviewing the initial
window you should be fine right I mean
you got the scene are the Rosa the
awesome there was a mark on the scenic
just react to congestion and go on with
it
actually we did some measurements we
drive the 500k top Alexa servers there
are a few of them that actually supports
in AK AC marking I mean ECT marking in
the scenic none of them actually does
what 55 60 to the specifies okay so that
doesn't listen I mean as far as we can
tell nobody's doing that right so what
we're suggesting is to actually update
55 62 if needed I don't that's
procedural
I think that needs to be discussed
whether this document should update 55
62 but actually what we're suggesting is
that the support for the ECT marking on
the scene at should be this right simply
reduce the congestion window and that's
it
next so the other thing is we're
suggesting that and we're proposing that
you should be able to ECT mark the acts
the pure acts so 3168 doesn't actually
specify what needs to what the receiver
that receives a CE marked pure rock so
the the the thing is that it may be it's
possible that they actually doesn't send
the CEA Kobach right so this is a
comment from media so the question is
whether we should enable ECT marking of
pure acts given that there may be some
unresponsive a receiver so that
basically that you may be the receiver
may receive the burek mark with C and
doesn't and do not send the echo back i
understood that was that was your
argument me :
the comment was because it's actually
not a problem whose neck X are not sent
for every packet if you lose one there's
no penalty there other than for the soon
so you don't have to take the risk
sorry can you if you if you don't mark
your X if you negotiate the classic easy
and not accurate easy and and you don't
mark your X and you lose some X because
they are not marked and so there's loss
there's congestion and they get lost
it's not it doesn't cost you any
performance penalty what do you mean if
it was the last ACK yeah that's gosh
sure unless performance yes so again if
if
I mean the thing is again what I think
we probably need actually that I think I
have this data but I actually didn't
process it is to find out whether
whether current deployed servers do
actually send a echo back from from
Purex marks with with with ECT right so
that that's an easy test to do right I
mean you know only need to send Pyrrhic
smart would see and see what what you
get back right that should be that
should be possible to do and and learn
something no I mean that's for sure
useful to do it's just like the general
concern when you mark a packet and you
don't have any feedback about if it was
mark or not that's actually something we
don't recommend in general but yeah I
agree
okay so this is something that we need
to we need to figure out I'm happy to
try to provide some some data about what
what I'm what I'm able to find about
this and and based on that we can figure
out what to do okay the current
recommendation is if you receive I mean
you should I mean that you should mark
is ECT mark the pure acts and if if you
receive an echo of a CE Marking of Iraq
you should react to it you should reduce
your congestion window appropriately and
eventually you should you could employ
the Jana's congestion control relaxed if
you think that you don't do that okay
does the reason the draft was
informational the Darcys informational
it's actually as it turns out it's it's
it's fairly complicated to get this
right that's what we discovered in
looking into this and it was just a lot
of there's like I I think the RFC has
like over ten
corner cases about things that you need
to be careful about and a yeah it turns
out that it's if you try to do
acknowledgement condition control you're
you're very close to shooting yourself
in the foot and you're likely to do it
so I'm I'm generally inclined to just
allow acknowledgments to flow as they do
and rely on signals on data packets to
be the more useful ones so so so there
are two things here right one is whether
you should if if Purex
is a useful efficient mean to convey
congestion signal I think they are at
their packets if you if you're getting
the signal that's fine the question is
the other question is how do you react
to this congestion even either only with
data packets reducing the congestion
window in case you have data packets to
send in that direction right and if you
don't whether you should actually try to
do something along the lines of the
congestion control regarding acts so
what I am standing is I think it's
useful to to receive information through
acts I think it's very useful to
actually mark acts in order to avoid to
get them dropped I think it's useful to
get to get them as a me as a vehicle to
get to obtain a feedback on congestion
write about the problem the problem is
that when you're getting so yes the way
I see it right the easy and marking
that's happening on the flow that's only
sending acts is getting a signal on
bites that it's not counting really so
it's a weird signal and so I'm sending
you acknowledgments and then I get easy
and marks and then I receive that signal
back what exactly is that signal telling
me that my rate is too high yes yes
therefore has to be the number of acts
I'm sending times 40
no but that's assuming the case that
you're only sending that you're only
sending pure acts correct that doesn't
have to be that case right you could be
sending some pure acts and some data
right
I'm not saying it's common I'm just
saying it yeah okay
I don't think about that and and and the
other argument is in their argument is
is that you you want to avoid acts
getting more drops Purex getting more
drop right because if you don't work
them right if you have a high load of I
mean how congestion then acts get
systematically dropped right and and
then you're in very bad shape you're in
worse shape than if you if you write
when compensating for it fair enough
right that's what I basically wanted to
say I think there are corner cases where
you have like a very very low rate a
very congested link where it actually
helps maybe not in a general case so
this might actually be there might be
room for experimentation here what
what's the right thing to do so maybe
you just can't give a recommendation
that might be useful to change something
in that RFC 56 90 is an example but
there's further thinking needed here all
right Briscoe I just wanted to emphasize
that the case that muscle that just
explains Jana where there's a mix of
your acts and data that's why we said
must reduce Seawind because then if you
are sending data that will affect that
data and if you're not sending Daedric
won't know what you don't have to do the
may but the point is the congestion is
probably because someone else some other
flow is sending data
you know maybe someone's uploading
something that's how I mean certainly
congestion control should work that over
over a round-trip time the probability
that you get a mark should be on all
your packets not not just on those that
have data yeah
otherwise you're ignoring some of the
drops or marks or the problem the
problem here is that we mark the marks
you're getting is actually related to
this the other side's condition window
not yours because you're simply sending
acknowledgments back in response to all
the packets you're receiving and those
are getting marked you look at those
marks and reduce your own condition
window that's em silly because those
acts are not constrained or conditional
because if if you're sending excuse me a
small amount of tighter your congestion
window is not gonna reduce and you're
still gonna be able to send with it1
it's only if you send a large amount of
types the congestion mean that's going
to restrict you so you're you're okay so
yes your congestion window is a large
amount of data but you're reducing the
congestion window yes you're not using
the condition window but you're still
reducing it yes so you're reducing
something that you're not using yes and
to me that just seems like yeah you know
well but you were using juice pack
you're congested window if you're
effectively got an idle connection or at
least an idle half connection but you're
getting seeing some congestion then you
reduce back faster so if you do start
sending data you're you're correct you
know you're using all information you're
getting okay actually funny enough I
think that you could actually make I
think you could actually use this
information to keep a regional track of
your of instead of completely starting
from from slots that again you see what
I'm trying to say is you get some
information you can actually try to make
this to be an accurate estimate for a
bit longer than then what you would have
to track more state based not not just
state but you would have to track at the
receiver roughly what the other side's
condition window is not the other side's
conditional you're trying how many acts
you have outstanding in a in a
round-trip that's currently something
that you don't try but yes
yes yeah I don't think we want to get
into sure it still seems odd to me that
you could have a condition winter of ten
thousand and ten thousand packets and I
have a condition window of ten because
I'm not use anything yet let me give you
I'm reducing it to five because I got
conditioning I think a different a
different argument so I think there is
value on on ECT marking Purex agree with
that yes okay we cannot not react why
not
because media doesn't like it no I mean
no I mean no one said purely the fact
that you get congestion marks and you
don't react to them that's something
that as I understand some is a message
that we don't want to give tonight in
general
I mean if define is so the thing is that
I'm getting condition I'm getting C e
marks on my a crate so if I'm not
reducing my a crate but I'm reducing my
condition windows it seems oh sorry
sorry sorry sorry sorry sorry
a couple of things first you are
strongly assuming that you're not
sending data which is I don't have to be
true no idea you don't know what sin are
you you are ok enough so I agree that
what what your what your the scenario
that you're suggesting is fairly common
yeah I'm not I'm not don't know right
yeah and again you can know it but but
let's go on yeah weird optimization
right if you only send in pure rock for
the last ten round three times or
something then you don't react to
congestion but at that point I would
like to understand a bit more what what
usually do with the congestion window
because as far as I understand if you
don't send data at some point you you
just reduce the congestion no the most
common deployments won't reduce and you
won't even if you have an idol an either
connection they don't start with slow
start again anybody here who does reduce
condition window an idol raise your
hands please now
you own your laptop in your specs yes so
the specs will reduce the condition the
spec says limitations may not okay so
it's not it's commonly not reduced okay
which is one of the reasons I was
pushing for pacing as one of the things
that you want to have in after idle but
yeah that's yeah it's not reduced you
know the car doesn't get you don't want
to reduce it I mean it seems it well you
don't know having conversation have that
here but but again the the simple thing
here is that I'm trying to tease this
about in my head and perhaps it's just
my confusion but it seems like a sender
is sending packets at a certain rate and
that packet rate it's ax is basically
directly proportional to the rate at
which I'm receiving packets yes yes I'm
not getting marks on these and I'm going
to go reduce I am variable reduce my
accurate I understand you're right
that's disagreeing with you yeah I'm
just no but it so you can do other
things with it a congestion control
being one of them but reducing the
congestion window seems like an odd
thing to do okay so doesn't it
basically the to summarize I understand
that one option would be to detect
whether you're only sending your at and
at that point avoid reducing the
congestion window that that would be
your suggestion if I understand yeah at
least in that case I don't think that we
should be reducing the condition without
seams and not and you still don't want
to do your well even I may seems like
the right thing to say that I'm saying
that it's gonna hard to get this right
people are unlikely to actually do
something that just realistically
speaking in terms of also in terms of
data rate again the same thing comes to
mind if I'm if I send one packet and
then 1,000 acknowledgments because
that's the rate at which I'm that's the
number of packets I'm receiving this is
common by the way right I send one
request I sent I receive a whole object
back so you're sending me 1,000 packets
and then I send one packet out so if
that happens that's I'm gonna reduce my
condition to again from ten to one that
that's why am i working was if you have
a send data for I even peeled that needs
to be determined right I mean so maybe
we can include that particular situation
I'm just saying that that's that's a
proposal I mean then with you how much
for how long you haven't sent data and
that's a but first let's agree on the
approach and then we figure out how to
tune the parameters yeah and I'll say
that it still seems it seems to me that
if we are looking at signals on ack ack
packets those should actually apply to
the sender of data because acts are
simply a blind response to the data
that's being received because those are
its yeah those aren't directly control
right now
and that's that's what I'll say and we
still have eight slides to go into
presentations on closing the line of the
Corey vehicle even first of all on
Tanner on changing the congestion window
say the problem is congestion
information will be outdated after a
while like in both directions if you
increase your congestion window or if
you reduce your window and say if you
don't send any data you have like
outdated data information about
congestion you don't want to react it
but I think that's true also for having
like a large congestion window left
after a certain idle time it just
doesn't make any sense anymore because
because it doesn't reflect the current
situation on the link
say maybe this can you can be used to
reset the to the initial window quicker
then we do it right now reducing it
below the initial window probably
doesn't make too much sense and then my
second point was because he said we
should not not react to it so first of
all there are two things one is you
not send a marking if you cannot ever
get feedback because then you cannot
react to it if you never have fun back
then you can for sure not react to and
then if you get the feedback you should
react somehow to it but it also doesn't
have to be immediately you can also say
I'm reacting overtime at some point if I
have a certain number of markings or
whatever so what the reaction is this
very can be very different
okay okay just just to to summarize your
case I understand I think I got all
right um just in response to Jana I just
wanna put a scenario say you're using
HTTP too and you're you're doing
byte-range gets and so you're getting a
large number of packets each time you do
one and then you're sending a little you
know now that byte-range get and you
know you're controlling what the
server's doing over multiple streams all
in one connection and then by your logic
if one of those byte-range gets gets
marked you would sort of residual
Seawind less than if a large packet got
marked at you know you know I'm trying
to do the case between a little ACK
packet a small get and a large data
packet and I'm trying to say that just
because the acts are marked is actually
telling you what your congestion window
reduces to correct so it's only reducing
it's never increasing this is Michael
speaking as a first for the remote
participants is very hard to follow
conversation and second I've actually
close to Mike so it could be please make
this quick
quick very fair keep choosing quick at
the moments not going to simplify things
okay so just two points and they are
quick the first one is if the accurate
is introducing and we're seeing marking
them then we're always going to get this
reduction so c1 is just going to drop
into the floor isn't it yes okay the
second thing is we did all this quit
when we did the cwv stuff in was it
seven six six one and we got some
conclusion there it seems like we're
reinventing the same thing here so let's
just think what happens when I'm not
sending data the cwv work we did in TCP
m76 61 okay which is what applies when
you don't send data and whether that's a
good choice or a bad choice all you need
pacing etc so I was just saying well
let's take that one into consideration
when we think about what's doing
that's what media was I know in three
okay good thanks we'll do that
so please continue but I keep it as
short as possible yes I will try okay so
we are also we are also proposing to ECT
marks on the transmissions so in this
case what we did is we strengthen the
language regarding on the checks that
you need to do when you receive CE mark
our transmission with a city mark
next we also propose to mark a finn's
and besides there is a kind of trade off
here on one hand and you if you mark
them you protect I mean you cannot react
to this right I mean there's no reaction
if you get a mark on on a Fenian our
reset right there is no more data to
send so that's it so why do we do this
well in order to prevent them from
getting more drops when there is a high
level no I mean there's a high number of
marks and so the counter-argument for
not doing is is is that if you mark them
if you enable for them to be marked then
they will not there is likely to there
is less likely they get drop if you're
they're heavy load and when you are in a
deal in a Dios attack or something like
that
the the the the attacker can actually
use this in order to send this this
handful packets with with less chances
to getting dropped but however so the
first thing in the first observation is
attackers will send them marked whatever
in no matter what right no matter what
our RFC says or what our specification
says so we cannot do much about them and
on their hand if we allow them to to get
to be ECT mark then it is more likely
that in normal situations they will
actually get that so why that's why we
decided to go for it
next so we did a lot of progress since
the scene since in since last since last
revision again thanks all the reviewers
it was very very helpful
and this is a summary of all the changes
I'm not going to go through them and
undo as Andrew burger it is very good
question
does this mean that the network devices
can completely remove all the special
cases for different kinds of teas if you
can drop packets in they're easy and
maddening decision sorry what what do we
might remove so I present ah no I say
one misconception is sorry
so we did we did a few experiments to
get some data about this this is
basically an experiment we're trying to
figure out if using ECT marked packets
for launching an attack is more
efficient than sending regular packet
right given that switches are supposed
to turn off ecn treatment when there is
a high loss
alright so next slide so easy what I'm
not going to go through this but
basically what you see here is different
situations where there is an attack that
it's there is a TCP flow either ecn or
non-linearity incapable that it's being
used and suddenly attack start right so
the ASEAN the ASEAN flow
the legitimate flow is the one that it's
in black or in red right it's very hard
to square so basically what you see is
you are launching the attack with ECT
and without the city and basically what
we're seeing is that the reaction is the
same there is a slight difference
because at some point the the ACN
mechanism in the the ACN mechanism in
the router is still working but suddenly
it gets deactivated actually it gets
deactivated in these red lines here and
then after this is exactly the same so
we actually we don't see too much
difference if you are using ECT mark
pockets when you're launching and
attacks and we're using just regular
packets right so basically that's that's
the conclusion next life and then we're
doing a bunch of experiments on figuring
out if these actually if ECT might
control packets and we transmission is
all this type of packets actually get
how they get processed by the network
and by the servers right there are out
there our conclusions is basically this
that they basically the same treatment
than ECT mark packets right and and then
normal packets right when you send no
regular ecn on data packets whenever ECT
packet initiative data packet goes
through control packet gets through as
well and so there is not too much
difference there is no special treatment
of control packets as what we can see
now so we're going to report this I mean
the data set and and the results of our
experiments in probably for the next for
the next meeting and okay and we have an
open issue I was thinking that it was
the last one so this is one open issue
that both Pat McCrory brought up that is
what happens if because you send the ICT
marks from the seamless was and and and
and you managed to see that EC end
plus plus is being supportive along the
path what happens is in the middle of
the connection you start losing ECT
marked pockets or DCT control mark
pockets right understood that that
because there was some changing the
routing and now suddenly you get a
different middle box so is there any way
you can actually react to that we
haven't actually come up with a very
neat solution for this at this point
it's still an open issue I'm not seeing
that it's very pervasive the fact that
control packets are treated differently
than data packets so this is not we
don't see that this is there is boxes
that do this specifically for for
control packets this may happen to you
sorry we do haven't found any right
sorry sorry sorry yes we haven't found
any cases that that's that that's that
that's the situation right so probably
maybe that's not a big deal I don't know
media me a cool event um this is an open
question for you CN in general so you
need go she ate you CN you mark your
packets and then you take that something
goes wrong and then you should stop
marking your packets yes say and like
yeah we don't really have a good
solution for Italy for easy and in
general if we would have a solution
would be the same solution here so I
don't think it needs to be addressed in
this document that would be great please
go to the mic if you comment something
so upset you can't detect it you can
detective Swiss I could easy end when
you have to accurately see an option go
to the mic you said you cannot detect if
you're using pure X okay so we take this
to Middle East I'm mouth fear well next
steps so we're going to post zero one
version that actually incorporates
actually I've been so meters already
that incorporates all the feedback and I
mean and all our changes reacting to
those to those comments
hopefully we were able to address most
of them I would really appreciate the
people who actually review the document
can check that it reflects what you
wanted out of the document and we need a
more measurement so we have done a few
we hopefully we hope to to report
probably in the next meeting what what
we found and more measurements are also
welcome and more reviews as well but I
think the the document is in pretty good
shape thanks to all distributes that we
had so I think I think we are we are
pretty good done
thanks sorry for being so long yeah okay
so this is Michael speaking and this
this time more or less is chair so I'm
wondering a little bit about the cross
dependency between EC + + + + equity Zn
I'm not really asking that to you um
it's more to the working group so
because I understand there are some
cases where the the two could be
deployed together or if even get its
value if you use them in combination but
my question to the working group is is
is there something that the working
group really believes is an important
case as I just explained why I'm asking
this this could mean for example that we
have two that we could publish the
document together something like that it
so I'm particularly interested in cases
where implementers would only implement
one of the tool so just just to to help
with this question this is the summary
right I mean basically what the
dependencies as of today if we don't
change the products and stuff right but
what the draft dust
reflects today is this right the
dependency is on the scene right all the
rest it's okay
just to summarize and yeah and one more
thing to add there's a dependency in
this direction but not in the other
so expertise en doesn't depend on this
document yes there's a dependency of
this ECM + + document on equity sin but
there's no dependency of accurate easy
and on ECM + + correct yeah
I'm more interested in if for example
implementers would be interested in
implementing that and have no plans ever
implementing a Christian so that would
be something that we would have to
understand from a process perspective
yes yeah so Bob Briscoe and maybe I can
put this in terms of companies because
that it the RFC 3168 columnar is more
for people over already deployed ACN
3168 like Apple all right and what this
is saying is you can get the advantages
without also implementing at crazy and
if you want alright but you don't get
the advantage on the sin which is one of
the big advantages so it's it's sort of
to allow companies like Apple to think
do we want to do that so yeah I never
send a perfect game or as I said I'm
asking the implementers in the room I'm
just making the question clear to them
me I could live in again I'm not
somebody who's going to deploy that but
I think one of the biggest advantages is
having it for the student so I yeah I
mean yes but or for the soon we could
also find for door once I think I mean
it depends but but as I said my my
question is more on the implementers if
there's a strong case for implementing
only a ECM plus plus and not a tradition
right that's not it I mean it's
important for us to understand how
closely those two things would be
coupled because it it impacts the
process that we have to write and and
not only the process but if that's the
case that I would assume there will be a
strong push back to make the dependency
of the scene right so we probably need
to look if there are other ways of doing
this for example and that's why we would
really like to understand that case as
fastly so one of the problems with the
send case with ECT is it's not always
obvious what the fallback case is
because there are boxes which hatch on
the ECT field effectively because they
take the whole type of service and so
currently you would establish a sin and
ECT is zero so it's fine if you
negotiate ecn you end up passing in an
anycast network to a potentially at
different box and you get a reset
if you do it straight away with ECT and
you just get a reset later on it's
completely not obvious that that might
have been because it congestion marking
changed and so you ended up in a
different box and I didn't see really
any in the measurements in particular
the assumption is ECT makes it through
so success I'd be curious what happens
if you then change the marking to see if
you end up in the same place because for
lots of CDR networks that might not
happen I I have that date I look into it
Andrew McGregor of course if you're
hashing on the entire byte in the
presence of easy and your network is
broken so and also most of the boxes
that do that with the configuration that
was suggested in their documentation for
hashing there I have a different
configuration that does it the right way
so I'd say that many many CD ends and
they're like who are who might
investigate deploying ACN that don't do
it at the moment we do it because of the
benefit on the syn here and therefore
would want to do accurate ecn I think
the case of not wanting to do accurate
is he and kind of means you don't want
to bother with this either right that's
it that's what Bob thinks yeah that's it
doing this without basically this
simplifies the implementation anyway by
removing a bunch of special cases so
yeah you might do it just for that just
for the simplicity benefit even though
it actually has a little bit surely it
should be there should be a strong
strong case as what Michael was saying
because you will eat quite a few whole
points in addition if you wanted to
support all the possible combinations
thirdly right so so it will be expensive
if you if you want to do some other
things than this right so there should
be a strong case but that that's what
he's asking hmm yeah I think the benefit
on the Centers is most of the 1 and
accuracy in his
own benefits so yeah I think from my
point of view that the main benefit of
doing either of these things as is doing
them in combination good the line is
closed off Nepal so just to agree that
the whole hashing thing is completely
broken but it does give a barrier of
entry in terms of implementation cost
because like you end up paying the cost
and customer support for a broken box
somewhere else in the internet and so
this is a hurdle for deployment that you
have to consider right yeah and this is
the whole problem with the original
deployment of ecn which had the same
kind of implementation hurdles which
were kind of waved off because of the
huge benefits of ecn so we've been
through here before I think now Mia yeah
at Bob's house I think I'm sorry Mia
cleave and say I think the point you
mentioned with the hashing is true for
all easy end uses not only for this case
if and whenever you want to use easy and
on any packets you have the problem yeah
so while we are changing and going to
the next presentation are as anyone has
everyone signed the blue sheet so you
haven't
series whose present presenting this go
ahead
hello everyone today I'm here to present
the new TCP option tcp low latency
option and the motivation behind this
option is that the next recently L the
next thing the data center machines
recently are usually up to speed 10
gigabits per second that makes the RTT
time less than 100 millisecond 100
microsecond and this pretty low ITT time
makes the some of the fixed parameters
in RFC outdated and one of them is RFC
one one two two it defines the lay back
mechanism and in most modern operating
system it usually delays act for 40
milliseconds up to 200 milliseconds and
as you can see the delay is mostly about
400 times the RTT time and or so for a
minimum RTO time the retransmit timeout
RFC 62-38 i'm of 1 second and that is
10000 times of the RTT time and also
above the 2 above parameters that both
of them introduce unnecessary delays to
the data center machines and more so yes
so next is the FC 73 22 23 it defines
the tcp timestamp option and the
granularity of the timestamps is usually
1 millisecond to 1 second and even
though it's granularity of 1 millisecond
it's still 10 times then the RTP is so
it makes the RTT measurement from the
TCP timestamp option not that accurate
so we propose this one solution to the
above problem as that
during the collection establishments
face the local side will advertise some
hints of the above parameters so that
the remote side will pick the hang up
and then do some adjustment on the
related parameters so if you go to the
next slide here is an example that
explains a little bit more how we do
this so during this three-way handshake
when the active site sends a sing it
will include this TCP low latency option
and take the maximum ACT delay as an
example if the TCP low latency option
will specify that the maximum actively
used on my site will be 10 milliseconds
so that when the remote side pick it up
it can use this parameter to do some
adjustment its retransmit timeout and
similarly from the passive side when the
Sentencing Act it will also include this
TCP low latency option and specifies
that my maximum active a will be 5
milliseconds so that the active site can
also do some adjustment accordingly and
after the the connection is established
when the same side wants to send the
packet and the receives I received it
and if the active if the delay occurs
active then the receive site can only
delay ACK as up to 5 milliseconds as
advertisers before and also for the same
side when you when you do retransmit the
maximum retransmit time out on your site
will be set accordingly that will be it
will be greater or equal to 5
milliseconds so the format of this
option similar has some other options it
will have kind and this will be an IMR
assigned the option number and the lens
will be 4 bytes and in the initial draft
we only include the maximum active ice
so 2 bits will represent them
maximov delay unit and templates will
specify the maximum absolute value and
there are four bits reserved that will
be for a future use so as there is no
Ayana option number yet so we are going
to first use it with experimental ID so
then the kind of will do will be to 54
and the length will be 6 and the
experimental ID that we get is of F 990
and the rest are the same so when when
when the user wants to spell to use the
specific maximum actally the appellee
the implementation should know it's a
must must provide a user API to
configure it either for a specific
connection or for all TCP connections
Thank You Carol
ok so we are proposing that in Linux we
will use 2 if he is one as through the
IPL command so you will be able to use
it to specify a maximum activate per out
so that all the connections going
through this route will use that and the
other is through a socket option where
you can specify this for a specific
socket and the implementation should use
a value as close as possible to the user
specified maximum at delay oh the reason
we use as close as possible it's mostly
because the because of the timer
granularity limitations on the operating
system if the user specifies a timer
that's but too low will be rounded up to
whatever the operating system supports
oh and when the user specifies a maximum
ACT delay this will be announced in the
TCP low latency option and this option
will be only included in sing and sing
act packet and we're normally we're
hoping both sides
support this option so that it will
advertise their own map option to map
value to the other side and we are also
proposing that if the active site does
not announce this TCP low latency option
the passive side will will not announce
its own value just to be conservative
and when the receiver receives the
maximum ACT delay value it can use it to
adjust its read retransmit timeout
calculation and according to RFC in 62
98 it currently now does a maximum of
smooth RT t plus k times RT t variation
and then and do a maximum of this value
with a 1 second so if you receive this
maximum active a from the other side
then you no longer are you no longer
bound to this one second upper bound it
will now you can do smooth RT t plus k
times RT t variation and then just plus
a maximum active a received on the other
side and nor so when we are trying to
compute the probe time out in the rack
draft
initially it was using this there is
this WC tell act ii initially it was set
to 200 milliseconds now if you receive
this maximum active a value you can
replace that with with switch what you
are receiving and the status of this is
we have already submitted the initial
draft and the draft the second draft as
is currently so the first draft only
includes the maximum actally and the
second draft will also be including the
micro time microsecond time stamp and
the maximum x value by maximum active a
has been used in who those things 2005
and the microsecond time stamp option
has been used in Google since 2000
and we are also currently working on the
upstream Linux implementation for both
of them and we're also hoping that other
platforms or operating systems can
support it and that's it thank you but
Bruce Kyle I've read this draft very
carefully you'll get a long written
review of it because but I you know in
the last week I had a lot of other
things to do so I haven't actually
written it out but it's if I can
summarize my comments I support where
you're trying to get to but not the way
you're starting and maybe I need to pre
pre start this with a question why are
you bringing it here presumably because
you believe this has benefit for the
whole internet not just inside Google
yeah and and then all these arbitrary
values are all wrong except for certain
cases you know that they're right for
one case and then they're wrong for all
the other cases when you've got a host
that's using different round-trip times
for different flows picking one is
always wrong apart from in a very few
case you ain't picking one for all the
connections they're picking an arbitrary
number and configure it and saying this
is the number we're going to use so I
think the way around this that way to
think about this is once a flow has
started and you know it's round-trip
time let's try and make all these
numbers go away and base them on the
round-trip time and only have arbitrary
numbers before you start like for the
sin for the time out on the sin and
everything else why does it need to
depend on something that someone's
configured rather than what you just
measured right I think the main reason
that we want to pre configure it is
because say if you're in the data center
environment and you you have prior
knowledge about what the maximum like
round trip round trip type will be
inside the error center so that you can
you you I'm not saying you don't do that
but you only do that before your flow
starts for the for the initial party oh
I once your flow started it's better to
have get you've got your art round-trip
time measurement from the handshake and
then you base all your numbers on that
and the reason why I say it the way
you've started is wrong by just doing
one of them first which is the initial
RTO and not doing the delay back it
means you can't reduce the initial RTO
because you haven't reduced the delay
that whereas if you you know because
otherwise you'll get spurious
retransmissions so you need to do them
all together and then you'll only need
one bit to say I'm doing this are you
know I think I think thinking behind
this is during the step a connection
establishment phase you communicate this
with each other so that's before the
before the connection builds you adjust
its corresponding parameters so that
after the connection establishment is
finished then you can use this yes but
but the point I'm making is that you by
that time you both know your own
round-trip time and you both got an
estimate that's reasonably the same as
each other so if you just then say right
we're gonna use our my own our own
round-trip time I submit we don't even
have to tell each other what it is
because we should have both measured a
similar round-trip time yeah Gorgo
Bob by your argument why do we even have
this Matz audio or whatever your
limitation for on RFC's no we also have
that for the data yeah the the issue is
that the the thing that we're
advertising is something that the
receipt the sender can't necessarily
know what the receivers policy is so
that quick because you typically what
happens is the sender sends a bunch of
data and you're not seeing any delay tax
because you're seeing because you're
sending enough data packets that the
other person is acting immediately and
the thing is you don't know what the
other person's delayed Act policy is and
tell you how does various retransmit
so that there's you can't really measure
the other person's delay that policy one
bit says we agree with both policy okay
so so you're you're basically suggesting
compressing the option to agreeing on a
new good value and agreeing a proportion
of your round-trip time is through all
these values okay I see so you're okay
so you're suggesting that we would have
a standard fraction of the round-trip
time that would be used for they'll be
used instead of the Internet is is
potentially talking to a media server in
in your home
you know with it with a 500 micro second
round trip time and it's talking to a
another host that's got you know to 200
millisecond round-trip time over the
other side of the world so you can't
configure it to any good value in our
experience the the the things that are
really constraining the delay back timer
are sort of end host considerations that
have to do that time alert granularity
of the operating system and not really
much about the network path okay the
formula if you can go back two sides
that one having the configured value
once you've got started as as a minimum
can be awful you know it it's really
unnecessary once you know your
round-trip time so then still have to
wait I don't know what you you saying
this was it 200 no 200 milliseconds was
it was something we're suggesting that
the receiver would decide what its timer
granularity is or what its timer value
is for it's too late I might advertise
that as a hint right so and we would
suggest if the value of five
milliseconds but you you think that's
too high and you'd like to use a
fraction the round-trip time okay yeah
we can we can definitely incorporate
that future dress sure hi I'm Brian
Trammell while we're talking about how
to clamp this thing so that it's not
dangerous this this seems incredibly
dangerous to me in an unauthenticated
header um because just random stuff on
the internet can say oh I I would I
would like to flood things down
up under return-path on the backside for
me so I'm actually gonna clamp your max
RTO down to essentially zero so there
needs to be some sort of there needs to
be some way that you're not going to
essentially get a bunch of spurious axe
as soon as you drive the state machine
into the point where it's going to start
um or it's going to start timeing out
there barrel race it seems like it would
be very easy to implement this in a
naive way that would um that would be
easy to have an on path device forward
to this header and drive your state
machine to a place we're gonna be
sending packets where you wouldn't
otherwise be what I'm talking about is
the the the parameters that this
extension allows you to reach down into
TCP and change seem like things that we
should consumes a little bit more
dangerous to me even than sort of the
way the báb saying things that just run
everything off the RTT right because
that's running everything off the RTT is
much harder to fake down to below the
actual RTT this is not okay yeah Neil
Cargill Google one of the co-authors of
the draft I mean keep in mind that the
the thing that we would be driving down
here is essentially a term that has to
do with the the variance of the ax we
and we've still got the the round-trip
time and the regular you know K times
the RTT variance in here so the thing
that we're changing really is this sort
of artificial one second value and we're
changing that yeah so it's okay there
still has to be demand to send okay okay
that scares me slightly less the other
the other comment that came up here to
make is actually um obviated by
something Bob said so thanks and rubric
rigor I was going to comment about
number representations but actually
that's been obviated by discussion it
seems to me that you need a little bit
more than Bob's one bit you also need to
know what the what each ins
Ayana granularity is but I think that's
but I think that's all you need to
communicate is we're doing this and by
the way the time' granularity is x yeah
i think you could find a different
number representation that might have a
wider dynamic range to future-proof it
and use fewer bits at the same time but
other than that yeah yes I know
so this is Michael speaking from the
floor so the reading is a wondering and
does this have to be in the sin because
I mean soon space is course so could
there be a design where you basically
achieve what you want your but you
negotiated after the soon okay that
would be something I think you should
think about the course and I don't know
the answer but soon spaces cars so if
you could do it afterwards there could
be value in at least thinking about a
mode where you negotiated after descent
I think we put it in the thing is
because then after immediately after the
three-way handshake you can use this
value to you sure there's a there's a
great up here but I mean it's in space
is a scarce resource so if you lose
maybe the first handshake and you can't
use it for that first handshake but you
can use it afterwards maybe that's so
good enough for as I said at least I
would suggest of thinking about if
there's no optional mode of doing or
maybe the answer's no but I think it's a
very soon space is cursed so and you
keep adding things to the sin and
soonerlater B we run out of space so we
have to start thinking about it but I
don't how good that is possible I'm just
saying it it's valuable thinking about
this okay yeah cool even I want to that
was my I hate the same comment and I
want you additionally say this is not a
negotiations it's not something where
two people have to just do something
it's just I let you know that I do
something so I really don't have to do
it in the handshake okay Jenna Inger
going back to Bob's idea I'm not sure
that that actually so the idea of
indicating wire a bit that that both
endpoints would use a fraction of the
already plus indicating the
seems like it's too much information
that ultimately both sides have to
coalesce into exactly this what else am
I going to do with the timer granularity
or the other side if I'm not going to
use it to construct this particular
value ultimately it seems pretty clear
it doesn't it seems to me that that
information might be richer than you
really care for it to be I like the idea
of using RTD but I'm not sure exactly
what to make of setting a time of
granularity instead of this number
because they're both absolute numbers at
that point maybe I was maybe I was
thinking that you both the great to use
the the coarsest granularity of the
turkey you know which is fine but it
goes to the same thing you're sending a
constant at that point now the constant
could be this or the constant will be
that yeah okay the reason the reason why
I didn't think of that in this is the I
mean Brigitte Jeff and I care already
did this thing where he was trying to
use the timestamp you know what's the
what's the resolution of your timestamp
option and whether what he had
possibilities on the way to do that and
I was sort of in my mind assuming that
had already been done amen you know
right so it sounds like if I was to so
it sounds like in the current state of
the world the you would send a bit plus
a constant and in this case we send only
the constant hope your constant is not
with you're not only saying the term
granularity you're sending this maximum
actally which i think is is wrong
because the onion and it doesn't apply
through the whole range of ramjet sound
you go on the internet it's gonna be
very badly wrong for most of them right
but as as an endpoint I have to figure
out what to do so if for instance so if
every endpoint was to say fraction of
already plus time on granularity is my
max AG delay and ship that if the words
that
they effectively ended up doing you
would be I'm saying that the endpoints
have the same information in your world
that they do here if they are
constructing that information from the
two bits that you're handing them one is
the one bit and the second is the
constant I didn't explain my motivation
my motivation was I really objected to
this line if you're going to use this
you must configure it and I thought what
you mean every users got to configure
their me no it's not it's not you must
configure it no what I meant as the
implementation must provide an API for
the user to configure it but the user
the user is not necessarily to to
confide I appreciate that but but what I
then thought is okay so how do you
configure it what you can figure it what
what advice could give on how do you
configure it and the only thing the only
advice you could give is base it on the
round-trip time so why not just use the
round trip that yes so I think in most
operating system it has a default value
there for example England let's change
it it's wrong to have X constant it
doesn't apply maybe I give you a little
history
sorry choo-choo go go we're using the in
the installed data center we actually
use the refers to a VHS Shack so even
though our design servers and you know
sometimes they talk too long RTT right
so yeah you can argue that we have this
configuration isn't less versatile you
know it's not as useful as we can get
rid of it but just by this right inside
your telecenter you know your max
parameter are tedious one millisecond
you configured right but if you can
either up this then you will tie it to
RTD but like Neos at this value you have
to do is also the max tier I have to do
is your server side operations OS delay
have you like it to come back to peak by
some data so it's not all about Artie T
on the
right that's the only variable but the
the granularity on the LTTE you don't
need this is this max activator is the
problem you should not be not just a
grant a 19-yard surety but not just a
quality old-timer but also your policy
on the right side what is a max act
delay right that is all those a brief
answer yeah I think in my mind did the
the max actually sounds a lot like how
you're thinking of the timer granularity
because it the well because the it's
yeah I mean there's some minimum timer
granularity that makes sense for a delay
DAC and I think in practice people
should probably try to delay their acts
for that minimum feasible amount and
then communicate that is a hint I'm
using their own variable name I didn't
mean the max activator that could be the
confusion um this is all different
variable names from what's in the draft
so Jesus standard granularity from 5 6 8
1 oh sorry at 16 minute where's the min
RTO in this oh you know the minute you
that's oh yes it's the one second that's
the bit yeah yeah well know the thing
that replaces it you also can get rid of
oh but I can't see max SEC no so if I so
Bob I think what you're saying is
there's a constant which is one second
we should absolutely get rid of it and I
think so exactly I was gonna say yes we
should totally do that
so the the so I think what might be a
little bit of confusion is that what
you're saying is use G which is the
granularity don't have a max AG delay
independent of G right so
or right or a mac sack delay that
includes G and something else and that's
the part that I think I disagree on I
mean I it seems to me that if what you
want to indicate is how long do you want
the other side to wait if it's based on
granularity and based on something else
then you just ship the number that you
on the other side to wait for instead of
just shipping a granularity and have the
other side construct something from the
granularity because but yeah I think you
don't want a constant value you want
something that depends on the amount of
time and it might be a fraction and the
garage yes but you don't want the
constant value there you need depending
out here is something you configure in
your toilet it's depending on what your
operation system is doing yes but it's
also not a constant it's not a user game
constant and another thing I'd like to
inject here is that if it's something
based on the RTT then we get into this
question of the fact that the two sides
don't know what the other person's RTT
estimate is and so if I'm trying to
communicate that I'm gonna delight X by
a quarter of my RTT estimate then you're
gonna wonder well what's your RTT
estimate I have no idea what that is so
I this is when the reasons why we we
were advocating for just communicating
this as a constant value at some point
in the connection lifetime and we take
your point that that might make sense to
allow this to being it negotiated later
on in that connection just a safe center
space my thinking on that work Bob this
is Bob I think he on that was that
you're also allowing hn2 to estimate you
know not use what the other end says but
use what it thinks is best
and so that's got a similar error on it
to your estimate of what the round other
ends round-trip time is the line is
close after Jonathan David black got up
to try to say something a little higher
level than this detailed attempt to read
to redesign it based on power point
which is this mechanisms clearly
been designed and is in productive use
in data centers where you know Apriori
the exact characteristics of the network
and as a result advanced configuration
makes sense because somebody actually
does know what's going on when you
brought it out to the broader Internet
that a priori knowledge is no longer
necessarily there and so there needs to
be some way to check that oops we goofed
no it's not working the way that the way
we expect it to and therefore what we're
going to do what's appropriate for our
higher delay path the round-trip time
sound like a good way to go there which
is if you did something like this and
then check the round-trip times all of a
sudden oh good lord the round-trip times
75 75 milliseconds maybe we didn't want
to do this that would help greatly to at
least back out of this when you discover
somebody's put it in the wrong place I I
just wanted to say I think the mechanism
may not be perfect as specified in the
draft but I think this is definitely
something that we should be doing and
you know I think that's exactly the kind
of thing that we can hash out over
multiple drafts in the future but I
fully support the work I know there's
other people doing work in this area and
I think that TCP M should be taking this
on Thanks you could live in adding to
David's point so I I know that you did
this because it's easier for you but if
you have a prior knowledge a probably
knowledge then you can and you can
configure it everywhere you also know
what the other end is doing so you don't
need to exchange information anymore
say I don't think the data in that case
is the interesting one here except when
you have data centers big enough that
you can instantaneously upgrade all your
machines to the next operating system
provision which i think is the the kind
of situation we run into also there are
more situations coming in coming down
the pike that are where this would make
sense so for example in in cloud
scenarios where you might have thousands
of machines in the same data center but
they're all
different vendors different operating
systems and they need a way to know what
the other person is gonna do this is
we're thinking this might be useful
Neal Cardwell Google and since we've
closed the lion as our two sentences
know we've closed the line general anger
Google I I think what Jonathan said that
I think broadly speaking the problem is
interesting I agree with Bob completely
that the one second is arbitrary random
is not used in practice so it's actually
quite nice to be able to change that and
maybe think about something more
realistic and more useful and more
practical that can be used then so the
one second
maybe the precise mechanism here is not
something that we may want to do for the
broader internet I think it seems like
it's closed and that can be hashed out
over time I think there was one sentence
actually very long one okay so I think
we had enough discussion on that one I
think there is some positive feedback
here in the woman general of course the
details of the probably need to be
reviewed so I think be encouraged the
author's to look into the feedback that
I got and possibly come back to us with
a new version next presentation hi
everyone my name is Safi Cole and I'm
going to talk about TCP control block
interdependence so a quick recap what we
have done so far so the reason for this
base revision was to provide an overview
of the current implementations so far we
have data from freebsd linux and windows
and we want to provide clarification and
updated machism details at the key
issues that we address to provide better
details on share tcp parameters and
shared algorithms and we want advice on
the limits of sharing when to share and
when not and also we want provide
interaction with TCP options we have a
data table for it and also we have added
all the listed all the options in the
appendix X like this so we actually
current we are currently seeking adopt
what group adoption
BCP so that we can recommend best
practices based on the current
implementation experience and if it gets
adopted we want to fill out the TBD s
related to sharing table and focusing on
the known safe behavior water okay to be
shared and what a problematic in the
internet today and we want to leave the
cost-benefit decision to implementer but
explain the aspects of taking such
decision and we are also open to finding
information related to other operating
systems thank you so this is Michael
speaking this time is chair so then the
situation for disrupt is as follows
we've run an adoption call on the
mailing list we didn't get a lot of
feedback as actually be got zero
feedback and that's why we wonder or we
would like to check in in the room if
there are thoughts on on this draft so
at the moment the feedback that we got
is honestly speaking and not really
sufficient to adapt it and the working
group so that's why as a first of all I
would like to ask you mother any
thoughts on this document any feedback
that you want to give the orders or any
reasons why you've not commented on for
example on the other optional things
like that
Andrew McGregor I didn't comment on the
adoption because I wasn't paying
attention on the mailing list
it's a widely deployed behavior it's
sometimes problematic and sometimes safe
and I actually think there is value in
documenting when it is reasonable to
configure this and not and of course
there are always going to be parties out
there who configure it in a radically
different way that aren't talking about
but you know at least documenting the
basics of why it is and is not safe to
do share various various of this data
has value so I think it is worth
adopting even if
it's insufficiently controversial to
attract comment okay then the more
formally speaking I'd like to raise two
questions to the room and to check the
sense in the room the first question
that I'd like to ask is if if there's a
belief in the room that this is a verse
wall to document in this working group
and so I will ask two questions I will
asked first if if you support it and I
also been asked if there are any
objections so that will be the first
part of the question and then in the
second formal question we have to stay
Jewish out there so there are a couple
of different things what we could do
here the you can see on the slides the
also is proposed this as PCP and it's
also possible to do this for example as
an informational document so that's why
the second question that I will raise to
the room is if their support for this
being a PCP so but under the assumption
that we get some positive feedback for
first point so starting with the first
question and maybe we do it with a show
of hands for that one so if the please
raise your hand if you think there's
value in documenting that behavior in a
TCP and document sorry dish show your
hands okay so for the note takers this
is of the order of ten people and it's a
pretty strong feedback and is there
anybody in the room who thinks that is
not a good idea to document this
behavior so for the note takers there is
no objection so there's clearly a sense
in the room there's value in in
documenting this behavior now coming to
the second question so on the stators so
in in particular among the people that
think there is value in here as those of
you who think that this should be a PCP
please raise your hand
and I see and maybe I have to add I mean
maybe working who can change the status
afterwards after the question is
actually about the milestone that we
would add to the Charter so to be
precise Sodor Aoife has to here I would
suggest in a discussion that we should
postpone deciding whether it's a BCP
that he could be a BCP from my point of
view if lots of people here say this is
the right document and this is the right
advice it could easily be informational
if people didn't actually sign up to
that later on um maybe we don't have to
decide now is my yeah complete you don't
have to as it's actually correct but the
I mean we don't have to think about it
if there's no support for it ever being
PCP so I fully agree in this was of one
of the options that I gave in my
adoption called that the postponed a
question but I still am in particular
interested if there's support for it
possibly becoming a PCP Jahangir Google
I'm I'm not very excited about it the
coming BCP I'm more interested in it
being informational because I think
there's the the rat hole of hey this is
what these implementations do now let's
discuss if that's a good thing or not
I'd like to avoid the second one because
I think the value in this draft is the
first one which is this is what
implementations do so I would like to
add something as for the meeting minutes
from ITIF 96 where I lost and you
mentioned as well so what what last
suggested to have it as BCP like putting
BCP with an appendix where all the
informational stuff should be sent to
the appendix and focusing on what are
okay to be shared on what are
problematic today so then basically it
would fit quite well and that actually
we want to propose and we want to like
we intend to do i I've had long trouble
with the BCB line because we don't have
a place to document deployed stuff we
tend to push it towards BCB it's hard to
make judgments about things that are
deployed if what we want to say this is
what's deployed not necessarily this not
necessarily say this is
best practice but I think that's that's
finagling that can be done later I'd
like to have a whole new thing called
deployed current practice or currently
deployed something or the other BCP but
yeah so I have in the line which is not
me so hello it's only been on I mean
only the only type of help that was
offered so far has been in terms of
helping document whether implementation
ideas to get clear practice clear
recommendations about about the current
practice and what should be done if we
just hand wave about possibilities
informational RFC really helpful and
this isn't really about the working
group input so the CDs to be found in
almost all of them were about what is
for even what is it people are figuring
out what is safe and what isn't then for
the working group the PPP I think in
another quarter gen Iyengar Michael how
do you define safe this is one of the
issues right and I fear that this is one
of the rat holes that being able to say
that's such-and-such behave we can say
what's conservative but things have been
implemented for a very long time
you know firing MSS sharing cotton tubes
but the fact that things that if these
are things that are deployed in
operating systems and are used right now
it's and the internet hasn't actually
collapsed I would say that there perhaps
safe from one point of view that's what
I mean it did they all safe no not all
of them sharing as a stretch isn't
necessarily see Aaron sebum isn't
necessary to see if it depends on
various things so there's a clear
distinction yeah okay we are getting
into the rathole and that's but yeah I
said this is probably a conversation for
later I think the more important was the
first question anyways right yeah I mean
the just to be clear I mean we can have
this conversation afterwards that still
I'd like to get the sense of the room
for my question we can hold off the
status discussion later but I'd like to
get a sense of the room how many how
much support we have for PCP right now
and I fully understand that this could
change throughout the document you know
I mean I would say that the conversation
around water does that we recommend if
you keep it a little if that's not the
critical part of that or if it's useful
it's it's definitely useful to have
thoughts that the working group thinks
that you know maybe this is a good idea
and this is not a good idea and so on
it's trying to have that but I think the
more to mean the more the useful part of
it is the documentation of what actually
the current practices and Romero
Guardian I you didn't get to asking the
second part of your question but I
actually think that it's situate the
feeling I'm getting from this
conversation is that there is support
for publishing the document in some form
and there is a little objection for to
it being a BCP but that I think we can
leave it choice to the authors as to
which way they want to push it and lay
someone it means when you ask the second
part of the question does anybody object
to publishing this as of ACP there's a
strong link there's a strong arm okay
since you're running out of time I'd
like to raise the two questions and we
will figure out afterwards what exactly
we do
have to talk or ad on on that one so um
the question to the room is so please
raise your hands if you think or if you
think that this can be coming at ECP so
please raise your hand now if it can
become a beast PCP it doesn't mean that
you think that the current wording is
already PCP but it can become possibly
disappear okay this is four or five I
would say four and a half and please
raise your hand if you object or if you
think that there's a huge risk if you
would head for a PCP right now okay so
there's no significant objection to a
PCP okay as on that one we will have to
chat amongst the chairs and probably as
our ad in general the clear feedback
from the room is that there is value in
adopting this document and we will have
to figure out the formalism thank you
thank you you can kick me out now okay
so this means we're done with our agenda
so that was the PC p.m. meeting see you
in Singapore
you