yeah
check out the prison
yes I'm 30
if I eat the path you take the loss of
mine
Oh
good afternoon this is the t's Working
Group hosting the joint young session
with C camp MPLS and PC you can access
the agenda for today and the slides
using the pointers on the slide ITF note
well this is Thursday afternoon you
should be well versed by this by now lou
has presented the recent changes to this
note well a couple of times this week
this was presented in the appeal of
working group and also in the routing
area open meeting if you miss those two
presentations please do with you this
read as far as session logistics are
concerned this session is being streamed
and recorded so pleased to speak only
using the microphones and to state your
name before speaking for the pen bit of
remote participants as usual you'll be
taking the minutes using etherpad so
pleased to participate in it and we'll
be on jabber as well as far as agenda
for today goes we have three slots
dedicated for T specific crafts there
are a couple for C camp there's one that
discusses generate young infra
enhancements and we'll finish off with
an update from BBF first up is an update
on the t2 palsy traffic
good afternoon I'm chicken welcome
people reporting the status of the Tea
Party models have the authors and
contributors we still have our regular
meetings even cut them all or
contributors but a big changes okay but
the changes are getting minor now so the
tape the models are stable and we hope
to publish the modem soon I don't
requested by the
incrementals so here's the last this
type of changes we have made since last
IGF session so now we allow multiple
instances of interim they unlock IDs and
we added missing TTP ISM to Mandalay and
the way I just some attributes to the
link termination point and talent
ownership wants so we also import
handling aqua connectivity metrics
labeled and we were sharing of the tea
types between our protocol and
we also have read under genetic fungal
is modeling so now we have just um talk
to sir your comments and acted a model
to the nmda style then here's a some of
the changes mentioned earlier so he is
into the internal a anak ID so we fixed
the situation for multiple loci disease
each particular Commission points here
we changed the interlayer lock ID from
live to live so this were accommodated
this situation back here for the case
here we have to be peacefully
you have to lock IDs 1 & 2 then we are
requested by some implementers we added
a few attributes to the information
content comment dimension points so we
already have admin status and names many
entities but they are missing here under
television points so either them here in
the underlay tunnel cases sometimes we
need to specify the unerring
confirmation points so we added in the
model here so that we can specify such
conduct requirements then for the
connectivity matrix labor handling we
were raised by situation there or one
region of the involved with a table from
one and maybe change at the other end so
for the modeling we need mode and label
relationship sites label rejection from
the matrix entry to each termination
points then we have been doing this hour
long so we're trying because we have so
many similar scenes to share between
camera model and the target model so we
would whatever we can share between the
two models into two types
recently we have found was three copies
here path constraints of optimizations
and computed passed properties for those
things they are now in the gene types
proprietary we'll talk more on roles in
the tunnel model presentation then for
the Pend Oreille is modeling we had this
have been discussed before and the
recorded comments from
she come people he is also some more
comments can also suggest that we should
do more detailed modeling so here we
have inside of a generic screen we now
have routines have that a better model
here and then we had the model will be
able to buy the young doctor
so we traced all the concerns including
present continuous terminology
consistencies and some cookies then the
bigger issue he is a DA style and we
have been discussed this for quite a bit
time we all know that this is that you
actually want more tool and this would
be provided better structure and better
features so but the question is how and
one which we commute with this kind of
architecture so now a couple month ago
we have the published an MPA guidelines
so this is what we were trying to move
from current models now student late so
the proposed the Caroline is like this
so if we need I'm the in use the state
which is the case we are having not then
we can have an MVA module of life and
also companion state module on the right
so big portion of those shared between
two models and we notice that in the few
differences there I mean so the module
name is appended with the state and in
the namespace also change a little bit
and it was more here because everything
is a config fault on the right side so
this is a at a glance though the change
is not a match we can reuse pretty much
but depending on the model complexity so
this is a trivial case it's easy but a
soft case it's not that easy we need for
some restructuring and here so we have
had many discussions so she won and how
about motor so we want to hire while
modeling capability we need to maintain
our state and configure all those speech
capabilities from the modeling
perspective they also need to ring King
the protocol and application features
recipe we don't want have a model
delayed and though we also don't want to
have them they impact communications so
now since we after that many discussions
we decided to move this as quick as
possible so because we are depending on
the partly based model which is I advise
to target model so we have described it
I tries to find a lot of people and so
the advice model has screen to update to
MTA and they thanks for Alex this
happened down so then we we calcified we
it's possible for us to move to an NP
also so we have made change so I did
move our model to the main an MTA
translation mode module under man they
also added a state module the same idea
because we have used a lot of defects
which contains XPath
so it's a not led to simply very other
go P so we had to do something to stop
it now they structured according opens
this may not be the same case for every
model so we receive a found some
augmentations could be easier so in our
case the nmda model and the
befallen and the amount of pretty much
stay inside the same model they hire
some duplications
but it's tolerable here we have like
fifty percent the things need to be
repeated so basic changes like this so
you have used to have music container
and still continue then we have moved
all those attributes from the containers
inside this config and State moved to
the tyrants and remove those containers
so this is a simplified not show you
what we have been doing and then pretty
much we have the current state of a
model so we think it's pretty much
stable and we're asking for the last
call so after this model we have two
other augmentation models try some
blankets and so they are three into
partly we this model is the
told occupation so that's the
augmentation to the touch tea party
model and we have they are three key to
pocket model which is referencing poster
advice they are straight apology and the
teeth part so they also have been
updated to the nmda style because they
are little bit different right for the
augmentation cases you see here and put
my some data points for the moving to
90s so the NPA module let's play the
videos because uh we don't need to have
sides and then we have some duplications
in the state module but eleven thing
with with with we don't have any changes
to the configure module but the stay
module can be fully reused
Robertson Cisco so it's just a quick
comment on producing the state modules I
think you should produce them by hand
and you try to optimize the size of them
which is fine that's that's okay but
just as a general observation here is
the expectation is you can produce these
very very easily but just by taking a
copy of the ending and then da ma Joel
copy it change its name to - state
change the name say sir - state and
re-shared type this and keep the group
being separate and then the intention
isn't to make that state model very
short it is to make it very very easy to
produce throat in the appendix and
you're done
so if I talk to my zipper just to say
there are trapezius reduce as well
without having you
try sizes of one factor also we don't
want to have duplication right so
there's some maintainability issue the
one who however changes here and there
because if you only try to search and
replace all names its we have like
hundreds of cases right so whenever you
change this config model we need to do
the same thing again at the state model
yeah so we're we're hoping you have the
tool which can make it a fully automated
you know you don't have this and we
don't want to have these duplications
there so we want to minimize the impact
okay so um that's what - makes sense
um that's all I'll I'll check I think
I'm not too far away from it you know
you have to work to generate the same
order affordances of defensive for
transformation yeah and I think again
just an observation to the room that if
the state watches here a temporary thing
so this is not a long-term plan for
these state modules hang around once the
nmda complying implementations come
along the state modules are
automatically replicated and are not
required yeah yeah eventually when the
Netcom fund in that restaurant updated
hopefully we don't need to have a
statement but however for some protocols
with if they don't want to support the
matter for data starts this still would
be needed if they choose to say yeah
yeah
and another
observations that are run in a structure
unless we hit a limitation for the
coping cutter coping you cannot pass
predator to that so even though we have
simple differences between the two
structures my little namespace team
otherwise such a mistake so if it can do
some simple see kind of micro this would
easily can be reduced but this is not
possible here
my name is tarick Francisco so the
proposal of adding a module with the -
state and my understanding is to hold
the applied configuration or a state and
that's my my understanding yes
there is a third argument to this or
it's another state which is a automatic
or dynamic state what is the thinking
that we will have a - dynamic module
there and the second part of my question
is if augmentation other modules will
augment your your model they will have
to augment both the model and the -
state models and maybe the - dynamic
model so that's that's my concern
Robertson siscaly so this state module
serves two purposes one is it allows you
to report the before the nmda
implementations come out it serves two
purposes one is it allows you to report
the applied configuration value the
other case where it's used in the case
that probably matters here is system
created interfaces a system created
state effectively so it's required in
that particular scenario and to address
the other comment about dynamic no
there's no intention will ever be a /
dynamic I think intention there is you
require in MDA compatible implementation
to work with dynamic data sirs this is a
transient thing right that there are
implementations that support dynamic
creation of objects how do we until then
MDA comes
they did scan sectoring stay alert yeah
we're gonna go to Hutchinson - state but
that only stores can use the mycotic
yeah
so the - state my understanding is
holding the applied configuration but
not the dynamic universe in Hawaii it's
a good discussion and it's a good
general discussion but for example in
the context of tea topology model a lot
of things we do not simply consider we
do not consider dynamic data stores who
are okay what about state the state
blueburger
any hat just to be clear the
recommendation that came from the ADEs
and that is being follow through in all
these different working groups is that
state create the - state model the one
that goes in the appendix include both
applied and system created information
so system created could be dynamic for a
particular model if for some reason
that's insufficient and there needs to
be a representation of a third thing we
should talk about and that's specific
case but - at this point no one's
identified that third thing that can't
be addressed by this approach during the
gap during the transition period Sioux
hairs um I think in this hat um I - RS
chair with the topology dynamic piece
the the benefit of the topology model
with the ending MMD a well that's a
tongue twister some days is that it can
be loaded in that dynamic ephemeral
davis store without problems the dynamic
data store is a unique definition I
think you need to be careful to
disambiguate between dynamically created
stuff and the dynamic data store
yeah for that know that the same thing
we did for the I saw and I saw two
pocket models we also know that into an
NDA compatible modules and so in this
case this is a poorly augmentation so
which is similarity formed convention
infidel it gives 5 2003 I'm one of which
is we don't in this case we don't have
two hairs I guess in this case by the
our co-chair hat are you into
we're working to make the you know
there's a point not an MD a BGP model
was which hopefully is a basis for this
s are additions to BGP and but we are
working rapidly toward an M and D a
model are you anticipating data coming
from a BGP nmda based model plus an
augmentation for service routing to be
put in to be linked to your T srte
topology modeling defense right here the
I saw portion we are using the cooking
from the I saw Yama those second Marathi
Miyamoto which provides us like a copy
so in that case I saw modo I think they
are they're working on that to make it
n98 so it's no problem and some of the
TTP that's a idea this I saw we ideally
we should move that will an MD also but
the how and why it will be moving to
empty I have heard I have heard my 80s
and I am the chair and I got obey yeah
we go there okay but the quest
is more for technology bases it looks
like as a guiding share I must make sure
that it all who use the right types and
all the stuff if we do an SR extension
to put to look at stuff I need to make
sure the models align carefully and they
all should align based on an NMDA did I
understand that yes yep that's right
thank you very much for that
clarification sue this this model family
doesn't take a sappy policy into code so
this model currently does not take SRT
policy into account the one that should
hang just right it's the HP SRT epoch
apology would be in its ome ask question
clarifying question Kevin there are two
types of policy BGP policy related to
srte and basic SR topology which one
were you in play in that way right now
all this does is add as a specific
extensions to a key topology in terms of
P policy mapping that's not covered here
but yeah we can have that discussion and
see where exactly that means to be model
okay
another thing we probably need to align
probably needs to be independent but
that's just the chairs and they shall
guess I'm not the authors thank you
thank you Eric
hello everyone my name is dark exactly
and I'm with Cisco Systems can you hear
me okay in the back I hope so I can come
closer so I'm given a quick update on
the modeling effort forty an RSVP models
that are described in three drafts at
the moment the latest yang code sets and
github at the location you have there
this presentation was done on Tuesday as
well by my colleague and this is a rerun
basically at now I can go faster a bit
but please do ask questions and stop me
if you have anything to clarify so I'm
going to go over the updates to the
drafts and then open issues and next
steps first off I'll go with the updates
to the te model so before I describe the
changes we've done let me give or
recognize the efforts by Sergio it Aloha
Carlo Francesco and others who reviewed
our model gave comments and I hope we
addressed and we'll continue to address
open comments from them and for the team
for continuing to show up weekly on the
discussions to cause on the modeling so
that high level changes we've done we
moved some attributes that are packet
specific to the packet module we added
some additional constraints for the path
computation and we introduced some new
attributes for the LSP State and other
attributes to do some stitching of
tunnels the first update we're adding a
probably a year shifted the order in the
previous slide but this is the
operational state we're introducing in
the LSP
it's basically a state machine of the
LSP state as it progresses from path
computing to computation okay or failed
and then setting up and it closes up
with a state up so it's incremental
state as it progresses right the second
update we're adding computer path
properties which will hold the
accumulative metrics of the path there
are multiple metrics that the path can
carry we have it as a list and we have a
metric type metric types that we defined
RTE metric IGP metric latency hop count
average delayed actually latency and
average they may be the same so those
are identities that we can augment and
add more metrics so once once the path
is produced it can have an accumulative
affinities of the path and we're
describing those under the LSP as well
as the srl G's that are collected when
computing the path as well when we
compute when the computation engine
produces the path we are going to store
the ero that comes back or the the hops
produced by the computation engine as a
list of euros or route objects and we're
storing this under the LSP again so this
is applicable on the ingress in the case
the computation is happening on the head
end or the ingress it's also applicable
on the transit LSR where expansions of
the path can happen for loose hops the
fourth update we added some bounds on
when doing path computation or assigning
some constraints on your path
so the bounds again we have different
metric types it's a list where you can
set the metric type and and the bound
that you want upper bound so you can
basically set multiples of those in the
list the fifth update in terms of
optimization or objective function or
optimization criteria we try to model
what was defined in our C 55:41 in the
PCE space so we have an objective
objective function there as well we have
some more elaborate way of defining an
optimization metric that you want or
multiples of those that you want to
optimize for so there were there was
some vendors that thought that we could
do we they're interested in optimizing
multiple metrics although some had
concerns with that but so we have these
two ways of optimizing for a picking a
path and applying an objective function
either you'll say oh this is my
objective function I want you to give me
the optimal path or you define your own
objective function by producing a list
of metrics and you close off if you have
multiple paths that you compute engine
produces you want to break the tie
between those and pick one of them
you are tiebreakers so basically you go
over the Baths you list them by the
first metric if they're equal you go to
the second metric and you pick the one
that the winner basically at the end in
case of GAAP
so there was a the sixth update we did
was with respect to constraints
basically to realize what was mentioned
in RC 3209 and it was specific to the
bitmap and not the the name think they
named way of computing computing
affinity paths so we added the usage
leave there to allow for exclude any
include any include all so we support in
the model these three that are listed in
RC 3209 now the last update we did was
with respect to stitching multiple
tunnels together to produce an
end-to-end tunnel and for this we are
introducing a label set with with a
bitmap and an in segment and out segment
basically in order to stitch on the way
in and way out so that you get
end-to-end so there is a forward leg
there and an a reverse leg and there is
an incitement and an outside knee so
that was it for the te model the next is
the RSVP nrz Pte draft update updates to
those two drafts the summary of changes
we have not made changes to the RSVP
model should I ask questions about the
first presentation at the end or now I
know is good ok could we go back one so
just a point of information right
clarification not a suggestion underline
in your tunnels you said that was an
update for stitching did you ever in
your tunnels look at points of
encapsulation and decapsulation precise
labels yes or our genetic key model is
independent of the technology
so our labels can be packet or non
packet so we we try to define the
generic model independent of the
technology and then there are other
modules that are you know packet
specific would of labels and okay and
this isn't a generic one right so you
will notice here that the label is in
the model here the label is a
generalized label and it does not use
the packet type
so no updates to the RSVP model there
were minor updates to the rsvp-te mostly
a tutorial in order to align with the
changes with the T model because we
augment the T model
now I switch to the open issues one of
them is the migration to NMDA style we
know of one implementation that's
ongoing right now so women want to
minimize the changes or the impact on
this implementation if we want to do the
nmda migration we have multiple modules
external modules defined in other drafts
and in other working groups as well that
are augmenting our models so if we go
ahead and make a change to the nmda
style we want to coordinate with them as
well and notify them that we're doing
this and they will be impacted so their
models need to be updated and
synchronized as well we have one last
point which is the dynamic created
tunnels which is a system generated
tunnel so far we in our discussions we
were attributes of those tunnels we're
going to show up under the state leaves
so we branch config and state to show
the applied and their intended on a
fight as well as captured the dynamic so
far this was the thinking now if we
migrated to the dash state module we
were not sure if we're okay to continue
showing the dynamic attributes of
tunnels of dynamic tunnels under - state
or should we have two lists a list for
an applied configuration and another
list for dynamic created tunnels so we
have a case where in NT tunnels where
tunnels are created dynamically by the
system an example is auto bypass tunnels
or
- back up tunnels or automesh tunnels
these are created by the system and we
wanted to model those ok Rob Wilson
Cisco say if you to move to nmda style
then when you have an endgame Oh Joel
we've had the confidence state in a
single tree the operational state data
store would show you these dynamically
created entries because they're not
coming from the Dino datastore they're
just coming from the system that's fine
and you can create them there so when
you create a separate - state version
that module again you'd put the dynamic
entries in the same one there's no
original one in the - State or the
original if if you're running in an MVA
on an existing device you create an
extra - state tree to serve that purpose
I haven't state module and you write it
there so effectively the - state modules
you could think that is being like the
short hormones implementation of a
dynamic data set of an operational data
store yeah but but my understanding is
there are two data stores the
configuration they restored and then the
applied data store operational
operational and will there be a dynamic
data store potentially for tighter s but
only fights are assignee no but we have
a use case here in this model where we
have dynamic State as well that's fine I
mean you have lots of dynamic state in
the system if you have like a BGP here
that sort of dynamic state so that's
well known and not an issue I just guess
that just goes into the same stage we
like the rest of all the other state you
have okay not in the - state or the -
state module is offline okay we need the
job yeah it wasn't so clear where would
we put this stuff so we're okay we want
to move with a story and if you want
explanation on a dynamic district lad to
help you well we're the the folks who
wrote the MM nmda the the stuff actual
gave a datastore
template in our choice is creating the
dynamic data store
we're glad to help you with anything we
can we've been very helpful with the
other stuff thank you yeah definitely we
want some clarification on it so we want
to move with the working group consensus
on this so the tea topology model is is
is doing the - or - state module we
could migrate as well to be aligned once
we chat offline and clarify although
knishes in terms of next steps like I
mentioned we need to grow close on an
MVA we need to continue on working with
other team defining our pcs for the
tunnel and the path computation in terms
of RSVP base and extended draft it is
stable we think that it's ready for
working group last fall for the other
models or drafts we asked further review
from the working group and we promised
to address done thank you
afternoon rain instability from Nokia
I'm going to present updater for the
petrification request young model we out
of Quattro's and contributors okay this
is a summary of the changes we are from
the last IDF 98 so we added
consideration for status and stateful
solution try to address comments that we
received during last ideas meeting
particular family group we made close
cooperation with the eternal guys Tareq
and the other co-authors and
contributors for a eternal model and we
have solved some common issue and we had
now a grouping in young via types that
accommodate also some it's also for path
computation so in particularly for young
our PC of data we are the redefine as an
augmentation of the eternal LTC so they
our our disease is provide as an
augmentation of the eternal PC we align
our grouping in in younger EA types
common grouping and other support for
multiple paths computational requests
using more or less the same concept as
vector in this era with the
synchronization list okay here is the
there is the G table support with the
link and we use this support for
tracking young model for state officiant
to track also issue and we track some
opening we have some open issue but we
solve some sudden open issues with
respect the last IDF and we there are
other five that are being discussed
jointly with the TA tunnel model this is
the basic open issue that we have we are
still in discussion with that yet with
the eternal guides the first one is that
for topology D we solved the problem of
what is the meaning of topology it is
clear so with track but the follow-up
question is how to use this topology D
in the sense how can be chosen this
topology G's to be used and if it is the
case that among DSC can decide that
request ta tunnels at ARPA in topology 1
or 2 depending of path computation that
has been provided before so this is us
to be discussed with with the other guys
so other issue is related to the request
for to shrink a little the tunnel
parameters config list of attribute that
we should we cannot it is useless no it
is not used to use a full to use for us
because there are a lot of thought butit
are not needed for us and we agree to
have separate routing that can be used
by the path computation model specific
and we need to finalize the list of
attributes that is a real needed for us
then there is a residual bandwidth of an
issue that there has been provided at by
Daniel a presentation about this in PCM
PC this is for us his general T concept
not just for a preceptor and we think
that is a new metric for a minimum
salvadore several bandwidth and can be
help to minimize the number of odd
computation requests then there is the
request to have a relaxed about
constraint concept so in in in TCP there
is already this feature and that that
providing the fact that the path
computation must must fail if a
constraint is not met or in cases a
taxable constraint can be relaxed at
Assad the path competitions not fail so
needed again some needed also for Pat
computationally DC and and as to be
discusses that can be bring into the
context of the eternal model the other
issue is relegated a class type class
type is defined actually in that the
eternal model but is is correcting the
augmentation of MPLS we need also to
have an augmentation for just for packet
MPLS path computation what we need to
understand in which document because
actually in the ta channel the document
is the same there is a separate model
but is in the same document the last one
is is the missing local protection so we
would like to have local protection also
here in the cost of of computation like
the usage for RFC's at 32 when o 9 this
is already or covering for the eternal
regarding in case'
it is used signaling to setup for the
tunnel but we would like to have this
feature in the penny on the fact that
you use same thing so in the case of the
eternal in
case of LSP static okay next step
obviously we need to resolve the the
optin issue that is still open so
continued collaboration with ETA Tunnel
outers obviously needed to have further
comments and feedback from working group
so that there is the the the basically
an issue that issue discussion regarding
then they needed to reduce the number of
part computational requests but we think
that it is is an implementation issue is
not a problem of standardization we our
view is try to have a toolset so
encompassing both yet topology te
channel and a PC part computation to
create this tool set to provide in the
ends of of for system use okay so I
think that we think that the the the
draft is in a good shape the younger has
been extended and so I think we think we
can be ready to become working questions
holy I think a surgeon for summarizing
all these issues there are some very
important one and useful like for
example the lack of order of relaxation
of constraints that is definitely
missing and it's quite easy to address
there are some issues that I think is
just misunderstanding like for example
the last one that you said about
protection I don't think that we
actually are related to signaling in any
way so we model cheat on our model we do
not assume that it would be signaled by
some protocol and protection local
protection entrant protection it's not
only important parameter for
in tunnels but also for Park
complication and stuff like that so some
of these things is just we could just
figure you know talked and started yeah
the the think about it apologize the I
didn't even understand what you say that
it is missing in the LSP state okay come
on this is a more general comment but it
it it is highlighted by this gentleman's
slides the based apology we're going
through the final working group West
called publications of the base bottles
and hopefully the te base model many one
of the things the anchors asked us is
were we doing our pcs or were we doing
just reads and writes this one seems to
focus on our pcs along a train my
understanding is the base model needs to
be able to do reads rights and our pcs
did do I understand that in your in your
work and that's just a excuse me it's a
point of question because it's part of
the standardization process of the base
given the topic discussed in the draft
are pcs is what they're shooting for the
we will run it by the young doctors at
some point but it makes sense to how are
pieces this oh wait I totally agree that
this makes sense are pcs it was just a
question whether you're gonna continue
to keep the base model on all three yeah
this part yeah we have our pcs in all
the base models if our pcs in all the
base files but you will allow edits edit
rights and the base models as well we
are not building them at this point yes
thank you very much we typically don't
gauge the interest for a document in the
joint session but given the overlap of
the topic but PCE we're gonna make an
exception so I'll do a quick poll
how many of you have read the latest
version of this document can I get a
show of hands please a few of those who
read the document how many think that
this is ready for an option see a few
more hands than last time
we will take it to the last exit thanks
which shirt commandment so in the
interruption working group we adopted
practice to reveal document externally
twice one when its process of being
adopted and the content before working
or plus code so rather than waiting till
working group last columns and going to
young doctor you might want to review it
with external party while it's going
through working reproduction so you
don't want to focus on something that
might be changed very close to the
health yeah we don't have a set policy
on that yet but yeah it makes sense to
get the young daughters enrolled as
early
it makes quality of document
significantly better as chair T co-chair
one one counter to that is if you do it
too early you're getting feedback on
something that's immature and it may you
may change in a radically different
direction so as long as you're making
the anchors know that it's very early
and something radical my comment
becoming that we don't waste their time
there are other people who know young
besides younger doctors so you might
keep your doctors II wasn't it interview
the doctor for the record cap said we
will review it thank you eat honestly is
all woozy from away and para maybe we
can share the document with PC because
we have got the questioners in the past
that we need to keep a PC working group
inform that since there is some say
common expertise to be addressed I don't
I think it could we can do that so it's
not a problem
yeah so for we've come across this
before as you say and we've had the
agreement with PCE that T's would as its
name implies focused more on the
architecture side and and they would do
the piece upside this is a little
different because it's mechanism for
both diesel llamo about llamo that isn't
isn't easy but is good to keep a PC
working group informed it's a really
good point to raise while we're running
these joint meetings it makes it easy to
just keep this discussion in in here I'm
not sure if we're gonna you know we say
this meetings in experiment so we'll see
what happens and we'll make sure
thankfully we have the PC here so make
sure to cortex them okay yes but the
records the others could put together
all the open issues and sent it sent
them on the mailing list
so if you want to contribute the to
closing those issues you'll find that on
the list with something to the C camp
laughs now hello this is the only I'd
like to give the update on Dublin
applause young model actually we try to
augment the pasty topology model on this
particular update that's a major update
and we claim that it is an MDA compliant
as the apology claim that they are named
a compliant but I think we found some
issue when some it compiles well until
they topology update was taking place so
we have some glitches here for the
namespace on I think some of them you
know after Network types we'd have a /w
sent apology I think we probably need
some prefix on this will fix that and
other than that we didn't have any other
update but I think I remember teacher of
mentioned default frequency should be
anchor frequency so I haven't changed
that I forgot about it but I will change
that in the next revision so this is
update and I think we need to continue
to you know make some efforts online the
theater policy and then kind of copy
whatever you choose to do and really
kinda reflect put some of the appendix
issue as well but this is simple model
so I don't know I need to talk to ship
and how to do that any comments on this
model what once the key topology is
approved it but once the key topology is
approved
what's left to do in the duct so there's
a good question actually
we don't have impairment validation a
model here although in doubles and Jim
police work
we actually have that aspects so if
people feel we need to add our
impairment validation for linear
parameters to be added onto here we can
do that or there can be a separate young
model and augment at this model so
either way is fine but that's something
that we need to talk in C careful detail
it's not this year so I rather not talk
about much surer that's after this we
have another meeting right yeah okay but
actually I have another all right
actually I sent our integrated model
that we fancy model you don't have there
it's just a last paint okay okay great
yeah this is the first presentation of
chi tunnel model which is basically
augmenting she he a tunnel model that
Tara Tara presented
so the model name is ITF - TW son and it
arguments it on the model and it is not
yet and then they comply a model is
going to be also pending t eternal model
so this is a basic model that we added
we have both containers or tunnel
configuration internal state and Alice
faith and device configuration quite
simple it's not complete yet but you
just start it as a base for zero zero
zero one and you need to continue to
line with the latest updates from T to
no and any comments and I think this
might be a good place to get out adopt
it although it's a sinister version
there might be some fiction issue in
September I'd like to have this model
adopted and we have deterring the queue
let's see the how can you give me an
okay my question and I having the young
graph it defines connectivity matrix for
w.zahn networks question is why don't
you reuse the connectivity matrix that
is defined in the T topology yang model
why is it really fine for W son yeah I
think you know when I when you started
this one this is a technology specific
connectivity and it has a little bit
different implication because here our
connectivity is an old connectivity
coming inside and coming out interface
and out outside so we have a little bit
different implication from topology
connectivity matrix that's the first
stage and also I think it's about like
it's very much the same like in the tea
topology model
yeah it could be a so I haven't looked
at it so in terms of actually we
actually argument
actually we augment basic connectivity
so we do yes and then poor interface
type wise we have to specify w sign
interface reference so we do do we do
I'm sorry yeah yeah I was I was asking
why this augmentation is needed and why
can't you reuse what's already defined
in the T topology model that so that was
my question why do you have all meant I
don't believe that it's necessary but we
can take that offline okay
so really just University no I I agree
with basically today are in the
connectivity matrix we have all the
parameters including for example label
limitations and everything that are in
our view is sufficient pretty much for
always across the technology that we use
okay so there is no really need for
augmenting this particular piece of
information yes I think this is a bigger
issue I think because when they write at
this model we assume that after abstract
apology will have a generic model not
technology specific but I think over the
time you guys included various encoding
so there's some issue that we can need
to resolve because this was written
before you guys or have connectivity
might matrix right this is inherited
from gmpls so we can now take that issue
in Sycamore that was the history right
oh you started with the optical layer
then we realized that it's not basically
only specific to the optical wear and
it's also applicable to multiple layers
and then eventually it is also very
applicable to abstract nodes for pretty
much any layers when you have like I
agree but I think a charter 40 topology
is generic model so I think you are
actually violating those a multi-layer
assumption so
either way is fine but I think we need
to make a career on that because we have
other OTN and flexgrid those guys are
defining their lair specific topology
and t eternal model so I think Lou is
here I think what well well right
discussion with dieter we're discussing
a particular this like a you know first
W where a specific model if the say a
flexor great we'll need some more
information then it would be a reason
for mentation but so far neither me nor
him nor anyone who is involved in the
theater policy model discussion see a
reason for for this a good intimidation
we have teetering the queue again we
will be able to speak after them hi Lou
Berger this this is like a classic
discussion we've had in C camps and C
camp started where we come up with
something that is technology specific we
get it nice and polished and then once
we have the solution and gone through
all the the difficult details to solve
it for that one case we have to take a
step back and look at it and say which
of these things are sort of generic and
belong in generic capability so from
those who are working on it absolutely
always feels like they're done at that
point that they once they solve it for
their technology they're done but from
the common and from the the way we've
done things in a generic way it's when
they're done that they have to take a
step back and say we have to separate
this we now have enough understanding
about how to abstract the piece to the
generic and and it is it it's always
tough for the people who are working the
problem because they feel like they're
done and they just want to ship it and
then you have to respect that they
they've done their hard work and they
want to have a solution they move
forward but we part of our standard
process is making sure that we at that
point I have the aspects that are
generic representative generic fashion
and this is a constant struggle and
tension in NC camp but I don't see it
ever going away the way
just because you deal specific tech
technologies it's a tough thing for the
working group to manage but it's really
important because if we don't do it we
don't end up with generic capabilities
and reusable capabilities sure okay
dieter yeah I have one more question
regarding the connectivity matrix
typically the connectivity matrix is
there because it reflects system
limitations like switching capabilities
in the photonic switching fabric of a
w.zahn switching node my question is now
this seems to be a configurable a node
or attribute connectivity matrix is
already writable so my question is
shouldn't that be a read-only attribute
yes I'm sorry yeah for this topology
model yes for the TE tunnel model
configurable correct I think you're
right this should be a read-only you
could brew scanner so to answer your
question say for physical raw drops that
this is probably true but for example
you can see a node as a representation
of optical domain and then you actually
can configure the desirable connectivity
metric okay so you may administratively
limit for example of various
reachability from from one interface to
another you can also differently
optimize the connectivity meters for
example different paths could be
selected if you want to have a locker
different optimization criterias so for
this reasons we're in the base D
topology model way we make it
configurable okay but but for physical
rotom's this is probably limited to just
learning what is possible and what is
not okay
[Music]
just a correction to the agenda the
draft is now a working group document
the OTN tunnel model was became a
working group document right before at
the start of the meeting sorry
oh my name is Troy fan from Wow a very
agreeable present two crafts for OTA on
data models basically this these two
models had have not had technical
changes since nasta idea for meetings so
I will briefly introduce is two models
and for the Herodian topology a model is
a Ockman teeth balaji model that focused
on the in actual layer of OD n which is
outer layer and and in the model is we
define the OT ontology and for times
when the network type is o TN and we
have a name with screen type for
networks and an old and available how do
you information for link link actually
built actually and also audio term net
termination point information currently
is under being termination points but in
the main image that you call suggested
that is a good issue would be in the
tunnel termination points and this is a
young tree from the from the quality
Emoto and for the link attribute the
country the we are
to the older version of the teeth
quality model we were updated this model
and the changes are past and also move
the also move the available audio
information of all to the Dinka
attributes container and this is a
termination audio termination point
information and including the adaptation
types and tributaries throught
informations and yes no technology no
technical changes in the since the last
ITF and next step we will address the
audio termination point issues and
changes a model tool to be an FDA
compliant for the audio for the OT
internal model this draft is recently
adopted by the working group version
version 0-0 has been uploaded and the
distrust contains two your models and
one for ot and tano and there is also
our Auto for transport types including
signal crime signal types and tributary
protocol times and the OT internal model
also Audient Animoto augments te hono
model okay and for the OT internal model
we have a tunnel
we have attributes for tunnel endpoints
some of the attributes are for actually
for multi domain scenario like pillows
treatment attribute it indicates that
where there is a service in the tano is
transpose through this domain or is
switched to another tunnel or the audio
dunno in the nenes domain and the kind
source current signal and destination
you know I can be different to indicate
not bookended internal and this is part
of the this is a cop okay
eager brisk in hallway when when we
started working on t t models the tunnel
models and he topology models we adopted
strategy to produce a layer specific
limitations right and over this over
over the last couple of years and
especially this several months of
intensive discussions we came to
conclusion that this is this works
pretty good for t tunnel model but we
have serious problems with a layer
specific recommendations for T topology
model a one one is it falafel that is
that for example in the same topology
links could do one two different players
okay and it's not clear what kind of
augmentation you would use if you have
in the same topology say o TN and och
layers och league furthermore access
links could be multifunctional the
dependent on configuration they could go
the one to ten different layers at the
same time okay it could be it could be
Ethernet it could be SDH it could be F
corner right so again it is not clear
how do you do that so what we started
working on and what we seems to come to
conclusion it is better to introduce
layer specific types rather than clear
specific admin tations and we started
doing this by defining for example
earlier groupings for grantees okay that
describes the benefits for different
players as a choice statement so that in
the same topology you can have for
example links belonging to different
layers and so happened I I predict a
forty TPS so so this is a very important
question how to
to go about that yeah actually that's a
very good information that we just
learned since last ITF meeting so what
do you keep that type in a separate
young model okay and then you just
reference stereotypes yeah I think that
makes sense you know in my opinion
however hard I think to provide a few
follow-up to egos comments we're trying
to we really hope to see a kind of
stable T generic attributes and
including both the parameters
augmentations and the types description
so that we can based on this kind of
generic TV parameters to generate those
kind of layer specific tactics including
Bo's W song and note here so your person
so basically what we're saying is that
it is fine to have a layer specific
augmentation for example say it is it is
fine to have say IP MPLS layer specific
augmentation for topology and but only
if it have like a new constructs are new
in in addition to what we produce in the
base a topology model so but for example
if you want to have more attributes
attributed say to links or a tunnel
termination points it is better to
basically define less specific types and
not to use augmentation at all okay so
augmentation again you need it for
example where it's like FRR kind of
considerations which which is specific
say to take it layer but not other
layers but say if you want to have again
layer specific parameters for link or
TTP's i think it is better to to do
which is pretty much similar what we
used to do in gmpls
okay when we defined a layer specific
Elvis
ha Mahalo again just wanted more sin has
I think that at least for the parameters
listed in all this favorites ties the or
almost all the parameters are from the
existing offices and we're not creating
any any additional stuff to make this as
a new issues for the future for the
later way versions of the this maybe it
is to speak closer to the mic okay sir
yes we are
I think we can make these open issues
for discussing for for these two Krauss
and actually yeah I'm almost done and
the next step is will for the OT
internal model we will follow the tea
panna model when it becomes a mpa
combined
yes and that's our thing now we have a
remote presentation Nicola are you there
hello okay can you hear me yes
everything okay
I fine throw this draft hello to
everyone so this draft presents young
model for thanks actions and finished
state machine okay so this this as the
objective of increasing the
programmability of network devices in
for devices model with with young we
found one one particular one is case is
related to flexible transponders
flexible transponders what multiple
rates multiplication formats fact
particular population format and can be
set based on optical or physical layer
so for example copy s key is more robust
than 16 QAM and it's possible to
readjust this physical this transmission
parameters of modulation format in fact
if something at the optical layer images
so for example some parameter its
degrade to 2h something or something
like that yeah thank you so the the the
scenario we we are continuing is is
referred to to the abnormal architecture
where in particular we have an SDN
controller that configures and
configures not applying devices while
drawing the Mangler
receives and processes alliance in case
of birth and problems and if needed
configuration for for the maintenance of
of the services how can I can change the
from my oak you're not allowed to do so
just ask okay okay so considering this
scenario at the state-of-the-art without
assuming model of this draft if let's
assume to have an active service
connection then we have a decoration of
the physical layer implying a bitter
narrating does this degradation of the
service performance are detected and an
alarm is sent to the on demand at that
point new transmission parameters are
computed and after yes the uncontrolled
goes to reconfigure the data devices so
the transponder and and at that point
the service is recovered so you can see
that that this workflow implies several
tasks so can be time-consuming next
slide please
but if we apply the young model in draft
with we can do something something
different so while active connection
while the connection is ill in service
the SDN controller instructs the data
plane devices on the actions to do to
perform if an event at and so for
example if the degradation opens the Sdn
controller instance trucks these devices
on how reconfigure that itself so that
when the degradation happens
the recovery can be can be faster so
this can be done with models for events
and action and unfinished state machine
that can be included into Matt Kampf
messages edit concoct message for
example next slide please
thank you so this is the tree of the
young model for for event one leaf is is
the attribute event that that is it is a
list so for example we can have the
event bit error rate increase the
attribute to the sub leaf filters can be
used to further expressed event so okay
we are the bit error rate increase but
which which impact so this filter can be
used to put attraction so so that we can
identify if the bit error rate is higher
than this threshold so can be a problem
effectively a problem and the area area
should be done the reaction in our use
case can be the change of the modulation
format and the attribute execute
actually recalls an RTC where the task
is encapsulated so the young model for
the finite state machine extends the one
that in the previous slides slide by
including the state information and and
the transition next slide please
thank you so we in the lab will install
the the finished state machine into the
local controller of the transponder
control plane test but in practice
assume to have steady state condition
where were the the network and the
service and the service works properly I
seem to have an event of bit error rate
increase over the threshold so we have
to take the reaction of the up
adaptation and at that point we transit
to the new state his FAC adapt but from
this state we can come back to the
steady state if the bit error rate goes
returns below the threshold and in that
case we can reduce the redundancy of the
coding so that's it
this is well we can stop in at those are
further slides but I think we can stop
here so we have enough time for for
discussion if if there are comments and
so on in particularly if there are
suggestions for other use cases so since
this model is in practice is generic if
there are there is interest and
suggestions for other use cases the
comments are welcome thank you thank you
thank you so before we started with
questions this draft was linked to C
camp the ops working group and the supe
because while to see Kempe because it
started from from an
optical use Kaiser but it's a for sure
this is something that can be can be
generalized can be used in a lot of
different contests so as in see camper
we we would be happy to see technology
specific extensions but probably this
work that needs to be done in in other
places I don't know if the observer
working group is the right place or net
mod could be could be one Louis
contributing moving his eyebrows no PR
this is something we can I mean I just
wanted it to give you some background to
this like today that I'm the draft
o me Anna okay Holly I have a question
for clarification considering the the
the mechanism you delivering the
presentation my feeling is you are
trying to optimize the message flow in
order to improve the performance
so usually prove what sorry to improve
some kind of performance parameters nor
are you property additional functions or
you just try to oh you know what well
it's not exactly it's not really a
problem of optimizing performance some
performance parameters the performance
parameter we can see that the
performance we have some performance
parameter to monitor this performance
parameter as to stay inside an
acceptable range so it can be it it's
enough that it is in this acceptable
range
while it goes outside this acceptable
Ranger becoming critical so creating
problems to the service problems in
terms of quality of transmission does
quality of service we have to take some
some actions so it's something the use
case finally is something more related
to to the to the to the maintenance of
of the service
in my opinion okay thank you thank you
Greg and then deter yes Greg Norskies
City so then you know I agree with your
statement that it would be good to
extend and look at the generalization of
this I can pour into a couple things
first probably work on L map that
defined their framework and it has an
informational in data model for
controller that performs performance
measurement and then passes the
information to collector so the
collector can be the one that monitors
quality of the service and performing
measurements it uses new performance
measurement registry another thing is
that in many cases especially if we talk
about tacit network then it would not be
only one metric that will be monitored
as a characteristic so the mechanism
probably should be looked at extending F
having the policy that combines multiple
metrics and then defines an ability to
define in and out of the gradation state
thank you yeah actually like it to be
because it's very
good idea and I was looking for it to
come thank you thank you very much
yes our as I said two days ago in the
LPS meeting yes
that the work started with optics but
finally we tried to make it generic and
yeah for sure
the the packet networks are something
that we we should think about because
yeah because it's it's it's important
and can be a use case so yes thanks we
we will think about and if you find some
I will start some discussion by in the
mailing list if you any contribute
contribution and any comment on the use
case cases in is welcome regarding the
performance monitoring that that word
that you cited made in my opinion can be
parallel in part can stay in parallel to
to this to this work because we are not
defining any any way of monitoring but
yet the our system will exploit some
monitoring system so they can stay I can
go in parallel in my opinion dieter is
next yeah I have a question regarding
the use case that's used here as the
major motivation for this work as I
understood you're saying that the
optical transponder can actually
autonomously change its mode of
operation depending on the signal
quality typically when the signal
degrades you have to switch to a
modulation
scheme that also has an impact on the
service data rate meaning that it's
typically reduced let's assume that you
have an optical transponder that's
capable of carrying two times hundred
Gigabit Ethernet and in case that signal
degrades it will only be capable to
carry 100 Gigabit Ethernet or not
two times hundred keke Gigabit Ethernet
this means that this has an impact on
the service that had to be dropped and I
have doubts whether this should occur
autonomously I would prefer that an SDN
controller or a network management
system subscribes to receive telemetry
data from this optical transponder and
that an alarm is raised and then in case
the signal degrades then either the Sdn
controller has to make sure that the
traffic that cannot be carried and
longer by this optic transponder needs
to be rerouted or that the operator
takes other consequent actions rather
than letting the optical transponder to
to add enormous consequence actions that
may impact the traffic typically these
degradation are increasing slowly over
time so I don't think expect that these
changes will occur very frequently so
that those are my comments yeah this
comment is very important yes
for example passing from 6 a.m. to QPSK
without an additional
carrier optical carrier we would have of
of the bitrate the same would happen if
we work at fixed bound rate and we
increase the redundancy consider that
this work this use case comes from a
project called the orchestra were
involving operator and also bandage and
one of the use cases of the of the
project to consider that we we have in
at the optical layer some service a
service class that admits the reduction
of bitrate in case of specific events so
if we look at the literature we can find
the justifications for that despite
telecom italia and which is in in this
project I found justifications from from
that from from Nokia in in a paper of
last optical fiber communications
comforts and which is also in this
Orchestra project Nokia and there is
also some other justification from the
Deutsch tile del telecom another paper
cited in the one by by Nokia and way
this is a case is just a use case we we
are thinking to a way of enlarging the
filters because if we need to keep the
same bitrate we will we would need one
carrier more something that the
sliceable transponders admit but we will
need to enlarge the filters along the
path and we are thinking to an execution
task that will imply also the
enlargement of up filters okay we have
two more people in the queue then we
will cut it Amy thank you Amy from
huawei
I have a question sir
I understand what you want to achieve
but I don't want them why we will do in
that way because you would like to speed
up the reconfiguration this could be
done within the discipline you don't
have to help the interaction with
control or management Li and so this is
a point that I could announce them and
the second comment is that I think yes
mentioned by several people I think in
this case it's coming up some generic
and we're also working on the microwave
radio Ning and it's have a similar
feature which will be automatically
changes the modulation level due to the
external conditions so there's some a
possibility to make it's more generic
thank you thank you for the comments reg
on regarding your first comment so sorry
but I don't I don't see another another
way to to to readapt transmission
parameters without going to a
centralized controller but maybe I'm I'm
wrong but I don't I don't see another
method currently we with the current
state of the art we have to pass through
a centralized controller this is time
consuming
well I thinking you could make the
decision by the note itself and if you
find that the current bis Norris and
stration holders and the Noda could
adjust as a motivation to maybe you can
do in a proprietary in a proprietary
proprietary way but the objective of the
work is to program the to reprogram
these devices in in a vendor natural
natural way I think it's not so easy to
do that without something like that
without passing through a centralized
control
who are listed this is a common
technology which is why are using our
microwave link system I think maybe I
could talk more offline okay thank you
thank you
so few comments and extendibility and be
more generic so you might want rather
than enumerator use cases to split them
in traditional another model and to give
you ability to scale better would be
more easily to consume especially as
you're going to packet there number two
today our condition is binary if you go
to packet there it's not going to be
binary you really need to understand
what it is so it's not just also true
number three and back to Greg comment
usually there are number of conditions
so I should be able to do something like
logical enter logical or to come to the
conclusion action come it's mostly about
the suitability to higher layers sorry I
didn't catch well the the comment from
from my side and I'm sorry can you
repeat please
so number one today you're only focusing
an optical a number of cases as low as
you going the layers become more generic
it will become much larger space so you
might want to split or get the cases
okay with two actions today they're
binary it's either false or true okay so
you might want a balloon to gradual
degradation number three its ability to
combine different events okay and so you
you are you are saying you are telling
me some suggestion for for for usage of
this is model if you want to become more
generic and across layers okay okay
thank you
I see data online our data if this is
use case specific please take her to the
C camp list we're gonna start with next
presentation so thanks to all thank you
I thank you
yeah hi so um my name is William Lupton
and I'm speaking here for the broadband
forum just to give an update on the on
the yang work that that we're doing and
how it relates to the young work the
idea okay so there's the is the
questions I'll try to answer so what
what is it we're working on and what
would we not work on because we would
regard it as as out of scope
what are we currently working on what
are we published what are our sort of
ongoing projects how do we publish it
and where are young what about drafts
because people probably know that
broadband forum is a member organization
so you know the work does not take place
in public and what about the yang
catalog are we putting our stuff in the
uncataloged speak to your guests from
the fact the question is there that the
answer is yes and then also just a bit
about our you know our practices our
ways of working you know what what rules
do we impose on ourselves what about
using external yang and that sort of
thing okay so our emphasis is on
addressing requirements of our BBF
projects rather than on providing
general solutions which I guess is a
contrast between us and what you might
call core SEO such as ITF who I think at
least in some areas particularly a net
mods definitely have an ambition to
provide general solutions that would be
generally useful outside of IETF and
currently the emphasis is on broadband
access nodes so nodes in the access
network particularly or for example more
requirements from those two standards to
our 101 and to our 301 and you can see
what those are so what were we doing in
in BBF will define you know yang for our
own protocols that we've defined or
interfaces that we've specified but
we're also to find yang for non BBF
protocols or interfaces if the owner
organization is not interested in to
finding it and is happy for us to do
that and that's been the case for some
itu-t physical life standards for
example and also we will reuse yang from
other organizations whenever we regard
that as being possible what are we
working on what what have we published
well the this is just a quick outline of
our of our current yang related projects
I won't go
through them in detail you can see the
top two have been published and there's
also one that pond management one has
we've published a draft there so all
that yang that's been published is
available for anybody to see the yang
from the other projects is not yet
available but I will be talking about
that a little bit more just a little bit
more on the two we've published so the
first one was what we call TR 355 which
is young modules for ftt DP that's fibre
to the distribution point which is like
an axis node that's very close to the
home and serves multiple homes it might
be mounted on a power pole and what we
want to mostly doing there is actually
publishing some it's defining some yang
for some physical air interfaces that
have been defined in itu-t so these
being the physical layers that are used
for these this type of device and so we
did this depending on the ietf
interfaces from and also the eye net and
ITF yang types from from from IETF and
we're now working on a new version that
sort of adds some more stuff bonding and
reverse path EDA means that these
devices can actually be powered by the
the power supply from the homes that are
using them so just to give an idea of
what what the scope of that was and then
the burger can I go back once mike yeah
yeah sorry so this brings up a topic
that actually didn't come up it when you
presented this the first time but it
follows some discussion on the net pod
working group list and it's good
information for this group as well are
you aware that IETF interfaces is gonna
be revved oh yes okay good it did come
up on so I have no memory of stood in
agree anything yeah exactly yeah yeah so
it's good for us also for this group to
know to be aware that the IETF
interfaces is gonna be revved and if you
want more information on that look at
the net mod list there's discussion on
it but I've seen some in several of the
contributions this afternoon have had a
section on sort of nmda implications
right so yeah I just wanted to highlight
the one on interface runs it's so basic
and make sure that EDF was aware of it
that was really there we are now great
thank you
we are now and I think the
certainly ITF interface is one of is one
of the main ones that will impact us the
other one which is not currently an RFC
is the me entity the ITF Hardware bond
which also has that same state
separation so absolutely we've got to go
back and decide our reaction to this but
I believe I think our reaction is likely
to be similar to that of the working
groups within IETF I think no I think
quite likely to consider the same
guidance that's being given internally
right and at least halfway done this
split it just didn't make yeah but the
difference attorney being halfway done
and done is that I believe you won't
deprecated the state tree you'll delete
the state tree right the update is
halfway done it wasn't published so if
you went and looked in the repo which is
publicly available you'll see it
partially done sorry done that's alright
so yeah sorry I thought you were just
distinguishing an RFC and an ID though
right okay so yes so absolutely yeah we
have to definitely consider how to
handle this some thing you've just Paul
you've thrown at us um so the other one
we've published is I mean I don't
necessarily expect you to be able to
read that it's just to get an idea each
of those some boxes there ISM is a
module you can see the impulse you can
see that the blue is the sort of general
areas the general topics you can also
see the external dependencies and IETF
which this time does include the
dependency on when IETF hardware so this
is what we call common yang so the idea
is that this is it's sort of roughly
equivalent to the sort of thing that
might happen in that mod here but goes
beyond that a bit it's some really young
that we see being used across multiple
of our work areas even if some of it is
actually quite I mean like you can see
there's some forwarding modules in there
and some and that sort of thing so it's
not all just pure core stuff and we're
working on some new stuff too now and
you can I've listed some of the things
we're working on I'll particularly
mention the one at the bottom alarm
management we definitely have a strong
interest in the IETF alarm work which
has been moved to C camp but the draft
hasn't yet been updated in sequence so
it's not on the agenda in any way I
wouldn't be able to go to the C camp
meeting because it conflicts with the
meeting so since it's an individual
contribution we cannot force anyone that
over to to submit the draft yes well
let's just hope the buttons before the
next meeting if you really want to then
draft please reach the others sorry
please the I have in fact done that one
of them sailing and the other one isn't
here but yeah okay yeah but I'm
certainly hopefully before the next
meeting yeah and actually if the alarms
is something we're very actively
discussing internally I mean we're
definitely want to build our work on top
of the so called Valene draft the IETF
alarms draft but we haven't quite
decided yet
so what it's done we want to purely
augment it versus bringing some
proposals back into into ITF okay so how
do we do Berger again there's an
opportunity there you can present you
can submit an alternate individual draft
yes but I think we'd like to work with
the authors of this draft just note that
it's not there's not a working group
document there's no yes okay great we
have some ducks to get in the row in a
row first though you know because we're
multiple members currently discussing
various options we need to get those
aligned before we even those individual
members as contributors would bring that
into ITF I think but yeah no I'd rather
I do rise that um the thing to do here
is not just say B be effort like this
please do it IIF we do absolutely
realize that you know that doesn't work
we realize that we or our members have
to bring the proposals in we really do
understand that okay so how do we
publish it we we have our luck and
internal software release registry which
is just a grand name for a wiki page
which does list all our published
software which includes both drafts and
standard yang and we publish BB F yang
into one of our own public github
repositories but with draft and standard
areas within it but we also have that
linked into the sort of de facto
standard yang modules area via the
singer get sub module which is
essentially a pointer
within gate to another module with
another repository which i think is a
good way of doing that and there are
some examples in the background slides
ok draft yang we have made draft young
available for some projects and just
noting though that the draft yang we
make available does have a differ
licensed because we're we're not wanting
it to be used making we're not making it
available publicly for to be used in
implementations or making it available
publicly to get feedback and to tell
people what we're doing and we are
working on making that more such draft
yang more generally available I mean we
want it to be the general rule that it's
available for all projects and what's
more that it's updated recently
frequently but that's not happened yet
the yang catalog has suffered did this
more for net mod but the the all the BBF
yum the published BBF Young is in the
young catalog and I'll just quickly flip
through the UM the next three slides
just to shows just an example of a of a
query for something that was cunningly
defined to only come up with one result
and then to show the impact analysis
which and what that's doing is it's
showing a draft module which is the
excuse me I'm color blind but I think
it's green both depending on one of our
publish modules and an IETF publish
modules publish module and you can see
also that you can go right back to the
the documents and so on and will
reference there so that's mostly a plug
for the own catalog really we don't have
a policy that um that our modules must
use standard Ayana IETF young modules
whenever possible and we do by that mean
more than just it just you know
importing them we do mean using as they
were intended to be used and I've
already mentioned these grunt just
pulling them together here so the ones
we're currently depending directly on
are the unit types the young types I
have type interfaces and then in a draft
the hardware and then also system and I
already mentioned that we're also in
progress yang is also planned to depend
on the alum alarms draft and I think
finally we also have an internal sort of
best practices document which is sort of
the broadband forum equivalent of the
RFC sixty eighty seven and indeed it's
based on that and it here's to it as
much as possible I mean it's not just
specific to idea but right now i hf is
the main sto we're looking to well the
soul sta we're looking to and so the
sort of some of the categories we have
in their qualifications to or extensions
of RFC 6jg
best guidelines and we also have some
additional debía specific guidelines we
do have a plan to share this with ITF
but we haven't quite yet worked out how
to do that
and the backgrounds files have some
specific examples of some guidelines in
those two categories and I believe
that's the end and so I don't know if I
was too brief already name so if there
any or maybe this is for you to ask any
questions think we're done thanks hey
thanks for once about one question
sure comment so if you gives ago we
we've quickly discuss possibility of
start working dear on related data
models
I think PBF unknowns this morning that
they're going to create some open
consortium so we're really interested in
cooperation working together okay so
what was what was the category of SD run
right what we do have yes I right now
most mobile for working on a sort of
pretty low level um we do have an
internal I'm not sure yes I mean those
were but there's will be new projects
that ma'am I'm not sure how many details
are publicly available and I but I think
what I can say is that some whether this
would be an example of this but we do we
do want to be flexible in sort of how we
work and let me just put it this way I
hope that you know we may be able to
create some projects that are not even
necessarily just restricted to members
you know I hope that would be able to
create some projects that provide a way
of of non-members to contributing
directly to those now whether that would
be the case from what you're talking
about I don't know but we do recognize
the problem of for some people of us
doing some point we will start working
on data model for jointly service
definition an ATF so would be great to
do it together
thank you
thank you that brings us to the end of
the session thanks everyone for
participating we will see you all in
Singapore teas in Singapore
you