need perfected nopes but we do need some
notes to be taken during the meeting for
us to be able to proceed okay thank you
Dave Deb Dolson thank you are you able
to take them in etherpad excellent thank
you we're also looking for somebody to
keep an eye on Jabba for us
just in case we forget excellent thank
you very much can you announce yourself
in the Java room
we switch over to yours or no no no yeah
can you show me each other cuz mine
one's been hiked to show his general
it's really got this secretive like is
exactly we're doing do not like this is
a private meeting
[Music]
alright okay wait a minute how does this
include a coupon on this place that's
what problem is bingo I should do it
okay sorry I'm simple I can't deal I
can't deal with two displays that don't
do the same thing Oh so welcome
everybody this is the transport area
working group again and we are about to
start
I'm Gauri forest I'm one of the cultures
here we have a second culture wise Eddy
who is not able to make this meeting
he's travelling somewhere else and
unable to join us today but David black
my other culture is sitting beside me
and he's going to introduce the meeting
today okay so welcome to the first of
welcome to the first of two TS uwg
sessions in Prague this is the note well
I think there's an RFC number two isn't
updating in any case it applies to you
so we've identified note takers and
jabber scribes diverse crowd thank you
thank you all very much we as always
when the reviewers were working group
drafts will ask as we go to this session
people take a look at things and a
reminder please use TS UWG with - before
and after as part of the name of
draft submitted if you want us to notice
it
we'll say that that's what we look for
in trying to figure out what's what's
relative the meeting a standing document
view request doctor quality relies on
reviews please review documents in your
working group and at least one of the
DUP for another working group in general
if you'd like documents you care at
review please put the effort to review
other documents ok collards and status
we got four RFC's published between 1987
97 98 between seoul and chicago so we've
had no our sees published uh since then
they seem to coming back in in waves
we're working on creating next one there
are turner drafts in the RFC under queue
diffserv and with rtq OS and the details
in Kappa CTP
both of these are in miss rep state for
the SCTP end data draft about which we
have good new good good news report
there are no IDs and ietf but no no
drafts on ie less Club post ITF class
call processing but we hope to see that
change so the end data draft which is
two drafts the arcs and are waiting for
is now in ad evaluation before IETF last
call as is ecn experimentation and
within in just a little bit we'll talk
about some minor changes committee EC an
experimentation uh
there's been some discussion about will
they do about I Anna duration attract
Tom Josh and feedback we have an open
issue with that draft Leaburg last call
we've talked to the area directors will
need to go talk to the authors we think
unfortunately that significant changes
that draft are going to be required to
to to resolve that open issue or
anything the time due to feedback draft
draft offers here today we'll take it up
with them offline but some significant
changes are coming are going to going to
your card that draft Spencer
so yes mr. Dawkins responsible area
director the I did a chunk draft I'm
about halfway through idea evaluate the
evaluation on
and I really like it I am I'm generally
a decent number of comments that most of
them are questions about clarity the
easy and experimentation one versus do
we closed on the on what that really
what that one really needs to say yes
won't you that know it seems parent
ation is going to do what releasing
instrumentation draft does is it D it
documents the end of the ECM knots
experiment and provides the rationale
for making are the ECM naughts RFC of
chars thirty five forty historic we're
going to add one line to that that
removes the registration of the flag in
the TCP header that was used by the by
the ECM knots accurate ecn needs that
flag the TCP M working group will figure
out how to use that flag for accurate
accurate to uh easy end but in this
draft we're just simply going to remove
remove the registration cool thank you I
had been waiting on I've been waiting on
that window so settle down before I
finished may the evaluation of itself so
I'm trying to keep up you guys are doing
a lot of work oh just wait till you get
to some of these slides there's more
more stuff here on this one when you're
going to submit the update is that ready
to do in the next week or two that
update with me next week or two the
update will do two things one is it will
change and accelerations and the other
is it will add the ECM plus plus name
for the journalized EC and work over in
over NT CPM that that probably will not
be this week I'm going to guess next
week so I just I just found out
yesterday that the indebted draft was on
the 3gpp dependency thing which I did
not know sitting in the meeting where
they were reviewing the dependencies so
properly motivated it's the last of our
RTC web dependency drafts we are so glad
to be free
from from from that heat from that air
ball I hope just to point out you
there'll be another dependency in that
you'll need to write some or one of the
IDs will need to write some status james
thing that's correct in order to send
each an experimentation spencer this
drop Spencer baba sure money you have
another action item on your to-do list
which is an order Sinisa experimentation
to ietf last call you need to send a
3540 status change document to last call
at the same time with it and you get to
write that one absolutely cool thank you
very much occasionally we can be these
work I did to you usually ones the other
way so it turns out that public
humiliation is really motivating for IDs
and this worked just just remember that
it works both ways okay we have one idea
that's basically completing Strickland
grab last call we're going to declare
the end of that last call on the gift
serve agropoli uh a trail of and Wi-Fi
mapping draft this week that's here
we're gonna do that today and the Tim's
got a few slides on what he's going to
do about it
the good news is the mappings the code
point mappings are stable all the
changes and all the discussion is around
is Ron traffic conditioning text and
what what you do is sort of class the
traffic but not not the base mappings we
are hoping to get through the serious
open issue on the diffserv Laura effort
pH be draft today which is which DSC
PDUs once we get through that money
should be ready to go to work the last
call and we've got eight more working
groups drafts all the tool will will get
covered today and Thursday a couple for
one and two are eating encapsulation
three and four more SVT piece of
four five six and seven are l4s eight is
you the options draft but wait there's
more
as note of the mailing lists we are
announcing the adoption of the these two
FEC for two error correction drafts
Vincent our workers been working on
these I have not had time to update
these slides the agenda is updated these
are now working group drafts I will
probably might cope with spare time for
use of v3 of these slides that gets
these draft names updated to the to the
correct draft names for the working
group grass reason for doing this is th
DWG is among other things the home of a
maintenance work on transport area
protocols that doesn't justify for me
its own working group this is a
moderate-sized update to FEC and we
don't expect any additional FEC work and
that's why it's here okay
it's a red dress my long-suffering and
hardworking co-chair has written a
couple of drafts on transformer
encryption impacts and datagrampacket
ization a path of path MTU detection
more same thing about those quarry talk
to me about them if you're interested
the initial version so just talk to me
if you're interested right so offline
discussions here you may seem to come
back there are three drafts related to
TC BG that are over on the inch area
agenda this time around the interior
tunnels draft which we talked about here
number times of four MTU is a particular
particularly important topic in that
draft and it does does a good job on
that a draft on a network multipathing i
was initially target qwg it sure looks
like it is it's it's it's a more
appropriate draft for inter area because
mostly about how to send packets down
down network has in parallel and there's
a version six draft of the sun sorry a
draft for version 6 the sox protocol
again
also being active discussing in Terraria
and on their on on their agenda if you
interested in any of these three please
go to the interior meeting which i think
is on Thursday before our second session
maybe I can add on the final one or any
of these if you think there are specific
transport issues then please speak up on
the mailing list or tell us and if they
happen to be more related to some other
area in the ITF we will do the main with
them okay so we need to go I need to go
sit over in a minute to bash the agenda
we've mostly done comic accomplishments
the status milestone review is next and
then this drafts Thursday's agenda
you'll see the note well again and draft
so let me go see about getting the
agenda up on the screen okay so this
agendas been bashed a few times I was
editing it just just just before the
meeting so we do status updates um we're
going to quick cover to month or two
three once we get done the agenda bash
and then Tim's got a few words to say
about the the 802 211 diffserv draft
we've noted um these drafts as being
related interest then the bulk of
today's meeting is diffserv ecn and l4s
draft CC and respect recent cat
encapsulation drafts and then on
Thursday we're gonna take a look at a
couple of SCTP drafts RC 4960 is the
main SCTP spec the two thick frame
drafts and a individual draft from
Michael Tilson on you on some
considerations and updates to uni pain
cap of SCTP any comments questions
requests all right consider the agenda
bash let's quick knock off items two one
two one three two three we've basically
done two one
we I think we based on that you want to
to interview on congestion draft Tom
session feedback draft the outcome is
that we it's going to need some
significant more work in particular I
think we want to see a worked example in
it and we'll take this up directly the
draft authors eating experimentation you
just heard the colloquy between myself
and the area director that drafts going
to get an update on then they'll take it
from there and the end data draft is in
the is in the eighties hands and with
that Tim let me see if I get your slides
up here you want to talk about eleven
draft scream oh there we go yeah so you
have to tell me to be in slice I don't
know I don't have the remote hooked up
but that's a pointer sure okay sorry
so Tim Sogeti Cisco Systems I just like
to review where we are with the diffserv
to 802 11 mapping the mappings the the
reasons behind this of course we have so
much more traffic now that's Wireless in
fact this balance is shifted there is
now more IP traffic that is sourced from
wireless devices and wired that happened
this year that trend is going to
continue by 2021 is expected at 63% of
tropical resource from wireless devices
however QoS policies are not aligned
because we have two independent
autonomous standards bodies
administering this not administering but
administering the standards pardon me
and then the goal is to maintain that
consistency of treatment regardless of
whether the traffic is on a wired or
wireless network the next slide please
as David mentioned the mappings
themselves have been stabilized we've
had two years of discussions really good
discussions on the group and so this is
now good to go
the couple areas that we are going to
talk about have to do with the scavenger
class or the le PHP that Roland will be
discussing all return to that in a
moment
but then if we could just take a look at
the next slide I want to make the point
to is that these are already in wide use
on millions of devices from Cisco we
wanted to get with this whole initiative
started by getting our own house in
order and then we realized look why do
we have so much disparity from one
platform one software version to another
and then we wanted to do a greater
service to the Internet community at
large by arriving at a consensus
consensus recommendation so that would
have that consistency across all vendors
across not only the makers of APs and
wireless infrastructure but also
wireless endpoint devices so I think I
tallied this up it's like about 800
million devices are already using the
recommendations put forward in this
proposed standard what's remaining you
may some comments from David coming from
a security background even though in the
terminology and section 1.6 of this
document we outlined the context of the
word trust and non trusted these are
used extensively in RFC 45 94 which is
what we draw heavily from however we do
recognize very clearly that these have
very strong definitions outside of Kos
so to avoid that confusion we will make
the changes to the wording and avoid the
use of the wording Trust we will use
other things like pass through and
process and other suggestions that have
been made by David and very happy to do
that and much more intent on pushing
this through then getting tripped up on
wording the next point we do have a
dependency we have a dependency on 4590
for the goal of this draft wasn't to
introduce new recommendations as much as
to reconcile existing recommendations so
as the le PHP draft will solidify and
hopefully that will be soon the Romans
draft there that will have a direct
impact on obsoleting RFC 36 62 the
marking for this lower per domain
behavior which will now be a per hop
behavior and then that in turn has a
cascading of
don4t 594 in turn that will have an
effect on ours we're very happy to make
those changes once they are finalized
and we'll do that and then finally just
some wording knits have been suggested
and I'm welcoming anymore
during this working group last called
number two what we're asking for the
final slide is that we will make all the
changes per your comments for your
reviews I want to say thank you for
everyone that has done a review on this
so far it's very valuable I think to the
industry at large and so we really
appreciate you taking the time and
offering that feedback and then one will
make that reviews soon as within a few
days of the working group last call
closing and then we'll ask the chairs
for shepherding report and passing it
down to or passing it up to a high ASG
all right I like the done you don't have
believe so I believe I believe we're
good last call is now is is now closed
but of course somebody has any last
minute comments get them in we would
like the chairs share Tim's sense of
urgency we'd like to move this draft
sooner rather than later and so we're
gonna do on the issue around Ellie is
let's see where that DSP discussion that
we're about to have goes and if it's if
we have a pretty clear consensus and we
know where we're going we can update
this draft to encompass the Ellie draft
if however it looks like we have a long
adventure ahead of us we're gonna figure
out how to ship this one and deal with
the deal with the new improved Ellie
later okay thank you does anybody have
any comments in the working group last
call that they want to bring to the mic
but use the mic are using less speak to
this gentleman he's quite happy at the
moment we got lots of comments during
the process of developing this draft and
we don't expect more but we'd really
really like to hear them this week if
there are any okay thank you take it
thank you alright do we have anything
anything to say about UDP options aside
the fact we were adopted this traffic
all right cool
whoo at Tom Jones University of Aberdeen
and we have a working implementation on
top of FreeBSD we would love to speak to
anyone who's interested in running our
code or anybody who's interested in
doing an implementation or another
operating system so we could do some
interoperability and probably best if
you wanna talk to this you talk me down
mm-hmm and what running codes kind of
important for this draft because it's
taking advantage of otherwise unused
space um that turns up if the IP packet
length and unity packet lengths don't
met don't match and so interaction with
existing plantations that aren't
expecting this is is of major interest
okay um comment when you change the
FreeBSD code did arts Dave Wilson
sideline did you notice if the old code
would have been okay with the options it
sounds like he made freebsd support the
UDP options was the old code a problem
so what an old FreeBSD version trip over
the the options in an incoming packet
and so if you look back as far as the
the 4-3 BSD stack this space is trimmed
out of the pocket anyway so it shouldn't
cause any issues with running hosts so
we think it should be okay everywhere
thanks good people who wish to
experiment please speak to Tom okay
looking great dress working group drafts
only PHP is first you um should we start
with wrong sponsored you want to start
with measurement slides well your sides
Rhonda set set set context so we just
bash the agenda but we're going to treat
you before 31 all you can do come back
at the end and top what it's all up to
you Roland okay
yeah so this is a quick update on
version 0-2 so I applied several
suggestions from David thanks for the
Thor with you
so yeah the changes are also documented
right now on the draft so I clarified
something that has to do with deployment
the ANA section was little bits cleaned
up and I also edit multicast traffic as
a potential use case so multicast
traffic usually has a problem that
multicast traffic can suddenly appear in
your domain as soon as a branch is newly
created and in that case if you want to
avoid let's say traffic sources that can
cause severe condition in your ISP
Network you may be better off using Kali
in order to avoid that so that could
actually help in deploying little bits
multicast and on a more global scale
I also added text about implementations
using a QMS and UCM usage for Ellie and
I also revised text and security section
so next slide
yeah so one aspect that came a little
bit more clear in this version is that
one essential characteristic of Ellie is
that it has there's no harm to
best-effort traffic property and so if a
provider actually decides not to support
nowhere effort then it cannot take
advantage of these features so they must
be aware that they may be side effects
on on this Airport traffic if they carry
the war effort within the beste for a
grenade and currently the draft discuss
discusses two types of users one is the
element user which means the user
doesn't care whether lower effort
traffic is actually better treated then
the intended so remarking - best effort
is okay for them and the other uses the
the L a strict user which means he
doesn't want to he doesn't want that the
le traffic is treated better then part
nearly as good as as best effort so you
want to make sure that L is only
transmitted if the resources are
otherwise unused and wants to make sure
that there's no harm property is
actually guaranteed so in that respect
maybe the the difference would be if we
would use two different code points for
that that the le strict code point would
be remarked to be in case it's carried
as best airport so that it can be
detected by the endpoints for example so
currently the draft proposed only to use
the le Minh semantics and maybe to use
some kind of lower if for transport like
like that if you want to make sure that
no traffic is really pushed in the
background so one question is have we
means to detect any remarking using I
don't know arm the the connection
establishment of TCP or something so we
usually need been some kind of DHCP
feedback there's right now at least to
my knowledge no no means for doing that
next slide so next steps I'm not sure
whether people like the semantics of a
liminal a straight I don't know I mean
for me le Minh is fine but it seems that
people made some comments in the past
that they have any strict semantics in
mind and I don't think that we need
actually two years apiece
to support this so yeah one dscp is
maybe enough but this is time to discuss
now and if we have one
gscp right now that the drafts resists
to use the SCP are to number two which
is the main purpose of the draft right
so it removes the ambiguity that was
introduced in 36 62 and also the
follow-on draft so the idea is the gscp
should not be leached in case the upper
bits are cleared due to IP precedence
clearance so there's only a small set of
potential choices left in the current
ESP stand a pool and yeah so I guess
Gauri has more input data just in a few
minutes
and so yeah more reviews and feedback
appreciated and yeah I think we are
nearly ready for going to work in group
last call except the fact that we may
have to think about updating the arrow
2.11 mapping draft or the web RTC draft
after they've been published I don't
know let's come back to that after we've
done the next talk yeah let's figure out
what what we're gonna do with with the
dscp and how fast we can converge on it
so Tom does your question relate to this
talk or to the selection of the code
point the selection of the code one okay
let's take a talk on that first okay are
there any of the questions for Roland on
the draft as it is okay well come back
in a moment and to the pink box okay so
a mere 2% a set of the measurement on
city this is the follow-up of a talk
that we had in my perjury where we
present some of this measurement in the
last where ikf and now we have done a
bit more experiments and we want to
present that thanks
so a really this talk is about what
would be the best choice for a code
point for early what's the state of this
discussion first of all I received forty
five ninety four specified CS one but is
understood that this is not a good
choice it would be zero zero one zero
zero zero and by the way now the
analyzer sorry for to simplify this
discussion so the binary of this code
point so that there is consensus SE not
not a good choice because we will create
a priority inversion so we should select
something that start with zero zero zero
and then something in the top down and
the bottom three bits in the current as
we've seen the carbon suggestion is zero
one zero so our experiments our
measurement were meant to really see if
it would work in today's network and it
it's a good starting point because we
saw that at least it has good
survivability in the internet sense that
using this Co point it in the a large
number of parts it's if we color the
pocket with the this dscp can get to the
other end that's right so first let me
spend a couple of words about what
experiment we did we developed this this
tool called path scope which as the same
as looks inspired by trace route
it was a traffic generator that use a
syn packet to send in packet to a target
and increase the time to live each time
then I collect all the ICMP the because
of the time to lead the expedition at
the the traffic at the sender and it
does an analysis of what I see starting
with different coupon so it changed the
point is scriptable so you can decide
which compiler to start with and it does
this automatically and we've done this
with several point from three vantage
point in this open network all
digitalocean
from 300 point towards 300 targets
chosen randomly from the Alex that 1
million lists using TCP and UDP and
that's right
so one pathology that we saw starting
with several code point is that the top
three beats are some time bleached we
call this a toss bleaching because these
three bits correspond to the ole toss
semantics and this means that for
example what you've seen that several
compile like a f11 f12 3 1 & 4 4 1 that
all of this strip bit non zero but the
bottom tributed 0 1 0 after resetting
are mapped to the SCP 2 similarly for a
F 1 2 F 2 2 3 3 2 & 4 2 we have known
that the top tribute non zero and are
mapped but the bottom 3 bit 1 0 0 M and
on map to yes it before and the same
story for a F 1 3 F 2 3 so our friend
Bowie series that's the question for or
with
all these 900 the unique search
destination pay we see that 70% of parts
of the SCP modify so the fee at the end
of the part wasn't the same day as the
one that we started to start with but in
10%
we are the this pathology to us bleach
so you understand what is that the track
here is that some for example if you
choose the SCP 2 nd freeze mmm
start with the I priority class like a
f11 it would be mapped to the SCP to
next so then we done some other of this
measurement in we develop another tool
called edge traced that it's collect
rates because it wants to do exactly the
opposite of this so it starting from a
pool of of sorts at the edge of the
network and we selected we had control
of 177 nodes distributed across the
network then more on this was on the map
algae presentation using this tool we
can see also looking at this webpage
here at the bottom we saw that when we
send a probe from one of these point to
one central send server we saw that this
pathology of tos bleaching was non
insignificant we had is 70% and also we
had the other measurement using a mobile
network in a protocol Moreau were really
this is used mobile nodes in different
operators across wireless operate across
Europe where we have bought control of
the sender and the receiver it will
accentuate experiment using two two
nodes and we have the opportunity to
probe the many many tests many many
parts across in this
work and yeah we saw various other
pathology but still that us bleaching
was detectable because we are at least
for quest point 7 when we went to see
the pathology specific oh of a certain
ruler so how did ESET changed from the
input to output in 4.7 percent of the
routers presented this this pathology
next so okay that set up the the the
question is what is that is the SCP -
the best the best choice because we can
see this issue of resetting the top
tribute and so I've this priority
inversion of course it's important to to
consider that if it was mapped to
something like is like this F wouldn't
be a problem but because the uniqueness
of this code point that is lower than be
safer then we don't want this priority
inversion so thanks Ruffalo for setting
up naturally getting some measurements
so we can see what's happening for real
I think it's important we talk about
this now because all the other
diffserv classes we've created all the
other ph bees are actually being pH bees
which could live with the best effort
service but we're being elevated by the
diffserv mechanism this particular pH B
is one that seeks to be worse than best
effort so we don't want other traffic
mapped above it by accident or below it
by accident we don't want this inversion
so let's talk about the presentation and
let's think about this topic please Fred
so Fred Baker
you've only got eight options and
actually for that you can use in your
collapsed dscp and the reason being that
the least significant bit if
puts it in a special use class so it
pretty much has to be zero for any
public vscp
so that leaves you a grand total of
three values so if you're gonna argue
against using to Fred that's not keep
going not completely I wanted it a
little bit when you get done okay so and
so we're talking about pillow pillow one
yes the pool on allocation which is
currently allocated personnels actions
I'm ordering it his slides and which say
to might be a bad value yes for me okay
so you've got eight Cal use there zero
one two three four any odd number is a
local user code point not quite yes no
absolutely a local user code weights not
the I on a registry has half of those of
local use and half of those is reserved
for Ayana or local use well okay you
can't get to them bottom line if I'm
going to put it in anything resembling a
standards action I have to go change
something in order to get to it this is
true good but let's talk about what we
need to do having understood that that
they are make my comments to let stick
with Fred's discussion we come back they
honor stuff like a phrase discretionary
registry right so what are we ready to
talk just carry on okay so the values
that value you'd like to wind up with
zero the value that you're arguing you
could wind up with and not like would be
two or four or sex and I'm not sure I
see the real difference in them you know
from that perspective I would really
like to go back to these people that are
doing cosplay Qing and tell them that
that was 25 years ago
the Internet has been different for a
really long time throw up this is not
your grand
father Janette okay so we can do this
the how many Reuters were we talking
about here are we talking about one or
several aces or hundreds of aces we are
talking about tens of the yes in terms
of measurement okay we seek ten census
and 900 measurements okay Tom Jones
University of Aberdeen and just so just
another argument against - SSH is
squatting on core points for encode
points - for friends right of traffic
and - for a bulk traffic so bulk copies
over SSH if you use the core point
- might end up with the early treatment
which is probably not what they want hmm
okay another point Michael Abramson so
the seventeen seven percentage points uh
can we go back to the okay did you
observe any when he says modified the
DHCP was this like all of those so the
17% includes the 10% of the total aging
or is this in addition to okay so we
have 7% where it's not doing only toss
bleaching its it is all that it's
setting it to zero or did people do even
other things but most of it is to zero
okay but how much of it is not how much
of this is not just setting it to zero
well I guess it's a small percentage and
for example we can see it from the last
slide where we had yeah we had like the
main the main the dominant pathologies
are really bleaching and toss bleaching
in different proportions and then we
have the small number of other good
point that we detect at the end that are
related if you want to the one that we
set a beginning okay
but it's not significant that we should
take that into consideration of any time
that's just you saw a few but that's
like it mean pathology I guess leaching
and possible and it may be that some of
these code points are intentional
policies within the diffserv domain that
are admissible the issue I think that's
on the table is the marking of packets
that is not probably intentional and is
disruptive to the use of this code point
yeah once a disruptive because it's
intentional apparently okay yes so I
think that comment to Fred as well I
think a lot of people just their
equipment does something and they don't
even know about it it's probably not
even intentional yeah so hi Brian I'm
reading this i chart and I don't
actually know what any did the
destination points are because the URL
okay I can go get me well no so no it's
pretty clear from from even from here
that there's a few things that there's
basically probably one or two a SS that
are actually leaking out like weird you
we're using a for dscp for actual
engineering inside our network and inch
leaks out right um and they don't bleach
it on the out on the other end or
somehow her story the question that I
came up here to ask was actually so you
said tens of a s's are doing things that
might make beat the two four and six
code points not works of bleaching the
top three great how many S's were in the
sample so we had ninety two oh two
unique source destination pairs monroe
has an access network diversity of like
nine different a isatis so if we're
looking at tens of a s is in thousands
of a s is that's different than ten two
bases and hundreds of asses so did you
look at the at besides the a s path like
art you look at the union of all the a s
is that you were traversing yes yeah i
mean with the one that we traversed and
really we consider all we discussed some
some sample because if the dscp was
changed that quite early along the path
okay maybe it wouldn't be it's not
longer significant for the the one that
for example if it was bleach
you can infer anything from the next
measurement so we had many as assets
that were Amina reachable from our
amazement
so so so what what is the size of the
union of the set of a SS that were
traversed by these measurements well I
mean in total we I think we we measure
the yeses there were there were only 30
a SS on the entire path
what do you which there I think there
were three data sets here right so there
was a large data set from digitalocean
and he's a measurement right right for
which there isn't pure
ass okay and and and the magnitude and
so so we're really talking about sort of
tending the negative Theret in a
negative fourth instances right like so
if we're talking about tens tens of a s
isn't a big data set then it sounds like
we can make some phone calls talking
about 10% box that we saw from
digitalocean how'd this feature yeah but
how many different yeses is that is the
question and what's the proportion yeah
so I would I would suggest going going
back and I'm gonna look at that I mean
it's pretty clear as input to the
discussion that we should start having
here that two four and six are bad and
now we get to go fight about one three
five and seven right but but I mean like
so from from a measurement standpoint it
would be really interesting to know what
the denominator of the number of a s is
he said they were like tens of a s it's
like it's tens of tens then we're
screwed if it's tens of all of them then
it's phone calls all right all right
thanks right and the to the point where
we're gory and I were sort of equivalent
quibbling with with thread it's roughly
up on the screen this is the int
registry and the important point is that
the code points in pole three that end
in zero one were tagged as maybe utilize
your future standards action if
necessary so we did warn people
however running code wins this one every
time
so now we have the debate because we
have everything on the table okay right
okay so we need a system we if we're
going to publish this as a working group
document we need to know it's going to
be better than using cs1 and it's
deployable so we have various things on
the table and how do we balance these at
your at our problem
yeah thanks for for these measurements I
think just bleach is maybe a misnomer it
should be IP president's bleach also so
it's more precise exactly for instance
please yes so yeah I think we should
stop around so I'm basically a second
threats comments we should stop working
around broken implementations and also
I'd like to get this SSH stuff fixed I
mean why are they using KO point to its
its allocated for standard section or
not not yet that's right so and and the
question is if if we use that their
other pool we have to do the same thing
looking out what's currently used in the
wild in this DHCP pool right I think I
think maybe we have some detron that
really we really want to go there but
that's a relatively easy experiment to
figure out whether that code points
change how operators are using it isn't
an almost impossible experiment because
we don't know how how many people put
PhDs behind that core point right
although I think my Michaels comment was
is is quite wrong with a lot of what
we're dealing probably dealing with here
it operates you have equipment that
ain't broke and they're not critically
clear on what all the details are of
what it's doing but but the traffic
seems to flow through
okay so all right let's see if we can
make up some straw polls let me put the
mic aside and let's let's do look look
look inferring about what we want to ask
the posed to me asking half a dozen
questions and getting and and and
getting it in coherent
okay
Rafaela thank you thank you very much
your co-chairs about to earn their
absorbance salaries okay we're gonna do
this we're gonna do this via show of
hands this is a straw poll this is a
straw poll not a final decision
can I see from a show of hands how many
people in the room think how many people
think they understand the issue okay I
see about about a dozen how many people
think that we have enough information on
what's going on to make a decision to
make a decision now raise your hands
okay the decision trying to make here is
okay so the decision when I set up here
is Dooley stick with dscp - thank you
Bob good good good good do we stick with
dhcp - that is currently the draft or do
we pick another dscp
which is probably gonna be an
odd-numbered one because in essence this
says that the site looking at here that
says the two is bad
we'll also apply two four and six so if
we accept the argument here the two is
bad four and six go away and we're gonna
be looking at odd-numbered dscp so the
decision being the decision that we're
looking at is to be simple - or we go to
one of the one of the odd numbers odd
number DCPS cps and the question i want
to ask is how many people think who
understand the issue think we have
enough information to make the decision
now please raise your hand if you think
the information make the decision now I
see no hands raised that is a
significant result okay
don't I don't need to ask more questions
because I think we now know what has
happened next comments can we take
points of the light Bob just so we can
make sure we round here's because this
is where it gets interesting
that could be a mix of no and not sure
indeed even so um if it there there were
no hands raised for yes yes conference
in making decision now and that that
that I think is an important important
input to publish to what happens next
Rowland given this table yeah Ron plus
given this table I think the ACP four
and six are even worse than the ACP too
because they have if and and voice
admitted which is kind of yeah I think I
so it's so the the the low priority AF
is usually ending three yeah so G AB
which is basically well I think I agree
with you which is that this this this
slide not not lame demolishes to blossom
masters for if you believe this slide is
a reason not to choose to it's also a
reason not to choose four and six and
will wind up with will wind up having to
deal with the process consequences of
using an odd one and I guess just to be
fair on the other hand if we do decide
to use two it shows that two is better
than four and six just two because of
the age or at least is good or bad
no no I'd really don't see EF and V a
mixed in which led button carboy and
speaking from our own network Janet we
don't change any markings as packets go
through our network so I think the
problem that one is you don't know
whether or if people will fix this
bleaching and what to what extent it
actually is out there
the second is are there any major
applications that are using DSP - other
than SSH bulk data and the third one is
I'm not quite sure
was there a reason that we picked two in
the draft or not say five the last
question let's see the last question
does have an answer in essence it's the
IANA registry that was set once upon a
time many thousands for RFC's ago
designated the even-numbered code when
she enters action and Disney the odd one
in to experimental local use pool so
that's the answer your very last
question the other two I don't know that
the site yeah line three it does say
that we might steal it back sometime
Yeah right yes my inclination would be
to go with two and things will get fixed
if it proves problematic yeah I would
hope next 20 years or so yeah it's like
yeah before net Ryan so um
as somebody came up to raise doubt
earlier and then you know raised by and
and then didn't raise my hand I wanted
to explain why but then I had it thought
actually I wanted to ask did you guys do
passcode measurements for 105 we we
didn't choose one we've done Pascal
measurements for and some of these
numbers and I can't tell you that I've
actually done one we have done some odd
well great odd and even numbers with an
even numbers but like so the interesting
ones here are one in five right those
are the two that did this yes um are
fraught with minor amounts of process
payroll and not just straight-up illegal
we have a spider which of course you
might be interested measurements for the
scp-100 the rate it gets through the
network rate so it's not blocked by
people routinely from the core rate and
the pathologies we have would indicate
that ISPs who intentionally remarked
would just remark it the same way as
they remarked anything else right
there's no particular reason why bad
from a traversal point of view that's a
that's a low-end study but it would seem
to indicate that one is better than two
to me on the SSH thing that's the
OpenSSH code base can we just like send
a pull request just like don't do that
well that there's a book report filed
for a long time oh don't talk to him
yeah yes so there's there is a pull
request fixing those two and it's like
twelve years old and they're probably
never gonna take it
just on the the one-in-five we have edge
traced measurements for one in five the
plots are online which means I can just
look what's up and but they the the
bleaching behavior looks the same as two
four six and five they all they all have
the same braids on basically the same
behavior as two but without the peril of
to alright so I'm gonna raise my hand
and say I have enough information to
make a know Andrew McGregor I'll be
sitting next to one of the open easy
search maintained is in about three
weeks time so I'll see if I can convince
them to get off those cooked ones okay
thank you alright
but do you think we have a conclusion
that we can't make a decision now and
you may have noticed I carefully did not
go through the milestones earlier now
would be a good time to go have a look
have a have a look at our milestones so
we now more or less know what's going on
here we'll do milestones and then and
then then we'll come back to there the
Reza gender okay
TCF I think that's gonna be middle I
need to talk the authors but it's gonna
it's gonna be pushed out a while
probably probably 2018 this is not not
not apparent without trying to criticize
them this is a one of many things that
they're working on and not probably not
not overriding priority okay
I'm in Kim you're right on cue I'm
inclined to leave that September
milestone for difficult eleven and move
it moved with CS one and deal with what
happens to le le PHP later what would
you like to do agree David I just was
questioning the submission for diffserv
to 802 11 as an informational RFC it's
currently indefinite status is a
proposed standard that should be fixed
David you're wrong all right thank you
fix I will fix that all right this is
why we put these up here
bugs the bug sneaked in no idea how it
got here - the only sin copy/paste error
okay on the other hand I'm trying to
move le p HB to december let's see if we
can get this resolved we resolve between
now and singapore roll what world is not
screaming at me that will do okay but
for that one I'm ruff Chloe do you think
we would be able to take on doing some
more measurements because um it seems
like one person was convinced but maybe
we need a bit more data yeah
yes I think I think that took that
what's presented was really a part of
the measurement because we were looking
also for other things and we also have
our other measurements okay so maybe we
could get more debt with net before the
next meeting or on the working group
mailing list beforehand and if other
people want to join in to speak to
Ruffalo because we could perhaps
coordinate this and find out really what
lies at the bottom of this dscp rat hole
okay Bob is October plausible for the
eastern cat truth tuition and cap drafts
okay
and Michael SCTP both the 4960 update
and the nat support end a year are you
gonna kick your net neck support is the
one I think we that that that needs your
bandwidth okay and part of the reason
this slide exists is when I look at our
set of milestones I discovered we had 5
September crafts due in September I knew
that wasn't going to happen ok now we
need milestones for the of the remaining
drafts um Bob September 2018 is is is a
swag for out for for for l4s do your
better swag means that that's basically
a year basically a year out we'll go
with that for now
L is good yes we write early the 80s
like us the ad and and the other IDs
like and the other 80s like our IDs when
that happens just to explain Bob what I
mean about that when we did the
presentations we're gonna say that
essentially those drafts are finished
barring changes to in TCP em to the TCP
prog stuff so we're just sort of sitting
in holding pattern there is also the
possibility if you want to freeze
something like the architecture and undo
it early working group last call but not
actually publish it because we might
want to update it but just to get
everybody's consensus on it so yes yeah
okay
UDP options making a guess I guessed
after the spring meeting next year that
that gives us gives us gives us two
meeting cycles and I think I I don't
think the spec that's gonna change much
I think it's mostly at an understanding
of of implemented bility and of and
effect on implementations that don't
support
right options a pro 2018 is Vincent here
Vince Roca Vincent is June next year
plausible for the FEC drafts okay good
enough excellent we'll take what we're
happy to share the credit if you get in
you get in debt you're getting done more
quickly we'll talk more on Thursday
right and the rest this is all agenda
stuff okay let's see where were we next
yeah three three David well I'm talking
on the first half the second slides I
tend to you I just realized there was a
priority inversion in my in one of the
slides I've seen correctly set of slides
um okay with the shim okay you you you
question you'll get to see the actual
probably do is just just in the
unplugged where I go find me find me Mia
let's go - lets go through this set of
slides and then I'll go find your others
okay so this one there's the co-authors
for ages next slide just to recap what
this one is
it's a BCP intended its guidelines for
protocol designers of lower layer
protocols and there is that have
actually been - going on since this was
started which have both used it it's not
straight for because it's cross layer
and it's also cross organization so
we've done liaisons on this and in the
process of writing this the normative
text in it being a PCP we decided to
pull it out into a another standard
track document so the ticket update of a
standard track drafts which I'm going to
come up to right
things that been going on recently this
this draft has been tabled for quite a
while it's but that stuff is happening
one very important thing going on in
3gpp is - a proposal from Ericsson in
fact number reference number one down
there to try and make ACN visible of the
RLC low in the 3gpp stack because the IP
header is compressed both both time to
get there if and this is for
architectures where the BBC P layer is
distributed from the RLC layer so so and
so that that would require this this
draft it was proposed in the June
meeting and there were counter proposals
to because because it's sort of that
they've already got this technology
called Ram based codec at that
adaptation that's just for one
application it's basically for voiceover
LTE and so there was some people saying
no we don't want to do ACN because we've
got this I was saying well let's do both
and I was saying not and all the rest of
it and when you look at the minutes
everyone's quite confused about what the
differences are between them and what
their scope isn't all the rest of it so
in the end of the decision was deferred
until August but I would encourage any
3gpp delegates to understand the
implications of this decision mainly
because the the proposal from Ericsson
was primarily to like a support l4s with
very low latency without having to jump
back in the stack to another node to
report ecn so this also this also came
up over lunch at this at the 5 g + IETF
meeting is georg here nah I just made a
half news because the the 5g people will
come talk now liaison slot on Thursday
okay so you might want to do a laser
let's let's let's bring this back up all
those students - Stu Stuart Cheshire are
put put this on on a breeze right on
everybody everybody's radar screen over
lunch so
that was that's a start yeah that's
because I put it on here now don't sure
what how the sausage is made the other
recent activity is Donald who's sitting
here right in front of me and myself
who've got a ACN supporting show through
and I think this has to hold it's gone I
think it's working great law school
completed yeah yep but it's got a
normative reference to end cap it's an
end cap guidelines so I assume that
still goes the write-up goes but then it
just has to hold until and as you saw
from the milestones we just bashed arm
the hope is to have both they should
have eaten cap guidelines and the 6040
shim draft a similarity publication
before Singapore so it might be quite
nice if they all go to the ICG together
because then they will have read them
all we just mean so they all understand
them all together
okay next so I've got some edits queued
for the next revision but I'm holding
them in until the updates the edits are
all in the section that summarizes the
bit we split out and until I've been to
interior on Thursday to talk about that
I don't want to put those some that
summary in stone because interior might
say differently but otherwise stable for
some time and I've now got an incorrect
slide because you just changed the
milestone so whatever you've done check
the milestone it's ok it's ok is it look
big bitch yeah right so I guess did you
manage to get the corrected slides no
I'm gonna have to go don't don't worry
don't worry don't worry I can just
explain my brain flip yeah I apologize
to the people on the list when I
couldn't decode binary to decimal as
well earlier on
actually that's a pointer yes your
Franklin okay so this is okay walk while
we're doing this um second side Lucic
they were here for a moment ago who
hasn't seen the blue sheet ski put your
hand up random pattern I'll go looking
who's got the other blue sheet or there
it is okay two blue keyboards okay go
ahead
Oh Bob Karen okay so this was the one I
just mentioned that was split out of the
other one to be a proposed standard so
it could update other proposed standards
can i movie on me this is the diagram
that split the like it you can just
there that one's correct but upside down
[Laughter]
sorry GF week yeah okay but the point
here being that are you have an L to you
you you'll have an L to head or riding
on a Shem riding on riding on the outer
IP yeah hang on just let me tell you
what that slides about on yeah so this
the scope was of RFC 6040 was IP and IP
and it never said anything that I IV has
to be directly on IP but some people
assume it did and some people zoomed in
so that this updates make it clear that
includes a shim and that shim might be
extended with a layer two header as well
before you get the other IP header and
it could even apply where you don't know
whether the you know is IP or not but if
it's something inside a layer two it's
probably going to be IP and and then if
you don't know what it is you you really
shouldn't be putting anything in the you
send field on the outer except zero
so there's text in the draft to make
this all clear I won't go through the
text you can read the draft carry on
next so then when I'm had a look at how
many specs are covered by this because
you know we we covered the IP and IP
with about three or four but then I
discovered that the interiors been quite
busy and also maybe some of these are
actually routing yeah yeah so what what
these columns mean ended up deciding
let's not let's not deal with anything
here except standards track stuff or
widened avoid stuff so the first column
if there's a cross in there there's no
further information in the other columns
because we're going to ignore all that
when I say first car I mean third column
of course you should all know when I say
first I mean third then the the a okay
column is saying that it refers to
either RFC 6040 on tunneling or on a
previous compatible to a previous
compatible RFC IRC 3168 and I'll come
back to some of the exceptions like the
SFC one in a minute I'll just explain
the table first then the two in okay not
okay columns they're two different sorts
of not okay one there's text in this
draft now that makes them okay if
there's a tick there and the final one
is they're not okay but they're not IDF
documents either or at least they're
RFC's that document other people's
protocols if they are you know so we
don't have to change control over them
and what's the chick that's not that's
not a chick against in be GRE I want to
know if it just says it depends on the
one above Oh CCC above as an Asian when
you fix that you get this one for
failure okay okay I mean a but not
applicable in NFC SFC saris which is
service function
allegedly they are they haven't produced
in you encapsulation they've just
produced a load of vagueness about
they've they've just sort of produced
architecture and stuff and there's no
actually encapsulation yet I look for
draft I think within it which it used to
be an N SH was the name of the thing it
was yeah yeah you know but that doesn't
actually say what what the encapsulation
is it just says how it might be and it
doesn't yet say how it would be if
there's already an encapsulation and we
fight back in it so then the ones in the
column where it says the text in this
draft updates them are now on the next
slide all about them so there's two l2tp
ones for the very old b2 which is still
around for PPTP point-to-point tunneling
protocol and then l2tp version 3 which
is often used for Ethernet and other
other layer 2 stuff tunneling and then
there's GRE in this tirado and these are
all significantly different actually the
lttp one it's that all the controller
management is is automated
you know this protocol to do that the
GRE one as far as I know is manual only
ever manually configured there's some
cheap VPN products using GRE well this
is sort of what I want to know because
I've been asking I mean if there are
they must be automatically configure so
but I don't I can't find any protocol
that does it ok and I can't find anyone
who will sort of admit to looking at the
interior main unless long enough to
answer my question right so is the
question to TS vwg does anyone know how
GRE is automated in another protocol
does anybody know oh I've got some
people to look at me five minute head me
a lot of a lot of GRE when it was
originally done was that it was was said
of him figured I have seen a number of
Auto tunneling for protocol pose but I
can't recall IETF adopting EMU okay so I
actually would like to answer that
question um I can't say yes or no but I
can say that if banana which had AB off
yesterday is chartered and they decide
that GRE is a tunneling mechanism that
they might want to use for non TCP
traffic for doing multi path bonding
then they will find or define a
configuration provisioning discovery
whatever we couldn't go over the word
that that not like after the room hated
protocol which would kind of qualify as
automated GRE tunnel setup so I think I
learned if and if and I might do invest
in dick and that constructor Brian can I
also say that if they find it doesn't
have that can they know invent one
because there's plenty of other choices
right yeah that's I'm actually um if if
that charters then I took a picture of
your slide that I'm gonna show at the
first work and repeating it's late key
choose one or choose to or two six but
but preferably in the a ok column so
this doesn't impact that work thanks
and so I'm still just going through the
cat why these things are significantly
different then of course tirado is
generally n system 2n system and so it's
it's not you know network configuration
and thing doesn't apply so I see
Christian there so maybe I'll get some
answers out of Christian as well so I'll
talk to him later
so going one level deeper on each one
the lttp one I've proposed and in
consultation with Carlos and in natio a
new actually
pairs of two ends from the go she ate
etn and that's all written out and the
honor I on a registry bit is written up
um and who or how it's meant to work for
GRE it's just manual configuration as
far as I know so there's not much to
write other than comply with 6040 if
you're the person manually configuring
it and then tirado it's sort of
difficult because the spec didn't
mention ACN and there's a lot of tirado
out there so if we start having ecn
working underneath tirado it's um it's
good I don't know what and I'm sure
Christian can't remember what the code
looks like without thinking about it but
whether it copies the ecn header or
zeros it is important because if it
copies it then it will be black holing
ACN if there's any easy and enabled on
your path so we need to check that and
it's like question Jake and I don't
think EMT was on that list okay that was
a question I meant to ask is there I
missed anything
IMT I also I also don't see IPSec tunnel
mode this is not IP and IP is not on
this this because they were already
covered by okay good but these are ones
with shims ah I don't even know aim to
use what so empty
7450 automatic multicast tunneling oh ah
no I did find that now why did I what
did I reject that I can't remember but I
okay oh we probably should have a talk
about that one and because there was a
big discussion in the group that control
plane and how they interacted with it so
we should have something in the document
the refers to it Christian we tomorrow
the question about Teredo is that there
are two parts that to to answer your
question there is it conceptually hard
to have a support for easy and intuitive
and and the answer is no it is not a
snow particle reason why not
and the second question is if we update
the IFC to specify that support will
application also be updated and data is
a much harder case because as far as I
know some of the implementation is in
Hardware yeah yes so this is all about
the legacy problem yeah and so it's it's
unclear that yeah I mean it might it
might be but I mean it's it will be
updated typically for new products and
it's beer and then there's marido as
well and because I overheard and yeah
and it's and and Microsoft is not the
only one implementing theodoros yeah
it's a David Olsen um if I understand
this correctly this could be a like
Apple app is you know IP with Ethernet
or actually it's Wi-Fi yes header and IP
and you're talking about skipping ahead
to find IP header so that you can market
it appropriately when you when you move
in two aspects one is one is and I've
got slides on what what the problem is
next but what one is that if there if
there is an IP outer and I'd be here
somewhere
then if you're going to not have a zero
in the outer ecn you should first check
that the other end of the tunnel will be
able to process it I guess okay all
right and and so it's a question of
coordination between the two ends of the
tunnel and if you don't know then you
should zero it that's the that's that's
the first mate that's the main problem
particularly legacy go stay on this but
no stay on this one a bit longer so no I
think we're done on that yeah other than
to thank all the people it acknowledges
in the various working groups I have
been beating up on a number of people
for
the last couple of months right so this
this is exactly what David else was
asking so Sen is different to any other
field in the IP header when you're
tunneling and so it's a given example
diffserv gets copied down but then when
it comes to the D capsulation it's just
thrown away the answer is just thrown
away but with ECN the capability goes
down and then any changes to it have to
be propagated back up again right and so
it has to check when it's doing the
encapsulation whether the D cap would
support that combination of the inner
and the outer before it gets boarded and
if not it should zero it so the problem
is if it does his check then marks it
ECT because it's come in as ECT so in
that like in the Teredo case then you've
got easy and capable on the path if you
go through say oh if you call upstream
on your trade oh it might mark it but
then those markings just get dropped on
the floor and you get all hell break
loose as you see there and so what that
will mean is it will toggle between tail
drop and then ACN and it will give you
really bad performance so that's the
problem
next the next problem on top of that
problem is that in RFC sixty forty I
wrote it and we reviewed it as a
specification of what compliant
implementations would have to do but
what we didn't do is write it from the
point of view of what an implementation
that doesn't apply whether it should do
and in this one case even if it doesn't
comply with it it has to do something
it's like a requirement for all things
that use the Internet Protocol all
tunnel endpoints whether or not they
comply with RFC six deported and so in
this update sixty forty I've added some
text because all you can do there is
just say the operator should configure
it to be safe right
and I've actually Raman should I've said
there if possible the operator must
we're gonna work with that for you well
I don't know if Spencer's happy with
that yeah but let's talk about those
words because what that implies is that
the implementation gives them the
possibility of configuring it and that's
why there's the if possible if it's not
a big herbal they can't do it if it's
configurable they must but I can
entertain telling an operator must it is
sort of you know this is this is one of
the few cases in which we do use do you
use must and get yet get kind of
insistent about it because losing
congestion indications from the network
is a must not yeah so Matt and then in
the writer case the operator is the end
user you know though not quite okay
that's true yeah because the operator is
I mean the tomato setup is really
automated and we do effectively as an
explicit set up with a system of ropes
and all that so I have not done the work
and I don't want to presume of the way
it's possible to specify something like
if your initial set of probes carry the
bit end to end then you notice that your
saga is capable and and you use it wise
if they do not then you did use it it is
not capable and you zero the flag yeah
so so many things like that are possible
is you know like in the windows 95 and
things like that what's happening no
Matt you you will you will be in a way
it which basically windows like if I
will always send me to zero anyhow and
it's not windows 95 at least Windows 7
but but they will send a bit to zero and
and they will not acknowledge it when
you send a probe and that way
the auto system will notice that the
system at the other end of the table
since then I can't do it so you get you
caramelize it it's possible yeah okay
right so yeah that's the end of that
slide so spaces make steps there's been
four revisions of this draft a lot of
works gone into this draft to try and
meet that deadline of what was September
and I think I think we can still meet it
hopefully interior will close off
something remaining issues I've got a
session with Praveen next week because I
thought he was going to be here but he's
not so to deal with tirado so I think
we're in good shape
are you actually presenting at the
interior meeting yes unfortunately I put
in a request very early to do so and it
got lost so they have I mean only given
me five minutes but five minutes to do
heads up when you I mean it's being
around many of the interior groups so
just as long as people get heads up
because I think this is an important
cross area document it's good to get
eyes on it yes the time is l4s how does
your first team want what will you use
this you know I have no get if you said
mean less right let's go find sites
let's go find sites all right title
slide with your name yeah okay so so
there's three drafts that have been
adopted by the working group and we are
looking for people to actively engage
with this process and the whole purpose
of bringing these drafts to an IETF
working group is that they become owned
by the working group which means people
get a chance to change them people get a
chance to implement them or experiment
with them or see how it fits their
architecture so if these drafts are
going to mature as we whole Bob's going
to need help from the working
just to get more feedback on them as
they go forward hope that was okay Bob
Alan kitchenette was and and just as you
have a sort of state of the working
group slide one of my slides is going to
be stage of but l4s across all areas you
know because because it's not just these
three drafts and not not so it's sort of
a coordination problem within a
coordination problem if you like and and
that's where a lot of other people are
putting in effort and things like that
right on the L price architecture I
think I can remember how the slides go
it's essentially written could be
reviewed but we want to go into a
holding pattern as I said and work on
more on the transport layer now and
check that we can produce a safe
transport that meets the TCP Bragg
requirements we've already got one
that's unsafe and meets them so we're in
pretty good shape as far as to having an
existence proof excellence like okay
there's the co-authors this is the
architecture one first a recap the opera
architecture is three parts the aqm with
the dual cues to protect l4s from
classic and but to still check out the
capacity so you get very low latency
which is the whole point very a queuing
delay I should say there's a classifier
which I'm going to talk about in the
next a draft talk which is ECT one
that's been for that preliminary early
decided and then there's the congestion
control on the host next so this is the
holding pattern slide just talking about
in very small text there that says one
minute in that loop goes around so I'm
gonna get an email every minute
have you finished yet yeah so in in
effect we're nearly we're nearly done on
the jewel q1 goons gonna talk about that
after me
and then that will go into a holding
pattern I think as well because there's
some assumptions in there that depend on
you know that's just so that just in
case we have to change CTP prog like
requirements it's best to put them all
in a holding van and we gave a talk in
IC crg about some of the more ambitious
things we're trying to do with TCP prog
because we're researchers but then
there's basic stuff which is just
implementing it and putting together a
curie CN CN plus plus DC TCP and all the
bits and pieces to make it safe and
testing that all out and that's the sort
of thing I'm talking about to finish and
then everything go through we don't have
to do all of performance improvements
because it's already ten to hundred
times better latency than anything else
so we're you know we don't have to make
it even better to to do that to get all
the drafts to go through so ya know 500
milli micro seconds delay queuing delay
versus the best is about five
milliseconds and that requires fair
queuing so flow queuing so yeah we
understand this holding pattern because
you'll always be updating your transport
protocol and we need to have a cut-off
point next so this is the eye test this
is what I said about the status of all
the other parts as you can see all the
red bits mean work being done updated
bits and pieces pretty cool actually in
the IETF specs bullet which if you can
see that there's only now one of those
specs is not adopted in the various
working groups they all adopted the only
one that isn't is the quick one he's
getting quick
and what else should I highlight out on
here
oh yeah the 3gpp bit I'm gonna talk
about oh no I just talked about didn't I
and that's coming up with discussion in
August oh and finally we're still trying
to get the paper we wrote about it the
research paper we wrote about it accept
it so that all the measurement results
with millions of scenarios or
measurements but this one got rejected
by sitcom on the basis it's not novel
because they'd heard about it in the
idea well we can happen to two seconds
of silence as everybody sighs when they
did the same but carry on even though
we've made it very clear which
contributions there wasn't work that way
so they're going for journal submission
now and you'll hopefully have that
public right so moving on to the
identifiers I'll go straight into this
we were having a discussion about or
this is written into the identifier
draft but maybe I ought to call it out a
bit more we've talked about ecn being
the identifier but if you like that's
the default identifier and the
ever-present identifier for the
end-to-end service but it's possible we
or we don't want to prejudge how this
gets deployed by different operators and
they may want to make it initially
something that they do only in their own
network or only for certain like
business customers or or you know in a
you know for their VPN customers or
whatever you know we don't know so it's
possible that this will be these are
easy an identifier and another
optionally and so that may be the
address of one end it may be a VLAN ID
maybe they serve Co point maybe a local
one or a global one it may be the bearer
ID and a mobile network you know so and
we're we're about to put the hooks in
the code to use the Linux classifier
architecture to so that so that people
can just add another classifier as well
as the EC n1 um and really just just
what I'm discussion about this because
well a the implications for diffserv as
well
but but also just the business
implications because if you provide this
flexibility it will probably get used
and that could delay this being an
end-to-end service for many years and
where you don't provide it I suspect
people will abuse it and do it in a bad
way the idea of doing this is that at
least when you take out the optional one
it becomes an end-to-end service
eventually build-a-bride speaking from
the floor so I suspect Bob and I have a
Socratic dialogue in our future on the
subject glass half full glass half empty
on this one I'm one of people poking Bob
on this for a couple of reasons one is
that at the very least dscp and to make
other classifiers that that Bob mentions
help enormous amount when you think
about incremental deployment and it's
it's I think that's really important at
what important aspect to bring out and I
think beyond that in general the the
notion that this is a selectable add-on
to a service is it is is a good one yeah
I just wanted to pick up on the point
about incremental deployment I think the
more identified you add together the
less incremental deployment you'll get
ACM currently goes through pretty well
most places although we've got some more
recent measurements on mobile network so
we're going to talk about but the next
idea
but you know out saying easy and this of
you reduce the Venn diagram of where
both will get through to just the middle
of it yeah and and this this is also a a
a perspective discussion because I'm
thinking thinking in terms of this being
and enhanced service on individual
networks and there you're going to want
networks or classifiers and then we see
how the world evolves and and extent
which we can get this to become to to
become in end to end and the I think I
think a better word
I'm incremented diploma this diploma
motivations business motivations for
deploying it may require I works I just
didn't wanna make make it make the other
the problem I talk offline
there's some wording changes need in the
draft it to emphasize that that that
that second classifier is optional and
quite useful and important to are as I
usually would support the deployment
motivate deploy motivation and rigor if
you don't specify that or put it in the
Linux code someone else will because
because I cannot see how I can do the
testing required to put together a
deployment of this without it so I think
it'll just be thank you okay it's a next
so we had a bit of a discussion in TCP M
about another piece of this jigsaw which
is now called ECM plus plus plus it's
the file name there TCP I might
generalize dcn which is about making
sure you've got AC and on all the tcp
types of tcp packet not just the data
packets and the point was made there as
it has been before that this at least
now makes everything consistent so you
don't have all these exceptions in your
low balance and things where where these
load balancers another thing that it's
broken in you know as fred was saying
they're still working on the internet
our grandfathers bill
they're still using the 8-bit the toss
by so when the ecn field changes they
they load balance to another place so at
least having all the packets in one flow
at the same CCN field can be useful but
I just wanted to point it out here but
of course if they're classifying on the
on the last bit just you know I'm a
second from last bit
then there's ECT and cee yeah this is
really something that people have to fit
I mean we saw the other dscp mess but
this would be up to fiscal soon as you
your Reuter happily marks easy to you
one or zero to see II it blows so this
just brokenness we big headlines please
don't use the whole byte called Lata's
bite in olden times
use only dscp field the Lord balancing
because what what we've been finding we
haven't yet found any correlation is
because there was so much they said
bleaching that it was under percent so
we couldn't correlate with something
that was the the ecn field bleaching was
I suspect about from people who thought
it was the toss by rather than trying to
bleach these in feel but I don't know
hey Dave Dalton it occurs to me it might
be nice to have you know tools to debug
this so you think someone's working on
like the traceroute version of report we
use choice bolts so do we actually like
change traceroute so that everybody's
traceroute gets like this big flashy
warning and both the ECM bleaching I
just wonder they're making idea there to
do that sounds fun change is by making
tracer
it comes up it comes up in red if
there's a change from what you expect
I'm true
Andrew McGregor there's also the species
of hilarity that occurs when routers
pull the entire the whole of this bite
into their ecmp entropy and then you get
ec in marks
drastic reordering okay ECM pp-people
also do not do that that's also written
but please just don't do it because I
think Moulton if you take the bike the
thing that being that I'm aware at least
two different router vendors who have
multiple ways of configuring a DCP their
you know deceive implementations the
right way and the wrong way both in the
same device um
and for a long while the default and the
documentation was the wrong way
and going back to l2tp this is this is a
problem there in that a lot of the
tunnels allowed if surf configuration to
set the diffserv code point to a certain
thing or to copy it so code point four
minutes way out and and most of them
create about ten minutes remaining
[Music]
short of review for the duo queue drafts
next slide so further improvements that
were done was we have we submitted at
the end of the draft we added the
overload handling to the cola for it
also the the PI heuristics which were
removed from the dual PI Square have
been assessed and discussed now on the
mailing list so we were also working on
this open source release for in Linux so
we have simplified the PI square
parameters so we would say we do should
would do some cleanup so the PI squared
configuration parameters they were
simplified because there was quite some
interdependencies between parameters
like if you wanted to change the updates
the updates time you have to also
accordingly change the alpha and beta
parameters similar 4k with the dual
with a coupling factor between the two
Q's so this is being removed and well
the extra classifiers
we are working on and we hope we can
zoom upstream it that's more or less
about the status and next slide I also
want to repeat a kind of concern that we
raised in the ITC RG meeting so it's a
warning or at least a concern of a clash
that we see looking more and
experimenting more on with with VBR
mainly so there is a sender only
evolution having also solving on a tail
drop based or buffer bloat it's
environment where you have big used
without a QMS there is also a solution
and evolution which is which is okay
because we can't have a cramps every
where immediately but on the other hand
all the aqm work that has been done it's
is actually clashing with what is
currently in the linux kernel as bbr and
which seems to be deployed already
extensively in the next slide so if you
look at VB are on a tail drop queue you
see that there is so here you can see
four flows running and you see the
dynamic flows I don't know if you
remember but there are multiple sizes
and that's the completion time so you
see it's a reasonable good completion
time that is also without an a cram a
limited queue of around 20 milliseconds
in this case which is on a hundred
megabit link and 20 milliseconds
round-trip time but the problem of
course if you introduce an ATM in this
situation which is on the next slide and
we have a PI aqm which has a target of
15 milliseconds it will increase the
drop probability but VBR ignores drop
for quite extensive amount
so it will induce a lot of drop
probability which has an immediate
effect on the completion times for the
short flows even for bbr in themselves
so which is of course not good so it
makes the situation with an AKM
worse than without an atrium which is
not a good evolution let's say it's not
what we want and it's not what is the
intention of the work done in the aqm
working group so in the next slides
question is will be BR as is and and
this evolution force operators to
disable a crimes in the future together
with ecn so that's a little bit concern
I think and in the next slide the
question is well we we proposed actually
a solution in ITC RG which probably we
will further experiment with and also I
hope to be BR people but question is
also in which group a working group or
should we handle these kind of crashes
interesting but BPR isn't in any working
group so this is a topic we just have to
discuss ICC RG seems the right place to
discuss it at the moment since it is
being presented there and but heads up
we should be aware of what's going on in
the internet for real yep any other
questions what do you plan
next always a good question yeah so if
there are review comments for the duo q
drafts we're happy to receive them and
if you have experience with it please
test it and try it we here like to hear
comments from you and experience thank
you
so we have a another slice of TS BW g on
thursday and it's in session 2 on
thursday afternoon please come along and
that will also condylar liaisons
discussion the SCTP drafts and the fake
frame so please come along to that also
otherwise have a great day
thank you ever so much for coming
[Music]
you