yes yeah actually laptop down to this
thing you know no no I got the recording
going it's best I can screen is what
they're gonna say yeah let her know hey
if you're seeing just yourself have to
do that for showing Alan Arkin okay
Megan I ver maior Kenobi already in a
little box extreme I don't think so i
think the people better might be so for
questions or the bathroom is pick up
Adele yeah maybe not sure I think about
it we got walk around this way since
with Trudy anyway I thought any glass in
the other 50 to Canaan overlooked there
we are yeah okay go down on the move it
to a leg sorry I would end up putting it
on our side this is cool i like this
yeah Jack essence of excitement when
rock it and then you bump and then we'll
just drop right into it okay and I'll
just speak the truth urgency soap on my
screen right now how to speak cat
picture resilience yeah
[Music]
hey gee mister man what's still here yes
okay were you no never good are you guys
are we glad I also see you though yeah
yeah I think we're about any negativity
about Megan yep bitch didn't commit to
do I can't see your whole slide we see
this other side of this mind if I feel I
can't see I think what it may be an
issue on resolution on my side that I
can't fix I'm moving it from my nine
versus think i fixed it never locked it
you got it good yeah good swing
privileged response to response let
minds my lamb reality show got bad
I handed my faculty that how's that huh
yeah so just raise your hand so that we
can see it I should the population well
I know she can but at the same time we
were to be a thumpin I may go make a new
video guerrilla and yes okay okay so do
you understand ok you ready then putting
an action no action sounds good that's
true action making me less than ready
appends oh I got off the five everything
well the nike i know you're watching hi
I don't really so happen to be
presenting for you guys my name is scott
lyons we're gonna go a little bit into
bio here very shortly but I'm Scott
Commission and today we're speaking
about how to speak cat pictures we do
you see okay and to do so you need to
know about how to make business case for
proactive incident response so first
thing for clear weather we are so I'm
Josh Martha I'm the CIA good one I've
been on the block man we want to
probably between me to content down
again I respect megaphone I remember a
super organization's mission ship misery
I share I one to decide lol with my life
a Tuesday and sleek and I guess thrust
up and I am Scotland I am the CEO of red
line I'm graduate school of business
apart not have worked all the histories
and commodity government I better go the
next two conferences which moon
comic-con to be tied Vegas be sizable
now b-sides dollar which is your
conference courts analysis right I bunch
of certification I'm not going to say
just which ones and what I'm really
loving it drives me are people business
and technology so if there was no II
farther I just want to go really click
that we are presenting their welcome
from Curtis you would like to gradually
a new thanks Bill Buckner and
age-related everybody at eight for
letting a specific moment we do
appreciate very much but since we're the
lender this week that kind of tough to
get West Virginia on the snap of a
finger we represented about catalyst
it's important my god peppers or most
important one unit god I love that
picture in the lower it's just Quantic
for talking about the agenda the redcat
the hair me not
me too nope lol is not that bad actually
it's me I parable each other men piece
of housekeeping but we have any
questions nucleus healed but Megan who
is a producer can raise your hand and
negative matching the static screen
ensuring palace of the discussion we
have cut to you ahead screams not making
anywhere near there so real talk about
Catherine Wiz not that into the response
or the fact that I our business cases
absolute languages and transmitting them
how to speak fluent in disease 100-point
so let's make a point that all of it
interesting search we need to talk about
can cast our data so in the castle
really there we go we're in the capsular
data we really have to ask why why are
you so serious about this guy the fifty
percent of clearing a break for fifteen
percent of all internet traffic is not
related I know right here's a couple of
links about more data right the data
grumpy cat vs dog or a cat videos right
and no presentation will be complete
without nyan cat have to put in there
okay no I talk about into the sponsor
minute now I knew come on with the
Appalachian is individual evidence my
response is kind of impaired with it so
different responses bansal atcha and
sorry Appalachian we're very picky a
hike announcer and wrong okay after
action and open the George I within
double run l and there's a city of
Memphis estate but it's spelled any
double-a arte the new jersey-newark and
lowers you work so I understand after
matches they said I don't yes yeah sure
anyway so irresponsibly so important you
have to make sure you have anymore okay
going to prepare that identified
and then you better learn the lessons
the compliment most common or any
lessons from in some spots but what do
you mean we never get ready for the next
one we don't learn how to talk to people
learn how to move forward you ready to
the next time you need is it a response
and come on let's be honest when's the
last time you may never have to get
ready cuz they're stopped again now when
looking at all of this you save yourself
for which one two most important from an
SME expert point of view they're all
important you know if you are not doing
your tabletop exercises and your
policies are correct along with your
standards new guidelines then doing a
lesson learned document after incident
you pretty much you pretty much shooting
yourself before you know when you're
looking at how to identify the group
left little when how and most important
why you have to go through your to the
top coat we said back in the prepared
speech to understand your contain stage
and Tamara it's to be the forensic
analysis is handing off the deer heading
off the methods that you're learning it
another teaching to be able to say to a
wrong person also should really did sure
how you duplicated as user exhibit it
should come out where effectively and
restrictions build on each other we
should compare because you learn for the
last one we should understand the root
cause analysis completed hours because
you learn from the last one everything
we do should build on the previous step
the previous indicates okay that's
basically we makin desert that one
before we can learn how from aid from
those teachings from various books and
courses and think that we read on the
internet because nobody ever live man
that I had we can learn what to do it
unit with ever done wonderful all right
that's family members and Giants so why
do we do I out what those please step
forward something's going to happen we
know that we instinctively leather why
it was it
also an exploring of a doctor because it
happened to us when I people explore
data push on email I mean how many
people here never ever ever been fish
yeah not many hands on back ok but we'll
do this person the mean as we speak with
Isco technologist okay I didn't think of
no other them so we know it's when we
would ask cliff that's not a question
Smithers I'm sorry sir they're talking
about I are the current business case
let Justin saying is when will we get
hit right you can't answer that what is
the percent chance that we'll get it how
much is it gonna cost me as we get hit
and most of it like little preparation
the preparation the incident remediation
when we saw my ability to speak out
because like honestly these things at
our customers a little subliminal
internet let's be honest here so if you
can to get those to run for daughter
okay but good to say yes again I'm going
to expound on that if we're gonna say
the percent put in certain lift are you
sure really Lindsey young look I don't
know when could be wrong could be next
year but what's gonna happen Josh you
know it's really funny that when
businesses do get sick by a breach or
where they have an insider threat with
them over there is some form of removing
money in skin in any way from
those businesses end up spending more on
security then when they're either
because it breached of course I mean you
got massive cost associated is the
response that's our networks I know
you're talking about this already
apologized but the costs include
everything from media remediation
ingredients a response a long-term code
changes will also productivity credit
monitoring depending what kind of build
that you've got all kinds of different a
cost associated with an infant and those
costs on the nitrous be unpleasant so
the Powder River business doesn't think
we need to think about those costs
relative and are you sure is the conger
I mean really want to tell me that and
we do it another spin close out more now
than 50,000 hour later that you can
easily add into a number that by the way
so when a business looks at security or
IT in general nine times out of ten for
this here I late what's known as a cost
Center okay it's not a prophet revenue
generating part of the business it cost
them money right so to be able to
understand how to translate that you
have to understand the speaking of
different languages from our to business
so looking at the real word let me say
well how does the deeper things person
out of the business personal effects
which are things like the brutal
business is provided that the been
diluted engine into the comp money it's
pretty common for the business which
enters open looks not right I don't know
it's not here is fixed rate and hilly if
you take it down to a person no members
access to my castle ensures that that's
that's problems and then we're actually
tell me what to make and which one up
with them at the dinner cartoon and say
Rebecca schedule
render them I'd be happy to provide it
to you a good attorney knows super
happiness and watching blinded you know
it over give a lot of really great
advice snarky Raven was good advice that
could actually be used to power a when
baby is teaching now too crowded this
actually works you know Adams over there
better than a straight of engineering
videos just outside so you'll see we say
this week 103 potato first of all ready
you can concentrate or segment the
network and persecuted wonder they can
talk about it yes they say the segment
the network does increase the security
with an air of a safe isn't it now yes
well then why do we do it well because
the hope of being is true I'm sorry look
now I'm gonna be the change 200 visited
earlier cost center well what's it gonna
cost to do that segmentation sure the
return on it may be more secure Network
nuts rest are lifting the pivot and so
on and so forth but really is it
committed it's going to cost because
it's not in the budget and yeah well I
wouldn't linux i nothing to you so these
things were done with this conversation
break lose a million dollars an hour and
they go all family and that's what you
have to do we have to explain the
ramifications then go to this case the
problems that can occur that these
problems actually delicious got that and
if it is much much more that it will
read books or religion tributions
imagine not even without the river would
possess place to understand how we can
make that money appear the next module
type of the next month the next clover
the next year you gotta make it a
business case not a technology case
really that something how do i add the
technical person make the topic
relatable how do i make explanatory how
to write elucidate
I say well this person looking you care
about then you pray about money you 10
11 even care that costs you clear about
service do knock-knock time but I
paratroop n you clear about every page
monkey business so hard on them to do
this well the event and so there's a
chance then a good example is pretty
long okay these industry sensitive areas
panini you have a website went down the
rules are perfectly attack that specific
effect on how to decipher set on and to
take that a step further it's not just
that the website went down is that now
our online presence and marketing is not
being affected though so we can't
generate new customers which means new
webinar right so learning to speak sweet
business Eve is really a big part of
this for the test of the person needs me
today all and simply put our network
apply our Active Directory include
properly and with the proper separation
of duties right so businessperson look
at how look at how long the explanations
are on the slide the business
explanation and the justification for
that one technical resource okay and
then going to put the scene of an
exactly text so will you tell us about
was that yeah there was no budget but
it's a Salesman faster it will help with
our many numbers and you can make it
relevant as a marketing terminology
and justification that helps a lot if
you behave when will increase
versatility with a customer data will
increase the security of our network and
want to use it as a marketing thing to
say we after security we need to be even
safer than ever before and the morning
another facility can use that then guess
what you turn into from a call center
come on revenue Center you know we were
just down in Orlando presenting an input
that wall and that's why we're here what
a presentation is about a very simple
concept and only if you and what you
talk about it go ahead Josh I have to I
have to do this because it is so
important that everyone everyone I mean
cousin you want understand this core
common contact okay so thank you for
bearing member solid a library so that
he was permitted it in a sec walk and in
oh man that was a great conference I was
really really recommended it's
unfortunate with the same time the road
who's already be there in West Virginia
we talked about with the technology very
good five percent and you could talk to
a venture capitalist and so he really
care about but instead turned up a
business I care enough routine I care
about the history I care about the
implementation internet the technology
isn't indirect Kirko said to me by
venture capitalist a serious thing we
must do you the doll I said I would hear
that the technology five percent but
unnecessary about but I understood that
perfect I recorded the technology the
complementation is pretty much worthless
and incredible invention of immediately
technology is with millions to billions
of dollars so that the technology to be
new technology that you discuss at
nanami issues you can break up don't
mean much for their destruction I just
got an email might if you can describe
it and elucidate alma mater mater that
makes sense to them you can explore them
them in a way that will understand the
monetary there the social the goodwill
the bleach 30 passes but none of the
clean sheets but if you can explain your
things in business language nothing why
does the care of our set which brings us
to our next topic and the reason that I
wanted to hear this was because we want
to be able to get across how to make
your point right and in making your
point it's very simple you explain these
things very clear stance and the senses
so why do you need the better when do
you need the budget and is it going to
interrupt me preventing my numbers as a
business as a service person to working
person consumable exact this quarter
this happier than one or two orders
annual whatever like the by doing this
how can you protect and how can you
improve lets going on with the business
how do you ensure with the business move
rooms in the class direction in a secure
manner and a lot of people have a really
long time being a roommate report so
we're better friends that goes does that
matter I mean the technology looks into
the business in business does it really
matter if they understand does it really
matter of things are you're working on
the revenue Center side we've got the
technology local leader for want an
answer is no and put this is an
ordinance okay I'm not gonna get into
the citizens united v or whatever that
that but a business an organism you
better have suppose that make we process
the Toyota car okay that has a technical
offers that make things work
dependability technical department
specific illiterate and the company's
products
but he also did the suspect the deposit
services but they are there to get them
into the customers hands administration
make sure you're getting to you because
I don't know about you but I read a page
that I got a common but you're gonna pay
check enginuity I mean I mean you're not
getting good to be there don't worry
right now okay but included a paycheck
you're asking out of the company so if
you look at they the payment of murder
we're probably make sure the customers
are coming in and you look the customers
coming in you'll repay you mean the
facilitation of the other the service
and products goes ahead and get
complicated our presenters balance only
did they make sure that the budgets
arrived from each other everything is
good the mixer things are working
correctly and you know you need hope you
know everybody else needs your net
happen in the end we all need to there's
no no we didn't want me to dance
somebody can hit maternal another minor
executives have to make sure the number
of the metal with the riverbed you to
lose your child in the company closing
down everything
way ok so the extra balance what we're
saying we need to do we need to spend
150 thousand or VPN concentrator federal
authority budget and we've seen when
fully funded so can we spend 75 and 7-5
mcclure you never know I at the box I've
been in my box another 15 Ellison are
they going where do we go for a quarter
you know ha you have to make the case
for that week and concentrator and
whatever the protector remove the new
enterprise for being proactive about
what a big galactic nuclei business case
for these things in a way to understand
how does this can we guarantee 75 this
quarter i do feel i committed one pile
of it and the next quarter with the
members have because people helping and
a little pain to be concentrated that
will be protected by than I really exist
the rivet economy when we didn't make
amends back and that's the resistance
and then you think it is this relevant
so in making it business relevant I hope
that we've been able to get the point
across to you on how to communicate how
to put it in Byzantine Rite and how to
really show the value behind what you
did more often than not we as security
people have to make the case for what we
do and it sucks you know it absolutely
stop having to make the case for your
job every day every hour every whatever
how often do you excited hey why do you
do we give you them because i don't i
don't understand it you know yes it is
so I think what we're going to do now is
uh Megan can you track the feed from
eight please the possible every day it's
not yet an item
we can't turn the laptop easily cuz we
don't have much room you're going to
come to us too and they're so is any bit
of entertainment can turn the cameras
memory well okay we have the issue of
having very short table angle the screen
I'm really the shit all the way so this
would be good sirs contents proper
credit disconnectors yeah that's not but
she won't see fuck that's right behind
you nothing doing the relay don't mind
but anybody who come into question where
we can just come up here assam done
daddy says it yet bueller view of its
trop froid at every website and hitting
on anyone okay so let me answer question
how many people that are actually
responsible is the response to it right
now okay how hard is it to get funding
done for your company if you don't put
in the business case very hard ah and
you learn to put in a business case for
them and if you have with a something we
would just sort of naturally even do to
get the word out Trevor pictures and
risk analysis your honor for you that
look at that in response person alex is
a very refined even left to collect and
you can tie them together and put
mystification place you can do something
that actually
you are significant about middle of
course when you're under to the next
problem a familiar which is if you
protect someone against that attack that
never actually happened but it will get
better before even starts to become
value with me really everything we've
seen but has been compression down the
river good value guys are amazing the
woman is going to find you here more
often or not is it a lot better of the
two taser yeah people need this company
to suffer breach to understand how much
money they really need to put into it it
it is such a difficult decision
particularly understand so how many you
have a comprehensive interest on
planetary devices how many of you about
400 people raise their hands sure
hundred people yes the audience a guy
cum having been proved you wrong oh now
let's sure that the people I don't you
have a possible how many times have you
filled every time what are you doing
very liver hands on your head desco we
can choking hey it's actually a bit funk
I'm not to management we have to get
character really had to come good any
why did you become an joke after don't
shut up okay so fugly may be passive and
her romantic fetishes the missus of
person that the names and they will be
same except everybody yes we're gonna
reserve attack but you learn about
Tamara yes he had not yes I said god I
appreciate that will give any questions
and really have an answer we're good
we're definitely not that kinda question
so I'm you listen you were while I
perfected it it's an excruciating tables
I don't think
I don't know good question I protect
y'all talking and thinking it time to do
this remotely next time it's required
you have to be here your little bit an
extra bone now that sounds so the point
here is everyone all you guys wear bells
but that's icing on a cake this comes to
a point guard Oliver's I'm not next year
that's this year let's discus
requirement next year sorry the next
year's requirement but you actually eat
here oh I mean this one this morning's
you in a dress company ramen hey thank
you for thank you for your time take you
to 82 thank you site for that TV guys go
and check them out go check out where I
keep their that TV is doing you can sign
up for a free account start viewing
videos and then if it's something that
you like the prices when we are not that
bad and it's great content delivered by
a very knowledgeable industry level
professional class they may let us use
their server room is the studio it's
kind of cool I mean you can Sophia it's
better go meet thank you ever giving
thank you guys
[Music]