when I'm on okay no so whoever it was
hanging everywhere you need to sound man
apparently so I'm bill Gardner and lets
you know me from digital forensics and
information assurance degree program
here at Marshall University so today I'm
going to sit down got bad knees you
can't see me on the video so we're going
to talk about rushing hacking so what is
this story about Russia hacking the
election so everyone's heard this right
so what actually happened well let's
talk about what actually happened and
talk about the narrative that we need to
be concerned about and sort of debunk
some of the other narratives that are
out there so basically how Russia hacked
our elections not really about hacking
it is to some extent but it's more about
information warfare in cyber warfare
nation-state against nation state and so
basically how this was done according to
the intelligence community there's a
joint report released by FBI NSA dia and
CIA which says that a Russian agent or
someone a hacker under Russian control
broke into join John Podesta desta's
email who was the chairman of DNC and
head of Hillary's campaign and stole a
bunch the email and at the same time the
Russians are well known for cyber
operations especially cyber warfare
Ukraine and March 2 2015 it's been
alleged and people have said they found
true proof that the Russians took down
Ukrainian power grid Matt Perry was
talked about this earlier about how he
went through his users and disabled
their macros because the attack vector
here was
macro so they basically send out we sent
out microsoft office files and told
people to enable it macros so that they
could it was supposed to be part parts
of utility operation but anyway that's
how they got pwned and that's allegedly
the foothold they use in order to take
down the Ukrainian power grid Russia has
a long history of cyber warfare there's
the 2007 disagreement with with Estonia
where a Russian war the Russian hero war
statue was in every Soviet bloc country
it was a tribute to date to Great Mother
Russia and how they'd send their troops
to liberate them with communism the
Estonians after break up the Soviet
Union said we want this thing out of our
town square and when they used when they
actually moved it there was there was
some hard feelings so in this attack
Russia basically knocked Estonia offline
for number of days sunny is a specially
wired country so banks were knocked off
line newspapers television I mean to me
that's them as disconcerning thing you
imagine waking up tomorrow you know wake
up tomorrow the power being out would be
pretty bad but if you woke up tomorrow
and none of your device's would give you
any news about what was going on the
world and then you want to get money out
of the bank and you can't that is kind
of discerning disconcerning and you're
able to do it with a country like a
stunning it because it's relatively
small also in the Georgian conflict the
2008 Russian cyber campaign actually
took down georgia targets including
defacements of the Georgian Parliament
website this is water not vodka by the
way in denial serve
attacks so most of the time what they're
trying to do here is disrupt information
so in the case study want to use to look
at this Russian hacking allegation is
the Democratic National Committee so
John Podesta is email was accessed by an
attacker or attackers using fishing and
and basically what they did was they
attack the weakest link you know
attackers don't break in through
firewalls anymore they're going to try
to bypass your next-generation firewall
and the billions of dollars that you
spent pending blinking like boss boxes
that your network parameter they're
going to attack user because users a
weakest link because people will always
make mistakes people will always fall
for your tricks for social engineering
so how this happens the attacker goes
through the following phases there is a
phase of information gathering attack
planning and then finally attack
execution so background an attacker will
look at an organization and use open
source intelligence so this is publicly
available information to find a number
of employees locations job openings the
names of the executives so they could be
targeted email formats and also current
events we have a very good example of a
current event that would probably make
people click on the links what if you
got an email this morning that said
actual footage of tomahawk missiles
hitting Syria would you be interested
enough to click on that if there's not
already efficient campaign using that
there will be soon because what what
fisher's what to do or attackers want to
do is to
to compel you they're going to sort of
reach for the your gut and say you know
hey you need to look at this there is a
need for you to look at this which will
overpower your other sense of I
shouldn't be clicking on links I don't
know where they go and you know
sometimes clicking on the link wins out
I mean I've been fished because I was
compelled by the link so we keep we had
a talk on Tuesday by one of my students
who's doing fishing campaign for
Marshall health and and one of the
complaints that the peeps the target of
the fishing the internal fishing
campaign is course security awareness
but they complained that you know
fishing campaigns would not be that
sophisticated and if you look a
nation-state back fishing campaign it's
going to be very sophisticated because
it's got billions of dollars and hot
into tens of thousands of people behind
it not everything is going to be an
offer from some prints in Africa to give
you money some fishing fishing campaigns
are very very sophisticated social media
websites are good for information
gathering and if you go to the
organization and finding an individual
you can drill down so that Facebook do
they have LinkedIn do they have twitter
do they have they have a Grindr profile
I mean you just keep going on you will
either asleep or don't appreciate my
jokes so you can find out about people
does anyone take in those surveys what's
your favorite color what street did you
grow up on where did you go to grade
school what's your mother's maiden name
I mean the mezz well just ask what your
freaking social security number and
password is right and I see a number of
people take those I've seen security
professionals takes those
because they're compelled they're bored
they want to interact with other people
and it's very easy it's sort of like the
copy and paste stuff that goes around
the Facebook you know in the 1990s all
we had was chain mail which was where
somebody would see something funny and
and they send it to all their friends
and then they would send it to all their
friends now with social media that gets
optimized by the ability to reach tins
you know tens of people or thousands of
people pretty quickly so if that's
weaponized in some way you've got you
can pretty quickly put a malicious link
or something that might cause data
leakage in front of people through
social media apparently and you know
okay so the other thing is google
hacking who is a very good book by
johnny long on google hacking does
anyone read that book which is not about
hacking google but using search terms to
find sensitive information and it's not
in the slide but I think another one
that's really great is show Dan if you
don't know how to use showed an if
you're a network defender figure it out
soon because it could you can really
give you a great insight on what you
might have on the internet don't know
about the recent example that I've used
is you know do a search for your state
and in search for windows XP and you
will find enough sort some of those are
false positive but you'll find 150 some
just for west virginia alone so there
what happened March the 19th of last
year there was an email sent to mr.
Podesta said someone has his password so
I mean this is pretty good right it has
the google logo on it it's got red it's
got blue it's got a little blue box that
you click to check your link to change
your password is would any does anyone
see anything fishy about this I'm sorry
would you like to walk up to the board
and take a look at it so anyway what we
have here is a festive sophisticated
attack they're hitting all the right
notes there's no misspellings it looks
really good it led to a bitly link which
led to a server in Russia which has been
dubbed by the antivirus people as fancy
their apt 28 were so fancy there needs
to be a rosetta stone of these different
names that anti viruses give them out
wear because it becomes a marketing
campaign okay also I'm trademarking the
term apt 69 so I have prior art this is
a this is actually proof of prior art
its chair squeaking i thought from
minute I was hallucinating so not only
defense against these sorts of attacks
social engineering so mr. Podesta was
you know clicked on the link and so what
happens is now they gain access to his
computer wherever it is it could have
already been on to dnc Network it could
have been in his house it could have
been in a hotel either way if it's
outside the network you dingos home or
goes back to dnc plugs it into the dnc
network and then it starts to propagate
so what the attackers were able to take
was just a bunch of freaking emails and
then they went through the email and
then it was leaked to WikiLeaks and the
attacker is known as gusoff or two point
oh who said
he's remaining and he's not affiliated
with the Russians but based upon the
intelligence community's assessment they
say is and I say it's probably still
opened to question but I'm stating the
facts here I'm not making a judgment if
he is or he is not employed by the
Russians either way there was an effect
on the election of some type now there
are some people who say that it's
overblown that you know this sort of
thing and the whole lot right campaign
which I'm going to talk about in a
second but they had no effect on the
election I think it's open for debate as
well you know the only defense is user
education if you go out look at
borschberg licks talk or the work by KC
urine on social engineering they've done
a really good job of talking about
defending its social engineering and you
should definitely go check it out and
one of the things that I talked about
not what I talk about social engineering
is we all have different learning styles
some people are visual some people are
are better listening physical etc so
basically what this boils down to is the
lecture is dead which is kind of funny
because I'm setting a pure lecturing to
you but hands-on training is a lot
better than listening to somebody talk
about it Amanda think left but she had
some good examples of security awareness
training one of our other speakers test
has basically built a security awareness
culture in her organization and you do
that by having a good internal marketing
campaign she makes it fun so for example
on in the summer and July they have
cookout and the cookout is themed about
security awareness and you have prizes
and accept you know all that sort of
thing security awareness is not
something you can do once
and it sticks if you're not you doing it
when you on board people you're making
the first mistake there if you do it
once a month or what's quarter once a
year you're also a bleep missing the
point it has to be a constant message it
also has to be a constant message
without making people tired of the
message and there was a recent study
from UK saying that the people have just
entered the space of malaise in what you
need to do a social engineer your users
to be more secure right you want to
trick your users into being more secure
if you preach it people I mean if you
got kids you know how is it how is it
how do they react when you preach to
them oh you know I've heard that before
you know and that our users are becoming
that way about security awareness about
fishing you know how many times can you
tell people not to click on stuff there
needs to be a better more targeted and
more sophisticated message as we move
forward also hands on does anyone have
an example of a good security awareness
hands-on exercise well if you're doing a
fishing campaign that's usually pretty
hands-on when they click on the link and
they realize they're not going to get
free baseball tickets but actually takes
them to an awareness page where they can
read about it the other thing I have to
say about awareness is that you know
this is the Dave Kennedy version is if
you if you're salesmen it makes you most
money in your core and your corporation
gets gets fist are you going to fire
them well he'll know you're throwing
you're throwing the baby off the
bathwater you're going to keep that
person you're going to educate that
person so it's all about education this
is all about learning styles
so in my example of a hands-on exercise
instead of telling you what a good
password policy is have them develop a
good password and there's some different
sites you can use or you could just set
down with them and they say well what
about this password or what about this
password and then also when you do your
your your own penetration test you can
just go ahead probably guess their
password you also might want to talk
about password policies and why we have
them so it's more than just saying we
need to do X it's about explaining why
we do X and as a result people will be
more willing to do it the other thing is
you need to explain to users that you're
not just guarding guarding corporate
organizational data you're guarding
their data in order for you to work at
an organization they have to collect
personal information about you social
security number where you live your bank
account so you can get direct deposit
your kids names your kids social
security numbers do you want to protect
that you're you have some skin in the
game you're personally invested when you
realize that your data is is there with
all everyone else's data and it's just
as important the other thing is you need
to talk about what malware actually does
and what it's targeted to do a lot of
people think Oh malware I'm going to get
a virus and slow down my computer if
that's the worst thing that happens
you're pretty cool off if usually what
will happen if your computer starts to
slow down its poorly written malware or
you're part of a botnet and the sort of
ironic thing is a lot of older people
just go buy a new computer and of course
they log in using and then do the same
thing that they did before and then it
gets gummed up with malware so they go
buy another computer they make Walmart a
lot of money doing this so you need to
educate users what malware is actually
doing so is it
an attacker cha putting you into a
botnet are they attempting to hide
credit card data they stole some place
else on your computer so they can move
it to the dark web to sell it so we have
to think the reason you know what our
attackers after we explain what
attackers are afters another hands on is
to have is to have the trainees read the
organizational organization security
policies and then reflect on why these
policies are in place so who's read
Marshall University security policies
test test test they're not just for
system administrators and security folks
if you are a user of Marshalls network
of course there's not a lot of students
in here you need to read those actually
use Marshall security policies as
examples in my network administration
class so that people can write their own
policies based upon their fictitious
company they come up with so the case
study again as the dnc hack and the
intelligence report which is the IAC
2017 dash 01 d intelligence community
assessment assessing russian activities
and attentions in recent elections so
they come to a conclusion and their
conclusion is that basically there was
an information warfare campaign part of
that where information warfare campaign
was based upon John Podesta Z male part
of that information warfare campaign was
the release of information to WikiLeaks
in order to embarrass nore Clinton's
campaign and the former administration
thought this was important enough to
release it is very rare to see
intelligence of this nature released but
I think that what the former
administration was trying to do was
trying to clarify the narrative the
Russians hacked
election now they didn't hack the
election we tried to influence elections
some people say that they did influence
to the election whether if Vincent 2.0
works for the Russians or not it still
happened and there has to be a reason
that it happened and the only reason
that people can point back to is the
Russians are trying to influence the
outcome of our election the other thing
is is that we're sitting around having
this conversation is enough to say that
they influence the election did we set
down in 1976 and talk about how China
got Jimmy Carter elected no but yet I'm
sure information warfare was in play in
1976 as it is in play now information
warfare has gone on forever there are an
entire units of the US army that do
nothing but information warfare so
propaganda public opinion propaganda was
a great class that I took as an
undergraduate what we're seeing as a
manifestation of this and it's sort of
bubbled to the top and as a result it is
confused and upset a lot of people and
that in itself is the goal one of the
goals of information warfare yes you and
a black shirt yeah so in 2011 the
Russians caught then Secretary of State
Hillary Clinton i'm reading this back so
that people in a video can hear it of
trying to promote on what rest to make
sure that mr. Putin was not re-elected
and that's probably the reason the
motive behind this is that what you're
saying the New York Times the same what
Bill article was written in 2011 as well
we've done this for years you know you
know seeing what's familiar with the
rise of the Shah of Iran that was all
cia-backed we had this word Vietnam
where basically the leaders of South
Vietnam was appointed by CIA we have
meddled in other people's politics
forever that's what NSA CIA do that's
their job NSA's job is signal
intelligence CA his job is is covert
intelligence and human intelligence if
they weren't doing this they wouldn't be
doing their jobs so I don't think it
should be shocking anybody that one
country is trying to influence election
in another country but it's very clear
based upon the report and also the
recent testimony of the head FBI FBI
call me that the Russians did not
penetrate our election system such as
voter registration and voting systems
but they were attacked which is also
probably happens every day I mean if you
look I always tell people who are new to
security to sit down even at your home
network and look at your firewall logs
there are so many automated attacks out
there and there's always somebody hammer
and down the door we're trying to hammer
down the door now if you see a lot of
these and you can find some sort of
pattern and that's what it appears to
has happened here the other problem is
attribution you know attributions a hard
problem
I can write you know right now i could
go on this computer spin up a VPS and in
japan and launch attacks against
wherever in the world there go my god
the japanese are attacking me now there
are forensic ways of going back and
figuring out who that was but it's not
always clear its many times muddy and
now what the release of the CIA vault is
a vault 7 others they actually have
tools that are made to confuse
attribution we all joke about the
attribution dice you know I used to have
some let's roll the attribution dice was
it North Korea you know if we're up to
Mandy at China would have done
everything here's the other issue in
this case which I will raise the actual
forensics was not done by the FBI on the
DNC servers or the DNC computers it was
done by cloud strike and then that
information that forensics investigation
was handed over to the FBI and when call
me testified before Congress they're
like why wasn't the FBI involved and the
reply was because our people said it was
just as good beware of the cyber
military-industrial complex when you're
making policy foreign policy decisions
based upon the attribution of a private
country company who was trying to please
shareholders I think there she be some
sort of question about that and if
you're a law on for takin see you
probably should follow up with your own
investigation the FBI is a law
enforcement agency it's scary to me you
know i'm not saying cloud striped
anything wrong but it's just scary to me
that we can have private organization
comes do forensics oh yeah well this is
it we know this is it because it's just
as good i don't know we could say that
especially when you're using that to
make foreign policy decisions
so let me talk about how it's good on
time now I'm going to talk about the
second part of this I'm going to talk
about the alt right and I'm going to
talk about hacktivism so hacktivism is
hacking for political means we all have
heard of anonymous right so anonymous
carried on a number of different
operations starting with operations
chanology operation technology was there
was this video of Tom Cruise just acting
kind of weird was released it was an
internal Scientology video was released
the internet Scientology using their
usual tactics of scary lawyers and
threatening letters we're able to start
taking these videos down but there's
this place called be on 4chan which is
the random channel which is inhabited by
a bunch of internet trolls and
malcontents and they said well every
time it gets taken down we're putting it
back up somewhere to the point where
Gawker actually got a copy of the video
put it on their website and under the
video it said if you want us to take
this down you're going to have to send
the FBI to come seized our servers so
then it became a free speech issue so
chanology was the first real hacktivism
as far as anonymous cos there's other
hacktivists operations out there there
was there were denial of service attacks
in in Germany and around 2000 because
believe it was boutons Lufthansa was
using their planes to deport immigrants
yeah 4chan did work with purveyors of
child porn in the past so United there's
this whole we're from the internet we're
here to help and you know technology was
the beginning we had op Soni we had
Operation Payback we're basically this
group of people on the internet wanted
to make things right
in their mind right but in in the in the
process of doing that some of them broke
some laws now you don't have to be a
hacker to be a member of anonymous and
some members of anonymous joined for a
specific operation and then leave
because they don't agree with the next
operation a lot of people left after
chanology because what happened next was
the the WikiLeaks controversy where you
could no longer give money to WikiLeaks
through paypal mastercard or visa so the
people and unfortunate people and
anonymous are like what I can give money
to the KKK and the neo-nazi
organizations of America what's the
difference between them and WikiLeaks
and this also goes back to the whole
information wants to be free which is
one of the basic values of hacker
culture right so WikiLeaks is making
information free I can't give money to
them anymore yet I can go out and buy
t-shirts with hateful riding on it from
the KKK or whomever so they they
basically took the meadows in their own
hands and watch denial-of-service
attacks against these a MasterCard
PayPal and took them off line in
Charleston at that time I was working in
a law firm it actually knocked our
network offline so I lost communications
with two of our offices couldn't
communicate with them because the denial
service attack was affecting other
network activities if you went down
capital streak that had lunch you could
not use a credit card or bank card
because all the point-of-sale systems
have been knocked offline so this took
over this happened over a course of a
few days wiki paypal mastercard and
these are all reversed their decision
you could give money to WikiLeaks again
so you know hooray we're heroes of the
Internet so what we have are basically
trolling denial service attacks and web
defacements in the case of operations
Sony there was a hacker named george
hotz george hotz was the first hacker to
jailbreak the eye
and he wanted to do the same thing with
his playstation and sony sued him so
anonymous went after sony operation
we're not talking about the North Korea
hack people get confused we're talking
about anonymous going after Sony were
threatening to sue are actually suing
George Hotz I think there was actually a
suit file in that case they started
defacing Sony websites across the world
and finally they broke into the
playstation network and took it down for
months they also help themselves to some
credit card information but in the end
they had proved their point the lawsuit
against mr. hots was broken and everyone
went on their way now you ask what
happened to people who did this I don't
think they ever caught the people who
did operation signing they did catch a
lot of people were doing denial service
attacks because they were downloading a
piece of software called low Earth ion
cannon it was a good ssin it's basically
a push-button script kitty kitty tool
where you put in the web address and you
push go and it would launch denial
service attacks and they're kind of
famous now they're called the paypal 14
they were indicted there were a number
of hearings all them pled out to very
small charges in the end and you know
but they actually think Brian Mittman
brink did a year or two in jail and
after he got out he couldn't touch a
computer so he's like how am I supposed
to look for a job if I can't touch a
computer so some people went to jail but
anyway what I'm getting to is is if you
look the all right they are the mirror
image of anonymous you look at weave and
storm front they are a mirror image of B
now Gabrielle Coleman who does a lot of
riding on hackers and activists
disagrees with me but she calls it the
weapons of the geek if you look at the
weapons of the geek which is trolling
denial service attacks troll
itself was used as an information
warfare campaign if I yell Pepe to you
what do you think you know the internet
frog was turned into a hay symbol so if
i say Pepe is that well I'm Noah saying
but they truly are able to take a NOC
uous internet meme and turn it into
something it was not in itself its
information warfare so Gabrielle Coleman
and other people who've written about
anonymous says that they had that the
alt right had no effect the problem
really is not this Magic Bullet theory
of communications we're i was like 'oh
Pepe oh yeah I left Rome that's not what
happened you have to pay you have all
this information this hate speech that
got passed down from person to person
call it multi-step flow communications
so it gets mangled again you don't know
where some of this information comes
from so by the time you get it the
information gets three or four people
you know three or four maybe 20 people
down the line they've got some narrative
that's come actually from the freaking
hate site so i think that the outright
did have an effect but not a direct
effect on the election and it's pretty
obvious where does we've live ukraine
right we've isn't as a nationalist he's
white nationalist he he gets along for
you but you know the Russians who
invaded and the people who want to yeah
the rebels in Ukraine they get along so
I'm not saying we've works for the
Russian government that they are pretty
well lined and there are other people
pretty well lined as well who may not be
direct agents to the Russian government
that they have been working as agents
the Russian government and the weirdest
thing to me as the people who were
formally identified as anonymous hate
this report
they say that guccifer 2.0 is just some
hacker that's fine and they also say
that WikiLeaks is just telling exposing
the truth that is also true but you
can't look at that a vacuum and not
understand that an election was effected
through the leaks through the trolling
web defacements on the use of memes in
December 2016 crowds cloud strike
actually found malware that was used
which was similar called fancy bear
which resulted in heavy losses of
howitzers and Ukrainian war with
russian-backed separatists what they did
was they were able to there's there was
basically an Android or an iPhone app
where you could use to target you
artillery that cut the number of the
amount of time to calculate you know how
high you raised the barrel and all that
sort of thing and they were able to use
this malware to target the artillery men
who were using it and the result is
according cloud strike heavily losses
and that was rushing back because it was
originally these were originally Russian
artillery the app was written by Russian
so they just basically weaponized it and
he used it and the point of really of
this is just to point out that the
Russians are not afraid to use these
sort of cyber means information warfare
etc in order to achieve their goals
don't have any questions this is worse
than teaching the afternoon everyone's
one
okay thank you for coming and for those
of you who gets the good to listen to me
talk all the time I'm sorry