by else is ready hi everybody welcome to
aid my name is Matthew Perry not that
one that one's they might know what CCP
stands for ways they mine old enough to
know what CCP stands for actually says
for certified computer professional it's
a it's a degree that it's a degree used
to be able to get back in the 90s
working with the IBM stuff I used to be
a board member of aid a board member and
treasurer of three or four geeks help
run a conference here in Charleston
called hacker con it's in September just
look it up everybody should come I work
right now at the Masters law firm I'm a
network administrator and a detective I
run an online gaming group called red
sky that's a picture of the family and
I'm actually a licensed minister so what
does that mean I really do well you know
I do litigation support trial support
network admin database analysis box
carrier hacker and I'm a little bit of a
social engineer so at the end of the day
I'm really just the computer guy today's
talk is about ransomware we got hit at
work twice and on the first day of
seminary school my professor said the
key to a good sermon is you have a good
opening and a good closing and you don't
make a very far apart so I'm going to
give you guys the secret to surviving
grant somewhere right at the beginning
and then we'll go through a little bit
about what read somewhere is and how it
goes but the secret to surviving
ransomware is real simple backups got to
have good backups and we'll talk about
that and the secret to having good
backups is this not those guys but keep
it simple keep it really simple
pick whatever kind of backup you want to
do tape backups off-site backups cloud
backups doesn't matter but you have to
do them you know and this this really
hit home to me back when I used to work
at the Sheriff's Department and we had a
reel-to-reel tape backup and man that
thing was it was it was ridiculously
hard to use and I made a mistake of
never Testament so consequently we had a
date we had a hardware failure and had a
big problem this surveying company did a
survey of IT professionals over 300
organizations and found and nearly a
hundred percent reported that they were
actively backing up their data and out
of those that had not yet experienced a
ransomware attack eighty-one percent
said they were confident that they would
be able to recover any of the data that
the attackers our cryptid encrypted
without paying the ransom however as you
can see from the bottom of the
professionals that had that had been hit
by a ransomware attack only forty two
percent were able to successfully
recover their data and the main reason
for that was because of unmonitored and
failed backups matter of fact that the
reason I have the job that I have now is
because of a failed back up the at the
law firm their server crashed and they
went to restore from the backup and it
was it was empty and they called me to
help them recover their data and that's
how I ended up getting a job there so
the more all of the story with backups
is you test test and test if you've got
to back up and you haven't ever restored
from it then it's not really a backup
this is how i do my backups is real
simple i just wrote this little batch
file that runs on my computer at night
at eight o'clock and it copies
everything to one of the network access
storage devices and then i have an
incremental backup we'll talk about that
later in at the end
so now that I've told you the secret to
surviving ransomware let's talk a little
bit all this is this is the screen that
pops up on my computer every morning
when I come into work and I check it
every day just to make sure that it
worked great so what is ransomware read
somewhere is the type of malware that
affects computer systems restricts
access to the infected systems there are
a lot of variants going around and it's
evolved over time but most of the time
they ask you for money to get your stuff
unencrypted how does ransomware work
well there are several methods that you
can get infected you can most popular of
course email attachments you can get
infected by what of going to the wrong
website and having malicious code
downloaded to your system you can get
infected from a bad USB Drive or you can
actually get infected through an instant
messenger file or link and here's a each
ransomware variant is engineered to
operate a little differently however
common traits include fairly complex
stealth techniques and covert launch
mechanisms meant to avoid early
antivirus detection including obscure
file names modifying file attributes and
operating under the pretense of
legitimate programs and services and as
an example cryptolocker which is one of
the more widespread ransom wears it gets
installed by a zbot variant and that's a
trojan an email trojan and after
execution is edge itself to start up
under a random file name and tries to
communicate with the its own command and
control server and if it can then it
gets a public key and a Bitcoin address
and then it encrypts the files on your
computer and it does over 70 different
file types so why does ransomware work
well the main reason is this
because you clicked it not many people
here know Boris but he's famous for
saying don't click stuff so that's the
main reason ransomware works is because
people clicked it the second reason is
because most people have a disaster
recovery wood frame like this and then
the last reason of course why it works
is because people just don't have good
backups so where does ransomware come
from there's been a couple of stories in
the news the Dutch police busted a
couple of kids who were running a
ransomware scam here's an article about
ransomware scam people from China but at
the end of the day rolled bills
attribution dice and you just come up
with wherever ransomware could be from
why can't anyone stop it well just like
Smokey the Bear says the only real way
to stop ransomware is you have to stop
it yourself nobody's going to do it for
you nobody's going to protect you the
government can't protect you that matter
how many air bases we blow up in Syria
they're still going to be ransomware and
the other thing is read somewhere works
and it's so popular because people say
you know back in the old days when email
first started and everybody got
thousands of male enhancement emails in
their junk mail box every day the reason
people were sending us out is because
somebody someplace was bottom they
weren't just doing it for fun and that's
what the deal is was ransomware people
are paying so as long as people keep
paying there's going to keep being
ransomware so here's the first attack
that I was hit with it was Christmastime
2015 and of course all the supervisors
in the office were on vacation and I
came into work one morning and I'll
check my backup screen us all that huh
that's not good so I go walking around
the office and I find
a computer at this lady's desk that had
that screen on it and it was telling me
what I needed to do to get my data back
now I started looking around on my file
server and fortunately this version of
crypto where only attacked drives that
were mapped on her computer so she could
see the main server drive and she could
see the drive for our document back at
our document management system was and
in her c drive that was it and
interestingly enough this version of
ransomware had an error in its code
because it crashed out at the old two
gigabyte file limit so it only encrypted
the first two gigabytes of my server
fortunately for me so what the
aggravating thing about this resin where
attack was this was this was on her
computer and it had been on there since
the day before and I asked her about it
and I said did you see that right and
she's like yeah I was like well yeah why
didn't you call me just well I don't
know i just opened an email and that
popped up and i didn't know what to do
it newest to say she didn't work there
anymore so this is how I fixed it I
first called my friend bill that was his
reaction but then I deleted all the
encrypted stuff and i restored it from
the back up that was it I took her
machine out of service didn't even
didn't even attempt to clean it i just
knew too wiped out the hard drive
started over on hers now the second
attack i had was in the summer well it
was in last summer I was about to go to
lunch and I have an incremental backup
that runs during the day and it has a
little window on my screen and I can
kind of watch as the files go by and all
of a sudden this stuff started popping
up and I thought oh that's not good so
jump up from my desk run around to the
computers in the office and sure enough
I find one with that on it an interest
this situation was a little different
because as I walk into the room the
secretary looks at me and she says I'm
glad you here I was about to call you I
tried to open an email and with the
picture in it and didn't work and I was
just getting ready to call you I said
okay well and then as I was yanking her
computer out of the wall and carrying it
back down to my office I said okay
thanks so this version of ransomware
septa worked a little differently and
that it ignored what drives she was
mapped to and it just went out and
scanned the network and it started at
what would have been the lowest drive so
like my z drive and it started
encrypting there which oddly enough was
my backup drive so the main server was
fine but it encrypted the backup and so
I really didn't suffer any loss in this
because I just deleted the back up and
made a new one so let's talk about
building a defense against ransomware
which is the project I've been going on
at work for the last 18 months and it's
a it's a progressive thing and after
after every attack of course I had to
change and get better but the first
thing to know about building a defense
is it has to be in layers just like
onions and ogres it has to be in layers
the most important thing and the first
line of defense is always training and
education you know the first lady and
the end the that I told the story about
from the first attacks she didn't speak
up I all know Washington call me but
that was the main problem I had with her
now the second lady she was going to
call me and I believed her when she told
me that because it was lunchtime and was
right the beginning of lunch and she
said she was going to call me after
lunch so I've made a big deal about now
you know soon as you see something I
would rather get filled 10 calls a day
from people asking me if this email is
okay to open that I would spend a bunch
of time fix
one of these the second thing is report
something if you do click on something
that everybody clicks on something that
shouldn't at some point in time I have
everybody in this room has at some point
time you click on something and after
you click on it you thought I shouldn't
have done that well the key is you have
to tell and this is the screen that
people get I've started using a piece of
software called hitman pro and I've got
all my staff now trained us is but if
they see that screen they better call
now how do you tell if an email is
dangerous and that's the this is the
first obviously the first big part of
the education that you have to go
through with everybody so here's a few
examples these are going to be really
hard to see I have a feeling but the the
the main thing is the first thing I look
at is the URL but you know the thing
about this email is striking to me and
and and I'll tell this story you know
this is an email from british airways
and I don't know why somebody would
click on this because the first thing
you have to ask yourself is well did you
buy ticket on british airways why would
they be talking to you and it seems
silly but you know i had a lawyer in my
office so this is a guy who'd been to
law school been a law clerk for a
federal judge practices law could be
representing you or someone in your
family and it would create a case and he
calls me and he says Matt you have to
help me i won the canadian lottery and
it says on this email that i have to do
some stuff to claim the prize and i said
let me ask you a question did you buy
ticket in the canadian lottery and he
said we'll know i said well then why do
you think you won well because this
email i said you didn't really win
that's a fake email please tell me you
didn't click anything and of course he
had and he got a virus on his computer
so you know the first thing you have to
you have to beat into your users heads
is the email legitimate the other thing
I teach my you know you teach everybody
look at the spelling look at the grammar
hover over the links in the email and
see if they match who the emails coming
from is it something you were expecting
here's another good example you know the
email the subject line is bad and you
know the attachment is it is a dot zip I
just quit except in God zips at work I
we just we just quit taking them if
another law firm says it's something and
it's as if I I tell them they have to
drop box that are sending some other way
we just don't think of this is a good
one everybody gets these fake shipping
emails and you know if you're not
expecting a package then you know don't
even bother looking at it you know it
was the email sent to if you look at
your if you look at an email and there's
a 37 addresses and who is going to and
you don't know any of them then you know
that's obviously fake and you know
there's this one's from Germany I mean
do you even know anybody in Germany it's
just obvious things that you but you
really have to beat these into your
users heads over and over and over again
this is an example from this is one of
our emails this one's very close to the
one that was the cause the first attack
it's a zip and it's about an invoice to
what got me about this one is look at
the country code in the emailed I'm not
sure where ESS I guess it's Estonia you
know why would we be getting an email
from there to begin with why would you
even be open in that and then this one
was very close to the second one now
what this the lady who got hit with the
second attack hurry the email that got
her was very clever because and it was
really kind of lucky because we had a
client his name was Rita and the and it
was this lady's caught a case she was
working on and she was expecting her to
send some pictures oddly enough and so
she got an email this is nothing
exact same one but she got an email that
said Rita at and then it just had a
generic email address and it said it was
a Jeff now it was a jiff top zip like
this but it was a Jeff and so she
thought it so it was really kind of a
perfect storm that she got caught up in
now so I started investigating after
education I started investigating some
other solutions to try and help this and
make it stop first thing you can look at
is you know call your call your email
vendor and see if they have a spam
filtering virus filtering at the source
you know whoever your host is they can
filter out some of this stuff the next
thing and this happened this is handy
for a lot of things other than
ransomware especially spam stuff I had a
buddy of mine in Oklahoma City they got
email bombed I mean he was getting five
or six thousand emails a day because he
had been somebody had subscribed him to
all these listservs and he couldn't get
out of all of them I mean he was trying
to do it it would be they were coming
faster than he could deal with so I
helped him implement whitelisting and
there's some interesting whitelisting
solutions out there basically it's you
only get emails from people that you
allow to get emails from now you know in
some businesses you probably can't do
that but it helped help them and it's
it's good practice hardware solutions
you know everybody needs a firewall to
keep the devil and the death and the
fiery skulls out you know when everybody
likes a good blinky light box some
firewalls can can do content filtering
email content filtering they tend to be
slow and they tend to be expensive there
are some good software solutions that
you can install on everybody's desktop I
really like hitman pro it was cheap for
our office like 600 bucks for 30
installs
and for three years and it runs really
well the other ones malwarebytes it's
similar to hitman pro but you know I
called them about a about a solution for
my office and I said I needed 30
licenses and they said I we don't think
we could do one that small so they were
they were for obviously for much bigger
much bigger organizations another
important thing to do is check your
security settings on your on everybody's
computer and this is something I'm in
the middle of right now is you know this
is a concept of the least privilege so
have everybody security settings set
everything to know and then only turn on
the things that they gripe about not
being able to do that's kind of that's
kind of the policy implementing right
now and then the newest one I'm going to
do is the new round of computers i'm
going to install nobody is going to be
admin on their own pc everybody's just
going to have a user account and then
i'm going to be the admin on everybody's
pc because the machines do we have now
everybody has an admin account and so
I'm going to just on their PC but i'm
going to switch that to everybody just
having a plain user and then i disable
macros on everybody's system you know
nobody needs nobody needs to be able to
run all those macros onward stuff now
the next thing is when I talk about the
beginning layered backups this is kind
of how this is get an outline of how
mine kind of works I do a daily backup
at night to the network storage device I
do a daily backup to a local hard drive
I started doing that because of the
second ransomware attack you know that
the zip toe was able to scan the my
entire network and see everything so I
needed a place to back up to that wasn't
shared so I'm doing I have a local a
local device just hooked up to my pc
that I do a backup to every day
I do a daily incremental backup to a
pendrive that goes with the and I carry
it with me all the time that goes with
me home to the off-site backup and then
I have a weekly beers my daily
incremental backup do a weekly backup to
a different hard drive quarterly to
still different hard driving and I
update the off-site backup every three
months something else you may want to
look at especially if you have a
business lost insurance policy already
is making sure that you have cyber
insurance cyber loss insurance so does
your insurance have an exclusion for
data loss it may and if it does then you
have to have a cyber insurance policy or
writer to your insurance and then even
if you have a cyber insurance policy a
writer then you have to check out the
cyber extortion clause to make sure that
you're covered for ransomware or check
the limits and the deductible the
deductibles to highs probably it might
be worthless anyway the last thing I'm
just going to the next thing I'm just
going to briefly mention is you know
what is a Bitcoin and I never recommend
paying for any of these but and I'm not
going to go into how to get a Bitcoin
and how all that works but you know you
just go to Bitcoin calm and you can
start reading about it we were kind of
having to discussion out in the hallway
a minute ago about bitcoins and the
wallet that you have to get and all the
personal information that you have to
put in there but it might be a good idea
to at least familiarize yourself with it
until you're having to do it in an
emergency situation so oh man you got
hit what do you do now because sooner or
later everybody is going to get hit
whether you want to or not where you
want to be or not no matter how careful
you are no matter how prepared you think
you are so the first thing is how do you
know you got hit well I know because I
check my backups and my data every day
a couple times a day I view this screen
in the morning every time when I come in
and then I look at it again at least
once a day just to make sure there's
nothing that looks like that the other
thing the first thing to do is you got
to find the entry point and so if you
got hit somewhere on your network there
will be a pc that has this on the
desktop and the first thing he's always
encrypt is the stuff that's on the
desktop and then the C Drive and then
they jump out from there so they'll be a
desktop someplace that has that on it
now you know if you can remote login to
all your desktops that makes it easy I
have to get up and run around check with
everybody and look at them all but
you'll find one the next thing to do is
to stop the infection from spreading an
easiest way to do that is this just yank
Arella wall that's what I did both times
then you have to start looking to see
how bad it was get on your server start
doing some searching you know all these
tend to have the same like zip code
names all the files dots up those so you
can just do a search and see where all
it went and then they all have a little
HTML file at that they put in every
folder that has that instruction screen
you can search for that and see how bad
it is and then this is something Jason
Street tweeted day before yesterday a
news article about this website called
new more ransom and that's their that's
their URL and what they have is a bunch
of unencrypted tools that they have
posted on their website so that maybe
you could unencrypted your stuff
yourself without without having to pay
and this was put up by you can see just
put up by their the Dutch police
Interpol and Intel and Cooper scheme and
I looked I looked on there yesterday and
is that they have a bunch of different
types of resin where's that they can
help you unencrypted
so then the next thing you got hit what
do you do well at the other day you just
delete it restore it and move on any
questions comments queries yes mr.
Gardner yes this will be on the phone
and it was on the syllabus anybody else
yes it will well the gamble in that is
I'm assuming that it's not going to it's
not going to encrypt my device see it
because if I don't trigger the
ransomware then it's not going to get to
my pc you see what I'm saying because
see my drive is not shared on the
network so unless I trip the ransomware
it's not going to get the local device
that I have on my pc now if I screw up
in trip to ransomware then you're right
yeah go ahead right right II
[Laughter]
right right well and in my case in both
instances of my case it did ignore that
because my document management system
has its own backup like you're talking
about and it doesn't back up into a zip
it has its own esteem because it the
name of the program is called Tom
matters and it backs up into a dot TM
well read both versions of ransomware
that TDM wasn't on its list so in both
instances my document management system
and its backups were untouched because
the extensions were not on its list that
it looks at but yeah the ones that it
was basically the same as the ones that
you're talking about you know I I lost
all my docs I lost all my excels I lost
all my powerpoints I lost all my pdfs
you know those are the main ones that
they're going to look for anyway now
that the interestingly enough we did
have some you know I have some very very
old data that was WordPerfect data from
I mean from years ago legacy stuff from
very old cases that we keep just for
reference and didn't get those this is
too old so yeah you know that's a valid
point you know if you if you if you have
a backup archive system that you can
kind of hide in plain view if you're an
extension that's not on the list yeah go
ahead
branson area that my state so you may
get the infection but it but it won't
act it won't start encrypting because it
can't go back to the command control
server yeah right right because it can't
get the key ya know what's good that's
probably true right right yeah that's a
good point anybody else all right thank
you guess
tell adrienne to come back in turn to
turn the camera off