Vulnerabilities from Venus, Management from
Mars: How to Navigate the Unknown
Cassandra Brunetto
CHERYL: Cassie Brunetto is our next speaker,
great experience in terms of IT, risk and
compliance and building security programs.
She's also the founder of Gatebreachers this
talk is managing success with programs.
And then some question and answer afterwards.
so, please put your questions in the talk.
And a word of praise and thank you to our
very generous sponsors.
Thank you if you've explored the expo hall,
if not, take a few moments to say hi.
And without further ado, I will pass this
over to Cassie Brunetto.
CASSIE: Thank you.
My name is Cassie.
My talk is Vulnerabilities from Venus, Management
from Mars: How to Navigate the Unknown.
Before I get started, I would like to introduce
myself.
My name is Cassie.
My pronouns are she/her.
I'm the ID and compliance manager at Graylog.
And dog owner of Astro, the lovely German
shepherd on the right and many of you know
from Twitter.
I play a key role in identifying, managing
and monitoring cybersecurity risk within more
organization.
I started in help desk and worked my way up.
Got my bachelor's degree in information security
and assurance and got a master's degree in
my second position in security.
And then in 2019, I founded Gatebreachers,
and we work on inclusivity and look to see
more underrepresented genders in the field.
Shoutout to everyone trucking through and
learning more while we have been in a pandemic.
You're awesome.
And I got some certifications.
Just to learn and, you know, I think that
everyone can learn from them.
And but not required in the field.
So, I have the CISSP, the CISM and the Security+.
And you are all joining me for my first GRC
talk.
So, thank you so much for joining me!
So, why do we care about building effective
security programs?
Well, in 2013 Yahoo! suffered a security breach
affecting 3 billion accounts.
They were fined $85 million.
And it took them 3 years to discover and disclose
the breach.
And almost 4 years to complete the investigation.
In 2014 Home Depot credentials were stolen
from a third party which led to a compromise
of the point of sale system.
This resulted in a $200 million fine.
Threat actors likely completed the initial
breach through a third party supplier workstation.
Then they surveilled the cardholder data and
then tested the attack to capture and expirate
data.
In 2016, Uber paid the criminal that hacked
its driver and user accounts $100,000 which
led to a $148 million fine.
The chief security officer and one of his
deputies were fired for their roles in concealing
the attack.
In 2017, Equifax lost personal and financial
information of 150 million clients due to
an unpatched database framework resulting
in a $575 million fine.
Threat actors were able to move from a consumer
complaint portal to other servers because
they weren't segmented from each other.
And they had usernames and passwords stored
in plaintext.
This year in 2021 the Colonial Pipeline proactively
shut down its operations after a ransomware
attack, resulting in fuel shortages along
the East Coast.
The company believes that attackers exploited
a legacy virtual private network profile that
did not have multifactor authentication configured.
The Colonial Pipeline also paid a $5 million
ransom to the Russian base criminal group,
Dark Side.
As you can see, it's extremely important to
build a program to protect, prevent, respond
and recover from cybersecurity incidents.
So, you have been hired to manage the information
security program at a new company.
How do you build a security strategy without
becoming overwhelmed?
How do you define the scope for security initiatives?
Before we can create a security roadmap or
strategy, we need to thoroughly understand
the basics, so we'll want to talk to employees
and discover more about the new company and
its culture.
What does the company do?
You want to talk with senior management about
the current state of the organization.
What product or service is being provided?
What kind of data is being accessed, processed,
transmitted or stored?
Do you have any information security or regulatory
requirements that have to be met?
What are the company's current initiatives?
Is there a new functionality or service being
implemented into a product?
Does the organization plan on hiring new employees
or building new teams?
And what are the company's goals for the future?
You also want to consider scalability and
cost efficiency when architecting security
processes and controls.
Next you want to understand the company culture.
Is this currently a managed security program?
You'll want to review policies, procedures,
guidelines and standards.
You can also interview employees about currently
implemented security practices.
And is there any framework that the security
program is already aligned with such as national
information, NIST cybersecurity framework?
And how do employees feel about the security
controls in place or the lack thereof?
Are security controls hindering operational
effectiveness?
Are the security controls aligned with the
mission and vision of what the organization?
Are the security controls actually meeting
their objectives?
Is there a security awareness training program?
What type of security awareness training program
is provided?
Is training tailored to the organization and
its employees?
And are metrics being used to measure the
effectiveness of security awareness training
program?
Finally, are there documented security policies
and are they disseminated to employees?
Are new or updated policies communicated to
employees?
Is there a central repository where employees
can review relevant policies?
And how often are employees required to review
these policies?
You'll also want to understand the data classification
scheme being used, if there is one.
So, we want to ask ourselves, is data being
classified currently?
If so, what are the data classifications currently
being used?
Is there a standardized classification?
Are the data classifications clearly defined?
Ideally, there should be an easily accessible
data classification policy or standard that
defines data classifications and provides
clear examples.
Next, you want to identify the crown jewels.
What are the crown jewels?
What does the company consider important to
its mission, objectives and operations?
The crown jewels can be source code, intellectual
property, personally identifiable information,
personal health information, and other proprietary
data.
Who owns the crown jewels?
Who is accountable for the confidentiality,
integrity and availability of the crown jewels?
You'll want to interview senior management
and other business unit managers to identify
the information owners.
Then you want to understand where the crown
jewels are located.
Where the crown jewels being accessed, processed
and stored?
You'll want to identify any applications,
systems, and services.
This information can be extremely helpful
when you're creating data flow diagrams.
Next you'll want to understand how the crown
jewels are being accessed.
How can I access the crown jewels?
Is there multifactor authentication required?
Are there shared accounts?
Which brings us to who has access to the crown
jewels?
Who are the people responsible for using the
crown jewels during their everyday tasks?
It could be developers, engineers, sales,
or marketing teams.
And finally, who needs access to the crown
jewels?
We want to make sure that we're removing any
unnecessary access.
We want to also ensure that we're provisioning
access according to the principle of least
privilege and ensuring that we are reviewing
all privileged access.
We have to remove any accounts or any access.
This could include service accounts and any
type of things that are standardly configured
in Active Directory.
You'll also want to take an inventory of the
infrastructure.
What does the infrastructure look like?
Is there a network flow diagram or a data
flow diagram?
Are we using Linux or Windows on servers?
Are we using a cloud hosting providers in
are we using containerization or a container
orchestration technology such as Kubernetes?
Then we want to understand the technology
stacking with used for product services offered.
Apache?
MySQL?
Elastic search.
And then who is managing the infrastructure?
Is there an engineering team?
Is there an operations team or is it information
technology?
We can also interview any employees about
the current practices and processes.
Third party vendor risk management.
Is there actually a managed third party vendor
risk management program?
If yes, are there any established practices
or procedures?
Any templates or questionnaires that are currently
being used?
Or are we going to build program from scratch?
If so, we want to consider the third party
vendor life cycle and the processes that we're
going to develop to onboard and off board
vendors.
Who are the high and critical vendors?
Have they been assessed?
How frequently will high and critical vendors
be assessed in the future?
And is the right and ability to audit controls
currently included in any vendor contracts?
Which vendors are being assessed?
You want to create an inventory of third party
vendors, document the services that are being
provided, the business unit being serviced
and any third party vendor contacts.
You'll also want to determine the assessment
requirements for third party vendors.
For example, cloud hosting providers must
provide type 2 reports.
Who are the organization's key players?
It's important to identify the owner of risks.
Who are the risk owners?
Is it the chief technology officer?
The Vice President of a business line?
It's important to establish and document any
type of risk ownership.
Next you'll want to identify key players.
Who are the information security program's
stakeholders?
It could be the marketing, sales, or engineering
departments.
Who are the subject matter experts?
You'll want to identify information technology
and information security subject matter experts
throughout the organization.
And keep in mind, they might not necessarily
work in the security department.
There may be employees in other departments
that have security knowledge.
Who do other employees trust?
Is there somebody that can assist you with
implementing security initiatives that other
employees trust?
You'll want to build relationships with these
key players.
It is crucial to build relationships with
the key players in your organization to gain
trust and credibility with other employees.
Key player are the vehicle that will drive
your security program.
They will have insight and tribal knowledge
that will be overlooked if you try to establish
processes on your own and it's integral to
include them in important conservations and
discussions.
Defining the scope of your security program.
First, you'll want to identify gaps.
What is the current state versus what is the
desired state?
You can use the NIST National Institute of
Technology Strategies of framework implementation
tiers.
There are three tiers.
Partial, risk informed and repeatable.
So, for example, your current tier might be
risk informed and your desired state would
be repeatable.
Then you'll want to identify risks.
You can use threat modeling and perform a
risk assessment.
Then you want to consider the risks presented
by identified gaps.
Does the risk of an ineffective security control
surpass the organization's risk appetite?
Then you'll want to prioritize these risks.
What risks need to be mitigated based on the
identified impacts?
We want to mitigate the risk with the greatest
adverse impact and the likelihood of occurrence.
It's important to develop realistic security
program goals and I'm going provide you with
some advice that I wish I had when I first
started creating security risk and roadmaps.
First off, set yourself up for success.
Develop SM ART which stands for specific,
measurable, attainable, relevant, time based
goals for performance and project management.
Your goals should align with the mission of
the organization.
For example, one of your goals could be to
decrease security risk by developing a vulnerability
and patch management process.
Or increase security awareness by providing
interactive security training to employees
on a periodic basis.
Don't be too ambitious.
There may be dozens of fires to put out, but
you only have so much time and energy.
You'll want to prioritize critical and high
risks and develop a project plan.
Do not be a jack of all trades and a master
of none.
There may be many opportunities for improvement
in areas such as network security, application
security, logical access security, or third
party vender risk management.
But you should target significant gaps that
have been identified during the scoping phase.
Focus on one area and be exceptional.
Improve one area with significant gaps.
For example, if you don't currently have an
identity and access management program, one
of your initiatives can be focusing on standardizing
roles and access and then integrating single
sign on or multifactor authentication with
critical applications and privileged user
accounts.
Communicate your boundaries with your manager
and other teams.
Don't be afraid to say no just because you
think you'll disappoint your manager or your
team.
You want to define you and/or your security
team's job scope.
And establish open lines of communication
between other teams and the information security
department.
Do not take on an overwhelming amount of projects.
Avoid burnout and avoid stress by managing
less projects.
Create a project plan including a timeline.
You can create a Gantt chart or use free online
tools.
And consider using other resources.
This brings us to leveraging third parties.
You can hire third parties for larger projects
like incident response or disaster recovery
capabilities.
Third parties can also help you build and
house teams.
Third parties can be more cost efficient than
building capabilities in house.
You can also consider hiring consultants for
short term projects like creating policies
or hiring employees.
Consider outsourcing short term projects that
require experienced subject matter experts.
Consultants can also be more efficient than
hiring full time employees.
Last but not least, make incremental changes
throughout time instead of attempting to remediate
all gaps within a short amount of time.
Patience is key.
It takes time to implement processes, change
or build a security culture, and create key
performance or risk indicators.
But you want to make sure that you're documenting,
tracking, and measuring and reporting all
of your progress.
You can easily show your impact on the organization's
security posture.
Don't forget to celebrate small wins.
It's like a 10 mile hike.
Don't focus on getting all the way to the
top of the mountain.
Be enthusiastic about reaching small milestones
throughout your journey.
Well, that was my talk on starting a security
program.
I can be reached on Twitter.
My handle is loquaciousloka and I'm on LinkedIn.
I have included in my slides the implementation
tiers.
So, feel free to take a look at that once
I have shared my slides.
Thank you!
CHERYL: Congratulations!
That was a great talk.
I like how you walked us through the steps.
But you just really simplified, but called
out the important things.
We have some good questions from people in
the chat.
I'll start with the first one.
This is from Duane Dunston, and he wanted
to know how many organizations you have consulted
with that identified the crown jewels and
now where they were located?
CASSIE: I would say that the amount of organizations
that had that before I was there would probably
be zero.
Maybe one in the financial industry.
But I would say that this is a process that
not many people do, in my opinion.
And creating an asset management program or
inventory or configuration database is like
something that's I've rarely seen.
So, getting this, you know, obviously you
build upon asset management into vulnerability
management and patch management.
So, it's really important to know what you
have before you can protect it, of course.
CHERYL: Absolutely.
We have another question.
This is from a volunteer, and he wanted to
know, how do we make some of this work in
a small business environment?
CASSIE: A small business environment.
I would definitely recommend thoroughly doing
your research.
Your due diligence.
And preparing any type of evidence that you
can provide to whoever writes the checks.
And just really getting intimate with your
fellow coworkers and you're gonna be building
relationships and having to work with them.
And just really understanding what role everyone
plays in the organization.
And architecting security controls that make
sense financially.
That play nice with any type of legacy technology.
All of these factors you really have to take
into consideration.
But I would definitely put an emphasis on
the cost benefit analysis because small SMBs
are gonna want to go with the least costly
controls or processes to implement.
So, you want to make sure that you have, you
know, evidence and proof of a benefit and
return on investment.
CHERYL: Great point.
I love that you highlighted the importance
of knowing who does what, so you know whom
to ask when things come up.
As sort of a not what you know, but who you
know approach to things.
CASSIE: For sure.
CHERYL: We've also got a fabulous question
from Edmund here.
What's the strangest thing you have discovered
on a network during an asset inventory?
CASSIE: Totally Windows XP.
Default admin privileges.
Just really just scary, scary things like
that.
And seeing people that use privileged user
accounts all day for like their daily tasks
I think has been like one of my nightmares
of my life.
So, please don't do that!
CHERYL: Oh, real stories.
I'll see if there's anything else.
No, I think that we are good for questions
here in the chat.
And again, you're gonna make your slides available.
We've got the links to the NIST framework
which is a very helpful tool, and you want
to have that to work alongside, and this was
a terrific presentation.
CASSIE: Thank you very much.
It was a pleasure to meet you.
Thank you for having me.
CHERYL: Thank you for being part of Diana
Initiative 2021.
Thank you everyone for attending.
CASSIE: Bye!
CHERYL: Bye!