Burnout: Destabilizing Retention Goals
and Threatening Organizational Security
Chloe Messdaghi
MICHAEL: We've got a whole
bunch of development talks. In fact, the upcoming
talk by Chloe Messdaghi and a topic that many of
us can probably relate to. Burnout: Destabilizing
Retention Goals and Threatening Organizational
Security. Before we start, I would like to
take a moment it thank all of our sponsors.
We have iNE and eLearn Security, Axonius,
MongoDB, Juniper Networks, Corelight,
Google, We Hack Purple, BridgeCrew. Thank you
to all of them for making this event possible.
Also, don't forget to check out all the
other things we have going on. We have
awesome villages like the IoT village and the
mental health village. We have the expo booth
that has not only our wonderful sponsors, but
also there's people who are looking to do hiring,
community organizations that you can join.
They're not for profits that we support that many
of you may not know about and be interested in.
Different booths have swag, contests and raffles.
Check out all of these wonderful things.
And now we have our speaker. Someone I'm
honored to have the opportunity to introduce.
Chloe Messdaghi is an award winning changemaker,
innovating tech and innovation security sectors
to meet today and future demands by accelerating
startups and empowering organizations and people
to stand out from the crowd. She is
an international keynote speaker at
major tech conferences and events and
serves as a trusted source to reporters
and editors such as Forbes and Business Insider.
Additionally, she's one of business insider's
50 power plays. And outside of work, co founder
of Hacking is NOT a Crime. And We Open Tech. So,
without further ado, here is Chloe Messdaghi.
CHLOE: Hi, en. And thank you so much, Michael,
for the wonderful intro. I'm very touched.
Thank you so much for that. I'm gonna play these
slides now. For everyone, welcome to this burnout
session. And I want to just put one thing in here.
Now, slides I'm gonna talk a lot about how we
need to be better and how we as an industry can
be better. But there's one part that I left out in
it, and I wanted to speak on that really quickly.
A lot of times when we think of burn out, it is
when it comes to our companies. The workload and
not balancing our personal life. But I also
want to mention a particular thing, which is
our industry. And particularly on social media.
Burnout doesn't just occur in our work, in our
daily life. It also happens when we're on Twitter.
We are non stop seeing a lot of really concerning
things happening on Twitter within InfoSec. And
it's really important that we keep an eye out.
There's so much cyber bullying that is
happening. And that also leads to burn out.
But also, it can lead to people leaving our
industry. So, we need to do better on that front.
I wanted to bring that up really fast. Because I
know it's not in the slides. Talking about social
media. But I have seen people get burned out from
it because they're seeing the drama unfolding
and just can't believe what they're seeing.
So, let's try to be better with each other.
Because that's how we are as a community.
And I think this is the time where we need
to come together a lot more than ever before.
So, let's dive into the slide deck now. So,
welcome to Burnout: Destabilizing Retention
Goals and Threatening Organizational Security.
And overall, just think of it this
way, burnout can be a security threat.
So, let's dive into that, shall we.
But first, for those that do not know me,
Michael did a fabulous job sharing a little
bit about myself. But I'm the co founder of We
Open Tech, and hacking is not a crime. And we have
been working to get organizations to sign a pledge
guaranteeing that they're going to do whatever
they can to increase the voices of marginalized
representation in leadership positions.
Because leadership is the one in charge
of vision. And in order for us to actually have
diversity, equity and inclusion, we must have
representation at the top. Because there is
a trickledown effect and that's what we do.
I really recommend for everyone to
check that out. Because we need this.
We need this a long time ago. And time's up.
The other organizations you may have heard of,
which is We Open Tech which is an organization
for marginalized genders to all come together
in tech and security. And for allies too.
Because allies, we're not going to get anywhere.
It's really to bring a welcoming environment for
all of us, whatever our gender is, that we can get
whatever role we want in life and have the career
that we should have. Regardless of who we are.
Hacking is not a crime is another organization
that I cofounded with my friend Brian. And we're
basically trying to change things by challenging
public perception of the hacker community.
So, then we can get a change when it comes to
out of date legislation. Because hackers deserve
protections, and they deserve rights. And it's
about time that we've had it. Because it's been
since the '80s since we've had legislation. And
it's even before Y2K. It doesn't even add up to
even today's standards. We need to revisit that.
Other than that, just giving you the spiel of
all the things I do. I'm a consultant at this
time. I basically do product marketing. Mostly
looking at organizations to help grow and be more
strategic with their growth internally as well.
I do provide an advice column for Security
Boulevard called Ask Chloe. Every Friday
it's a new one. Feel free to ask a question
so I can answer it. It's also anonymous. Host
of the Changemaking podcast on ITSP Magazine.
If you want to roll up your sleeves with the
changemakers that are doing the work, this is
a perfect place for you to learn about them.
And if anything else that I'm missing out,
go ahead and visit standoutintech.com. You're
not here to learn about me, you're here to learn
about the industry and what's going on right now.
This room may look really familiar to you.
This is RSA conference actually about a year ago.
We're all in this room. We had absolutely
no idea what was heading our way.
Some of us had doomsday idea. But we didn't think
it was ever gonna be what we have seen in the past
year or so. But we were all in this, you know,
going to events. We were like shaking hands,
we were giving each other hugs. We were like
yelling in each other's ears because it's
noisy and crowded around us. And
we have no what's going to happen.
That's what happened later on. And at that point
by the end of 2020, we're just wanting it to end.
And even in 2021 at this time, there's this
glimmer of hope. And we can actually get there if
we work together collaboratively. Because we have
to. We have to come together. When we're so broken
up, we have to come together. But let's also be
real. To be able to come together, we have to
recognize that right now we're walking a very
fine line of just being barely okay and terrible.
And all of us have been dealing with
burnout at some point this year.
Okay. Well, maybe not all of us.
I'm looking at you, New Zealand.
But even New Zealand, even before 2020, we've
had ongoing issues. And it's been because of
our industry. The way that it's set up is not for
us to succeed. And that's one of the reasons that
we have to look at this. That this has been an
ongoing problem before all the chaos in 2020. So,
it's best that we actually do something
about it instead of just talking about it.
And with burnout, we need to understand that
we're placing ourselves and our organizations at
secure risk. And we'll most likely click on a
link because we're not 100% who we are. And we
may not patch right or be overwhelmed
by what is needed to be patched ASAP.
But let's also be real, sometimes we're seen
as bots and not as humans. And humans cannot
handle 24/7 work. It's just be realistic with
each other. Because we're working all hours and
we're expected to be on all calls. So, how do we
even balance a personal life and a work life?
Because burnout occurs when we do not practice
self care. And when our work demands more from
us and we spend less time on our personal life,
the balancing is completely gone and stress
increases. We feel really guilty,
and we struggle to sleep because
we feel like we're trying so hard not to drown.
And you may even notice changes on your team such
as your employs are withdrawn, and become angry or
sad. Or delays in the email responses or projects.
This can be seen in remote too. You don't have
to be present to not see it. And right now,
working from home and remotely has increased the
number of work hours. It's also increased this
expectation and really increases the blurriness
of work time and limits. And some people have
quit at this point because they cannot handle
the juggling of work and personal life because
their company failed them. I want you to
understand that. The company failed them.
Because they couldn't be more flexible. And they
don't practice inclusion and equity as well.
And that's one of the things I'll
just quickly touch on is that
we are all able to get burned out. But the ones
that tend to get burned out the fastest are the
ones that are always seen as the type A. The ones
that always get their work done on time. And it's
very hard for them to recognize sometimes when
they're already feeling burned out. But also,
when it comes to those marginalized persons inside
our community, they are striving to be on top of
everything and will take additional work and
jobs because it's already hard as it is to
have that job. Because job security isn't there.
So, that also is a contributing factor to always
having this off balance lifestyle of life and
work. Because we're not doing any actual proper
diversity, equity and inclusion at this time. And
let's be blunt. We haven't had a 9 to 5 job for
ages. It doesn't exist anymore. And this is a
contributing factor of why employers are pushing
employees to work from 9 to 5. And yet they
still send emails at all hours. They Slack you
at all hours. And this places you and
your team at a losing situation because
they feel obligated to respond. And this
is why the burnout cycle continues.
And for those who are not aware of what burnout
starts to form and look like, it can be that it
used to take a few minutes to respond to an email.
But now it takes an hour or so. You feel exhausted
and trapped. And you may even feel empty. You push
yourself to your breaking point. And where you're
no longer coming up with ideas. But rather, you're
taking meds to help with the aches. You're overly
anxious. And that could be over events. Like over
deadlines, anything. And you can easily cry or
get angry fast than usual. You may not respond to
your friends or family when they call or text for
some time. And then that's when that guilt starts
entering a little bit because your personal life
is slipping, and your life is now your work. And
you start to feel unappreciated for your work.
And that gets even worse because you
then start getting resentful at your job
and you end up hating it. You start dreading
your job. And this is the moment where you
may lose your team members. And sometimes it
can get so bad that we have people that leave
our industry because it's left such a bad taste.
And this is the thing that we have to understand
and recognize. Because what we have been doing
is putting employees at a huge health risk.
And if you don't believe me, here we go in
here. So, something to keep in mind is no
matter how much sleep, you just feel exhaust
when had you're burned out. You feel also
emotionally depleted. It can mimic depression. And
have trouble falling asleep or staying to sleep.
When we're stressed out and cortisol levels
increases, it is hard to shut down our minds.
This causes us to toss and turn, and reduce
deep sleep or even get enough REM. And when
we don't get proper sleep, the stress levels
increase. And mental state can start shifting to
depression and anxiety systems. When we're
overly anxious or experience depression symptoms,
we start to get sick a lot more often. And we
start having gastrointestinal issues, headaches,
infections, cold source, rashes, lower immune
system. When our immune system is low and
the stress is high, the bones and muscles are
getting stiff. Your body is on survival mode,
thinking it's a perceived threat. It can
even turn into muscle weakness and fatigue.
If left untreated, this
increased high blood pressure,
heart attacks and strokes because there's too much
adrenaline and cortisol over an extended period.
So, overall, clearly burnout is not a joke.
It's actually very serious. And if we don't take
care of this right now, we are keep putting our
colleagues in a huge risk. And ourselves as well.
So, let's start looking at
the results of our industry.
Of what happens when the reality of working
in security. Because the high demand 24/7. So,
these facts are taken from Dark
Reading and I'm gonna read them to you.
Please remember these stats in this research
was collected priority the pandemic. This
article did come out in 2020. However, it does
not reflect what we've gone through too this date
point. So, please note that these statistics are
probably much higher than what is being reported
on the screen or what I'm reading out loud to
you. 21% of CISOs said they taken a leave of
absence due to job stress. 41% took the step even
though many report being afraid to take sick days.
35% neglected to take all their time off. 48% of
CISOs said their work stress impacted their mental
health. 45% said this impacted their physical
health. And 40% of CISOs said that their work
stress impacted their relationships with their
families or their children. And 32% said that
it impacted their relationships with spouses or
romantic partners. 32% said it's impacted their
relationship with their friends. 23 said they're
using medication or alcohol to manage stress.
Once again, I want to reiterate. These
stats are probably a lot higher than
what I'm reading right now. And it should also
be stated that the other reason is that simply
we're also scared to be transparent with
other people about the situation that we're
in. Especially when it comes to mental health.
We don't really talk about it with each other.
And this is a problem. Because if we don't talk
about it, then how does it ever get addressed?
So, here are some more stats around CISOs. 94%
of the American CISOs and 95% of the UK CISOs
reported that they worked beyond their contracted
hours. On average 10 hours a week or more. In
addition, 83% of American C Suite execs and 73% of
UK execs confirmed they do indeed expect security
teams to work longer hours. In other words, we
are expected to work beyond normal work hours.
In other words, everything that we're doing,
we're always gonna be expected to be on call.
That means there's never a moment to relax.
Because you never know when you'll be on call
and it's expected of you. This is not normal
for most roles. But it is for our industry.
Now, the thing to understand is that the
CISO is your manager and your leader. And
having somebody who is burned out that leads can
become very dangerous to employers. This can lead
to security risk and increasing possibilities
of managerial issues. Coping with such issues
can lead to them self medicating on the job
and making a very    of what is appropriate.
But once again, this is not the CISO's fault. I
want to reiterate. The CISO's job is hard because
whenever there's a breach, they're the
first to be blamed and the first to be cut.
It is extremely stressful to have this role.
And most CISOs only spend one year in the role
in the first place. Those know once again,
we have a system that is very, very broken.
We have an industry that isn't sufficient
in the long run. And it's never matured.
And it's in this industry that it continues to
fail us. And it runs on people being burnt out.
And I want to take a moment here. We have
a foundation that doesn't empower us.
At all. We have a foundation that
disempowers us in every single way.
And there's no wonder we have a rotating door
and a mental health crisis in our industry.
And I'm about to show you why it's like this.
So, why are we so burned out? Well, of course,
being in security, we monitor and operate 24/7.
And sometimes we work throughout the middle of the
night. And sometimes we cannot sleep well because
we're always at the edge of our seat. And when
it comes to security. Because we know attackers
work at all hours. And we're always worried of
when that breach will occur. Because we all know
that if there was a breach, it would be an
ad hoc style to fix it. Don't believe me?
According to the Institute, while response
planning is better over the years,
the vast majority of interviews were
74%. And they're reporting their plans
are Ad Hoc or applied inconsistently or they have
absolutely zero plans at all. And additionally,
more than half, 52% of the security response plans
said they never reviewed it since it was created.
Or it had no set time period of
reviewing or testing those actual plans.
So, with COVID 19 and working from home,
how many of these plans have been updated?
Yeah. This is one of the reasons why we
had a 300% increase of breaches last year.
And you know what we tend to
do about it in our industry?
We don't    we don't think of better
planning and having less disruption.
We throw tools at it. Because it's so much easier
to understand the human element role that plays
here. It's    it's so    it draws    it just    I
don't know. As someone who came from outside the
security world and came in, it is always the thing
that we do. Which is like, oh, we have a problem.
Let's just do    let's just throw another tool
in. The thing is, is that if you don't have a
proper foundation of understanding the human
element plays a huge role in security, because
security is built by humans in the first place,
how are we gonna be successful? Throwing tools
at it is not going to be helpful. If anything,
it's going to make the situation a lot worse.
Because when we add tools to it, guess what
happens? It's not in the plan and coordination is
off and these third party tools. We don't know how
secure they really are. Are you feeling stressed
out yet? Perhaps cortisol levels rising? No. Well,
then I want you to imagine another situation.
You know, cruise ship. You know this is
going to get one of those type of stories.
But I want you to imagine. You're a part of a
crew. And you just found out your ship is sinking.
But you found out after for some time because you
weren't alerted by your system. And your customers
are on board trusting you for their safety.
And your team is scared. And some are actually
paralyzed by the fear of failing. But they're
trying their best. But there's one thing you need
to know. Your crew hasn't slept at all for quite
some time, and they have a bit of seasickness.
I mean, you could actually say that they're
not exactly 100% state of mind. They're not
100% charged battery. If anything, you could
say they're kind of functioning as if they have
burnout. Because it's kind of the same rate and
scope. Okay. So, now you have the back story.
That's your situation that you're in. Now, imagine
your captain pulls out the binder. This safety
binder that you're like, oh, thank god, there's a
protocol here. An incident response plan. And it's
up to date, right? No. Unfortunately, that binder
that was updated is not on the ship. And you're
actually having    you are actually using a old
procedure, but have new features to this ship.
Are you stressed out now? Because this is what
it's like when we're dealing with bad plans.
And when the human element is not taken into
account of. It leaves you with a wreckage.
The truth is bad actors are everywhere.
And they attack at all hours. And they drop
often, and we constantly need to be up to date of
what bad actors use. That takes energy and time.
And this is why we're struggling. We're a part of
the crew and we don't function well or communicate
well, and it becomes a really scary situation.
The reason we're insecure is because
we know how incredibly important it is.
But we also need to come to terms that if we work
around the clock and don't practice self care,
or even promote employee wellness, what's the
point of all of this? Because then we could be
a danger to the organization. As well if we're
running on low battery and feeling not well.
And this is why burnout matters. It's not
just a trendy thing. It's a very real thing.
And this is why we keep turning to tools
to try to fix our problem. And not find
time to plan, prep, practice self care.
We become that security team that sinks.
We won't be able to fix a
breach fast. And it's scary.
And I really want to just reiterate here that,
please, whatever you do, do not turn around and
blame your employees for this. And because they're
not performing as well. Because the majority of
you, that is what you tend to do. You let go of
a team member without checking to see what you
could have done that    that probably could have
reduced their performance. Because chances are,
they're probably burned out and feeling very much
alone. With COVID 19, we're taking care of family
members opinion on camera daily. Unable to leave
our homes. Can't see our friends and family. Some
of us live alone. Some of us put off important
life events. We've also lost people. We've also
are seeing our colleagues struggling. We're
trying to be there. We're always worried about
our ability to perform and keeping a job. We're
worried about affording the life that we have,
and we're worried about COVID. We're worried
we may not make it through either. We're
not a machine. We are human. The human element
created security and runs security. We were all
struggling with staying okay before COVID and
during COVID. And I want you to acknowledge that.
Except New Zealand. Okay. I'm just going to be
real with you. New Zealand had it pretty well.
And there's a reason why. And
I want to talk about that.
So, how can we lead like the Prime Minister of
New Zealand? Think about it, she worked with
people and planned. And when you plan, there's
less disruption. So, we're going to go through
a couple of investment things. So, here's the
first investment. Listen. Take action together.
In other words, be strong, be kind. Ask your team
what they need. It's so simple, right? Whenever
people are like, how can I do better? Ask your
team. Don't ask me. Ask your team. They're gonna
tell you how to be better. Because they live in
that environment. They know that environment.
They are in there every single day doing the job
they're supposed to be doing. They're hearing from
their colleagues. They know how to do better.
You just have to ask and listen. And not just
listen also, I just to want to reiterate this.
Take an action. When we listen to each other and
strategize together on how to improve the team and
our department, it reduces stress for everyone.
Because stress happens and we're not being
listened to. Or we feel uncomfortable to speak up.
Your colleagues may share that certain tools
aren't needed. Or that there's a tool that
does like five things all in one that is better.
And they may share what is missing on the team.
Perhaps less meetings are needed as well.
By working together on what are the issues,
we could collaborate together on how to
reduce the issues or completely resolve them.
Investment number 2. Plan together. Strategize
together. With collaboration and listening,
working together with the team to make strategies
revisit your security response plans. Make it up
to date. Revisit that plan every time a new tool
is added or removed or there's a team member
change or environment change and so on. It is so
critical that by creating and making solid plans,
it helps speed up your recovery. Reduces
the stress of when a breach occurs.
That there's a plan to follow that's up to date.
You owe it to yourselves and your colleagues,
your organization, your customers. I mean, look at
what New Zealand did. They planned. Not only that,
they strategized together. They had 25 deaths.
You know how about we have had in the US?
Over 560,000 deaths in the US. Because there were
people that didn't to want to listen to the people
around them that knew how to do better. And
they didn't want to take action on how they
could do better. I know that's controversial
what I just said. But it is the truth.
Because we have to work together. We have
to listen to each other. We have to do that.
Otherwise, we're gonna fail all together.
So, keep your ego in check on that one.
Investment number 3, encourage self care. When
dealing with burnout, taking one week off from
work or anything related to work provides recovery
for burn out. And I want to say for like a mild to
moderate burnout. If you have severe burnout,
that could take two weeks or more. But that one
week does help you recover slowly. So, if your
employee is burnt out, allow them to take time
off. And a lot of times we don't want to take time
off because we worry about our team members when
we're going. Or we're more nervous of the thought
we're going to walk into when we come back. When
you take time off, it helps a lot because we have
a lot more clear space in our head so we're able
to take it on a little bit better. So, it's really
important that we always encourage self care
and taking time off and being flexible. That
also means looking at work hours as well.
And lastly, you should probably make sure to
have one day per week where you have absolutely
zero meetings. And this allows your colleagues
to catch up on any items or projects. For
investment number 4, be kind and respect
boundaries. Please be kind to one another.
It is so frustrating to see throughout a pandemic
where people are being cruel to one another.
It's not    when the whole world seems like it's
in chaos, that is the time where we need to come
together. We put our egos to the side or behind
us. And we start thinking about how our actions
impact others. It's important that we understand
that what we say and what we do can impact another
individual. So, think it over before you take
an action. It's so important that we do this.
Because we need to be kind to one another. Like
seriously. It shouldn't be like this sometimes.
Because from what we have learned, is that when we
work together and understand how we impact others,
we are then starting to practice empathy.
And empathy is certainly missing at our times.
In our industry. But by listening and being there
for one another, it remind us that there's people
who care for each other. Because we cannot assume
how one person is doing just by how they look.
Or how they're doing on their performance.
You could be a high achiever and be in a really,
really hard place. So, it's really important that
we don't know what each other is going through.
But we can always be there for one another. And
try to understand. So, instead of going at
someone, refrain from that. And think before
you speak or act. Because you really don't
know how that will impact another person.
So, as New Zealand shares their be kind message,
it's because there's an element that we need
to stick together to protect the world together.
But also, know that being kind is respecting work
boundaries such as 6 feet distance and a mask.
So, what can you do right now? Okay. So,
this is what I would love for you guys to do. Take
a screen shot of this, or take a photo of this.
Share it with the people around you. Share it with
your employer. Share it with your boss. Share it
with your colleagues. Because this only takes 15
minutes to do all these things right now that you
see on here. Set up a weekly one on one for 15
minutes with each employee. If you're a manager,
you should be doing that. And then
after that one on one with them,
don't have any more meetings with them. Just
do it once a week for up to 15 minutes. This
is how you build a relationship. This is how you
build trust. Because when you're micromanaging,
which was a really big issue throughout the
pandemic for many folks. Because there's this
belief that if I don't see you in the office, then
I don't think you're working. So, micromanaging
has been very high up there in a lot of complaints
these days. So, do this instead. Set up a weekly
one on one for 15 minutes with your employee.
And on that, talk about the products that are,
you know, on the roadmap. And also, what are
the items to prioritize? Make it a conversation.
Be there for your employee. This is
a great way how to start a trust.
Now, the next thing you could do is make a
Monday or a Friday a no meetings day. The
reason I say Monday or Friday, because it
doesn't really impact the week that much.
Because usually a Monday or a Friday falls
on a holiday. So, it doesn't hurt as much.
So, making one of those days as a no meetings
day is great. Because that could be that day
that everyone uses to conquer any projects that
they're behind or their emails. I don't know
about you, but I like interesting a zero inbox
person. That would help a lot for the folks.
The next is set up a meeting with the
team to explore ways to improve together.
This is important. If you don't have an incident
response plan or it's out of date or you don't
know if you have one, now is the time to talk
about that. Meet, discuss. What tools do we have
right now? What tools do we need? What tools
do we not need? What things do we need on our
team? How can I be a better manager? How can I
be a better leader for our department talking to
other departments? What can I do to make things
better? Because as a manager, it's your job
to be a coach, a mentor. It's not your job to
dictate how things should be. It's about working
together collaboratively and making sure that
your team can thrive by pushing them up there.
And also, the last thing that you can always do
is create an unanimous survey. And I mean that,
anonymous. And there might be not everyone
who wants to respond because they're worried
if it actually is anonymous and they're worried
something is going happen. You want to try it,
but you can't enforce it. You need to build trust.
And trust is shown over time through actions.
Now, lastly, remember, when we work together and
listen to each other, magic does happen. And when
we work together making sure people get personal
time off without the fear of taking time off,
we're then becoming collaborative.
And when we collaborate, we reduce
the stressful items that hold back the
team from thriving. When we focus on
balancing work and personal life for
everyone, that's when we no longer
have this dumpster fire. And burnout
is no longer a security concern for us.
Because we know we are human, and we know that the
human element rules the world that we live in.
And whenever in doubt, just remember. If
New Zealand can plan so well, so can you.
Because in all of us, there's a Frodo who is on
a journey to get rid of some malicious threat.
So, quick overview over this whole
talk. If you spaced out at all.
Turnout does place you and your team at a huge
risk. Not just mentally, but physically as well.
The best way how to actually deal with burnout and
reduce it is to collaborate to form strategies to
improve the team by asking your team how to do
better and listening and taking action. Start
making plans and revisit secure response plans.
Seriously. We need to do better at that. And I
know we don't really have enough time sometimes to
go into a response plan and try to make it better.
But we have to do this. We owe it to ourselves
and everyone around us who are impacted by it. It
will help us. Because if there is a breach and we
have an incident response plan that is up to date,
we're gonna be feeling a little bit better.
Because we will know that we have everything
covered as much as we did have it covered.
And most importantly, promote self care by
being kind and respectful to boundaries. Please
respect one another, you guys. Please be nice to
each other. It is so important that we do that.
Because we're in this community together. We're
a small community. And it    whenever something
happens to someone, it does impact other people.
So, we have to be aware of this. That our
actions and words do hold value. And can
also impact another individual positively and
negatively. So, we must do better as ourselves.
I just want to say thank you all so much for
attending this talk. And if you want to ask any
questions, I'm here. I do have over time. So, I'm
going to stop sharing now my screen and answer any
questions that you guys may have.
MICHAEL:
So, haven't seen many questions. That was    that
was actually a wonderful talk. There was a few
things you mentioned in there that I noticed
a lot of people, you know, personally related
to. Especially the zero inbox. Yeah. That
that's like a myth as far as I know. So
CHLOE: Yeah. There are strategies
to get there. But I have to admit,
how I do    this actually might be a good skill
for some other folks that have issue. So, what I
do is I open my emails. Every time I get an email,
I open it. If it's something that's going to take
longer than a couple minutes to respond, I have
to review or look up or something, I star it. So,
then I have a zero inbox at all times. But I
go back to the star items when I have more time
throughout the day. This helps me don't get
overwhelmed. Because I'm a type A person. I have
to answer emails. So, it's one thing. One way how
to go about that, you still have that zero inbox
thing. But just note that it's not the unread.
It's also knowing what to prioritize. That's
gonna help you out with that zero inbox idea.
MICHAEL: Another thing that you    actually,
I'm going to take that into consideration. I have
a tendency to star too many things. But another
thing you mentioned that I really liked was you
were    you were saying that about how companies,
you know, how they use tools and things. And I
mentioned it in chat that they tend to when they
have these breaches, you know, they want to add
a red team. And these are things that are very
costly when, you know, the real truth is, if they
had took, you know, took the time to, you know,
pay attention to their employees and offered,
you know, some sort of service, which would be
a lot cheaper, they could probably avoid that and
to some degree    and it would be a lost more
cost effective to them and a lot more healthy
to them and the people that worked for them.
CHLOE: Yeah. It's like this constant situation of,
I always think of like firefighting in some ways.
Where we're so into putting out the fire that
we don't do preventive work. Because we're like,
well, I don't see any return of investment. So, I
don't need to add money to this. But however, oh,
my god, when there's a breach. Suddenly, oh,
here's all the money in the world. And you're
like, where was this money before? We could have
avoided this situation. I mean, as someone who
worked in like marketing and PR, I feel like it's
better to do preventive work over reactive work.
Because a breach is gonna happen. No matter what,
a breach is gonna happen. You don't know when.
But being prepared helps a lot.
MICHAEL: Definitely, definitely. I agree.
We do have a question. Somebody wanted to know,
they said, how do you support employees in staying
offline when they're on PTO? I made it clear I
don't expect people to be online. But some still
carry their laptops around on their days off.
CHLOE: Yeah. It's one of those things where
it's a tricky thing. You can't really tell them,
stop responding to messages. But I have to admit,
I remember last year I took my first vacation
in two and a half years for one week. And the
first day I was responding to emails. And then my
manager is like, stop responding. You're on your
time off. I'm going start telling people to stop
writing to you. It just hit me in that moment. Oh,
wow. I felt like I was a workaholic in that
moment. So, the trick is, when you're talking to
your employees about taking time off, remind them
that is a good time to disconnect. Meaning like,
you know, this might be a good time for you
to turn off your devices, get off of social
media for a bit. Or just get away from InfoSec
in general and don't try to study for a cert
test. Do something for yourself. I want to learn
to play guitar, paint. That's a good question.
We have to be encouraging them to understand
that it's okay. We have to be reinforcing them,
it's okay for you not to respond. You're on your
time off. But do remind them that they should
put in their calendar that they're going to be
away. And also have that out of office message.
And the trick for that for everyone who
is concerned about that, I'm going to
tell you something that's easy to do. First
thing when you're about to take your break,
make sure you have your out of message scheduled.
Your message. Now, you want to make sure in there
that you state one or two days after the date that
you come back. So, say if you are coming back on
the 14th, you're gonna say, I'm coming back on
the 16th. This helps you so much because no one's
expecting you to respond until after the 16th
then. Also on your calendar, take the whole day,
the first day you come back, block it. Completely
block it. Meaning no one can set up any meetings
with you. You just have that day for you to
respond to emails and catch up on what jobs you
need to do. And when you come back on your first
day, also make sure that you look at your emails,
kind of get a sense of what's going on. But then
what you're gonna want to do is message your
teammates and ask if there's any pressing issues
that you need to respond within the next 24 to 72
hours. So, then you can also draw your attention
to that. This helps you be on top of everything.
Gives you about two day period of catching up.
And without having any impact or stress on you.
MICHAEL: Very true. I personally    one of
my main worries when it comes to taking time
off is can I afford it? You know? And questions
like that. Instead of, you know, realizing that,
you know, regardless of whether I can, you know,
quote, unquote, afford it, my mental health is
more important because it will affect me more
long term than, say, a short term problem that
I could, you know, fix in other ways.
CHLOE: Exactly.
MICHAEL: Go ahead.
CHLOE: Exactly. It's like
that completely. If we don't take off, you're
gonna start failing a little bit more in work.
And the last thing you want to do is lose your
job. So, always put your mental health first.
MICHAEL: We have another one. How have you
successfully communicated the value of self care
business cultures to higher ups? In my experience,
culture trickles down from the executive level.
CHLOE: Kate, I love you. I don't know you.
I think. But I have to admit one thing to
you. You are completely right. When it's the
executives, they're the ones that set the vision.
They're the ones that dictate how it's
going to impact the rest of the company.
This is one of the reasons why I strongly
believe we'll never have DII until we have
those in leadership positions filled with people
that are marginalized. You're completely right.
But the good news is you have a manager. And your
manager is supposed to be there to support you.
And it's so important that they support you. If
you have a boss that isn't gonna be there for you,
that isn't wanting to coach you, mentor you, and
see you thrive beyond them, you have a bad boss.
I hate to break it to you. A good manager is
someone who is like, so, what do you want to do
for your career? Excellent. I'm gonna help you get
there if you want me to help you out. You tell me
what you need from me, and I will be there. That's
a manager that you want. You want a manager that
understands be flexible, but also wants to see you
thrive. That is the job of a boss. And they can't
really do too much other than go to the executive
teams and say, hey, we have this problem. I have
been there before. I go to an executive team. We
have this problem, we need to fix this. And it
gets ignored because they're thinking of profit.
They have to understand that
sometimes you don't see the profit
immediately. It takes time to show it.
MICHAEL: Definitely, definitely
agree. And, you know,
when I read that question, I personally
can relate to that because, you know,
a lot of companies, it always    you would go
to a meeting, and you would hear whatever the
higher ups are telling you about safety and
this or that. And, you know, and that goes,
you know, for most things at businesses. But
having a business that actually, you know, can
reverse that process and let it flow in the other
direction and pay attention to what the employees
are saying and the problems that they're having.
You know, that's    that's just as important.
CHLOE: Yeah.
MICHAEL:
Well, that    let's see here. We...
I'm trying to read through these.
Yeah. It seems like a lot of people can relate
to this. And I know    I know personally. Yeah,
it's a big thing. I'm one    one of those people
who I can't say no. So, I end up agreeing to this
and to that and to this and to that. And before
I turn around, all I have are deadlines. And
I look at the calendar for today and    oh,
no. And so, here I am at 2:00 in the morning
still working. And then, oh, I'll take a day off
to catch up. Well, that day off, like you said,
is meant to not work and to relax. And I just
you know, I really do    I really can relate.
And I feel like a lot of people in here can too.
I personally have been following Chloe for quite
some time now. She has a very    a very avid
interest in people. All people. And I really
like how, you know, she goes for it and tries
to not only change the opinions and the views of
people that are, you know, you know, higher up in
government all the way down to the average person
so that we can all relate to each
other and have better mental health.
CHLOE: Thanks, Michael.
MICHAEL: Yeah. One last question we have is how
can you set those boundaries after you have been
doing it and is now    and it is now expected?
CHLOE: That is a great question.
Hi, Miki. I would say that...
that's a really good one. I'm going to
be honest. There's going to be times when
your employer is not going to be happy that
you put down boundaries. But the thing is,
I want you just to know that if you have other
team maybes that have similar boundaries,
this maybe a good thing. Having kind of
like a All Hands in for your team or having
those like weekly one on ones with your manager,
it might be a good time to reiterate like, hey,
I just to want to let you know. When you send
me a Slack message after 5 p.m.? I'm not gonna
respond to it. If it's something urgent, I would
prefer that you text me. That's gonna let me know
that I need to respond to it. Because I'm
gonna be off of Slack during my off hours
so I can do all the things that I want to do.
And I don't want to be attached to my laptop.
That's kind of how the way I've done it in
the past. Which is like I'm gonna be offline.
I'm always offline at this hours. But if it's ever
an urgent thing, text me, call me to let me know.
I think that's one way we can do it. Always give
them one thing to note. Like this is my    this
is my boundary. I'm not gonna respond during
this time. But if there's something urgent
during those non work hours, you can do this
instead. I think that's really helpful for
everyone. Because let's be real, I feel like all
of us want to be off Slack and Discord for an
hour because we just need to turn off our minds.
MICHAEL: Yeah. Definitely. I personally have
learned a lot from this. And I'm gonna try to
apply a lot to them. First thing I'm going to do
is get on my phone and unpin Discord and Slack.
They're pinned. I can't turn them off. I think
are we out of time? Do we have
time for one more question? Or is
I don't know. I think the cutoff is...
okay, yeah. We're out of time.
CHLOE: Okay.
MICHAEL: All right. If any of y'all do
have any further questions for Chloe,
I know she is going to be in the    the
Hopin in the different areas. And Chloe,
maybe tell them where you're going to be?
CHLOE: I'll check on the comments and respond
in the comments. If you want, you can also
DM me on Twitter, Instagram or LinkedIn.
Either of those work. I'm also gonna be in the
booth on and off for hacking is not a crime
and for We Open Tech. If you have questions
about those two orgs, I will be in there too.
MICHAEL: Thank you for showing up, all and
thank you, Chloe, for the awesome conversation.
CHLOE: Thank you.
MICHAEL: We'll see you
later on in the conference.
CHLOE: Take care, everyone! Thank you!