and
we are live
look at that my uh my second i would say
it's my second time at diane edition
today i've been
hanging out over in the uh the old
mental health village
yeah isn't this your second talk of the
day too douglas
i'm saying it again isn't this your
second talk of the day as well
basically i've been talking for about
six hours straight now
look at you go well as i always say
if anybody ever needs me to speak just
ask
it's getting me to stop talking that
nobody's been able to figure that out in
45 years so
all right before i introduce douglas's
talk today i want to give a shout out to
the sponsors
as well as our awesome audience here
don't forget to check out the career
village
i heard they got some awesome resume
reviewing and mock interviews going
um our awesome speaker today is douglas
brush
who is a global advisory uh cso at
splunk and his talk is titled
you don't have to be crazy to work here
an honest talk about mental health
um the stage is yours
thank you thank you everybody for
joining um and i hope a couple of you
have had a chance to check out
the village today so mental health
hackers
quick plug to them huge huge thank you
for
mante amanda berlin also knows info
sister
and to ray redacted for everything that
they do
i'm humbled and honored to be able to
even just help them and even wear this
t-shirt even though i
paid for it and i recommend that you all
get out and
donate and get your t-shirt too huge
shout out to them and everything they're
doing and obviously a big
big gracious thank you to the diana
initiative
um i i can't even put into words how
proud i am of what they do
and how quite frankly humbled i am by
what they're able to do
i organize a lot of conferences and
being part of seeing them put this
together
the past two weeks has just been amazing
i mean they're absolutely
ninjas when it comes to this a huge
thanks to uh nicole and jamie not really
everybody else behind the scenes
for those of you just attending i i
can't even express to you how hard it is
to get this done
um and it's it's it's a feat of
amazement so
thank you everybody for joining in thank
you for dying initiative
um because i really want to start
talking about things that i
have just recently been talking more
about in our community
and that's mental health and self-care
cyber security professionals spend
most of their day focused on the health
and well-being of their environments in
their care
however this comes at the cost of
reducing risk of our
individuals i mean i'm sorry comes at
the cost and
not reducing the risk of our individuals
and our professionals mental health
a lot of people put a lot of things on
the line and it's taxing and it really
pushes people to the edge so many
information security professionals burn
out
suffer from anxiety and depression and
turn on
helping unhealthy coping mechanisms
um like drugs and alcohol and danny
and i were talking about that in the
mental health village today it's a very
easy thing to fall into and
um you know get out of at times
um so this only further exacerbates when
you do have
poor healthy or maybe find the wrong
maybe poor's out the wrong but
use the wrong coping mechanisms to
manage psychological and physical
well-being
so my goal really with a lot of these
talks now is to
alleviate the stigma around mental
health and really stress
the importance about frank and open
dialogues about this serious
issue impacting our community i really
want to share my journey
reverse engineer some of the stigma and
meant
around mental health and business and
look at ways that we can try to kind of
hack back at mental health and be more
productive and think about things in
more meaningful ways so
as we go into this i know it's been a
long day for a lot of folks
um i just ask that you all just kind of
focus on me
which i know is you know a little bit
narcissistic but
just try to listen to what i'm saying at
least put down the phones mute the
alerts
and really kind of let's focus and work
on this together so let's get started
and first i want to say i'm gonna there
there will be some trigger warnings in
here and
there will be some uncomfortable
subjects that i'm gonna talk about that
can act as triggers and triggers are
those
things that to put it mildly kind of
haunt us and when discussed can make you
feel like you're experiencing a past
trauma
sometimes you might not even know why
this is happening and i've had this
happen recently
uh on one of the tim ferriss podcast he
was talking about early childhood
early childhood trauma and it it just
impacted me in a way i couldn't describe
i became
shaking i i got really upset and
i it was just something about the
subject matter he was talking about uh
about abuse and other things that really
impacted me and i had this awful
reaction i had to turn it off
and just kind of step away go talk to my
wife about it because what the hell just
happened
um and these things will happen and it's
natural so if you do feel that way
if there's something i'm saying that you
find upsetting and you can't get through
by all means just step away there's no
harm there's no foul on that
do not feel like you need to tough
through this
if you start feeling bad so please turn
off walk away
result resettlement do not try to talk
it out or tough it out i should say
talk it out yes tough it out now and
finally i'm not a doctor
nor do i play one on tv i'm a global
advisory ciso with a pink mohawk
talking to you uh on zoom or hopping so
let's let level set on that and this
presentation's information is not
intended or applied to substitute
professional medical advice diagnosis or
treatment
so all the content all the text images
graphics and information
for general information purposes only i
my employer the diane initiative make
no representation assume no
responsibility for the accuracy of this
information
contained or available through this
presentation this is not
medical advice so please speak to your
physician before embarking on any
treatment plan
and never ever disregard professional
medical
advice or delay seeking medical
treatment because of something you've
heard or saw in this presentation
so i've got a little bit of a legal
background so that's my legal disclaimer
but please
take this as information but do seek
help if you feel you need it
and i do want to talk a little bit about
some of the definitions about what we
hear out there
um in mental health you know when we
talk about mental health what is it
health and human services describes
mental health as
our emotional physical physiological and
social well-being
it affects how we think feel and act
it also helps determine how we handle
stress relate to others and make choices
and many factors contribute to mental
health problems including biological
factors
such as genetics and brain chemistry
life experiences such as
trauma or abuse and family history
self-care is any activity that we do
deliberately
something you really make an effort in
order to control or take care of our
mental
emotional and physical health these are
not passive actions per se but things
that we do with
intent that are self-initiated and
self-controlled
in a topic that i want to talk about and
again i'm on the
neurodiversity employee resource group
at splunk
and co-chair of the community group
uh community engagement group and we
look at ways that we can define what
neurodiversity is this is a rather new
term
we've all heard and so i've kind of put
together a definition from a variety of
sources that neurodiversity is the idea
that neurological differences like
autism adhd
mood and other functions which have
historically viewed with a negative
perception
are in fact just the result of normal
natural variations in the human genome
and so this represents a new and
fundamentally different way of looking
at conditions that were traditionally
pathologized
so it's a viewpoint that's not universal
universally accepted at this point
but it's being increasingly supported by
science
so neurodiversity advocates such as
myself and others point out that
neurodiverse people often have
exceptional abilities alongside what
society has
labeled disabilities but due to the time
constraints and there's you know really
only so much time i can talk about all
these subjects
we're going to put that aside but
understand that that is a underlying
theme
about how mood disorder works that it's
not something that's broken it's just
part of who we are so not going to
firehose you without too much of that
information about our diversity
but understand that there's a huge
overlap and
i would encourage people to do some
research on how to promote
neurodiversity in your workplace and by
all means reach out to me
um i started a i guess an international
coalition
of neurodiversity uh employee resource
leads so we work with other companies or
i do to help them build their programs
do not hesitate to reach out to me for
help and guidance
and for me you know my my goals going
forward i've been doing this a long time
this is even dated to say 26 plus years
it's probably closer to 30
years in it cyber security information
um governance data privacy still
obviously do a lot of work in that
and right now i really have this kind of
global role of helping programs
and individuals and almost say it's like
uh i'm like a cso therapist where i go
in and
talk to them about their program and be
a shoulder to cry on and a way to
let them verbalize what they're going
through and then we can find
constructive ways to build out their
programs
um but it takes it takes a lot of effort
in doing that
but really it's to me it's like i've
been talking about technology and cyber
security bulldogs for 30 years and
a lot of the problems are still the same
so i thought i'd tackle the easy issues
like
diversity and inclusion and equity and
mental health because
i think those are becoming easier issues
in cyber security at times so that's
really become my focus
on my talk tracks recently outside of
work i love snowboarding cooking
making craft cocktails uh the joke is i
moved out to the boulder area
because zombies can't climb mountains in
my overly analytical almost obsessive
brains that time i
took out a map of the united states
after so many different things that
happened which i'll talk a little bit
about
in new york and said okay well boulder
seems like a safe place to live
there's good schools my job carried over
here
um why wouldn't i move here and worse as
the zombie apocalypse comes
and gets a higher ground zombies can't
climb mountains that's a little bit of a
joke
but in all honesty i've been doing
incident response of some form
for as long as i can remember
when the proverbial hits the fan
i'm usually the first person somebody
calls
they look for me for guidance support i
got this plaque in 1986 when
a friend of mine we were skiing at a
local resort for
um you know an after school thing
and he fell and hurt himself and was in
terrible pain
we're a weird part of the mountain i
went and got first aid i got there back
with them i did all these things that
were
response and crisis management at a very
young age i was only
you know not even that was only nine and
a half at the time
so that's been part of my dna and it's
been really who i look at as i build
this persona at work of this idea of
almost being the wolf
from you know winston wolf from pulp
fiction
people call me when they have a problem
and i show up
i don't need a lot of context i'm here
to help you get rid of that dead body
and make sure nobody nobody gets in
trouble
but i really kind of go into these
crisis situations with a cool as a
cucumber persona
but i have really bad anxiety and that's
odd for people to accept at times like i
don't understand that like
you can literally walk into a burning
building um
but you have anxiety how is that even
possible
and it's weird it's a hard thing for me
to to comprehend at times too and it's
taken me a long time to come to terms
with it and i struggle with it because
i i don't understand it why can i
solve some of the world's biggest cyber
security problems you know i've been in
global newspapers i've been quoting all
these things i'm like my school
doesn't bother me at all where people
are like that freaks me out and i'm like
you know about four years ago i
accidentally bumped my backpack into
this girl on the new york city subway
and i'm sure she's still upset about it
and oh my god i'm getting all
worked up about it i mean these
free-floating anxiety issues these weird
things come into my brain
that debilitate me at times and i
obsessively worry about things
and they're small meaningless things
at times but to me they're the biggest
things in the world so
yeah i struggle with anxiety and it's
led to depression and other types of
issues that have hurt me professionally
and personally
so it's the monster in the closet i have
to deal with it's the yang to my yang
so while my super power is to be
even steven just cool as a cucumber
underlying that there's a lot on on
manchester on any day-to-day basis
which i'll talk about and i look at it
wider you know
really in our security community i mean
that's
a lot of people i talk to are dealing
with this idea that
hey i can't deal with my own stress i i
have to maintain this
damn near perfection in what i do in my
day-to-day life
and andrea lombargo said it
a interview a few years ago says like
there's never down time it's non-stop
and every day is a battle
and it's like in cyber security we need
to be right seemingly like
all the time and attackers get
to get
it right once or maybe a few times and
explode a series of vulnerabilities
so it's no wonder that depression
burnout and even
suicide are becoming more prevalent
among cyber security professionals
depression is still the leading cause of
disability in the world according to the
world
health organization after heart disease
so that's
that's pretty big but we don't talk
about it enough
and people with mental health conditions
have the highest risk
group for suicide there was a nominate
study in 2019 and this was just for csos
but draws a good example for a lot of us
in our careers
is that it was a global study of of of
cyber security professionals again focus
on csos
91 of the cso surveyed said they had
levels of stress that were suffering
that were moderate to high
60 percent rarely disconnected from
their work role
88 of csos work more than 40 hours per
week and 27
that work up to 60 hours 89
of us-based csos never having a two-week
break from their job
so most of them feel that they're
unappreciated by senior leadership
almost all felt like a breach was
inevitable however
when asked in the same organization when
they asked the
ceos only 60 of the ceos felt that a
breach was inevitable
but a third felt they would lose their
job or be written up formally if there
was a breach or a major incident
so there's no surprise that in the
leadership community for csos
there's a high turnover many don't stay
in their jobs for long
and so when i think about like where we
are as again
solving the same problems for 30 years
and where we are programmatically
you know in working with dc says it's no
wonder that we continue to have these
problems and that we haven't solved a
lot of the
issues because it really takes a c so a
good c so
18 months to two years to really start
affecting change in the job
so let's think about this you know we
have this slow ramp up over a year or so
things go well for about three to six
months then they burn out
then a new cso comes in
with the same mismanagement and
misalignment i was misalignment with
leadership and management
go through an 18-month cycle and they
leave and it becomes this vicious cycle
and it really starts with me to think
well then we really need a top-down
approach of managing
stress anxiety depression mood disorders
from the top
down you know we talk about everything
in information security is top down from
technical and tactical why not with the
people need to start with leadership and
thinking about
the way that leaders are able to cope
and maintain within these environments
so you know mental health conditions
come in many forms
but the stress that
folks have right now gets exhaust
will exacerbate a lot of these
underlying conditions and can
accelerate early onset acuity of a lot
of conditions
so stress management it becomes this
huge root cause for episodic symptoms
and these underlying diseases really
kind of rearing directly ahead
and like i said before it's causing
folks to really
not know where to go and what are some
of our
go-to coping mechanisms and we're coming
up on vegas in a couple weeks
and we know the problems it's alcohol
it's drugs it's strip clubs it's the
party scene to blow off steam
in the summer but that's not for
everybody so that further alienates
people
in our community you know jamie
tomasello's speaking of black cat in
talked about the stigma she faced being
a recovering alcoholic
in a culture that pushes us far too hard
and quite frankly as a community we've
done a piss poor job of helping each
other here
and look i'm not going out for having
drinks i'm drinking actually red bull
right now which is
probably worse in many regards we're
having beer
tap on the office but it can't be our
only answer to
coping with this and this is why i
encourage things like
mental health hackers in the villages of
why we're doing something in defcon this
year
as a leader in the the splunk erg for
neurodiversity i'm putting down
our money and we're renting a room i
just signed the contract
at paris i'm not paris i went down sorry
plan hollywood to have a chill-out room
so people can go and decompress without
alcohol without the scene without all
the noise
places where they can reset and let
their neural chemicals
go back to where they should be so we
need to find more answers to coping with
this
because i'll admit i've done a really
bad job up until recently
um you know it's all my staff and
clients know i'm the first one to say
it
let's just go let's go have fun but
there's got to be a better way to do it
because it's almost like saying well
screw it you know
the only way to manage the risk is let's
throw av at it good to go we walk away
and there's no one silver bullet to deal
with attackers
or our health so we know this is not
true in our computer networks but we
seem to avoid a multi-faceted
layer approach to maintain health in our
neural networks
so we need to change this and it's
getting worse right now because with
corona
it's been a hard year you know work
school loss of routines and schedules
that has an incredible amount of stress
on
people people have lost loved ones
people lost jobs
people just gone through a turn a lot of
trauma
and you know up until recently i mean
i've only started traveling again and
for 30 years i've been on the road
um and i miss seeing all of you and this
being in the room with people doing the
doug show
on stage in front of clients and
customers i feel completely off my game
i'm not looking for pity but to say that
you know if you're feeling this way
you're not alone
everybody's lives have been upended and
multiple times a day i'm talking to
friends and family that are really
struggling
coming out of covet i think we're gonna
have a real
strong issue of ptsd of this because
people don't want to have
look back and cope they just want to
jump into the next thing
so you know right now i feel like i
would do anything for
those i love and those close to me but i
feel kind of powerless right now because
they're still limited in what we can do
and i can't just sweep in like winston
wolf and just fix
everything and there was one article i
read recently that still talked about
corona and everything that's going on
and obviously there's a new delta
variant but it's this
this unrelenting horizon list of this
covert world so this
this idea of just it's more than just
depression it's more than just
you know burnout it's this fatigue of
this never-ending
cycle of trauma so we need to start
looking at new ways of how we can
approach this
because if we don't the end game is
could be really worse the
long tail effects of this are
devastating suicide rates have been on
the rise throughout the last year and
even my home state of colorado it's grim
it's this toxic stress that are pushing
people over the edge
and people feel hopeless
and i relate to that i i get it i don't
talk further about how where i felt like
that
so we need to think of things in more
constructive ways to support each other
and really acknowledge
that feeling of hopelessness and
you know one of the things that i think
about when i think about hopelessness
there's there's a
band i really love h2o from new york
near hardcore scene but
it's like helpless not hopeless there's
always hope
you got to keep that pma and you need to
find ways to address these issues
because we have to talk about this
mental health cannot be avoided as a
topic in cyber security any longer
so my pledge to this community is to
raise awareness and remove this stigma
i do not have all the answers and i
won't pretend to
but i will not be shy anymore to talk
about this issue
because we're hackers we can figure out
a better path forward together
you know corona side which is the
obvious elephant in the room
it's only exacerbated the underlying
issues we still need to do root cause
analysis
on the profession itself and i start
thinking how did we get here
and you know information security really
is an industry that's relatively new
it's this
frankenstein monster that's been brought
to life by i.t
consulting operations legal compliance
privacy
quite frankly we have a bit of an
identity crisis as we've entered our
teenage years
and with that i felt like we've adopted
a lot of good business practices but
also a lot of negative
there's so much pressure to work harder
work longer tough it out just have this
aggression aggression aggression
there's times i do well in it i'm a type
a personality
but it comes at a cost
in this type of mental construct of just
driving hard doesn't work for everybody
i've seen it change generationally and
the staff i've had over the
past five or ten years have straight up
said i want a better work-life balance
money titles glory they're less and less
important
so we need to address this as an
industry because we don't have good
answers to these needs we can't tell
people
we'll throw more money at you if you
work longer that's not the answer
so i have some ideas and i can actually
show how it has worked financially
they still need to be adapted and
peer-reviewed and tested but
i want to work on this with all of you
together
um because i think it's something we
need to we need to figure out
you know we just can't burn the candle
at both ends anymore in this industry
we have 400 000 job wrecks allegedly
if we're burning people out that's not
sustainable
so another thing i want to talk on or
another factor before i touch on my
journey
is um you know lives can be on the line
with cyber if you're in certain
industries and when i was in pure i.t i
can always blame a bad patch
for a down server but a breach that's
not a technical problem that means a
human
had an interaction at a certain point
that a breach happened
and that's heavy stuff we don't prepare
people for
and again we don't have we have this
idea we have to be right all the time or
else
and we need to be easier on each other
in on this industry
because it's not fair it's not healthy
it's not scalable
because most of the time lives are not
on the line it's a business that
maybe didn't fund the right controls or
see so they didn't articulate it to
the the business of what the risk
management is but we got to stop taking
it out on the analysts
in the proverbial intern when bad
happens
so right now i'm going to jump into
my journey and again just again it's a
little heads up of a trigger warning
here's if you
want to step back um by all means
i was born in 1976 new york city
and i was one of only children although
i three half sisters all very type a
hard driving personalities my youngest
sisters the broadway tour manager for
hamilton please do not hit me up for
tickets
i can't even get she can't even get him
um
and just i've been surrounded with these
type ages hard driving personalities
even as a teenager i felt i had to leave
my mark on the world that there would
have to be this
this thing i do but i didn't feel
comfortable
in high school i was beat up bullied
alienated
i was a skater punk you know that didn't
fit well
in upstate new york or upstate-ish new
york i was in the hudson valley region
but that didn't really align with that
proverbial jock mentality of you know it
was
it was almost like living in the heather
school um
and it i just didn't fit in i didn't
think the same i didn't
look the same i didn't approach poems
health teachers in in the administrators
were like you are bright but we don't
even know what to do just
just don't get in trouble because i
would find creative funny things to do
that they didn't appreciate either
but i really started having these these
feelings i couldn't really identify with
and
i was hanging out with my friends and
somebody had some weed
which was you know kind of crazy back in
the 90s
and i smoked some weed and had this
massive massive panic attack crippling
it went on for days and i i thought i
was gonna die i mean i
went finally told my parents what had
happened they kind of laughed it off a
little bit being
you know parents from the 70s brought me
to the hospital
doctor what's wrong with you your heart
rate's up but overall you're fine like
all your blood works fine
go home can't kenny can't sleep massive
insomnia
ongoing ongoing panic attacks go back to
the hustle back and forth finally a
doctor said
hey you're having a panic attack this is
anxiety i'm like what the hell is that
he's like well
you have um a reaction of something
there's something that's going on
your brain chemicals but you're having a
fight or flight response
and i'm like what the hell is that and
so really if you look about
just a quick medical side note so if the
difference between the synthetic and
parasymphatic nervous systems this
sympathetic nervous system prepares the
body for the fight-or-flight response
during a potential danger
on the other hand the parasympatic
nervous system inhibits the body
from overworking restoring a body to a
calm and composed state
the synthetic and parasympatic system
for me can be triggered and broken in in
various ways even though like i said it
can be under
weird stressful conditions doesn't
affect it other things maybe chemical
stimulants maybe
i don't know all of them you know can
have things i'll talk about a couple but
it can throw me off and so i didn't know
this and i felt oh god i'm broken
like i'm that's it life's over like i'm
you know
16 17 years old like i'm a broken human
being i was like no
i could get some therapy and put me on
paxil and things got better and i got
out of that
and coming out of high school i didn't
know what i wanted to do again i didn't
fit into the world they were like go to
go to college you like computers
like i'm not learning mainframes i'm
1993-94 like i don't
know like i already can build networks
and rebuild computers like what what are
they going to teach me like i should be
in there teaching about you know network
operating systems and they're like no no
well
we don't do that so i'm like all right
so i started my own business i started
my own business in 1995
right in the first month got really
successful my parents
being the people who they are really
were supporting me allowed me to take
uh some of the college investments i had
start a business and i was off to the
races with a company called computer
house calls basically doing a break fix
type things
for computers um in the 90s setting up
networks
and i was growing and i got some really
big good business clients that brought
me to other enterprise business clients
all of a sudden
within four years i'm serving merrill
lynch in new york city and i'm building
out huge networks
and i burnt out just kept going i was
traveling i was not taking care of
myself i kept going
and i had another bouts of anxiety and i
completely just had a nervous breakdown
it was burnt out
and couldn't work for weeks i had to
cancel a lot of projects
i hurt my business i i just didn't know
what to do and
again i went back to the doctor and
they're like like you need to fix me
like well
you have a condition it's not that
you're framing a little bit wrong
got on the medication again things got
better and things really went well for
for a long time um 2006
uh 15 years ago in a couple weeks in
july
of 19 of 2000 july 3rd of uh
2006 i met my wife and
things went well i'm still my businesses
now running pretty calm i'm
taking time for myself i'm taking care
of myself
but as this grows up and or as i grew up
through that process and
started to mature and have a wife and
then
you know a family i have a baby i was
really struggling
around 2012 with who i am and what i'm
doing and
having to leave behind some of the
entrepreneurial stuff and going house
out of company
and i just i wasn't right i was in the
right
kind of mental framing let's say for
that and strongly i say how do i be
you know working for somebody now i've
always been the outcome i'm a hacker i
don't work for people man
that was the outcast i i not having to
work for somebody to have health care
for a kid and all this it was
just really i was really struggling and
not doing well with this up until about
2015 and
16 and started another practice so i
kind of went more into an intramural
role
but was not communicating well i was
very isolated i was depressed all the
time
focused too heavily on work and
it was hurting my relationship with my
wife and even my new kid and it was just
i was
despondent i probably should have gotten
more help than i
did at the time i got some therapy and
counseling but wasn't really serious or
committed to it
and really felt that what i had to do
was get out of that environment so what
my wife and i started looking at again
we had a series of
wonky things that happened in new york
city that were noticeably stressful
like having to move twice because of
hurricanes you know there was
hurricane sandy displaced us for several
weeks like seven weeks
and we just got tired of that in the new
york city life and we're like okay where
do we go let's go to new york city let's
go to boulder and look at look at this
map of boulder
did all my risk analysis i knew at that
time there was going to be a potential
um i even said i don't know if i use the
word avian but i said there was going to
be a respiratory type
infection that was going to come from um
chinese
origins because of things that would
happen with stars i had mapped out i've
been doing a lot of
business continuity and pandemic
planning at the time i was like
something's going to hit a major city
let's get out of here so we're getting
ready to leave
um and we are
packing up we're getting everything out
of the apartment we're coming to boulder
start a new life and we'll leave
the be the crap behind me because just
too much stress and things i haven't
processed in my past so i'll just i'll
just go somewhere new
that will solve everything until
somebody on her phone uh ran a red light
texting and hit my side of the car
two weeks before we are about to move we
were actually out driving around
to go find a breakfast place in brooklyn
because they were showing the apartment
and wanted us out there for renting and
get out of the car everybody screaming
crying we know what's going on
luckily everybody was nobody was you
were able to see
who that they were hurt but the next day
i couldn't move i
turned out i'd blown out two uh discs in
my back pretty bad i had severe
neurological pain um and impedance in my
foot
it was called drop foot because the
nerves were so badly compressed in my
back
i was just it was nonstop pain and
numbness and where it
just felt awful sorry i'm trying to move
to a new city
um our new town and i'm in immense pain
um can't help my family move and that's
just taking his toll on me i get out
here
okay i'm going to get some help and i
get some really great physical therapy
help i mean
boulder is great i was getting help from
people that helped star athletes and
olympians so it's great
i told the job when i was with at the
time you know look i want to go out
start a new life out there but i'm going
to still maintain this business
and i've always had a kind of rocky
relationship with them but it was
something i think when i was out of
sight and out of mind
they re-pivoted the way they wanted this
business and
about two weeks out after here use
everything we could to get out here
cars destroyed backs hurt they
eliminated me and my entire division on
the spot
i was out of work i was out of
healthcare insurance
um their reaction was look this is just
a financial decision what's the problem
i'm like look i
i have medical bills now that i need
this insurance like car insurance is
covering some of this but there's other
things and
i got a family man like you can't just
do this and like
no this is this is just business and to
them it was this cold-hearted thing
and i had people that were working for
me you know i had i was
a practice leader of a group and for
sales people
bunch of analysts everybody's out of a
job and looking at me like what do i do
so
the people in my care are struggling so
i'm feeling horrible
and i'm like screw it i'm just going to
go i'm not going to deal with this
trauma i'm just going to dig in
so i start helping with b-sides denver
reach out to some of the the
groups out here in colorado start
working with them but i'm not
really taking care of myself i'm
re-hurting my back actually getting
ready for peace sites denver
uh which it's certainly i'm on the board
of still
um and the pain just gets really bad and
at that point i just collapse
i i can't move on um
it was it was too much and really i
think the the physical pain the mental
pain everything caught up
in may of uh 2017 and i became
just despondent couldn't get out of bed
um and things got things got dark and
it just continued to get worse and one
of the ways that you can start raiding
some of these things so you have the
american institute of stress has this
home's wrong stress and inventory scale
so most people like you know or you want
to stay around 150
or lower so you add up all these things
that happen on that left-hand column's
too small to read
you can look it up but it's things like
death in the family
new job moving birth of a kid like all
these things and
good or bad stress in your in your body
is going to build up over time
and particularly for short periods of
time 300 points or more is like
really bad like you're you don't want to
be that
when i added up everything i was over
400.
i mean i was literally off the chart in
the levels of stress i mean i only
highlighted a couple we only have so
much time
but so much happened in such short
period of time of starting a new life
with injury that the depression just
starts setting in
and emotional pain starts manifesting
its ways in
physical pain like there's no other way
it's really hard to describe
but you know once you start getting
these kind of mild areas
to moderate you know you really need to
start
getting help and seeking help and doing
things but to me it was like i was going
to tough it out
i actually still tried to get help but i
was really hard part of our american
system of health is if you don't have
job you don't have
insurance so i couldn't get insurance
help and at that point
you know we we had to get government
assistance just for things like food and
stuff
um which again just takes his stress i
mean i went from this
incredibly high paying job being able to
pay for my family to not not be able to
get my own medical insurance and it's
just
compounding and building on itself to
the point where
you know the severe scale
you know when you're in that seven
you're avoiding things it just got worse
it got to a 10 if not more
um you literally
can't think it's going to get any worse
and you don't you want to stop
and you start thinking pretty dark
thoughts you think suicidal
and for those that have never been in
that hole you know it's one thing to
have
bad days and really struggle but when it
goes on and there's emotional
trauma for a long time it starts to eat
at you
and there's a there's a passage by
william styron that really
describes it better than anything i've
ever found and he wrote this
memoir and depression in 1990 called
darkness visible
and there's one quote i never never read
from slides hell i never put this much
word on slides but
i think this is profound to look at and
hear at the same time because it
it gives you a glimpse into what that
dark closet is like
and it's the great drizzle of horror
induced by depression takes on the equal
it takes on the quality of physical pain
but it's not immediately identifiable
pain like that of a broken limb
it may be more accurate to say that
despair
owing to some evil trick played upon the
sick brain by the
inhibiting psyche comes to resemble the
diabolical discomfort
of being imprisoned in a fiercely
overheated room
because no breeze stirs his cauldron
because there's no
escape from the smothering confinement
is entirely natural that the victim
begins to think
ceaselessly of obliviation or oblivion
you want it to end when it's that part
when all these things just crush you
um it's horrible
but god willing
i'm an atheist but not willing i found
help i finally got the therapy
and the help i needed i was able to get
the medication i needed
i was able to get out of that hole uh
love and support a family that
took its toll on them to this day i mean
it was it's
not a good spot to be in and really was
and i can say it now and say it seems
weird to say but only three or four
months
but those are the longest three
months of my life and
at times i didn't want to live but i got
out of it i found a job and i built a
practice here in denver
that reframed the way i thought about
work so i took a lot of lessons learned
about it because
you know it was never easy but it was
worth it um
for my family for for those i eventually
got to
employ for more importantly for me
and i need to i need i deserved it and i
needed to understand i need to accept
that i deserved
to live and i deserved to love myself
and i deserve to be loved
and to continue i'm glad i did
and i have an amazing life now i get to
do all the things i love to do
but it took it took a lot to get out of
that hole
and it took reaching out and asking for
help
um and look it's not it hasn't been easy
i've
last year there's been corona i've
gotten a new job but it's been
incredibly stressful and
i sometimes don't know when to say no to
things um
you know when i was going to speak here
in mental health i said i'll help out
the mental health village
because hell i'm doing it on site at
wildless hackingfest def con
i'll help at diane initiative and
that would have been fine had i not
agreed to speak at four of the
conferences
had i not agreed to teach a class at
harvard while taking it
had i not um agreed to take on another
federal appointment
had i agreed and i just i put too much
on my plate lately and i'm pretty much
near the walls of burnout right now and
so this weekend i'm really gonna
take some time to unplug but
it's a constant battle i mean i i just
know it's always there
and i've come to accept that this is who
i am and i love myself for it i'm okay
with it
i'm not perfect i don't need to be fixed
but i need to know that mental illness
is an illness
they've got to move past the stigma and
the shame that people feel about their
illnesses
and differences that's quite frankly it
promotes people
not to seek professional treatment
forces people to self-medicate
so we've got to remove the stigma
because you know if somebody had it was
diabetic you wouldn't tell them to suck
it up and just smile
you wouldn't call them names like hey
insulin baby like we call people who are
crazy so we need to stop treating each
other that way
and i bet many people have experiences
what they just didn't feel mentally
healthy for that day
and then ended up using a physical
ailment as an excuse to take a sick day
and not going to work
it's we need to go past that
and people say well you know why don't
you just being altruistic you know
capitalism you know we need to keep
going
again what if i told you that in my
post-traumatic
journey when i started building a
business and looking at things in a
resilient fashion just like i would look
at
building a cyber security program for
resilience not perfection
i looked at how i could build a practice
in a business that had resilience and i
started thinking about the mental
well-being of my staff
and you know what it resulted in people
who were happier and therefore better at
their jobs
which results in a higher employee
satisfaction
higher retention rates higher
customer satisfaction as well it ended
up with more top-line revenue
and greater profit margins when i had
happier healthier
employees because when people feel their
best they perform at their best full
stop
so this about mental health
versus business
is a joke there's no zero-sum game
everyone can and should win and you know
what are some of the just the basics
that people can do right now in their
workplace and
raising or alleviating some of the
stigma
first talk openly about mental health
it's not easy for me to do this like i'm
this takes this toll out of me every
time but it's worth it
because ultimately i want to educate you
and others
so you need to get out there and educate
others about this as well
do be conscious of your language like i
said i mean we use hey this must be
crazy
there's a lot of trigger words that we
use in our environments
that hurt people emotionally that have
emotional trauma
just as we are being more aware of
things that we say that could hurt
people that have
um other underrepresented or that come
from underrepresented groups that are
now learning to adopt and change our
language part of natural
linguistic evolution is to change and
adapt so it's not that hard to stop
saying things that could be
triggering or upsetting to people
because i really want to
you know fourthly encourage equality
between physical mental illness i want
it to be this parody where people are
not like
oh you know mental illness is but you
know physical like oh we go to the
doctor for that now there needs to be
that open dialogue so somebody is
not feeling well mentally they go out
and they seek the help
ultimately i want you all to show
compassion for those with mental illness
because this is not
an easy journey so please be there for
people and i ask i know a lot
of what people try to do is comforting
at times or saying oh don't worry doug i
know i've been there too i had a really
bad day
please don't be dismissive like that um
unless you were
identified without you've really been in
there don't identify with just listen
listen to us who have suffered this
stuff just as you would listen to
somebody else
in their experience and life journeys
and maybe another group
you wouldn't say well i know what it's
like to be black as a white guy no i
don't
so please don't tell me you know how it
is to go through what i have through
unless you've been there and if you have
it's okay and we'll get out of it but do
allow that open dialogue for others
because i really
want to have empowerment over shame i
want people to feel bad
about these conditions understand that
again these are just differences
and we can celebrate them and be better
because of them
and when you do need help be honest
about the treatment you know it's
it's something that you need and it's
okay it's okay to ask for
because it's it's it's something that um
a lot of people need but don't seek and
i'm trying to encourage more people just
to be
honest about getting it and then pushing
it in the workplace
you know whether it's a mental health
day or whatever it is just getting
people out that's more of a self-care
thing but
you know these ideas that we need to to
need time off to deal with this
and do call other people's out you know
you know i said this in my my
diversity talk about hiring is that
you know call people out when they're
being stigmatizing about things silence
equals compliance
and i know there's going to be those
folks that we say oh
everyone's so sensitive these days and
like no
people have always been aware of what an
you are we're just finally
letting you know
so do not be afraid to call people out
when they're using language that hurts
others i mean it's not okay
and just because that's the way it was
doesn't mean it's the way that
things should be
and ultimately please do not harbor
self-stigma
it's okay not to feel okay
i have some resources sir that i can dig
into
deeper into each one of these areas but
the one thing that my therapist said to
me
and i'll share a little bit how i got
out of my my thing and just
quickly brief into to what i did to get
out of these these
kind of darker areas he said to me
on this side pain is inevitable but
suffering is optional it's a little bit
flippant
and i've been criticized for using this
slide before
but i think it's important to understand
that you know you you
you have to get out of that hole that
the pain that you
there is it's gonna happen you're gonna
have pain and trauma in your life
just have to make a conscious choice at
times to
find ways out of it so some of the
things that i've done
um are a variety of different things so
it's been medication
um that's worked i finally had to go
through several different iterations of
things that i found worked
and keep me in a balance um you know
it's just lexapro it's nothing crazy
but i found it helped it was the minimal
effective dose which helped too
another thing is cognitive therapy so
acceptance and commitment therapy has
been extremely valuable to me and for my
personality and my
neurotype for it what acceptance of
commitment therapy is or act is this
action-oriented approach
to psychotherapy that stems from
traditional
behavior therapy and cognitive behavior
therapy so
individuals in treatment learn to stop
avoiding and denying and struggling with
their inner emotions
and instead what we do is we accept that
these are deeper feelings are
appropriate responses to certain
situations that should not prevent
me from moving forward in my life so
with this understanding
you know people in this modality of
treatment begin to accept
that issues and hardships are there and
you just
make committed necessary changes
in your behavior regardless of what's
going on in your life
and choosing how you want to feel about
it you know you again you're going to
have these reactions it's very much
centered in being in the moment saying
this sucks right now i'm okay with it
because i can't solve every problem
and some of the things i had to do is
almost existentially to help me get in
those mindsets of being in the moment is
reducing some of the external stress um
because we're all facing with it
and you have to set these boundaries
these ways of not letting
people kind of eat off your plate or
your time so
some of the things i've done is reducing
alert fatigue i don't have
and i haven't had for years i don't have
work email on my phone i don't have work
slack
i don't know what i have in my phone i
probably have brave browser and google
maps i mean i use it for very little
but i removed all the alerts all the
things that are specifically designed to
make you respond
in a certain way i got rid of all that
um
and i make sure i have very good
schedules that when i work on something
i work on something no more multitasking
focused periods of deep work um i've
used things like the pomodoro technique
to get motivated when i've had to get
over just like small
things to get myself motivated working
on a specific task but i only work on
that task at that time
and a lot of this comes down to routines
like for example i set morning routines
and before i touch any tech or do
anything i'll do some meditation
some journaling just kind of ease into
the day
because it's it's important to really
set that mindset for me
personally as i enter the day and have
this routine i get up at 5am
i go through this every day or most days
i can again i don't strive for
perfection
but i find it helps me kind of level set
for the day as much as i can i make sure
i'm hydrated as well enough i'm sleeping
right
i'm getting exercise where i can um
and i take breaks from things like
drinking i am starting a cocktail
um bitters company and i know that that
can lead to a lot of danger me
excessively drinking so i have to take
conscious breaks and and not drink for
periods of time it's just healthy
against it you know it's just i need to
balance
and that's what this all comes down is
finding that balance in my life
um because overall i just want to be
more accepting of who i am and being
focused more on the moment
and this is who i am and this is who i
am going to be and i don't have to fix
everything
and i really want to share the moments
i'm with with the people i'm with at
that moment so it's a real strong focus
on me
and it leads into a little bit of this
ideas of self-care again the self-care
is this idea is what you do deliberately
for yourself
to establish and maintain mental health
or really any health and the idea is to
prevent
and be ahead of long-term illnesses kind
of early down in the kill chain and we
joked earlier today in the
mental health village that now i've
again i'm going to overextend myself and
come up with a
um self-care early prevention kill chain
for stress
so preventing burnout with kill chains
it's another thing i need to put on my
plate
but if you think about self-care is is
this it's a proactive and preventative
steps just like you didn't work for
vulnerability research threat hunting
patching firewalls it's the stuff you
kind of do for yourself
because what you want to do is start
balancing out some of these brain
chemicals and the two main ones being
serotonin and dopamine
and serotonin does a variety of things
in the body
regulates anxiety happiness mood low
levels have been attributed to
depression and anxiety
so they think or at least which most of
the research has shown they still don't
know a lot about it
and dopamine is the feel-good
transmitter it's the one that the brain
releases
when we eat food that we crave or when
we have sex contributing to feelings of
pleasure and satisfaction
it's part of that whole reward system
it's an important neurosystem
neurochemical which boosts mood
motivation and attention
it helps regulate movement learning and
emotional response and it's very easy to
overdo it over stimulate yourself and
your brain stops
having that cycle where the healthy
parts of that work
and some of the things you can do for
self-care is and they're simple
small little things that can have a
bigger impact
one of the things i think is really
important to celebrate the small wins
um if you had a good day celebrate it
you know something to be crazy you want
to go balls out to the wall but
maybe have a nice dinner just go do
something celebratory for yourself
when you're down don't be afraid to call
a friend ask for help you know that's
that's the one thing i think that
more people can do is just pick up a
phone and you know just slack somebody
at work you know if somebody you're
close would say i
just need to vent or get something off
my plate
those little bursts of just dumping
things and steadily letting them faster
can be incredibly important
um certainly exercising danny and i were
talking about say don't
you have to go crazy just simple start
small maybe it's a i'm gonna walk five
minutes today
and i'm gonna walk five minutes twice a
week and maybe i'll do 15 minutes twice
a week whatever just start small and
build up
because it's going to help you get to
where you want to go goal was
one of the things too is obviously when
we talk about corona and everything
that's happened over the last year is
stop doom scrolling like get off social
media um
as good as things like twitter can be
for our community i've seen it go
extremely toxic and you all know what
i'm talking about
um it has an emotional response so get
away from that stuff as much as you can
and stop reading the news obsessively
um particularly with the last year this
has been stressful there's a lot of
things you can't change with that
be aware don't be consumed
again i talked about these routines like
getting into these routines of sleep
exercise meditation that can be
incredibly helpful
and the one thing i stress with all of
this is that done is better than perfect
like you don't have to
every day have this and i did that and i
did it wrong for a long care time for
self-care it's just
it has to be this rigid thing that
doesn't you know you want to just have
these
these slow kind of builds of things and
if you do it 80 of the time that's great
um
because that's gonna be really important
because you can really it up too
you can also do fake self-care and i've
seen this as like i said it's a drive
for me it's like i overdo it and it's
you know it's i've done just about all
these antics on the list of fake
self-care
you know most notably dieting drinking
harmfully
talking down to myself to motivate
myself just a bunch of bs or
oh i'm gonna miss out on something this
fomo thing so instead of saying
time with my family being in the moment
like i talked about rushing out and
being away from things
so it's very easy to fool yourself and
do things that
are unhealthy in the name of health
but you deserve it you know there's
these myths about self-care and i really
want to get rid of that stigma
that is selfish or you know it's
like this big ask in your life it's not
you deserve it
again when you feel better you'll treat
others better
and just get these little routines of
doing it you know this idea that you do
something for 21 days you get into good
habits
let's try for 21 days just try good
healthy things that i put on that slide
little routines that you can add on for
21 days you'll find that you'll build
some momentum you'll start feeling
better and guarantee it
but it needs to be an ongoing practice
so please that's the one thing i
encourage you is starting with some
self-care because you just you deserve
it
we love you we think you you need it you
need it love yourself and start there
and i just want to leave you all with
some parting thoughts you know it's
again this is obviously some
heavier subjects and we've gotten some
deeper stuff but
i really love this quote from robin
williams um
because ultimately the one thing that i
try to
learn from in my past miss i don't even
use the words mistakes that's not right
my journey is not only to
be more aware how i am to myself but how
i am to others
so first you know obviously forgive
yourself be kind to yourself
be vulnerable and we spend so much time
addressing vulnerabilities in our
networks but how much time we time
looking at the vulnerabilities that we
feel in ourselves and we improve our
cyber programs
do the same with yourself accept them
focus on what you can improve in your
own well-being and be resilient
but be nice to others um because
honestly
you can't control other people in most
situations
you can really only choose how you
respond how you choose to respond to
other people
warren buffett was uh giving this tv
interview one time and he says
this gentleman by the name of thomas
murphy
and um so i'm sorry so the best piece of
advice that warren buffer got was an
issue he was talking about this by his
friend thomas murphy and thomas murphy
said to him
warren you can always tell someone to go
to hell tomorrow
meaning that it was kind of this easy
way of putting it you don't have this
missed opportunity to tell somebody to
go off
just forget about it for a day if you
feel the same way tomorrow
tell them but don't spout things off in
the moment of
anger like again we call a lot of what
we do incident response not incident
reaction
don't react to everything slow your role
we do not have to react to everything in
our environment because like i said in
most
situations you can only control how you
react
so respond be in the moment but as my
friend dalton said
at the double deuce be nice don't let
everything get under your skin
it's a simple little reframing of things
of how you choose to respond to life
stresses that's gonna
start you on this journey because
really you need to make time for your
wellness or i guarantee
you'll be forced to make time for your
illness
encourage everybody do one little
takeaway task
tonight before you go to bed
put down by your bed i'm sure
everybody's got a pad or something they
can write on
and when you wake up tomorrow write down
five good things about yourself
first thing when you wake up maybe do
your meditation before you touch any
tech you know as part of your morning
routine
write down five good things about
yourself and i bet that's gonna be a lot
harder than you think
and it's a tough thing and the reason i
want people to do that is
to really sit and focus and think about
the good things that you bring to the
table into the world because you do
but you need to consciously do that
because we all get this
negative habits of putting ourselves
down and saying we didn't do enough
but start your day right by maybe just
writing down a couple good things about
yourself
you'll be surprised how that reframes a
lot of what you do because
you're worth it you know we love you we
need you
community needs you so support each
other
hack the planet i'm open for q a
douglas i think i speak for the audience
here when i say your talk was immensely
enjoyable and we all learned
so much um i don't think i've seen any
question here and we've got about two
minutes left
so if anyone in the audience have
questions
please send them in now
so i don't think there's any questions
from the audience
thank you so much this is such an
important conversation to have
so have a good rest of your day thanks
everybody