hey everyone welcome back to stage three
uh our next speaker is grace chi and
she'll be talking about cti behind the
curtains for cyber threat intelligence
careers
take away grace thank you all right uh
thank you everyone and i'm gonna pull up
the comments now um if there's any sort
of issues feel free to uh send them in
chat i'll try to monitor them as far as
i know there might be like a three to
five second delay so i'll give plenty of
time um thank you so much i see some
comments already you're amazing too
jessica
all right so welcome to cti behind the
curtains for cyber threat intelligence
careers today we're going to cover the
basics about what threat intelligence is
maybe you're somewhat familiar with it
maybe you do a little bit of it in your
current job or maybe you know you're
just checking out all the different
options you have within the threat
intelligence in the cyber security space
you're all welcome um hopefully we're
gonna keep it high level
get you introduced and then we can jump
into some questions some tips and some
resources
if you're looking to expand further in
the career
all right moving forward so a little bit
about me i'm the co-founder and the ceo
of pulse dive i spend a lot a lot of
time working with different threat
intelligence pros
home hobbyists huge organizations and
their teams across like every level of
threat intelligence maturity and we'll
get into a little bit about like what
maturity looks like and what that
current landscape is within uh security
right now
for me it's really important to get more
talent from all walks of life into this
expanding and critical path that's
becoming quickly integrated across the
entire security environment
i'm a personally a huge advocate of
interdisciplinary backgrounds i have a
little bit of behavioral neuroscience i
have a little bit of art history i have
a little bit of visual arts and uh like
just a bunch of different hobbies and
passions in my life and to me they all
really importantly impact my career my
work too i love working um always
enjoyed startups and so that's what i
want to bring back into this community
and also help other people who are
interested who have different
interesting diverse backgrounds and
perspectives work together and bridge
the gaps in security
and also congrats dwayne who just got
their threat intelligence cert inviter
attack very important the attack
framework
and finally a quick note i was talking
to somebody earlier who's like you can't
send emojis in the chat you actually can
and that could be kind of fun if you
open up like emojipedia or any of you
know your other keyboards that has
emojis you can copy and paste them so
feel free to send them throughout this
session
as part of my job because i work within
a threat intelligence data and platform
vendor space i'm talking to people at
all levels all the time they're
researchers they're from academia
they're from um
government groups they're from you know
commercial sectors as well and they're
all across the world and so i get this
really unique perspective talking and
listening to their issues and then also
seeing what makes teams successful what
kind of investments what kind of skills
really help grow individual careers as
well as grow cti programs and so part of
that is oh and i see a lot of people are
sending emojis yeah looking good
part of that is bringing it back to the
audience of folks who might not have
access to this type of information
and if we step back like
why why talk about cti careers like why
does the diana initiative you know try
to invite different folks to learn about
security blue team purple team grc red
team
and this is something that is related to
and any new project any new initiative
you're taking on
stage one uninformed optimism
that's when let's say somebody's looking
to pivot in their career and that all
they see are blue skies they're just so
excited you know cyber pays well uh you
get to really make an impact what you're
doing helps protect organizations and
helps protect citizenry and you know you
can learn and it's a great field which
it is 100 it is but you don't know
everything that's going on and then you
start to get involved and then you move
into stage two and that's informed
pessimism you're starting to see a lot
of barriers everything feels hard the
benefits of you know what you've tried
to take on move further and further away
and unfortunately i also see a lot of
people getting really frustrated feeling
like they cannot really start to grab
onto a cti career or they're applying to
a lot of jobs they're not able to get it
they're inundated with pressures to get
a lot of certs or other qualifications
and that's where you get into stage
three that's the valley of despair and
what i like to unprofessionally call the
big sad that's where you are almost
burnt out you feel nothing but impostor
syndrome you really are like i can't
continue
there's no way i'm gonna make it past
this um i'm it's it's too difficult i
don't get it um and then that's where a
lot of people might quit and repeat
phase one through three where you try
something else and you either do push
through or you don't
the talk here today is to equip you with
some knowledge some advice some
frameworks about how to look at a threat
intelligence career if it's interesting
to you so you don't quite dip that low
in the valley of despair
um
i saw somebody just say that the valley
of despair is real yeah it is and this
isn't just for your career could be when
you start a new job could be when you
start a new hobby could be
your attempt at getting healthier and
exercise and it's really important to
understand where you are in these mental
states and also get resources to help
you so that you can get to informed
optimism that's stage four more quickly
that's where you understand
what priorities you need what work you
need what effort you have to put in and
you're starting to feel like you're
getting there you're able to contribute
you're able to teach yourself and make
an impact in your organization or
protect your home environment whatever
that is
and then uh stage five which is you know
nirvana that's where you have found
success and you feel like you're
fulfilled that you have a purpose and
this happens at micro and macro levels
too and every time you bring on
something you can and you may go through
all of these stages so once again when
we're talking about all this you don't
have to feel pressured to remember
everything you don't have to take
screenshots or crazy notes but feel free
if you do
it's just so that you might take enough
nuggets of knowledge out of here so that
you can guide your path and you could
understand what to be worried about what
not to be worried about what foundations
you need to have in place
kaya yes uh lots of emojis i threw these
in actually last night because i thought
it was just a little bit more
interesting in the presentation
so today getting into the nitty-gritty
cyber threat intelligence 101
what the cti stand for
cti in action just an example of what a
day
what a program what your job in cti
looks like and then tips and resources
just some things to leave you off with
some hyperlinks we can also send out in
the chat as well i might be able to post
the comment uh later when we get to that
point
a quick snapshot of the audience
how familiar are you with cti and feel
free i'll give you a few seconds just to
send in you know
you don't even know what it stands for
or like maybe you took a course or maybe
took a general course that had like
one day of cti um or you know it's your
job you could you could honestly be
presenting it right now alongside me
so go ahead and type that in the chat
i'm seeing some comments coming in
and while we wait
i'm going to show you i mentioned
earlier and i want to live up to it i do
a lot of crafts in my spare time like
non-digital get away from the screen
refresh my mind so i have plants but
they're not living plants so while we're
doing this first poll
this is my plants versus zombie plant
these are actually perler beads that i
created in a little pot
this is the bean shooter peashooter p
peashooter and this is the sunflower
that you can buy more plants with in
plants for a zombie so they sit on my
windowsill at home
all right
just looking around are you doing a
little in your job very familiar
following and reading along took a
general course somewhat familiar perfect
exactly the right audience
so moving in let's get into a mind meld
what are some key words related to the
definition of cyber threat intelligence
that you might have been familiar with
that you think are relevant
um that you've learned about in your
studies
so i'm seeing you know security
operation center people using cti yep
yep
i see people now are loving the plant um
i'll show you actually i'll show you
another one while we're here
um
there's taking course threat hunting yes
of course
i'll show you a small one this time
i also get into miniatures because they
don't take up that much space but they
take up a lot of time which is a great
uh hobby during covid
so here's a tiny i don't know if my
camera looks good or not tiny little
potted plant
and then here's a tiny little
i don't even know what they're called
does anybody know what this is
a little bead
and i have little cafes and stuff in my
house shelves full of these things
all right checking out chat now
um
[Music]
ioc's of course indicators of compromise
threat actors threat groups apts
behavior
c and c so infrastructure yes excellent
all of that is related
so let's define cyber threat
intelligence
i'm going to go to uh gartner who's you
know one of the big voices on the block
and their their definition
it's evidence-based knowledge including
context mechanisms
indicators
implications and action-oriented advice
about an existing or emerging menace or
hazard to assets
okay
this intelligence can be used to inform
decisions regarding the subject's
response to that menace or hazard so in
cyber their intelligence it's all cyber
security related
every vendor
every single kind of
group might define it a little bit
differently but if we boil it down it
ends up being data that becomes
contextualized that informs action
steps things to do
and one thing i really want to debunk
right now
is what cti isn't in this space and in
security a lot of people tend to
conflate just technology with
whatever that domain is so cti is not
just having a notebook a dossier with
every threat group or apt
it's not consuming every expensive feed
or free feed
and having every tool in-house
it's not even
having a dedicated team member or
provider
and it's not ingesting every indicator
every ioc that you can find and it's not
oh sinting all the things either and the
most important of all when you're moving
into this career or you're just talking
to people about cti it's never set it
and forget it that's something that i
have to remind users
clients prospects all the time
cti is so inherently ingrained in an
organization in their thread landscape
that over time you are optimizing but
it's never like let me turn some things
on let me get some workflows going and
then okay great it's just working the
threat landscape is changing every day
that actors are changing um your own
environment is changing and that in and
of itself is important and intelligence
in regards to that is also changing all
the time
to provide some context about cti's
discipline
sam's institute has been doing a cti
survey every year and so i pulled in
some data from their 2021 survey and
they've had five years of history here
which is great
does your organization produce or
consume cti so five years ago sixty
percent of the surveyed respondents
replied yes
either producing internally consuming
threat intelligence it's part of kind of
their security posture
over time that number has gone all gone
all the way to 85 percent and that's
that's a pretty significant majority
on the other end 25 percent five years
ago had said not yet but we're planning
to it's somewhere on the horizon we know
it's important we just need our budget
we need our time we need somebody who
can come in house and really help us
operationalize that number has dropped
down to 15
which is the entire remaining amount of
respondents so what does that mean the
left over from 2017 that had no plans
didn't care and no cti for us no thank
you that went to zero so everyone's
changed their tune so either they are
now involved in some level of cti
production consumption or they have it
on their plans
when it comes to being a cti
practitioner
where do teams exist right
pretty standard for the rest of the
industry but there's a lot of vendors
out there who produce cti who have cti
tooling a lot of times they are doing a
lot of cutting edge research and they're
both startups and very large
organizations
there's consulting so mssps manage
detection teams cti specific teams so
they are professional services that work
with many clients to help them get their
cti in order
there's government groups as well for
local state federal
and there's institutional academic
health care nonprofit for-profit and
finally commercial that includes
enterprise finance probably has some of
the best well-known fusion centers and
there's also manufacturing supply chain
just really any commercial sector
they all have different levels of cyber
threat intelligence ingrained in their
security programs
now who and where right like how does
that look in a
company going back into the 2021 cti
survey by sans institute
most organizations have formal dedicated
teams or at least some sort of shared
responsibility across security groups um
so
overall if you look 55
have a combination that means some
in-house maybe some external services
professional services providing uh
context information uh
finished intelligence for them
the in-house segment is 36.5 but that
has grown five percent in the last year
so that means that more organizations
are bringing more talent like purely
in-house to work on cyber threat
intelligence
and about 7.5 are just pure service
providers so kind of like outsource
consultants providing threat
intelligence and honestly i don't know
what that like point zero one percent
others but uh feel free to put your best
guess in the chat
and as far as the users and the
contributors to threat intelligence in
the ideal world it's across the entire
organization but most commonly right now
it's found in security operations teams
there are cti teams
often too you'll see it involved in
incident response or vulnerability
management moving out from there
risk and compliance sometimes when
they're doing assessments and audits uh
cti can come into play
executives and leaderships even if
they're not necessarily uh cyber focused
they need under an understanding of
their threat landscape and what actions
what budgeting you know how to plan
moving ahead in their strategic roadmap
and as well as other business units
in addition
customers and end users play an
important part as well as red teams and
different abuse research
cti at this current moment is not really
an entry-level job you can take some
classes you can do a ton of research
but very very very often uh cti is a
specialization maybe like two three four
five plus years down the line and they
can come from security operations
security consulting um digital forensics
and incident response is a very popular
kind of feeder role into a cyber threat
intelligence-specific uh career
and also security engineering and system
administration too people from it often
find themselves in cti
and two other
less traditional paths um government and
military intelligence and wow i'm
getting an absolute downpour hopefully
you can't hear that but if you do let me
know and i'll try to adjust my audio
military intelligence they're very
familiar with socio-political
geopolitical information and creating
important reports so that translates
very well into cyber threat intelligence
as well and finally technology reporting
so being able to understand technology
find sources right information for a
specific audience that in and of itself
is a great skill to have and so you'll
see all the different kind of components
of those jobs
the skill sets that work really well for
threat intelligence are writing and
reporting technical research
digital forensics networking scripting
is always always a plus but not
necessary and data analysis
it does not mean that you need to do all
of those things but kind of out of the
box they all are immediately useful in a
cyber threat intelligence role
i saw somebody in chat mention that you
know they did research couldn't really
find entry-level jobs it's true
sometimes they do have
security analyst roles that have a focus
on threat intelligence and if you have
some ocean kind of skills or some
projects you've done it helps but
typically typically threatened hell is
something that happens a little further
down in a cyber career
and so now we talk about like currently
like what's happening right
even when i put this slide together a
while ago i mean it's only it's only
gotten worse and it this is not about
fud at all it's just there's double
extortion taking place where not only
you know do you have ransomware and
everything you have encrypted and you
know you do or you don't pay up but then
your private information sensitive
information may be leaked um hackers are
working for hire there's affiliate
groups and they're really coalescing as
like a legitimate business um enterprise
where you know their subscription
services and they're growing more
sophisticated in their capabilities as
well as you know
there's just a lot of vulnerabilities a
lot of gaps a lot of targets that are
open
and there's just massive growth on both
sides and so threat intelligence it's
it's not going away i think it will
evolve over time but truly and this
graph shows you just the number of leaks
that's even just one slice of the puzzle
here the number of leaks that took place
in 2020.
so the job so your career in threat
intelligence why
your job includes understanding that
means you have to have a really good
grasp on the context of your
organization your security the strategy
that you need moving forward
you need to do right those are the
things you're familiar with you're
mitigating you're detecting you're
protecting
you need to optimize always need to be
thinking about how you can improve
things over time how to get the right
resources and operationalize and build
your priorities and you know at the end
of the day like everything else in
security you're protecting the bottom
line whether that's
personal private information whether
that's finance whether that's helping
the business keep going and keep growing
and so the intelligence cycle underlies
the entire discipline right of cyber
threat intelligence the tools all just
support different parts of the cycle the
the staff are helping apply the cycle
into uh the different organizations they
work for
and so i'm going to try not to get too
light jargony here and just keep it fun
but walk through what each stage of this
means and really at the end of the day
this is relevant to many different
careers as well just the process of
planning collection processing analysis
and sharing information back
planning
you start with
what do we care about
why do we care about it
you're setting a purpose you're setting
your scope of your project of your job
you're conducting stakeholder interviews
the people who will care who will be
doing things with intelligence you're
setting core objectives you're learning
how to measure uh you're understanding
your goals and what tasks you might be
setting up with kpis key performance
indicators and you're also understanding
the current risk landscape your users
your consumers and also your
capabilities what you can and you can't
do and what you need to start
doing then you move into collection
that's where you have both internal and
external sources
you might be familiar with this there's
network logs past incidents you might be
getting risk analysis reports internally
externally you might be consuming threat
feeds
just reading blogs or scraping twitter
for iocs right
you might be looking at ttps collected
from vendors on both the open and the
dark web and so what the collection
phase is all about is what data do we
need and from where
but data in and of itself is not enough
like what does a single license plate
mean if you're at a store and you're
trying to protect against criminal
activity it doesn't help so what you
need to do
to go from there is to process
processing includes enrichment and
contextualization
you're taking a little data point an
alert a log an ioc an ioc can be a url
an ip a domain a hash
and you're finding more information
about it you're looking at the narrative
you're doing a correlation as well so
that's you can find things from ocean
engines
different a lot of different tools out
there you can conduct scanning um you
can do footprinting you can also conduct
human intelligence and social
engineering go out into forums you know
you have an informant who can tell you
more information about what they see and
what they know and that also includes
trust groups asking people who've been
doing work uh related to something what
they know and having you know like uh
private shared conversations
and that moves into analysis
within analysis you're then creating
intelligence and this requires a lot of
sophisticated strategic work you're now
sussing out you're building out motives
targets behaviors uh impact right how
much does this matter what is at risk
and then from there you're producing
actionable reports informed narratives
to then protect your organization or
protect whatever you're protecting and
inform decision making and next steps so
that's like
like what recommendations do you put in
place what needs to get done right now
what needs to be in budget next time
because you know this is something that
is high risk
and so the the key point here is out of
all that collection all those data
points and all the context you get
sometimes it's relevant sometimes it's
not so helpful what matters why and to
whom which audiences need to know
and this is the final point which is
there's a lot of really interesting
conversations in threat intelligence
right now about sharing and the
importance of effectively sharing your
intelligence
this is dissemination and then getting
feedback so that you can iterate and
improve next time
you have to select your format your
output how timely when and where you're
going to bring this up what meeting or
what email and the distribution of
intelligence is it public is it private
is it only to executives is it to your
security engineering team with clear
actions and considerations
context that these audiences need to
know about
plus uh just like feedback getting
feedback what was useful what isn't
because you need to improve over time
and this strives at who needs to know
about what you just created and what do
they need to understand what do they
need to walk away with understanding and
this means you sometimes have a whole
breadth of research that's done and one
group might only need the headline
another group might need all of the
technical mitigation measures that need
to be taken place another group might
need a write-up in a different format
and this is absolutely essential and
then the entire cycle starts back again
if you read you know any of the major
vendor blogs they're a great place to
start just to familiarize yourself with
like what how do they determine a target
how do they determine motive how do they
determine uh ttps tactics techniques and
procedures of a threat group but it can
feel very
far away very distant so just a short
quick example of what threat
intelligence looks like even for just a
regular you know you me home hobbyist
in 2020 we were getting a lot of really
weird links uh that includes related to
you know covid related to vaccines
related to ppe
and uh sometimes including yours truly
you get stuff from family members or
friends or you know
older folks who might just be like
sending links out and it might sound
really scary and so
a lot of times if you see those links
like internally you know something's
wrong and you've already assessed that
what matters to you is you know your
financials uh your private information
of course your credentials so if you see
one of these links if you go off into an
ocean tool
i'm just showing postdoc because i you
know i know it's safe to use i won't get
in trouble to showcase this example if
you plug it in you might be able to pull
context here some some information like
screenshots or if they're using a meta
description for facebook which was true
in this case and you know that that's
being suspicious you know that something
there is wrong and they might be trying
to steal passwords for what reason you
can do more research or you can just say
like it's likely that you can take your
stuff maybe try to get money out of
people you know pretend to be you um see
what other information they can get
right pivot within your environment to
uh further further provide a text
and so
now that you've done some processing you
know just like a little bit you want to
disseminate that information you go out
you tell your friends if you saw this
don't click it first of all don't click
it don't use it this is dangerous make
sure you block it uh if you think there
might be something change your password
immediately that's you providing a
report in a very light way of course to
your friends and family that's you
giving action items and so that's like
kind of the smallest microcosm example
of threat intelligence at work and of
course you can report it to registrars
or reported to open fish and they will
also take more actions to help protect
you know the community
going back into the kind of high level
large cti teams there's a huge variety
of maturity levels
on one side there's cti on a budget
that's the photo of a college you know
microwave and fridge where
maybe a team that doesn't have that many
security resources has somebody who's
like an analyst or even an i.t person
who's starting to look at intelligence
try to do more research try to write
reports and respond to requests for
information and that's cti in a budget
they're kind of going with free tools
you wear a lot of hats um definitely
starting to build out resources trying
just to understand what you need at all
there's a lot of people out there in the
commercial space as well as in you know
other spaces
a lot in the middle this is the kind of
a mess where it's like collect them all
but maybe don't operationalize
everything there's a lot of tools
there's some standards there's some
workflows in place but at the end of the
day it's very disjointed because there
are so many new tools taking place new
functionalities
and teams are having trouble finding out
how to integrate it properly how to get
the most value out of all their tools or
if they're collecting a lot of feeds how
to de-noise that right make sure they
don't get false positives and reduce
also false negatives which means you're
not getting alert on every single ip
that comes in but you're also not
missing anything too important
and then on the last side yes there are
some very mature fusion centers they
usually hire uh
very robust teams very very specialized
skill sets they have a lot of great
tools and they also have just a lot of
investment in and that's kind of the
iron chef kitchen where they know
you know it's not a solved problem but
they're creating a lot of intelligence
for the community they're processing a
lot of data and uh if you ever have the
chance to work somewhere like that it's
really great too because you get to see
what the top of the industry looks like
at the bottom i just
peppered in some terminology that you
might see
it's messy um don't feel too overwhelmed
trying to understand everything
like security as an overall domain
i will tell you even in trust groups
where they're just the smartest people
you know they don't know everything
they're focused on uh one sector or a
certain threat actor group or certain
technologies or certain types of
exploits or certain type of attacks they
don't know everything either and that
that's where really sharing intelligence
is very important and knowing what
network of trusted partners you have can
help a lot in the threat intelligence
space so not working early and often so
you know what sources to be looking at
or you know where to be sharing
intelligence as you're getting it that
might help another group or you know
somebody they used to work with
very critical
the technology standpoint which is you
know not and all be all
but right now very commonly in an
example flow there's a lot of
intelligence so that could be domains or
ips urls vulnerabilities and also news
and enviro advisories unstructured data
going in a threat intelligence platform
is a pretty common way to dedupe to
enrich to correlate and just kind of
start
processing that intelligence and then
having analysts manage that actively to
curate it for an organization
but that's not always the case um i have
talked to some folks who have their
intelligence in excel sheets lots and
lots of excel sheets very large excel
sheets
in slideshows and you know it's a little
bit painful but i've also heard that
they kind of have intelligence but it's
just living in email threads but it
quickly does outgrow that once you're
starting to really collect and and look
at you know past information um
i see some okay tim thank you so much
for sending some uh definitions out
and then from there you know the threat
intelligence platform is your database
your analytics layer for managing your
threat intelligence but you know how
where does that operationalize of course
you're writing reports you're sending
advisories out but you can also push
your intelligence uh block lists uh
automatically enrich indicators or
alerts with indicators in your security
information and event management system
and that's correlation that's detection
and that's alerting and also like more
recent years source security
orchestration automation response
moving forward what do you expect um
there's nothing mind-blowing here but if
you're looking at a career in threat
intelligence if you're looking to move
into the space i have a couple um
findings from just talking to a lot of
individuals
one continued growth that's why i'm here
talking to you there's gonna be more
training
more investment uh
from
across the board and from the board
that's my cheek way of saying like
leadership is going to require
threat intelligence the ability to know
reports the ability of you know your
threat landscape
and then also
as far as the marketplace new
technologies coming out and a lot of uh
market consolidation m a there's some
really large news recently too about
some threat intelligence platforms that
were being acquired
another piece is investment towards
hybrid semi-automated processes and
that's not replacing an analyst not
replacing a cti researcher by any means
but it's just helping with the
monotonous work so that's correlation
deduplication the integration and
automation from getting your steps done
and also in dissemination of your
intelligence
next and this is really exciting
refinement on threat intelligence
requirements so that definition that
curation the last five years there's a
lot of like just get everything we need
get everything that we can afford but
now it's like let's think really
carefully about who our stakeholders are
what their needs are what they need to
understand what are our you know crown
jewels and then really tailoring where
you're getting intelligence creating
your own means of intelligence producing
intelligence right your own um
information that you're saving and
sharing in-house and then measuring the
efficacy of your program
and finally and i hit on this a bunch of
times because it is very important
the emphasis of sharing and trust
building across and within organizations
and you'll see like uh stixx taxi is an
example of standardizing threat
intelligence information and data and
that can be used across both formal and
informal coalitions
uh informal includes like trust groups
like there's discord groups out there
they share some sensitive information
they work together because you know no
single team alone can can
handle a lot of the requirements when
you know major events are occurring
and then improved awareness across
internal business functions so cti
supporting the integrated security
program red team purple team blue team
etc and then being a factor of you know
having a presence across business
functions marketing sales just everyone
executive teams as well
getting in um i love the slide because i
get to tell stories of other people and
the cool things they've done
you'll see that i plopped some examples
of kind of like pick and choose your
adventure of how to get in
and the reason it's like messy and the
lines go everywhere is because
even on twitter you'll hear people
arguing all the time it's important to
get certifications you need to have your
own lab no don't do that you need to be
involved in groups the reason why
there's controversy and drama is simply
because there's no clear answer there's
no one path so you can feel what works
for you and then start getting involved
um
i
like telling stories where of course
work experience working in i.t having
intelligence experience can help but
most people have multiple things going
for them and
for example like getting involved in
social media i was talking to a woman
mary who had come from you know some
always loved computers but thought
threatened hell was cool didn't have any
of the traditional qualifications but
was following a bunch of different
researchers and practitioners in the
space saw a job she thought was
interesting wasn't trying to go for it
but reached out to the poster or
somebody who's promoting the job they
had a conversation she actually landed
that job so she's six months in now and
she's loving and she's learning about
how to write reports how to do a lot of
googling how to do a lot of osun
another example is um dorothy who i
absolutely appreciate i had the chance
to connect with her over share the mike
and cyber campaign
and when she first came to me she was
like i was surprised at how many women
of color were in security and i thought
like what i've never heard that before
in my life out of talking to thousands
of groups there was only one time that i
was uh
working a room just full of women and
it's because she was parts of
volunteering and networking groups that
repre had more equal representation and
so when she did hit some challenging
areas or sometimes that felt
demotivating she had a group of cohort
that could you know work with her and
help her and i think that's where it
really
struck out to me that like diana
initiative or dave security or empower
her are really important here as more
people are moving into the space and of
course you know she worked really hard
went to a boot camp networked got an
internship in a slightly related field
and then just continued networking
internally to land her first cti job so
it wasn't
you know just one-to-one but as you're
building this repertoire over time as
you are working on your personal
projects or your posting or you're
following researchers
things will come back too
one last pro tip and this came from a
senior threat researcher from proof
point
if you are reading
threat research reports blogs you see
their name of the authors and you really
liked it reach out say thank you say oh
this was really interesting say that
you're interested in intelligence and
you know you really appreciate the work
they did because they work so so hard
and sometimes they post and then it just
kind of goes into the ether and they
know they're doing good work but it
always helps and it makes their day
honestly to hear that somebody out there
is reading their work appreciating it
it's helping them and the threat
intelligence kind of professional career
for the most part they're very open
they're very willing to help they're
willing to answer questions you know if
you are looking at something and you
have like a critical eye or you don't
quite understand or you want to
replicate their research um feel free
and don't hesitate to kind of step in
and just
get engaged
and finally participating there's
you know nothing's too cti specific
for from my experience most groups are
you know invite only just because
there's a lot of sensitive information
taking place but you can
check out the new to cyber
uh sans summit that took place for the
first time there's an international
consortium of minority cyber security
professionals alice in cyberspace is
close to my heart because it's based in
new jersey and it's an event that
happens every year
for women in security girls go cyber
start for any of the younger folks who
might still be in school or in college
looking at cyber careers or just messing
around with some like fun ctfs
and also i have a diane initiative dave
security empower her as well
i'm going to while we're here i will
copy these links for anybody in the
audience
because they are blogs they are
playlists they are a great way to start
collecting some information and let me
know if guyana initiative allows me to
post this much out
um
faqs to getting started in cti
how you move from journalism to cti
discovering a pathway um they are all
really important narratives and
different experiences of folks who got
into threat intelligence
and once you're ready to really like
dive in and mess around learn about
tools learn about frameworks get some
free resources go to awesome threat
intelligence which is a github
repository by herman he's collected like
so much information it will blow your
mind so you have to know what you're
looking for but really valuable
and then uh the last point ctis sams has
a cti summit every year they publish a
lot of the presentations online so you
get to hear exactly what the cti
discipline
is looking into talking about concerned
about
you know technical research how to be a
better writer all of those content and
that's all on youtube all for free all
public
and finally uh thank you to all the
references for all the important folks
who are doing research that i referenced
earlier in the presentation
thank you so much
so um
if you want to connect and i highly
encourage you you do you can go to
twitter and follow me euphoric fall or
add me on linkedin and my handle is
there grace sg
oh last note while while i'm popping out
and tim you can kind of close out i
don't know if we're in a rush but um
this is something that i created this is
my last plant that i'm sharing with you
guys this is a watercolor so i painted
um and then i folded the papers and then
i plugged it into another one of the
pots that i had actually a leftover
plants for zombie pot um with rocks and
toothpicks and so this is you know my
longest living plant to date
all right if you have any questions feel
free to
connect with me ask them here if i do
miss them here you know go ahead and
ping me on uh social media as well i see
that somebody asked where was the github
repository if you google herman slatman
or just awesome threat intelligence
github it will show up
and yes as tim mentioned
please leave a review
good bad feedback i want to hear it all
go heavy on the good feedback though no
i mean nah i like criticism it's good to
know what to do better for next time i'm
sweating over here actually um the
thunderstorm stopped though so i'm happy
to hear that
my lights flickered for a second so
good still here
um so yeah this was this is really good
is also very interesting there were not
was not a constant feed of questions for
you so you're either very in tuned with
what everyone wanted or
they're sleepy but
they were there were questions so i have
a feeling it was uh you really tuned
into what people are looking forward to
i know i threw a lot out there and one
thing that's important is like sometimes
like even when i was getting started and
you read a blog it's just like so many
so much jargon like so many terms
threat groups you know pick any number
of letters and and symbols and that's
kind of like your reading and it feels
like gibberish and it's really
overwhelming like at the end of the day
understand the foundations even if
you're not working in threat until if
you're in security understanding threat
intel is really important so like why
are you doing that and then from there
kind of learn each component
and i'm reading some i i didn't get to
catch everyone's comments earlier i
think a lot of people just like the
plans and i'm happy to hear that like
should i do that again in my future
presentations show more of my crafts my
arts and crafts and my paintings
definitely
should do more plants
okay second here at the end to you know
say very you know big thank you to all
of our wonderful sponsors that make this
possible and uh danish
would not happen uh without without them
so i don't know if
they're still open but if they are go
check them out at the event expo
and here's a little way you can get to
them i just posted in chat
and um
yeah there we are
and
i see
by the way just about for charlie said
make it a wall to background
i encourage you to add me on any social
media platform and then ask me about my
pokemon sprite wall i literally a
thousand pokemon sprites in my living
room i will send you a picture
all right great um
thank you everyone great questions
perfect yeah
oh and thank you ryan i see ryan
chapman's in this chat i really
appreciate that he's saying nice things
about us ryan's also awesome i think he
had some talk so make sure you check
that out and i think i don't know if i'm
allowed to share but you're working on
some really interesting course work
where you might want him as your
instructor in the very near future
[Music]
don't forget to check out the uh closing
talk here at the end of the day
and it has been a pleasure it's been a
pleasure for me listening to this uh to
to your your presentation and i i thank
you on behalf of everyone who can't
actually speak in chat right now so
thank you i appreciate that
and while we you know we are up i think
a bunch of folks were sharing uh their
own information there's no shortage of
resources in threat intelligence it's
just it's very disjointed so if you have
links feel free to send them in too um i
know somebody mentioned miter attack all
of that is open source
do your own research there defend was
also released recently by mitre
different group but related um
all good avenues to start but if you
feel
like way overwhelmed by what all of
these you know different stages and
terminology means just step back and
just start looking at some blogs start
following some influencers in the space
and then kind of curate your own
intelligence that way as you're learning
and say the number one problem you
almost
could boil everything down to
is a vocabulary issue is if you move
past that word that you do not
understand
whether it's you know just an acronym or
a specific word in a report
you're
going to have a misconception
about everything you learn beyond that
that builds upon it
so that's uh
awesome advice
yeah
and there's a lot of uh
a lot of acronyms a lot of abbreviations
and even group to group organization
organization they don't always agree or
there's aliases up the wazoo so
never feel like you know you don't know
something
google is your best friend
and uh
also asking people and building your
network people who do know also your
best friend
i think i have a newton's telecom
dictionary version 1 billion i just keep
growing
sweet all right um should we call it
here and then everybody can migrate on
over to the closing session uh yeah i
think so uh so everyone if you were
still here well thank you for staying
and now
go over to the um
the rest of the either that not the expo
center the main stage
or the socialization area and
get your last few linkedin contacts
connected
and be here for the the closing and
thank you so much
and thank you so much grace
all right
you