okay hello happy saturday everyone i
hope everyone is doing very well on this
blended day today we have mary ann with
us who is going to present on secure
coding i'm very excited and looking
forward to this presentation i just want
to say thank you to our sponsors as well
and she's going to take it away and i
will sign off
hello everyone and welcome to diana
initiative and we'll be talking about do
your developers write super secure
coding
presentation will be discussing
projects and secure coding through all
the phases of the software development
lifecycle
and are your developers writing super
secure coding
and we'll be discussing all the tools
they need to be super
topics discussed will be
secure coding guidelines best practices
secure cutting standards
and checklists
and how to use them throughout the the
agile team meetings as well as care
cutting trainings and certifications
now we all probably know what these
terms mean secure writing guidelines
best practices and so forth
but not all of our development teams
actually use them or actually know what
they mean
so
let's go ahead and go through these and
make sure that we know as secure coding
practice practitioners actually know
what they mean as well
my bio
i'm actually a senior cyber engineer too
and i've been at raytheon for over 30
years
i've actually been a
cyber engineer for about 10 of those
years i was a software engineer for 20
of them
i have a masters in cyber security and
two certs in secure coding
i work with
programs and help them with the sca
process and sca tools and help them to
analyze their issues
and that's why i'm giving this
this
demonstration or this discussion on
tools and secure coding because i've
kind of found a problem with some of our
programs that say hey we're going to do
this but
i'm not seeing it being done
and so
even though
their requirements say they are
they don't always do it and so i have to
kind of help
a lot
so let's start out with the design phase
and how to use guidelines
so
most programs could create their own
coding guidelines
and
if you're going to create your own
coding guidelines for projects
it will really depend on the type of
organization that you are
and it will also depend on the type of
software you develop or the languages
that you use and that will depend
really on
or why
because it depends on
how complex or if you have to use
specific securities
or house your safety and so
coding guidelines are very
very specific to if it's safety if it's
hipaa if it's pii
so things related to coding guidelines
are for like
coding style understandability and
readability
but if you have
things for
languages and so forth related to those
as well
it's going to get a little bit more
hairy
but coding guidelines can also make it
so that your code is
your code may be too difficult to
understand so a secure coding guideline
can make it more easy and all of your
code could be
similar in readability
and once you have your coding reviews if
everybody's code is
designed the same way
it would make it easier to have your
code reviews
if your code is well documented
and you have a developer leave the next
person who picks up your code
that would make it easier for a new
developer or another developer to pick
it up and be able to fix something if
your code is not documented well
well
you understand i mean i've got programs
that have been around for 20 years
luckily i've got developers who've also
been around 20 years
so
in that case it's
a little bit easier to
fix that code but when some of those
developers leave some of these newer
newer developers are going to have
problems if that code is not well
documented
also having functions that are way too
large
oh my lord you have to talk about
spaghetti code i've seen some of those
and unfortunately i also though some of
those legacy programs that they did not
want to fix that code
but if you
i really wanted to fix some of it and
because i found errors and they said
nope fix that one line
and i finally left a program because
i couldn't handle
some of the code that i found it's like
all of this needs to be fixed nope fix
that one line
i finally left that program and left
went to another one because
i couldn't handle that
um in go to statements trying to debug a
program when you have a failure in a
code that has goto
that is
just problems
do try not to use go to statements that
should be in your guidelines try not to
use go to's
then we go to another guideline um
advantages of using guidelines is
your code if you have increased
efficiency
because everyone is doing the same way
so your your reviews are faster you have
less development time because all of
your code is being done the same way
your reviews are going to be faster and
you may find errors quicker because
everyone is developing the same way
so
another way to do it is using best
practices and making using rules to
make your best practices better but also
using
coding standards and there are many
coding standards that can be used
as well
that can help you in your design phase
some of the best practices that can be
used for your design phase would be
commenting and documentation
making sure that you actually comment
and document
but a lot of
code in my static code analysis
trying to figure out sometimes
some of these
errors that i come across
code that is doesn't even have a header
and it's like what the heck does this
file do
is it even their code is it
somebody else's code what what does this
code do
there's no documentation no commenting
no nothing
i don't even know what this variable
does
you really need to have some kind of
documentation in a function some kind of
something
but
there's some programs that just have
nothing that is a best practice people
you really need it
and it makes it easier when you have
problems or even for new people like i
said to pick something up
consistent indentation
if you have code that has multiple
indentations
sometimes even a static code analysis
will tell you
hey this is an indented write
and you go to look at it it will
actually
i've got some that is indented
completely off and it'll you'll have an
if else that is completely not right
and i'm going they just
it's because they indented it wrong and
it was just really off
and so making sure that consistently
indenting make sure people are using
always in your program using always
using spaces or always using tabs ooh i
know i know everybody wants to use one
or the other but as long as you're
consistent that's the way to go
um i know some people always want to use
tabs it's cleaner but some people always
want to use spaces
consistent namings
there's still people that want to always
put an i before an integer they always
want to put an s before a
string as long as you have a consistent
naming scheme
and make sure your names are not
30 characters long
i mean come on people i'm still finding
some like that in some of the code i'm
reviewing
that's just really overkill
and avoid deep nesting again some of
those if else statements
that
i'm sorry i'm not doing their code
reviews i'm just doing the sca's but i'm
finding some of those and
avoiding the deep nesting those that
that kind of code could actually be
simplified i'm sure
there has to be a way to make that
simplified and
there has to be a way
because usually that means that you just
keep adding
cases as you've gone down and oh we
found another we found another we found
another there's there's got to be a way
limit line length limit the line length
to 80 characters you go to try to print
a print your file i'm sorry i'm old
school
um
when i would go to review
something i go print it and then i would
check it
but if
something is over 80 characters in
length like i've seen some
and it starts wrapping
try to look at that code and you try to
debug something like that
especially some of the c sharp code i've
been looking at lately
okay um yeah that gets kind of hairy
so make sure that your line length is
not because you've just
compressed all of your commands onto one
line
and then capitalizing sql statements now
that's good common practice that's so
that you can that jumps out at you
that's a sql command you know that
because sql commands
are capitalized
avoiding magic numbers
don't just assign a magic number don't
assign a number to something and don't
and without commenting on it if you've
got a comment as associated with a
number
assigned to a variable at least that
will tell someone
when you leave the company
that this number
is assigned because of
its
it was assigned because of this reason
because if for some reason that number
needs to change at least they know why
it was assigned in the first place
if it's just assigned and nobody knows
why
and it fails for some reason down the
road
hey we need to change that number now
why was it assigned in the first place
nobody knows
well if there was a comment associated
with it they would know why it was
assigned in the first place
so
if there's a reason for assigning other
than just initialization
for
zero
or true false something like that
that's
that's avoiding avoid magic numbers
always validate your input for any kind
of external data sources
again just a normal common best practice
any input coming into your
your your code should always be
validated
whether it's input strings characters
you know make sure that your your
numerics
anything coming in if even if it's
network values um something
coming in as path data make sure that
it's size wise everything is in is
validated people
don't just say oh it's
it's coming in from our our software we
know it's it's valid
no always validate your input
because you don't know
someone might have put something
in from another source
error handling and logging
ugh
that's been one of our biggest things
this weekend i think is logging
and some error i've heard some error
handling
but a lot of a lot of the code that i've
been seeing lately is also a lot of
error handling is missing
and so make sure that your code is
catching errors
a lot of programs that have been around
for years all of a sudden static
analysis is catching errors
really ah that error is never going to
happen
oh but it could
so put an error handler in there to
catch it otherwise your code could crash
and what happens if it could
oh that could go down not a very good
thing
why don't you put the error handler in
just in case
use the compiler's highest warning level
okay
now
maybe you don't want to do that because
okay you're gonna all of a sudden start
getting warnings that you never got
before
but
what are you using now
are you using the lowest morning level
i can almost guarantee you that most of
our developers are probably trying to
use the lowest one they can
but i don't know
check check with your developers check
to see what their warning levels are set
to
deny access by default yeah that's one
of those that's like um
what do people say
do you
check the conditions you know
do you always allow access do you always
exclude you know what what should your
code do
you know it depends on the the code
what what what is it depends what the
code's supposed to do so that one is
kind of one of those that you know
that's where the best practice is
okay
your code has to do one
or the other but deny access by default
that's one of those that's like oh okay
it says always deny access by default
yes that's supposed to be the case
another best practice is using a style
guide
formatter a beautifier and a style
checker
and those actually would make your code
beautified
makes everything pretty and lined up
indented
that's okay
as long as you don't have legacy code
thousands hundreds of thousands lines of
code like i do
i don't think i want to run something
like this against some of ours
because
i'm not sure what this would break
but if you've got new code
something running something like this
against your
against new code to make everybody's
code the same
this is a great idea
because
you know this would make it so that
everybody's is the same
and it would make it so that everything
is
following a standard format
these are some example
style guide checkers the beautifiers the
formatters
there's you know different languages
um
there's some for every language you can
think of everything from python to c
to
c plus plus
um
vb java
there's linters
everything in here
now like i said
at my site we don't use any of these
because a lot of our code is legacy so
we don't use these
but these were actually given to me by
another sort another source so
they say that these are great
so and and recommended that they that to
use these
for instance
this is great code this would work
but
in case of looking at code that looks
like this
oh no this is
i'm sorry
if i saw a code that looked like this
i would
throw that person
and no i i would throw them out of class
if if they were in a class that i had
because this is not
well formatted code i'm sorry
now that's a good good one for like
a for a
formatter or a beautifier
that would
then make it nice and pretty and well
formatted and if there was a problem
with the code would be found
very easily
because this you could find it
and
a static code analysis tool would make
it much easier to find sorry it went off
the page i couldn't put it all on one
page and make it readable
so now we're getting to standards
secure coding standards are used to
prevent introduction of security
vulnerabilities
okay
we all understand
security vulnerabilities or at least we
should
so
examples
one example of a security
standard
is the sei certs
down here at the bottom of the page is
a link to the sei
website
where you can actually download two
downloadable books
the
cutting standard for c and c plus plus i
have both of those printed out at my
desk because i am
c and c plus plus
uh coding standard
certified professional i actually
completed that cert that is one of the
secure cutting certification
that i do have i also have the white hat
certified secure coding professional
certification
um but actually at that site they also
have the sei coding standards for
android java perl
um but that site actually
a lot shows you all of the standards
from from sei
for all of these and they explain
each
of the different throughout each of
these languages
the standards and how to make sure that
a
vulnerability would not get into your
code
how to write
good secure code
now
it is
a little difficult for a
new developer maybe to
understand
and that is
probably
why
someone who is
unfamiliar with cnc plus plus maybe to
try to get
one of these professional certs
but
we did have some of our more advanced
developers follow the
just the regular cnc plus plus sei
training they came in and gave the boot
camp in our
building
so um you can actually
take the class and get the regular
regular cnc plus training as well i have
that link at the end of this
another coding standard is the nvd
coding standards now these
are the national vulnerability database
and it contains
links to perform analysis on the common
vulnerabilities and exposure cves
and associate cves
to
cvss
cwes and cpes
now this this database
or this standard um is a link to a whole
bunch of different
associated um
[Music]
standards and vulnerabilities and it's
it can tell you
a lot of different
vulnerabilities and
um
it can tell you how things all
interconnect and
how
one weakness can
link to another and how one
platform can link to one other
vulnerability and so forth
so
trying to use this by itself is
not a complete but it is part of
your
process
then we go to the cve website
um the cve website is
where the common
vulnerabilities and exposure the cves
can actually give you
a
list of the vulnerabilities
and give you examples of
fixes
in many languages
and
this is a site that
in
my job i've actually pointed several of
our developers
to how to fix some of their issues
because
it actually
we use coverity in our job in my job and
as a static code analysis tool and it
does have a link to cves
and for those developers who are newer
to
some of the languages and may not
understand
how to fix something
if
um they
may not
want to come they don't feel comfortable
coming to either myself or one of my
associates
i have pointed them to the cve database
and said and there are some samples um
on that database and if that doesn't
help you still come to me
and we can talk through
and
we can actu i can actually maybe show
you how to fix it
um
and so we've
we've actually
gone through the cv database and found
some examples on how to fix some of the
some of the issues
for
some of the problems we've had
okay um the other way to do it is
actually having programs or projects
create a their own
secure coding standard
at the end of my presentation i have a
link to
a project specific
secure coding standard document it a doc
that i found um
and it
links you to whether you're going to use
sei whether you're just going to use cwe
whether you're going to
use
uh style checkers whether you're going
to do this whether you're going to do
that
um
if you're going to include
high risks if you're going to do
specific things
and it actually was i thought a very
well thought out document
and um
like i said i've got a link to that
document at the end of my spreadsheet if
anyone is actually interested in it
it is at the end of my doc at the end of
my document
okay um for for reviews when you get to
code reviews for secure code reviews
if you do agile processes
sprint planning
sprint reviews do you include secure
coding reviews
such as manual code reviews or automated
code reviews and you track them
track this information in a tool like
azure
a manual code review
now
don't get all up in arms at me when i
say manual code review in this case
it's not what a lot of security people
think as a manual code review a manual
code review in this case is not going
through all the code and finding every
flaw that can be found
at this time
and every link that could be
evaluated
a manual code in this time frame means
just reviewing the code that was changed
at this time
for instance
um
this is doing a manual code when you
don't have
say azure set up
you're not doing an automated when
you're using jenkins or azure tfs azure
and
so this is a little bit different than a
normal manual code review
and you're thinking of a security review
this is this is a true code review i'm
going back to my old days here
um so who should attend these type of
reviews
someone with definitely someone with
domain experience you need someone that
understands
when someone made a change to this
code
did this code change
actually do any damage
um so someone with domain experience she
really should always check these reviews
so someone
hire up like a
um
a tech lead or someone someone
like a tech lead should always attend
these
i a
junior developer
should always probably attend these
and
have
your security personnel should start
should should probably attend these as
well
and then have code review checklists
the code review checklist we'll discuss
in a little bit but
if you use a code review checklist
we'll discuss why to use a code review
checklist but
um
this
this process is going to make it a
little bit easier
so doing a manual code review
if you do manual code reviews you find
logic errors and flaws where you might
find them in the design in the
architecture
and you
um
you find
you add room
um that
you have room for extra set of
experienced eyes you don't have just a
um
automated person an automated code
checking it you have experienced people
checking it plus you have
a
security person in there you have absent
knowledge you have people
that
like us reviewing it
the cons okay you have to have somebody
like i said you have to have a security
person
but you also need somebody that is
experienced with language and frameworks
in there
so um
you you have a little bit of a con in
there and then
if you're not using the checklist you're
going to get different reports so
that's why
i say you might want to use a checklist
because otherwise
it's not going to come you're not going
to have same reviews
so what should your checklist be
if you're going to use a checklist for a
program
probably should be language neutral
because i don't know about you but a lot
of my programs use multiple languages
i've got some that go
v b c c plus plus c sharp dot net
all on the same program
so
if they're going to have a checklist
it's probably going to be really
language neutral
have a plan of approach to approve code
changes
make sure that you always know it's only
going to be this amount of time
it's going to
include um this certain amount of things
um
don't over
don't overdo it people just
always include certain amount of
of topics
sections for a checklist
include things like exception handling
um auditing and logging
i mean you guys can all read all of
these but you know
make sure that you're you're verifying
that if you're in these sections
or it neat or or a section should have
these
maybe you should say hey
in the future maybe we should add these
i mean i know if you're only adding one
line you don't want to go in and say hey
you needed to add this no we don't
always want to add code
just because hey there wasn't an
exception handler you needed to add it
because we all know that if you add too
much code you're going to break
something
but you might want to add a new cr to
say hey in the future you might want to
add an exception handler to this section
and get it reviewed
at a later date
so other things like a general
libraries make sure your libraries are
up to date yeah
sensitive data hasn't been identified
okay that's something your security
person
is gonna have to make sure
layered security okay
that one's a little bit harder unless
your security person is familiar with
the design
some of these cryptography
input validation okay yeah some of these
are
are you checking for special characters
validating numeric input
we like we talked about earlier input
restricted to known characters
we talked about that earlier
checking
your inputs
authorization
um some of these
are you actually
checking are do you have things where
you have a url where you actually have
session cookies do you have
acls
where you actually have to authenticate
so now we're going to an automated code
review
so automated code reviews you can use
full code coverage
or nearly i i know not all
sdas can do full code coverage
but i have uh like my coverity i some of
my coverity can do almost full code
not i've got some that don't go all the
way but you can use tools like coverity
and fortify
and run it during an automated build and
best time to do
most the time is is when you're doing
the building development and run nightly
or when you're adding i have some that
run nightly
because they add code all the time
and then i have some that only run when
they add code to their
scm
some
and that's because
they add code so on
infrequently that
they don't need to run nightly they may
add code
once every other week
so coverity
just needs as an example for those that
aren't familiar
coverity you know as an sca tool helps
find
security and quality issues
and can be used to track um
across the application
and in
it can mute
with cyber and security working together
can be used to fix find and fix issues
that are found
and it supports 21 languages
looks similar to this with the dashboard
being on the side
and then the code in the middle
and then the triage window on the right
side
fordify
we have had some programs trying to use
fortify
haven't really had much luck getting too
much out of it yet
but you can get a prioritized result
again with by severity of risk you can
fix vulnerabilities with cyber and
software working together
and it supports 26 languages
its usage
looks like something like this
the
um cover there are some desktop static
analysis tools which coverity is one
and then desktop or developers can run
it from their desktops while
doing their development
and that way they can actually find
issues while they're actually doing
their development
and
if they actually inject issues they can
actually fix them
before they actually get sent up to the
desktop or excuse me sent up to the web
server
and that way you don't actually inject
issues all the way up
if you fix them
in earlier in the pipe in the the chain
and so
if you if you find or them earlier
you don't you inject
fewer issues and
fine
you can actually fix
issues earlier
but you can also fix maybe some that as
you're working on code if you see that
there's an issue related
to what you're working on say you are
working on
a line of code and there's a coverity
issue related to that you can actually
fix something related to that at the
same time and fix multiple coverity
issues at the same time
so it's we're we've got um
one program that's actually
doing that right now and they're
they're
injecting less issues and fixing more at
this fixing multiple issues
so it's
it's actually
working fairly well
so um the pros for doing an automated
code review is
it
it detects and
it may detect low hanging fruit and it
it may find a lot of vulnerabilities
um
but i it says that there may be a lot of
of
false positives but i truly have not
found a lot of false positives
um
not in a lot of our code
you can test quickly and have large
large large chunks of code
it's very important to do it in an agile
environment
um
to be able to test over and over and
over
and if you can do something like
static code analysis and be able to do
it in an automated environment
and
this is this is really the way to go is
to be able to have
the
to be able to run on schedule and then
on demand and then
it's we've got program i've got
something like 20 programs running this
way so it can be customized
be able to use all kinds of different
standards
but i've got it so that it's it's
running this way now
um cons it does say there's false
positive negatives but
really i'm not seeing very many
um
it does depend on the type of the tool
you have a learning curve
it did i have been doing it for over 10
years
so this i mean i was i was dumped into
it that was my first job as a as a
security cyber security person so
that was my first job so i have been
doing it for a while
um
so if it's it's also not viable for all
budgets so
you might try an open source tool if you
can afford like coverity and fortify
luckily we have a corporate license so
that's why we can do it
but we also had to merge
all the data from one
server over to my
companies
and
my building and i am now manager for
that server so
that's why it's now my job
another
secure coding tool is code quality tools
but
using code quality tools like sonar cube
and style cop you can use you can find
code quality tools
within your compiler
and you can find issues
and make your code better
quality because even your static
analysis tool will find quality issues
but if you can use stone sonar cube and
style cop to find those issues
earlier on
they would make your code better
and
less issues later on down the road and
they can be used during your manual code
review so that if you don't have an
automated build you can still use center
cube
and style cop as just the desktop
versions
center cube has
25 languages
they have they they can find bugs
are which are errors that break
your code vulnerabilities
your codes open to attack and then code
smells
just makes your code more confusing as
what it says
looks pretty much like this
that's what i thought was very
interesting it actually can do it for
cobol and how many of us actually still
remember cobol
and
stylecop
can be set up
to run during a visual studio build
and it can be run automatically from
tfs or
jenkins i actually have
two programs now that actually run it
from azure
and it can be run through
a desktop mode in visual studio
it looks like this if you actually have
it run
through your desktop mode
when you click on one of those issues in
the fir the previous page you get the
actual error
and it said this is
the cause and the rule description
some of the training that can be found
for secure coding include things like
the certified secure software lifecycle
professional which is my next cert
i'm actually been studying for that
the
sci cert secure coding in java
professional sci secure coding in java
the sans develop defending web
applications
the seo secure coding and cnc plus plus
which i said that was the one that they
came out and did the the boot camp in
our building and then the sei cert
and secure coding and cnc plus
professional cert that was the other one
that i already have
and then there's this game
this is an amazing game by secure code
warrior
and it it was so much fun i had
it was it was just a blast
um
you actually go in and you actually have
to go and find
the
problem
that they are talking about in each of
the different languages and each
each threat is a different language so
you want you might have jabba ruby
um
c sharp.net you might
each one was different um i am i had a
15-day trial that i played with
and but since i'm pretty presenting at
four different conferences
i didn't get much time to play with it
but it was an amazing game to play
so i really recommend this secure code
warrior
it was um it was amazing
so um
again this is the
the
checklist
i mentioned
um
and some of the
the secure coding standard
some of the other
trainings
and there's hack.edu that's the the
training
that i just showed you
but
that's it
so if you have any questions
okay
thank you everyone um i really
appreciate that talk mary ann and thank
you to our sponsors we're gonna be going
to a lunch break um and that was really
excellent
thank you