hey all my name is bree helton and i'm
here for diana initiative uh 2021 on the
virtual event and we're excited to
present another talk here on stage two
today
uh first off i want
i just want to thank our speakers uh and
our sponsors uh for our sponsors this
year we have elearn security uh noxus uh
mongodb juniper corelight google
uh and bridge crew uh with us today i'm
all basically sponsoring this event and
the tracks and such uh give them your
thanks and feel free to visit any of our
exhibitors today over in our exhibit
hall and give them a lot of love and
attention there in addition to that we
have an exciting amount of ctfs going on
today i believe we're at three or four
at this particular point in time so
after these talks are in between talks
if you want to catch a ctf and
participate virtually feel free to hop
on over there and such
um i just want to introduce our speaker
for today
and our speaker is megan carney and she
is here on the stream um she'll be
having a talk today entitled
uh bobbing for apples developing alerts
for mac os
um and so in this talk she'll be uh
giving a bit about herself and the
actual topic at hand she's a security
analyst and bad news giver in several
different environments over the past 10
years or so she's currently employed
with target and she spends most of her
time searching for places that badness
might be and can often be found staring
into the abyss and it's true the best
stares back at you and as a fellow
beefer analyst i spend a lot of time
also staring into the abyss and uh yeah
it really does stare back into you which
gives you a great place to get bad news
from and kind of bring to other people's
attention to introduce it to them um
it is really um so i'm going to hand it
off here to uh megan thank you very much
hey everyone um so i really wish i could
be in person and see all of your smiling
faces
but that wasn't in the cards this year
so i just want to encourage people to
ask questions or
if you have comments you can find me
later on twitter
as i go through the slides i just want
people to know i am gonna post these
online and i will put the link on my
twitter feed
so
that's not a flex like i'm okay if you
subscribe or follow me for two days get
the slides and then disappear that's
cool with me i just you don't have to
copy down the details
as we go through the slides
all right cool i think that's
housekeeping stuff so
about me um so you know where i come
from
i
have been doing infosec stuff for
10 years or
and a few now
mostly on the blue team side of the
world though i've also done
some like light penetration testing
consulting sort of stuff
and for the past few years i've been
focusing on
mac os stuff because i don't
it just feels like an area that not
enough people are working on
and one of the problems that i found oh
sorry there we go
is that
macs are just harder to manage at scale
and i think if you talk
without mac admins and i've talked with
our team at target a little bit
there's just not as many tools available
for people to use
and they're
not they're just not as mature which
means if you're
managing a bunch of macs within your
enterprise it's just
not as easy and this isn't just true
for
things like managing settings
it's also true for security tools
so just getting logs to a central sim is
harder so if you know anything about
mac os
over you know the past few years
first there was syslog but then syslog
went away and then there were apple
system logs and now we have unified logs
but
ever since syslog went away
there hasn't been a built-in way to send
logs to a central location
and a lot of alerting depends on sending
so it can be
a really difficult problem
and given all that it's not really a
surprise
that most security orgs don't focus on
max i mean i get it windows machines are
still a larger target for malware
authors you know we all know mac malware
exists we all know that it can be
dangerous
but
there's still a larger number of windows
malware samples out there
and because the tool sets are less
mature it does require more effort if
you're going to set up alerting or start
writing custom alerts for your macs
so
why am i here today
talking about
mac alerting if it's a more difficult
thing to do when it requires a lot of
effort
so the truth is your macs are probably
tied into the same environment as the
rest of your windows machines
so
they're tied into the same domain
they're accessing the same file shares
and if you're in a large org
and maybe two percent of your machines
are max
that's still a lot of machines right
were
and it's completely possible for your
max to be compromised and for that to be
a foothold into taking down the rest of
your network
so
we know in infosec
and this is really
common wisdom
that
your security is only as strong as your
weakest link
and if you ask any cso they'll agree
with this
but it's curious how many companies
just don't monitor entire segments of
their network and i'm not just talking
about mac os here though that's a
problem it's also things like linux
machines
like do you have monitoring on your
linux servers
and
i think it's important
to
think about all of the operating systems
on your network and what you're covering
so today i'm going to focus on mac os
but i completely realize that mac os is
not the only operating system that has
this problem
so you might be thinking
well i have antivirus i have some sort
of ids sitting on my network
why should i be doing more than that
and
this isn't a dig to vendors i'm not
saying that vendors are terrible or that
all their products are terrible but
vendors aren't everything if you are
mcafee if you're sofos you have to tune
your detection based on all of your
clients
and what all of their environments look
like
if you are writing detection for your
environment
you can tune detection based on
how you know your org runs
and your org's appetite for risk
so if you're say a nuclear power plant
you might have a really low appetite for
risk if you're
i don't know a small startup maybe your
appetite for risk is larger or smaller
so if you're writing your own detection
you can really tailor me your alerts to
your environment and there are some big
advantages there that a vendor just
can't offer you
and you can also create
trip wires to make it more difficult
for an attack in your environment to
succeed
so you've probably heard the phrase an
attacker only has to be right once a
defender has to be right all the time
and while that is technically true i
think what gets lost in that discussion
is that you as the defender
control the attacker's playground
and there are always choke points or
tripwires that you can set up to make
their job more difficult
in particular
i think we need to redefine success and
i know this has also been talked about a
lot but
do not assume
that your prevention measures are going
to be 100 accurate
something is always going to get past
your spam filter some piece of malware
is always going to find its way into
your environment so the question is
are you going to find that piece of
malware early when it's an easy problem
to solve or are you going to find it
later when it's a really big problem to
solve
and the way you find it early is by
looking for these choke points so for
any operating system i'm talking windows
macs linux unix whatever
there are only so many ways to set up
an auto run job there are only so many
ways to move data in and out of the
network
and if you look at your configuration
and your machines and your network you
can start saying things like well we
don't use startup items
cool
so i can create an alert for if any
startup item is added and you can go
down the list for all the persistence
mechanisms and really tailor your
alerting to your environment
so hopefully i've made the case that
custom alerting might be a thing worth
doing in your environment
so let's talk about some of the
difficulties you might face in building
a program like this
um
so in terms of my background and
i became a detection engineer a year or
two ago i don't remember exactly but
before that
i was an incident response and i was
dealing with a lot of mac stuff and i
was super excited to come over and be a
detection engineer and i thought i'm
just going to go play in the data i'm
going to find some alerts to write it's
going to be this really great technical
work
and it is like the technical work is
interesting
but looking back
it was really naive of me to assume that
this would just be a technical challenge
it is also a people challenge and it's
also an organizational challenge
because
writing alerts is not something you do
in a vacuum
it's something that i need other
people's support for and it's something
that the engineering has to be set up
for
so when you're talking about increased
visibility
it's not always pleasant
when you start setting up new pipelines
when you start bringing in new data
you're gonna find some stuff that looks
gross
some of it's dangerous gross some of
it's just gen and some of it's just
gross
but
be prepared to find some things that you
probably didn't want to know
and on top of that
you're probably going to find
some departments in your organization
that have been creatively solving
problems in ways that are not
great
and
if you can
work with these departments to find
better ways to
get the job done so that they're not
creating noise for you when you're
writing alerts
because a messy environment
is really hard to write good alerting on
if you have a lot of false positives if
you have say
i don't know your entire
mac fleet is being managed by shell
scripts running out of
user directories that's going to look
really sketchy
and you probably want to see if there's
a better way to do that
um
so once you have the data coming into
alert on the next stage
and this is more organizational stuff
is looking at
incident response
and the engineering
and the engineering side of it
so
as i was sort of alluding to earlier i
cannot write alerts in a vacuum i cannot
work alerts in a vacuum like the work i
do as a detection engineer writing
alerts to find badness on our network on
mac os machines
only works because i have other people
on my team
and those other people are mainly
incident response and engineering and in
particular these feedback loops like
communicating with these other
departments and really listening to
the difficulties they're having
that's especially important
with incident response
incident response
needs to
know how to do basic forensics and if
you
are spinning up alerting in mac os and
your team hasn't really done a lot of
mac os forensics before
that's something that you need to
support it might not be you working on
it
but before you roll out your first mac
alert you need to make sure that at
least some portion of your incident
response team knows how to deal with
that
and the other part of this is not just
you telling them
you know information it's them telling
you information too
i
so i've been doing
writing alerts in some form or another
for a few years now like
i switched to this position and i
started to focus on it but i've been
doing it for a few years now
and
i am continually surprised
by the alerts that work and the alerts
that don't
and sometimes
something i've had in testing for two
months looks great
i roll it out and something changes and
all of a sudden there's a bunch of false
positives
and i cannot afford to just ignore
incident responders when they tell me
that because if an alert triggers too
many false positives it will be ignored
that is completely human and completely
natural
and as the person who's managing these
alerts it's important that i'm listening
to
what happens when they actually get
rolled out and responding to people's
concerns and to the extent i can
filtering them or fixing them or in some
cases just saying
that was a nice idea but i don't think
it's going to work
and in addition to incident response
it's also
important to remember
that all of the alerts i write
sit on top of an engineering
infrastructure
and
that's work that i cannot do all by
myself and those are also teams
that i need to work with
and the tools that we're given to work
with i
this isn't going to be news to everyone
but if you haven't worked in infosec
um or you've never had like a job where
you regularly have to deal with a sim or
a central management tool
it is surprising how often
tools are not as good as they were
advertised to be
or they have really
weird little quirks that you just have
to discover on your own and then
understand that maybe in this situation
this tool or this sim isn't going to
give you the answer you're expecting
so
especially when you're rolling out new
pipelines or new data sources
you have to learn your tools you have to
test them
so
let's say you have a vendor that's
promised you they're going to do process
detection and you can write alerts
inside their system to say if a process
runs out of temp and has these other
specifications
then i want you to alert
you should test
by creating that process
or testing as much as you can to make
sure the alert fires as you expect
because there will be gremlins there but
there will be weirdness and you can't
just assume that everything works
and if you're lucky you get a bonus team
and at target we're lucky um we have
something called a hunt team yeah excuse
me just need to
so i don't know if this is true for
anyone else
but since i've been working at home my
voice is not used to speaking for long
periods of time
anyway
back to the presentation
so we are really lucky at target we have
a hunt team
and
even if you don't have a hunt team you
can still set up a hunt week and these
are really useful to test theories
so one of the coolest hunts
that i've done
is we just sat in a room for a week and
looked at what are all the ways
that
lateral movement happens
in mac os environments and how can we
detect those in other words let's turn
on remote apple events and see what the
unified logs look like
can we write some sort of detection for
that is there some sort of say sensor we
can write so after an incident happens
can i scan the environment to see if
remote apple events were used
and this isn't just about lateral
movement if there's a particular piece
of malware that you know it's really
important for you to catch
running that in a controlled environment
and then making sure you know what sort
of artifacts are created
and therefore what you need to search
for those are all super valuable
exercises so based on our hunt weeks and
based on open source information
i'm going to share with you
some alerts that worked for us
so all of these required some testing
and some tuning
but they've all worked in our
environment with relatively good
signal-to-noise ratios
of course your mileage may vary um
because your environment is different
and that's kind of the point of doing
custom alerting you you can really
tailor the alerts to your environment
and catch things early and create those
choke points that we talked about a
little bit ago
uh but before i get into talking about
specific alerts
i want to talk about
how i evaluate alerts
so
when you're trying to figure out to
whether or not you want to implement an
alert or not
definitely false positive
rates and false negative rates are
important and i don't like i'm not
telling you to ignore them
but you also want to factor in risk and
overall volume
so i've made up my answers for this
chart your answers might be a little
different than mine
but when i think about an alert that has
a high false a high false positive rate
but the malware that that alert finds
indicates a very bad day
i might implement it anyway depending on
how often it fires right
if it's firing once a day that's
probably still too much
if it fires once a year even if 50 of
those are false positives then maybe
it's worth implementing
and again your answers might be
different i just want to encourage you
to think beyond you know this has a 50
false positive rate or this has a 90
false positive rate and also factor in
the risk and how often that alert
actually fires
and as a side note you probably have
noticed this presentation as she-ra
themed
if you haven't watched she-ra i highly
recommend it super cool
um
yeah all right
so moving on to
evaluating alerts
when they fire
responders need to understand what an
alert
means
and i know that sounds a little basic
but
when an alert fires it's important to
understand what stage of an attack
that alert references right
so
incident responders always have a list
of things that they're looking at they
always have a list of tickets that's
coming in and they need to prioritize
those tickets so if your alert
represents an attacker that's actively
in the network that's maybe running
recon that's already established a
foothold
it's important to know that versus maybe
this piece of malware got delivered but
it hasn't been executed yet
it's also important to know what types
of malware use this technique so instead
of saying
something bad happened you know this is
used by
ocean lotus for instance
or maybe it's used by bundler
and if you provide that context
it gives people a clue as to where they
should look next
so let's say you fired an alert for
ocean lotus execution
then maybe you can point to some
documentation for here's what the rest
of an ocean lotus infection looks like
so there are spent so the responders can
start to look for artifacts
and confirm that yes this is a problem
or no this was a false positive
all right cool so after that brief
detour um
we'll get to talking about some alerts
that have worked in our environment
and then at the end i'll do a little bit
of a wrap up
and hopefully
after that wrap up there will be time
for questions
uh so suid binaries
for those of you who aren't familiar
with unix's systems
suid binaries are kind of a weird beast
i
i'm not actually sure there's an
equivalent on windows
there might be
anyway
what it means is
that
program
or that executable
when it runs has root permissions
even if the person that executes the
binary
does not have root access
and the reason attackers love these
obviously is because it's something you
can run from user land
but has the privileges of the root user
and
they're also relatively rare
because they are a security risk
i don't know
how far
back
people remember but there was at one
point a pretty serious vulnerability in
one of these suad binaries
and the vulnerability had to do with
being able to parse some command line
things and if they were parsed in
correctly then you could basically
execute arbitrary commands as wrote and
those are the sort of things that suid
binaries if they are not properly built
allow and that's why they're relatively
rare but this is good news for us as
defenders
because we can find their creation or we
can find them sitting on disk so these
two commands these shmod commands
are both process detection things
and if you have os query deployed you
can also use this
query to search for them
i should probably explain a little bit
about os query for people who don't know
about it
so
os query
is a tool that lets you
ask questions about your operating
system as if your operating system were
a sql database
so this select star from suid bin os
query
internally
builds a table called suid underscore
bin which then references suid binaries
present on the system
so it's a really useful tool
particularly for mac os which doesn't
have a lot of tools available right now
so if it's available to you
it's something to consider
the malware that uses
these techniques it's a long list as you
can see below
bundler xcset echelar search mine adware
ocean lotus which is nation state stuff
xcode spy
bella which has been known to be used by
fitting seven
um
so some of this stuff listed here is
adware and i'm gonna talk a little bit
more about that later
but just right now
if it's adware
that doesn't mean you should ignore it
it can still be dangerous and we'll talk
more about that later
another alert that's worked well for us
is the installation of new root
certificates
so
um
certificates are
trying to decide how far in the weeds i
should get if you're not familiar with
how things like say https or
that works
the reason your browser knows to trust a
certain certificate is because it's been
signed
by
one of
the
big organizations that sign certificates
for other companies
but sometimes you as a company are going
to install your own root certificates
like say maybe you're putting in a proxy
that's going to intercept web traffic in
that case you're going to be installing
your own certificate
so that you can man in the middle
traffic in an authorized way
but of course if you are an attacker
being able to man in the middle traffic
in an unauthorized way is also super
useful
and installing a new root certificate
will allow an attacker to intercept and
modify network traffic
without your users ever knowing that
there's a problem
these are the two commands
that look for
installation of new certificates
this is process detection only as far as
i know
um
i think there is a way to list
let me
clarify i know there is a way to list
all the root certificates present on a
system
that data is surprisingly messy
so if it's a short enough list in your
environment that you can list all of
those certificates and say boom done
anything that's not on this list that i
know to be good is bad
awesome
but i suspect that won't be the case
um so anyway you can detect the
installation of new root certificates
using these commands
this is used by doc malware and some
malicious browser extensions
some of which
are look like adware stuff but again
if it's adware it still can be dangerous
particularly if it's intercepting
traffic
even if it's intercepting traffic just
to install ads or say may maybe
redirect traffic to
their favorite search engine
it's still redirecting traffic it's
still a new certificate on your network
all right um
launch agents
so at the beginning i talked about
persistence mechanisms being a good
target for custom alerting
and this one has been really useful for
us
so for people who aren't familiar
with mac os systems
a launch agent
is really just a configuration file and
it says hey
run this every time the system boots or
maybe you run it on a schedule
and launch agents
just have a command in them so
in that configuration file you specify
when the launch agent runs
and then you also specify the command
that gets run
and for most well-behaving applications
that command
is
the binary for that application
but launch agents can use python they
can use perl you can put
a shell script in a launch agent if you
want
and you can even put hidden directories
in a launch agent it just you're just
including a configuration key that
specifies a command to run and what you
put in there is really flexible
one of the most common persistence
mechanisms that we see
in malware is user land launch agents so
there are two versions of launch agents
on mac os
one of them requires privileges to
install and one of them doesn't which
means it's a very attractive target for
malware
and in a lot of cases
they don't want to download their own
binary which is why they're using things
like python and perl
because one of the great things about
mac os and the reason that i have used
it for a long time
is because it's like having a unix
command line but you also get a pretty
gooey attached to it
but all of those things that make it fun
for me to play around on my machine at
home are also tools that attackers can
use
so you can build a full back door in
python
you don't need to install python on a
mac to do that it's already sitting
around basically everything you need is
there
you just need to
get the code down there
sorry that was a bit of my digression
but anyway you can implement this via
yara 6 and it's a pretty basic yara
signature
because these are text files they're
small text files because like i said
they're just configuration files
and you can look for that configuration
key
that specifies the command to run and
then look for
suspicious scripting languages basically
we've seen this used by
multiple fake flash infections
and some other types of malware
all right um another type of persistence
this is going to be a common theme here
uh because i think
that
concentrating on persistence mechanisms
is one of the best ways to do alerting
in your environment
um is cron jobs
so again if you're not familiar with
unix cron jobs are just a way of
scheduling tasks
they're specified in what's a pretty
simple configuration file where you
specify do they run daily monthly
on a specific hour every other week
it's pretty flexible
and because
cron tabs are defined per user
you do not need elevated privileges to
install
a cron tab for the user on that machine
which obviously means as an attacker
it's a great way to establish
persistence
um and
the one of the easiest ways to find
these is with os query
uh with that query that i have there
select star from cron tab
process detection gets a little tricky
here because basically you're looking
for something that edits that
crontab file
and there are a lot of ways to edit a
so
if you do want to do this
via some sort of process detection i
recommend looking for changes to the
crontab files as opposed to looking for
a process that matches a specific
signature and these are the paths that
you would use in that case var a t or
depending on how your tool reports it
system volumes data private var at
cron jobs are known to be used by impair
empire gravity rat qbrat and vind
installer and these are some pretty
heavy hitting pieces of malware so
they're a good target
and especially
if
again you know in your org cron jobs
aren't normally used it's a really good
way to start finding some bad things
another method of persistence
i hope you're sensing a theme here
is doc replacement
and
i am going to link to the blog post
later so you can read about all the gory
details
but sort of the
top level overview here is doc
replacement is the equivalent of link
persistence
on windows
so again you can look at the blog post
later i
it's too much to go into right now
in order to
look for this technique
you can look for changes to file paths
that end with this path right here
library preferences com.apple.plist
um and i say end with because there is a
copy of this file for each user and
there is also a copy at the system level
so if you want to change this file you
can change it in either place
and as a defender
you should be aware that there are two
different places to establish
persistence this way
and we've seen this used by some fake
flash infections
all right i think
that is all
for most of our persistence mechanisms
anyway
and i'm gonna i have a few more alerts
to go through and then we'll get to the
wrap up
the quarantine attribute
is
a really useful bit of information on
mac os
i'm going to explain a little bit about
it just so people who aren't familiar
might have the background
when you download a file via chrome
on your mac machine
it gets the quarantine attribute added
as a piece of metadata basically
and then the internal security features
like gatekeeper or xprotect or their
malware removal tool
look at files with the quarantine
attribute
and because so much
of
mac's internal security tools depend on
that quarantine attribute being present
a lot of malware likes to take that
attribute away
so
the thing that's important to understand
here is the quarantine attribute is just
a piece of metadata
that sits on that file
you do not need root privileges to
remove it
and in fact not everything that gets
downloaded has to have a quarantine
attribute
programs like curl when they download
things don't add the quarantine
attribute
um
but anyway
you can use process detection to find
out when the attribute gets removed and
that's with this x adder command
x adder um
is how you edit attributes
this dash d means delete and
com.apple.quarantine
is the bit of data or if you want to
think of it the key
and that tells gatekeeper and xprotect
that hey this file was downloaded from
the internet so you might want to check
it out
and we've seen this
i say we've um
i should rephrase that it has been
documented that this is used by ocean
lotus and xcset
so some of the things i'm talking about
here
uh what malware uses what technique are
oscent and
i will give you a link to that at the
end
all right
um execution from library scripts is a
sign of malware and it's also relatively
rare
in normal operation
which again good for defenders
and you can just look for processes that
start with this
this is known to be used by snake
malware which is not a long list but
snake is a pretty nasty piece of malware
python i mentioned earlier is a thing
that is sometimes used by launch agents
to
establish persistence and with to
establish persistence without
bringing down your own uh custom binary
or maco executable
this python as a parent of openssl or
osa script is especially suspicious
um
because openssl is something that's used
to do
command line encryption or decryption so
if you're
a piece of malware and you want to pull
down like
an encrypted or obfuscated bit of code
and you want to decrypt it or
de-obfuscate it on the command line you
can use openssl
osa script is another scripting language
that's built in on mac os
that attackers like
because you can pop up really realistic
dialog boxes
using osa script you can pop up things
like hey this installer requires your
password to
proceed and then get the user to enter
their password and then capture it
and users fall for these dialog boxes
not because they're dumb but because
they look really similar to the system
dialog boxes that pop up and say
we need your password um and this
technique is known to be used by bella
evil osx and sh layer which is adware
but again you know don't discount all
adware
and the last alert we're going to cover
today
is deleting unified logs
this is one of my favorite scenes in
shira
but
i should not get distracted all right so
i talked in the beginning a little bit
about how there was syslog and then
there was apple system logs and now
there's unified logs
unified logs can be messy but they are
one of the richest source sources of
information on mac os hosts there are
things that you can find in unified logs
that you cannot find from any other
source
you can access them via the log show
command you can search them
i don't have time in this presentation
to go over
what to look for that was a previous
presentation
but this is precisely why attackers want
to delete them
and if you have elevated privileges
like rope privileges you can delete them
using this log erase command
i don't have any specific groups or
malware that i can put on this slide
but i do
um i did hear an objective by the sea
last year that this was a technique
being used in the wild that attackers
were going through and just
erasing all the logs in the host to hide
their footprints
all right
so it looks like we're pretty good on
time here i'm gonna do a wrap up and
then we should have time
to do some q a
so i've talked about a lot people tell
me i tend to talk fast so
hopefully i didn't overwhelm you too
much
but if you're looking for a place to
start doing mac alerting
i really recommend start with
persistence mechanisms
because even though attackers have a
billion ways to get on to a host there
are only a few ways to persist
and there are only a few ways to persist
that are built into the operating system
right so if you can look for changes to
startup items or
login items or
cron
or
there's a couple others that i'm
that are a little bit
uh
like launch agents and launch demons are
obvious but there's also like
file and folder actions like if you can
nail down
what exists in your environment what is
used by
the people who manage your max or used
by the people who
actually use your macs every day and
then just alert on everything else
that's a really good place to start
common activities done by malware is
also another really good place to start
i mentioned curl earlier
a lot of the malware we see
loves doubt loves to download things
with curl
curl does not add the quarantine
attribute when it downloads a file and
this is one of the reason that malware
really likes to use curl
because if it doesn't have the
quarantine flag it doesn't get scanned
by gatekeeper it doesn't get scanned by
xprotect and that malware can fly right
under the radar um
scripting is another good target for
custom alerting in your environment
so built in on mac os there is python
there is perl there is osa script
there's
a few different kinds of shells
all of these can be used to do scripting
and
patterns like
openssl as a child of python
or other anomalous uses are a good place
to start
looking for bad things
if you're lucky and your users don't
install a lot of software outside of
like your centrally managed catalog
you can look for installs from dmgs
i would say
like 90 of the malware we see
is some infection because a malicious ad
popped up or something like something
popped up on the user's screen saying
you need to upgrade flash
even though flash is no longer a thing
people still click on it people still
download that malicious dmg and then
install software
and recon commands
so just like there's a set of commands
you run on windows to get a feel for
what's running in that environment
like ipconfig who am i um
there's a bunch of commands that malware
tends to run in mac os environments so
who am i which works on both macs and
windows um
ifconfig syscontrol uh listing kernel
extensions like all of those recon
commands if they're not being done
by
the tool that's managing your max it's
probably not a good thing
and
if i were in person this is where i
would get out my soapbox and climb on
top of it
uh i really think
we underestimate adware there's a lot of
stuff that gets labeled as pua or you
know that's just bundler that's just sh
layer
basically
a lot of this adware is a remote access
trojan
with root privileges
and right now it might just be
displaying ads to your user
but it's still a remote access trojan
with root privileges
and these tools regularly update
themselves
that could become anything else anything
else anytime it wants to
and it has root privileges
so
you know if i
wanted to be sneaky if i were i don't
know a nation-state actor
i would
distribute some pua
widely
get it labeled as low risk or hey this
is just adware and then deliver
malicious ads to like the 10 machines i
was concerned about out of the 10 000
that adware was installed on and then
i'm in the environment right
so
if the adware you're looking at has root
privileges
don't discount it just because it's only
displaying ads you still want to get
that out of your environment
all right i think that's the end of my
rant slash soapbox
um
there is a really good reference and i'm
going to put this on the next slide too
this is an article by phil stokes at
sentinel one it just goes over 20 tools
and techniques
that are used by mac os malware and mac
os thread actors
and a bunch of my slides in this
presentation said you know this
technique is used by this actor or this
piece of malware a lot of that
information came from this article
and particularly if you're getting
started in mac os and you don't know
what malware does generally this is a
really good article to start with
all right
so as i said i'm gonna have these slides
available via my twitter feed
maybe
today if i'm motivated or tomorrow
and you can get these links or you can
grab a screenshot right now
there's
a lot being added to mitre specifically
for mac os which is very cool and very
needed
that article on link persistence or
persistence via the doc is on this slide
and that slide where i talked about the
attacker's dilemma and how really as
defenders we have the ability to make an
attacker's life difficult
that's the last bullet here
so the idea is if you know your
environment well if you look at these
choke points if you set up the right
alerts
you can make sure the attacker has to
make noise
and you can find them when they're in
the early stages of their attack
all right um three that is the end of my
slides
hey megan uh we just had a few questions
for you here i'm gonna start with a
really
uh quicker one here uh windows logs have
an event where the logs are deleted and
that gets logged i believe that's uh
1102 if i recall my windows event logs
correctly is there any uh mac equivalent
of that or where basically any of the
logs gets cleared either partially or
just maybe all the logs on the system
um
so i don't actually know what the
unified logs record
when you do that log erase command
that's a
that would be a good thing to look at
one of the annoying things about the
unified logs is there aren't any event
ids
so
you know how in the windows world you
talk about well that's 4795 or that's a
4652 and it makes it really easy
they that is not in the mac os world yet
so
it's unfortunate
gotcha there yeah because i'm used to
for ransomware if you see it occurring
on system like that deletion of uh like
um logs or potenti or more often you
know um the backups and such for
the volume shadows just are just like
the canary in the coal mine for those
types of things so there's just certain
things that you expect and just like yep
that's gonna be alert we're gonna have
really fast um what other questions we
have here we have another question
on uh regarding detection queries um is
there things that can pick up on
precursors to the ransomware like
inhibiting system recovery or backups
such as deleting volume shadow files or
such um just
probably i haven't looked in that
particular direction before
but i imagine
so we don't have volume shadow copies in
mac os at least if there is a thing like
that i don't know about it
but there is time machine
and if you're using time machine and you
want to see
if somebody sent the order to delete all
your time machine backups
that would be a good thing to look for
and if i had to guess i would say it
would be in the unified log somewhere
but i haven't looked for it so i don't
know for sure
gotcha um and then we had another
question for about 20 minutes ago um
when you write detections um when these
binaries are created um
would you suggest as a hunting mission
to review all uh
suid binaries
um yeah i mean those are that's actually
a great point sometimes good hunt weeks
are just
let's look at the behavior of this in
our environment or
you know how many of this widget do we
have how many applications do we have
and see if you can build a good list
and suid binaries should be short
hopefully
gotcha um and just one last question out
of curiosity since you're dealing with
an enterprise environment and such um
somewhere attacks against windows
machines and different types of
environments are all the rage nowadays
and one of the things gets the most
newsworthy stuff are you seeing those
similar trends within the mac ecosystems
within corporate environments from you
or other colleagues or such that you all
are having to worry about ransomware is
it still kind of behind the curve
compared to where the rest of the
industry's at
well i mean there's always
there's been ransomware for max for a
while now um
and i haven't
so in this presentation i haven't talked
about detection for it
but
i did run a ransomware a few ransomware
samples through
for a different experiment a few years
ago
and one of the most reliable indicators
that i saw was number of processes
because that particular piece of
ransomware
would
run a find command
to find all the files it wanted to
encrypt and then spin up a process for
each
for each file it wanted to encrypt to
encrypt that file and so if you see like
a process tree where like it's python
and then it's got a thousand children
then
that's that's what that particular
sample looked like
so
i haven't looked at ransomware
specifically recently but you know it
exists for max it always has
gotcha um i don't see any of the
questions or anything else and we seem
to be at the top of the hour here um so
any less words for us megan
um
yeah
so go forth learn things make me look
bad
and if you have questions that come up
later feel free to find me on twitter or
in chat around the conference
yep and just a note again um megan has
their twitter account here as ponyvan um
listed on there so if anyone's looking
at the slides that is the name of their
twitter and then um thank you very much
for enjoy um taking our session here
and look forward to the next session
coming up and if anyone has any
questions feel free to put them else in
chat and we'll try and get an answer for
you and take a look at anything else
going on the diana initiative today we
have a large number of exhibitors and
ctfs and other events going on today so
it's not just limited to our talks and
such thank you very much and have a good
day