hi everybody welcome back to i think
we're on stage three of the diana
initiative we're super excited to have
you here today
um up next we have rebecca hoffart and
she's going to be talking to us about
inspiring girls
to find pathways to the cybersecurity
pipeline we're super excited to have her
here with us
as her talk goes on feel free to post
questions up in the
comments and we'll be sure to get to
them if we have a time so i think
without much further ado
this is rebecca hoffarts computer
science teacher from the us virgin
islands we're super excited to have her
with us
rebecca take it away
awesome thank you so much meg i am so
excited to be here this is my favorite
organization and i'm ridiculously proud
to be involved in this today this is
going to be a little different kind of
presentation i'm not the technical
wizard in cyber security but
i do really feel that we just can't have
this next generation fight as hard as
all of you all did to get into this
pathway
and i know that when we reach out and
help others it builds our self-esteem
and helps us make
makes us feel good so i'm hoping to give
you some inspiration on ways you can
reach out give back and boast your own
self-esteem along with that and with
that i'm going to go ahead and share my
screen and start to give you a little
bit of the background in context for
this talk bear with me
okay
meg is everybody seeing the slides
i didn't lose everybody did i hello
nope you're good up okay let's see if
that'll stamp for me because i kind of
did just stop sharing all right good
so uh yes my name is rebecca hoffert and
i live in work in the u.s virgin islands
i'm going to give you a bit of context
about uh what i do after i explain why
i'm here and why you are here
i checked the diana initiatives website
and i found a friend i'm sorry rebecca
i we were almost flawless going through
this but i think that was my fault um
can you reshare please sure no i believe
that was me because i thought for a
minute you guys could not hear me
i think that's my bad let's see here
okay i'll try to be more patient this
time can you hear me still and see the
slides
meg yes you're good to go
great
so i'm rebecca hawford and i am here to
talk about being an inspiration to the
next generation
i found a phrase on the diana initiative
website which inspired me
and it really
spoke to exactly what it is that i want
to do i don't think anyone would be here
if they didn't support
this statement we want to elevate
inspire and support all underrepresented
genders sexualities races and cultures
in information security i know the title
of my presentation is specific to girls
but inclusivity is part of what
i do and i'm sure you all
value inclusivity as well let me tell
you uh the environment that i live and
work in i am not originally from the
island of st thomas but i have lived
there since the year 2000 it's the
longest i've ever lived anywhere in my
life
um we're in the caribbean i always tell
people we're that little tiny pencil
point to the right of puerto rico so
yeah that's us right there to the right
of puerto rico we are a u.s territory
under the u.s flag and it is an
incredibly terribly beautiful place most
people uh when they think of this
concept of beautiful st thomas think of
something that looks rather like this
of course you've seen this meme and you
know that the reality is
oh yeah it actually does look just like
that that's a real picture and if you go
there that's basically what it does look
like
it's a fantastic place um but it's a
very small place we're a tiny rock in
the middle of the ocean in between the
caribbean
and the atlantic roughly 32 square miles
it's about three miles north and south
and 12 miles east of west um those great
views we get are because we're rather
mountainous and you may have heard on
the news back in 2017 we got hit with
twin category five hurricanes irma and
maria or auntie or maria as we call them
so we are very much still
rebuilding from that it has been slow
slow slow
we have a population of roughly 50 000
on that 32 square mile rock at least
according to the 2010 census we think
it's pretty much the same pretty stable
in terms of overall numbers
it's interesting because pre-covered we
would have cruise ships that would come
in every day and the population of
cruise ship visitors would outstrip that
of our local population we had almost 2
million every year on average so more
visitors than locals
our population is diverse and always has
been the us virgin islands has always
been the crossroads of the caribbean
even back in pirate times highly diverse
people from every corner of the world
but we roughly fall into about 75 76
black 15 percent white the rest is very
mixed and about 17 percent of us
identify as hispanic
despite our natural beauty we have
issues with poverty a high percentage of
our population on our island falls below
the poverty line especially in our
younger people people under 18
it's a 37 percent live in households
below poverty
almost all of those are households uh
headed by single moms
because of the hurricanes students had
half day schedules for most of that
school year when the storms hit and
because of covid we've had school
closures we've had half schedules we've
had online school with our unreliable
power and internet connections on our
island
since march of 2020 when our school shut
down so
the current graduating class of 2021
barely went to high school they were
home or doing whatever they were doing
not at school
a very high percentage of the time so
that is indeed a challenge that our
graduating class faces
it's not all bad we have rich cultural
traditions we have our st thomas
carnival we have amazing things that go
on in our schools like this picture up
here at the top rightish
is a student troop from an elementary
school and that what they do is they go
to various events and do bamboola dance
and they talk about the history of the
dance and they go all over the place
it's
incredibly enriching to be at some of
our local events we have fantastic food
some of my favorites are the johnny cake
and of course the franco's don't go
anywhere but rudy's it's the best
fantastic music and we honor our history
the 1892 commemoration that we do every
year is a commemoration of coal strike
workers who are striking for
higher wages so we do have a bit of a
feisty spirit in the virgin islands uh
we're proud of that as well we have a
fantastic hbcu the university of the
virgin islands has brought a lot of
wonderful programs to us and it has
enabled a lot of our young virgin
islanders to get a college degree that
otherwise they could never afford
we are rapidly approaching um
progress
in fact this year and i was traveling i
did not make it there um but this past
july 10th we had our first ever gay
pride parade on the island of st thomas
and it was our own little version um it
was kicked off with speeches by the
rabbi and the minister
that's our downtown area right there
interestingly uh as our values are
changing and moving forward we are also
changing in technology if you go to
submarine cablemap.com or one of the
other similar sites you'll find that our
us virgin islands is the crux of
one of the biggest just
confluences of underwater internet
cables on the planet we just have far
more than our share for a 32 square mile
island and we have had companies come to
take advantages of our tax breaks
programs that we offer if we can ever
find a way to really suck off that
availability of bandwidth potential and
get that out to our youth community
we may be changing the world right in
front of everything covet is also
changing our population because
it is possible to get decent at least
internet connectivity on our island many
people stateside uh during kovid decided
that they wanted to be close to that
natural beauty and come down to us and
that has
changed the um the figures on the
diversity of our population most of
those coming down to the island were
white people and we definitely noticed
that um there's a difference in who's
around these last this last year and a
half
i am sure that in your communities
similar changes are happening i wonder
if kate can maybe help us out because i
for whatever reason can't see your your
chat contributions right now but if
there are changes that are influencing
your communities that you could share in
the chat that would be greatly
appreciated i'm sure we would all be
interesting and knowing what is going on
for us it's changes in technology
changes in the diversity the population
changes value system
and recovering from these two disasters
the hurricanes and also the covet
and maybe kate if we get some
submissions there we can just pop in and
talk about those
as far as my personal and professional
context
not so long ago i was a school librarian
yes a bit techy but mostly helping kids
enjoy reading i love reading stories to
children and our hbcu uvi uh was awarded
a five-year
over a million dollar grant
to and build the k-12 pipeline into
cyber security
i got the benefit to attend a cyber camp
back in 2014 mostly it was students
there were a couple of his teachers and
i just got very excited by the whole
idea of introducing my students to the
cyber security career path i started
coaching cyberpatriot the next year
and i got the chance to be a leader as
part of the 2015
cyber camp the following summer
here you can see our campers in that
2015 cyber camp that's on the uvi campus
here in st thomas and they are
they're just wonderful wonderful bunch
of kids there they're ranging in age
from entering sixth grade to some
graduating seniors one of the students
here matthew he's over on the the right
of your screen by me
he's graduated and you're going to see
him in some future pictures in fact a
lot of these kids you will see in other
pictures but what you won't see is a
predomination of female campers you got
mostly boys and five female campers in
that picture
so i wasn't satisfied with that and i
got together with some people that i
knew from my school and
worked with the partnerships that we had
made through that grant program we put
together a little cyber saturday's
program
through the local ywca that turned out
to be one of the best things that we
ever did the
people who are in charge of the ywca
are open to
an incredibly inclusive program you
don't have to be christian you don't
have to be a girl you don't have to be
anything to be a part of the ywca in st
thomas so we threw up a little website
and we
were able to get access to a public
computer center which was hosted by
the saint andrews episcopal church but
really that initiative comes through the
virgin islands next generation network
they're a quasi-public corporation that
um
through their
economic receipts by selling bandwidth
and through some grant money they are
able to kind of provide a middle mile
in our
local network infrastructure
so we had about 12 computers maybe about
eight of them could connect to the
internet at any time but we got a great
group together and we even got some
donor sponsorship people started
dropping by and donating new computers
to us it was a really exciting time and
we just it was a nice beginning to see
what we could do
it was wonderful that we were able to
bring together vi ngn the secor
partnership out of university of the
virgin islands which brought in all the
federal grant people department of
energy and a network of hbcus along with
the ywca and along with the church
probably the most important uh we
brought the church ladies and these two
women just organized everything
as far as being an instructor my life
was so easy because i didn't have to
deal with any supervision and they
always brought snacks
that was very different from my usual
experience in the classroom so for me it
was a way to learn that the more
partnerships you can bring into your
movements
the better off it's going to be because
everybody brings a little something to
the table it's like a potluck dinner if
you only have to bring the baked beans
and that's all
makes your life so much easier and it
makes it a lot easier for more people to
hop in and participate
lesson learned
not only did they bring snacks but they
brought me a whole fair they decided
they wanted to organize uh girls in ict
fair so we partnered up with girls in
ict which is an organization that's now
supported by the un women
and they
organized a whole fair for the students
at my school and it was called girls in
ict but you can see there were boys in
the picture too everybody was invited
and we were able even to get a high
school student from up in the united
states to come in via video conference
this was before we were all doing video
conference instruction
so it was pretty exciting my students
just loved seeing her on the screen and
she taught them how to make the fashion
scene with scratch
we really had a fantastic time so i
never expected to get a whole girls in
ict fair out of the cyber saturdays but
i can't honestly say that i did much i
brought my baked beans and the rest of
the whole spread was done by the ladies
from ywca
and coming around full cycle
our
2016 uvi cyber camp if you want to look
at this picture
um
shows eight female campers so that's a
pretty good ratio i think in one year
our numbers were starting to build we
were getting on the rise
this is my 2016 middle school cyber
patriot team my school we would have to
do a bake sale to pay the registration
fee for the cyber patriot team
competition but if you have an all girls
team then cyberpatriot waves your fee so
we put together an all girls team so we
didn't have to do all the bake sales and
instead we could practice our cyber
security tactics
these are all middle school students and
they are all uh the first ever all-girls
team out of my former school
um
out of that team of seven girls uh one
of them is now entering 12th grade and
she's an nc wit national center for
women in information technology national
award winner in 2020
another one is just graduated she's
entering ganon university this fall to
study cyber security one is now entering
her sophomore year at our hbcu
university of the virgin islands
studying cyber security one i know is
going into a stem career i thought it
was possibly marine science i just found
out yesterday that she tends to be a
double major in biomedical and economics
and she wants to do
genome studies for the center for
disease control so
that's amazing it is not however cyber
security
but pretty cool
uh when we did cyber camp 2017 we had
some more changes we had more girls
but maybe even more important we also
were able to bring in two female
instructors uh one of which i worked
with at my institution
but who also had a university
affiliation and the other who was a
student at
the university of the virgin islands she
graduated while we were in the midst of
our of our camp i believe but bringing
in local women i mean i'm i'm white and
most of my students are not and it
really is true that the more they see
someone who looks like them the better
they're going to be able to relate to
you and they also relate to young people
i
wasn't 50 plus then but i am now so
having some young women of color
participate as instructors in the camp i
think it really made a difference for us
it was an excellent change to add um to
add to the program it just showed that
we were growing and we were bringing
more people into it
super exciting
that's when i decided that i wasn't
happy with having uvi's camp and i
wanted to have my own camp so i actually
worked with nc wit that's the national
center for women information technology
wrote a little grant and we put together
a summer camp just for girls nc whit
wants the girls to choose a topic that
they feel passionate about and focus
their efforts on that topic so
we
focused on a couple of different things
but you can see that my student there
jessica she worked on her tablet and she
did a an animation program related to
global warming
we brought in some women of color from
the community who were working
professionally in computer science
related fields one was doing network
wiring
we had some coders and programmers we
had
people working for the isps about four
different um
different speakers and yep that's one of
the ywca ladies she is a retired
engineer so she came and gave us a talk
about cyber security and computer
science related to
engineering and we just had a wonderful
time this is
donette over here
she and michelle ventura they were both
the two new instructors in our uvi
summer cyber camp and they both wanted
to help us out with our code like a girl
camp one of the best things that came
out of this was a brand new partner
kritika iyer she's out of plano texas
plano
and
she was a national award winner from nc
wit she wrote the grant with me and was
with me all the way organizing this
grant and was able to come over to saint
thomas from texas the year before she
entered the summer before she entered
stanford university
and she was one of our primary
instructors in this camp as well
at the end of the camp we were able to
get one of the auditoriums at uvi we put
together a little forum we were able to
get a sponsorship through the secor
partnership at uvi to get everybody cute
pink code like a girl t-shirts
and we put together some of our guest
speakers some of our students some of
our instructors from the program
and we made a fantastic little panel
group we had a panel of students and we
had a panel of our instructors so we
were able to invite the entire community
out to join our forum and hear a little
bit about what we had been doing it was
really exciting
then
after that summer that amazing summer of
17 with so many so many wonderful
progressions we got hit by the
hurricanes uh these photos of our r of
my school's hour of code celebration
this is actually not in 2017 it was 2018
by the time we got around to doing hour
of code because we just didn't really
have any connectivity and often no power
right after the storms at my house we
were out of power for four months um but
the schools they did a little bit better
job and
got us connected a little bit faster we
still did have hour of code though and
we really did have a good time
that's when one of our guest speakers
from the code like a girl camp um
convinced me that we should start a
girls who code club over there at ubi so
we did that um that's a 2018 photo but
we actually started in the fall just a
couple of weeks after the storms hit
so the ladies that you see in the
picture there were part of the very
first girls who code club ever in the
usbi it's an amazing organization
i definitely encourage you to get
involved with them and they're my
uh fall 2017 summer patriot team members
they're thanking one of our sponsors who
actually put together some t-shirts and
snacks and jump drives for us corporate
sponsorship is always helpful
[Music]
and that
is a little bit on how i've been trying
to spark a journey in my community
i
was asking earlier about
changes in your community and how you
might be a part of that
um but that's a little bit of what i've
been doing i'm going to show you a
little bit more and then we'll move on
basically i've tried to focus my efforts
on what i have seen that works
and those are in
four forks of the pathway competitions
such as cyberpatriot are great of course
i probably don't need to tell anybody
here yet that ctfs are very fun and
motivating for students cyberpatriot is
a great defensive competition it's
really exciting meg is actually a very
successful cyber patriot coach um
and i've enjoyed working in that program
for for many years now there are other
c2 ctfs out there that are geared to
young people more and more and more all
the time so that's always something to
check for on google picoctf is really
good p ico
sans institute which you are probably
familiar with as a provider of cyber
security
continuing education certificates etc
they've done a great job with their
cyberstart competition uh and i just
anybody who is a young person or who is
an educator
of young people if you can share with
them those competitions are out there
they make it so easy for somebody who is
not a technical wizard such as myself to
lead the students and get them involved
they really make it impossible to not do
the competition because they give you so
much support and help the students get
really excited
i would also say that hands-on practice
in the photos you saw some raspberry pi
development you saw some
lego pie that we were working with legos
are really fun
to add to the raspberry pi experience
anything with robotics and it doesn't
always have to be electrified you know
you can build
robots with uh soda straws if you want
to and marshmallows
but anything that hands on works well
for the very youngest ones i've always
found that the tablets are fantastic
they're not so good yet with the mouse
and the keyboard but that doesn't mean
that you can't bring cyber security
programming down even to as young as
three
because with the tablet you can make a
lot of things possible
increase that local pipeline in my
community virgin islanders are very very
best and most proud when we include our
local people so although i'm i'm
definitely a state senator i've been
there a while
um and that's appreciated but it's
really wonderful when you can
develop your population in your own
community that houses you
and build them up and get them into your
pipeline and get them mentoring
it just makes
makes the impact that much more powerful
finally inclusion and i've touched on
that youngest people can be involved in
these pathways three-year-olds can learn
that keeping your ipad flat on the table
instead of holding it in your lap is a
form of physical security because then
it doesn't fall on the floor if it's up
on the table flat
uh things like you know how many windows
does a house have and you know which
house is easier for the bad guys to get
into the one with one window or the one
with 17 windows all over the place they
can answer that question it makes them
really happy to know about that
and uh boys you know whenever and it has
happened lots of times whenever uh
someone who might not look like a girl
shows up at one of my programs that
person is embraced with open arms you
know we wouldn't ever turn anybody away
for any reason so just make sure
everybody is welcome
and here are some photo examples of that
the children in these pictures range uh
from nursery school age so three and
four year olds all the way up through uh
fifth sixth grade elementary and it
absolutely is possible to get these guys
involved and they're very excited when
they are
i'm showing them a little bit of scratch
programming we're working with some
basic robotics using the cubelets
that are building block robots pretty
exciting and you know for these young
ones when they're running their first
program that can be a very big deal
and it's um but it makes everybody happy
to see how excited how alive and how
just full of joy they are when they run
that first program
for the older ones
it's always good to
include them
yes but start to give them a chance to
lead those younger ones just as the
bigger ones like to have young people
from the university instruct them that's
their favorite for the very youngest
ones in the elementary school they love
to have the big kids come and work with
them
so after a few years of working with
these programs i had a core group of big
kids who i knew i could rely on whenever
we did a fair an event a saturday or
anything after school
they would um be my team and they would
be the ones uh working with the younger
kids so it builds their self-esteem
teenagers sometimes have a hard time
with their self-esteem one of the things
that makes them feel good is doing
something for others and it makes them
feel like they've got ownership of this
knowledge they do know a thing or two
teaching the younger ones makes them
really happy especially when they see
that the younger ones are so so happy as
well
i want to point out in this photo that
one of the young people from the
earliest cyber camp photo showed matthew
he was in senior a senior in high school
at the time and here he is back again
now he is a university student and now
he's participating as one of the big
kids team helping out with these
initiatives and he does that all the
time so he used to be in the camp
now he's leading these camp events
that said
we don't want the older ones to just
teach they wouldn't like it if that was
their only responsibility they very much
want to keep learning so even the ones
who are kind of in the big kids section
now they don't want to spend their
entire time as junior instructor
instructors now they they want to
explore new stuff too so we added high
school cyber patriot teams to the middle
school cyber patriot teams we kept them
involved doing hands-on sometimes the
big kids like to use the cubelets as you
see on the right here and use the
building block robots so there's nothing
wrong with doing that every now and then
letting them have some fun
um
down at the bottom they're using each
other as a human piano to play notes
and they can
enjoy um
continuing their own learning
when they succeed you have to celebrate
sometimes for those big kids
it's just like for the little kids it's
still run your first program i am
introducing students who are unfamiliar
with computer science and cyber security
every semester every year and so it's
always somebody's turn to run their
first program which isn't always in the
trinket pythons a lot of different
platforms but it's always fun when
somebody runs their first program hello
world here i am i've i've arrived on the
cyber security pathway it can also be
getting points in cyber patriots cyber
patriots super motivating because
whenever you get points for your team it
says
my kids tell me that's a video game
sound from
some video game that i don't know but
they they love it when those when that
points alert comes on
uh sometimes it's celebrating that you
even have a cyber patriot team in the
middle of covet even if you have to
compete in mass even if you have to
compete from different houses
that was difficult
um but you got to celebrate that i had
students who were in the sands
competition
last year i had a team go to the
national championship this year i had a
bunch of students who were
semi-finalists and that i had
one go all the way to the finals and
become an official cyber scholar got a
scholarship
and then i had a student who uh just
like krithika iyer in the code like a
girl camp had won the nc wit national
computer science award well this young
lady who was in the camp with grithika
when she was in 10th grade she got that
very same award so now she can actually
be a partner and run her own camps
we're winding down on time are you
winding down too i
am uh
so some suggested part i could go all
day meg i warned you about that you did
warn me
thank you so much so great partners i
mean the ywca was great uh some of the
photos you've seen come from the women
of 18t locally who always sponsor event
days i've mentioned girls who coded nc
wit i'm a big fan of the cyber
innovation center i'm going to show you
a photo from one of their programs
that's me
building my very first program i hate
that picture of myself but i love what
demonstrates that's
the first time i ever built a robot and
i was pretty pretty proud so we all know
professional development has to keep
going so learn
mentor
when you be when you're a mentor it
builds your self-esteem builds your
network and it helps you to know what to
look for in your own mentors and without
mentors you wouldn't get moments like
that
inspire
uh neither of these two young ladies
ever thought they were going to do
anything with robotics but
given a little bit of a taste of it they
absolutely
loved it so find ways to inspire them
and never ever give up even if there are
storms even if there's coveted that's
one of my cyber patriot students
we just can't have this fight be so hard
it's it shouldn't have to be and
anything that we can do to make it
easier is is going to help all of us
so
my four takeaways for you learn mentor
inspire
never give up
spark a journey
i love tips and suggestions please feel
free to drop them in the chat
would appreciate it and there's brought
us here those are the people who got all
this for us
and we love our sponsors thank you so
much rebecca are you going to be
available to chat with on the hop-in
platform yes okay awesome because i know
we're running down on time and i
appreciate
especially this past year we did um one
of our cyber patriot competitions
outside in the snow so you know
everybody had their struggles this year
oh my goodness you are just amazing
um thank you so much that was so
inspiring to hear you and i know that up
next we have um passwords so i know
people are excited about that talk we
don't have a lot of time for q a so i'm
going to encourage people to reach out
to you in the hop and platform and hear
more about it feel free to reach out to
me too if you're looking for more about
cyberpatriot there's a bunch of
cyberpatriot mentors i've discovered in
almost everything i'm in today people
are like oh i'm a cyber patriot mentor
too so if you're interested in starting
something i'm sure that you'll find
people within this network today that
will be able to help you
so um thank you so much please please
listen and take to heart rebecca's words
and and do what you can to inspire our
next generation it's so so important