morning guys I'm Rankin and I'm here to
present a talk on IOT from an attackers
perspective so yeah I'm a security
researcher at one of the largest ship
making companies so I've flown all the
way from India just for this conference
so I hope I don't screw this up and have
something of quality so my areas of
expertise include our web mobile in frog
code reviews and the regular stuff so
the past few years have been performing
researchers on linux kernel's
and IOT related stuff ranging from the
devices platforms to the applications so
yeah
the agenda or the takeaways that we can
expect from today's talk is that we will
be able to understand what I 80 exactly
is and what are the components that are
required to build an IOT solution and
understand what kind of attack surface
it reveals to an attacker and yeah
basically that's what we will be looking
at today in the interest of time I will
try to keep this as short or as short as
possible but in case you find me going
to cast please feel free to interrupt so
the first this is the foothold at this
point of time we can understand from
this kind of a diagram that IOT have
reached various verticals ranging from
home automation healthcare
transportation retail and so on and so
forth so we are pretty familiar with all
these smart devices that we have on our
phones so we have dumb devices like
coffee makers even our television is
becoming smarter and smarter so they
call it smart device but I I call it an
entry point for an attacker because all
it does is brew coffee and have an N IC
which we shall sit to cry to the
Internet so here and IOT is grow
pretty remarkable it's growing pretty
significantly so there if you research
out there that suggests that IOT could
be a few trillion dollar industry in the
in the coming year so this is a great
space to ventured into right now
and make some money so yeah this is
another screen slide that gives you an
idea of what kind of components or what
kind of smart devices we have in each
vertical so we should be we are pretty
familiar with the home consumer stuff
right so smart security devices and even
the motion sensor that is here I'm sure
it should be working on CB protocol so
we should have some hub within this
auditorium or theater so these home
automation or home consumer devices have
something that we will we find in our
day to day life moving on to transport
and mobility verticals so we find all
these autonomous driving or self-driving
cars that are gaining traction a lot of
traction these days right so we also I
mean vamo is are trying to build a fleet
image which is self driving so in the
near future we can find ourselves being
driven to destinations we thought driver
or a chauffeur so that's something that
we have to look forward to and
healthcare here Healthcare also has a
lot of IOT implementations where the
patients don't necessarily have to stay
in the hospital to get get 24/7 health
care so essentially what that means is
the patients could have some variables
that that keep monitoring their health
that that boils down to home consumer
devices as well so as we can as we saw
Apple watch the latest version of it it
has an ECG built in so they are also
trying to they're also trying to embed
that pressure monitors engineer
SmartWatch so healthcare healthcare is a
huge consumer I would say when it comes
to IOT space and we have smart building
smart cities smart buildings yeah we we
see all these are temperature sensors
motion sensors within within all the
buildings that we are huge buildings
around these days so that is something
that that significantly increases the
attack surface so what is IOT ionely is
nothing but it is a coalition of various
devices embedded devices sensors and
applications basically so all of these
components work in tandem do it's
basically like neatly choreographed
dance right so all the all the sensors
kind of collect data from the physical
world and this data fn2 cloud
infrastructure which is the backend
which which goes ahead and process all
this data and does the work for you the
work can be anything ranging from
turning on a light to driving your car
sure to better understand this let's
take a look at the Samsung smartthings
and architecture so what we can see here
there are a bunch of devices right so
devices require a language or a protocol
to communicate with each other and the
hub so the protocols that we can see
here are V wave and we'll be using B if
we have a v-mail
or a CB device then these math things
have or essentially they have should be
speaking the same language it should be
able to communicate with the devices on
the same protocols
and this hub would essentially be
located in the same premises this does
not have a huge range or something
so whatever data is being collected from
the devices are fin sent to the hub
which then connects to the internet
using a home router so the architecture
that we are looking at is for home
automation right so it connects your
home home router and then that data is
uploaded to the cloud services so the
reason why cloud infrastructure is a
huge deal when it comes to IOT is that
the embedded devices or the endpoint
devices that we have installed in our
homes buildings whatnot so they are all
essentially they have a very limited
storage the storage that we are talking
about in kilobytes so within that
storage it should it should run a
bootloader it should run and kernel it
should run in an operating system and it
should also run an application so given
so due to the description the devices
cannot they usually don't have the
compute power required to process all
the data or all the information that
they collect from the physical world so
all that compute power is given to an
IOT solution from the cloud service so
yeah and we can also understand from
this diagram that these devices can also
be controlled by Amazon Amazon's Alexa
and Google home the reason why that is
possible is that so they have so there
is this thing called a third party
integration right so Amazon Google and
Samsung have come together and they have
they have opened up certain services
that each of them can leverage to
communicate with each other and control
the devices essentially so you can this
this is also being implemented by
Philips whew it's just not like a
Samsung thing or something so
essentially what this means is you
use your big cell phone or your Amazon
Alexa to control any Samsung bulb that
you might have but your home or even
their refrigerators and their waters and
dryers so - from a convenience
perspective all these home automation
solutions come with a smart home smart
phone application and also a web
interface so even that is a attack
surface when you look at from an IOT
solution as a whole so let's dive into
each of them in their features right so
yeah these are the IOT components so as
we talked about so there will be a
device it can either be an embedded
device that is placed in your coffee
maker or it can be an actual sensor like
definition that we have right here in
the corner and so each device will have
an operating system so the operating
system that we are talking about is not
an apple - or a Macintosh so it is
something called as a real-time
operating system or commonly known this
are known as Aptos so there are a bunch
of real-time operating systems out there
like free free are two tiny OS and stuff
like that so the IOT OS that they often
lack kind of regulation where so what
happens here is that each vendor they
come up with their own operating system
and when we take these operating systems
into consideration they lack all these
traditional security measures that
mitigations that we have in our OS right
like a SLR DB and so on and so forth so
that is something that needs to be
addressed and as discussed via mobile
application and web interface is still a
huge attack surface in an IOT solution
because that is basically how all these
devices are controlled and how ya hub is
something that collides the data from
all the devices and so hub is
essentially proxy which which which
takes the require
from the user and sensitive to the
devices and vice versa it also collects
data and send the information back to
the user so of course I an IOT physician
hugely depends on communications so the
communication protocols may range from
ZigBee free wave bluetooth to your
regular Ethernet cable and yeah cloud
infrastructure is pretty pivotal in an
IOT solution so moving on to the
security perspective of an IOT solution
the CIA triad stays true here and this
is this is basically the pillars of
security even when it comes to an IT
solution so confidentiality the state of
being secret is ok so as we discussed
earlier smart devices are present
everywhere right so we have security
cameras around our homes and we have all
the fencers laying around for example if
you take Amazon echo it has a webcam it
has a camera built-in right so we may
have them in our bedrooms and we're not
so that is something so whatever data or
whatever video feed it is getting it is
capturing should should remain
confidential and it should only be
accessed by the product owners who I
mean the device owners and that is a
huge if this is breached then there's a
huge privacy violation right so
confidentiality is pivotal
so as integrity so integrity is the
state of being unmodified by an author
edit and unauthorized entities right so
if we have the security system in our
home so we only want us to be able to
unlock the door and not anyone else so
that is something being addressed by the
integrity of the solution availability
is just a state of being available so if
we have all these devices and if they
don't respond to our commands they are
no good to us so moving on to the attack
vectors there are three attacked with
tears
similar okay this is not similar so
political is something that gets add-on
added on to IOT solution so physical
attack winter is where and an attacker
routine would require physical access to
the hardware itself so this essentially
means that okay the kind of attacks that
fall into this category are like getting
a root shell on the device itself and
offloading data from the devices local
network is something where the attacker
needs to be on the local network or your
home network when it comes to home
automation to carry out these attacks so
remote is the holy grail of attacks here
where an attacker essentially carries
out the exploit from halfway across the
globe so this is a brief list of attack
surface that gets opened up when an
ideal solution is introduced anywhere so
ranging from your industries to basic
home automation so yeah we can see that
device hardware device firmware device
memory or rather hardware and firmware
are a pretty unique to one IOT solution
and device memory local storage
operating system they remain across I
mean they remain the same right so we
find this even when it comes to our
mobile applications right so software
update mechanism is also a new is also a
new attack surface that IOT opens up
network communications web interface
mobile application cloud in front third
party integration are basically similar
to what we do in our day-to-day pen test
so what if a device device as we
discussed earlier could be an embedded
device that is in in any dumb device
like your refrigerator
washers and so on and so forth so what
an embedded device will essentially have
a minimal processor it will have a small
and NAND flash storage we are not
talking about megabytes or gigabytes
here it's odd it's basically in
kilobytes so that is an embedded device
and sensors can range from anything
anything from motion to a temperature
sensor motion sensors are pretty
prevalent in buildings and proximity
sensors as well and temperature sensor
is where you saw something where that is
mandatory when it comes to your
thermostat control and yeah basically
that and hubs as we discussed hubs are
required to offload the data to cloud
servers and this is the only mode to
communicate with the devices because
they they communicate in a custom
protocol which and none of the mobile
devices can at this point of time so
moving on to device security to carry
out a physical attack you wouldn't
require physical access right so the
physical access means that you need to
connect to the board via any one of
these debug ports it can be a JTAG you
are SPI I or I squared C so DS debug
ports
could be found pretty easily but in a in
a production or in a secure device you
will you may not find all these pins out
in that case you will have to manually
go ahead and identify those pins and
solder on those to the board and then
connect connect your system to those
goals so if you can see that a red ring
kind of thing so that's what a JTAG pin
looks like often what happens is the
JTAG has made I mean the board mentions
it to be a JTAG there will be a
spring written FJ tag it can be JTAG
easy tag on what not so J tag is
something that you can use to connect to
the board itself this is how you will be
you will be able to get Coon shells on
the devices and so on and so forth
so lack of or TLS that it speaks for
itself right so any kind of
communication if it is not encrypted can
easily be captured by an attacker and
they can easily eavesdrop on it and
missing security patches yeah so any
kind of device
I mean breaches happen every day so I
mean no one no one can call their
product completely secured so breaches
do happen and when a when a researcher
comes ahead I mean come forward and
discloses that vulnerability it is up to
the OEMs to go ahead and bastard
vulnerability and send OTA updates so
and we can find a lot of small companies
that that that revealed that launched
products and basically don't offer
support they work more on updating or
upgrading their hardware rather than
sending updates to their current
hardware so that is a huge gap there is
a huge security gap when it comes to
security patches and so yeah in a case
that you if you don't have if you don't
have from where with you which is the
case when it comes to security
researchers so if you have to extract a
firmware from the device you need
something called as a bus pirate that is
the red color boat that you can see on
the top right corner so you can use that
to connect to the board that you would
like to offload or extract the firmware
from and so the pink color board is
something called as a Jetta you later
jtagulator something that one can use to
connect their laptop to the device that
they are testing so this is how you
would be establishing a connection
between the PCB and your computer so to
usage a tack you later all you need to
do is connect the jtagulator to your
laptop via USB and it comes with a
dongle kind of thing which plugs onto
the board and you'll have to connect the
other end of it to the JTAG pins of the
PCB that you are testing all you need to
do here give the imported that's
basically it so you'll have to identify
the pins like the B Fifi ground rx T X
and stuff like that so generated or
something it takes to do all those
things for you if not you can also use
something called as a logic analyzer
logic analyzers tend to be a little on
the pricey side but yeah they do a
pretty decent job in letting you know
what what each pin does so if it is a 5
volt if you see and it will also tell
you I'll let you know which is the
transmission pin and with just a
receiving pin so that makes your life
easy so these two are just an example I
mean you don't officially have to use
the same device you could there are a
bunch of other devices that a researcher
could used to accomplish these tasks so
yeah you would require a lot of jumper
cables you connect these boats to the
PCB and yeah if you are not able to
identify the ground and be 50 then you
will have to go ahead and grab a wood
meter and you'll have to figure it out
yourself and as we discussed if there
are no prints then you will have to take
out your solving equipment and solder
all the pins onto the boat
so yeah how can the hardware be
compromised so these are okay we can see
the device you can see a bunch of
vulnerability here like both
shall be experiential security defaulter
blank passwords in secure storage of
root passwords and stuff like that so
what happens here is a lot of devices
what they didn't do is they okay already
I have to become one okay so what
essentially happens here is that if you
connect we are you at or JTAG bones then
if you are if you are doing it for the
first time then a lot of devices let you
indirectly and they don't even ask for
any password or anything and certain
devices what they do is they let you go
ahead and set the password if you are
using it for the if you are connecting
those devices for the first time of
course I mean when we bring a smart
device into our home we don't
essentially go and remove the cover and
connected to our laptop side so if an
attacker walks into your home they can
easily open up the device and connect
connect it and have a shell access and
what they can do from here is dick they
could essentially he pop a backdoor on
it and that that's a very easy way for
any attacker to get back into your home
network at any at any given point of
time so as we discussed extracting
device firmware is something that is
very important when it comes to an i/o
dissolution right so okay let's discuss
about firmware in the next slide and all
this we want to look out for
misconfigured all or one durable
services okay device firmware is
essentially okay we can compare a device
firmware to your jar files in an android
application so firmware is something
that contains all the services and
whatnot so if you are able to dump the
firmware from a device and and if you
are lucky enough to find that your
permit not to be encrypted then yeah you
can basically do whatever you want and
you've got you could look for
any kind of accurate credentials you
could look for any doorman service which
you could activate and one more
interesting thing is that okay whenever
a firmware is being flashed on to a
heart or whenever permits being flashed
on to a device there should be a
signature validation but often times you
will not find that happening all the
time so what you could do is you could
you could modify the firmware you could
create a militia premiere of your own
version and you could just write it
flash it onto the device and these are a
bunch of tools that you could use to
analyze the firmware liftoff which is
been work so been working something that
helps you to extract a disc worshipers
and the route Efes are basically the
file systems from the firmware so the
firmware essentially is a dot pin file
which you cannot you cannot read
directly like using cat or wim so you
will have to extract the data from the
binary and of course you will require a
lot of debuggers and what to do here
yeah one thing the first thing that you
have to do is I check for encryption and
yeah extract the firmware and do that
right so go into the file systems look
for any hard-coded credentials
you could also interestingly if you come
across some I mean I should not say that
but if you come across some Chinese
Hardware oftentimes you will find some
kind of a back door or something I mean
which may not be unintended but yeah you
may find a lot of those those things and
yeah so also look for encryption
algorithm so if you find any hard coded
keys there then you could basically
compromise the communication all the TLS
basically and sensitive information
sensitive URLs as well you could you
could find the admin endpoints or any or
any sensitive endpoints to the API is
that they expose
you could also look for vulnerable
services and so on and so forth
moving on to device memory and local
storage as we discussed earlier an
embedded device would have limited
storage because of which due to the all
major majority of devices tend to have
an SD card so if the card is something
that the devices rely on to obtain the
firmware and flash it onto the device so
the firmware directly does not go into
the device it gets downloaded to a nifty
car and then get flashed onto the device
so you could you could kind of perform
mi TMI tag here and control what kind of
firmware goes into the device and flash
storage as we discussed so there is a
technique where you could we had you
could leverage the non storage you could
just short out a few pins and you could
basically bypass the boot and I mean
that that that makes the bootloader to
fail and it'll give you a root shell on
the hand on the device itself so
volatile or non-volatile memory is
something that you will definitely have
to look at during runtime and after
after the device is closed oh my god
okay so also be on the lookout for
sensitive product information and so on
and so forth
IOT security is not just hardware
security I think we should be able to
understand this by now so okay operating
system as we discussed so real-time
operating systems is something which is
fairly new to the industry and due to
this Duty art was being fairly new they
do not have a majority of operating
system level security mitigations like a
SLR for example and because our toes are
- because of the operating system like
in a 64 KB size you you it's very hard
to extract kernel from the arctos itself
so water
essentially if it is a fugitive version
of your bootloader your kernel your
operating system and the application
itself that drives the device so if
you've calls you can use something
called as a fifth caller two of the
system calls that particular artists
uses if it isn't if it is based on a
Linux kernel if not then you'll have to
write your own reserve treating is also
something similar to scholar it is a
little little easier to use and more
versatile and what to do here yeah if
initially next kernel then you could go
ahead and try to exploit any known
colonel exploits and also look for
misconfigured operating system services
so this is something that okay go ahead
software update mechanism as we okay so
this is something so software update or
a firmware update if something is itself
a huge gap here because the thing is if
you are able to if you are able to
bypass these okay if there is no signal
validation being done
you could easily flash your malicious
form a right and if it's more okay
network communications these are the
various communications communication
protocols that IOT uses at this point of
time which are pretty prevalent so Wi-Fi
if it be via Bluetooth NFC MQTT and so
on and so forth to to play around with
the network communications you would
require some custom devices like a
hacker of one and the uber tooth one is
the device that is shown in the right
corner so hacker of one is basically
used to capture any kind of radio
frequency signal so it can capture
anything from your Wi-Fi signal to
GSM and uber tooth one is used to
capture your Bluetooth communications
and from a software standpoint then you
would require a Wireshark to capture the
packets why I shot this pretty versatile
right it lets you capture anything from
HTTP to MQ Tyrian what not eater kappa
the hitter camp is also a really great
tool when it comes to packet capturing
and GNU radio is something that you
would require to I mean GNU radio
basically paid appears with the hacker
of to capture the data so what to look
for in a network communication is that
always look for unencrypted data and you
will definitely find a lot of traffic
that is not encrypted MQTT these days it
is getting encrypted but if you are able
to find an older device that uses
impunity you definitely find the data
not to be encrypted and there is an
issue with MQTT where MQTT connect
command whenever the impurity current
command is run it sends out username and
the password along in that in that
request in that request so that is
something that you should be on the
lookout for and so yeah map out the data
flow basically just to understand what
kind of data is being sent back and
forth from the device and protocol
fuzzing is really important so I mean if
you are using the custom protocol then
you should definitely go ahead and
perform protocol fuzzing to identify any
vulnerabilities within that so moving on
to vapour mobile application so it is
our home turf right so web applications
for mobile applications have been out
there for quite a few years or rather a
decade now and we we basically know what
to look out what to look for in a web
application or mobile application and
these being the okay these being okay
maybe application and mobile application
is something these applications are the
entry points to any of your solution and
this is where you you get the data
this is where you live how you send your
commands as well so yeah we know this
and I think we just four d4 credential
is an encrypted communication logic okay
infrastructure this is something that we
discussed earlier so when it comes to
huge enterprises then we really don't
have to worry about cloud infrastructure
but still and in the recent past we we
did have been preachers to Apple cloud
services and things like that so
relatively speaking of relatively
smaller companies they tend to not have
all the security medications in place
and they even don't have a proper orders
going on on their back-end servers so
that is an easier way for an attacker to
get into the IOT solution so it doesn't
it doesn't really impact a home
automation system but this plays a vital
role in becomes shown industry in an in
an IND of failure you tease a kind of a
situation third party interaction this
is something that a new attack surface
when it comes to an i/o definition this
is where I mean Samsung Google and
Amazon tries to work to work together
work in tandem shared their data and
okay this in a similar fashion when it
comes to huge enterprises then you don't
have to worry about it that much but
while compared to a relatively smaller
company when it comes to a smaller
company the odds were that the third
party or the data being shared is not
particularly restricted right so
unintentional data leaks are something
that you could find very easily very
easily and code review something that is
really important when it comes to an
ideal solution a proper a proper rundown
of the total source code base is really
important here you
to perform the KO tribute to plug all
the all the all the security
vulnerabilities because this is the
easiest way to identify any security a
shortcoming
so yeah security is not a strip by the
process so you will have to keep
researching for vulnerabilities and
releasing patches for all the identified
vulnerabilities because let's face it
the breaches is something breach is
something that happens every day and we
will have to there is no other way to
get around it but to activate and fix
sixty vulnerability and send out patches
so yeah thank you for bearing with me I
you know I have been really fast and I
couldn't cover most of it but yeah I
will be happy to take any
[Applause]