thank you very much Dylan thank you
thank you and if anyone wants pretty a
get right cuz I don't like responsible
disclosure no we have to do it all right
sorry anyone that well let's go straight
to the end so we all like dark roads uh
you know unless I have some light modes
on the talk so let's turn it on right so
special mentions to few guys that helped
me out over the course of this time that
I've been doing this my name's Phil
Miller but anyone that doesn't really
know me I work for coming all day after
exploits we kind of do you know
responsible disclosure yeah regulation
the boring stuff I'm homeless I live out
of hotels it's pretty fun yeah kind of a
thing you do when you work remotely but
for the talk let's just remember I'm not
a lawyer I'm probably the last person
you want to talk to when you have this
much Jager you don't want to attack me
yeah representing you terrified young
but yeah but I'm not offering legal
advice I wouldn't go to AFF go to
lawyers go to people that actually know
what they're doing
yeah so let's go straight into it types
of disclosures so we've got responsible
disclosure we got coordinators closure
which similar very similar for
disclosure where you just kind of you
know throw it out there and hope that
you know things don't go wrong which
often times they do send what's this
caper partial disclosure where I've done
it a few times when you know people
aren't really listening the right people
aren't really kind of kind of
approaching you or you can't get a hold
of them and that's where you kind of
really give kind of a redacted version
of your disclosure be like okay well
this is an issue I can do there
and you kind of get them involved
because even certain will get involved
to be like this is a big problem someone
else will get involved and that's kind
of a good step forward their
non-disclosure zero-days a PT's the
things that you don't really want to
happen they often happen with some
disclosure responsive disclosure kind of
as I was going really yeah
just as things kind of happened with
yeah you approached the right people in
a sense so you kind of you know talking
to the appropriate you know vendors
organizations trying to get people
involved from our yeah kind of creative
dialogue where you're getting involved
in that sense and kind of giving them
what they need to patch those issues
full disclosure you know kind of doing
it without any you know warning kind of
going straight into it
kind of not really giving any kind of
precursor that hey I'm just gonna drop
this which kind of causes problems a lot
of companies I'm like that Google's good
fracks doing full disclosure because I
do it quite often nowadays and then you
know they go out I'll expand you know
nowadays we just gonna drop this man has
given notice it's really yeah there's no
way to patch it there's no way to kind
of do anything about it
and you know it's gonna cause a lot of
issues for the vendor farm people for
yourself even because if you kind of you
know give them you know this disclosure
which you're doing you know openly
there's gonna be a lot of issues in that
sense with you know Cisco's good example
a lot of companies they really please
just close you just thrown out at them
as like well all these corporate you
know kind of companies are just gonna go
down the wall because there's nobody to
really patch in time yeah for disclosure
right so moving on we go to the first
kind of case study in that where we
worked with a company called beer 52
which is based out of Edinburgh they
kind of provide beer because
hackers love bail and you know we kind
of need free beer so how do you free
them right so this is kind of example we
kind of go about yeah we found a few
different vulnerabilities and we're like
well you know how do you go about doing
that and we kind of emailed them to say
well yeah we found a few issues in your
company we'd like to go about you know
disclosing this jr. we understand that
you're not involved in a bug bounty
program and yeah
we'd like to kind of open a dialog kind
of create yeah this context of where we
can talk and yeah we often ask you know
can we have some swag can we have
something here a turn because we're kind
of doing this for free but at the same
time a lot of companies do understand
that yeah you don't for free but you
know we have a lot of swag laying around
we might as well give you some yeah give
you a t-shirt give you some stickers it
says you know we love it we love it all
so you know let's take it so you know
shortly after we were given a kind of
email where they were glad for it they
were like you know we understand those
issues we understand that we can't
really cover a thing and yeah tell us
what you have shortly after I was also
we had the C seed into this a developer
which kind of got involved into this and
we were able to directly talk to the
developer involved to kind of have that
issue or issues and you know get that
patch so as a result the actual I
believe he was a co-founder of their
futu
basically told us you know we can send
you a free few you know cases of free
beer and we're like damn I'm right
trigger
ESMA salt we kind of you know produced
some proof concepts because usually when
you provide a service you're kind of
giving more of a report when you're
disclosing to bugs you kind of not
really doing in a report style they're
not paying you to do a report i'll see
don't waste your time too much they have
all the time in the world and if they're
not paying you you might as well do it
in a yeah proper way but without wasting
too much time to kind of you know
constructor report on that sense so yeah
few proof concepts what it does all you
need really to kind of do that as was
old jason holla bill on the way we
actually got free bill so that was one
of the better kind of installments we
did know
so this yeah i put it to free kind of
principles to disclosure and you know
you got communication without
communication you don't really have
anything begin with and you're kind of
go in the wrong path because you're
gonna go to have an open disclosure or
you know you do something that's gonna
annoy them because they weren't warned
they won't talk to you it's not really a
good way to kind of engage with a vendor
or engage with a company
integrity that's a big one because you
want to kind of keep your integrity with
a you know disclosure because if you
kind of go this wrong way you know and
you're kind of going for some you know
hey what kind of asking for some staff
but asked for money or we're doing
something yeah it's kind of gonna kind
of seem as if you're doing something
maliciously and that's why you kind of
want to keep your integrity the whole
way forward even if you hey you can send
some money to another account that you
know you are keep your integrity there
where you can go well we didn't though
so that's why we're disclosing us and
that's really why you want integrity in
this transparency always have complete
logs of exactly what you've done every
network you've touched every subnet
everything so just in case it goes wrong
or even if it doesn't you want to be
able to go that come
I feel like you know we've done this
we've done that we've connected to these
networks we've you know attached to this
computer and this is what we've done and
you know when you're going for it they
really appreciate that because it makes
it easier for their job they can look at
you and logs and be like okay
bet your hosts them that's you know we
know what you've done cool yeah we
understand that you're just disclosing
it purposely and you're not actually
trying to be malicious you're not hiding
yourself through all these tunnels
moving on to AXA this is actually for a
kind of a developer for AXA which we
actually disclosed to and we actually
went about kind of the issue was the
company didn't actually have a proper
presence so we had to get a hold of
their clients which happened to be you
actually was one of them great team they
have their own search which is perfect
and yeah it's it helps us out a lot when
we can go to a client if you like hey
one of your developers is you know kind
of doing this and we'd like to get a
hold of them and that kind of helps us
you know reasonably disclose these
things to them so they got in touch with
the company which you know this year
actually come to contact with us and he
actually you know responded saying well
we understand there's a lot of problems
with our thing and you know we kind of
be interested in using user services so
that was a case we did there risks in
disclosure there's you know quite a few
risks when you disclosed legal threat
yeah pretty self-explanatory
which kind of results to you can sued a
half the time just legal threats half
the time you're gonna see a lawyer at
your door they're gonna kind of you know
knows either way in
depending on how yeah your exposure is
how deep he went into network what
you've really done and
how serious they say that kind of
implication if this see you know hey
clients are gonna be affected
hey client or stakeholders gonna say hey
yeah what's this they're gonna be
interested to kind of see you out of
talking because they will try that
they'll try every way that they can you
could go to jail
that is a very likely you know thing
that's gonna happen and a lot of people
didn't realize when they're going to you
know responsible disclosure or are they
going to kind of screw research that
there's a very good likelihood that you
may go to jail
because the CMA is pretty loose and
we'll get into that later
hey you can't go salted as I found out
once going to a trade show that after
talking to a vendor for so long and
we'll get to that one in a bit that you
can actually get assaulted by at the
vendor you're disclosing to because
sometimes they do not like you talking
about the incident and sometimes they do
not like when you talk about it on
Twitter but that's the yeah that's kind
of the risk you take and yeah we got a
great you know pendous kind of bingo
going from Pentos banners which kind of
you know kind of outlines exactly how
you know pen testers get hold their you
know crumbs are sometimes it's just hey
it was a feature you know it's as simple
as that and that's a real big issue for
us because it's not a feature it's a
buck but so going on to the amazing
company that we you know had a bit of an
issue with kind of at the you know late
last year into the media we had a bit of
a kind of issue of a fender we actually
were in touch with FBI as a result
because of this very hitless we needed
to make sure that you know companies and
clients were aware that hey you're you
know vendors not doing anything about
this so we kind of need to make sure we
have a back-up plan in case someone
actually realizes what's gonna happen
long story short we spoke to the company
and yeah
kind of said you know while on occult
with FB honor we said well they said
we'd like to buy you out
and we ran okay but we do provide a
screen service and you know if you're
willing to we can provide reports and we
give you a ride up and yeah we're
estimating 140 hours so we kind of gave
them that fair go we gave them exactly
what we were going to provide and yeah
that's kind of how you normally go about
your business clients but in the sense
they actually seem to be agreeable and
went you know we're going to work for
the financial aspects we're gonna want
you to delete anything that's you know
kind of incriminating for us or that's
gonna kind of make us look bad and it
took a you know quite a while into
January when is up in the end we were
like well you know where's the documents
every every week it was like well now
we're ready you're gonna send us this
we're ready with our documents when you
guys gonna send us your documents and
they just kept saying you know they kept
putting it off bring it on bring it on
and like subscribe a trap right so I
actually went to see the client at a
trade show she kind of put a face to a
in an email and as a result I was
actually assaulted and about an hour
later I was given nice email saying well
you know stuff you guys we're gonna you
know want you to do this I've watched go
see yeah and yeah as anyone that's
actually rehearsing law or actually
knows lawyers you'd understand that
there's not actually a proper legal fret
it was just made is baseless but yeah
it's scary to most people it's like well
yeah I need to lawyer up or I need
to do this nut I'm in trouble yeah so we
had a kind of nice kind of reply to them
which they weren't appreciative of and
they kind of went away so it's nice
there but yes it's away from resources
for also the researcher because we've
put months of our effort into it
we've got no return if anything we've
actually lost money on you know our
lawyers on our kind of resources
everything no very long
so yeah reward says closure you know you
get some swag yes my maybe yeah maybe
it's public bug grab me amazing if it's
not you might not yeah you might just
kind of get thank you
and that's really what you expected this
kind of job when I was starting out like
nine out of ten companies who just say
well thank you for that yeah
wait small or yeah we just don't provide
this and that's the case with most
companies so it's you know it's pick and
choose and so kind of monopoly kind of
you know you're kind of gambling other
resolve that one company might want to
services or one company might one choose
you
legal issues there's quite a lovely
issues there but the main ones in sigmay
and Syria and the CFAA we won't really
go too much into but see may affects us
in the UK so we can go into that right
now
yeah so what is hacking and going to
yeah DK government's hacking is really
kind of not really a good term it's it's
really you know as long as you do
anything on like a PITA that's kind of I
will go into the actual act in a second
but really it's yeah a cheetah nature or
anything kind of unauthorized access in
pedo and they don't actually define a
computer properly and you know that can
be a serious issue because when you
don't define what a computer is you're
kind of looking at a technology he's
kind of done something that's out of
scope in the senses yeah you might have
just logged into a account that was
already logged in and yeah kind of you
know authenticated against the default
account and that's an issue so you know
as the Crown Prosecution Service will go
they'll go through quite a lot of the
law and they'll kind of consider you
know what fraud was a anything else in
their sense kind of you know
a little bit descriptive and that's kind
of an issue for us so computer misuse
Act really defines for kind of sections
is you know I don't has access to key
material and compute material is not
defined we don't define material self so
it's very broad and you know it could be
anything you know with intent and that's
a big one if he knew what you were doing
you're actually looking at a lot more
time than if he didn't if you were just
you know misusing computer once to use
kind of what they're looking at
prosecuting for and usually it's lapping
the rest when it's with intent you're
kind of looking a bit longer still
you're looking at the kind of high end
of two years so you're not too much into
it
but it's still pretty scary to think hey
I'm gonna get locked up for about a year
and do like he is you know time served
in that sense reckless plus you know it
could be I've destroyed data and that's
really was looking at is yeah I've
destroyed some data from the company
yeah
doesn't matter what the data is could
have been in a cache faster than
anything but you're looking at the
higher end of the scope which you know
we'll get into in a second
if you you know touch say a SCADA system
or anything that's you know kind of
controlling actual things like hospital
or something you're looking at you know
a lot of time so I'd kind of move away
from your phone safaris where you going
hey IFE system because some my offices
IOT systems actually you know effect the
real world and that's where you're gonna
look at some serious harm if you do
something wrong and you know sometimes
we like to you know press the on-off
button and see what happens but let's
kind of steer away from that and less we
know what it's actually doing so you
know you can be convicted for up to 14
years and that's kind of a serious
factor to realize when you're doing
anything relating to screw research if a
company doesn't know you know hey I'm
kind of just researching this
I'm looking into system oh it might be a
you know default gateway it might be
anything as soon as it says you know you
need to login or you need to be
authorized you look handsome trouble now
and then there's the even worse factor
when you're going into actual you know
damage of the network or damage of an
actually students wire from where you
know we're talking about you know SCADA
system easier you could access anything
that's really serious in that nature and
that could actually result in life
behind bars
so yeah the u.s. actually has quite a
nice the system in that sense because it
actually defines you out you you're
looking at ten years maximum twenty in
the sense of you know you're going to
serve some time but you're gonna be you
know watched that's where the survey
comes in and that's where yeah you have
to still know about it in the sense that
you know even though you're not in the
US and even though you probably don't
think you know you're gonna be kind of
pushed towards the you know US law as
long as that company has any stake hold
in the u.s. it has any stake holders in
the u.s. it has anyone that's remotely
involved in the US you have to be aware
of the CFAA because the survey they can
easily get you on as long as someone in
the company is from the US and that's
why yeah it's an operating us your
bidding trouble does I've stakeholder so
Phyllis you're in trouble you can be
extra and that's you know that's a nice
fact to know you can actually be tried
in the US and as you know something
whoops no yeah Marcus oceans
it's a step in the right direction we
are getting kind of used to this
yeah this is quite a new topic everyone
really think of ski research is this big
thing people think oh she research a
student here now I'm even yeah bug
bounties everything it everything
relating to security has a sense of like
InfoSec that the sense it's is still new
as much as it's been around for you know
ten
twenty years it's not really been in the
sense that we can close bugs to
companies because a lot of companies
back then you could go hey I've got a
problem and they weren't really looking
into it in that sense so you know we've
got enough food subscrive Center
actually has posted really that you know
we understand that issue we'd like to
engage with companies to kind of build a
bug bounty program and they've actually
done this by doing yeah they've got
involved hacker one they've had to push
them involve hacker one Katie was very
from ludus Trudy she's come getting both
of this she's also been involved with as
we go to the next one the international
standard ISO 291 the four seven so yeah
yeah so those kind of things to look out
for you can get it for like free a few
Oscar nicely otherwise hundred pounds
give or take worth looking over even the
2014 version is free now I believe and
this is worth you know seeing what to do
because it's really kind of giving us
standard to go to a company and be like
well you know I followed these you know
I'd like to kind of you know make you
aware of this please don't sue me please
give us a report or yeah please do as
you can but yeah be nice to us how do
you disclose do they have a bug bounty
program yes perfect grass you know go to
the pub bug bounty program policy and
kind of goes that way about how to do it
on the other side do they not is there
ready to communicate with them do they
have a you know scree page I advise any
company that doesn't
so you actually include a screen text
file because everyone looks for it
nowadays and that's the best way to kind
of get involved with you know scurry so
just because they will be looking for
that if not is there any other way to
copy a hold of them do they have a
security team kind of way do they have
any contact details about a department
that could be it helps you as we
down they do Congrats they don't get
ready to kind of research into how to
contact them look at you know do have a
Facebook page Twitter page Instagram
page anything that could kind of lead to
you know contacted them which we've kind
of lead to another company which would
kind of give you information on how to
contact the right Department or the kind
of people who will be involved in that
sense and that's what you want to do you
really want to get the right Department
off because if you get just anyone
involved you know the social media team
is not gonna help you yeah but kind of
widest of plug banners or you know the
kind of widest vulnerabilities and
that's the way to go forward yeah how do
you disclose if it's you know it's
something serious look at going to cert
look at the e FF look at legislative
organizations which you know would
include so for example or yeah NCIC
anyone who's gonna really kind of be
helpful as we've done in the past we've
got involved because we believe you know
kind of people who are wise needed in
that sense that yeah if this was a risk
factor of you know critical or some
sense how do we kind of mitigate this
and you know you kind of want to make
people aware of this so you want to go
to the right kind of organizations that
sense if you've done something wrong and
you know as long as it's sort of our
ability you know potentially talk to zff
they're very helpful
they'll give you advice potentially look
at kind of a safe harbor program you
know which kind of you know protects you
in some sense to kind of if you don't
give that information out but without
you know any recognition of yourself or
you know kind of mitigate your own risk
as well and yeah that's kind of a little
bit into how we do through research and
how screw so it can be good and can be
bad there's no right way to do it and
we're still learning and you know that's
the way to go forward no thank you
[Applause]
so I started my first network engineer I
found out that I prefer you know the
streets other things I actually broke
into my school systems when I was
younger as a result I actually found
like I was like hey you know they're
rewarding it's like attaboy kind of
thing and it's interesting that that was
an attaboy because nowadays it's not and
that's kind of where you know problem
now but I kind of felt well thanks
everyone's kind of rewarding in that
sense so I kind of moved to hey what if
I break into big systems so I learned
that it's not all attaboy
but in the end they will you know reward
you if they see necessary and so I
fought well it's still a good community
if you're involved in InfoSec it's
amazing community as we are all here
you know InfoSec is a great thing but
the corporate size not as good as we
think but it's getting there and that's
why as we progress as the years go on
yeah we're gonna get to a deploy to
everyone but as long as you follow the
rules and regulations as is safe so what
your people for example screw
sandbox escape it's kind of way to do it
yeah purposely releasing disclosures so
you think they go to harm kai I'm not
sure that's their purpose but it is in
that sense I
it's I don't feel that house you know
tabatha has done it is kind of
responsible I don't feel that they've
done it it's kind of better the
community I feel that they've done it
because I can and I feel that yeah of
course harm you're doing it maliciously
in that sense and as much as they might
not think they've done it in that way
and as I think I'm a few people few I'm
not gonna mention their names but a few
come in of people have actually said
well yeah they're going for a lot or
something it's still not a way to you
know disclose something even if you
think hey yeah I'm going for a lot I'm
you know stressed or anything I'm just
gonna release these it's there's no
excuse to how you go about it's you know
just closing anything you have to do it
responsibly regardless as long as you've
mentioned to that company and if they've
ignored you after a year or something
Shawn look at disclosing yeah we go you
know often we go one ninety days is a
good time to kind of respond to this
focus and I still think you still want
to give them some advance warning even
as you go you want to go off tonight as
we go well I'll give you a month now
I've got it ready here's the pages are
they yeah if you can't patch that in
time wrong time or something give them
advance warning again that yeah after
they elapse of time hey this is an issue
if you're just going straight out well
yeah you're breaking some laws making a
lot of issues there's gonna cause a lot
of havoc in the FSA community luckily we
all follow Texas care phone we can go
well a lot of these are kind of useless
they do have some nice ones but a lot of
them you know they're not going to be
relevant that yeah if it's something
else it can be same as a troubling issue
[Music]
frameless Microsoft that'll only have so
needed and they still thanks to release
thanks i I feel when it's a bigger
company there is actually as I've worked
I understand that there's a lot to go
through it's not just that they can't do
it at 90 days they can't do at 90 days
it's just that it's it's troubling in
that sense that hey yeah we're a big
company we can't just go after a bug
every day so we have to kind of create
this timeline and a lot of you know
people like Microsoft for example they
have actually different people who don't
actually work at the same time working
on the same project so they're not all
involved in that same thing but they are
involved in how to fix it so yeah I
believe you know you kind of have to
give them more than 90 days and I think
we're just learning how to do it the
still so even though we've said 90 days
is acceptable we've kind of learned that
and I think by now we've actually
learned that 90 days is still not
acceptable we probably should look at
longer times just like Randall oh yeah
[Music]
this is here at a brokerage house no
sense I've dealt with over the past you
know dealing a zero days it's will be
dangerous now he's actually so most
people actually sighs away from doing
that just because you know you kind of
evolved to nation-states and stuff now
and it's just you don't want it but you
say that but it's you know see seller
you know Microsoft zero day for you know
main office your day so East European
company country and you're looking
Stuart I mean yes it's five figures
still it's not it's not too much if you
were to disclose out responsibly you
probably get yeah maybe a little bit
left but at least you get the
recognition and you can actually say
you've done that because we've you
really want to say hey I've disclosed to
a nation of state probably not and you
know can you look at your safe you know
you look at yourself to say way knowing
that you know you're Terry's line
hacked because well we know what apts do
we know what people do when they're you
know involved from that kind of sense we
know what's gonna happen with those zero
days do you really want to be a spear
researcher who wants to disclose yeah to
governments they have their own you know
departments they have thrown you know
professionals and you know they have
loads of your days the issue is do you
want to you know kind of you know add to
that probably not so it comes back to
integrity in that sense that's the first
thing thing to say because I believe
it's a bit of your it is again you do
that a bit because I believe when I do
it I look at the company itself
I look what that what they do I look at
their kind of founders and you know
their age range I go well then you to it
you know they're a small company that
startup or you know they're a big
company but they're young guys old guys
I go I kind of build that kind of you
know reverb I I do for fun I come you
know my clients in that sense but I
think I will still send an email to
every single company that I finally just
go to work because I will just go well
you know you still have this issue
it's how I go about closing it to them I
think that's you kind of build a
template around what that company does
and you have to kind of profile that
company and then go I'm gonna do it in
this way because you want to make them
aware in the safest way there you go
well they're gonna read this you know
they're they're 30
or they're 50 and you want to go it well
they're gonna look at this and be like
oh yeah these guys are nice chest
they're not like they're not gonna you
know they don't ask you for money
they're not doing anything where you
know they feel intimidated by that sense
you don't wanna make your clients are
intimidated and that's kind of the way
to do it
[Music]
have the answers that question so we
actually in-house we use a in terms for
which we've developed which kind of
scans most of our your hunters and
they're kind of quite like shown but we
kind of do it in a sense where we have
two different services and our kind of
palos how we go about payloads and we
kind of get a nice list of companies so
we kind of go from those and we kind of
it might take a year before we get to
them but it depends on the priority you
know what kind of issue it is and we go
from there but for anyone that's going
involved in it I think yeah just pick a
company but pick a company that's
probably involved in a bug bounty
because a bug Valley is gonna be you
know the best way to do it because when
you're going like us you're kind of
looking for them to get you as a service
so it's actually better if you go you
know to a pea size or something and you
go network with a company and go well oh
yeah we can provide the service it's
probably not good to do what we do where
you just open email kind of like kind
like a like you're and scare and that's
okay just like hey we found this can you
wire us that money but it's not in that
sense it's yeah it's much nicer but it's
more yeah we can provide the service
if not we can give you our basic package
it's kind of more of a sales tactic
where we have this package but we can
defeat dispatch and that's kind of the
way that we kind of aim to do it