so today I will introduce to you my work
in statistical security for Internet of
Things actually I'm a first year PhD
student and this is my work so far so
first we will introduce the IOT security
problem and after that we will introduce
the motivation behind our work and then
we will introduce what we we did so far
so as we can see the IOT security
problem is an emerging problem nowadays
because of first the total number of
active IOT devices connected worldwide
is expected to increase by 22 billions
by 2025 so what's the problem of that
the problem that we have a very poor IOT
security measures especially in the IOT
devices we use in the high-density
applications so as we can see we have
90% of the devices collects 90% of the
devices collected at least one piece of
personal information and also 70% of
devices used and encrypted natural
service 70% of the devices along with
their cloud and their apps enable an
attacker to Untied enta phi a valid user
accounts and 80 % of the devices along
with their cloud and mobile applications
fail to require password of sufficient
complexity and
also a recent research showed us that
there is 25 vulnerabilities in the most
10 used IOT devices in the world
so all these vulnerabilities ly lead to
a lot of IOT security incidents in the
recent years as we can see from the
chart developed by the cyber threat
report in 2019 that in 2018 the cyber
attacks increased by 200% than the cyber
attacks in 2017
which is a really very big number we can
remember the ransomware attack happened
in the NHS and cause the NHS to lose
like 63 billion pounds in order to fix
and to install high security devices are
along the NHS and the funny thing that
third of the devices infected by the
ransomware where IOT devices used in the
health sector and also we can remember
the famous Mirai attack which is which
happened in 2016 and led to most of the
East Coast most of the East Coast in the
u.s. lost its connectivity to the most
popular internet service providers like
Amazon and Facebook so the me right
button it was a distributed denial of
service attack and it used along with
routers it used
CCTV cameras which the problem with CCTV
cameras it it has a default password and
user name used with it so as we can see
from this chart that the traffic this is
one of the the traffic in the affected
companies with Mirai in 2016 and we can
see here we can see here the normal
behavior we can see here a low traffic
and there are several attacks and there
is several attacks up to two hundred and
fifty gigabit per second so if we had a
mechanism to in the IOT device itself in
order to know that this device is
behaving abnormal is not behaving in a
normal way so we can and then we have a
mechanism to block this device then we
can we could save we could save like
millions or yeah so what is the solution
the solution one of the solution for
this is not the only solution of course
one of the solution is anomaly detection
and as we can see the an animal
detection is to find the anomalous
behavior
at to find the anomalous behavior of of
one dimension at some points and then to
the key to declare anomaly so so to to
have the anomaly detection we should
know the normal behavior and then we
could know if there is anything go wrong
with in anytime after that so what is
that challenges for IOT for anomaly
detection in the IOT set up so the f-101
challenge is the anomaly detection in
the high-density IOT in our networks in
the massive IOT because we are using low
cost and low energy and massive numbers
of IOT devices so what happens that we
have low cost and low energy devices so
we could not do very complicated
security measures at the device end and
also we have a very high number of
devices used massive numbers so this
mean a very huge data we should process
in order to know the normal and then the
anomalous behavior so in order to make
the sorry in order to make this problem
simple we want to develop a distributed
IOT IOT anomaly detection method that is
not complicated not computation
computational complicated and also it
can be done in the device and so it can
use
the device data only and it doesn't need
to use the other devices in the network
data so the problem with that is the
modeling of the normal and anomalous
behavior of the IOT device we can see
from the charts here we have the normal
behavior and the anomalous behavior on
the other side the normal behavior we
described the number of packets per
second in one day for this device is a
motion sensor we took this data from we
have them we have the the data source
downside so
as we can see here the volume of the
traffic is is not high in the first in
the first chart and it is very high in
the second chart but it is very bursty
that means we have the number of packets
sent per second by the motion sensor is
from 0 up to 80 packets per second and
in the other side in the normal behavior
it is from 0 to 20 packet packets per
per second and as we can see we cannot
if we want a real-time detection for for
this scenario we cannot fix like I mean
and said if it is above this mean then
we have anomalous behavior or rum if it
is down this mean we have a normal
behavior so we should characterize as as
well the inter arrival time and also the
the number of packets sent per second
that together so as we can see from the
two challenge challenges we described we
described before we need a real-time and
a distributed algorithm which is not
very complicated
and we need also to use oh we don't have
we need to use we we need to use not a
high volume of data so the IT security
suggested scheme the first we so this is
our word is a statistical solution this
the first
so this is done this is the number of
packets sent to each IP this is the
number of packets sent to each IP
address in the first chart we can see
the IP address here is the IP address of
the gateway which has the highest number
of packets sent and in the second chart
where where is the attacked traffic we
have lots of other IP addresses and you
can see that this is not the normal
behavior from this chart so what what is
our solution our suggested solution is
so our suggested solution is do the Q
modeling for the income traffic first we
get we cluster their income traffic into
different packet sizes and each packet
size we have a stream of traffic we
enter it into a queue that have a
service time which is greater than the
the mean Araya mean arrival time of the
packet and then from this we can model
the delay or the queue size you can see
the chart down you have the queue size
per second as and as you can see it is
coming up and going down depending on
the number of packets sent per second so
we can see the difference between the
normal behavior and the animal's
behavior when we use our methods so in
the normal behavior you can see that the
keel is building up and emptying and
within a certain range and for the for
this type of attack
this view is building up infinitely and
as you can see we set up a threshold
so after this threshold we assume that
every point after exceed this threshold
is is regarded anomalous point and so an
attack can be declared how we can choose
the throw shot becomes to the threshold
off from the complimentary CDF
the delay will be modeled earlier so
what we did is for for 30 days we have a
complimentary CDF for each day and from
this complimentary CDF we set up a
reasonable threshold and then we have
the mean for 30 days and as you can see
when we set up the threshold it was in
this case 1 1250 we declared an anomaly
in 700 7000 seconds and it was 2,000
seconds later than the actual attack so
we can we can always reduce the
threshold so we have an early detection
but there is a trade-off between the
early detection and a false positive
alarm still in some cases yeah so the
future work is to develop simultaneous
fuse for different package sizes so in
our analysis we used just one stream of
packet size which was the for the TCP
protocol in for our IOT device and also
reducing the difference between the
detection and the actual attacks are by
selecting optimum threshold updating
threshold to his time so because we know
that the behavior of IOT devices is not
uniform in most cases like for example
in the motion sensor or in the IP
cameras or so we have a normally heavier
that changes with this time slightly and
also we are starting to develop our own
testbed and assess the real-time
application of our algorithm thank you