I thought I would start the
controversial title and we'll see how we
go
apparently I'm to get you all excited so
that you start the two days in good
style so we'll see how well I manage to
do that
I do a number of keynotes through the
year I have to confess I prefer these
because normally this folks in suits and
I'm talking about
why cyber risk is something they should
care about or why it's really important
and the likelihood I kind of get the
feeling I'd be preaching to the
converted if I did that so I thought I'd
do something a little bit different and
I thought I'd talk about something else
it's a little bit closer to my heart
which is to have a little bit of an
inward look at the security industry and
the way we behave the things we do and
why I think some of the stuff we do is a
little bit broken maybe very broken and
therefore what can we do to maybe change
what we do to actually have a bigger
impact to make the world a better and
safer place so a little bit about me 24
years living in Cheltenham we'll leave
it there certain doughnut-shaped
building lovely career I think I
recognize a few faces as well so they
are amongst us but about three and a
half years ago I had an opportunity to
become C so for the RBS group it meant
to move to Scotland which I've said that
is very nice but doesn't quite agree
with my waistline but for me it was a
great opportunity because I'd spent many
years sign government telling industry
and other government departments what
they should do to be secure and I was
very conscious that I'd spent of my
twenty four years in government about
half of those were doing that kind of
job and I was really concerned that I
was talking from the position of an
ivory tower and I wanted to demonstrate
to the world or at least to myself that
I could go and do a job where actually I
do have a fixed budget
I do have fixed resources I do have
business priorities and that I could
balance all of those and still do
security really really well so that's
what took me to Edinburgh
for those of you that don't know RBS
group you might just think Royal Bank of
Scotland to put into context RBS group
oh yes robbing Scotland we own that
worst Koontz child and Coe Adam and O
test my memory now but Papa yeah a child
and Co which is the oldest one of the
oldest private banks in the world dates
back to 1640 sometimes it feels like RIT
was inherited from 1640 but we have to
keep it safe and secure nonetheless and
given all of that that means that I'm in
the in this I think interesting position
of having to secure about 70,000 staff
some of whom can spell security and
about 19 million customers for whom they
are nine times out of ten the target of
the attack mutters using technology that
we have not given them so my problem is
to look at that bigger picture and work
out how we can keep customer knees safe
and as I see so my job is quite broad so
I do information security I have the
interesting job of physical security so
I get all of the pretty diagrams of what
happens when a bomb goes off outsider
headquarters or a London offices that's
quite interesting and I'm also
accountable for fraud prevention as well
so my job is to put in place the
controls that protect our customers and
help prevent their and fallen victim to
fraud or more each increasingly nowadays
scams so I think that's kind like any
interest in portfolio things to look
after but I've learnt a lot and I think
my view on security has changed from
when I was sat in government giving
advice to where I'm now sat with the
budget and those responsibilities so
we'll start with a bit of a history
lesson some examples of why I would
assert that what we're doing isn't
working
nineteen sixties blank looks Captain
Crunch few nods I don't want to know the
significance of Captain Crunch
someone shout out Captain Crunch and the
whistle exactly the the interesting
about Captain Crunch was that they gave
away a free toy in the 1960s it was a
whistle and it turned out that that
whistle was a perfect 2600 Hertz which
is pretty innocuous until you discovered
that AT&T s phone system used a 2600
Hertz tone to tell the exchange that
you'd put a coin in the machine in the
pay phone so what they were doing the
the young scamp's as they were were
going up to the payphones because I
think in the u.s. local calls are free
but they would pick up the handset they
would blow the whistle down the handset
the exchange would go thank you for your
money you could make a long-distance
phone call to me and I'm sure Sameer is
that not a bit like client-side security
of something we deemed to be a bit bad
and that was in the 1960s what are we
now have 50 odd years later and still
making the same mistakes so in 50 years
we haven't really learned that lesson
particularly well I mean we all know it
but generally as a technology industry
still makes a mistake would anyone like
to guess where the when the first
documented buffer overflow was he
guesses very very close 97 that not
quite 1977 1972
so 1972 there's an academic paper and I
was trying to find it last night and I
was really struggling as I was writing
my notes so I haven't able to find the
title as an academic paper published in
1972 it doesn't call it a buffer
overflow but it basically describes the
vulnerability that's a buffer overflow
the fact that you can insert too much
information into the allocated memory
and overwrite adjacent data so that was
1972 nearly 40 a former metal riff
expelling me 48 49 years ago have we
solved that problem yet not going by the
list of vulnerabilities I get have to
patch every month so in 40 odd years we
haven't fixed that lesson I'll move for
a little bit more in time 1990s Mitnick
if you
not Mitnick was famous for UNIX was a
she was more famous for social
engineering so a lot of what Mitnick did
was phony that the telephone companies
and just asking them how stuff worked or
asking people for the passwords he's not
the first evidence of a confidence
trickster or confidence artist that goes
back in the histories of time and yet
today one of the biggest problems I have
to tackle is people phoning up my call
centers trying to social engineer people
on the end of the phone or more commonly
phoning that my customers and persuading
them to do things that ideally isn't in
their best interest so again that's been
going on for decades and we still
haven't got a solution for confidence
artists yet so maybe what we're doing
isn't working
2003 another landmark in InfoSec history
anyone like to guess what happened 2003
sequel slammer
yeah some I'm in the fortunate position
I know David Litchfield and he still
talks to this day about the horror of
when he got that phone call to say that
proof of concept she published has now
been used against everybody I think it
still gives him nightmares but in 2003
one the biggest and fastest spreading
worms in history hit the internet Lee
you know it ground various backbones to
a halt there's lots and lots of
organizations that lost service because
of slammer you the thought would have
learned something from that
yeah 2017 we had one a cry and not
picture Island 2016 we have the mirror I
bought so again will not learn in the
lessons of history and what and you're
I'd like to dig into why that is the
case so if it's not working what is it
that we're doing wrong and I think
there's a couple of things so if I'd go
through them feel free to heckle if you
think I'll you could disagree and then
as I go for each one I'll have a bit of
a explore of what maybe we can do to fix
that so to start off with
we are two key we love our cyber does
all the hype is extraordinary it truly
it truly horrifies me the things that
are in the press and in the papers that
our own industry are saying about cyber
don't get me wrong we've done some great
work I think it's really good that
stories about heartbleed and want to cry
and patch in actually make it to the
front of the BBC or on the nine o'clock
news do you make it into the red top's
that's not the problem I have the
problem is the message we send with
those we say over and over and over and
over again the sky is falling in it's
the end of the world
this next vulnerability is going to
bring doom and Armageddon to the world
and it never happens
there was a gent I hope he's not here
because I know he's relatively local was
quoted heavily I believe he was Miss
misreported but he was heavily quoted
for saying 2017 was going to be the year
a bank went bust because of a cyber
attack the amount of admin that created
make I instantly had the board on my
back Chris what do we have to do we
don't want it to be us but when are we
2019 and has a bank gone bust as a
result of cyber attack no we've had some
big incidents we've probably a lot of
instance over the years i doing 2017 was
particularly special it's just more
reported but we've not having one good
burst and my challenge with all that
kind of dazzle and Hyde is that we will
get to the point where our message will
no longer be heard a bit like yeah
calling out the Fox attacking the Sheep
and then you know all that kind of good
stories eventually they'll start to call
our bluff and say it won't happen and
that's when we'll have a really good
problem because we'll have missed our
opportunity
I think we've in a great place now the
interest is there I do have the board
phone me up quite regularly when they
see something in the paper and I quite
like that they do that I had this
interaction I don't like that the
Baroness at the Baroness has a hotline I
think she's got my phone number on speed
dial
and when she phoned me on Boxing Day
about
Specter a meltdown and that was an
interesting way to spend my Christmas
but we've got a great opportunity
because the interest is there I think we
now need to look and change how we talk
about cyber so when I'm talking to the
board I don't talk about sorry fast if I
could banish the word cyber I'd be a
really happy mountain because it doesn't
mean anything so when I talk to the
board and the execs and the regulators
because I'm in the fortunate position as
a CEO of a financial institute I have to
have a one-to-one with the regulator
every quarter and I don't just have one
regulator I've got two regulators in the
UK I've got one in Ireland I've got one
in Hongkong wanted Singapore you get
that you get the image and each day our
Chinese regulators will come and talk to
me about what we're doing on around
cybersecurity and I invariably annoy
them because the first minute able to
stop talking about cyber because it
doesn't mean anything and the way I
explain it to my executives is that we
need to start talking about the things
we care about so as a bank we care about
fraud we care about protecting our
customers money we care about ensuring
that customers can do transactions we
care about the availability of our
services as a result we care about our
intellectual property and to do all of
those things we use technology and
topknot technology can break and can and
will break sometimes that'll be because
someone designed it badly
I don't you fall over sometimes because
hardware fails and sometime it's because
someone took the dial and had a look to
see what happens if you turn it up to 11
but we need to talk about those attacks
that turning the dial to 11 or giving
them a good kick in or whatever we're
talking about in the context of losing
money because we care about fraud or
lose an intellectual property or our
ability or inability to deliver a
service as a result because that's the
outcome so I don't say to my my execs I
want another couple of million pounds
for a cyber thing I always put it in the
contest of I want a couple of million
pounds to reduce fraud against our
customers or I want another couple of
million pounds to ensure the
availability of this new service you're
building and then suddenly the context
is there it's nicely bounded
they get it because they're not
technical experts and then I have a much
better and informed conversation my
seniors and I'd love to see a lot more
of that in the wider community I also
get really irate within out of fear and
uncertainty and outlet guess but off you
wouldn't believe that as the number of
phone calls I got after wanna cry hit
the NHS I had company and company after
company phoned me up and say Chris
you're C so I can solve your wanna cry
problem which wanna cry problem and this
surprised how many companies think they
know my business better than I do
even though they've never spent any time
talking to anyone who works me so
there's a lot of sense selling that fear
by vendors I think we need to tackle
that I'll talk a little bit more about
that later
which kind of leads on to my second
point I believe and this is where the
industry you tend to lynch me I I
believe one of the problems we have is
we talk about security on its own we're
too busy selling secure widget a and
secure widget be and I think that worked
in the early days of the industry but it
isn't the solution going forward so I
get my vendors in nowadays and I don't
want to bind up a security product I
want to buy a secure solution so I think
the days of me buy of me working with
our tech my technology partners I'm
saying right so your boss you've bought
email right to secure email I now need
email scanner on the boundary I'll need
to put something else on the server I
need to roll out Demark and SPF and I
better do something about URLs so I'll
have a sandbox and Technol you get the
picture they buy email and then I buy
about two dozen solutions to make it
work securely or I can buy office 365
that does that all for me
it's a bit of a no-brainer so for me I
think we need to start talking about
stop talking about security in an
abstract way as a separate thing it's
not a separate thing anymore
it should be built into everything we do
we should be buying secure by default
products so all those people in chat
will be smiling because after a mantra
they've been raving about for quite a
few years but I generally believe having
sat there now and having to spend
millions of pounds on add-ons to make
stuff that the business want to use
secure isn't sustainable in the long
term and there's an example of this I
had a musing conversation it was about
my second week at the bank and I won't
that the company will remain nameless
but they're one of our big integrators
they run and as their systems for us and
they turned upon mass there was their
chief exact for this and their head of
widgets of that and and they came in and
they sat down with me and said you know
great to meet you Chris you're in the
bank we do all this wonderful stuff for
for the bank but we don't do any
security and we'd like to change that I
wish point the conversation took a real
nose dive because I just looked at them
out so you do all of this but you don't
do any security I think we need to
cancel our contracts because if you run
our solutions and you're not doing
security I'm sorry but you're not
meeting your contractual obligations I
wish when they kind of left the room and
they came back about a month later very
apologetic and said well here's all the
stuff that we do do but they were very
much seen security is a separate line a
separate thing they sold so they did
system integration over here and I had a
different security team that they were
trying to sell to me and I don't think
that's the answers if any ones we hear
from a vendor and we just get away from
that separation of jobs they don't come
apart anymore we sell it as we here as a
secure solution here's we need to have
awful small space here we go
cool and this isn't just about our
technology as well and this is probably
the bit where I'm probably the most
controversial
well at least amongst my peers most
controversial the way we do security
overall is a bit broke
if somebody wants to deploy a new
solution in a generic company they have
to do a risk assessment they probably
need to do some pen testing they
probably need to fill out a risk form
they'll probably have to go through some
security gates we designed the processes
we have for doing security in a way that
actually gets in the way of the business
our job seems to be make it really hard
for the business and that is why
developers tend to not do security
because it's hard it's it's something
else on top of their day job that they
don't really want to do so we need to
get away from that there's a company in
Spain anyone who works for me will be
spire at this point because you're never
going anybody know what are
non-newtonian fluid is it's a few knotty
phases there we will give we have some
educated people in the room excellent
would you like to describe the
properties of a non-newtonian fluid yeah
they're harder the impact on a
non-newtonian fluid the more solid it
becomes custard is a really good example
if your filler if you watch Mythbusters
they filled a swimming pool with with
with custard and discovered you could
run across earth because the impacts of
your feet on the surface made it go
solid and you but as soon as you stopped
you sank into it so non-newtonian fluids
are this an interesting property as a
Spanish company they have taken that
filled what is in effect a very long
water balloon with it
and created a speed bump and by tuning
the fluid they've got to the point where
if you hit the speed bump at or below
the speed limit it just squashes out of
the way so you don't feel it it's not
there but if you go over the speed bump
it goes hard and you really feel a jolt
and I think that's what we need to do
with our kind of partners who design
technology our web developers our system
integrators we need to put processes in
place where security is invisible until
you do something wrong and then it
really hurts because at that point
security and doing the right thing is
the easiest route and if we can find
processes and technologies that enable
that suddenly everyone will do the right
thing because it's
painless whereas at the moment we do the
opposite we put lots of things in the
way we make security really hard to do
I assert at least or maybe it's just me
but typically if you're a developer
security gets in the way so I'm really
keen that we change that we will still
need a security industry don't get me
wrong but I think it will change so at
the moment we try to be the leading star
on the stage we want to be the lead
vocalist of the band I think we need to
be a bit more like the car industry so I
remember and this probably show my age I
remember the days when my dad had to go
and have pay extra to have seatbelts
fitted to the car and the days when an
airbag was an optional extra and
anti-lock brakes were really expensive
but they're now all standard there's an
industry that does safety for cars but
we don't really talk about it it's just
features that we inherit when we buy a
decent car nowadays I think security
needs to go that way and then in the
industry side where we're looking at
those features I think we don't need to
start doing some basically some some
moonshot efforts to pop up a bear I
think we have to stop blaming the users
because to be honest to the blue if the
users aren't doing what we need it's
probably as much of our fault as it is
their fault I think we do stop playing
whack-a-mole so we're doing lots of
sticky plasters at the moment I think we
need to stop tackling all of the
symptoms and look at the underlying
issues so if I look at email first email
is invented allegedly in 1971 I think
the SMTP standard RFC 8 for 477 there's
that where's James Lynne when you need
him was in 1980 and we're still using
that and it's only insecure so I almost
take it as an insult on against the
technology industry that we're expecting
people to use unsecure stuff and then we
blame them when it all goes wrong so who
in the industry is reinventing email to
make it secure
who in the industry is working out how
we solve the identity problem
I kind of take it as a damn incitement
as a technology world that it's possible
to spoof an email address listen the
fact that it's possible to spoof a phone
number probably says more about us as
technologists than it does about the
users who fall for the tricks and scam
artists are pulling on them so I think
we as a technology that has been broader
than just security but I think as a
technology industry we need to tackle
some of those some of those issues my
next point is I think we over rely on
education I've talked about we blame lis
users too much some interesting
statistics and I can't claim the credit
for these there's a fantastic professor
at Portsmouth University called Debbie
Ashton Dunn and she shared these with me
did you know that 20 foot 20 to 30
percent of prescriptions and never
filled out that was news to me and there
was some research in the US and that
said in I think the research was in 2012
that identified that not following the
doctor's instructions resulted in
125,000 deaths per year in the US alone
so I look at those stars I go well if
people are willing to die because they
think they know better what's the odds
they're going to listen to little old me
about using a better password probably
I'll hide into nothing
so user education is really important we
can't just ignore it but I think we just
need to look at how we change that and
we need to reframe the conversation we
have between ourselves as experts in the
field and those who aren't in the
medical industry they've taken that
research and they're now looking at that
they don't call it but in effect it's a
a mutually agreed contract between the
doctor and the patient where they
jointly agree what the best course of
action is and by doing it
collaboratively so there's a
conversation between medical
professional and patient they've
discovered that they're more likely to
follow the advice I've been given so
what's what's our security equivalent of
that how do we have a conversation with
non specialists
that says here's the things you've got
to do so one of the things I do in the
bank is I have a conversation with our
staff and it's not necessarily protect
the bank but it's here's some good
things some good practice you need to
get into because it'll protect you at
home it'll keep your kids safe I don't
keep your own money safe and they'll
learn that and that's more of interest
to them and then those learned habits
kind of come to work with them and then
they do better things at work and we've
seen that those behaviors that that
approach to education is actually more
impactful than just saying don't do this
don't do that we've all sort of
recognize it's not just a technical
problem as well Google Chrome Google has
got a great blog post about a change
they meet at May to Google Chrome and I
use this quite a lot because it
demonstrates how when we design stuff we
need to think about how the human mind
works when you go to a site that fails
the SSL check you get an error page
don't you do they one noticed the change
in that error page about 18 months two
years ago mmm few knobs so what used to
happen we got and when you got an
encryption error used to for a big error
pager with lots of information and it
used to give you two options go back or
proceed anyway and what Google discovers
from their instrumentation was about to
first just over two thirds of users
would proceed anyway because you want to
see the dancing countdown you hear a
page in the way of you dancing cat
dancing cat wins so what they did after
a little bit of experimentation is they
changed that error message and they
reduce the amount of information it gave
you and more critically or more
importantly they changed the words on
the buttons so the buttons now say go
back to safety or advanced no customer
education they just change the words on
the buttons and now those numbers have
been reversed less than a third of users
do the dangerous thing
and that was just by playing to how
people think and doing that kind of
behavioral science behind the user
interface and had a huge positive impact
on the way people acted and behaved
online and as an organization we're
taking those lessons and we're trying to
apply them and it's early days for us
but we try to apply them to the way we
design our systems were trying to use
those in the way we write our letters to
our customers one of the big successes I
had was last year and please say I was
in the bank when we started paying a
dividend again fantastic after many
years of making a loss and the success
for me was that the community the comms
team phoned me up out of the blue and
they said we're about to write to all
our shareholders because we need to know
their bank details so we can pay the
dividend but we want to do it in a way
that can't be thought is unlikely to be
abused by fraudsters so we had a great
conversation about things you could put
in the letter how your personalized us
how you put a reference how you loo
links back to our corporate website we
lost all the things we could pull
together to make that letter look as
genuine as possible and difficult for
someone else to then take and abuse it
wasn't perfect because at the end of day
we were writing to people but the fact
that the comms team saw that as an
opportunity that could be used as a
fraud and phoned me up I thought was a
bit of a success so moving on where are
we up to 0.4
are you assert that behind a lot of
things we do and things that are deemed
industry best practice
there is just no science to back it up I
like the fact that Google did a post the
other day that said if you have to
factor weakens your enabled we can see
you have less attacks if you have this
enabled so some real nice science around
passwords and two-factor authentication
backed up with hard evidence and
statistics but that's quite rare I mean
how many conversations do we have around
what's a good password and the bad
password where's the science behind it's
not how long it takes a computer to
crack it or what hash you use it's
bigger than that
I get audited regularly by our internal
audit and old Toyota you don't doing
user entitlement reviews that's bad I
don't go well that's fine that's your
opinion but where's the science to prove
that having that rolled out across all
of our systems will reduce our risks so
we're kind of in a bit of a strange
place where I think we're kind of into
12th century where there's some
perceived good behaviors we're kind of
in the world of leeches if you keep
applying the leech you'll get better and
if you die well you were too ill anyway
and it's kind of like that with security
you need a firewall you need to use
micro segmentation you need to patch you
need to have five layers of protection
if you don't have five layers you're not
good enough but where is the evidence
where's the science where's our
double-blind testing there's a great
book called black box testin and it goes
through lots of examples from not from
medical industry and aviation and
engineering where it shows and explains
where a lot of perceived fault is
actually based on bad science just
because you did something once and the
problem got better it doesn't
necessarily mean that what you did is
the answer because it might have got
better anyway so we need to do more work
so when we are giving advice when we are
making decisions when I'm working out
where I spend my annual budget
I'm trying to avoid that those mistakes
and I we as an industry are a bit bad at
that at the moment so I across across
the bank I've got about hundred and
seventy things I measure month on month
that I really care about and as we make
investments we look to see what happens
to those figures and we see whether they
move in the right way or the wrong way
and we'll do some a/b testing
occasionally and we'll see what that
more how that alters our metrics and
then that helps me demonstrate the value
from the investments are making and
you'll be unsurprised to hear that we've
actually put some stuff in and then
taking it out because actually it made
no difference at all to our security
posture but I can evidence eart but I
don't think many people do that I've got
quite fortunate I've got quite a meaty
security budget you know 19 million
customers drives yeah some some some
some nice budget but how many other
companies who don't have a security team
of my scale and therefore can afford to
do that sort of thing how many are just
taking vendor assertions and just
throwing stuff in because it's been
asserted that that's industry good
practice so I'd love to see more science
around what we're doing that is
defendable and repeatable I kind of
related to that I don't know anyone work
for one of the big four couldn't you
maybe we don't want to admit a big for
consulting firms everything I can spot
you because you can't spin your head low
every one of those has a cyber maturity
thing and they'll all sell it to me and
they'll come along and they'll have
their lists of stuff and they'll compare
me against that list and I'll get a
number it's a Kris today you're a four
what does that mean
and then I'll go to some of the else and
go off sorry Kris you're a two and then
I'll go to another company go well
you're a free and it's not repeatable
which for me just proves that we need to
be more scientific around how we measure
cyber risk there's a great guy called
John Hubbard he's written a book called
how to measure anything it's all about
the quantitative measurement
of stuff and he in particular talks
about risk is absolutely often quite
fortunate that my chief operating
officer who seems to know everybody
knows John
so we're half looking at the work he's
done because I think that's the
direction we feel we need to have
quantitative measurement of risk I want
to get to the point where I can say to
my board the probability of losing
insert number is insert number percent
that's where I want to get to if you
care about losing ten million pounds a
year the probability of that happening
because of security because of a
security of failing is this probability
and that's what I'm going to get to and
we're doing Monte Carlo simulations
within loads and modeling we're taking
lots of raw data feeding them the men
and seeing what happens but I'm a kind
of a exception to the rule is anybody
else doing that isn't indeed in academia
where is that oh fantastic there's a
couple of people doing that just
brilliant
but we're in the minority and when I
talk to other people about this I quite
often get glazed looks it's kind like
you're mad Chris you'll never get it to
work well at one point someone said
you'd be mad to put a man on the moon
but we achieved and we persisted someone
won so you never send yeah you never
invent medicines that you have cure
various illnesses but we did we
persisted and I think we as an industry
need to do more of that cool where we up
to dead another Oh an amusing story so
we talked about measuring risk I saw a
great great great story from from the US
and I think was honest predicting that
things will fail the press I can't know
which President it was had asked the
intelligence agencies what's the
likelihood of this bad thing happening
it was for informing foreign and
military policy so they got a load of
intelligence analysts from all the
different agencies put them in the room
and they they kind of discussed the
topic the likelihood of this bad thing
happening
the end of it they all agreed they all
said it was very likely and that was
good well off to the president there's a
brief and very like yeah mr. president
what you care about
very likely it'll happen and that
informed this policy went on a few weeks
later one of the senators who'd been in
that briefing met the guy who did the
head of the analysis and he said it was
fantastic briefing
he said it's very likely just out of
interest there's a number what is that
is it lies did it very likely not 80%
85% and the hedonist no that's an
interesting question we never framed it
like that so they went back and they got
all the same analysts back in the room
again and they were all asked to put a
percentage probability on something bad
happening and it turned out they didn't
Talde agree agree apparently some people
thought 20% was very likely and some 495
percent was fairly likely but because
they'd use words rather than science and
kind of repeatable processors that
fallen into a false trap or thinking
they all agreed and I sometimes wonder
whether we're in the same boat so if we
can between strength and strength and
that kind of scientific approach that be
really good I am getting to the end
we've got some time to seem better my
next point is around professionalism I
don't think we've solved the
professionalism problem in information
security which kind of kind of saddens
me a little bit before I go into it and
for the people in Cheltenham I'm sorry I
am stealing somebody else's story slight
diversion does anyone know why planes
have round windows if you if you come
from Cheltenham we've heard the story
before you're not allowed to shout it
out anyone know why planes have round
windows yep distribute rest that's
absolutely right
but surprisingly the first commercial
airline airliner had square windows the
Havilland comet when it was first built
first commercial airplane arshad square
windows and it was a very successful
plane and then after a certain amount of
time they start to disintegrate in
midair which is never a good thing when
you try to encourage commercial
commercial air flights and trouble and
stuff but what was interesting was not
so much that the plane lighter
disintegrate was more around what they
did as a result as will bring us full
circle
they built a water tank somewhere down
on the south coast big enough to surf
plane in it and then what they did was
they filled it with water and drained it
again and they repeatedly filled it with
water and drained it and what that did
was emulate the stresses on the fuselage
of changing in air pressure house as you
take off and land and they did this and
what they discovered I think was
something like thirty five thousand
cycles they started to sport hairline
fractures in the skin of the plane on
the score Taniya web square corner met
and at that point they can't realize
that that wasn't that had that had an
issue so what they did next was they
didn't care ound the fleet because
that's quite impactful is they put into
the maintenance manual something that
says every time a flight lands
particularly as it gets towards the
thirty thirty five thousand you need to
do an inspection of the corners of the
windows and if you start to see evidence
of micro fractures you need to replace
that bit of the fuselage and that
stopped the plane from disintegrating in
midair well they then did it was they
started to retrofit stuff to the planes
so they started to change square windows
for round windows one with the curved
corners which again solved the problem
and then further down the line it got
written into a standard that says you
never build a plane with square windows
so if you designed a plane today with
square windows
you probably get a struck off you know
you're not gonna be allowed to practice
engineering anymore you surly probably
end up being in jail for gross
misconduct and that for me is the
fascinating thing because if we go full
circle in 1917 whatever it was we have
1972 we had the first buffer overflow
but we still have engineer as software
engineers making the same mistakes we've
not learned from it if I go back to the
1960s and at about 2600 Hertz whistle
we're still making those same mistakes
today so why is it in engineering
mechanical engineering we have a process
we have a system in place where people
qualify they learn a set of standards
and they are dear to them if you don't
do good practice if you don't learn from
the mistakes of the past
you get struck off and in some cases you
could end up locked away yeah for the
systems we built today which use
software we don't make we don't have the
same rigor you're not held to account
how many CISOs have lost it well I want
to have lots of job how many ceasers
have stopped in a sea circus I had a
bridge now in some cases it can't be
helped breaches happen and they always
will happen but some of them are because
stupid things were done but you just
move on to a different company if you
design a bit of software that's got a
bug in it you just move on and you do
another one
and I'm not saying we need to get to the
point where just because you write a
book you lose your job
but I think we need to get to a point
where we have a set of standards that
help constrain what we do is you can't
design a bad solution we should be
designed in knowing that humans make
mistakes and part of that I think it's a
technology problem that we expect one
person to do everything I've got the
builders in at the moment and I really
know what builds in the moment because
I'm stopa my wallet and they're helping
themselves every day but there's a
carpenter who knows how to work with
wood and there's a brick he who does all
the brick laying stuff there's a there's
a
a structural engineer who will tell them
what the you know how it needs to be
designed to carry the weight of the
building above it there's an architect
or help with piecing all of that
together there's there's probably some
material experts will be able to say
well given the weight load and you need
on that beam I recommend you steel of
this thickness there's a quantity
surveyor who pulls all the parts
together make sure as I've got enough
materials but we don't seem to do that
in technology we think it's acceptable
to have one person who's doing the
security controls and writing the web
interface and doing the code and
probably looking after the operating
system and configuring the firewall and
putting the rules on the content
inspection etc I think we need to
recognize that technology has to be a
team game where each person plays to
their strengths with a bit more
specialism I think and we pull together
multifunctional teams who then deliver
an outcome and people held to account
for the expertise they bring I think
when we start to do that well then fast
start to find out from an engineering
perspective we will be much better
delivering good secure solutions I said
earlier analyst C so I have to speak to
the regulator I'm held to account if I
mess up I won't be allowed to be a C so
in the financial sector again
HR loved telling me there's an orange
jumpsuit in my size
that's really motivational in your media
talk but it's true big companies will
always have breeches but if I'm found to
have been negligent because I didn't do
something or because I lied or because I
hid something I will be held to account
for that I will be fined I could go to
jail and that's because I'm in the
financial sector I don't think that's
the same for all CISOs I think it
shouldn't be that's not just because I'm
suggested that regime I think it's cause
of security professionals we should be
held to account for the information we
get and the guidance in our behaviour
it's a scary fort when
I was gonna mix up equifax had the
breech yeah Zeca max there's lots of
interesting chatter amongst kind of the
seaso community around all US government
are after the sea so they might they
might it might actually file criminal
charges against him and it was surprised
at how many CISOs got really unnerved by
that as a concept all of us in the
financial sense were going well yeah
that's yeah we thinking of us in our
contract but it's not accepted across
the industry I'd love to see more of
that if I look in the medical industry
there's the Hippocratic oath it says
really good stuff like you know doctors
swear to treat the ill to the best of
their ability to preserve the patient's
privacy teacher secrets of Medicine to
future generations etc etc what's our
security info SEC equivalent of that I
think we need one I can be really good
if we had something like that I don't
know what the answer is but you should
know a professional recognition which
isn't just about your ability but your
behaviors and what you'll do in the
future on it is really important which
is why I really like b-sides and I don't
where Joshua is I'm not saying this
justice I'm speaking of besides it's
events like this that I think are really
really important
there's too many big commercial
conferences set up to earn money for big
nameless corporations I love these
little conferences these are the sort
things I'll come and talk to because
this is where we share knowledge between
ourselves this is the real practitioners
learning from each other and it courage
you to make the most of today and
tomorrow
I'm gonna have a look at the weather
well I don't where the car is the
vehicle hacking thing about that looks
awesome so I'm gonna go and broaden my
knowledge there later
I love besides enjoy the day I hope what
I've talked about as being interesting I
haven't sent you to sleep it's been the
power point so enjoy the day and thank
you
any questions we've got their time give
it a jump neither front
love the talk Thank You great you
enjoyed it one question around metrics
the reso metrics company I'll try not to
name them whose metrics now take a lot
of open-source feeds of information back
companies and they've got to the point
now where they're discussing the
possibility of distinguishing in those
whether the company's being audited or
whether it's been breached from your
change in the metrics do you think
there's going to be real visibility into
companies like your own through that
kind of technology and is that going to
change the game in a positive way
potentially there's a couple of
companies to do that in fact I think the
challenge I have with that is that as an
external entity working without the
cooperation that company you don't get
to see what's behind the things you
measure in so as an example there's one
company that repeatedly gives me a
really bad score and when we dig into it
the reason why that happens is because
they can't distinguish between our
customer free Wi-Fi and branches and our
corporate network there are different
addresses we've told them that's a
difference but they but externally it
just looks like hers and I know the same
goes for the telco providers they have a
real headache with some of those
companies because customer behavior
which isn't a reflection on them as a as
a corporate entity often has a negative
impact on their score so I think there
is some value there but I think needs to
be taken with a pinch of salt because it
can be easily diluted by little mistakes
like that now if those companies are
working in cooperation in the companies
and they get the inside then there's
maybe lots of value there's one that we
use internally that look that tracks and
sinkholes command and control for a
malware and they use that as a way of
identifying which companies have got a
problem
and we use it not just to check on us
but to get a feel for what the state is
for our customers because if we know
that our customers been hit with a
particular piece of malware or the UK
he's been targeted by particularly smart
the stuff we can do in response to that
we can work with government and the
other other entities as well as stuff we
do ourselves so I think there is some
value but I'm a little bit worried about
whether it's actually the answer I think
it's probably part the answer hi um when
you say like you like keeping security
in the background it should come with a
product what are some in terms of
integrated security into software
development life cycles what are some
things like processes and methods that
you endorse that you fan are pretty
useful to do that and career results yes
one of the things we're trying to do in
the moment we're really struggling
because the tools aren't very mature is
we're looking at the end-to-end kind of
software life cycle all the way from a
product design through to doing your
code into your test your pre prod tests
and the deployment and we're looking at
how we can hook security tools into each
of those stages so one of the things
we're doing yeah we do and I know many
other companies now do we scan our
source code repository so every time a
developer checks something in it gets
scanned at night and then that issues
bugs back to the user and they can't
merge there but they're there commit
until it passes those scans and then
when they do their first testing we'll
tech know we're looking at how we can
test with symbols and do automated
testing on those binaries because with
the symbols compiled then it gives you
more information and then when you come
to do your next phase of testing we'll
take that symbols out but we'll put it
into over the container or a virtual
machine that you want to deploy and then
we'll scan that and then you can see
there's you go along then we come to
proc I don't need to pen tester because
we've done all of these tests in the
past and then our automated scanning
kicks in and then anything that goes
live on our estate is scanned regularly
for known vulnerabilities and then on
top of that that's where the red team
the penetration testing comes in which
means that developers can be really
agile they can commit and develop as and
when they want we don't get in the way
because we just we've bedded our checks
so a vulnerability scale is just
alongside you know of a compatibility
test and it's just another gate they
need to get through and that's my
aspiration for the future the challenge
is the tool sets for doing that aren't
very mature at the moment so I think
there's something around how we build
those products and work with the vendors
who are in that space be they open
source or Oroville eyes to see how we
can make that better so the questions on
kernel metrics again so you mentioned
that when you get people to give a
verbal description of risk it's kind of
hard to baseline that and I was talking
to a customer the other day about you
know looking they wanted to put some
additional security controls in but it's
working out you can let the company have
a go guessing what their single loss
expectancy is but okay what's your you
know reputational damage and that's you
can pass the back to the board and say
that you can work out how hard it's
gonna hurt you if you get hit but the
question of how likely you are for you
know let's take the vulnerabilities for
example how what's the what's the risk
of you getting hit by you know either
women or zero-day but a newish
vulnerability that you know you're
struggling to get patched it's really
it's really hard to get any decent sort
of numbering on that so how do you it's
not not necessarily for your business
but how do you quantify the risk for say
a you know a smaller company say it's
maybe 10 20 percent I think unless you
and this we get some sort of scoring
system against the score against the the
implementation of security controls on
the company but unless you marry that up
with the actual results of when people
do actually get rinsed the other way for
me to one teams do telemetry they they
know and stuff breaks like you
you can't live stuff until you know when
the break point is and then you can say
right we can we can map the the controls
implemented with the number of people
that got owned from it and then you've
got some date evening news but at the
moment I'm trying to work out and you're
lost expectancy with the customers right
how likely is you're gonna get popped so
I think that's how you calculate the
loss the loss as a result of compromise
I mean there's a lot more data available
now than there has been historically so
I've got I've got a mix of experience
Equifax
you know they've now taken a write that
right down on their risk credit score as
a result of cyber breach so that has a
material impact that you can measure if
you look at mask their write down was
300 circa 400 million dollars I think as
a result of not Petra attack I mean
there's increasing amount of information
and data points that you can look out to
understand the impact and likewise we
trying to work out probability of you
being popped I think you it isn't an
exact science but I'm as we become more
there's there's more visibility of
compromisers I think gives you more
evidence so you I can tell you that if
you prefer
yeah I want to say how I know this but I
if you refer to for example to miss
configure your firewall and leave a
vulnerable Hadoop cluster exposed to
Internet it was two minutes before it
was compromised that's a useful fact
that you can feed into your model in
that vulnerable software with an
external visibility gets hit very very
quickly and I've sat there idea Isis
build up an AWS instance and I just kept
repeating it you know but a vulnerable
service expose it to the Internet and
sure enough on average it was about two
two-and-a-half minutes from being hurt I
think you can do those experiments now
to give you a gauge for likely hurt you
can work out you know size of a company
I know you for our email boundary we we
stopped about 80 some percent of all
emails we just dropped them at the
boundary we never ever delivered them to
a member of staff so that again gives a
gives us a sense of scale of how much
malicious stuff is hitting our external
boundary I
can tell you of the eleven and a half
billion web requests we make every month
I can tell you exactly how many of those
we identified malicious content erm and
again that feeds into a likelihood so we
can you know it's not exact science but
it's better than some medium which is
what we tend to do at the moment and
over time we just need to refine it and
get more data and that's why I've got a
lot of respect for the mask see so
because in the right forums he's been
very very open about how they were hit
what the impact was what they've had to
do to get out and can't get around that
and what it's meant for them as a
company and to have I think it's not you
know it's not being talked about
publicly but in the right forums among
CEOs and other security professionals
that's a fantastic reference point we
can now go back to and say okay this is
what it means when a large corporation
gets hit the norsk hydro again we can
look at that there's a lot of examples
about what happens we've run somewhere
you know they have to stop production
for a number of days you can see what
that means in terms of material impact
we just need to collect that sort of
information and put it in a big melting
pot it won't be a hundred percent
accurate but I think I assert and I'm
happy to be proven wrong that that's
better than what we're doing at the
moment and as long as we're getting
better a year on year then we're heading
in the right direction sounds the
question kind of anyway look your aren't
going to be it for questions okay
however as with any of the talks we're
going to be trying to keep to the
relatively tight schedule but there's a
speaker meeting area that's just through
the way and we'll be encouraging and
asking speakers to meet with attendees
people who are further questions after
the question period then so Chris thank
you very much thank you for coming and
sharing your insights with us if you'd
come