my name is shake work at the scene
security consultant IDT solutions based
in Dubai in the UAE and one of the key
in a discussion . today's around
building security operation centers and
the reason why is throughout the last
two days what we've identified is you
know the cyber threats are going to grow
and already significantly growing and
targeting different types of systems
applications across enterprise
environments and one of the key things
are usually start by Enterprises is
logging and monitoring so the agenda
that we're going to be discussing is the
need to build an enterprise-wide cyber
security operations center the
components of the sea stock what we call
c sub 2 20 and you'll see the reason why
we call it 2-0 the key components of
building SI saket obviously same
solutions which is security information
event management a tooth actually
collects all the logs correlates them
and provide security analytics and
correlation information and also try to
understand specific threat cases that
are within your enterprise environment
itself the most important thing in
trying to identify an attack breach is
to basically build early-warning
detection systems within your enterprise
and this is something that we find quite
often specifically in the Middle East
because it's a hot target you have a lot
of investment within the Middle East
where for example organizations are
building smart cities everything is from
the smart devices from smart phones you
can actually you know if you wanted to
book a train ticket you could do it
through your phones you can pay in a
meeting and taxis everything can be done
through the front door
everything is basically being put onto
smart cities environments and within the
middle east building basically a huge
data store of information from IOT
devices senses which you know developers
can then use to create nice applications
so of course the requirement to then do
perform monitoring and reporting becomes
one more important and as part of the
sea stock of course you need to build
processes procedures in order to
identify exactly how to carry out the
incident response when an incident does
occur so what are the current challenges
onslaught of security data right so
within an enterprise environment you
probably have perimeter firewalls you
have a DMC you have application
firewalls intrusion prevention systems
you might have an internal data center
fire
at the end . you might have anti virus
malware protection daily Prevention's
you have a huge number of different
types of devices within your enterprise
environments each one of them generating
huge amount of logs and as a security
analyst who's basically performing
security operations cannot simply
understand this looks right you need a
tool to be able to correlate them right
and at the same time what we're finding
is that cybersecurity is moving into a
very kind of a precious area because the
the regulations are being enforced by
the government so what we find for
example at least in the region that we
work in that the government is actually
developing information security
standards and enforcing it onto the
enterprise's so just like for example
you have iso 27001 you have a
country-specific security regulations
that is pushed to the enterprise's of
the government's and the government
federal entities they have to comply to
the security standards and that's the
only way the organization is going to
invest in security and implement the
right type of controls so there's a
there's this you know this the dynamics
are changing the other thing also that
we're finding is that the the line
between having a breach and legal
matters or legalities within
cybersecurity is also changing so if you
look at for example in the UK if the
cyber security breach the government has
the right to find an organization for
the negligence of the beach right so I'm
not sure if you guys saw the hacking
attempt that happened in the UK for talk
talk right which wear something like
around four million post API information
was stolen
there's there now under a an
investigation and approximately and
they're going to possibly be fine around
millions of pounds so the point here is
that legal framework is also changing of
course when you're looking at you know
protecting your organization's it's very
common to find that organizations are in
adequately prepared
why because there's no instant there's
no coordinated incident response
there's no understanding of the assets
that you have with digital assets that
you have the system honor the technical
owner who to escalate to and who to
respond to
so typically one of the things we found
and this is a very classic example in
one of the major oil and gas companies
in Saudi was impacted the mouth culture
moon not sure if you if you guys have
heard of the malware but it basically
impacted 40,000 end points within the
organization so first of all the
compromise happened through compromising
privileged access for admittance system
admin for domain controller and then
basically took control of 40,000
machines the malware was then installed
and it and it was a time bomb so
basically it it executed exactly eleven
o'clock on a specific day which
basically removes the Master Boot copy
of the entire endpoints basically making
all the 40,000 machines useless now of
course if you had monitoring controls in
place you could actually be pretty
proactive in understanding what is
happening to environment now that
particular model where was specifically
designed for 32-bit systems now their
servers are running 64-bit architecture
so that's the only reason why the server
is actually survived the attack so we're
saying in the inn at least in the region
that we work in a huge amount of attacks
coming from different organizations
because of you know how active activism
activity geopolitical reasons etc right
so there are two approaches in building
a stock you can either in-house it or
you can outsource it right so as an
organization what you can do is you can
build the expertise within your
environment right or you could simply
outsource it to a trusted service
provider but one of the challenges is is
typically you can outsource security but
you cannot outsource your risk right so
so typically what we find is a
successful stock implementation is
usually done within the organization
itself and that it's a separate
organizational department that's
developed so it doesn't have a reporting
line 2i t it actually has a reporting
line much higher up in the
organizational chart and it has key
teams from the finance department from
the HR department etc and this goes back
to the point of use education which was
the number about previous session right
social engineering is a very common way
to you know carry out exploits within an
organization so the sock team is
only responsible from monitoring your
activities around event logs but also
responsible to educate and raise the
awareness of information security within
the different departments so why do you
need to build the sea stock right it's
designed to be the nuclear so it's the
heart of any organization from a
security point of view right is doing
continuous monitoring continuous
prevention is identifying any attacks or
different locks sources are you know
integrated into your into your system
solutions and of course you can build
computer emergency response teams around
it as well so if there is an incident
you know you know exactly the protocol
to follow to be able to get to be able
to remediate right so what are the key
objectives of a sock managing coordinate
the response of cyber threats and
incidents morning to the cyber security
posture and report deficiencies right
performs for under $MONEY billet
assessment so as as mentioned in the
previous presentation we're talking
about patch management patch management
should be applied in the regular basis
right whenever this for example in your
vulnerability is disclosed immediately
they should be you know a patching cycle
within the day within two days depending
on the criticality now whose
responsibility is it alright so it could
potentially be the responsibility of a
song because they have the ultimate
authority to say we've identified as a
new vulnerability on this particular
system and then informed the system
owners that please make sure that this
system is then patched right so you can
now see the link when it comes to
building a security operations center
another important reason why you need to
build a sakis you know remove over the
last two days we've heard about cyber
security breaches hacking attempts or
the nice different models are being
created etc but the most important thing
for enterprise is how quickly you can
recover from a breech right so you must
define artios recovery time objectives
how long can my web application for my
database that are you know how long it
can be outta class for before the
significant impact of the business right
so the ability to automate the
requirements to meet compliance so i'm
not sure about the landscape with in
Romania but certainly within the Middle
East is a huge risk
garment for compliance specifically if
you're working for a bank you have to be
PCI compliant because they want to trade
in math and music art so without this
you cannot will not be training with you
but also for government entities you
know you have to be at least I to
complain but also some of the
organizations are state dependence of
the state's actually create security
policies and enforce it with the federal
entities and then the public sector at
the same time if you're working with an
oil and gas sector there are specific
frameworks like I c64 43 that can help
you basically improve the security
posture so by creating and building
compliances you can build the compliance
framework into the security operations
center other things are important is to
build our processes right so for example
there are a huge number of processes
that need to be developed as part of a
sea stock and that's something that
we'll discuss later on but one of the
things that you could do is you know
when you're building us our security
operations center you don't necessarily
have to invest in a huge team of
individuals are security analyzer you
know malware reverse engineers incident
responders etc you could actually build
you know capabilities within your team
as well as you extend the team within
for example the IT department right so
you have your system admin your network
admins your security admins etc at the
same time you could build trust
relationship with the service providers
that can provide you I'd find services
so while the components of building a
sock right so real-time monitoring is
important so data aggregation so just as
you have in your enterprise environment
depending on what kind of industry you
work in you have perimeter
next-generation firewalls intrusion
prevention systems where application
firewalls load balances a sell-off Lord
explicit proxy the list goes on and on
right you need to be able to integrate
all of these devices into a centralized
same solution right which is basically
your along aggregation . of course one
of the most important thing is to
correlate the data so if a user has
logged in remotely on ssl VPN from Dubai
and at the same time within five minutes
is logged in from Russia then you can
correlate the two data that the two
source IP addresses you know user cannot
be in two different locations within the
same time right so you can use this kind
of data to
identify that there's something
suspicious going on but also building in
a building security operations center
it's important that you know you
justified management what you're doing
right so you need to have he s delays
and kpi's to say for example within this
month we've actually defended against
fifty attacks have prevented you know
five different attempts where USBs
wanted to be plugged in eccentric cetera
right so this will allow you to then
gain better advantage point in getting
better investment from security
perspective so key success factors in
building a soft people process and
technology and I know this is a term
that's used everywhere but people
obviously they need to be trained you
need to have the right sort of people to
be able to deliver see so you need to
have the processes and of course the
technology to complement all of that so
just to quickly cover some of the points
proactive monitoring is important right
so being able to make sure that you
wanted to all the different types of
devices are connected in your network
alert notification is important if there
is a security breach who to notify what
is the severity level where is the risk
level and how to remediate that so that
the most important question to ask
yourself is if one of your critical
assets or ERP solutions or web services
which is performing eat in ecommerce
transaction if it's been breached
how do the incident response you have a
plan in place already right event
correlation is important compliance and
other things mentioned before change
management whenever there's a
configuration change in your
infrastructure you need to be able to
make sure that it doesn't impact
security right so for example I'm
firewood admin login to the perimeter
firewall I make a modification because i
need to allow a port on my web server
but this could impact security right so
change management with an IT
infrastructure must correlate to
security into the response behavior
analysis reporting aspects again these
are very important points and of course
everything is then comes down to from a
risk perspective so now when we look at
the second example architecture you can
see here for example you have all the
different type of components you have
your internet layer this is where you
connect to this
is provided you might have to service
providers you have a perimeter which is
typically your you know for a
next-generation firewall you have
potentially might be having a
distributed denial-of-service DDoS
mitigation tools your IPS etc and then
you have your DMV or public services
this is the primary attack vector from
the external point of view right and
then you might have internal middleware
type applications back in databases
mainframes etc these are all sitting
above what we call the data acquisition
layer right collecting the data from
different methods using this logs at the
eyes xml odbc log files etc on top of
that you have the data collaboration
layer where you have policy management
asset management security
vulnerabilities along with event
correlation layer as well and of course
sitting above that you have you know the
security management aspect which is
reporting to to the key management
typically when building a salt we've
seen successfully implemented where you
have similar components right so here
you have your different devices all
sending log data to the same solution
right so an active directory for example
if you integrate your Active Directory
into the same you're going to get all
the locks right so security logs event
log system logs now what happens if
administrator for the active directory
went back to your presentation he logs
in and modifies the user gpo's or the
Machine gpo's this impacts the entire
domain these kind of activities should
be marketed and then should be monitored
against was it a violent change request
that somebody actually raise the change
request to perform this action right so
you can now see the link where you have
the logs you need to be compliant does
it meet the compliance requirements and
does it meet the requirements from a
change perspective some of the other
things that can do can also be done is
integrating with service desk so for
example if there's an incident how you
actually you know raise the ticket for
the investigation to occur and also you
can integrate with vulnerability
assessment tools as well so what are the
kids you know some of the components you
have sim which is not just like
management rights are you collecting
events but also collecting
closer netflow SJ flaws I pics but
another important aspect is building
assets right how many if I ask for
example the question of do you know all
the assets within your enterprise
environment and have you classify them
on a risk level from a criticality of
high to low risk are you able to do that
the usual answer is typically know right
so it's important to build an asset
database of all the digital assets
within your environment and that could
be not just pcs and servers but also you
know smart devices like for example
printers voice-over-ip wireless access
points etc right configuration
management is important as well so
typically when we when we look at for
example you know the security operations
center first-generation you would find
that most of the organizations have a
lock to lock management tool which is
acting like the same collecting all the
data and the security analysts are just
looking at the logs without really
understanding what activities are
happening right and then you have the
security auditors who are running for
example the vulnerability management to
like your you know your nexus your rapid
seven etc and just scanning the network
identifying the vulnerabilities and then
getting them down to the system wants to
patch the systems and then you have the
networking team who are just simply
monitoring using an SNMP monitoring tool
the links which is rather as acceptor
right now each one of these is working
in a silo they don't have any
integration so for example if we find
that you know distributed
denial-of-service attack on a network
interface is connected to your internet
zone right that will have a security
impact with the part that the person is
going to identify it is going to be the
network monitoring guys because they
want during the internet perimeter out
using SNMP so that the approach is
usually to have an integrated stock
rights where you can build automation so
one of the key things that can be done
is you can send all the logs from your
different type of devices to your sim
solution and then one of the things you
can find for example is the same
solution connects to the service desk
whenever there's for example incidents
that need to be reported and offenses
that need to be generated and the same
status same same time at the top
right inside you see vulnerability
assessment right so the security orders
are coming out scans or pen testers are
coming out the apt exercises all the
vulnerability data is not coming back
into the same so you are able to
identify that a particular system that
has been you know that I used when you
do see malicious traffic or suspicious
activity it actually does have a
vulnerability right and at the same time
compliance and monitoring so this is
typically the integration points when we
see a successful start being implemented
now some of the key important points in
building sockets to have the process in
place right data security monitoring
data as the classification normalization
data distribution event management each
different type of device generates a
huge amount of logs so if you take for
example a cisco a firewall it has
generally something like 17,000 logs
that it can generate events right
obviously we're not interested in that
because it is not all security specific
so you have to define exactly the type
of syslog event ideas that you want the
same thing that goes from Microsoft
Active Directory domain it generates a
huge amount of logs right so you have to
define exactly which event IDs this is
you know that needs to be marketed and
then having an incident response
practice in place so if there's an
incident breach
what are the things that need to happen
one of the things that we've I don't
mean usually come across is whenever
there's a breach the customers or
enterprises are not prepared in terms of
the readiness of it right
so having a process in place in terms of
communicating to the right individuals
how to isolate how to contain the issue
these are very important aspects and in
many cases you then have to also report
to report to national search right so if
you have a national search in the
country sometimes you're you know you're
also expected to integrate and talk to
them as all you can you should also
build a stock operating guidelines right
so how often do the stock island this
work is it by 5 24 x seven depending on
the type of support you need
escalation management is very important
right you need to be able to ensure that
whenever there is a cyber security
breach you escalate to the right . in
time data recovery procedures as
mentioned right so whenever there's a
breeze you need to be able to recover
and also every single type of security
incident has a different outcome right
so email phishing attack is a different
communicate communication mechanism in
place if it's a malware outbreak there's
a different process in place is it just
you know DDoS attack again is a
different outcome in place if there's an
internal disgruntled employee is not
happy with the organization because he's
been terminated installing a backdoor
there's another process in place to the
point I'm trying to make is within a
sock you have different types of
incidents and different incidents will
have different actionable items just
furthermore vulnerability manage patch
management and one of the important
things is to build operating guidelines
i'm skipping through some of the slides
but you will get them as part of us
follow this so it's very important that
when you're building a sock you
understand your overall environment
right without this you're blind
so you can only monitor what you know so
identify your infrastructure you know
what kind of environment you have your
internet connectivity DMZ back in data
centers mpls infrastructure you have
extra nice you have connectivity to
third parties ipsec ssl VPN try to
understand what your infrastructure
looks like because once you understand
your infrastructure and you understand
the services then you will have better
you know you have better success factor
in building sort this is one of the
things that we typically tend to do at
least but you'll see at the top
try to get mass working alright so this
is a typical example where we basically
build a security catalog and what is
this this is the Internet routers these
are the perimeter firewalls this is the
dns over this is the web
this is the Lord balancer with web
application firewall and this is the web
server so if you're an enterprise and
you're providing for example ecommerce
services typically this is the kind of
service you might be or security you
might be following it's important that
you understand all the services you're
providing on your DMV services and start
creating the flaws so here if you if you
follow for example you know my mouse who
come to the Internet routers through the
printer
viral on the Eagles own ingress and
egress on you'll be coming into the load
balancer which will hit the virtual IP
which will then come back to the
firewall as an internal zone and then
come back out again and hit the server
so this is my server here now
understanding the service flows will
allow you to monitor this service for
any abnormalities any security breaches
and that's exactly what you need to
monitor within the operation center
using heat maps to visualize this also
you know becoming more and more
important because in stock we always
find that this huge amount of logs that
come in and it's very difficult to
identify exactly the particular that
might be causing a note intrusion the
building heat map is important and you
can again into a vulnerability data into
your into your system solutions or as
well
building an acid repository is very
important right so every single digital
asset within your enterprise environment
should be labeled and if you follow any
compliance standards or international
international security standards like
ISO 27001 pci IC 624 434 scotter and
also there's a lot of discussions
yesterday around IOT security
well as you know some of the guys were
mentioning this now stands there is no
standard but there is a working progress
standard for next cyber and physical
security draft so there are standards
are being developed but it's important
that you build an asset repository and
you identify for example the business
owners and the technical owners because
when there is a breach
you don't need to inform the technical
person the IT administrator but you also
need to inform the business owner right
towards the business process as part of
building a sock you need to of course
harden your infrastructure so this is an
example where you should look at the
firewall configuration and start
performing hardening guidelines and
identify what needs to be hardened so
once you've identified the unit need to
build the sock you need to start
creating threat cases so identify
exactly for example within your
environment
what kind of threat cases you need to
develop so
you will have extra environments
internet environment data center Active
Directory net for analysis for more
access wireless these are all the
different environments within your
enterprise and you need to build thread
cases i give an example
everybody uses emails to communicate
ninety percent or even ninety-five
percent of our communications / emails
right now within an enterprise you ten
typically tend to use microsoft exchange
now within microsoft exchange if there
is an exchange administrator he can
literally log onto the machine on the
exchange server copy the mailbox of CEO
and drag and drop it into his mailbox or
save on the USB right so if you're not
monitoring privileged access or
privileged accounts you can't identify
any non-compliance you're not on
conformities so these are the types of
threat cases that should be developed
within your enterprise environment so
you what you can do for example build
configuration baseline documents for red
hat enterprise linux for windows
machines for example so this is a threat
case document for Windows environment so
if you see here OS wins your 10 this is
basically the offense naming convention
so what you can do is when you're
building threat cases in your
environment you can give it a specific
name tag and that's the tag you used
when you to generate new general
offenses that's exactly the tag the tune
that use so multiple log on from a
single user from different locations
right this should not happen could
obviously indicate a breach or the
passion password is being shared with
another user in another country right so
these are some of the things that you
can actually develop within within your
environment so just to give an example
in building threat cases it's not a
clear diagram but i'll try to explain it
so you have an ax over so it's like it's
like an IBM AIX server unix type of unix
based system you have to use uses a and
uses be right there both ssh connecting
with more remote access
SSH on the x over now
user logs in with his unique username
using be logs in with his unique users
username but both of them perform the
pseudo or su root right so both become
rich uses
now how are you able to differentiate
root user belongs to use a or used to be
right so the point is that you have to
correlate the data and you have to go
through the environment and understand
the different services you're providing
and make sure that you monitoring the
right things because more often than not
what we find is in a customer's deploy
solutions and build a security
operations center but actually eighty
ninety percent of the time they're not
monitoring the right things building a
fence management workflow right so the
most important thing is within within
building a sock is to reduce the false
positives so you can build a workflow
one of the things you could also do is
build an internal wiki page with in
stock so all the different thread cases
that i mentioned you can actually import
them into into the wiki page itself so
basically when you're building a sock
it's a centralized internal portal for
all the different thread cases it has
bigger like features all the same
processes the documentation is are added
into the portal itself so this is just a
sock sock wiki page what's fed into it
for the different processes that i
mentioned about right so if the
different security incidents will have
different processes so you can feed that
into the wiki page all the threat cases
across your environment on the internet
your datacenter your mpls infrastructure
that your server farms a etc workflow
which is your incident response program
right and identify and making sure that
you know this this false positives and
false negatives and then you you
actually learn from the incident and the
feedback system in place
this will allow the organization to go
from a reactive situation to being
proactive right so the idea in
compliance or at least from a security
maturity perspective is always to go
from you know that level zero level 1 up
to level three or four and this is
basically epitomized in this diagram
right so most of the organizations that
don't have secured in place that are
reactive right they typically tend to
stay at CMM level of capability maturity
model level 1 but as you build a sock as
you people proactive and as you start
driving things in a better way you move
up the
of the chain just finally one of the
things that you could do on a wiki for
example is i'm not i mean i'm sure you
know about RSA RSA token authentication
for example is the two-factor
authentication that you use to login
what you could do is you could for
example identify the different thread
cases you can see here you go triple
eight RS 800 1 2007 these are the
different thread cases if there is an
incident for example related 2001 where
you have excessive reject messages you
can identify that and it basically you
create an offense case using 001 and
then from a security operations center
perspective whoever's got that offense
ID which is put into the wiki page and
would get all the details about exactly
what needs to be done to remediate that
particular problem so the idea is
building in a better governance and
better monitoring being proactive in
when you're building security operations
center so that's that's my last life as
a lot of information within 30 minutes
but I hope you know about the gist of it
i'd like to thank death cab for inviting
us it was a pleasure being here and if
there's any questions then by all means
i know i'm not a lot of problems that
you have when you're talking about
instant response procedures and policies
that's a living document it's like
because the technology is going to
change what's the best way to combat
that because you know the people that
you're going to contact for instant
response are going to be different that
the do you do it
role-based or do it do it specifically
to the person and also how often should
a person a company or organization look
at their procedures and their policies
and revisit that to try to update them
to keep them current good question
so typically when it comes to building
processes usually if you look at the
standards they always mentioned to carry
out for example a review of policies
upon a major change within
infrastructure or at least in our yearly
basis so that's that's at least what
should happen on a yearly basis but
going back to initial question of
incident response
it really depends right it has to be
service-based so as opposed to in our
system based so one of the things that
we are we always tend to find is that
when you're trying to do and into the
response as a first responder you go
on-site you try to identify
exactly what happened but then you you
have the missing links you can't
actually put them together and having a
sock in place will allow you to build
these links because as they gave an
example for example for one of the oil
and gas companies which was impacted
they left traces as they perform the
attack right but having a software you
have all the logs being collected are
able to do that so it really depends
make any other questions
no and thank you so much for
presentation