ok I'll stack for hackers so first of
all who is a heckler this year or maybe
she reaches guy who Steph XLIV trying to
solve the problem in a unique way you
know I guess he has 99 99 percent chance
of stopping characters but personally I
think hackers are about connecting the
dots they know how to connect the dots
they know how to think out of the box
and disarmament features of hackers but
first comes first for my security
consultant at
we are a small but little company when
it comes to breaking in like there's
racial testing social engineering are
most street dance in their camp this is
the picture from 2013 were Milan garber
I don't know if you can see him in the
corner we presented elk steak for
hackers both how to analyze and the
republication in a dynamically way
basically region between games mostly
and should be here instead of me but
sorry you need to stick with me but I
promise I will give you some valuable
information so like hackers do now let's
try to connect the dots first of all
what is out stack it stands for
elasticsearch look station commander and
elk steak is usually used for event
monitoring for example if you have
computer network you want to know what
is happening on the network but we are
using toxic in kind of different way we
use it to put wifi data into the Arctic
and visualize and see maybe some strange
patterns because
if you know big data is all about
patterns and I will show you that when
I'm talking about wi-fi date I can talk
about big computer and their flocks and
she and reach and after that do data is
transferred to elasticsearch what is
elastic search you can say it's
distributed search engine for example
but it's a lot of more it's useful
storage and also for his grieving they
had them on top of it is cabana
nice kind of the Crary engine queries
Dallas and displays the data and
beautiful graphs you can have a lot of
stuff I'll show you later so just
shooting some big data according to
Wikipedia information privacy is one of
the challengers and why is that
let me explain I read an article about
that smart people prefer curly fries
what has curly fries do much more people
actually not think I try to either the
party it turned out that killed
ambassador was so but what they did they
can't alter experiment on Facebook and
based on the likes of these colic in the
first row with smart he tends to connect
with all other smart people because we
like to connect and share ideas with the
same people as we are so after he liked
curly fries it turned out that other
France that are also smart like Earth
rice and you can imagine our river
flowing and the aunt you turned out the
smart people like reference what has
distributed information privacy you see
based on the likes they can tell or
classify your for example they can tell
if you are terrorists or if you get a
great I don't know just likes so next
time if you like something conveys
building twice as already pointed out
metadata sexual activity reports and
then again I ask him how many times you
need to retreat and tweets to become on
the list on the Raider and he replied
the only once so I did it twice
not to become one on the radar but
here's another example of big data
anybody seen this this is what she was
actually pretty good at jeopardy he beat
two state championships
dude overall champions of jeopardy and
he was able to recognize natural
language and for the knowledge think he
he had more than four terabytes of data
structures on structure it basically the
whole Wikipedia so you can think in
terms of big data like there is
knowledge behind it
your family over the screen this is the
output of our dumping she has little set
of our crack and is used mainly
and monitoring by Friday and so on so
many of you use aircrack NGU ok the
right audience but what has to do big
data with five are actually a lot to set
up the health sector hackers and it's a
monitoring and office we have been we
are in the dance floor and monitor about
two weeks and this is a number of
records 25 millions so you can talk when
you talk about wi-fi he can talk about
them for hackers about that
else like we at the era dumping G to
this image and we have doubts that for
hikers but I would like to do some
hands-on I would like to show you how to
set up the sting for this purpose I will
go to the my colleagues machine I hope
you can see it here I have also cart I
already put it out into turning point as
you can see first of all to capture the
data we had some issues because she
would put doesn't support Jason YJ some
because elasticsearch speaks naturally
in JSON and also lockstitch knows about
Jason so we decided to modify the cult
of Aragon and ultimate oh that's called
on bridges is basically a copy of the
brides with slightly modifications so
this supports the
the JSON file format also what with the
change his number of props anybody know
what crops are OK for those that don't
know what crops are if you are for
example connected in your home network
and then come to the death camp
conference and put out your WiFi your
phone or device well as case my home
network around and this is actually a
broad and turns out I can catch those
crops and also done a lot of i-5 network
you have been connected to and I think
the number of us stand in the original
version of changes to 1,000 because we
found that one client has more than 100
Prague so he has been connected to one
hundred and four networks and you can
guess based on this data we can tell a
lot of about this client where he has
been moving my history he's been
connected and song I will show you this
later in practice but so let me go to
the to the Elks stack you see serious
elasticsearch running in the foreground
because of the bargain purposes like to
have a taste of what's going on and here
is lobsters running this is the typical
message he gets from Aaron dumping G and
you can see that he's doing some Rebecca
Jean Jason so in this kind of a he's
damn sending the data to elasticsearch
instance and here's combine irani let me
show you the conflict file of this is
the conflict file of luck session is
spruce a forward and easy we are are
reading the data from a file that is
located here
we are just seeking for Jason and after
that we are playing of filtering and
Talon locke says that it's actually JSON
and doing some modification at the and
the outcome is output to elasticsearch
and that basically it so let's try to
round ever dumped in G I'm the comment
here it is nothing special about it I
just tell her that the cult format is
Jason I would like to have the
manufacturer of the client so based on
the mechanism declined I can get older
manufacturer and I would like to listen
on channel one let's run this and you
can see the pretty much output of let's
move here and to look stylish and you
can see the data is running our is
parsing
to the final act this is kianna anybody
who's given a great you can see here
data and if I'm refreshed stuff you can
see the counter has increased but
nothing much here I can do for example a
full text search and grab some data out
of it but the real power behind combine
our visualization for example like this
and if you put all the visualization
together you come to the dashboard this
is an example of their sport it's from
today and
and it should be changed because because
data is running live from this regard to
hear and you can see you have already
are pretty good image was going around
you so with this basic setup you get
very quickly an idea what's going around
for example and culture at today
710 sixth clients that have been around
walking and we saw 12 wireless networks
around and also 76 physical access
points to be a success I D is the
abbreviation of the MAC address of the
access point but let me do some
filtering for example I was also
monitoring yesterday I know I was evil
but let's elect yesterday see you can
see the data has been changed
dynamically just by specifying other
filter so let's like for example dave
Camp free network so actually not the
right one sorry this was a pro
I need to add the visualization because
I forgot about it I think you know if
you do live demonstration there is
always something not working or karma is
a bitch and 43 right network and you can
see the graphs have been changed
dynamically you know the decryption is
open you can see that
121 station have been connected there
are 31 access points physically
yesterday but sometimes not accurate
because I was moving through the
conference and I sure didn't capture all
the clients that have been moving around
let me explain this simple graph here
from the inside to the outside you can
see it's about the death camp three
network and sheer outside you can see
all the access points listed and this
slices are actually clients that are
connected to those excess funds and
those clients have this one so it means
I can just a simple this graph I can get
a lot of information was going around so
from the network to the client to his
manufacturer and based on this data I
can tell you for example people to death
camp like Apple more than they like
something I can all study that hero
hackers around because they used the
laptop still not just with
Samsung devices also Apple devices I can
tell you that the Afghan Kush relying on
Cisco is the main manufacturer and also
hero can see the activity of the
client's home any plans have been
connected at which time you remember I
said that this date is not accurate
because I moved if I did the monitoring
stationary Israel would be more accurate
but not the funny part or let's say the
evil part about props for example I can
see the Bronx of this guy and what I can
tell about the ropes actually a lot if
you if you recognize yourself just raise
your hand if you still then probably a
student or a professor the fee of the
Pony Express I guess this is the form of
Jason's read because he works on Express
Company so let's see on sheer here but
you gotta point before there was a
presentation about about how they choose
the EPA to pass works and is based on
their assessment if I'm correct correct
so they came up with an idea that they
named by fire access point
uniquely this is actually ok it doesn't
tell you much about a person but the bad
thing is if someone has been monitoring
cue
and you have a unique access point and
he is doing like for example using
mister minit this kind of thing this is
a tool to locate the location of
wireless network it uses of legal
services do based on the SSI idea which
is the wireless network name together
location and for example this name maps
to Romania and so basically based on
your bro hope I could wear your home
it's not that funny anymore because this
stuff can be used for stalking and I
also do a lot of let's say penetration
testing can social engineering and you
know in the face of information
gathering you go to Facebook you go to
LinkedIn and based on this Probst I can
also tell you a lot about you if you
like danny's if you like to go to the
restaurant which kind of rest around
where is it located where you have been
there and song so basically scary but
funny things can be see here and this is
an example of big data
you know let's see gang for health
here's something interesting let's do
you remove this
and search for iPhone so I'm interested
in the products and let's see example
can afford to work on this desk I hope
this is not his name or first name what
I mean by that iPhone 4 usually
configured at least at the beginning
that they sent out props about the owner
of the iPhone it's time for me and so I
know he has iPhone he has worked awfully
sweet maybe an office that he is working
in let's try to let's try to find out if
this is actually a place in Romania yeah
it actually is so maybe an office he's
working and song so you got an India
based on the Bronx I can tell much about
a person I can classify it and i cant
find patterns in the internet so I would
like to show you something else because
we still have a lot of time how do you
know I expect is running basically
simply just let me find the comment you
can do our current search like this not
Alex X-ers elasticsearch instances this
turning on localhost and is listed on
this 4200 assists him and
once this wrenching cobalt elastic
searches that it doesn't have any
security access control into it
of course you can pay for additional
component like a shield for example and
then you have access control but the
only security feature in terms of access
is that it's running on localhost so you
cannot connect to my plastic surgeons
for example but as it turns out people
always find ways to do it the wrong
thing for example if you use children do
you know about children ok you search
it's in Romania and I just surged
elasticsearch drink and you can see the
turkey in some sense of elastic surgery
wide open what that means I can be
queried those that the basis I came
basically the lead the indexes were the
data and you got the picture I would
like to show you something out of the
topic maybe I searched for MongoDB this
is even nicer you can see the showdown
shows you how big is the database so
even a nice interface for example what I
mean by this
if the vendor doesn't do it right there
will always be people that also do do it
right so ok
and maybe not so many so if you're bored
story on thirty minutes left
ok elasticsearch I told you that is
based on Jason its document oriented and
its scale of its kind of distributed
data base and plastic surgeons also in
his all in his basic terms of hacker
because every every technology was
around and they just connected to dot
distributed databases of us around
full-text Search Search was around and
what they did find everything together
and make it easier
efficient to use and this wireless
experience also hecker
you know this is a beautiful you can
discover patterns patterns into the
visualization and so on so what actually
does all the heavy carrying here but
just a few clicks and Gabbana census
data LASIK surgeon then it comes out is
beautiful
reservation which looks kind of blurry
in mind
ok
look stylish I don't know if you see it
anything I told you already about this
this is the scary part and you can see
the week Mr probz location is actually
where he did two years ago
all the presentations now let's try to
construct a graph undertake its heart
any ideas
nobody ok let's put a new visualization
and select pie charts you search and
here I was slack for example and let's
say is I did wrong
ok ok again I was like the terms and
I've slacked instances I do wrong this
means actually I'm splitting and seeing
what wireless networks around limited
this kind of visualization to do for
example and I had I can see already
what's going around you know it's at
another sub orkut and let's do another
aggregation and let's say BSSID wrong
the MAC addresses of physical access
points and you can see here cleary how
many access points does not forecast and
if I'm adding another bucket
this
and selecting stations Mac I can see
already which clients are connected to
reach access points in which Texas
Florence are parts of one at work so
basically just by doing few clicks I get
a lot of information if you put this
information into a dashboard you can
have real power what I forgot to set you
is that we actually did apply to get up
on patch of Aragon and G it's available
for free you can purchase a crack in
science source called and you have Jason
support some basic information is
available here but it's not so hard to
do this stuff so many minutes still ok
if you know about us section just not
going to happen now I'm just kidding I
like to share ideas because this is all
about the conference's to shower and get
knowledge if you know what I mean where
this setup can be used for example of
course in penetration testing social
engineering and security targets this is
the first kind of thing you'd think
about it also we can use it as a fire
for example both to CNN's you may be no
for example if I have a small advisers
capturing putting dating back and I
locket for example 25 MAC addresses that
are connected to my network
and suddenly 10 MAC addresses are
connected you know dan something
terrible has been happening so this kind
of stuff you can do with it
of course even even intelligence
gathering this kind of example I showed
you based on the Bronx and you know if
you have a lot a lot of data if you
monitoring everybody around you you can
see patterns into the data match people
do something out of it and song or
something for example if you this kind
of person I'm not and I also read about
an article
policemen had a great idea about
tracking stolen phones because but the
only condition you need to know them a
colossal to form so if you need the MAC
address and you do the monitoring stuff
you know that somewhere around his story
but if you do
angulation for example you can pretty
much show the person who has gone from
not hearing this crowd but maybe on the
street so this is another idea where you
can set up or use the setup I talked
about it and also if I'm heading to
Africa wreck yourself open networks you
know open networks like that game 3 I'm
not encrypted so this means I can sniff
the network and I can capture of maybe
some you're browsing data and if I'm
adding to all these data that I have
also where you have been browsing and
when that it becomes scary so but you
know with great power comes great
responsibility and you should use it as
you wish
I'm just going for my back can you can
you give me my back there I forgot to
bring it here
thank you like to show you one more
thing and then I'm done here
yes this is settling reuter it's
actually small it consumes 3d many mom
likes a par and if I'm put it in the
battery I have my private monitoring I
just executed and put open wrt on it its
own always be device and also I did some
scripts so if I'm just getting the
better 28 aircraft automatically loads
and by now you should switch on your
wireless because I monitoring and after
I'm done and just putting out this who
has be and putting all the data that are
half into my axe attack and visualizing
searching parents and so on so it's
pretty easy to set up things like this
and with open wrt you can surely do it
so this is what I had in mind
are then questions
to finger you have already
scripts for looking for funds that were
connecting from particular location for
example can you find quickly my phone
that was connecting usually in poland
can you do this this scope because seat
interaction with their website
first of all if you have been connected
to a network and you didn't delete this
not for yes of course it is constantly
asking for it and you can search and
should have it already in your database
and the question he sees you can search
our country not actually purple country
because i dont have this data but maybe
if you tell me you can look for streams
with UPC of course the source about my
pocket
UPC a UPC a UPC this is the beginning of
the springs the second
like this yes maybe
know the particle number
you know ok here here because this is
the string you don't have space this is
on the perfect for it
ok maybe I didn't catch you but as you
know elasticsearch supports text search
maybe like this do you have what phone
do you have
which manufacturer Samsung of course I
didn't capture ok but I was talking when
you are sleeping with my followed with
maybe this you know there's some errands
you know ok but you can I don't i dont
can catch every phone but I just put
song of the day today regarding to the
database and then I go to do the
analysis there's fresh
I will try to answer when when you
thirteen key partner in unity with the
results
explored the result yeah the results are
in plastic surgery can I know they are
in like 30 Jun 14 simply want to filter
some kind of light drizzle have a look
at the heat or something I didn't do you
see how do you can export them as
possible and this is my my question is
why I think you can you can export it
here I think but I didn't go into it
because it isn't needed so basically I
think you can export into a
comma-separated very files and
everything I can from from API but both
but it's easier to do a search surgeon
exported data on this kind of way for me
any question they're going to act as you
know we have some kind of back doors
do you think that the engineering and
engineers who today more like the
factories that intentionally and the
thing that they take some kind of data
from dad and feel some kind of data
please do you mean regarding its
coordinated or is just like for telecom
purposes for updating a firmer but in
the process thing or something else
I mean thirty forty percent of the
Reuters that have backed boris that's
why I don't know maybe so maybe not I'm
not expert say state of affairs alright
so nice question do you think that
someone did until now like bigger David
B
database of these data gathering from
all around the world
I'll never heard of it I think they did
I think that thank you I'll question you
can catch me later if you want I'm here
till tomorrow so we can grab a beer or
something and have a nice conversation
no question to thank you