ok so now that we've done the make the
projector work dance let's stop
so my name is crystal i work at the
interlink a group called open source
technology center and I'm a part of the
team that is focused on finding security
bugs in open source software that ends
up in internal projects since android is
one of our projects so i'm going to
share with you how we've done some bug
hunting that is related to media on and
rate for the agenda i will give a brief
full introduction about what fozzy mins
and the water requirements to be done
before you start testing and how all the
box can be difficult be trashed and find
what is unique and make your life easier
in finding crashes so as a buzzing
basically is just the black box testing
technique you just send to corrupt
invalid files to one and then see what
gets onto the other and help how the
system rejects the files that are
corrupt and what are the reactions of
the system basically you are targeting
to have any kind of real security
related issues up to denial of system
and total freeze of the system usually
for advising can be applied to any
application or system that accepting
input wider x files or by your ports or
if as long as there is a partner for the
input for filing can be applied the most
tricky tricky part is that when you have
a protocol or through our complex
application where you have to be very
specific in how you define the input
otherwise you'll be sending input we and
it will not be accepted by the
application and will be rejected in
instantly as walkthrough you need to
prepare your data you need to have a
target and the target has you must be
sure that your input go straight to what
you're trying to test and is not
rejected otherwise
all the issues must be locked and safe
so that you can perform analysis
afterwards and it will be nice
especially if you're doing some testing
on open-source after to adequately
disclosed or finding so that the
community can no benefit of fixes also
ok so why audio and video
well these are the types of input that
require or the decoders are our be in
number of lines of code it so it can be
very complex with the code some specific
media type and also there are a lot of
applications and called their products
and everybody at some point everybody
starts to take something and optimize it
thinking that their version will be
better than the others and this this way
or the other fellows are introduced and
also there is a common belief that made
the files are usually harmless there
isn't anything there bad that can affect
my system and you don't need specific
requirements from permission system from
to open a media file it just opens it
and there is no need for you to open a
media file on any other system
ok for android we we took what are we
took at least we've built a list with
all the files that are accepted I mean
type of quarters type of containers type
of betrayed and made the list and not
that based on this specification we
start into building files we've tried to
look straight to what is the coating the
files and to avoid all the job of your
machines and all the job applications
and we were interested to go with deep
in the system as possible so that we get
close to the application and of course
you have to model to move monitor while
what the crashes are and save them and
be sure to that you avoid have avoided
all the false positives that might take
time to to find so in the past couple of
months there was a media buzz about
stage fright and all the vulnerabilities
stage fright is a house like a framework
immediate frame that contains a lot of
libraries and those libraries are kind
of rule they still need to still a lot
of work the advantage interesting this
framework is that it comes with a
command-line interface using this
command line interface just we can just
say okay this is the file i want you to
call it using this decoder and I don't
to specify okay I need you to use
software hardware and see how it goes
so it's very big point accurate and it
makes things very simple you can you can
you can generate data input for your
application by you're basically in two
ways
you either take a valid file with
invitational and you start by flipping
it and saving each iteration of that
process this is the most simple way you
can do it
the second option will be to use them to
use the generation you are you take the
file the files requirements
specification and you say that
ok the first five bites at the head of
the next five bites are data and all
that and you mark in your tool ok you
can you can find only this part of the
file and this way you are sure that the
code coverage increases and your results
are more accurate or based on what exit
do delete these this list of tools is
filter listed on our or partially sato
complexity of the tool in usage and in
the features the first ones of is just
you give the target what is the
application that you want to test you
give the input and the ratio of how much
funding should be applied to a file and
the to start running and saves all the
crashes and all that indonesia by ratio
I mean percentage of the file that must
be flip it flip it and it starts one by
one and flips all the beats you said and
you see how it goes
the second one it's a project from
search and it comes with a little
machine which you installed which is a
little bit of bass guitar machine you
install the application there you start
to couldn't
you have to do some configuration about
what kind of testing you want to perform
and it comes with white with has some
monitoring features where it goes and
checks the state of the Machine and if
reason or doesn't respond adjustable the
Machine and start the whole process
again the last one is an instrumentation
based buzzing so do the source code is
instrumented built and it goes to
specific points in the peanut binary and
the marks and if those two points are
have been touched by the input it starts
to modify the input so that it can go
deeper in the source code and this way
you can increase the code coverage and
make make make use of the tool when
we've done know when we run this process
we had a separate machine that was
crunching the data files and it was
saving the file generating saving
logging taking the results of the
machines perform the Hajj and so that we
can we don't interfere in the running in
the production system we also will have
the second line was a local machine
which was taking patches of files and
sending to the devices it was for
keeping also the state of the devices
monitoring taking the crashes out and if
one of devices was crashing it was just
rebooting the system and keep continue
to run in a period of weeks we got to
the point where we had around 11
terabytes of data so the files are in
that big they are a couple of megabytes
of four of size and the idea was that we
generate this type of this volume of
data so that we can increase the code
coverage as for the loading part android
comes with the specific system for
logging is called look at you know it
has differently different levels of four
usage you can get to you can put stuff
like that related to debugging and fall
high-level issues and you can insert
whatever you want their from up from
your application and we leverage this is
a look at and we started to put into the
what we are running what are the crashes
what are what is the file that crashed
so that we can afterwards take the logs
and parts and see what were the issues
that we found and if you start to doing
this type of testing and everything goes
well you will have this type of arrows
most of them are not quite exploitable
but we recommended that to just go into
the source code really what is around
and see how things what was the problem
and maybe we can find some some other
issues and using those 11 terabytes of
data and around the cluster built off of
after 20 around 10 to the android
devices and then appeared of eight weeks
we got to the point where we had around
a hundred 285,000 crashes and at this
point we found we said okay it's not
possible to manually feel they're all
these issues and so at night don't think
any human being like to go into look in
all these issues and we found that we
need to do some automatic garage of all
this stuff and we've built a mechanism
that was taking the crashes was every
crew was retested so that we can avoid
false positives and I mean the devices
were continuously running and maybe the
context of which the device was there
maybe cover for sport so we have to
retest all those issues to see if
everything was was clear and based on
the information in the tombstones we for
we filter something you some information
needed so that we can make sure that the
combination type of error and the
program counter where the arrows was its
unique so that we can build a unique
database of files
android helps by your sin saving all
these core dumps into places and we took
these files we put in the purse with to
do all the tombstone and also the file
that caused the crash we saved them and
so that we can help in the same place
and based on this information we were
able to filter all those crashes so that
the number of crashes will go very very
low ship and at the end at the end we
got to the point where you know after
eight weeks we had around eight if
185,000 crashes and we had to build we
also built a trash mechanism and we
started reporting girl shoes to google
and it took some time before we got all
those cds and the issues to be fixed but
in the end we the improvements have been
have been added to the Android and now
it's a big be difficult to find new
issues related to later to this so if
you about the tool that was used for
this process is available on github it
was open source for this year and people
started to commit to it and that
modifications and started to include it
in the their processing their app
they're testing
oh I'll be around here for today
tomorrow and if you have questions you
can ask me or otherwise get the email
and drop me an email and i'll try to
respond this brief as possible and you
guys have questions
I'm not aware what's happening in
Windows i'm working not that they're
opening the the source is going to be
cultural program so i was i was thinking
you know something about this is now I'm
no personal knowledge center so we are
dealing with open source stuff and based
I mean all operating systems or flavors
of operating systems that are used based
on Venus and on top of that so windows
you thought was my out of my range
okay then here
hey
yes so i can I have a couple small
questions first
how you actually generate the data
because you told that you use the
mutational faster or APL are using a
fearful for these numbers ofl we started
to introduce it recently so all these
restore these work was done with
rotational father's based on a high
corporal pine umber of files we've
started to using bit papers so we just
take the file sweet the binary forbid
save it and this way get a lot of lot of
files and therefore we've started to use
it recently with careful we use the 4
starting with FL we've used the file
that work work work causing the biggest
number of crashes in the previous
sessions and those files that were
having the biggest code coverage and we
started to put those files into FL and
this way we can leverage all the work
that we have done before and not use so
so where will you get the first test
cases the first files you have a a
database with a large amount of there
are some internal repositories where we
have your media files that can be used
to testing climbing or who you can use
this weekend stage fright to test softer
and horror we were more interested in
how the harder the coders work but since
we can since we've seen that too
away we can use this also to test the
software stack ok let's just stroll over
there and see how it crashes so finally
which is more or less the number of
distinct crashes but that you get once
you filter so that i forgot to mention
here by the number of crash of this
thing crashes were around 44 yes out of
the more auto 40 we had only for that
got the CB and there were high security
issues the other were also they were
different like we have different heat
exhaustion also take over phone stuff
like that that were not very easy to
exploit or cause any damage and while
the good parts of testing this on
android is that the stage fright is not
only used on Android and it could be
there all those patches were pushed to
the other the other software life there
are a lot of them who are you which are
using stage fighters
ok thank you i want it
oh that's what I wanted to ask whether
you try to exploit the vulnerabilities
you've identified so we've tested on the
latest version of Android and it would
be kind of so when you're playing with a
heap and try to use it mostly it's gonna
be difficult and we've said that it will
be more with cooking Mort if we just use
that time into finding other box so we
just find ok this is kids can be this
could be exploited just report it and
that's it basically your work stops as
soon as you can control the once we get
to the right so we can wash with cold
right in memory of setups that it i
think we stopped a cooler full
presentation
nice one question how do you categorize
the crashes in order to see if they are
exploitable or not the fastest way you
can find the frat exploitable the there
is little for that
oh there's an app for that it runs there
is a bank exploitable the name of the
tall it's so there's a version for will
extended version for windows and baste
it is based on the technocore dumping
based on the information the cord has an
e6 mail and xml file and if it's fine
something formula to just say with a
percent with an appropriate ok this
might be exploitable this might not be
exploitable so it basically has a list
something like that and it takes all
based on this type of arrow keys i'm not
exploitable these could be exploitable
you should look into it okay thank you
and another question for instance if one
person but his home would try to
reproduce your work what resources would
it need what we need so he only time and
a lot of knowledge about what is in the
android LSP three because you don't have
access to the stage fright command-line
interface by default is not a binary
which is installed in every hundred
image you have to modify the source code
and the oh so that you have the binary
and the end with all the testing
interface and after that you will need
some processing power to generate all
the files and a lot of devices if you
want to to gain some time otherwise it
will take some time to parse couple of
terabytes of data but it's doable
okay thank you have you tried looking
into other will other means of mutation
mutating the media files I mean you've
said you talked about beeping I was
curious whether so the air felt come
sweet series of fathers it goes by with
flipping one for a bit and all that and
after that it has some of let's say
mathematical ways in which it's not a
bit flip and compares the cold and see
which if new paths have been taken and
based on that stock white continues so
yes we are looking into that I was when
asked you this I was thinking about I'm
not sure if you're familiar with the
Franken certs I think that's the name or
they basically
use this technique for buzzing https
libraries or TLS libraries more
efficient to be more precise where they
I mean even the complexity of
x509certificate they basically taking
bits and pieces from different
certificates and feeding those is input
and i was curious whether to try this on
medium Milan so on funding for
certificate that's another story
it's nothing that there is very little
information from this that you can use
on that because you have seen handshakes
you have four months you have yours
you'll start to build the requirements
of the certificate and try to arrange
beats in that order that the certificate
will be valid then it's sort of
different and it can be done but it's
another let's say technique yes it's
curious whether there's other things use
sites beating you have to take some
tools from here and you can take the
fighting part out of it and applied to
the certificates and define what can be
fast or not and after that we have to
recalculate all the checks and all that
so it's different
did you try you're causing files on
different hardware platforms on brands
like you find any hardware box so for
the hundred quality stuff for we're ok
we we went to briefly on that and it's
we deal with we what we've managed to
survive all the stuff we've tried there
but at least until now we didn't find
anything but the you run your tests on
different the homes different brands or
cones or only one maker are we were only
targeting girl
of devices that were using the interlace
66 platform so that was late but some of
the software if some of the issues that
are related to software the colors are
pliable are available for all range of
platforms
okay think
ok so if you have any more questions
look from around here and thanks for
your time and I hope you enjoyed it