ok so first of all before we start I
usually take a picture of the crowd
before I start this is the first time
actually I'm going to have to take a
panoramic picture so let's let's try
that it's working
it's huge ok guided posted I'll send it
to you for innovators ok so my name is a
meat ax me this bill I work for check
marks I'm here today to talk about game
of hacks will go through some some
introduction about application security
which is what we do check marks we do
static analysis will talk about what
game of hexes will understand also
what's behind game of had so it's not
only a game it's much more than that
will have a short game which I need your
participation so anyone who has wireless
mobile or laptop whatever get it ready
there's going to be a quiz and even
though we're giving out the T-shirts
outside give the winner an extra one if
we have time I'll talk a bit about
node.js which is the platform and
language that the framework that game
and taxes based on and of course at the
end we'll go out with some takeaways so
hopefully everything will work as
planned and let's start so well you see
at the moment is kind of what we're
talking about the problems so the
problem is people hacking into large
organizations in different means
different ways but the bigger problem
which is why security became such a big
thing is because it costs a lot of money
to these organizations you look for
example at Target just you know the
costs of the doubt data they lost was
160 162 million dollars just for the
data and then they have the lawsuits and
the reputation that they've lost in all
of that as as kind of cost them probably
a few hundreds of millions of dollars
with the OPM reach that was a few months
ago
5.6 million fingerprints were stolen so
it's not even password for user names or
things like that it's fingerprints no
fingerprints of official
American employees government employees
very very sensitive data obviously it
has a value in cash as well
Ashley Madison we all heard of this one
other than the fact that it's
embarrassing for a few people who were
caught red-handed there's again the
reputation the company was kind of being
asked to close down they didn't close
down but a lot of money was spent and
will be spent on fixing the problem that
happened due to the breach sony also
famous one not gonna go into too much
details about it but again
reputation profit last they they showed
the movie what was it the interview I
think it was called they put it on on
the internet for free instead of being
able to make money out of it and more
and more and more organizations that are
being hacked regularly and constantly
the thing is that it becomes more and
more obvious that breaches are occurring
on the level of the developments on the
level of the code if the code is not
perfect if the code is not protected no
firewall no endpoint protection nothing
can prevent a user logging on and you
know running an SQL injection if the
code is not sanitized it's not clean
it's not secure the half will always
happen and we're seeing that more and
more of the attacks are targeting the
application layer so check marks as I
said we do static analysis and static
analysis means having developers
involved in the security effort so it's
not only the security personnel that are
in charge of it it's not only the IP for
example installing fire walls and stuff
like that
but it's also the developers and what
triggered our idea was when we were at a
conference about a year ago a bit more
and we saw a bunch of people just like
you and me standing in front of a big
billboard and we came up closer and we
looked at it had something like this on
the screen there was no prize no nothing
no fame nothing at all they were just
standing there a bunch of developers
trying to figure out what the
vulnerability is that we understood it's
really interesting for them so there's
some kind of potential here on top of
that there are researchers and and
concerns by Cecil's which the main to
our the awareness and the training of
developers when it comes to security so
a lot of the seasons are becoming more
and more aware that developers have to
become part of this effort the security
effort we put these two together so the
guys looking to find a vulnerability and
the the awareness the research that was
publicized and we said ok let's do
something let's make something and we
created game of hawks game of hacks was
launched about August last year since
then we had hundreds of thousands this
presentation is a bit few months no not
if you must but it's a bit outdated more
than a hundred thousand games were
played since then by people who are
trying to test their coding skills
let's take a short look at game of hacks
and I hope the wireless is fine and this
is this is the idea of game of hex very
simple it's available online
www.cammodels.com you choose if you want
to play by yourself or against a friend
and then you can challenge a friend if I
play by myself I choose the level that I
wanna play let's have a vote who wants
beginner 123 don't be shy it's ok I'm
not going to be able to figure out the
beginner as well who wants intermediate
ok all the same command output beginner
on and let me know if anyone can get
this so you get a piece of code get a
piece of code on the screen and a second
there it is and you have to tell what
the vulnerability is if anyone wants to
guess the vulnerability as BHP and I
guess is if not I'll just choose any of
them held up injection correct ok this
is how it goes it continues so you have
55 questions I think each question has
few options of answers it becomes more
harder it becomes more interesting for
some people and it's actually a very
good way to educate developers to
educate security and people who are
developing applications but there was a
bit more behind that so game of hacks
was indeed kind of the same marketing
and awareness education tool but we said
ok we're gonna do something it's
probably going to attract akers' it's
probably going to track the black hat
guys who wanna show off so they're
better than than an eyesore than anyone
else so what we did was that we made a
honeypot out of it as well and our
assumption was completely correct and
very quickly we found out that people
were rather than playing the game and
finding the vulnerabilities were hacking
attacks and that's okay because we left
it open on purpose we wrote the code in
a way that will allow vulnerabilities
and that will let people happy and show
off their skills so some of the things
that you can see people wrote on here
tries to teach security officials at
security
ironically it easy to hack a game about
finding security bugs and then someone
was clever enough to say maybe that was
the metagame so yes that was made a game
but not only a bit about the
architecture more boring no doubt sorry
democrats is based on node.js so we have
the client-side running on web browsers
mobile phones
iOS Android I must admit that I never
tried it on Windows but I'm guessing
it'll work anyone has a winner who has a
Windows Phone in here
22 out of 345 wow six so we have not bad
impressive festive windows are happy
bill gates's will check next year again
ok so it runs on the client side on the
browser and then we have the node.js
architecture running on
hiroko with MongoDB which work very well
together usually in MongoDB in node.js
no jess is interesting it's been
catching up lately a lot
the reason for that is kind of because
it's very very good for web applications
for quick I'll functionality and this is
an explanation about how node.js works
quickly review it but I have a better
slide that is easier to explain the idea
is that the event loop is the brain of
the system it get constantly requests
from the event queue and it passes it on
to someone to do the work so the event
is the event handlers the file system
database network things like that
whenever the event loop itself has to do
a calculation it will do the calculation
of want to anything else until it
finishes that which is the bedsit side
of node.js so it's very sleepy it's not
good for CPU intensive applications a
better way to explain that is this
so you have a fast food restaurant you
have the single thread which is the
event loop the the handler at the event
loop itself and then you have the event
handlers which are the people who are
getting the tests bring the coke bring
their hamburger bring me tries bring
anything like that and the guide the
cashier which is constantly getting
requests from the line from the from the
year what we call the event queue is
always free to take more event more
tasks however if you give him something
difficult all of the people in the line
won't get their food probably okay so
that's node.js and that the platform
that we used for a game of hats again
looking at game of had two different
entities and you'll see along the line
why I'm talking about this there's the
difficulty level which is marked at the
top the score that you're gaining
there's the timer sixty second timer the
question of course the answers and the
code snippet itself these are all the
different parts of game of hacks where
all of them of course our target for
hackers to attack so what did people do
what did we get out of this honey part
what did hackers try to do so
players or hackers or just people who
are accessing the website they the game
we're able to figure out that you can
send the same answer on the same
question many times and someone wrote
here so he writes Alex here after
getting a question correct you can
submit the same post requests with the
same answer and very large negative
number for the time I imagine they're
just adding your newly calculated score
30 miners time to your session previous
score and then at the end he says a
lesson it's sanitizing inputs is right
and that was possible
so what we did once we found once we
detected that someone found that
vulnerability that we left in there we
added a question already answered flag
on the server side another thing that
people did was play around with the time
or the time was calculated on the
client-side calculating a timer on the
client's sorry but it's plain stupid
people were stopping the timer answering
the question then sending their own
their own time that they decided in many
cases they sent a negative number so
minus 999 999 999 and that calculation
gave them a score as highest possible
because of our calculation so what's the
solution for that very simple where
should we calculate calculate the time
on the server side and yes there is some
kind of network influence but it's very
very minor and it's negligible in this
type of application another nice thing
that happened and this one this one is
not one that we put in and purpose I
still don't know how to explain it but
its iOS no one knows how to explain iOS
so someone found that if you plan on iOS
and you put your finger on the screen
the time or stops so that was also a
trick that someone was hacking hacking
the heck they called it and now I want
everyone to take out their cell phones
or something that you can browse
internet we're gonna have a game it's
fun not gonna have any of you I'm not a
hacker just wearing a black hat someone
gave it to me
let's go so I'm going to launch the game
you're going to get a pin code on the
screen if you go to Kohout . I T is the
sound working volume yeah anything I see
people starting to join its good I did
this at I did this at DEFCON we had more
than a hundred players so let's see if
we can break break that I like my small
goats
Sevigny who hasn't join are we supposed
to hear the sound on the speakers around
it'd be much nicer if we can it's coming
from here at the moment here this or how
do I switch to speakers or headphones
I don't know when those too complicated
nevermind we'll do it without musical al
saying okay we have a hundred and
fourteen terrorism gonna start now
there's still time to join so don't
worry
gonna ask you a question the beginning
we're gonna have two or three questions
just so you get the idea of it first
question no points is everyone
comfortable in their seats have a colors
choose your colors and it's really sad
that we don't have the music it has
really cool
adds to the atmosphere I know I know
playback device this one set as default
you know sound ok give it one minute
just much nicer when you have some music
in the background that way I don't feel
embarrassed ending here on stage
completely silent
ranged from the TV
ok let's continue anyway I mean we don't
waste your time last chance to join if
everyone hasn't joined yet how many
participants to have their say on their
oh ok bit better answers five more
seconds we're gonna get a bit more
serious in a second
nice
ok don't worry it happens everywhere
ok next question what about this one now
ok I'm just kidding just getting will
skip this one okay now we're starting
seriously we're gonna have some code on
the screen
we're gonna have some code on screen I
hope it'll be a show properly it's gonna
give you it's like ok same format and
let's go
beginner level so I want at least 60
percent correct answers then more
seconds you don't know just get a ride
at sea
ok ok that's reasonable considering the
fact that not everyone here is a
developer I hope next one another one
another piece of vulnerability in the
code
I don't know the answer by the way nice
very nice ok let's go on going to see
some questions about game effects as
well but before that extra points which
one is Tom it's different in every
country by the way some people are
obvious and other countries it's not
that clear and now of course we have
everyone answer at a hundred and
forty-five nice very nice it's a it's
it's a tomcat ok tom cat some of you
know tom cat rights patchy things like
that
ok let's move on and I have honor bility
I think that's the last vulnerability
after that we have some questions about
game of facts about what we talked about
this one is supposed to be a bit more
difficult
how many answers did we get that someone
notice not going to calculate all of
that more than a hundred ok ok I don't
know how to pronounce that SEC of nice
going and MDN as a doctor in the nice
going ok so this one is really regarding
the game of hacks question so if we
randomized the answer order what's a
problem if we randomized it on the
client I give you a little time for this
next time I'll give you some more
several will know the correct answer of
course if the client randomized is
there's no way for the server to
understand what the correct answer is we
talked about this one who should be
validating the answer correctness 100%
ready is the answer
should be a hundred 4545 before yeah
that was a hundred percent right so it's
obviously the server has to go through
that one piece of node.js code anyone
can recognize the problem here that was
a problem we discussed initially not
many more
that's the last one before another one
that just interesting for my curiosity
we had that calculation of the score 60
time to answer a difficulty which
parameters would be easiest to break and
I showed you the answer to that in the
presentation itself
alright I'm to answer correct very nice
ok last question no points just out of
my curiosity because of what we do check
marks you don't answer you don't have to
but I really like to know the
percentages I'm guessing some of you use
more than one some of you don't use any
of these some of you do manual testing
but there was just out of my curiosity
and it's interesting to see that you
have more more static analysis and
dynamic analysis that's as good as smart
even though I think you need both of
them at the end of the day
ok so we're done with the game now comes
the om-d
sorry guys I'll give you both t-shirts
and if you all come to the booth I'll
give all of you t-shirts so was not
worth the effort
ok so going back to the presentation
we're talking about node.js know this is
the difficult part of the presentation
for me but they have to try and make a
demo work and it usually doesn't work
but we were talking about node.js the
platform is based on node.js the fact
that no jess is not good for CPU
intensive functionality and remember
this single thread the guy at the
cashier he can't do stuff that requires
him to think thinking is not good you
have to take and pass it on if you think
you delay everyone else no one gets
their food so we found this so what we
found we wrote this small piece of code
with an attempt to cause a denial of
service
gonna follow you know seinfeld is
seinfeld so no soup for you so denial of
service this small piece of code
actually take the number one and number
P calculates the sum of the numbers
together so it's a CPU intensive task in
case the number is big and the number of
small obviously it's smaller and I'll
show you how it works in a demo and what
the problem is this is going to be
difficult
ok we see the full screen
yeah okay so what we're actually doing
now is running the script in on a web
browser so if we look at the end of this
URL code your line you'll see that at
the moment it's calculating until the
number one so easy it's one and you also
saw that when I collected it came up
very quickly
want now what I'm gonna do sometimes
crashes my computer so hope that this
time I'll change this one in 25 so it
should be 15 the answer if I'm not
mistaken and I'll change this one into
ten million
1234567 what do you think is going to
happen if I run both of them together
wifi run-first the 10 million and then
the five anyone sorry so it won't crash
them up well unless my crash them if I
really did a denial of service act on it
was too heavy for the task but what will
happen and I hope that I'll be able to
show it to you is that the ten thousand
ten million the calculation is very
heavy so it's gonna take up the full CPU
have quad-core on here it's going to
take up 25% of the CPU and it wont let
the smaller calculation come in before
it complete ok so let me try it out
gonna click enter here was a bit fast
they had another 10 it'll be probably or
maybe I shouldn't at the orcas and I'll
crash it so let's try this
told you that was the hard part of the
presentation see now it took a bit
longer so it won't that the idea that
I'm trying to show is being gentle
because it's my laptop them more the
larger the number will be the more time
it will take to do the calculation the
more time we're taking up the resources
the CPU resource and the event loop the
node.js won't be able to continue doing
anything else is the idea is very simple
to run denial of service on a node.js
application if no one did any
sanitization or validation on the fields
themself
ok another thing about node.js which is
interesting OJS usually works very well
with MongoDB the reason for that is that
node.js is kind of naturally adapted to
to Jason and MongoDB is naturally
adapted to be a kind of don't know how
you call it a document database it's not
it's not table based and they both work
together very well so again without
proper validation someone can send out a
node.js a Jason query string that the
MongoDB will translate and be able to
either run an SQL injection without SQL
which is another demo that I don't have
time to show today or you can also use
regex and as we all know regulates is
very heavy on the CPU so again if there
is no validation on there someone can
run a huge group regulates like this one
for example and crashed the system again
let me see if I can do that
it's not letting me login of course the
right credentials but if I open up task
manager and you take a look at the CPU
here goes up to 25% immediately by
MongoDB if there are no longer reggae
acts which again I'm avoiding because
it's my laptop i dont wanna crash my
laptop now not in the middle of
presentation it would block the whole
CPU for a longer time of course so
that's what we call Greg X denial of
service it's something that has been
research and has been discussed in the
past for an OG earth a few takeaways so
why was I talking about gains what's the
whole point here so I started at the
beginning by mentioning that we believe
that developers should be part of the
security effort in each organization for
developing code the first step has to be
that the code is secure the way for the
best way in my opinion and this is how
we actually execute our product is to
make it interesting
make it easy for developers developers
wanted development get rid of the code
and you know passed QA and that's it but
if you want them to do security also you
have to bring them in you have to get
there there you have to get them to want
to do security so it has to be
interesting
easy to do and a lot of it and a lot of
education today is around gamification
so whenever you can game if I your
education
do that you can use game of hacks it's
on the web for free at kmart.com
regarding usage of code of course don't
think I need to say that here but
validate input length validate the input
in general you have to study each
language each language has its own
pitfalls for example node.js has the CPU
issue it has the Jason string issues
that have to be that developers have to
be aware of
learn the language that you're
developing learn its problems burns
learn its pitfalls mentioned OJS CPU
intensive and that is more or less it
unless there are questions questions I
asked a lot of questions yeah the source
code for for the demos I can send you
that I think I can send you that I'll
check with our with our developers in
internally if you wanna you wanna give
me a business card or stop by the booth
later on give me your email anymore
questions how should I be insulted or
was a very clear
okay thank you very much oh wait
question no class is there any way to do
you like distributed denial of service
attack directly from the chrome dev
tools for example from sorry directly
from the chrome dev tools
good question good question I'm not sure
I don't know that I am I must admit I
don't know the answer and not a security
code ur so I can check that again is
there any possibility to you bypass I
don't know chrome filters and there is
with us directly from the chrome dev
tools for talking about chrome there's
or Firefox deficits I don't want to so
we can check that off line not sure
about I don't think I can give you a
straight answer right now we have time
for 20 questions ok I'll make it an easy
one
what's your name and how do you generate
the code snippets on the game so it's
actually it's actually a cool thing
first of all we collected a lot of code
snippets by ourselves and we put him on
there but later on we allowed customers
and people think the game to send us
code snippets as well that they found
what what happens with a lot of our
customers is that well it's an
interesting story some of our customers
actually asked to have the game of hacks
as part of their as part of our product
in their organization so not a public
one but a game where their developers
can test the code in static analysis and
then when they 55 problems they can
share that on the game of hacks and the
other developers will learn from it
again educational very important we were
thinking of doing that we might do that
in the future
it's it's an interesting approach but we
collect code snippets from anyone who
wants to share them thank you
have researchers distributed sort of
game when I asked the players to align
DNA sequences in order to find the genes
responsible for certain diseases or
something like that and it helped them
further their research because a lot of
players did what their computers could
do so did you would you consider doing
using game of hacks to do this so so I
think that part of what we did with game
of hacks it's not exactly similar to
what you're describing and and first of
all I agree with you know the more
people you have looking at something the
more information you get obviously but
what we did with game of house was we on
purpose
caused it to be vulnerable which gave us
more information about it of course I
didn't I'm and the code snippets of code
snippets within the game
yes you get more opinions and yeah we
are getting we're getting constantly
more snippets from different developers
globally I think that if we go to the
game itself just try to I think there's
an option to send
or maybe you could feature instead of
just choosing the vulnerability other
comment sorry I do feature instead of on
top of choosing the vulnerability maybe
you could add a comment about the code
ok yeah there's a lot of stuff that we
want to add to the to the game there is
stuff like you know how would you solve
the vulnerability what's the best way to
solve the vulnerability and things like
what you mentioned and this is the first
screen on the on the page you can also
submit your own code with the answers of
course so that's something that we have
the developer community participate with
us but yeah I agree there is a lot more
that we can do and we will thank you
okay thank you very much thank you so
much