said to us passengers i'm really sorry
but i made a wrong turn
you all need to get out and i call the
headquarters so that they can throw me
back
on the correct route this funny incident
set me thinking about the covet 19. if
only the world leaders
governments international organizations
were honest
as honest as the bratislava trump driver
the mistakes were made own up to them we
were not prepared
we failed where do we go from here
the to-do list is rather long find the
vaccine
put the world economy right on track
restore
jobs enroll welfare for the needy
deal with public debt and last but not
least
be prepared for the next black swan
one more anecdote do you remember men in
black
the blockbuster comedy from 1997.
it is about secret agents monitoring
alien activity on earth
there is one memorable line from the
film
the agent k with the face of tommy lee
jones
says imagine a giant cockroach with
unlimited strength
a massive inferiority complex and a real
short temper
is tear-assing around manhattan island
in brand new edgar suit
that sounds like fun no ma'am we at the
fbi do not have a sense of humor
we are aware of end of quote
giant cockroaches are not on top of my
list of threats
but similarly respiratory viruses were
rarely mentioned
in reports before january this year
we as civil society government officials
business community
need to be prepared for the black swans
it may not be aliens but it can be
terrorists
or hackers it can be enormous
opportunities
but the fourth industrial revolution
brings
everybody who watched men in black knows
that there is a happy end to the story
the earth is protected from the scum of
the universe
if only real life solutions were that
simple
well i think that uh from what i have
seen uh globesec has
convened a very uh impressive group of
people that are subject matter experts
on our most
pressing global challenges and i've
really enjoyed the depth of the
conversations and i've learned a lot on
the topics and also
the energy and the ambition to do
something about these challenges
is something that i have felt so i think
if anyone is serious about
learning more and doing something about
the challenges that we face
globally this is a great place to be
[Music]
well hello and uh welcome to the next
session
we're going to be talking about a more
geopolitical eu
amid growing instability in the
neighborhood
and i would like to introduce my
distinguished uh panel we've got uh
katarina matanova deputy
director general of dg neighborhood and
enlargement negotiations at the european
commission uh
roland freudenstein policy director at
the wilfred martin center
on european studies which is in brussels
jakob visniewski vice president
for strategy at globsec and malinda
bregu
the secretary general of the regional
cooperation council
in sarajevo
there's been a lot of talk recently
about european sovereignty
and a geopolitical commission
which i suppose is to distinguish it
from a political commission
uh of the last time round uh mr burrell
uh has talked about the language of
power
but how realistic is this is this just
this kind of nice slogan
or does it mean something
we're talking about growing instability
in the neighborhood but
which i mean our neighborhood is pretty
big and it stretches for all the way
from
uh belarus to libya uh
so the question is no
one what can the eu do and can it live
up to these ambitions
of being a geopolitical actor
or uh perhaps this is something that
we're going to
uh live to regret using this um
expression
well i'm going to ask first of all uh
jacob jacob visniewski um from globsec
um so to to to to start us off
you know jakub is this it would be great
if there was a geopolitical
uh if the eu had geopolitical clout 27
countries all acting together
uh to do good for europe
for our region and for the world
but is it realistic what do you think
uh hello greetings from sunny bratislava
and my view of the geopolitical europe
is less
sunny and mind you it's not a criticism
of european institutions i think that
the fault
lies with the member states and the
mandate
that we have or not have given
to them it is very common for conference
panels like ours today
to conclude that it is time for europe
to become geopolitical
to be a superpower at the global stage
and i think this is a very
funny statement to make imagine that
this evening
i i come back home and i announce
to my wife and children
in case you haven't noticed that today i
will become a super dad
demanding even more respect or reverence
i i think it does not happen like this
you become a super god or a superpower
when you are useful and
or even indispensable for others and
objectively speaking for europe these
days it's very difficult to assume a
more effective
role at the global stage why first of
all europe is more
divided than it used to be many
countries want to cherry
big elements from global europe agenda
for example say poland and hungary a
second
reason why it is not so easy is that
europe of course is struggling
economically and socially ever since the
crisis of 2008
but also covet will definitely not
help italy is a good example of a
country
which is a shadow of of its former self
the third reason is that the eu is being
cash
strapped and it no longer can export the
stability
into neighborhood through enlargement or
any other
instrument neighbor neighbors simply
cannot be
that easily nudged into proper behavior
like democratic standards or integrating
their markets
with that of the eu the fourth reason
is that the world environment has
changed
where traditional european strengths
have decreased in importance
simply speaking the world is
transactional these days
europe has fewer friends and protons
turkey is a good illustration and china
and russia
have chosen to be rather fierce
competitors
than their partners and last reason
is that institutional reforms of the
last 10 years
have brought a mixed results i'm talking
about
external action service or or any other
institutional matters and it's very
difficult
for for the european commission to
conduct its role
when the real power
is increasingly shifting to the capitals
let me stop here and maybe in some other
intervention i could focus on the
constructive constructive agenda what
needs to be done and what can be
salvaged from this entire
situation right well that's a sort of
rather gloomy
but um straightforward um introduction
um melinda let's let's go to you uh
in recent discussions about
neighborhood and about foreign policy
there's been a lot of talk about
belarus the foreign ministers are
talking about that today in berlin
um then that will be no doubt linked to
the eastern mediterranean
and there's been a lot of talk about
libya but there's been much less talk
about the actual enlargement countries
uh to the south i mean namely
the western balkan uh six um
do you wish that the eu was acting more
geopolitically or how do you feel
this uh uh this geopolitical europe or
does it or does it really not mean much
much from
from where you sit
uh hello to everybody and thank you jean
so uh hello from from tirana this time
so my office uh
is in sarajevo but i'm actually in
tirana uh
well i've been thinking while reading
the question uh a lot and it's
not the first time that we hear about uh
the geopolitical eu or the role of the
geopolitics in na
in the region i know that some things
lead to other things
and time after time different crises
shift the attention
from the western balkans but we should
not
forget as well that before the pandemic
hit
everything and even during the first
months of the pandemic uh
we had the situation that we was even
more more
awkward and bizarre regarding the
western balkans
and i'm referring uh to the postponement
of
the decision on on the enlargement
package last year
and then the new methodology that was
introduced
and now i think that from that from that
time
uh everybody has welcomed uh the new
developments uh
as kind of let's say with the wishful
thinking that they will really
really push forward the process of
enlargement in the region
which has really taken a long a long
level so i will just give you two
examples
all the countries in the regions uh have
a contractual relationship
with the eu and that contractual
relationship or that contract is called
stabilization and association agreement
that stabilization and association
agreement was signed for example in
albania on 2006
and it has to expire in 10 years so 2016
the date was that time uh decided
thinking that after 10 years of beniya
would be a member state
the same goes for north macedonia but uh
again uh we cannot pick and choose uh
which problems the world will face
and and uh and definitely you has to be
a global a global player on that
but uh i would really pose the question
what do western balkans are still
waiting around from uh from the from you
uh and i think that that's uh that's
quite uh
quite important uh eu has still
a lot of role to play in the western
balkans
what western balkans i think would
expect is to have in front of them
a more silent and and assertive uh
eu member states i'm not referring to
the new commission
or the two eu institutions who are our
main partners in this journey
i'm referring to the member states to
their decision making to sometimes their
local policies
and and national agendas that do not
really leave room to think that western
balkans
outside eu it will not really benefit
the eu
it will only harm eu so uh
western balkans do expect a more a more
uh competitive eu
both on political and economic
perspective we do expect to break down
the barriers that can help western
balkans to move on and not stagnate
uh cooperation in the region has become
a reality
59 percent of the citizens support the
eu membership of their countries
eu has a lot of majority in the region
it's the main trading partner
for 72.8 percent uh
it's uh let's say the main the main uh
contributor in terms of fdi's it's uh
the main contributor in helping the
countries to face to face challenges
such as that of covet 19
with the recovery package of of 3.3
billion that was approved in uh
in springtime so there are a lot
of there is a lot of room uh for eu to
play its high
role in the region uh and i
i hope as well that some of the agendas
that
uh that started even during the pandemic
among
among the region and among the countries
in the region and i will go back and
mention that green lanes initiative that
was
too much appreciated this might be
a starting point to bring the region
closer to the eu to bring the region and
make it and make it be part of the
european supply chains
it will help the business uh to to
develop business and to improve
with each other it will help the real
connectivity in the region
it will help the transfer of know-how
and technology in the region
so that it will mean that will be less
threats
on the economic situation in the balkans
which is a big problem
less threats on people living massively
the balkans
and you know that that almost one in
four people
young people are eager to leave to leave
their home countries
this will mean that the region's
security i mean western balkans
will always be safer so there is there
is still a lot that i think
can can happen great well that thank you
very much i'm i'm going to to come back
to you because
uh but i i'm going to go on to roller
now but i
i have to say that uh if i have to think
of uh
one thing uh about the eu and
um uh western balkans over this pandaria
you know what i remember is um the the
president of serbia
uh saying that the eu was uh was useless
and that
uh serbia's real friend was china and
posters in belgrade
saying uh thank you brother xi so uh it
may be that the eu is it's
the the biggest contributor but the
question is perhaps people don't
realize that
do you want me to answer
go
roland maybe before you take over just
to quickly react on this last point of
tim
so he doesn't leave us stay hanging
about
uh president uh uh praising president xi
for the greatest okay
very quickly i'll very quickly react to
it that
uh indeed at the beginning at the
beginning europe had uh had a sneeze or
a or
or a little bit on yawn at the beginning
where where
borders were closing et cetera and i
think that
uh fairly rapidly uh we actually got our
act together and
realized that not only europe needs to
help each other among the member states
but
needs to offer a helping hand uh
to our friends in the balkans in the
neighborhood whether southern or western
neighborhood uh
eastern neighborhood and and also beyond
and under in europe uh branding
actually by mid-april we we we put
together
together with member states eu
institutions and eu financial
institutions
uh 25 billion euro package of support
but i'm not mentioning it for the for
the money but uh
to to address the point team that you
raised
with malinda uh really for the first
time in a very systematic way we
realized it's not only about the money
we put
but the communication that needs to go
with it because the amount of
disinformation
that there was at the beginning coming
from china
coming from russia coming from all sorts
of
places was necessary to address very
very
uh head-on and this is
what we started communicating and if you
post a question
now in serbia or anywhere else
and we have the data to support that
everybody would say that the eu was the
one
quickest to respond and and actually
deliver the goods
great okay we'll come back to you but uh
roland back to my
my question is a geopolitical europe uh
a useful expression i mean are we going
to see a sort of a
more muscular europe um which is going
to
impose its will in the eastern
mediterranean and belarus and
libya and so forth or or could that be
a problematic expression what do you
think yes
yes it could well first of all hello tim
hello everyone
thanks for having me and uh you know
hello from uh
kind of sunny and rainy brussels at the
same time which kind of reflects
probably the uh the situation of europe
that we're talking about here
so to your question tim uh i mean i have
a huge problem with the term
geopolitics in geopolitical
very often it's used basically as
code for power politics and yes
of course we have to build some more
muscles
and um we have to work on our
willingness to use the muscles
so language won't be enough but the
other implication of geopolitical
we are now seeing in belarus where
the self-appointed realists claim that
there are some
geopolitical like laws of gravity
that uh seem to indicate um
that neighbors of russia cannot
determine their own future you know as
far as their political system is
concerned
as far as uh you know sending uh
authoritarian kleptocrats to hell uh
and of course also as far as their
international allegiance and
and their alliances are concerned so so
you know i'd be
really really careful with using the
word geopolitics
because it somehow indicates that
some nations cannot choose their own
fate cannot choose their own future
because they happen to be neighbors of
this or that other nation
and uh those are usually china and
russia recently of course
uh so so so this is my objection to the
word geopolitical
but if it's just meant as a code word
for
the eu needs to be needs to work on its
capabilities
and its willingness to use force as one
component
of achieving its goals then i'm all in
favor but i
totally share jakub's skepticism
when he uh when he talked about the
limits uh to europe europe's uh
declared intention in the last 10 years
to become
uh a bigger global player and to become
uh
more geopolitical in that sense so
i think in order to achieve our goals uh
we also need allies and that's a that's
a key aspect i would like to throw into
this debate
europe will never be able alone to
become a global player we can only do so
with allies and that means other
democracies around the globe
and of course that's countries like like
canada australia but all
yeah japan and i think we have very good
chances
that after third of november in the
united states europe will
actually be able to remake to
renew the transatlantic alliance which
is
and remains key to everything europe
wants to achieve globally
okay well thank you thank you very much
uh we're going to come back to you uh
katarina
um you've heard
a lot of skepticism there um
there's been this uh clear
transactional element when it comes to
sort of belarus and the eastern
mediterranean with the greeks and the
the cypriots uh being kind of unwilling
uh
to to to to to to back uh tougher action
on belarus at what they want in the
eastern mediterranean
uh surely that's just going to sort of
think he's just going to um uh
the lowest common denominator which will
mean not much
well first of all thanks a lot for uh
inviting me
it's uh great to be uh virtually even
with globsec again and in my hometown of
bratislava which is indeed sunny
um few few reflections
uh first of all i i uh
very much understand the skepticism with
which uh
jakub started and and roland echoed
about the the uh the ability of the eu
of
acting uh uh together i mean there is
the perpetual
question there how much power the member
states are willing to
feed in the foreign policy arena
for the eu to have a more efficient and
faster decision-making process
and this uh this uh question is with us
in the in in in reaching our
geopolitical
ambitions and this is also a response to
you uh
tim uh the i would not
write off today at this hour
uh what is going to happen with belarus
what is going to happen
with the eastern mediterranean because
the one thing
to understand about europe is that
it is a process driven process-based
decision-making
consensus-making uh entity
so this is something that needs to gel
it needs to
it needs to grow and and eventually
in many cases maybe uh there are
exceptions
we reach the the right decisions but
it's a
it's not something that happens with the
snap of fingers
because it's uh it's a multi-stakeholder
a multi-stakeholder decision making so
uh
i think that it's important to see
what is happening now in the
international arena compared to
what was doable or what was happening on
the eu side
some time ago uh you look at the pesco
discussions and you look at the
discussions on
on cooperation in the in the defense
arena
and things that were unimaginable some
years ago
are are happening now it it's very much
the same thing with the economic
uh issues the fact that the eu is now
looking through
national budgets before they are
submitted to national parliament was
unimaginable before the
before the crisis i think that there is
always sort of
uh a push factor through various crises
that makes the integration
uh uh more deeper and more more
efficient
and the two big push factors right now
is the
loss of the eu sorry loss of the u.s
security
umbrella you know i'm sure that there
would be changes as roland mentioned in
a few months but
whether we would go to status quo it's
not it's not quite clear so the
the fact that we are on the left alone
or left with with fewer allies in
defending the multilateral order
is something that is is is giving the
eu the push to be more cohesive in the
in the international arena and the
second one is the uh
the assertive nationalism of of china
and and so trying to figure out how to
navigate that
and the third one perhaps not as
important as these two but the third one
when we talk about the neighborhood is
very important
is is is russia and the behavior of
of russia so i think that these are the
the
push factors that are
making europe more cohesive
uh uh also on the on the international
stage
but we are not there yet so i i mean i
share the skepticism but i see
i see uh developments and and
possibilities and i will use two
examples to
demonstrate that one we already
discussed
uh enlargement i mean after the
the pause and the
really sort of a major slowdown that
happened in the previous
election eu election cycle i think that
the recommitment to enlargement as a
realistic prospect
is now making uh its impact on the
region as malinda was also
also mentioning so i think that this is
one of the
key uh success policies of the eu is
back on the agenda
uh i think it was actually a very
instructive
very instructive hiccup on the way which
was
the pause on on albania north macedonia
at first and
what was important was the really strong
reaction
of the other member states pushing the
ones that did not want to
go through with it into accepting
enlargement
uh for the future so i think that it was
a very instructive
uh moment that happened uh
last fall with a positive outcome and
the second example i want to use
is uh is the role that the eu has played
uh in ukraine on the reform front i'm
not talking about the
means process but about the stabilizing
and sticking
with the ukraine through thin and thick
on the
on the reform agenda where the eu
has become the federator essentially
of uh of the international
support not only from the member states
but also from
from from other donors and instead of
speaking
uh managing the process in a way that
the international
community speaks with
one voice and and is able to to continue
supporting ukraine so i will leave it at
that just as these two examples
not perfect not the linear process but i
think we're getting there
okay but um i'm going to suggest that uh
being a geopolitical
europe means um basically
leaving belarus to its uh fate and uh
leaving belarus firmly under
uh the thumb of of moscow i mean i've
heard that referred to as this sort of
uh
kind of armenian solution that um
basically
you know we can we give it a little bit
here and there but it's going to remain
um under moscow's um thumb uh uh whether
people there like it or not and
that's
i don't know whether anyone would like
to pick that up
yeah could i um go ahead look yeah go
ahead
nail on the head uh absolutely this is
what some people are saying
i mean they're not using the same words
that you did they would never say we're
leaving the belarusians to their fate
no what they're saying is we're looking
reality
in the face we are seeing uh
geopolitical facts and so putin is never
going to
um permit the belarusians
to choose their own future that's what
these people are saying
and i think i think one has to severely
object to this
because it's not only it's not only
morally despicable
it is also it is and it is not only
contrary to all the values that europe
is built on
but it's also short-sighted and
unrealistic
because i mean what we've seen uh in
in belarusians waking up and
rising to the challenge um just in the
last three weeks
i think has been totally amazing um and
that should that should tell us that we
would seriously put ourselves on the
wrong side of history
if we now gave even the impression of
negotiating uh the future of belarus
with putin um you know i mean we're at
the moment our leaders are falling over
ourselves
over themselves in talking to putin
about belarus
well you know i mean they talking is
good uh there's nothing wrong with
talking they should clearly communicate
that here these are our red lines
if you cross those red lines there will
be consequences you know sanctions
um uh we will we will refuse to deal
with uh lukashenko if you keep him in
power beyond september 10th
um and so on and so on so uh
you know whereas whereas if we only give
the impression that we're
we're telling putin look you know i mean
if you
just keep your tanks out of belarus
will will totally agree to this
so-called armenian solution in other
words
belarus will remain in the eurasian
economic union
belarus will uh will not will never join
uh the eu or nato even in the far-flung
future
i mean look these are things for the
belarusian citizens
to determine and not for mr putin and
it's not for us
to even appear to be negotiating with
him about
with the words um hong kong uh and
china and uh is there anything we can or
could or should
be have done about about hong kong would
somebody like to
to pick that up
well i think that uh very very
okay you're jumping around
no i just want to i just want to echo uh
yeah i just want to echo what uh what uh
uh president vanderlian uh said and
which
which picks up on what roland just uh
just mentioned
that it's the i actually
don't see the call by the below russian
public for geopolitical
uh changes what i see is yearning by
a huge portion of the belarusian society
for a regime that allows free and fair
elections that allows
uh freedom of speech freedom of assembly
human rights etc
and and i think that uh
the eu is very much there to
support what the belarusian citizens
want
i let's not forget when we are talking
about armenian solution
armenian solution yes armenia continues
to be a member of the eurasian community
uh but there's been a regime change in
armenia
and and uh so what i what
what we very much would like to do and
our offering
to mr lukashenko is support for
we are calling for national dialogue
on the future of the country we are
supporting the
the civil society we are supporting the
the media
we just put together a fund or
contributed
significantly to a fund for the victims
of
violence and we very much subscribe to
the notion that
uh it should be below russian citizens
that choose the future of the country
not someone else
i suppose in the commission you must be
breathing a sigh of relief that uh
they're not
flying eu or europe lags because then it
would make it much more difficult
a sort of a ukraine redux perhaps
uh okay you you wanted to come in here
or yeah yeah but then roland and then
we've got a live question
right i would not like to bore you with
my reflections my
any longer be in this matter because i
fully agree
with my predecessors only bastards
and idiots actually would like to have
concerts of powers talking about the
fate of bela russians
without belarusians over the heads of
them
uh with russia so i think we are clear
on that of course
the devil lies in the details and my
memory goes back to the early 80s
when poland was in a very difficult spot
and the solidarity movement under leg
valencia
created some options for reform but this
regime change was not possible and hands
of people well well-meaning people in
the west
were tied so sometimes it's a very long
haul
sometimes it's about making all these
little inauspicious almost
boring things that katarina is talking
about
like helping with the media helping with
a
civil society and also we need to
understand that
we need not we must not commit the
mistakes that the other side is doing
which means that we cannot present but
we know better
the future of belarusians than the
belarusians themselves
this is a society which has a deep link
to russia and we have to
also understand that there are cultural
links
linguistic things and this is with
anybody who plans
a russian future already in the european
union or nato
should a little bit pause and
think twice because this is much more
complicated and much
more longer okay so yeah i'm so i'm
going to stop you there roland very
quickly because then we're going we've
got a live question
yeah about those eu flags you know let's
face it
the european union for many people
in eastern europe has become the formula
for democracy and the rule of law i mean
why should we be
happy or unhappy about some people
flying eu flags or not flying eu flags
if they do so um they are trying to say
that this is our preferred way to become
a modern
normal liberal democratic european
country with a functioning market
economy with a
with with with as little corruption as
possible that's what they want to say
and you know putin's conspiracy theories
and lukashenka's conspiracy theories
about this whole thing that's happening
in billabooze
being a machination of the west and the
cia
and who have you i mean this is going on
already
whether they're flying eu flags or not
so so tim to respond to your
sigh of relief theory uh i don't think
there is any sigh of relief about people
flying eu flags or not
all we want here in brussels is for
belarusians to be able to determine
their fate and
within our modest our modest limited
possibilities i think we will and we are
doing everything we can to help them in
this
great thank you okay well now we've got
our first uh live
question
thank you very much uh for connecting me
my name is cornelia bachu and i'm
connecting actually directly from the
ecpr conference
which is the largest uh gathering of
political scientists in europe so i do
hope that my question
is not going to be too theoretical uh
but i think it is important to address
when we talk about mega trends
so to make the connection to the meta
theme
of this session the question is uh and
which i would like to post to you
what is your prediction about the role
of the eu
in the future world order so in other
words
um how do you see europe in let's say
uh do you see europe as a big power as a
small power
as a no power or as a hegemon
and i was wondering uh what would be the
advantages and the disadvantages
of the eu being a hegemon in the future
world order
that is my question thank you very much
great okay well i'm going to ask
that's the type of question which um
from political scientists which we could
probably talk about
for the next uh week or so but we've got
to we really don't have very have
very much time um my linda we haven't
heard from you
again so i'm going to come straight to
you uh
the eu and in 2015.
uh well listening now uh
the discussion about uh the
all the worse and which is right on the
language of powers
spoken for so long in vila russia
i was thinking that the language of
power is impeccably spoken in western
balkans as well
so since years i would say and
i was thinking thinking a bit and i hope
uh that the reaction or the attention
uh of eu and other global players
in the region as well as it happens time
after time
will not to be quite high only when a
crisis
appears to be quite quite big and not
and can be can be handled because the
situation in the region has changed a
lot so and and if
i i can i can just pick a bit uh on this
concept of geopolitical
uh narrative on western balkans i think
that there is a change in the western
balkans uh
as well because until some years ago uh
said
poorly uh external actors had a stronger
say
but now uh nothing can be can be
dictated or planned without considering
uh that respective leaderships are uh
ready keen to be to be asked and then
and then heard so uh the active
actors in in in shaping the interest of
geopolitical
actors uh in uh in their favor will have
as well uh
to hear a lot and then expect even the
reaction from the local elites in the
region
which makes me uh sorry my linda
interrupt the question is about 2050
tell us briefly yes which makes me are
you going to be like in 2050
yes so uh and and that makes me makes me
think on the 2050 what well
20 20 50 it's a long way
forward i hope that before the the 20th
we will have western balkans and uh part
of part of the use so
uh all of the countries being being
members of
of the eu and for all the reasons that i
mentioned i mentioned above this is of
utmost importance but well 2050 it's
too far from now so i wouldn't really go
on on projecting
a future in 30 years 20 has already
passed for
for the region and i do i do expect and
i hope
that the situation will start to change
immediately if there is no reaction now
on
then on 2050 two scenarios might be
might be in place first we might have
western balkans joining
uh the eu just in terms of of uh
of papers because people would have
joined you already by leaving one by one
and then i might even imagine one of
your of your major concerns being being
published and
said and and being present everywhere
that western balkans will be shrinker in
number
and that might really be a big problem i
don't think that that will really
really help uh the not not even the
western balkans
that the population of this region and
it won't really really
give any any better shape to to you all
right so katarina
katrina 2015
katarina 2015 very briefly what going to
be like in 2050 will
the use it exist or will it be a hegemon
as we were asked
but briefly if 2050 is too far ahead uh
you can reduce it to maybe 2035.
well let me let me say this the eu will
definitely be around
and considering uh that eu always grows
through crises
and makes leaps forward through crises
and looking at the world today i do
expect many crises coming along so the
eu
will be internally strengthening through
that process so
2050 you will be alive and kicking i
would say
i would say an important power i
wouldn't necessarily go as far as
calling it hegemon but definitely will
be around
great roland hegemon not existing
where are we going to be in 2015. it
will be part of a global
alliance of democracies will have solved
the
rule of law problems in the european
union itself and we'll be discussing
really important things such as you know
whether we need whether we need to
address the spiritual needs of
of artificial intelligence machines um
or the colonization of planet mars
great okay jacob
i just want to say that i exclude the
possibility of the european union not
existing
i think that it might makes my life
worthwhile to
to fight for the big status of europe on
the global stage
i believe in some areas we are destined
to succeed
for example the digital sphere and the
digital revolution
for example climate change global trade
democracy
multilateralism these are all areas
where european strength
are already here today
thank you thank you very much well
really this is
i i kind of feel we've just just begun
and um unfortunately it is already
uh 2 45 um in in bratislava so
unfortunately we've already amazingly
come to an end of this session
so i would like to say thank you very
much to all of my panelists thank you
very much to everybody who's been
listening
and i'd like to refer you to the next
session
which is called pushing back against
state
capture and i'm sorry we've really just
started this topic uh maybe
um globs they could have a whole few
days devoted to this
that would be that would be useful i
think jakob if you've got that down we
could do a whole few days on the future
of europe
so thank you very much indeed to
everybody
thanks a lot
[Music]
globesec tetra summit drives discussions
that shape the future of europe
uncertainty you have uh brexit
you have the trade wars the climate
change has become
the part of financial risk making europe
green
making europe strong and keep europe
united
you can translate this in