[Music]
[Applause]
i'm jakub visnewski from globsec
few days ago i was taking a tram in
bratislava
to my utter astonishment it suddenly
changed
direction then it stopped the driver
got out of her compartment she smiled
apologetically
and said to us passengers i'm really
sorry but i made a wrong turn
you all need to get out and i call the
headquarters so that they can throw me
back
on the correct route this funny incident
set me thinking about the covet 19. if
only the world leaders governments
international organizations
were honest as honest as the bratislava
trump driver
the mistakes were made own up to them we
were not
prepared we failed where do we go from
here
the to-do list is rather long find the
vaccine
put the world economy right on track
restore jobs
enroll welfare for the needy deal with
public debt
and last but not least be prepared for
the next
black swan one more anecdote
do you remember men in black the
blockbuster comedy from 1997.
it is about secret agents monitoring
alien activity on earth
there is one memorable line from the
film
the agent k with the face of tommy lee
jones
says imagine a giant cockroach with
unlimited strength a massive inferiority
complex and the real short temper
is tear-assing around manhattan island
in brand new edgar suit
that sounds like fun no ma'am we at the
fbi
do not have a sense of humor we are
aware of
end of quote giant cockroaches
are not on top of my list of threats but
similarly
respiratory viruses were rarely
mentioned in reports
before january of this year we as civil
society
government officials business community
need to be prepared for the black swans
it may not be aliens but it can be
terrorists or hackers
it can be enormous opportunities but the
fourth
industrial revolution brings everybody
who watched
men in black knows that there is a happy
end to the story
the earth is protected from the scum of
the universe
if only real life solutions were that
simple
[Music]
[Applause]
my
hello everyone and welcome to globe sex
digital stage event on china's rise and
the challenge to western liberal order
my name is bradley jardin the
schwartzman fellow for the wilson
center's kissinger institute on china in
the united states here in washington dc
i'm a researcher with a focus on chinese
foreign policy and economic statecraft
and countries of the former soviet union
i'm delighted to be joined here today by
the honourable kevin rudd
mr rudd has served as australia's 26th
prime minister from 2007
2010 and also from 2013
and as foreign minister from 2010-2012
he's also a leading international
authority in china he began his career
as a china scholar
serving as an australian diplomat in
beijing before entering australian
politics
as prime minister he has led australia's
response during the global financial
crisis
uh reviewed by the imf time as the most
effective stimulus strategy of all
member states as prime minister and
foreign minister mr rudd was active in
global and regional foreign policy
leadership
he's a driving force and expanding the
east asia summit to include both the us
and russia
2010 and launched the long-term concept
of transforming
the eas into a wider asia-pacific
community
mr rudd is also president of asia
society and a frequent contributor to
financial times the new york times and
bbc and cnn
thank you for joining us here today uh
mr rudd
um i'll begin with our first opening
remarks
today we're here to discuss um the u.s
china relations
um and the challenge of arising china
for
a western liberal order
every day seemingly every week there
seems to be a new crisis in the
bilateral relations
it seems to be spiraling downward and
out of control
at this point what is the the end game
really
for the way relations are going how do
we reduce
tensions
well i suppose there are three possible
end games if you look at the
underlying dynamics of the u.s china
relationship
one is a hot war the second is sliding
slowly inexorably into a cold war
or thirdly is to find some exit ramp
from
a and b above in terms of the exit ramp
however that would require
a considerable change in terms of
china's current policy direction
because china has become more assertive
in its international
policy in the last several years
particularly under xi jinping
and the united states at least since
2017 has begun to react
first episodically now more systemically
and if the democrats win the
upcoming presidential race i would think
that would continue but probably
on an even more systematic basis so the
challenge
for the diplomacy on both sides of this
equation both in beijing
and washington is to identify
what possible exit ramps exist but i
cannot see that occurring
unless china begins to moderate some of
its current policy behaviors
with the upcoming u.s election there are
of course
domestic um influences upon u.s foreign
policy at this
this point with china and china's
current
international trajectory what the
domestic factors behind
xi jinping's current strategy and what
the constraints against them
changing course
well the question is an important one
because often uh when we
analyze the u.s china relationship we
look at either through a foreign
policy perspective or we look at it from
the drivers from u.s domestic politics
but the reality is there is a third
dimension here which is chinese domestic
politics
often opaque to the rest of the world
but frankly critical for us
all so if you look specifically at xi
jinping
yes he is by far and above china's
single most powerful leader since mao
on top of that he has um
embraced a policy uh posture
which is uh infinitely more assertive
than that of his three most recent
predecessors
and he would like i think within his
period in office
uh to bring about for example
reunification with taiwan
assuming he can hold on to office during
the 2020s which lie ahead of us
but politics in any country even
authoritarian states is not without its
opposition
so the nature of the opposition to xi
jinping is
a from a group of people who see him as
having taken
the domestic politics of china far too
far to the left
okay
so with the upcoming u.s election um
china is of course watching much like
the rest of the world very closely
what could they be hoping for as we see
china has become
a real fixture in american foreign
policy discussions become a real
um one of the major issues really
for us domestic politics at the moment
as well
um what kind of changes could we expect
of a shift in administration
or with china be looking for continuity
i think you're right to say that in the
u.s presidential election
china not only looms large but in fact
is relevant to
obviously all three of the major
questions which have been
posed in the debate one is when will
america recover from covert 19
2 what will be the economic damage and
who has a way out of it
and three on top of that what is
america's future in the global order
of course china is fundamental to all
the above
what's china hoping for in terms of a
political outcome
on balance the chinese would still
prefer trump to win
many would find this puzzling as an
observation but the bottom line is
the chinese have judged that trump does
not have any appetite for
conflict or war with china that trump is
by definition bellicose
that china uh that trump will prosecute
a vigorous trade and economic agenda but
he'll prosecute a much weaker
security policy agenda against china and
an infinitely weaker
weaker agenda against china on human
rights
therefore for those reasons china on
balance sees
trump as a better outcome for their own
national interests
and their track record for analyzing
that is they've seen trump time and time
again
intervene to derail the rest of the
administration's relatively hard-line
strategy uh on on china
if biden wins i think what the chinese
are concerned about a little bit like
hillary clinton four years ago
is that instead there would be a
different hardline systematic
strategy against china because many of
the personnel who would form part of the
national security
and foreign policy team for a biden
presidency would have been those who
staffed it also
for hillary clinton i think that's
therefore how beijing would view the
current reality
you mentioned a more hardline approach
toward china
what would this look like a hardline
approach
in practice and what would the chinese
worst case scenario of this be
what was their perception of a hardline
strategy
well let's look at it first in terms of
the economy
there's what we describe as the wider
debate on decoupling
at present the focus on the part of the
trump administration
is in relation to trade
and the deconstruction
of global supply chains which are china
dependent
and you see already the outworkings of
that with a number of global
corporations
beginning to offshore their
manufacturing
requirements to the rest of southeast
asia or elsewhere
but under the democrats the open
question is would they then take
what's happened with for example the
trump administration's ban on huawei
as a provider of global 5g technology
and expand that ban
more broadly into all other categories
of high technology
whether that's computer chips
microchips semiconductors whether it
extends further across the entire
artificial intelligence span
and from china's perspective that would
be difficult and damaging because they
still lag considerably behind
the united states and the rest of the
world in terms of the manufacture of
semiconductors
and so that's on the question of
technology
but the six thousand dollar question
literally under the democrats would be
what do they do indeed what would the
republicans do
if it came to decoupling the two
countries financial markets
now that would be of profound
significance given the size of china's
own uh capital reserves and what it
seeks now to invest both at home and
abroad
so the open question is what would
happen in capital markets
in the national security space i think
you're more likely to see a systematic
doubling down by the democrats in
support of its friends and allies in
southeast asia in the south china sea
and probably an equally robust posture
with the current
administration on the question of taiwan
and finally i think where it would
differ
demonstrably would be the democrats
would take on
china across the board on human rights
this is much more a fundamental democrat
constituency concern that it has been
certainly for the trump administration
and this is of concern to china
because human rights and an effective
international critique of it
tunnels back into chinese domestic
politics and the long-term political
legitimacy of the chinese regime
with a democrat agenda and a a
re-emphasis on human rights could we
expect to see more
direct actions in regard to the
situation in xinjiang
and also the changes in hong kong and
how would that affect chinese domestic
politics
i think you will see a doubling down on
the part of us
policy and strategy on these various
issues if you look at hong kong first
obviously the passage of the hong kong
national security law
the response by the united states
congress on a bipartisan basis
with the hong kong human rights and
democracy act earlier
and now the hong kong sovereignty act
more recently
the sanctioning of individuals but again
the six thousand dollar question will be
if repression continues in hong kong
will the united states then
uh begin to look at uh decoupling the
current
peg and link between the hong kong
dollar and the u.s
dollar which makes it possible for hong
kong to still be
one of the world's largest financial
centres and why this is relevant to
china
is because the hong kong financial
market is where
many prc companies raise their uh
dollar denominated capital raisings so
that would be i think a real risk in
terms of
hong kong if you flip up to xinjiang
then of course there begins to be a
symmetry emerging
in congressional and therefore by
extension democrat responses
between xinjiang and hong kong
in terms of the sorts of laws and
resolutions being adopted by the united
states congress
so the pressure will come on again for a
more extensive sanctions regime
this gets serious when it begins to
touch on financial sanctions against
chinese state institutions
because that given the centrality of the
dollar to international financial
markets still
would then impede the capacity of china
to become a greater and greater player
in global financial markets
could we expect to see china pushing
back against the dollar hegemony
in the near future worth their security
outlook
to really identify the pillars of
american power as being
its military predominance and also its
financial power
um there already seem to be maneuvers of
china
um trying to challenge the dollar um in
some sense especially
with regard to its new cryptocurrencies
can we expect to see more
such policies in future
will you write to us as i've written
uh consistently and extensively that the
twin pillars of american power are
the power of its military conventional
and nuclear
plus uh the power of u.s dollar as a
global
reserve currency and therefore the
currency of exchange
overwhelmingly in global financial
markets
so china full of
realists has been seeking to close the
gap on both these
equations over a long period of time as
far as the dollar is concerned
china's strategy has come in several
waves
first they've tried to establish during
the first decade of this century
a whole series of bilateral
currency swaps between local currencies
and the renminbi
and all in order to avoid using the
intermediation of the us dollar
in settling international trade accounts
the problem is that still after 15 years
or so
has only resulted in a relatively small
proportion of global trade
being denominated in non-us dollar terms
the second wave of the approach by the
by the chinese uh in dealing with the
challenge of the us dollar has been
through the international monetary fund
and having the renminbi accepted as as
part of the global basket
of special drawing rights or so-called
sdrs
uh that occurred about a decade ago
and but once again if you look at the
proportion
of countries around the world who have
renminbi
in their national foreign reserves uh
the total proportion of reserves held in
renminbi
as opposed to the us dollar or other
hard currencies like
the euro or the yen is still relatively
small
so now we see the third wave which is
the launch recently of the digital rmb
china strategy there i think is looking
at the explosion in digital commerce
which they've had domestically
over the last several years through
alibaba and alipay and their domestic
competitors
has seen us now rolling out globally and
therefore
if china's being able to dominate the
global technology markets for the
global digital commerce through these
massive platforms
then their argument is we could also
dominate global markets as well
in having the digital
markets settled
in a digital renminbi and this has
recently been launched of course with
the covert 19 crisis
and the migration of much commerce
online it's possible we'll see
more and more of this but what's the
ultimate problem
the ultimate problem is still that china
refuses to liberalize
its capital account uh continues to
refuse to liberalize its currency
uh in terms of foreign exchange markets
and as a result
china does not have the confidence the
international community
to become a preferred currency in terms
of
what would then become a central player
in global financial markets
so so long as china refuses those two
core decisions
and frankly causes the rest of the world
to fear that it would still politically
intervene
in terms of the value of its currency if
it felt as if political sovereignty
questions were at risk
it's going to be quite a long time still
before the remnb
is in a position to effectively
challenge uh
the dollar's current supremacy
and as for global um economic order
more generally speaking with the
coronavirus
a lot of debate is being had as to
whether china is competing with the us
in terms of presenting its model of
politics
having been more efficient in dealing
with the pandemic
and your writings for foreign affairs
you've argued that both
the us and china have lost some of their
global prestige
could you speak to that a little bit
more and explain why that might be
and what the next steps would be for
reestablishing some control over the
coronavirus
well i think there's been an assumption
on an argument by some
um as is the way with many of these more
superficial international debates
that uh when chronovirus broke out in
china in january february
that this was going to deal a mortal
blow to the chinese communist state
in fact as i've written elsewhere you
could almost hear the audible popping of
campaign
of champagne corks in various corridors
in the pentagon
that was dumb in itself because it
failed to demonstrate any level of real
solidarity
with the chinese people going through a
terrible period of pain and suffering
but also it was grossly premature
because it assumed that the chinese were
not getting control
get in control of this and instead what
emerged was a china which could have
could effectively through its own
authoritarian systems and surveillance
technologies
bring about levels of social
surveillance and and uh social isolation
uh which would perhaps have been
impossible in western liberal
democracies
however the takeout is this the
centralized one-party state nonetheless
fail to prevent the outbreak of this
thing there were huge
failures in the chinese system in the
first critical three to four weeks of
the initial outbreak
which enabled it to go from a local
outbreak and a part of wuhan
in hubei province in china to then head
out across the entire city the rest of
the province and to other parts of china
and then to the world and doesn't matter
how much propaganda is applied to this
the bottom line is that's where the
virus came from
and the chinese system failed to contain
it in those first critical few weeks
and they should have done so based on
the deep learnings from the sars
outbreak of a decade or so before
as for the united states obviously the
champagne cork ceased to be popped
when the virus arrived in the u.s of a
and then we saw
on full display the rank incompetence of
the trump administration's efforts to
rein
in the virus across the united states
ranging from non-scientific denialism
on the part of the president through to
his episodic advocacy a bit like a 19th
century
quack apothecary of certain cures for
the american people
to then blaming the states of the us
federation for their
differing levels of response but what's
been on display
around the world and used for propaganda
purposes within china itself
is the dysfunctionality of the american
democracy
in dealing with this challenge but at
the same time
other democracies for example in new
zealand other democracies for example in
canada and other democracies
in various parts of europe have managed
this reasonably well
not to mention those in japan and most
acutely from a chinese perspective on
taiwan
what happens in the post-covered world
whenever that happens to be
if and when we obtain a virus and that
vaccine i should
say against the virus and the vaccine is
properly distributed
i think we're going to see a damaged
china and a damaged america
and the question for both of them is how
do they rebuild
domestically but most critically rebuild
a global credibility
which for different reasons has taken a
huge whack as a result of covet 19.
i believe we're taking a question from
russia
be appearing on screen
uh hello uh and uh
thank you prime minister for uh your
very interesting thoughts i am
mikhail troysky from moscow and
my question concerns your assessment
of the current extent and also the
desirable extent of coordination
between the united states and its allies
including australia of their policies
and approaches
vis-a-vis china so do you believe
there's enough
coordination between the united states
on one hand
and european union and australia
on the other hand in their approaches to
dealing with china should that
coordination be stepped up perhaps
or you are just having enough of it
thank you very much
well thank you very much for the
question and my greetings to all of our
friends in mokba
i've been there quite a number of times
and also looking at the question of
russia-china relations as well which i
find
inherently fascinating i think what has
happened is the united states over quite
a long period of time has sought
to coordinate um a general policy on
china
with its allies both in europe and in
asia
but for various reasons various of the
allies have been unwilling to be drawn
into
a more generalized u.s
china strategic confrontation
not just economic reasons for not
wishing to be so involved
but a range of um foreign policy factors
as well
however what has changed in i think in
the last
year or so has been almost an automatic
reaction against
china by a number of european and
asian democracies in particular as china
has become progressively more assertive
and certainly we saw some signs of that
in 2019
but in 2020 particularly in the covert
world
we've seen an eruption of tensions
between
china and a range of other countries
semi-simultaneously
certainly with the canadians certainly
with the australians
certainly with the japanese and
certainly
in europe with the british and with
others
and the net consequence of all this has
been
that whereas before there may have been
some reluctance on the part of
america's democratic allies to begin to
coordinate policy and strategy
in relation to china china itself by
virtue of the dynamics of its new
assertiveness
are reinforced by what they describe as
its wolf warrior diplomacy
using the chinese term jan lang waijal
has in fact created created its own
reaction
and as a result we now see almost
spontaneously
a greater interest on the part of allies
to have a common script in relation to
china i've observed this myself in the
last six to twelve months
alaskans in particular now where it goes
to in the future
is an open question i think it hangs on
two obvious variables
one if biden wins
that will provide the allies with
greater comfort because the allies have
generally found
trump to be mercurial unpredictable
and generally domestically politically
unacceptable
a biden presidency would be more welcome
and therefore a biden
asked for greater strategic coordination
on china is likely
to be well received but secondly the
other variable is what does the chinese
themselves do
will they adjust their wolf warrior
diplomacy or not
certainly the chinese in the last two to
three weeks
with important speeches by the foreign
minister wang yi
and by the politburo member and former
state councillor yang jia chu
as well as other statements in the
chinese official media
indicate a certain as it were
de-escalation of its wolf warrior
diplomacy
uh at least by several notches will
china continue to do that in order to
as it were de-assertive itself as far as
in which it's seen in other capitals i
don't know but they are the two
variables what happens in washington
and what happens in beijing thank you
for your question
one final question to round off our
discussion
um we've been discussing a lot about um
competition between the united states
and china
but the pandemic has really revealed the
need for more cooperation on the
international stage
which other areas do you think that
china and united states could cooperate
and how could we bridge relations
between the two through cooperation
well it in the future
in terms of the overall dynamics of the
u.s china relationship
in my argument it would fall within a
number of categories there are going to
be those areas of
direct confrontation where red lines
will be drawn
and red lines sought to be enforced and
those difficult and potentially
dangerous areas will continue
and i think we know what that list is
but there'll be also other areas of what
i describe as strategic competition
where the two systems will be not just
competing against each other
ideologically but competing in foreign
policy terms and economic terms
etc but all against the overall matrix
of a
competition of power but then you come
to the third category which you've just
referred to which is where it's still in
both countries interests
and their national interests to find
areas of collaboration
for example in the old cold war between
the us and the soviet union
soviets in the americans found common
cause in various significant
arms control agreements even in areas of
global public health
at the time with polio outbreaks etc
there was collaboration
so for the future where would i see that
lying
certainly under a democrat
administration one a more effective
approach to pandemic management
between china and the united states
and rather than playing the blame game i
think there'd be a predisposition to get
on with it
find the vaccine declare it a global
public good and get it out there as
quickly as possible
i think secondly climate change
collaboration
uh will be critical uh these are the
world's two largest emitters of
greenhouse gases
uh and the impact of extreme weather
events
uh look at the floods and almost
unprecedented floods in western china
but what's happened to chongqing uh look
what's happening with the wildfires and
currently in the west coast
the unprecedented storm intensities now
coming in on the atlantic coast
wildfires in australia similarly what's
happening in the russian federation and
elsewhere in the world
i think these global planetary factors
will bring these two countries together
as well
with focused climate collaboration third
possibility
maybe they will be be able to get across
the threshold
and begin to look at various levels of
arms control as well
for example in the new generation of
artificial intelligence driven
robotic warfare so there are three
potential areas for
let's call it a collaborative approach
mr kevin rodd thank you very much for
your time and for your
very informative answers
good to be with you on this program
even prior to the coronavirus pandemic
the u.s china's tensions
have spilled over into global trade and
heightened political confrontations
in addition to president trump's trade
war the u.s has repeatedly
condemned chinese track record on human
rights
and upped its military presence in the
south pacific
the relationship is at a low point
probably the lowest
since the u.s formally recognized china
in the 1970s
the big question is whether or not we
will see a further deterioration
or there is a chance to salvage this
relationship
as the world's largest economies and two
military superpowers
this question has ramifications beyond
their diplomatic
posturing the eu is often
caught in the middle and that's due on
one hand
to a lack of coherent foreign policy
when it comes to beijing
you consider china both a partner a
competitor or strategic rival
pointing at beijing's treatment or
unfair treatment when it comes to
european multinational corporations
and lack of access on one hand and their
anti-democratic governance structures on
the other
but in the same time struggles to find
the perfect middle ground to cooperate
with china
the eu has reached across the pond to
try to find ways
to work with the united states when it
comes to the relationship with beijing
but the low tide in the transatlantic
relationship might have a say
the big question moving forward is how
we will be able to ensure
that we are not moving towards an
escalation
of this conflict into something that
will have global consequences
and how we will be able as transatlantic
partners
to work with china without sacrificing
our liberal values
[Music]
[Applause]
good afternoon and good morning everyone
welcome back to the second day of the
globsic digital stage
my name is alina kutzko and i'm director
of the globsec policy institute
i'm very delighted to start the day with
the topic that goes
into the core of the discussion about
how the global system is structured
what are the ways in which it is
arranged and what is the current and
developing balance of power between
various
actors from climate change to trade to
pandemic to security
the debate about the future of relations
between the countries globally
is very much underway and we're very
happy today to contribute to this
discussion
and today debates on the constructive
way to move forward
for this purpose with me here today are
three fantastic speakers
andrew small who is a senior
transatlantic fellow
at the german martial fund of the united
states currently based in berlin
bradley jordin schwartzman fellow at the
wilson center
glasgow and miss jean li hua
resident scholar scholar at carnegie
sinhala center for global policy based
in beijing
welcome everybody and thank you very
much for joining
we purposefully and i admit slightly
provocatively
titled this session trends china's
continued rise versus america's relative
decline
we also encourage our participants to be
very
open very honest and in a way
provocative and ask our speakers
challenging questions
as we aim to find very honest and
constructive answers to the pertinent
topics
i will start with andrew and ask him to
be the first to address the question
that concerns everybody today there has
been a lot of discussion that covet 19
has been some kind of a great excellent
accelerator that highlighted and
overcharged the nascent trends rather
than developed something new
andrew does the same dictum applied to
the global power relations
how do you assess the change of global
power balance that is happening during
this poverty 19 times
thanks very much alina and thanks for
the chance to to join this
session today at globe sec and so i
think you can begin by analyzing this
um through the economic prism of course
and what this does to the distribution
of power
as a result of the covert 19 pandemic
china was of course hit first has
recovered first
a number of the other asia pacific
countries that were hit in the first
phase
two and generally dealt with the
pandemic very well are also recovering
relatively quickly
the us even now has failed to get a grip
on the pandemic really at all
europe was hit even harder than both the
us and china economically
um but it's forecast to bounce back at
least more strongly than the united
states
in 2021 and of course the the very
ambitious
even uh transformative recovery plan
given the new
um uh debt issuance mechanism and that's
really just to talk about the economies
and regions
that have the wherewithal to take on
debt and to finance a recovery
a lot of the developing world is really
going to struggle in the next period and
we haven't got anywhere
close i would say to to a comprehensive
settlement there
um even with the short-term agreement at
the g20
including with a lot of the cases where
china is now a major creditor
but i think beyond some of the things
that we can debate about the
short to medium-term economic trajectory
and what that will do to the power
balance
i think we have to look at the views
that are
that have developed of of the different
powers and and how they've handled the
the crisis
um where i think the picture in europe
has been quite mixed
um i think the us uh certainly taken
kind of a reputational hit for its
handling of the of the pandemic
but i think what's going on with china's
reputation through this
is likely to be longer lasting um than
that um i'm not necessarily talking
about
the handling of the outbreak in in wuhan
of course um significant culpability in
the chinese system for the fact that it
wasn't contained at that point
um but i think the legacy that we're
likely to see of this kind of
turbocharged assertiveness that has
played out through the pandemic
just to kind of run through a few of the
most obvious cases
the economic coercion of australia that
we're seeing even now
military incidents with vietnam japan
and taiwan
uh the worst border altercation that
we've seen with india really in decades
all of the wolf warrior diplomacy in
europe in brazil
in other cases uh what's played out with
the hong kong national security law
uh the treatment of african nationals in
guangzhou
and that's just to do a kind of you know
very short list of
of some of what's of of what's played
out just in the last few months
uh alone um i think the result of a lot
of this
is that you're getting a long list of
countries that are in the process now
uh of of going through a pretty serious
rethink of their
relations with china uh some of which
was already in motion some of which has
as you suggested in your question
been kind of accelerated by the crisis
whether it's india australia canada the
uk
a lot of europe and that adds of course
to the places where we'd already seen a
big briefing taking place in recent
years
united states japan and so on and what
we're seeing in most places
is more of an emphasis on competition
and in some cases rivalry
and i think kind of a pairing back of
some of the areas of cooperation that
were
envisaged and to some extent a more
ideological quality being being taken on
as as was
sort of suggested a little bit in the
introduction to this panel
and this is really happening
simultaneously across a whole range of
different countries and regions
and the big risk that china faces uh in
all of this
is uh even with its continued economic
success
uh the the potential for a kind of
countervailing coalition to rise as a
result
um and still even with the troubles that
the united states
has faced in the last period of time the
biggest asset that the u.s still has
if it can take advantage of it which has
not been able to really in the last few
years
is that its network of partners and
allies still completely dwarfs
in economic technological and military
power anything that china is able to
stitch together
and still really has tremendous leverage
to set rules to exert pressure
um and to construct new structures of
interaction with
uh with the various parties um among its
partners and allies
um with each other in you know for
instance technology and data
that effectively cut china out of some
of these important areas
and i'd say particularly if you have a
change in administration on the u.s side
you're likely to see a lot more of this
kind of coalition building
vis-a-vis china and that will in part be
a legacy
of how china has handled the crisis both
in its immediate manifestation in china
but as much how china has behaved in its
economic diplomatic military
assertiveness
throughout the crisis
thank you so much andrew for unpacking a
whole bunch of issues that i'm sure
we'll touch upon later
and i want to proceed connect what
you're saying also to
bradley and bradley your discussion with
the honorary kevin rudd
i remember you asked him a question at
the beginning that the u.s and china
relations seem to be
spiraling out of control i want to ask
you the same question what is your take
on that
and whether there is a qualitative
change in the relations
between us and china but also us a
chinese position globally in the world
in the aftermath of the covet 19.
i think there's been a huge shift in uf
rhetoric and outlook
toward china we've of course had decades
um based on the assumption that
cooperation trade with china would
eventually lead to
a systemic shift within china itself or
more liberalization of its political
system
there seems to be a growing consensus
within the u.s
especially that that that hasn't been
the case and the china is now framed as
a major challenger
a systemic rival at that with a
different um
political economic and ethical um
structure that challenges the us um
liberal order
so now this challenger rhetoric has
really become the centerpiece um of how
we think about relations
and to speak to some of what andrew was
saying it seems that
the pandemic has actually acted as an
accelerator where we're seeing
um now even the response to the pandemic
itself was presented in competitive
terms
the china model versus the us model
china model taking a lot of
global criticism of course for the
initial cover-up of information
and the delayed response to the virus
which allowed it to become pandemic
to begin with but also in terms of the
us which has also
been slow to respond and has taken a
large
economic hit china has been placed in a
very difficult position
and will continue to be for the the near
future
both in terms of dealing with um
criticism
um labeled out with um regard to his
handling of the crisis
but also with the belt road project
which has been
the major flagship um
chinese initiative on the global stage
now we're going to see
a lot more as economies around the world
are facing a lot of strain they're going
to struggle to
pay back these chinese loans which is
only going to enhance
the criticism of china and chinese
foreign policy that's been labeled for
years now which is this idea that
china's launching debt trap diplomacy
this idea that china will
in debt countries and then seize
strategic assets from the whether it be
ports
or gold mines in the case of central
asian countries such as purity's down
this places china a difficult spot where
it will need to
collect its debts back in order not to
for his projects to
suffer too much economically but at the
same time it would be a pr
issue for china to be bridging relations
with these countries and then to claim
such assets so this is going to be
difficult as navigating the belt and
road in the long run
um we'll probably see a shift in china's
strategy
of more a more focused belt and road
project where there's going to be a lot
more
scrutiny over investments a lot of
efforts to try and avoid these so-called
white elephant projects
um seem to have no economic value
so in some ways i think the the belt and
road as being the major flagship
aspect of competition between the us and
china globally
we could see china retrenching almost
focusing on core areas
and having a more rational allocation of
resources with regard to that
thank you so much bradley and uh i would
like to ask now ms
jean-liquid to respond to the previous
speakers
there's we can definitely sense that
there is a much more
awareness and even concern in the west
about the rise of china how does it seem
from beijing
and how do you see the change in the
power dynamics
in the global system now
okay thank you very much for your
inviting me
and your software arrangement
for this event i want to talk about
how high commander 919
impact the distribution of power
globally some people think
that the chronomers
has affected the global distribution
of power china is getting stronger
and in comparison the united stand
is in decline the world is
forming a bipolar system
between the u.s and china i disagree
with this view i don't think
that convention 19 will fundamentally
change the global distribution of power
the u.s is still
the only civil power in the world
and the eu russia china
other major powers although china is
rising
china has no intention to challenge
the statue of u.s and
no intention of changing u.s positive
position in a world of complaining
with the us for global heightenment
since the command 19
pandemic
administration has described it to china
and
extern a full run of extreme
pressure on china china is owning curry
out self-defense
measures china has been talked to
the us for continued cooperation and the
mutual
benefit china pursues the principle of
harmony with different this means
that even though i
cooperation with you i have my own
ability and i don't follow you
in everything if think
if i think you did it right
i agree and if you do it wrong
i still put forward a different
opening therefore in china will not
stand on the opposite side of the u.s
uh from another competition
group to establish the bipolar
world therefore there will be
no fundamental change in the
current international structure
of one superpower and
multiple major power this is my idea
thank you
thank you so much for explaining some
issues that we've been struggling with
and i would like to start with a second
question and go back to andrew andrew
you mentioned a lot the
value of the partnership and coalition
building in these times
and i'm wondering how the relations
between the united states europe and
china could look like
because we know that even relations
between the eu and u.s have not been the
most
stable definitely they are good but
there are certain frictions
and there are definitely different
levels of relations between the eu and
china and the us and china
could you untangle that a little bit and
maybe also mention which errors could be
the areas of strategic partnerships
and in which era specifically still the
three
uh centers of the relations are still
seeing each other as competitors
sure um well maybe i'm starting with
with with the us dimension and
again we're a few months out from an
election so
we know in principle the trajectory that
things are headed
on under the trump administration that
we might expect to continue
i think on the u.s china front we'd
probably see things stabilize a bit if
there's a change in administration
uh in a few areas less arbitrary use of
tariffs
language would be less confrontational
and there'd be some attempts to resume
cooperation in at least a couple of
areas such as
uh climate if you had a biden
administration um
but as i suggested in in the first um
part of the discussion um i think
abiding administration would also see
a far more serious push to join forces
with allies on china with the europeans
in a very very central role
and i think the prospects of that
happening and happening seriously
would be much more likely if you did see
a change in in administration
um and i think it will be one of the
major priorities for um
uh for abiding administration and in the
transatlantic relationship
um uh if you do get um a change in the
elections in in november
and then on the u.s china side i think
most of the fundamental areas that
where competition has accelerated in the
last few years economic
technological uh even ideological uh
military was
was always there before um or at least
in the last couple of decades
all of that will continue um i think the
european case
is is is is a more complex case
um we've seen clearly a shift in views
in europe in the last
few years bradley referenced the the
concept of
uh systemic rival which the eu has
started
um talking about um just in the last uh
two years
um and i think you've seen this move in
europe
um particularly on the economic side
towards a view that says that the level
of
asymmetric openness between europe and
china where
china is relatively closed to european
companies
and europe is relatively open to china
in all sorts of ways
has to be rebalanced there needs to be
greater reciprocity
and that europe needs to get some new
tools in place to be able to deal with
all of this
uh more effectively um and i think
you've started to see as well
and particularly as the kind of
prominence of china in the european
political debates has has gone up
uh much more emphasis on a lot of the
values questions that had
almost been buried in the relationship
for a while particularly as some of
those values
questions start to affect uh things at
home
in europe and 5g was a big example of
that where
um i think when you're talking about
data security privacy and
and so in in europe itself um that in
addition to all the questions around for
instance hong kong
and starts to raise the salience of um
of of the values dynamics in in the
europe china
um relationship um but i think europa
had still really wanted and still wants
to find
a fairly substantial set of areas of
partnership with
with china um but i think they just
haven't been
getting anywhere uh with with that in
the last period of time
i think europeans would like an
investment agreement that provides
better market access and investment
protection
they'd like an agreement that sees china
taking on more ambitious climate targets
um even on the belton road i think
they'd like to be able to cooperate on
high standard infrastructure in africa
and elsewhere and but these
can't just be kind of theoretical areas
where it would be good if the two sides
were able to work together
i think the sense on the european side
and even for the biggest advocates of
the partnership
uh is they've been trying again and
again and and really getting nowhere on
this
um and so i think even on some of the
areas of potential cooperation
i wouldn't be surprised if they took on
didn't take on a more kind of
competitive quality as well so for
instance
climate cooperation yes i think that
will continue to be a priority but
you know with a carbon border adjustment
mechanism or other sorts of steps
trade cooperation yes but with stronger
tools to go off the chinese subsidies
and force reciprocity
uh belt and road cooperation also would
continue but
i think with more of a push um to
provide high standard alternatives for
countries
and to go after unfair competition with
with chinese firms
and so i think the sentiment in europe
as well is that even some of the areas
of potential partnership
are taking on a different quality uh now
as a result of
of kind of this continued kind of
bashing against the brick wall that's
been going on with china
in in the last few years
thank you so much andrew and uh that
seems to me like a good timing to go
back to
miss jean vichua also uh in your
assessment whether you agree with andrew
on his
division between which eras currently
give the biggest promise for the
partnership
and which errors were still competitors
uh i want to talk about the second
question okay
uh how can the u.s eu china
a triangle perfection okay
may i go ahead absolutely
yes
china and the year share many
uh coming interesting the eu
is china's largest country partner and
the trainer is the eu's
second the largest uh training partner
so i think china and the eu
have similar outlook on global
governance already issued the great
potential of diversity partnership
between china and the eu for example
global governance environmental
protection a nuclear
non-proliferation oppose the
armories advocating uh multiliterally
and promoting the world a multi-product
structure and so on since the
dynamic the relationship between china
and the eu
have become closer than before
the leader of china and the european
health exchange
greeting encourages each other
provides mutual medical
support and operating
in complete the coronal
virus the 10 year comprehensive
investment agreement is also
in the process of negotiating
the u.s the u.s
ruling group believe that china is the
potential
threat to us and have money positions
in the world regarding china
as a strategic competitor
or even an enemy this is a
actually misperception
about china china is a socialist
country it's true
but it is the resentful peace and the
harmony
country and a chinese tradition cultural
manual
such as harmony benevolence
ratchetness courtesy wisdom
honest have influenced the stature of
the chinese people
and the chinese leader and the
chinese foreign policy the sort of
harmony
terrors to those things with companies
face of justice honesty and
trustworthiness modesty and protest
as well as respect for others this
philosophy also tells
that too much is as bad as
too little since
speaking hard money would hurt would
harm
chinese net national interest and even
pleasure neither tool is
that for a resident china will never try
to domination
the world there are
there are numbers examples showing the
difference of harmony then in
history in fact china is an
important force that helped
maintain the u.s superpowers leaders
cannot help with human resources
underwears china is the world's largest
formatted
especially as the largest consumer
market
for agriculture and technology products
from the us chinese
students scientists and engineers are
also
the backbone of american laboratories
additionally americans
have benefited from the signal u.s feed
by enjoying quality and in expressive
communities from china china hope to
continue
it's all around the cooperation with the
u.s
as before however the tribal
administration's
extreme press on china has
undermined 10 u.s cooperation
the number is changing
this is this is my idea thank you
thank you so much for the comprehensive
response and we have already a few
questions from the audience being lined
up
so i'm going to bring in the first
participant video to ask the question
uh good afternoon hello esteemed speaker
andrew hilton the defense
uh security fellow at globe sec uh
ingredients from vienna
building on what andrew smalls small
mentioned earlier about allies
wangi china's foreign minister begins
his tour of europe
apparently on a platform of jump
starting the global economy and working
on multilateralism
minister yi will visit italy the
netherlands norway france and germany
all countries that secretary of state
mike pompeo didn't visit on his last
european mission
so specifically to andrew what can
china's top diplomat realistically
expect with these meetings given the
reshuffling of both the internal
political dynamics in these capitals as
well as the lingering burn of the
pandemic
from my mind things like his ability to
offset america's full-court press on 5g
obviously skating the organization of an
independent commission
or even potentially avoiding the hostile
takeover of tick tock on european soil
comes to mind
thank you very much
thank you very much roger i actually
will ask bradley to answer the question
first and then go to andrew
sure thank you um for that question
um i think it speaks more broadly i mean
to frame that
question within the previous one which
is about the role of the european union
um in general between um
the u.s and china you know europe is
often the forgotten
actor within these uh bifurcated
relations you know even
with the cold war forget that europe was
actually
an actor throughout the cold war and
actually exercised the moderating
influence on both the us and the soviet
union at the time
i think europe can also revive that role
um today and it's um as a relations um
decline between the us and china there
are a lot of grounds where
europe and china have a lot in common
for example
the regard to climate change um the
criticism that launched against the us
um position on climate change under the
current administration
that's just one example where europe
aligns
um with china and also in terms of
criticizing
u.s foreign policy over the years so
it's not a simple i think at the times
the u.s
takes europe for granted i mean that's
part of the question here when you're
mentioning a pompeo didn't visit certain
states it's true that with the way the
us
talks about europe it's almost assumed
that europe will always be
um on the us side um
of this debate but that isn't the case
although as we're seeing the eu europe
um is also becoming more critical of
china
um in recent years i mean again
referring to china as a systemic
rival so in that sense china
has really tried to work um
to change the european perspective and
we've seen forums such as the 17
1 format where we've um had china
bridging its relations with
the countries of eastern europe um some
commentators say that it's exploiting
division within the european union
others would say
that china is merely building its
relations with
um former allies during the cold war the
former
communist states so in that sense it's
really leveraging as historic ties
in connections um in europe to
pursue important strategic ends
now for the current um discussion
especially with
5g infrastructure um that's another one
that's been
a complex debate especially if you look
at germany often
some of the discussion has been you know
china may exploit
um some of this technology um
in a way that undermines our national
security but they would some critics in
germany in opposition would point at the
us and with the revelations the nsa and
snowden
um which has created some interesting
debates
where it's kind of been this realistic
that both actors are actually exploiting
our uh
information infrastructure so we might
as well go with the cheapest one
and that's at least what some opposition
politicians have been
um pointing out but that's a good
example of where u.s policy has actually
been short-termist and actually
undermine some of its long-term
credibility so there needs to be more of
an adjustment the u.s part
um to you know upholding uh these
principles
um if it's to be an effective competitor
against um
china uh for europeans but
largely um even staunch british even
staunch allies of china such as the
united kingdom have come out in recent
years being more critical of china so
there's definitely
a shift and it will really depend on you
know the incoming u.s administration
will it whether we'll
seek to reconnect with europe and it's
european allies
or whether it will continue its um what
seems to be more of an independent
course for euros foreign
thank you so much bradley uh and the
same question goes to andrew especially
with the focus on the visit to europe
yeah sure thanks thanks for the question
um so
i think uh wangy's visit is part damage
limitation
exercise and partly preparation for
the fact that um xi jinping will be
speaking to
the european union leadership and
chancellor merkel in the middle of
september um it's damage limitation
because
um i think there has been some surprise
on the chinese side um how badly things
have been going with
with europe in in recent months i think
the way the eu china summit
uh played out in june was it was a
little bit of a uh
shock um the very kind of blunt language
used particularly by
european commission president uh
underlying um
and the fact that essentially uh all the
things that might have been agreed on a
kind of future cooperation agreement
to 2025 were pulled completely by the
european side because there'd been so
little progress
on any of the other major priorities in
particular um on the
on the investment talks um what wang
essentially has to determine in in the
next period of time
um is whether uh china is really going
to have to and
whether it's capable of moving on a
couple of these uh big issues because
the german presidency is going to be
this hinge moment
for the sino-european relationship uh
there is a real
continued interest in salvaging
important parts of the co-operative
agenda
but the political tide in germany has
turned as well it stand on 5g as well as
it has in most of
of europe um the only reason germany is
still holding out versus some of the
other countries
now is because the government won't put
a bill in parliament because it doesn't
have political support
um to give huawei the role in in its 5g
networks that it would
uh like and there's been a huge
turnaround on that which is again
accelerated uh during the the covet 19
crisis um the question is going to be
particularly after
angela merkel departs um this is her
that this will be essentially her last
year people already preparing for the
aftermath
um and the mood from most political
parties even in her own party uh is for
a very different balance of approach
now if in this little period of a few
months
uh the chinese side is able to make
movements
on the investment agreement and on
climate
then it may still be possible to lock in
certain forms of partnership with
um europe going beyond
the 2020 period but there's a real risk
that if that doesn't happen
and if the damage limitation exercise is
unsuccessful and there's still a view on
the chinese side that says that it
doesn't have to be serious
give in these areas and then we will get
to november
uh january uh december uh period of time
um in which you are if there is a change
of administration going to have this
very big renewed push on the
transatlantic front for closer
coordination
on china and there'll be a very
different level of appetite
uh in europe uh to be responsive to that
um yes pompeo secretary pompeo has not
necessarily been able to make as much
progress in in the short term but you've
even seen from
at the eu side the willingness to launch
this new u.s
eu dialogue on on china to find closer
ways to cooperate
and i think that that sort of effort
would accelerate considerably
um uh by at the end of the year and and
beyond so
i think it's a very delicate juncture
and it will be interesting to see
whether uh wongi actually takes back
some of the messages and whether we get
real progress
um on the sinai european front in this
call
in mid-september because otherwise um i
think there's a real risk that
uh the final european relationship heads
into very very different territory by
the end of this year
right thank you so much also for
outlining the time framework and the
expectation that we have with uh
connected to the changes of political
leadership in so many countries in
europe and also in the us
uh we have time for one more question
and i want to go back to the discussion
about the chinese belt and roads
but also the competition for influence
not necessarily domestically within the
european union or the us
but also in other countries be it in the
neighborhood of the european union
or elsewhere and i will go first to uh
jean li hua there is a lot of
discussions in the wise that chinese
belt and road initiative is questioning
the
western liberal order do you agree with
this statement
yes the chinese better losing meetings
is purely an initiative for economic
cooperation it aims to open up
transportation a lot between china and
its neighbor and as well as the country
along the battle route
so that china and other countries can
develop together
and get rid together very unsealed
uh there is an older thing in china i'm
good
you are good everyone is good so that
the world can be good chinese
development
is closely linked to the development
of other countries and rising china
can also lead can also lead other
countries to prosperity
the bli is not intention to
and will not change the
existing liberal economic order
now to compete for the
dominations of the global value chains
can adjust the one to achieved
collectively mutual benefit win-win
cooperation
and common prosperity between china and
other countries
the better and raw projects are largely
incompatible with
liberal economic order chinese companies
that
that are investing in construction
projects strictly obeyed by the rule
of market and the law of the host
country chinese cooperation and spending
and undertaking projects in eu
country also comply with the new law
since its economic reform in 1979
in 1978 china has learned a lot from
u.s and west country freedom democracy
and the rule of law have been
incorporated into china's current
socialist surveillance
that china wants to maintain the
existing global economic order and
liberal order
regarding the talent due to the extreme
high debilitation of the ui
and the decline you correct
decline of u.s dollar the bii
may adopt a variety of other
currencies such as europe
renminbi digital currency
or even better which
could challenge maybe which could
challenge
the predominations of
u.s dollars some german
and french elites elite worried the
chinese battle
project were completed of their
infrastructure
constructed market
chinese companies have considered their
council and have been work with those
countries to develop third party
cooperation projects in the developing
country so that they will also benefit
from the
big i br i
about the uh just now
somebody talk about
the problem of the eye
somebody said
perfect thank you so much for for your
take on that and i will ask bradley and
andrew
in about uh 70 seconds each
how do we respond to the chinese belt
and drone initiative
and also there are questions from the
audience connected to that
legitimately it would be expected that
there's
a economic support or loans offered from
the european side especially to the
neighborhood countries
to counteract the belt and drought
initiative how do you see the impacts of
belt and drought initiative and
what should be the european u.s
responses to it bradley would you like
to go first
you have 60 seconds okay
thank you um so first the beltway
is not necessarily a challenge to the
liberal order
actually often the belton road is
successful
especially because of the fact that
they're actually often aren't
presented alternatives for a lot of
countries
there's a lot of room still for
cooperation with china
um especially because much of this
infrastructure is needed worldwide
it would lead to global growth the
problem with it is more the
implementation the government of it
in the sense that it's a very state
intensive
program the deals are often uh very
opaque
and often we always view china as the
only actor
with regard to the belt and road but
china um
chinese money is often co-opted by
countries themselves which are
um quite savvy actors in their own right
i mean we see this especially in central
asia
where sometimes the regimes um in the
regions
in tajikistan co-opt a project such as
road construction
insert road calls and the finances from
them
go off into offshore accounts which
funnels money into the elite bank
accounts
so there are often these problems the
belt and road that the lack of
transparency
actually undermines china's interest
itself which is
promoting its stability on its bordering
regions
um so that's another thing with the belt
road is that there are different logics
depending on
which geographic region you're focusing
on but
typically with pakistan south asia and
central asia you have chinese domestic
interests
to take into account which would be
stability in its western provinces
so for this sense china actually has a
lot of incentive to
adjust its policies because they haven't
actually been serving its interests and
they may
actually be undermining stability in
neighboring countries
in a way that could undermine china's
own interest in the long run
thank you so much bradley and andrew you
have the final 60 seconds for your take
on that
okay thanks um so i mean there's nothing
inherently challenging to the liberal
order about um
the belton road if it's building a road
or a dam or something
there clearly are problems if china is
building the uh
digital and surveillance infrastructure
for countries and then using it to help
governments track down opposition
leaders or extra
data or facilitate great firewall type
measures and things like that
and as bradley suggested there are
problems if china helps corrupt leaders
push ahead with projects of dubious
value and loads of countries down with
debt so i mean there are challenges
um there is a cooperation model that
china itself sort of offered which was
the aiib
and i think we'd be in a very different
place if china was channeling more of
its resources through the aib
but there's a reason that china likes to
do these things bilaterally um
and uh there are um political and
security benefits that accrue to china
from doing it that way and benefits that
recruit chinese companies from doing it
that way
the problem is that and not doing it
through the multilateral consultative
structures that the aiap
um put in place and the kind of high
standards that were there do mean that
you're getting competitive measures from
from other countries
japan has got its act together on this
india and australia have to a certain
extent
as the question suggested in the first
place though the us still really lags
behind and the eu really lags behind
except on a sort of intra-european basis
and in parts of its very immediate
neighborhood
when it comes to really putting serious
connectivity finance in place
and countries are aware of that and i
think it is and the very last thing i'll
say
it's going to be a real test of whether
the eu is able to be a geopolitical
actor
as to whether it's able to operate in in
the connectivity space
now the budget is in place the budget's
been agreed um if there's a dedicated
stream of resources to do this
the eu should be very good at doing this
um
if it doesn't happen it's going to be a
real failure on the
eu's part because there's still a real
need for for this on the part of the
countries
and there's still a real need to be able
to compete with with china in this area
as well
thank you so much andrew i'm glad that
uh
despite the um a rather heated
discussion in the international scene we
found
we actually learned through the debate
today that the
uh european union united states and
china are not inherently incompatible
and there is a plenty area
of cooperation where this cooperation is
possible so thank you very much to all
the panelists for the
very rich discussion today thank you
very much for all the participants of
this session
we're going to have a short break and
resume the programming at
3 00 pm central european time and i have
a small announcement concerning our
scheduling on friday
we have another speaker confirmed for
the session
that will start at 6 40 p.m central
european time and we're very delighted
to welcome svetlana tikanovska
who is the opposition leader in the
former presidential candidate and the
belarusian elections 2020
who will be having a conversation under
the guidance of terry martin the
moderator from deutsche welle
we're looking forward to seeing you soon
with us again thank you very much
globesec bratislava forum is the
platform to tackle disruption and
discuss solutions for better tomorrows
basic theme of disruption is crucial
because to me
the issue is not whether it's climate
change or whether it's the chinese or
the russians or whatever
it's actually the concatenation the mix
of them all
and that's what i think is so valuable
about this because it is a generalized
conference
it allows us to see how