and security initiative we're also
vigilantly
following the national security
challenges
we explore how to counter terrorism and
violent extremism
as we did with our crime terror nexus
project and globsec intelligence reform
initiative
our democracy and resilience program is
tenaciously analyzing hybrid threats to
our democracy
and runs hands-on projects to make our
democracies
and the way we share and consume
information ever more resilient in the
digital age
we explore challenges facing our economy
intersections of technology and society
energy and sustainability and global
order
we are always open for collaboration
stay in touch with us
do not hesitate to approach us with your
thoughts ideas and suggestions
and we promise you that you will hear
from us regularly
about our ideas and what we do to
convert them into reality
[Music]
good afternoon everyone my name is elena
kutzko and i'm director of the globsec
policy institute
broadcasting from bratislava welcome to
our
last session of the day titled crafting
transatlantic responses to the challenge
of belarus
the session is organized in cooperation
with our great partners from the
atlantic council
for which we are very grateful here with
me are a set of fantastic speakers
ambassador michael ziebert who is
director for eastern europe caucuses and
central asia
at the federal foreign office of the
federal republic of germany
prime minister carl bildt who is
currently co-chair
at the european council on foreign
relations in berlin
and ambassador danielle fried who is
currently
wiser family distinguished fellow at the
atlantic council washington dc
belarusians have captivated the world
with their unprecedented and inspiring
social and political
mobilization we all know that the
peaceful
defiance of the population had been
intensifying throughout the summer
and culminated with the mass
demonstrations
that were that followed the disputed
elections and a brutal crackdown on
peaceful protesters
but alexander lukashenko seems to have
no
intentions of resigning anytime soon so
the question that is on everybody's mind
is what's next today even at our
conference belarus has come up
in pretty much all the previous
discussions which means that also
policymakers
and experts in europe and beyond are
trying to
wrangle their minds about what
approaches and responses we can jointly
develop to address the situation in the
country
ambassador zibert i'm going to turn
first to you
could you please unwrap for us what is
currently being discussed in europe and
what is the
european response look like
thank you very much for for having me uh
elena
i am happy to to start by
saying that i'm sitting here only a few
meters from
the vents all in our foreign office
where tomorrow morning
the gimnich meeting of the european
union will convene
of course i can't tell you what these 27
foreign ministers and the higher
representative of the european union
for foreign policy will exactly discuss
but i will start by saying that the
european union has very
early on reacted to the
situation in belarus the foreign
ministers as we all know
met on the 14th of august and
it was a special european council on the
19th of august
with a very clear targeted message
namely saying that the european union
does not
recognize the result of the
rigid elections that we
have the intention to decide about
targeted sanctions
against those responsible for a
the rigging of the election and b
of the human rights violation and
violence against
demonstrations also we have urged for a
national dialogue between the government
and
the opposition in belarus and we have
announced more support for the
civil society in belarus and
now tomorrow i'm sure that this line
will be reaffirmed
we the foreign ministers will
make the point about where we stand
unfortunately we have to say that
the developments in belarus in
recent days have not been as positive as
one or the other may have hoped
namely the offer that was made by the
osce
to mediate in the conflict and to
organize kind of a national dialogue
between government and opposition has
not been picked up
at all by the authorities on the
contrary
the repression has continued maybe in
the more
smart in the smarter way so
we will have to assess the situation and
i'm sure targeted sanctions maybe
uh even a longer list than initially
planned will be
decided upon and the main thing is not
how many people exactly will be put on
such a list
but the main thing i guess is the
unanimity
and the decisiveness of the the european
union
to go ahead and i have optimism that we
will find this common line
and then that we implement these
measures
as quickly as possible i may
add that we would like to of course
discuss
possible sanctions lists with
our friends in the us in the uk canada
etc to
align them as much as possible
maybe i stop here responding to your
first question
thank you so much ambassador indeed this
unanimity is of crucial importance
to not just to find the common grounds
in the u but to send a very strong
message
and once you mention the american
friends i'm going to switch to
ambassador freed
and ask him a similar question about the
united states
ambassador fred many observers are
saying that
the yes is not particularly visible or
potentially slight somewhat
less visible that the european union in
its response
is it a prudent decision could you
please unwrap for us what's going on
and what is the thinking towards belarus
and if you would like to touch also on
the outcomes of the trip of the deputy
separator begun to
lithuania and moscow as well
well first i want to express
my agreement with the path ahead that
ambassador siebert outlined
i think that's the right approach i
think the united states
should work as closely as possible with
the european union
we should move in the same direction i
think
that speaking clearly and
imposing individual sanctions on the
russian officials responsible for the
rigged elections and the
repression is a good place to start i
think
that we ought to um and having in mind
what ambassador siebert said i think we
all
we also ought to prepare to support
bella russian society in the long term
because this will be a lot this could be
a longer term process we need to be
prepared for it
finally and this was the only thing that
ambassador siebert
um didn't mention i think that the
united states and europe should start
considering not implementing but
considering
uh contingency sanctions
against russia should putin
invade either directly or indirectly
i'm not saying we should actually do it
i don't think we should but i think we
should be prepared and we should let the
russians know that we are prepared to
act
as a way of deterring them from
intervention directly or indirectly
now i think the united states has
rhetorically
somewhat pulled back we have made
statements but the europeans have been
in the lead i think this is right
i think that our deputy secretary begins
trip
is well-timed he's going to the right
places
and he frankly is the right person to do
it i've known steve beagan for 25 years
he's respected by republicans and
democrats he's a serious
person who knows the issues he's there
with
the state department's george kent
deputy assistant secretary who's deeply
knowledgeable about these issues
uh he started off in vilnius meeting
with chihanovskaya as well as the
lithuanian
foreign minister um then to moscow we
had meetings yesterday he's going on to
kiev and then vienna
osce so i think supporting osc mediation
is a good idea look
this is an issue where the united states
and europe should be
at one and we should be active in the
short term
we should prepare for the long term and
we should not assume
that um the yellow russians
any more than ukrainians are going to be
satisfied
living under tyranny that is an
important message for us all
thank you so much ambassador also for
highlighting the importance of the
coordination between the european union
european countries united states but
also canada
and other democratic countries prime
minister builds uh
we had a set of measures that were
outlined by the
european union and the united states and
i think we all agree on the importance
of transatlantic cooperation
from your perspective do you think this
is a sufficient
set of measures uh that will result in
the change on the ground
or would you recommend that something
else should be done or should be done
differently
well thank you first we should recognize
that so far nothing has been done
except uh statements uh i think those
statements have
there were some some some in the very
beginning that were not uh particularly
uh perfect but but but otherwise i think
the eu line has firmed up
quite considerably um notably in the
last few days
and that's good what has been said from
the u side is that one is preparing
sanctions
uh and i think that was positive there
was some fear
in the beginning of this particular
debate that there would be perhaps one
member country who was
less keen on sanctions but it was good
at the first
video conference of the foreign
ministers that everyone agreed with that
then we should recognize and both
the ambassadors have underlined that
we were in for a fairly long game um
i think after the election lukashenko
expected to
get this over with fairly quickly as has
been the case in
after previous elections i mean a couple
of days of more or less heavy repression
and cutting down the internet and that
was going to be it
that failed um there were some people in
the west
perhaps who believed that there was
going to be a showcase moment
and lukashenko was going to fold and
leave for
turkey or russia or whatever um that did
not happen
we are in a stalemate situation at the
moment
where lukashenko is not really
controlling the country
and where the opposition is not
unseating the regime
this might break the one way or the
other that remains to be seen
but i think it's important that the
policy is designed to be a policy
step by step and for the long haul
as for sanctions uh i think it's
uh i always say that dan freed and i
have had many discussions on sanctions
sanctions are effective primarily when
you threaten to impose them
so we should threaten to impose them on
a fairly
large number of people but we can do it
rolling
you can easily start with one list and
when that is
implemented you say that if the
situation doesn't improve
we are working on a second list and a
third list
and and then you move in to the
different organs of power and and of the
regime
and um i mean i don't think asset freeze
is going to be particularly important
but but
but uh not being able to travel to
to the eu is important belarus fairly
unknown country to most people but it's
actually the
country in the world that has the
highest numbers of people
having shengen visas per capita
lots of people of belarus including the
regime and administration or whatever
they like to go shopping in vilnius in
other places
and to sort of gradually deprive
more and more people that we see
associated with or accepting repression
or falsification of election results
denying that possibility will over time
have
some effect so i think that's that's an
important instrument
then signaling to moscow is important
i think that has been done uh i think
the last few days have been slightly too
many people calling moscow
uh belarus the capital of belarus is
minsk not moscow
um but an element of signaling to to
moscow was of course
important and then we have the different
long-term
uh support civil society short and long
term
um i've been involved in a couple of
crisis with belarus
and then and we set in motion certain
programs x numbers of years ago
um and i can see some of them having had
fairly significant effect uh i don't
think it's appropriate to go into the
details of those particular programs
but their scope for expanding those
things further
uh without having press release on every
single detail of it
not expecting that to have an effect
tomorrow
uh not even the day after tomorrow but
the day after the day after tomorrow
and the transformation of belarus from
fairly backwards soviet society and a
very sort of backward soviet economy
to a modern european nation which will
happen over time
uh will take some time and we must be
able to pursue that policy
uh with persistence and and and
and with the long-term aim so
get the message out that yeah we will
not forget belarus
we will continue we'll stay the course
and our policy will
develop over time in accordance with
what we see
developments on the ground
in munich itself thank you so much
also for talking about the long-term
transformation in a way what we see now
this mobilization of society was the
outcome of the long-term transformation
of the country
that was not coming in
that wasn't necessarily visible from the
outside or even sometimes from the
inside but it's definitely
a very different society and a very
different country that we saw even a few
years ago
but um you mentioned an important issue
of the stalemate and i would like to go
back to ambassador zibert
uh and also on the issue of who calls
who
we know that for example yes a lot of
leaders are calling moscow and vladimir
putin
but we also know that uh and both sides
seem to be confirming it that for
example
um chancellor merkel did try to call
lukashenko
but alexander lukashenko refused to talk
to alex
to chancellor merkel so uh ambassadors
ebert
do you have ideas of how we can get out
of the stalemate
especially if there seems to be no
efficient and effective way to talk
directly to minsk
and encourage the dialogue
yeah one million dollar question um
you are right that that chancellor
merkel
tried to call lukashenko and i think the
fact that there are fewer contacts there
than in moscow is exactly for that
reason that
the responsiveness is so low in minsk
at the moment i i would like to
say that i i liked
the co co panelists saying that it will
probably be
a mid or long term game
i don't see a quick way out of the
stalemate right now
although the situation may be more
fluent
more in flux than we we think at the
moment
this has been going up and down over the
last two
two weeks but in recent days
the power of lukashenko seems to
stabilize
and he seems to apply smarter methods to
to control the situation
i think it is very difficult for
us in western countries to to really
exercise
leverage on the situation
because the those in power do not
very much respond we don't want to
uh openly come in on the side of the
opposition
because we believe that this is a
a below russian uh situation
and and hopefully dialogue it is
not comparable to uh kiev in 20
in 2013-14 people
are not talking about geopolitics
and where the country should go it is an
internal
discussion about the system of belarus
so we believe that we should
encourage a dialogue along the lines of
the of the current constitution
we offer help by the osce because this
is a
an organization belarus itself belongs
to and russia as well
so um this this will be the way forward
but we have to hope that with this very
deep
politicization of the society that has
seemingly suddenly happened over the
last weeks
the situation will never be the same
again as it has been before
we don't know how long president
lukashenko will stay in power we don't
know how long he will be supported by
moscow we
don't know whether the economy
will play an important role i mean
the fact that there are strikes uh if
they
will be prolonged it may be
an instrument to weaken the current
power
we don't know exactly about future
orientation of the
security organs the silhoue key who at
the moment seems
seem to be at the side of lukashenko
still
in the major part so
these are factors we we can hardly
influence
and we will have to be
smart in adjusting to the situation and
of course
claiming and
demanding that in belarus the
minimum human rights and
obligations that belarus subscribed
itself within the osce
should be maintained and and react
accordingly
so step by step approach absolutely this
will be a first round also tomorrow for
for instance for the sanctions and if
the situation goes
worse in minsk the eu i'm sure we'll be
prepared to step up and
take further action
and one more word maybe to ambassador
freed
on on the you are mentioning contingency
sanctions
discussion on russia not everybody in
europe is
is convinced of this method because we
believe
sanctions are interesting when they
are a targeted
be reversible in case of
the intended action is being taken by
the other side
and c when it is not premeditated and
discussed
because uh it should be it should not be
known what kind of sanctions might be
taken
at what stage because it makes us more
calculable in our actions
and and that is not what we want to
thank you very much ambassador um and i
will complicate what you're saying even
further and go back to this discussion
about
whether it's an internal issue or there
should be a discussion also with the
actors from the outside because we know
for example that
alexander lukashenko is actively framing
the
protesters as being financed and
directed from abroad
which of course puts the eu and the
united states in a very difficult
situation about
making any statements that are happening
in the country
and i wanted to connect it to the
discussion about sanctions and russia
uh our audience on the platform is also
wondering
and i will switch now to ambassador fred
because you mentioned about
the topic of sanctions on russia what is
the threshold on sanctions because of
course
you mentioned the outright military
intervention
which doesn't seem to be something that
is in the plans today but what does
seem to be already happening now at
least according to the
reports from the country that there's a
hybrid support from the russian
government
in the form for example of the
journalists that invited to help the
belarusian states run the
media npr campaigns and that's at least
something that we
even know officially from alexander
lukashenko himself
so ambassador fred uh would there be any
response or
any reaction diplomatic or public from
the united states
or the european union whether there
should be any response
about more subtle methods
of russian supports towards the
lukashenko government
well first i agree with both
carl built and michael seiberg
about the need for unity and the
need to think through our steps we're
not neutral in this
we have our principles that is we
the west should stand with the yellow
russian society
recognizing that um they are demanding
the right to be heard within their own
country
this is not about geopolitics
and we should not introduce that issue
nor should we draw lines on a map
and start ruling things out for the of
russian people that's up
that that's not what we should be
discussing now
at present to answer your question about
sanctions
we should move ahead promptly on the
individual sanctions against yellow
russian officials who have been involved
in repressions or election fraud
and it's a good idea to do it in
tranches as carl belt says
i hope the european union makes a quick
decision
and i hope that decision is not the last
one
with respect to russia it gets it
obviously
is a little trickier um
the united states and europe coordinated
its sanctions on russia
after russia's invasion of ukraine in
2014.
these included individual but also
broader economic so-called sectoral
sanctions
we did it they had an important impact
they limited putin's aggression in
ukraine
having done it for ukraine we should be
prepared
to consider it with respect to belarus
um not to actually launch these
sanctions
but to prepare them and in this i may
disagree with ambassador siebert
i think it is useful for the russians
for the russian authorities to know
that the united states and the european
union are prepared to take steps
we can't bluff what we do what we
say we're prepared to do if there they
invade
we should actually be willing to do
and i think having contingency sanctions
maybe not spelled out in precise detail
but spelled out with enough specificity
that so they know we're serious
can be a good idea um i think preparing
them
is useful um the threshold
well okay let's try to unpack this issue
if the russian army moves into belarus
that's one thing
but it's more likely that it would be a
combination of little green men and
russian
forces augmenting bella russian forces
or even
in belarusian uniform um
i in that more likely clay case we
should still prepare
to move we could impose individual
sanctions
against russians um for example
the propagandists who were taking over
uh
gila russian tv but i also think
that preparation for sectoral sanctions
on a contingency basis um can be useful
and it may be that we want to prepare
some
in the event the russians move in in a
hybrid fashion
um we should not
right now the united states and europe
ought to be talking about this
and coming up with a combined position
we're much
much better off if we're doing this
together and frankly as in a former
american official i'd rather do less
with europe
than more unilaterally um i think that
would be
a strong message of unity but let's face
it
sanctions are not going to be the
decisive issue
okay the decisive issue i think will be
the will of the belarusian people
over time and although this is not like
um ukraine in 2014 it's a little bit
like poland in august 1980
it's a little bit like the orange
revolution in ukraine
you know in in in o4
um and it's you know it's going to be
unfold according to its own logic and we
ought to be prepared
to help build a russian society in the
long term
carl biltz right we don't have to talk
about the specifics
but the united states and europe have
good experience supporting civil
activism
and free media and
we ought to we ought to to
to back to back up the people who are
risking a lot
uh on behalf of values which we all
share
thank you very much ambassador uh i know
prime minister bill that
uh you will have a lot to say about the
sanctions on russia and how to time them
properly
i would also want you to very briefly
touch uh
on the uh faith of the eastern
partnership
and belarusian membership in it from
your perspective how it could look like
but also about the a little bit unpacked
the support for civil society
ambassador free just mentioned the free
media we all know that the
for example radio free europe was one of
the very few sources
that could provide the uh
rather comprehensive coverage in belarus
of course together with belsat
both of the channels are functioning
from abroad
so if you have some thoughts on how best
structure the support for civil society
that would be very much appreciated
well a couple of comments on a couple of
issues uh
and i i certainly try to answer those as
well but um
calling means co-calling moscow yeah i
mean talking lukashenko yeah
sort of he didn't take the call of
angela merkel but
not quite certainly would have been that
useful but uh
called the foreign minister um foreign
minister mckay
wrote a letter to the eu foreign
minister i think every u.s foreign
minister
should call him and say hi what are you
up to uh
call the prime minister he's a new guy i
haven't a clue who he is he
came in in june uh but we
we should sort of call all of those
officials that are reachable
so that they understand the message and
understand that this is not
going to go away i think that's
important on the
uh sanctions belarus yeah i think we
agree this sort of step by step
and i think it's very important that the
eu should sort of announce that
one is prepared to do more not if the
things deteriorate
but also if it doesn't improve
so that we until we see an improvement
are prepared to
step up each step can be fairly small
but the fact that it's seen as a
long-term thing and no one
in belarus can be fairly certain if
they're going to be on the list
tomorrow uh and that's the important
thing
the fear factor that they will be on the
list once on the list
it's another issue on on other sanctions
belarus
what then refers to the sectoral
sanctions
i mean the economy is in shambles
uh before it's a very weak economy
it's it's it's a moderately reformed
soviet economy
and of course the russians have been fed
up with it for a long time because they
have to bail it out now and then
and of course what we have been doing
particularly the u.s lately but also
lithuania
have been helping the belarus economy uh
to withstand some of the measures taken
by russia
uh when secretary pompeo was there in
march for example one of the things was
that u.s oil deliveries to the
refineries
in order to make them go because russian
deliveries were not uh going as well and
so so we have a balancing act here
sectoral
sanctions can take down the belarus
economy
it is not the russian economy it is the
belarus economy sexual sanctions can
take it down
um but that's that's something that
immediately would have uh belarus turned
up
the care of the kremlin uh so it's
a it's it's a somewhat double eight
swords
but i think for the worst of
contingencies
if if we have a very heavy clampdown by
violin by lukashenko
we should take down his economy come
whatever i mean
that there should be some some
some order we should not forget that
lukaszenko is distinctly unpopular in
moscow
um i would guess
that uh there are different camps in
moscow i mean there's clearly the
paranoia camp that
believes that sort of any any sort of
deal with this opposition means that we
will have the u.s army marching into
somalians tomorrow
um and there are those fairly paranoid
people around but also those saying
lukashenko thug is unreliable we we
don't really like him
um and and if we tie
ourselves to the mast of lukashenko
there's a risk of belarus
public opinion going the way of ukraine
long term
uh turning anti-russian in a way they
are not
and that is not in the long-term
interest of russia so perhaps the
moderate kremlin would view would be
well stabilized situation at the moment
and then we
engineer some sort of transition
to some sort of reasonable guy
that could also open up to the west but
how that would
play out remains to be seen on the um
what we can do um well
you belsat was mentioned i mean belsat
is one of the things that we've done
it's not been entirely cheap i can tell
you
but anyhow and other things
telegram is of course a special issue
but there are issues related to that as
well it's
written as we know russian system the
russians have been trying to stop it
they've failed is now run from poland
um and and and is highly highly
significant but there are other things
that can be done as well eastern
partnership uh i think
is an instrument that should be used
um in the eastern partnership you have
three sort of democracies and you have
belarus and azerbaijan
but i think um
why don't call a meeting of the eastern
partnership
foreign ministers uh will the high
representative mr burel there
not with the entire crowd and perhaps do
it in yerevan
because one of the templates here is
clearly what happened
in the spring of 2018 in in armenia
where sort of a popular
rebellion or whatever we call it popular
manifestation
led to a change um
and i'm quite certain that sort of
moscow was nervous for a while
uh but moscow noted that in terms of
their basic security interest that was
not the issue it didn't change
and and they they they accepted a
significant change in in armenia
so it might be that yerevan kiev
which is now to certain extent uh
can can play a role here as well in
long-term working for for for for these
particular changes
um have i answered that question very
much prime minister
uh i think so and i think we also uh
will have a time for probably one or two
more questions and for the first one i'm
going to bring in a participant from the
audio from the uh with the video call
who is going to ask the question
hi it's paul taylor here in france
um good evening to good afternoon good
morning
to you three gentlemen um my question is
that
what's happening in belarus is it comes
against the backdrop of something that's
been going on for more than 20 years
which is a contest between russia and
the west
for ascendancy in what you might call
the gray zone of the former soviet
republics that dwell
between russia and nato and the european
union
and while several of you have said we
don't want to bring in geopolitics that
that is there that's in the room and it
affects russian
thinking just as it affects our thinking
question as part of
a a a a an attempt to defuse
uh this and allow the belarusian people
to actually get what they're after which
is clean
fair elections and an end to tyranny
wouldn't it make sense
for us to state a bit more clearly that
where
neither russia nor the eu is looking to
take in belarus
and if that worked there perhaps it
might work in other countries in the
region where we've made
uh rash promises that we're unable to
keep
thank you thank you very much paul
and since we will have to be wrapping up
in about six minutes i'll add one more
question from the
participants and the question is about
the
lessons learned from the past round of
sanctions
what we learned what works what doesn't
work and whether it makes sense to
introduce
the sanctions against and i will start
this time
from the other end and please try to fit
your remarks in about two minutes
prime minister build
well on on sanctions we do have previous
experience with sanctions
in in in belarus after previous
elections
and where we we had toilet sanctions
and we said we're going to have them as
long as you don't release political
prisoners
political prisoners were released it
took some time but but
with a couple of other factors it did
work so it's not
it is not useless on paul taylor's
question
i wouldn't face it like that um
this is question of democracy this is
question of human rights nothing else
um it is up to the people of belarus to
choose their particular orientation i
think what we could state
is that the security arrangements that
are there between
between russia and banneras they have a
couple of uh defense fighters they have
a
strategic communication stations they
have a highly significant
air defense or strategic early warning
facility there
we have no objections to that uh because
these are clearly defensive
installations and you can see the
defensive
security interest that that that moscow
has
but that is a decision to be taken by
belarus
and by moscow it is not something that
we have views on
but we certainly don't have any
objections to them
because we see them as uh in their
present form
distinctly non-threatening
thank you very much prime minister and
ambassador fred
uh we're back to sanctions again and to
geopolitics versus the determination of
the people
right first i agree with carl belt
we should not and i'll put it this way
we should not be in a hurry to start
drawing lines on a map
it would be a poor response to the
yellow russians demand for free
elections
if we said that we were going to
essentially consign them to russia's
sphere of influence
it's not that is not the issue it's
about three elections
the yellow russian people have not
challenged their relations with moscow
therefore we need not raise that issue
whatsoever
and we certainly need not um
give the russians something which they
don't deserve which is
a recognition that they are uh that bail
or us in some sense belongs to them if
the law
belarus belongs to the bella russian
people full stop
they do not demand anything more than
free elections and the right to run
their own country
and that's where we ought to leave
things
with respect to sanctions look i do not
look at sanctions
as a magic problem solver
they can be a useful tool to advance a
policy that otherwise makes sense
and our policy ought to be united
it ought to seek support of the yellow
russian people for the short term
and the long term combined with
cautionary notes to moscow i'll be
interested
to see what conclusions steve begin
makes after his trips
he's one of the trump administration
officials committed to working
with europe um and on behalf of
reasonable policies to advance
um basic human rights so that's a
that's a good start we need to get
ourselves
lined up behind the bella russian people
not
ahead of them and certainly not
undercutting them
thank you very much ambassador uh this
isn't it a very
difficult situation because for the
belarusian
people themselves it was not a
geopolitical election from the point of
view
whether people were expressing their
views towards the us
eu or russia or other external forces it
was indeed a very
purely internal situation but definitely
for the countries around it
it's a very geopolitical question which
has to be squared against
with the principle of the
self-determination of people
and ambassador zivert for your
concluding word uh besides the question
that were addressed
i would also ask you to reflect a little
bit
on the how a geopolitical
commission and geopolitical european
union
can square this line that we want to be
both geopolitical but at the same time
actively are saying that this issue is
not a geopolitical
and we need to leave the future of their
countries in the hands of the people
yeah that is a interesting way you
you formulate your question i think
these two things in
here are not directly linked i fully
agree with
that dan fried that this is belarus is
not about geopolitics at the moment it
may be
kind of the elephant in the room for
many people thinking about the situation
but the people there should be supported
in their
endeavor to get freedom free elections
and
and civil participation and we should
not raise a question that is not raised
by them
so with moscow the messaging should be
very clear
we have talked about possible sanctions
etc i think
now it's the time for messaging to
moscow
which is being done and i'm sure that
moscow also understands the
linkages between their role
in belarus their own internal situation
the costs that any interference may have
internally and also these are the people
in belarus i think these are
important topics economic sanctions
i would be very careful maybe as it
has been said a last resort against
belarus because it would hit the
population
and the opposition as well
this is not what we should look at at
the moment
rather we should try to use any chance
to help
for a national dialogue for a situation
maybe as in armenia
certainly belarus is located in a
different position on the globe than
armenia and the relationship with moscow
is different
but that could be a way i
i wish that what has been said that it
looks a little bit like poland in 1980
and kiev in 2006.
i hope it is not too much like a proud
1968 we have to work for that
and we should keep all possibilities
open to reconnect to the country
whenever the situation
evolves in a positive direction and to
continue the dialogue and we should look
at the eastern partnership
in that vein that we re-target it a
little bit
now in order to help the society
and and to to
allow for further context whenever the
situation improves
in in belarus thank you very much
ambassador
indeed belarusian people have already
shown their
ability to choose their own way and
despite the fact that there are many
parallels that can be drawn with other
scenarios we do hope that the
situation will be resolved uh
similar to all the positive cases and
probably learning from the mistakes that
were learned in the negative cases
but thank you very much uh for the great
conversation today we unpacked a lot of
important questions
i would also like to thank all the
speakers and participants of the today's
conference
this is the last session of today but we
are definitely
looking forward to having you with us
tomorrow and on friday
we start tomorrow at 1 30 central
european time
and we will be talking about chinese
relative rise and american relative
decline in the world
uh that's a provocative statement but
also during the day we will cover
a range of various issues starting from
european strategic autonomy
to automation future of work and other
issues and the preview for everybody who
is listening to the current session we
will
most likely have a very special special
speaker from belarus joining us on
friday
so please stay with us for the next two
days
thank you for your participation today
and have a wonderful evening
[Music]
[Applause]
you