media channels
[Applause]
[Music]
hello everyone uh and welcome to today's
session
um i'm lily beyer i'm a reporter at
politico in brussels uh for those of you
who don't know our publication we cover
policy and politics in the eu um i'm
very excited to be
a with this panel um we have
a lot to talk about um it's
a very exciting time and difficult time
for the european economy
um just last month there was a very big
negotiation here in brussels
all 27 heads of state and government
were here
and they decided on a big budget and
recovery package
1.82 trillion euros
and that is said to have a big impact on
the economy also in central
europe today's subject is the disruption
as central europe's accelerator for deep
economic overhaul
and of course the disruption meaning uh
primarily i think
the coronavirus crisis how it has
impacted
economies in the region and um how
perhaps the fight against the crisis
and and the recovery process could help
transform
the region's economies today with us
we have uh four very special guests
first of all we have dragosh pislaru
he's a member of the european parliament
from romania
he is also a former minister of labor in
romania and he's a member of foreign
europe
welcome we also have laszlo andor
who is a former european commissioner he
is currently
the secretary general of the foundation
for european progressive studies
we also have alexander resh who is the
ceo of
vub bank in slovakia welcome
and we also have sonia muzikarova
from our host globesec she is the chief
economist at globesac
thank you all for being with us today
and i'd like to remind the audience that
you will have
an opportunity at the end to post
questions
and i i really encourage you to uh
because we're very
curious to see what sparks your interest
and i'm sure our panelists
would be happy to answer as many
questions as
possible so to start off i think it
would be very good for us to
keep in mind the extent of the
disruption
uh to central europe's economies so
sonia would you mind perhaps giving us
an
overview of the current economic
situation
what has been the impact of covid over
the past few months
um
i can't hear sonja
shhh
okay
should i do that now
okay um i'm sorry everyone we seem to
have a bit of a technical problem uh
hearing sonia
so um in the meantime if we could
perhaps go to
um diragosh before the session was just
telling us
that he has been working on the
parliament's position
on the um recovery and resilience
facility which is this big
part of money that will be going um two
member states to help with the economic
recovery
uh following the coveted crisis did i go
um what do you think
are the lessons learned from the crisis
and how can central europe
effectively use this new eu money
um first of all thank you very much for
the invitation and it's a delight
to be uh alongside such fellow panelists
and uh
to talk here this event um indeed
um i mean the title of the debate
was actually um quite in line with with
my feeling and
the lives the changes that we are
currently living um
it's it's you know been told
by everyone these months that in every
christ lies an opportunity and i do
believe
indeed that we have an opportunity both
to raise the ambition at the european
level
and also to see better the challenges at
the central eastern european level for
the central eastern european countries
and to see the in comparison with the
western europe
how we are actually faring now um we
all knew the structural problems that we
are facing in this part of europe in
in the central eastern uh part of europe
um
the crisis has actually uh revealed
those structural
problems uh even further and i would
actually say
that we see right now why we need
to increase basically the resilience of
the entire
uh european union and to act together in
this particular process
and there are three main dilemmas and
then i will go a little bit on the rrf
the recovery and resilience program and
you know the next generation
uh the solution that european union is
actually putting forward
the three challenges that we're actually
facing is that
um and and i'm talking here i'm putting
myself in the shoes of you know
any government in in the area so first
of all you need to fix
things that have been you know affected
by the crisis and
you know uh you know fixing things
referred to things that um
are right now obviously um you know
lagged in terms of the
investment projects that have been a
couple of uh
some some time ago planned also we
are also fixing things that are the
direct effect of the crisis that
is more or less creating new jobs or
creating
ways for the companies to come back to
their activity
insolvency programs furlough schemes and
so on and so forth
but that's one thing the other thing
that we have right now as an opportunity
and
especially for central eastern europe i
would say is to
basically leapfrog to use this
opportunity
to actually make that bold step forward
to increase the potential gdp to to go
on for innovation to go on for
technologies be that in the green
digital
or other economic ecosystems as they are
actually called right now in the draft
of the
uh new european industrial policy so the
first big challenge
is what would be the mix in between
fixing things
and looking for leapfrogging going you
know
raising the bar for for the european
project so and and this is actually
very very important and i would say that
the member states that the countries
that will
choose to do the leapfrogging would be
would be actually better
off i would the second challenge very
quickly would be
referring to an integrated approach
a silo policy right now there is a
tendency even in brussels to talk about
green and go very deep on green to talk
about digital version
of that talk about the
economic and then and the companies and
so on um
but at the same time there there is
evidence that we need
social resilience we need institutional
resilience and we need to talk about
our youth obviously and if we don't have
an integrated approach
if we are not working together then we
are going to have a problem so i would
say
the big challenge would be indeed how to
actually work out
solutions that will be integrated and
not um
you know sector and the last challenge
that i would say
is directly linked to the young
generation and i'm saying that by
looking at opinion polls
and looking at the fact that the the
young people are not necessarily
um let's say ecstatic about the eu there
are some worrying trends going on
and if you call the package the next
generation eu
and you are not going to tackle directly
the opportunities and access
of you know young people and talking
about the
the children guarantee perhaps and then
it's going to be a problem and i would
say that there is a
there is a big challenge that includes
the demographic challenge and the fact
that the elderly have been much more
exposed to the crisis than
um than other parts of the population
and the fact that
everything is changing and there will be
a polarization of generations
um threatening to to tear apart the
social strata in europe
so three challenges what we need and
what we hope to deliver to the rrf
is to to be able to do both the fixing
and raising the ambition to have an
integrated view and then in the design
of the rrf i'm actually very pleased to
tell you
you know right now in you know before
everything as goes public that we're
going to have six pillars so
green digital competitiveness social
institutional
and next generation and by saying that
obviously addressing the third challenge
that is the demographic challenge
and this is actually the package that
obviously would be adapted by
needs to be adapted by each of the
member states of the countries in the
centers to europe
but but it will actually create a
leverage at the year level it will have
an
impact at your level if we are actually
going to to follow that as a particular
strategic
view on how to move further so i'm very
optimistic about it i i don't think that
we are just having a
helicopter money um you know that will
actually spread spread
money around i think that uh there will
be um
a clear link with european semester and
we have the chance to be stronger
together uh in this particular process
so i have a
i have the news that i can bring you
that there are good prospects for ce
countries too not only to recover but to
become much more resilient for the
future shocks
thank you so much dragosh i was
wondering if we could next go to
laszlo who perhaps could give us uh
his views specifically on the situation
in hungary
um how has covert impacted hungary's
economy
and what do you think are the lessons
that should be learned there
uh let me thank you for the invitation
and it's um
really an honor to be able to join there
um indeed um the picture of central and
eastern europe is fascinating
uh because in the past decade or we can
even speak about 15 years
there has been a strong convergence
process and the growth rates of
this region although unevenly
and have been much higher
including in hungary including in other
countries
than the euro area
and um i agree with the previous speaker
mr pistaro that it's a it's a major
question
how to ensure that after this deception
uh
we are not losing momentum uh quite a
contrary how to gain
some kind of new momentum and i think we
would probably
agree that this region would need to
somehow reconsider
the growth model and why
would it need to happen
first of all because this is not the
first disruption
and already 10 years ago in 2009 the
great recession
also affected this region
and while before the great recession
the growth rates in the visagrad
countries
dynamic uh convergence
process that was not reproducible
after the great great recession so the
growth rates only became
about two twice as high as in western
europe
and i think it would already be a great
achievement if this could be
restored however what happened in the
meantime especially in the last five six
years
a major outflow of human capital
i think the importance of the outflow
of labor should not be underestimated
because already in the last five six
years we have seen
that um
this became a bottleneck on industrial
growth and other types of
economic and you were asking me
really about hungary specifically i
think hungary is also
a remarkable example of this bottom
lane because originally the
force was not as mobile as the polish or
as the baltic or as the romanian
but increasingly it became very very
mobile
as the austerity
actually the transitional uh
restrictions expired in 2011 the
so-called seven-year transitional
period and the industrial relations got
much worse and social rights and labor
rights
uh and and wages were undermined um
[Music]
following 2011 and 12 with the new labor
code
so there were many many push factors
which send hundreds of thousands of
people to other countries
and obviously when a new multinational
comes today
it's uh it's more difficult to find the
right workforce
and the drivers of foreign investment
which were very effective before low
taxation
cost competitiveness from the wage side
in other aspects
and not going
strong to deliver
investment and growth and job creation
as uh before
so in any case in hungary as well as
other countries
there will be an opportunity
to to reconsider the model of growth how
to escape
from the the of course competitiveness
and move towards higher value-added
which also requires more investment more
systematic investment
in human capital on this point i would
reconnect
with the question of the european union
budget
because from our region from my country
also
there is very often a kind of shortcut
when we speak about
eu transverse eu money we think
about infrastructure
innovation of the main square
and the costly especially if you want to
the population by this type of
activities but the point is to shift
towards more human capital
and in a way the member states including
in east central europe
and i think this could be a general
encouragement um
particularly for countries which
experience the labor
outflow like hungary for example uh to
invest
more in human capital and reinforce
the resilience of the school system the
labor
market institutions the training systems
um in order to provide better conditions
for the workforce itself but also for
the
mystery would come and of course
will compare the
member states not only from the point of
view of taxation
but also from the point of view of
available human resources
thank you so much i'm told that sonia's
technical problem has been resolved so
i'll ask you again sonia perhaps to give
us an overview
of the impact of the crisis on the
region's economies right now
yes thank you very much and i i hope you
can now hear me
um so overall the central european
economies manage the pandemic
uh quite well in the initial wave uh
with relatively contained infection
rates and some of the lowest per capita
uh death rates within europe um this
good management of the crisis surprised
to the upside as the government
efficiency is not exactly
um top rated and neither are the health
care systems
and also these countries are not exactly
technological leaders
so their response couldn't really rely
on
intelligent solutions and and tracking
apps
and even there was a leadership switch
in slovakia at the beginning of march
so it was a very good um management of
the crisis
uh given all of these features and
circumstances
there is a shared consensus that the
management was successful
mainly due to those due to the speed of
the measured
measures institutionalized mostly um
these measures were basically put in
place before these countries
hit the 100 case benchmark or even
before the first
death um so the infection curve did not
hit exponential growth so
this was very important and in terms of
the health and containment measures i
mean they were the usual uh
travel restrictions quarantines closures
are of
non-essential business and also limiting
production and industrial sites which of
course
uh took a toll on the economy of central
and eastern europe um
but before we get to that i wanted to
talk about briefly
about the main pillars of the policy
response
um in these countries and beyond
um basically on the so on a global scale
uh
the the response is unprecedented with
the direct fiscal
um stimulus reaching seven seven percent
of
2019 gdp and the scale of fiscal
response significantly exceeded
that after great financial crisis that's
also important to note
on the monetary policy front uh central
banks stepped up
their already very accommodative stance
we've seen rate cuts where possible in
czechia
in poland we've seen various
calibrations on bond buying programs
launching of new liquidity lines to
support the real economy through the
banking sector
and also micro prudential policies
relaxation of credit provision
requirements and elevation of capital
buffers
overall we can say that the central bank
response was timely
it was coordinated cohesive
and heavily also drawing on the great
financial crisis
uh playbook and even going beyond it
um on the fiscal front and i'm not now
talking about discretionary physical
measures
uh the response was more fragmented a
little less
coordinated and also um is different in
terms of
size of the fiscal impulse in europe um
so to give you a flavor the direct
fiscal measure is very
varied from around three percent in for
example poland or spain
to about 4.5 in france and italy to
about eight percent
in germany um and in smaller central
european countries they were
modest between one to three percent um
in terms of substance these policies
targeted mostly
stating firms and workers um it was a
policy mix
consisting of financial provisions
liquidity provisions and also
tax and social provisions of course the
health care
funding was expanded and government
guarantees
also played a very large role
um in addition there was the european
response and i think that deserves a
separate space and a separate discussion
so i will
leave that aside for later um in terms
of
impacts on the real economy so basically
there was the direct hit on both the
demand and supply side
for the central european economies but
there was also
the hit going through the external
channel
as we know that these economies are
opened and
they are very closely meeting global
value chains
so
um the the overall impact on these on
these economies
so just to give you an idea in the first
quarter actually
slovakia contracted the most uh in the
region
at minus 3.8 on an annual basis
um this was worse for example than in
germany and worse than the
than the european averages uh more
closer actually to the southern european
fears that were
harder hits by the pandemic but
in the second quarter actually the
number surprised to the upside so
i think the the bottom line and what we
can conclude based on this is that
um there will be surprises there will be
revisions because we know that the
quality of
macroeconomic data and national accounts
are not exactly the best especially
during the time of crisis and turbulence
um and uh just i mean in terms of
outlook also um the oecd the european
commission and the imf
um forecasts very greatly for these
countries
for slovakia um
ranging from -6 to -11 for 2020
for the czech republic minus six to
minus 13
uh with about four to five percent uh
bounce back in 2021 projected but
you know uh it's a wide range of
outcomes and
we'll see um so this is where we are at
and in slovakia the second wave has
already been confirmed by the
authorities just like in many other
countries in europe
so a lot is to be seen and over back to
lilly so we can
move to more interesting parts of this
discussion
thank you so much for that sonia really
fascinating and i'm very curious how the
numbers are going to evolve
uh in terms of the economic data over
the coming months
alexander you have a very unique
perspective on this panel because
you are coming from the private sector
so i was wondering from your perspective
as a head of a bank in slovakia what are
their lessons from this crisis
well first of all thank you very much
also for this invitation and the
opportunity to participate
and as you correctly said i'm coming
from the private sector so i have a
little bit a different
view or input or perspective from this
from this uh from this point of view
sonia already mentioned
a lot of things related to slovakia
so for me based on
my 30 years experience in in in banking
what we have gone through since the
beginning of the year was really
extraordinary because never ever we have
seen such uh a crisis especially
coming from a health perspective point
of view from the abandonment which
basically gave just one measure a
counter measure and the countermeasure
was
social distancing which means an
economic lockdown
and as sonia was saying the new
administration the outgoing and the new
administration in slovakia reacted very
quickly very promptly
in in a very um severe way
uh which saved a lot of lives i believe
uh they did a very good job here
but it had an impact and the impact was
that overnight
uh basically the whole ecosystem
economic system
came to a standstill families were
losing their regular
income for instance um companies
overnight lost their sales
opportunities were sitting on their
stocks and not coming in cash flows
even the public administration had
problems uh to
to sustain this financing because there
were some bonds to be issued
and there were some liquidity
constraints so uh what proved in this
moment
very crucial was the close cooperation
between various actors and i must say
what i have what i have experienced in
this period
the cooperation with the public
administration with the national banking
in particular as well was really
extraordinary good
and what proved crucial in this moment
was
um to have um a very well set up
business continuity management uh
in the past we were always a little bit
uh thinking as a
theoretical exercise business continuity
management
but in this moment it proved uh crucial
to be able to switch from one day to
another to a complete
different uh setup of your daily life of
your
daily operations and so on and that
happened extremely quickly
and that helped us for instance if we
talk about the banking sector
help uh quickly to discuss with the
public administration and to discuss
with the central bank to come up with a
very good moratorium which was very much
flexible
it's one of the most flexible in the
region which helped a lot
of families to overcome this
let's say missing income regular income
the other
side was immediately safeguarding
liquidity
uh to the companies as such so we were
preparing several
uh backup facilities also together with
the national bank
and that and obviously also for the
public administration
where we were able to um to commit bond
issuance
uh in such amount that uh it was easily
to be covered
all the needs uh for for all the aids
which needed to be set up
so from this perspective for me it was
very crucial to have this
uh business continuity management set up
in
in such an open way and not only as a
single operator but as a sector
and as a system then after once we have
settled this
obviously immediately uh
new business uh we lost a lot of new
business in certain
product areas we lost up to 90 so you
needed to quickly
rethink how to do your daily operations
and not only banking all the sectors
and i must say people have been very
creative have been very
responsive um in coming up with new
ideas how do we think
from physical presence to let's say
digital presence yeah
and this means how you identify the
counterpart how do you authorize a
certain transaction and all this type of
stuff you needed to cope
you found out you had a lot of
capacities which
were idle were not used what do you do
with this over capacity
and what will you do in the future
because you could already foreseen that
there will be a lot of over capacities
and talking about for instance
offices space
there will be a lot of things which will
change with the smart working concept
which will
will for sure come and last but not
least also the whole supply
supply management operational risk
overnight you lost
your regular supply how you deal with it
what is the backup
so there were a lot of learnings and i
think um
slovakia as such responded very well and
also
the hit was hardest uh as sonia was
saying
but also the recovery right now in the
second quarter
and also what we can see in the last
months the feedback i get
from the economic players the recovery
is faster than than
expected which is very very good uh we
will need to see how this is gonna
change in the
uh the upcoming weeks and months uh so
we are in the middle of a second wave
so how we will deal with that so but i
i'm very much positive
also because i have seen a change in the
attitude of the people
in the moment we we were suffering the
biggest crisis
i have seen so many people standing to
each other
helping each other supporting each other
mobilizing the community
to to to to face these uh these health
crisis these human crisis it was much
more
important to help each other than than
all the others so i'm very positive
about that we will manage that
and this according to me represents a
unique opportunity
to rethink our economical setup and this
is very much true
for slovakia thank you so much alexander
really fascinating uh how the banking
sector has been doing
um uh we talked a bit about hungary we
talked about slovakia so i was wondering
if maybe you could put on your
romanian politician hat um and
tell us a little bit about how romania
has been coping with this crisis
economically
um i was reading a few weeks ago that
the coveted numbers were relatively high
in romania
um what do you think the lessons are for
the romanian economy uh
first of all uh i am so um
amazed of the commonalities that we've
been uh
talking about in this panel hungary
slovakia and i mean a lot of
things are actually uh very valid for
romania as such
um romania i mean obviously we we've
been witnessing uh
in all these countries and across europe
uh
what can be called a dual shock both on
the demand and the supply
um and uh i mean uh the
the shock has been symmetrical uh
throughout europe basically so i will
not
go again in what happened as a
consequence i will talk a little bit
about the reaction of the romanian
government and what's actually happening
right now
um so the reaction was quite swift
i would say um so uh the authorities
have actually launched immediately
uh furlough scheme um and then
uh later on they even introduced
kurzarbite type scheme in
uh related to you know more or less
the flexible labor arrangements and
somehow to take
some of the burden of the companies that
have been uh shut down
in the lockdown or even afterwards um
especially the uh the hereka industry
and so on
um and um at the same time
obviously uh as was described by
alexander there were a lot of
investments that have been actually
postponed
um so basically what we are have been
witness is um
a try from the government to more or
less substitute the private investment
with uh some sort of a stimulus for
for public investment so right now a lot
of the projects that have been postponed
over the years
have actually been brought in this
investment plan that the government is
putting forward
um to actually push things uh uh from
from this particular perspective so um a
public
investment stimulus was there
unfortunately after a very successful
effort of the government to contain
the effect of the crisis people have
relaxed and
when we are calling about you know we we
are actually using the
the way the word relaxation so actually
everyone got
that relaxed over the summer that um
unfortunately uh
no one respected the basic rules uh we
you know simple things like wearing the
mask and
you know keeping the physical distance
and so on which led actually to
some sort of a second wave um and the
romania
um it's still there uh trying to
struggle
with this um you know
you know trend that was quite visible
actually
um in terms of new cases and deceased uh
cases
uh per thousand inhabitants and so on
right now i would say that the situation
is more
stabilized and we will probably see
some improvement in in the period that
that comes um
what is one lesson learned that i think
it's actually crucial for
um the the future as well is how do you
communicate with the population and with
the economic sector
so the lack of predictability is
actually sometimes worse the particular
shock that you have
and i mean there are a lot of questions
in the air
how when we are reopening the activities
what are the rules that
we need to respect how what are we going
to do what's the regulation that we are
looking at and so on so
so one of the of the commonalities um
that i've seen in other countries is
where you had more empathic
communication
a more uh you know clear um
discussion and and transparency towards
the population and the business sector
the results were better
when you adopted the more like military
style thing saying you know
we are closing here and closing there
and opening there and only in some
conditions
and not you know without having the
clarity
then what what actually was the result
is that people
either didn't respect the rules or uh
businesses
um because we are talking about the
economy uh
were actually diffident in in going
further with investments and so on
i would like to end this intervention by
saying that
um in terms of the perspectives
indeed as as was mentioned here by by
by fellow panelists we are looking at
the reset we are looking
at a model that we can develop uh you
know in in unprecedented ways because we
have the funding available from the eu
and we have the the right momentum to do
so and i will just you know
talk about three things very very
briefly first you have the technology
aspect
right now europe wants to gain back the
leadership in technology
you know at worldwide level and the
green deal is part of that
digital is part of that the ecosystems
and the industrial policy are part of
that
so central eastern europe can actually
you know play
play there with the with with the big
guys i mean we can actually be there and
create hubs
and ecosystems and and value chains that
that can actually be there for the green
technology the digital technology
and other ecosystem the second thing is
about solidarity and alexander has
described very well
this feeling of solidarity that we felt
it's actually
a very very good opportunity to
translate into reforms
you know reforms real reforms of our
social assistance
um let's say systems that we have in
central eastern europe and some of the
social assistance systems that are not
going
uh so well are not that efficient are
not covering
the ones that are left behind and
thirdly and
and this is actually very very important
as well um it's
it's a period in which we need to look
at the next generation and to
look about access to education and
health and for that obviously
you need reforms as well so you know you
know economy
you know it's it's one thing the other
thing is the social part and then
education and health are also two major
opportunities that we have
uh to to to to go on and activate for
for the near future
thank you so much i'm not sure if we've
reconnected to
to laszlo but in in case we have um
laszlo
my question to you is um we we've heard
a lot of ideas and one thing that
everyone
seems to be touching upon a bit is this
idea that perhaps
um the crisis could help the region
transition a bit
so what do you think could be done to
help the region
move up to higher value-added functions
can you hear me i think that's an
important question
yes we can hear you well okay fantastic
great
uh look um i think uh several speakers
mentioned the importance of education
and um i think this needs to be
highlight highlighted
also because there is an alarming
element
in the kovid crisis situation
i think we all welcome the possibilities
to
implement new models of online
learning however i think we also learned
in the spring and summer period
that the online education is not a
perfect replacement of the real
schooling especially when when it comes
to
primary and secondary education
so one way or another i think societies
would need to make some kind of
sacrifice
in order to ensure that kids can return
to schools maybe not full-time but at
least part-time
and then you know re-socialize and
return to the routine
of systematic uh learning because
otherwise
uh the gap is going to be very very
uh serious which separates
various social groups from the point of
view of
skill levels and and the competitiveness
on the labor market in
in in the future if i compare the
current crisis with the previous one
i'm sure you also remember there was a
an enormously high level of use
unemployment in the previous crisis
that's why we had to come forward with
policies like the youth guarantee
and by the way slovakia was also one of
the countries
where it had to be rolled out very very
quickly and but at least at that time
the narrative was
that the new generation is very well
trained the key question is how they are
connected with the labor market
and i think now because of the covet
crisis there is a new narrative
because if the extraordinary
circumstances continue for too long
we will not be able to say that the new
generation is better trained than the
previous one
because the damage is going to be
serious and long-lasting
so somehow reinventing proper schooling
and training
under the current circumstances also by
using the opportunities of
investing from eu funds is going to be
absolutely
crucial thank you i just want to remind
the audience that you can submit
questions and we'll get to them in just
a few minutes um alexander one thing
that i found really interesting is when
you talked about
how well the public administration has
done from from your perspective
during the beginning of the crisis for
the private sector i was wondering if
there's anything that you think the eu
should be doing that would help the
banking sector in central europe
get through this crisis or perhaps um
recover
um following the crisis
well in principle i think uh the banking
union is very much
influenced on a european uh basis so
when we were having this kind of
discussion there was a very close
coordination
with the european central banks and most
of our
uh systemic relevant banks are anyhow
under direct supervision of ecb
so from this perspective point of view
um
i think there is a lot done there is
still a lot to be done
but this goes beyond uh let's say
banking regulation as such
it is very much important to have also
uh common
uh legislative principles
and so on which would for instance have
to go on with uh cross-borders
uh mergers and this type of stuff but
maybe coming back
to this uh unique opportunity which we
have
right now in particular slovakia has
right now to
get out from the uh mid uh mid-income
trap the
so classical uh mid middle income
uh trap is really we need to transform
in a knowledge based uh
economy and this clearly as uh both
of my uh fellow uh partners here uh were
saying
uh laszlo and prague it is very crucial
that we talk about
education and that goes from the
kindergarten goes to the
primary secondary school and goes also
to obviously the university education
it is very much important the link to
the private sector
as it was mentioned as well so from this
the human capital
and we need to create that and we don't
have it right now
we are not ready to face the challenge
at least
in the regions we are operating so there
are huge challenges
besides this what i would say another
crucial factor
is to create a proper
business climate which means that
we have an easy way how to um
to do this uh research and development
to bring in innovation to bring in new
ideas to test new ideas not all of them
will work out
so there will be also failures naturally
but so that we can really facilitate
this
and this uh institutional setting
which currently is missing and i think
there is also
where public administration uh quality
of public
administration is very much needed to
favor this because
this will create the environment which
will be allowing us
to transform in a knowledge-based
economy which is necessary
um before we go into the questions um
sonia if you would like to quickly have
a last word we've heard a lot of
ideas about how economies can be
transformed and strengthened
from your perspective as an economist
what are the core lessons what needs to
change
for central europe's economies
um so i mean every country is different
and there is no one one size fits all
in terms of innovation strategy that
works um
for every country but i am quite
fascinated by the proposition
proposition of a um um
leading author her name is mariana
matsukato and she has been basically
arguing
um in favor of governments taking a more
active role
in innovation strategies and that they
could be
more active market co-creators uh not
only market fixers
so to say and this is also related to
another
recent trend uh the recent proliferation
of strategic ppps that have worked
really well
they are longer term uh public private
partnerships they are bigger in scope
and i think they're trying to address
big challenges such as combating climate
change unemployment
or um you know at the technological
frontiers such as
uh focusing on industrial strategy
and i think they have worked because
they're they're mutually beneficial they
reduce
risk for the private sector and they
also enable governments
to harness private sectors on the ground
uh creative capacity
and maximize gains from research
investments at the times of
constrained budget so i think this is
also very important um
in the current times in the current
environment
um also governments need to be asking
them
themselves the right questions so where
in the economy for example
to focus the innovation and the
upgrading of domestic capacities to
achieve
leap frogging in terms of productivity
and greater value added
and in the central european context um
where a significant part of the
gdp is associated with global value
chains police makers should
concern themselves with how domestic
firms can capture
greater share of um higher value added
and of course the success of any
innovation strategy depends on
governance and execution
so you know like-minded coalition may
partly fill in the void where
for example political leadership uh
is either short-sighted or is
not really um having it as an imperative
the the long-term innovation strategy
um so i will stop here because i think
we're running out of time but those were
just a few examples of innovation
strategy that can
that can be helpful and that central
europe
and other regions can rely upon
great thank you so much everyone um i
don't actually
see any questions so unless the
organizers
have received any i think we'll leave it
there for today thank you so much
alexander sonia laszlo dragos for this
very interesting conversation i have a
feeling we'll be talking about
this theme for quite some time thank you
thank you thank you very much thank you
very much
[Music]
the opening of the first globsec office
abroad at the beginning of 2020
in brussels was a natural step to bring
the rich experience and expertise of
globsec
15 years after its creation to the
lively policy made