commendations to a range of stakeholders
on both sides of the atlantic
but we also try to make a difference on
the ground by partnering with at the
think tanks universities public
institutions or media
we created two online courses on this
information we develop manuals on
strategic communication
we provide trainings for public
officials or ngos we even engage
youtubers in a campaign focusing on
young people
with all these activities we generate
new ideas provide creative solutions
and engage relevant stakeholders to
drive positive change
towards more resilient democracies in
its dynamic and digital age
to find out more follow our debates our
social media
and visit our website globsec.org
[Music]
[Applause]
ladies and gentlemen dear viewers
welcome to the session on disrupting
economies
of disinformation at globsec 2020
digital stage
my name is katana klingova i'm a senior
research fellow at globesick
and it is my great pleasure today to
moderate the session
i'm very delighted uh that i'm being
joined today
by my distinguished speakers and
panelists
i would like to introduce you vadim
biltchik the member
of the european parliament
bran baltzmann and deputy chief
technology officer and senior
information scientist
at round corporation
and claire melfort co-founder and
executive director of the
global disinformation index thank you
very much for joining us today
and i hope we are going to have a very
fruitful discussions
um before we start i would like to start
with a bit of a housekeeping rules
um we have a huge audience following us
online
therefore i would like to encourage our
audience to post questions
in the question sections at the panel
where you can also vote for particular
questions and
promote them to the top we will have a
session at the end of our panel where
we're going to go to your questions so
please ask and
uh you know pose your questions and
we'll go and try to address them
um so the carbon 19 pandemic
has been accompanied what the world
trade world health organization
described as empademic while this
information has been here for
with us for ages you know many actors
spread this information
and they enable the spread of false
information because they make a lot of
money
out of it while critical thinking and
strategic communication
are important antidotes to epidemic and
disinformation
a truly efficient plan needs to include
a plan how to disrupt the financial
streams of disinformation
and this is what we hope to address
during the sessions
and therefore i would like to start with
claire um
because she's from the global
disinformation index and
they did a really good research on it
and i would like to ask her
you know uh how is this information
monetarized online
who is making profit uh from this
information
and how can we stop it you know and what
kind of changes have you observed
with the covert 19 pandemic and its
financing
thank you so clear thank you can you
hear me okay
yes great there are a huge number of
people making a lot of money from
disinformation
uh we at gdi estimate that uh around
a quarter of a billion dollars a year is
made across disinformation sites
we did a study earlier this year just
looking at covid19 disinformation
which estimated that around 25 million
dollars would go towards covet 19
uh conspiracy theories bunk cures
etcetera just in 2020
the reason this is possible is because
of the
huge increase in use of programmatic
advertising networks which place
ads based on the number of clicks a
piece of content gets
so all a disinformation actor has to do
is make clickable
content that content then immediately uh
earns ads based on
dollars based on the number of clicks it
gets so you get you write something that
gets clicks
you get dollars the more controversial
content the more it enrages us
the more dollars you're going to make
and this is true for covert 19
disinformation
it's true across all sorts of conspiracy
theories and what we're seeing is that
many of the same websites
are trafficking in a lot of the same
conspiracy theories whether it is
kobe 19 or anti-vaxx or climate change
denial
anti-black lives matter anti-islam
you name it many of the same sites come
up time and again
trafficking in these uh in these
conspiracies and this highly
divisive content purely because or
partly because it is a way of generating
uh
high traffic volumes and therefore high
amounts of advertising revenue
but i would just want to add that
advertising is not the only way
that disinformation merchants monetize
their content
there is merchandising there are plenty
of shops
on etsy on ebay on amazon where people
sell
merchandising that uh makes money for
their particular conspiracy theory
and it also stretches across payment
systems so there is
a whole eco of uh ways that people can
monetize
the sort of divisive uh polarizing
and extremely harmful content across a
whole range of narratives
that we've seen particularly painfully
brought to light through the covert
pandemic which has resulted in people
dying from from bunk cures for example
and has undermined the work that public
health authorities are doing
to try and get high quality public
health information out there
but what can we do about it uh rant
you know uh how do we stop financing of
this disinformation
i mean claire mentioned that there is a
whole ecosystem
uh what can we do about it how can we
it's not about
the social media platforms who earn a
lot of revenue about it
uh but it's also you know bots and
trolls that are
readily accessible uh on
your browser you don't even have to
access the the deep web
but it's also about the young people for
example in bellas who are very much
you know popular in spreading this
information and are
earning a lot of money uh prior the
uh past uh presidential elections in the
united states what can we do about it i
mean is it really
about pulling the plug and leaving the
social media platforms
and you know creating the new social
environment
or imposing huge sanctions on
these actors um what do you think from
your experience
uh is the most efficient way
uh how to disrupt these uh financial
streams
and uh what needs to be taken and done
well so i so first of all i don't think
you're really ever gonna be able to
depend on the platforms themselves to
solve the problem
i mean it's not to their advantage to do
that really
and unless you make it to their
advantage somehow then i don't really
expect to see much from them so instead
i think
probably the most efficient thing is to
actually offer us a separate platform a
different type of platform we actually
which is publicly accessible and it's
accessible to controls it's accessible
to
you know it's it offers transparency
you can see exactly what's going on and
you have a chance to really um
you know to get a grip on things i mean
that so that's one general approach
to create you know a really a public
benefit type
social media platform where you can
actually try to establish some kind of
trust in it
i mean you know mark zuckerberg he's not
an elected official
he's not a public servant i mean the man
is running a business and he's going to
do whatever he can to run his business
and so
i mean the first thing i think people
need to stop doing is just just to take
whatever they say
that they say they're doing for granted
i mean i see too many reports where they
say
well facebook is doing so and so well
how do you know they're actually doing
that and the answer is you don't know
because they want to actually show you
all you know is what they say they're
doing
so the very first thing you can do is
try to get you know to try to force
some kind of auditing function on them
that that says
where somebody's allowed to go in and to
verify that they do what they say not
even to critique it but just to verify
that
what what they're saying in there is
actually doing then you have a
foundation at least for
a more a reasonable discussion about
what the right thing to do is
but until you can verify they're doing
things i what they're saying they're
doing
there isn't really much room for
discussion there so
that would mean that would be my general
price the other thing of course is to
disrupt
the activities so i mean i can hack
programmatic
you know ad systems so that while these
guys may try to show ads
i can make sure they don't get shown
with their i replace them with something
else
so i can get in and you know play around
with the bidding systems
so that my ads what i show gets always
displaces them
and i can disrupt their general
activities i was you know sort of
activity along those lines
but there is a whole other area which i
think is worth looking at and that has
to do with
you know using this information to
disrupt supply chains
so the supply chain that
that's becoming a really big problem so
there's a lot of fraud a lot of other
kinds of things
um which i think needs to be looked at
more carefully i've seen some
interesting examples of that
so i'll stop there
well not everybody has your hacking
skills rant
uh and uh yeah you know vladimir he's a
member of european parliament and he's a
policymaker so
what do you think about these
suggestions i mean should the european
union
or european countries develop their own
online platform that is going to be
transparent because
as we see the conversations with social
media giants are not really
fruitful or you know are lengthy or
you know should we develop our own
authority
or i know get our own hackers who are
going to disrupt the
uh bidding systems at as rand suggested
uh what's your how do you see all these
suggestions
well thank you very much for the
questions and i uh really
want to thank the organizers for having
not just this panel but actually
uh much of discussion in the conference
uh dedicated to the problem with via
facebook
the problem empademic that's the problem
of uh
this information that's the problem of
the
quality of the digital space which has
become in many respects
also a dominant space for our public
life so i think
it's something we need to take very
seriously when it comes to policy making
when it comes to
politics when it comes to politicians
it's one of
problem one of event when it comes to
just elections or campaigns
uh it concerns consumers it concerns um
the quality of the market uh because
much of
uh uh the business these days is done
online and so in that sense as claire
was saying there is this whole ecosystem
here which has
uh developed um in the past couple of
decades
um and i think we need to find a proper
responsible public way of how
we address and deal with this ecosystem
to take
uh take out the best of it uh and to
in in a in a uh in a way mitigate uh
uh the evils uh which uh associate
uh with with the digital space and i
think this is uh
um an important task for us in the
policy making
uh business policy making area uh it's
an important task for us also in the
european union
this is not a problem over a single
state this is a global problem so we can
only politically face it
at the level of uh of at least a group
of states and i
i here i see the european union
as as an actor at the forefront of the
efforts
uh to really face uh the um problem of
this information which has consequences
for consumers but also for the quality
of
our public debate public life and the
quality of
of democracies and of course democracy
and market economy go hand in hand so we
must protect
uh both of these by fighting this
information how do we do this
um now in the european union
specifically in the european parliament
uh we are looking at this
as a serious political problem
and i think we need to find serious
political answers and i think they're
coming up
very soon in the established a special
committee
which is going to look into the external
uterus role
in our democracies but also going to
look into
the problem of this information and how
we can best address it
we already adopted an important
resolution in this area
in uh october uh last last year
i was one of the co-authors of this
resolution and i will be also serving on
this special committee which will start
its work in september
uh and i very much look forward to uh
really making progress when it comes to
uh real political answers to the problem
of this information
and what are these potential political
answers let me suggest two which already
on the table and which we'll discuss in
depth
this coming fall one is the digital
services act uh which for the first time
will be a
comprehensive attempt to really uh
regulate
regulate this ecosystem which we have
i'm not sure
uh there is an answer and this is maybe
a response to what brand was saying
that let's create a whole new platform i
think we need to find
the way a way how we can best live with
the existing environment but also
control
uh the evil side effects of it and this
information
is an evil side effect of this
environment it can kill
as the pandemic is showing
um but not just the pandemic you know
look at the genocide in myanmar for
instance had it not been for facebook uh
perhaps
um it may not not not have happened the
way it
it did so uh so so really um this
information
on social media on platforms has real
consequences and
is a matter of uh life and death and uh
oftentimes
um and in addition of course to
regulation
um uh it's also active promotion
of um uh active citizenship
of uh fact checking of awareness
of strong media we need strong
free um responsible media and this is
where i see
again a strong european action plan
which i hope will
come out of the democracy action plan
which is going to be proposed by the
european commission
we'll discuss also in the european
parliament this coming fall so
so these are just the three examples in
terms of how we need to go about it
and let me just make one last point here
i think it's important
uh that europe acts here shows the
leading
way how we can deal with this uh to the
world but also it's important for us in
europe because we have
smaller and larger states we have some
states which have already attempted to
regulate
the digital space uh and the platforms
uh notably germany
but we have smaller states um who really
don't have the power on their own to
get in the direct conversation with uh
facebook google and the other global
platforms so that's why i'm i'm saying
we need a
a proper european policy action
including regulation
which will force uh the platforms to be
as transparent as possible about what
they are actually
doing and how they are fighting this
information
uh among other things and we can only do
this
effectively at the level of the european
union
claire when you hear these
policy measures that are being prepared
at the european level
what do you think about them i mean this
is enough
and then secondly you know you uh with
the global disinformation index have
monitoring
a lot of activities of the the private
companies
uh within um this pandemic
uh but also because of the black lives
matter
uh initiative um we saw
a recent initiative stop hate for profit
uh
um being emerged and launched um
is this enough how do we uh spread it
around how do we build this
corporate social responsibility not only
among the
businesses but among the uh individuals
uh who themselves you know
can spread this information and make
money out of it
so i think the first part of the answer
is uh
it can often feel like it's a the
internet's a big place and it's an
intractable problem
but actually if you focus at least as
the first stage on demonetizing
disinformation and breaking the
revenue flows it becomes a much more
tractable problem
three out of every four dollars that go
to disinformation
particularly their covert disinformation
report we most recently
was uh published were placed
on those websites by google google is by
far the biggest
ad exchange it places by far the largest
amount of
ad dollars in the open web so it's
actually a pretty
tractable problem if google would agree
to
stop providing its ad services to the
worst
100 or 200 sites that traffic
in covert disinformation in anti-black
lives matter conspiracies
that would be a significant blow to the
incentive to the to people to create
that sort of disinformation in the first
place
so the first thing i would say is it is
a tractable problem
the second point i would make is we do
need a systemic solution it cannot just
be about
google because if google stops funding
or providing ad services to certain
sites
they will just go elsewhere and find
another ad exchange
so what will really help is providing
uh and regulation has a as a key role to
play here
establishing a common set of standards
for what sort of content
can be can be monetized
so for example gdi provides a risk score
for every news site
that risk score could be used by google
by other ad exchanges
not only to determine whether or not a
site
should receive ads but also how high up
in your search or your news feed that
site should be
and if the the thing that would
significantly help
with the next phase of european
regulation
is if some sort of common standard
common risk standard
was included in it and if the
enforcement mechanisms were really
well thought through what we saw with
the code of practice on disinformation
which was a great first start but the
enforcement mechanisms just weren't
there
and what the platforms were able to do
is
offer really very very weak compliance
with the code of practice so for example
google's offer of
meeting its disinformation obligations
under the code of practice on
disinformation
was simply to make sure that no site
that didn't that wasn't clear about its
source of funding
would be monetized so all you have to do
is state your source of funding you can
carry any content you like and you will
be monetized by google
this is a really weak uh form of
commitment so whatever comes next
through the digital services act
or whatever mechanism is is to follow
really needs to have
very tight standards and really clear
enforcement
vladimir how do you perceive the
suggestions of claire's i mean is this
something that you're going to be
pursuing
at the eu level i mean this is do you
see this as something that could be
implemented into the uh european
european digital service act
um uh furthermore um
you know how do
you know we see some some actions being
taken by the social media
platforms i mean they're more and more
limiting the spread of this information
but this is not
enough how how do we ensure that they
comply
uh with the policies uh is this a way
how to
start sanctioning the social media
platforms if they don't comply
with the rules and then what kind of
sanctions would be appropriate you know
a few several of thousands of euros
is that enough for a multi-billion
corporation should there be one fit
um you know sanctioned to all
platforms whether they're big or small
applicable or
you know what are the policies that you
think that could be implemented
in the in the measures
this is going to be much of our
discussion in coming uh
weeks and months in the european
institutions and especially in european
parliament
um and uh i think what claire has
actually pointed out
to uh uh is a baseline uh we need to
have
all platforms we need to help the whole
ecosystem on board this
is this is the baseline so you know uh
um
if you have a code of practice code of
conduct it cannot be voluntary and it
you know platforms
some platforms can decide to take part
in some platforms decide to take a free
ride
i think this is this is the baseline
everybody has to be on board
and of course then we need uh clear
standards um
and those standards have to do with the
fact that uh
um we have a clarity of uh
information and data in terms of what
the platforms actually do
i mean the platforms actually provide
some data to us already
but we don't often understand the data
they are not disaggregated
so we don't really know what how how
well the consumer
uh is protected in germany and how well
the consumer is protecting slovakia i
think it's important
that we have a baseline which protects
um uh
the user of uh the platforms um and
the social media and of course the
business environment which is online
which is digital
in a very equal way across the whole of
the european union if we talk about the
eu legislation
so common standards and and the same
level protection for everyone
uh in uh the uh uh digital market
across the europe single market i think
this is this is essential uh and we need
to have a lot more clarity and
transparency on the data
uh so in a sense we need to force
the platforms uh to behave uh
responsibly
uh and not to produce um
if i can use the economic uh language
uh the negative externalities for the
public space because this is what's
happening
um just like we regulate big business
just like we regulate the banking sector
just like we regulate much of the market
because it produces
things we don't like environmental
damage for instance uh we must regulate
the digital space
so it uh uh serves us well and it has
served us very well
you know the digital revolution has been
something many of us have welcomed
uh but today we are critical because we
also see that it produces a lot of
problems
for our daily lives yes people make
huge sums of money of lies and
disinformation
but this information can also really
destroy people's health people's
lives our social and political
environment and this is a huge problem
um so uh yes uh we need regulation
uh we need uh and we need to discuss um
uh in in in detail uh what's the best
way to approach this and that's
that also includes sanctions but i you
know i wouldn't start the political
discussion with sanctions i think
sanctions should be the last bit which
we discuss
and of course for all these rules to be
effective uh we will need
sanctions as well but but
i would engage uh the business here
in a way in which we engage any other
business
which produces a lot of
public good but behaves also responsibly
when it comes to
uh the um all all the
bad uh byproducts uh for the public
space
and i think this is where the platforms
basically will not act on their own
that's clear
already unless we regulate unless we
legislate and unless we
engage very very seriously politically
with this um
and by the way and that's my last remark
here this is not
an issue for a few select policy makers
this is not an issue
which should concern us only when it
comes to elections campaigns
or big scandals this is something which
should uh
become uh the way a part of integral
part of of our policy making when we
think about um
health policy social policy
you know um all sorts of public policies
uh we
we need to think about the digital space
the online space
uh because of course this is where much
of it uh
takes place in terms of the interaction
the information
but also the business which is done
alongside it and
and we simply cannot create policies now
without
regulating the digital space
we see that some social media platforms
are already taking some measures but of
course the spread of this information is
not just about the social media
platforms but
um you know we see that uh
google for example will stop uh putting
ads on
websites that have been known to spread
this information
uh but you know it's not just about that
you know is it enough
we don't know we don't know how
effective that is going to be
we don't know uh whether the data
provided for
by them or by facebook and other social
media platforms
is uh going to be relevant and um
you know trustful let's say uh
but we've seen both claire and and
vladimir talk about
setting a certain standards and and uh
principles
in the european uh information space but
we see that a lot of these social media
platforms are actually based in the
united states where around the space
so my question to you is do you think
that there is a possibility
to set common uh transatlantic
standards you know and um
enhance these principles that could be
founded
and established by the european union uh
on the uh in america or in canada how do
you think that this
legislation could be established or is
there a possibility that
the legislation in europe and the united
states would be compatible
or you know there's a different
perception on how
this information should be dealt with on
the other side of the atlantic
well part of the you know part of the
problem with regulation
and policy and everything else is that
the people who tend to make those
they don't have they don't have a very
clear idea or understanding of what it
takes to actually
implement them so you know the technical
problems with implementing different
types of regulation and legislation i
mean you go to the banking industry yes
when people make regulations in the
banking industry they have a good idea
how to actually technically implement
them
but in this area there's a lot of
unknowns
about how you would implement any policy
so
unless unless government is so or
somebody is willing to invest serious
dollars
in actually developing the technology
that you need to implement the policy
the policy is pretty meaningless i mean
some of this stuff has german stuff that
i've seen
i mean it's ridiculous there's no way to
implement any of it i mean so
since there is no way to actually
implement it technically in a reasonable
way
the application of the policies tends to
be well
not very effective so that's one big
problem
um the other problem is you know like
you say cooperation across well
it's just a global issue the space is
global and unless you're
unless countries are ready to just block
out everybody else like the chinese
then you have to have cooperation and
that's a really big problem because even
within certainly within the united
states
i mean there doesn't seem to be any sign
of anybody doing anything in any kind of
an organized way to deal with issues
so i yeah i don't know but but i i still
emphasize the technical
the technical the technology required to
implement
policy unless you use that develop that
together with the policies the policies
will be meaningless
and the regulations so that's really a
big problem and i've seen this
in many cases this is a very interesting
notion that's why
uh that's why i would like to follow up
you know like okay you you talk about
technical issues
that we need can you name some uh
you know because we have a policy maker
vladimir is there so he can develop some
and or suggest development of some so
can you can you really name few
technical implications that need to be
done
well detecting detecting this first of
all defining this information and then
detecting it at scale
is an unsolved problem okay
i mean people do this by hand okay
there's a lot of people out there
tracing this stuff by hand but that's
limited
the the enormous volume is involved
you can never keep up with it by hand by
the limited tools that people are using
today
so so that's just one problem even
defining what you mean
and then actually developing means to
detect it at scale
which those things don't exist at the
moment so that's just
an example of a problem and you know
how you disrupt the flow of it
yeah okay go ahead uh vladimir you
wanted to point out something
uh i think this is a look um what what
brand is
basically opening up is the cracks of
the matter
um and i agree uh we need electric
mission uh we need rose to be ultimately
effective
uh but you know my point is
we've done this in other industries this
is a whole new area
technologically also politically also in
terms of the implications
we are all excited about new
technologies we are all excited about
the digital space
we you know cannot imagine our lives
without online and digital you know this
is taking place online digital and
thanks for that
we have the pandemic but we can we can
still do this and have this wonderful
exchange many people can watch and
that's good
so there are many advantages but clearly
uh the digital space has also brought
a number of huge problems uh for our
daily lives
for business uh proper business contact
proper proper market conduct and of
course for uh political lives of
democracies for instance um and yes
we've always had this information here
uh we just need to find a way how we
face it and how we fight it
in this new space i do believe it is
possible
uh we need to have a very honest
conversation as policy makers so we need
to have
a very honest and also um responsible
approach by the platforms
um you know the platforms out there uh
as as huge players affecting um
today uh the flow of information uh
way beyond uh what perhaps was
imaginable couple of decades ago
uh i do believe that platforms must be
responsible
for the content that they spread uh now
we can discuss
how exactly this this this this is
defined and and how exactly
this is done uh in practice uh but uh
you know just like uh new york times
will not spread any news
uh the platforms uh uh have become uh
real powerhouses when it comes to the
spread of information
and this information and they simply
have to be responsible and we have to
hold them to account
a lot of this can be done and should be
done by people um
we need to know what the platforms are
doing i have no idea how many fact
checkers facebook has these
days that's the basic piece of data we
are missing
for instance we have no idea how
the algorithm which the facebook uses
for spreading information
and misinformation and this information
actually
uh uh works um so so we need a lot more
transparency here
um and this is all a matter uh for uh
honest discussion
and ultimately a good piece of
legislation now digital services act
um and and of course other measures
which
which we'll discuss and consider are our
first
important step um and i'm sure you know
uh
as as we've done with other industries
uh we will
we will evolve in this area as well uh
but
uh i believe we must start um it's
uh uh it's it's high task and if we
cannot do it globally and i
agree this is a huge challenge we must
start within europe and and i think
europe
can lead and should lead the way here uh
so this is our
policy-making task and of course we'll
engage with
the business environment we'll engage
with those who who understand
technologies in discussing
uh policy making and rule making in a
way which will
improve the quality of our life on
social platforms
and also improve the quality of
information
but you know i have to say but the
question is is the government ready to
put money into developing the necessary
technology
because so far it doesn't exist and the
funding
that's necessary to develop this kind of
technology i don't see it coming and so
you know it's hard to take all of this
talk about regulation and policy very
seriously i have to say because
if there's no way to implement it you
know in other industries that technology
exists to implement policies
related to them in this industry it
simply doesn't exist for example you
talk about fact checking
i can show you two stories with exactly
the same facts which tell exactly the
opposite story
what do you do with that so right now
there's actually no way to automatically
detect that
and until you can automatically detect
that fact checking has a
limited value even if you could do it at
scale which you can't at the moment but
even if you could
it's still only limited value because
you can't there's no way at the moment
to interpret
to look at how are the facts being
twisted and used to tell a story
it was a completely separate problem so
and then another great example
i believe that claire wanted to see
something yeah i wanted to try and cheer
rand up
uh because i think uh i think the
situation is not as hopeless as perhaps
rand thinks it is
uh there this is exactly what we do at
gdi
we can detect a conspiratorial
narratives
at scale using ai so we use a
combination of artificial intelligence
and human review where human review is
is required because you're right there
are times when an algorithm is never
going to be able to pick up the
subtleties
of uh pernicious types of manipulated
content
but there you this is a tractable
problem
there are uh the majority of
disinformation that we see
comes from a fairly small number of
sites we're only looking at the english
language at the moment
but the english language is the biggest
market for disinformation
globally so you can look for
narratives and topics that frequently
appear and you can
do that at scale so you can look for
coded 19 disinformation you can look for
anti-black lives matter
topics and you can very accurately
detect with an algorithm
through a a a combination of the way the
language is written
and the type of site it's on whether or
not it's going to be
higher risk of disinforming and all
you're looking for here
is not an absolute this is definitely
false
what you're looking for when you're
trying to defund this information
is is this a high risk site is it the
sort of place an advertiser would want
to have their brand
you then give that risk rating to the
advertiser in real time
in the ad bidding system and allow the
advertiser to choose
this is too high risk for me i don't
want my ad here or i'm fine with this
level of risk
my ad can go here so it is a tractable
problem
at least at the level of defunding it
well so so what about the advertisers
themselves i mean you're talking about
the sites but i mean if i'm an ad if i
want to really spread something i'm
going to be the advertiser
i mean i'm placing my ads in all kinds
of fun places to do all kinds of things
so
you know i i mean i don't know i i
manage a 50 million dollar program in
technology development to this thing and
i so far i haven't seen okay you can do
some things
but the problem is far from inside just
for example measures of effectiveness of
campaigns
that currently exist no good measures of
effectiveness
there's no way to tell for example at
the moment
really i mean in an automated
reliable way whether what i'm doing is
making any difference
so for example i can measure an effect
that's one thing
but how do i know the effect as a result
of my action so to measure effectiveness
i need i'm what i'm interested in is
how does my action actually contribute
to the effect happening
so so that's a pretty unexplored area at
the moment
so without this kind of stuff i mean you
can never really implement these things
well i i i
you can do some things sure i agree but
um
somebody can always outpace whatever you
do by hand i mean i
whatever whatever technology using right
now i mean there's always
ways to get around it and and it has to
be more effort put into
developing that kind of technology
i love the fact that everybody is super
passionate
i i absolutely agree that that we have
to do a lot more
and by um i think uh
the especially the pandemic uh and
the information we're getting uh
out of the pandemic and of course the
pandemic is not over it continues and we
are
starting to learn to live with it um uh
is is is really uh another game changer
in this
uh we are realizing how much damage uh
this information can do uh to our lives
and i think this is also catching a lot
of attention of governments
um i think the issue is becoming uh
politically more and more salient
uh we will certainly uh uh make sure
it does um and i think this will uh put
the pressure on the governments
uh both individually but mainly
collectively again i think this is where
we need
european action we need eu action we
need european money we need european
investment
um because this is going to be european
regulation
uh ultimately uh which will make sure
that we can implement it
so this is also one of our tasks ahead
of us
and sure technology will always be a
step ahead of us
but i think we've gotten way behind
the the technology and we've allowed uh
too much money to be made of and too
much damage to be done
through the spread of this information
so we really have to get serious about
this and
and and i'm hoping that uh
indeed we can have a very good start
here uh legislatively uh and also
politically
this coming fall next year
when it came to the time when we go to
the
questions from our audience um
we'll try to
get as many as possible okay we have one
question from
andre matishak that is address durant
it is less about monetization but more
about the political power of conspiracy
theories q unknown is relatively new
thing but quite successful
conspiratory movement how dangerous do
you think you anon is
is
okay and then we have another question
from in person
can you speak to your question yes sure
hi there hi
my name is um and actually
thank you so much for this very fruitful
discussion on this information and
potential solutions
um my question is to mr bill chick
because
now the talk within the european union
on the digital services act is actually
quite exciting but um i guess it's going
to be really important
what will be you know the crucial
parameters that this
sort of regulation will take so one of
the main
issues that is being discussed is
whether actually the liability rules for
online
intermediaries that is digital platforms
will actually need to be
updated or whether you think that the
current
state of affairs is sufficient thank you
so much
so we have two questions one from
miloslava
let's start with you but keep it please
short and then let's cover the question
for around about q anon
i will be very short i don't think uh
they are sufficient
that's very short okay i'll also be sure
two and i'm these are extremely
dangerous people
okay simply because they're selling
stuff people want to buy
okay um so since you're super
short and very effective in addressing
these questions let's go to
another question from the audience um
there's one question from craig
to you mr bilteek how are they how are
they working with tech platforms on
aligning their ad and content policies
to stop ad funded disinformation
i think that's uh dealt with the
european union so how is european union
working with tech platforms
on aligning their ads and content
i think this is going to be uh obviously
uh
the this is going to be a big task in
terms of
how we address this issue in a
comprehensive way through the digital
services act
um uh the discussions have been going on
at the level of the european union i
must say that um
uh um tech giants are and digital
platforms are very active
um in brussels um and so there is a big
conversation
uh going on and
i'm not going to give you an answer in
terms of how we're going to do this
but this needs to be part of the way how
we address
the proper digital space so uh to keep
this very short
uh we are in conversation uh and
uh i think um what we need to do is to
inject
a sense of proper uh public and
business-like responsibility when it
comes to digital space i think we need
this from everyone
and just like we've been able to achieve
it offline we have to
achieve it also online
well thank you very much for your inputs
i mean we're at the end of our sessions
for me it was very interesting and i
loved that
everybody was so enthusiastic and you
could see
it by the fact that we were jumping
sometimes into each other's
uh you know um
sessions or attempts to answer uh
the questions um i will remember
and take from the session the fact that
we need to
start hacking upgrade our hacking
skills upgrade our technological
capacities we need to set common
regulation common standards come on
you know um policy
so that we understand each other and we
need to cooperate
uh first possibly on the european level
and then
uh enlarge this cooperation to the uh
transatlantic
uh um space um
i'm very happy that you were able to uh
join me today
i'll i want to thank you very much for
your candor and
invigorating uh ideas i would like to
thank vladimir biltzig
rand balzman and claire melfort for
joining me today for this debate
i i hope and i think that we provided a
lot of
interesting information for you that
could be implemented
you know at the european level and could
inspire
uh some of the policies established at
the
european union or by the european union
um
please stay tuned for our sessions
because we continue
our next session is going to be covered
covering belarus
and it's titled crafting a transatlantic
response to the challenge of belarus
it starts at 7 pm central european time
so please stay tuned
and stay safe stay home and i hope to
see you
sometimes in future in person and hope
to continue with this debate
in person when the pandemic is over
thank you very much
[Music]
so yes the public can work together with
the private sector to secure our
infrastructure
and to help keep society safe in my job
with the united nations in fact bringing
public and private sector together is a
key part of it
technology is part of the problem but
it's also part of the solution
and it can only be part of the solution
when we have the private