[Music]
good afternoon from brussels
my name is alex martin and i'm the head
of globsec brussels office
i am pleased to introduce this second to
last session of globsec 2020 digital
stage
we tried for the past days to bring to
your attention the most relevant
interesting and actual topics but we
decided to go one step further
and bring to this conference a topic
which is literally out of our
coveted world this is the future of mars
exploration so let's go to mars
and we are pleased to have with us dr
anita sengupta
who is an aerospace engineer
entrepreneur
instrument rated pilot rocket scientist
and veteran of the space program
she has developed technologies that have
enabled the exploration of deep space
and novel transportation systems for
over 20 years
at nasa virgin and boeing she is a
research professor in astronautics at
the university of southern california
and a founding member of two electric
aviation companies
dr sengupta will deliver a presentation
for the next 20 minutes
and then we will have the opportunity to
get a q a chat
to get answers uh also to to our tour
questions
so anita the floor is yours
uh good evening everyone from los
angeles and thank you for having me alex
at your wonderful conference so
today i'm going to speak about the
future of mars exploration
with a focus on what has been done to
date and where we're headed as
a species as we travel towards the red
planet my name is anita
gupta and i am an aerospace engineer and
professor by training so we can go to
the next slide
just to give you a little bit of
background um we can go to the second
slide because engineer in the future
hopefully it's up um so to give you a
little bit of background about me
i spent the majority of my career
working for nasa which is the u.s space
agency
developing technologies to facilitate
the exploration of space
and about 15 years ago i had an
opportunity to work on this amazing
mission to mars called the mars science
laboratory curiosity mission which was
going to send something the size of the
car
to the surface of mars and i developed
an expertise on how to land
spacecraft on the surface of other
planets and with atmospheres
ironically that's a class that i now
teach at my university
so the talk of my today is going to be
going through some of my lessons learns
and some of the challenges that we have
as a space agencies from around the
world to accomplish
mars exploration going forward if we go
to the next slide
the next slide will show you a video of
some of the challenges associated with
landing something
on the surface of mars you can play the
video now
[Music]
when people look at it
uh it looks crazy
that's a very natural thing sometimes
when we look at it
it looks crazy it is the result
of reasoned engineering thought
but it still looks crazy
[Music]
from the top of the atmosphere down to
the surface
[Music]
it takes a seven minutes it takes 14
minutes or so
for the signal from the spacecraft
to make it to earth that's how far mars
is away from us
so when we first get word that we've
touched the top of the atmosphere the
vehicle has been alive
or dead on the surface
for at least seven minutes android
descent landing
also known as edl is referred to as a
seven minutes of terror
because we've got literally seven
minutes to get
from the top of the atmosphere to the
surface of mars
going from 13 000 miles an hour to zero
in perfect sequence perfect choreography
perfect timing
and the computer has to do it all by
itself with no help in the ground
if any one thing doesn't work just right
it's game over we slam into the
atmosphere and develop
so much aerodynamic drag our heat shield
it heats up and it glows like the
surface of the sun
1600 degrees
during entry the vehicle is not only
slowing down
violently through the atmosphere but
also we are guiding
like an airplane to be able to land in a
very narrow
constrained space this is one of the
biggest
challenges that we're facing and one
that we have never
attempted on mars mars is actually
really hard to slow down
because it has just enough atmosphere
that you have to deal with it
otherwise it will destroy your
spacecraft on the other hand
it doesn't have enough atmosphere to
finish the job
we're still going about a thousand miles
an hour so
at that point we use a parachute a
parachute is the largest
and strongest supersonic parachute that
we've ever built to date
it has to be able to withstand 65 000
pounds of force even though the
parachute itself
only weighs about 100 pounds
when it opens up that fast it's a neck
snapping nine g's
at that point we have to get that heat
shield off it's like a big lens cap
blocking our view of the ground to the
radar
the radar has to take just the right
altitude and velocity measurements at
just the right time
or the rest of the landing sequence
won't work
this big huge parachute that we've got
it will only slow us down to about 200
miles an hour
and that's not slow enough to land so
we have no choice but we got to cut it
off
and then come down in rockets once we
turn those rocket motors on
if we don't do something we're just
going to smack right back into the
parachute
so the first thing we do is make this
really radical divert maneuver
we fly off to the side diverting away
from the parachute
killing our horizontal velocity and our
vertical velocity
getting the rover moving straight up and
down so it can look
at the surface with this radar and see
where we're going to land
and we head straight down to the bottom
of a crater
right beside a six kilometer high
mountain
we can't get those rocket engines too
close to the ground because if we were
to descend compulsively with our engines
all the way to the ground we would
essentially create this massive dust
cloud that dust cloud could then go and
land on the rover
it could damage mechanisms and it could
damage instruments so the way we solve
that problem
is by using the sky cream 20 meters
above the surface
we have to lower the rover below us on a
tether
that's 21 feet long and then gently
deposit it
on its wheels on the surface
as the rover touches down and is now on
the ground the descent stage
it's in a collision force with a rover
we must cut the bridle immediately
and fly the descent stage away to a safe
distance from the road
okay you can go to the next slide
well that was really exciting and
although it looks like science fiction
that is science fact we designed that
system that successfully landed the mars
science laboratory curiosity rover on
the surface of mars and that same entry
system design will be used to land the
mars 2020
perseverance rover on the surface of
mars but to go back to the ultimate
question is why are we so interested in
exploring mars and ultimately
the reason why space agencies around the
world explore other planets and other
asteroids
and other comets and other places in the
universe is to understand
our place in the universe and a great
example of that is really close to home
in this image you can see our home
planet earth in the middle
you can see venus off to the left and
mars off to the right what's so
interesting is that when the solar
system first formed these planets were
very similar to each other in terms of
having water on the surface
and appreciable atmosphere but over the
course of the past multiple billions of
years
the planets have evolved quite
differently earth of course is our home
it's beautiful and wonderful and has
water and air that we can breathe but
mars has a very thin atmosphere
a very cold temperature and venus has a
very hot
temperature and very high surface
pressure so what we can see
is that climate change is a planetary
phenomena we can see that with our own
neighboring planets mars and venus so we
can go to the next slide
so why are we so interested specifically
in mars well there's two reasons
one is the planet is somewhat
fascinating it has
interesting evidence of prior geologic
activity for example it's olympus mons
and the image in the upper left
is an extinct volcano about six times as
high as mount everest of dallas
marineris
which is the image on the bottom is sort
of the mars version of the grand canyon
but once again also
significantly higher and we can see that
the volcanic activity has shifted and
changed over the course of time
and that might be responsible for the
reason why the planet changed in terms
of its atmosphere
and water flowing on the surface and one
of the theories associated with that is
that there was a large celestial body
which impacted which then
disrupted the magnetic field and ripped
away the atmosphere and the reasons why
we send spacecraft there is to take
scientific measurements to understand
how the planet has evolved the way it
has the second reason of course though
is for future human exploration to the
surface of the planet
and when we develop technologies for
robotic exploration and when we collect
scientific data
about the planet using robotic
exploration we set the stage for future
human exploration so those are the two
reasons
why we explore mars we can go to the
next slide
so one of the things that's really
important for human beings and for life
in general
is the presence of water so that we can
use it to be able to survive and so that
life could have ever existed in the past
and what we've discovered with robotic
exploration over the past 20 years of
mars
is that there is actually flowing water
on mars it's not
big heavy water flows it's more like a
wet mud which you can see in these
images here
so you can imagine the first human
explorers when they go to the planet
would like to tap
into these potential sources of
subsurface aquifers
to be able to grow food and plants and
drink water
themselves and potentially produce
oxygen using that material
and all of this data exists because of
the robotic exploration of space
which is facilitated by agencies such as
nasa esa
jaxa and israel we can go to the next
slide now
and so one of the really important parts
of space exploration
is the development of new technologies
to facilitate our understanding and our
ability
to get there and to move around and have
mobility solutions on the surface of the
planet
so since the 1970s we have been sending
rovers to the surface of ours we've done
a total of our rovers and landers we've
done it a total of eight times now
and what you can see in this image is
that each time we send another vehicle
to the surface of mars
we increase its size we increase its
complexity so by learning on the past
we build the future and we evolve our
technology to be able to do more science
and eventually send people to the
surface of the planet and so the picture
of the rover you can see on the right
is the mars science laboratory curiosity
rover which is essentially
the same rover in terms of size and
capability as the perseverance rover
perseverance has a slightly different
mission
and a slightly different set of
instruments which i will discuss next
so we can go to the next slide so the
purpose of the perseverance mission
is to essentially conduct astrobiology
research to determine whether or not
mars once supported life
whether or not it was habitable and it
does that through a series of
instruments
specifically looking for something
called a biosignature and a biosignature
is sort of a chemical fossil which tells
you whether or not life
could have potentially existed on the
surface in the form of molecular
compounds or in the form of certain
types of isotopes
so when you think about the rover
perseverance which is on its way to mars
right now
you can think of it as a robotic
geologist carrying a suite of
instruments on its back
to make these types of measurements the
secondary purpose for the perseverance
mission
is to enable future human exploration
and it does that by
in one way actually demonstrating
something called
in-situ resource utilization which
allows you to take martian carbon
dioxide
and convert it into oxygen so showing
that you can essentially
live off of the land by using what is
around
if you're smart about it which is what
you would have to do when we go to mars
and of course the most fascinating
feature of the perseverance mission is
that it's going to collect a sample
it's going to cache a sample store it on
the surface of mars so that a future
mission calls mars sample return will
collect that sample
send it back to earth and with
earth-based laboratories
understand even better the potential for
life to have existed
on the surface of the planet so we can
go to the next slide now
so where is the perseverance rover going
it's going to a location called
jezreel crater and the reason why nasa
and the science community chose jezreel
crater
is because this area was once flooded
with water
many billions of years ago in an ancient
river delta
and when you look to environments which
are wet on earth you obviously find
evidence of lots of life so if you go to
an environment which was once wet on the
surface of mars
you could potentially find evidence of
prior life that existed
on the surface and the hope of course is
that we can find evidence of prior
microbial
life on the surface of mars in the past
and perhaps you know even in the present
but that's something that we will have
to uncover
when we eventually send back that cash
sample to earth and conduct more
uh detailed scientific measurements with
earth-based laboratories
but the image on the left here is
showing you the different vehicles that
we have sent to the surface of mars over
the course the past 20
30 years and where the mars 2020
perseverance
rover is located in jezreel crater
in that river delta from the past so we
can go to the next slide
so this uh coming up here is a video of
the entry descent and landing process
you can start the video
now if you're able to so the real
challenge of landing something on mars
is that you have all of this energy all
of the speed you're coming in at a speed
of 20 000 kilometers per hour which is
basically
30 times faster than a commercial
airplane so over a period of seven
minutes you have to slow that vehicle
down
to land the payload or the rover or
eventually people
safely on the surface of the planet and
you do that with a series of
technologies one of them is called the
heat shield
which takes you to about two times the
speed of sound then you deploy a very
large parachute which takes you to
around 300 kilometers per hour
and then finally you descend to the
surface on a series of
rocket motors or engines which help you
slow further down
to touch down softly on the surface of
the planet
so this sequence that you see here was
successfully completed by the curiosity
rover
back in 2012 and it's the same sequence
that the mars perseverance rover will
use in just a few months time
very complicated very difficult because
the rover has to execute this maneuver
autonomously by itself with no help from
the ground
because it's impossible due to the time
delay
of the speed of light and so that is the
landing sequence that mars perseverance
we'll use in just a few months time with
a few
updated editions so we can go to the
next slide and cut past this video if
you're able to
so what i'd like to talk about next is a
little bit about the science
of the mars perseverance mission so as i
mentioned before
the rover is essentially a robotic
geologist which means that
it carries a series of instruments on
its back and so by using a series of
spectrometers
as well as cameras as well as ways to
determine what is in the composition of
the atmosphere of the soil
uh the rover is able to make these
scientific measurements and
one of the most important instruments
which is on board the perseverance rover
is the moxie instrument which basically
allows the rover to create
oxygen from martian co2 this is a key
technology which will be needed
for future human explorers so that they
can survive
safely on the surface of mars so mars
not only has a low temperature
and a low pressure its oxygen atmosphere
is primarily carbon dioxide which means
that the crew would have to be able to
convert
co2 into oxygen to be able to survive on
the surface of the planet
so by taking a look at the geology by
taking a look at the atmosphere
by taking a look at the weather more
information can be determined about
where we've landed as well as about how
interesting the samples are that we are
going to be caching with this rover
so we can go to the next slide
so the way the rovers are named is
actually with a naming competition
before each mission and so the winner
here was perseverance which follows a
curiosity
you can see the size of this rover it's
about the size of a small car
it has about the weight or the mass of a
small car it has a series of six wheels
which allow it to climb over
very large surface features and safely
without tipping over
without getting damaged of course the
gravity on mars is less than what you
would have here on earth but it's still
very challenging to be able to climb
around
it does this quite slowly because it
doesn't need to do it quickly as it's
collecting scientific measurements along
the way
and it also has a very unique power
source called an rtg
a radioisotope thermoelectric generator
which means that it doesn't have to rely
on solar radiation to generate power
itself generates its own power which
allows it to keep itself warm and
operate
more hours of the day than you could do
on solar power or roam another
unique advanced technology which was
demonstrated by curiosity and is being
demonstrated again
by the perseverance mission so we can go
to the next slide
um one of the new features of this
mission which i think is very exciting
because i am an electric
aviation entrepreneur is that the rover
is carrying a mars helicopter which is a
single rotor counter rotating
system which will allow it to do aerial
reconnaissance in the vicinity of the
rover once per day
this tiny little helicopter is powered
off of a battery
and solar panels to recharge its battery
it's capable of a 90 second flight
and it's able to go into the sky collect
images which allows the rover to better
understand its surroundings
it's incredibly lightweight only two
kilograms and this is necessary
because the atmosphere on mars is very
thin which means it can only generate a
very little bit of lift so it has to be
very lightweight
to counteract the fact that the
atmosphere is quite thin this is the
first time
an electric aircraft is ever being flown
on the surface another planet
and i think this is very exciting and
it's an important technology
demonstration
asset that could be used on future
missions to other planets that also have
atmospheres
and it is called ingenuity athlete so we
can go to the next slide now
so the countdown to mars so where are we
today will the rover successfully
launched
at the end of july um now it's on its
way to the red planet
it's targeted to land on february 18
where we'll execute its entry descent
and landing sequence that i showed you
in that video before
after it safely lands a few minutes
later it will check out its systems and
then it will begin
its surface mission its surface journey
to collect the scientific measurements
for a minimum of two earth years which
is um
uh the minimum set of data that it will
collect it'll likely
rove around the surface for many many
years after that
so we can go to the next slide so what
is the future
of mars exploration we can now go to the
next slide so the future
of mars exploration is to set up for
human exploration of mars and so there
are many technologies that have to be
developed for
a colony no matter how small to
successfully survive on the surface
and a lot of that is surrounded by the
principles of in-situ resource
utilization which is living off of the
land
which is being sustainable which is
something that we need to do here on
earth first successfully to combat
climate change
and we can leverage all of those lessons
learned into our human beings would live
on the surface of another world so when
we talk about sustainability
for surface missions on extraterrestrial
locations we're talking about power
generation from the sun
we're talking about radiation protection
using the martian environment and soil
to mitigate some of those high energy
particles the production of water by
tapping into those subsurface aquifers
and then the creation of rocket fuel and
then also
plants called extremophiles using
martian co2
to grow those plants so um to wrap
things up we can go to the next slide
which is when are we going to see the
first human beings on mars
um you can go to the next slide if
you're able to um
probably within the next 15 to 20 years
is my guess
it is going to require international
collaboration and a lot of funding but i
do think that we'll get there
but this is an image of probably what
the first colony would look like
and then the final very final slide you
can go to the last slide
the question that i'll leave you with as
an audience is that would you want to
live on mars would you want your
children to live on mars do you see us
as the society actually living on the
surface of mars so thank you very much
and now we'll do a short q a
thank you very much anita this has been
absolutely fascinating and
not just for me i'm sure also for for
our audience
and i want to pick up where you actually
left
and um you talk about humans uh
to mars in about 15 or 20 years so
there is talk about the human mission to
the moon do you think that another
moon landed mission is needed before we
uh get
the humans on mars so there's two
different aspects to space exploration
when human beings are involved one is
the development of the technologies to
be able to accomplish it and the other
is the ability to be able to survive off
earth
in these sort of sustainable ways for a
long period of time so because the moon
doesn't have an atmosphere
a lot of the technologies that are
developed for a moon landing are quite
different than the technologies that are
developed for a mars landing so for
example you can't use a parachute on a
moon because there's no atmosphere
you pretty much would just use retro
rockets but that being said
the idea of being able to live
sustainably to be able to live for an
extended period of time in a higher
radiation environment is something that
we'll learn a lot about with a future
human mission to the moon
fantastic i do want to have a short
disclaimer saying that you were actually
a
responsible for the supersonic parachute
that
helped curiosity land on mars and it's
important for everyone to know
that that you are the mastermind behind
the technology of
slowing down from over 28 000 kilometers
an hour to zero to put
defender over successfully on on the red
planet so
you mentioned that in 15 uh 20 years uh
we will be
uh able maybe to to go there but
meanwhile the mars 2020 mission is on
its way with a planned date
of 21 for landing and european space
agency is also planning to send a rover
in 2022 so how can space agencies can
better pull resources together
to make this even more cheaper or even
more effective
well so first i will say it's absolutely
essential to support human exploration
for space agencies to pool their
resources because when you look at the
cost
associated with robotic missions when
you look at the cost associated with
human missions you're looking at an
order of magnitude
if not two orders of magnitude more cost
so it's simply impossible
for one country to be able to do this
alone you have to do it with space
agencies from around the world so
there's several ways to do that you
could choose to
break it up into a pie where one country
takes responsibility for the launch
vehicle another takes responsibility for
scientific instruments
another takes responsibility for the
spacecraft and that way you share the
costs or you can do it in a more
holistic fashion
where you look for who has the expertise
that we need and you form an
international team who works on
everything together and i definitely
would be a supporter of the latter
because i think that's super exciting as
an engineer to be able to work
with space agencies around the world
we'll make sure that at least this part
of our conversation will be sent to
multiple space agencies around the world
uh but still the the issue of space
exploration is not only a matter of
international cooperation
but also of uh space race and that's
where geopolitical tensions come
into place so what are your thoughts
about
about uh this issue is this the mars
exploration
will will it lead to more international
cooperation or to more geopolitical
pensions
i think there's another aspect of it
which is it leads to competition
and competition can actually lead to
efficiencies new technologies
innovation which ultimately facilitate
the exploration of space and a great
example of that which is completely in
line
with our discussion is the commercial
crew program that nasa
engaged in which now is sending
astronauts to this international space
station so the commercial crew program
came in at a very low development cost
only a few billion dollars
yet it gives us access to the
international space station which will
save
the us space agency money it will
facilitate space
tourism so i would see this aspect of
competition
amongst countries amongst private
companies is actually uh reducing costs
and finding new efficiencies in new
innovation
and talking about this competition we
have a question from audit from the
audience from katarina
asking if you could compare the goals
and technological level of the american
uae and chinese mars missions and their
significance for the future of space
exploration
well i'll be honest to say that i don't
know enough about the details of their
mission from an engineering perspective
to be able to compare it
but i would say that because they're
scientific missions and they have
scientific objectives they're probably
following the same objectives which is
to understand past habitability
whether or not there could have been
microbial life on the surface whether
there is still is today
and to be able to do um those types of
measurements you have to develop
instruments you have to have
telecommunications ability you have to
have power on board you have to have a
spacecraft bus
that can do those things so i think it's
great that we're creating
different uh sources of this expertise
across the globe because that
immediately feeds forward into this
vision of a
global or planetary earth human
exploration program that i hope happens
in the next
15 to 20 years you mentioned climate
change and sustainability and the idea
of protection of
of the outer space in your presentation
so uh this is a very important the
planetary protection is an important
aspect of
of sending spacecraft to mars so will it
be maintained once the humans the first
humans
will will get there so that's a really
good and important debate that we need
to have so just as a little bit of
background
when we send a spacecraft to a planetary
body a celestial body which may have
life we
use planetary protection protocols to
make sure that we don't bring earth
bacteria
or earth viruses to this planetary body
and therefore damage whatever might be
there
in terms of you know microbial life or
even contaminate our own scientific
measurements so when we send rovers to
the surface of mars
we engage in a variety of protocols
which make sure the rover's clean so
that we don't bring our earth-based
bacteria
to the surface of mars of course when we
send people it's going to be a very
different situation because people
inherently have a microbiome inside them
and they have bacteria that we use to
survive so we will be bringing bacteria
from earth tomorrow so we need to have a
global conversation
we need to have a policy discussion as
to how much is okay
what are we going to do in terms of to
reduce our footprint where we're
actually creating
um you know this human microbiome
environment these are conversations that
have to be had
at that geopolitical level which involve
scientists and engineers as well as
politicians
to say what is the right way to handle
this but it's something that we're going
to have to broach very soon
dr sigupta this has been really really
fascinating and a great pleasure
to have you with us today i would like
to thank you very much
for for joining the digital stage of
globsec and as i wrap up this panel
i would like to invite you all to stay
online for the last panel of
globstic 2020 digital stage and that's
an update
on belarus with zetlana tiscos nuskaya
moderated by terry martin of deutsche
valley
thank you thank you
[Music]
you