hello I will be talking about a Kaos
anomaly trigger attack on secure
operations for cryptographic key storage
the cat's socks
attack is based off of a Kaos anomaly a
trigger attack on secure operations for
cryptographic key storage known as socks
that use the Turing unresolvable numeric
algorithm tuna for key protection in
particular and implementation of the
cryptographic alig rate allocation of
nonces the can is studied and we show
that a heuristic approach using a
performance adaptive workload scripts
also known as pause can be used to
penetrate the secure storage so we will
we will now present the acronyms we have
chaos anomaly trigger secure operations
for cryptographic key storage tutoring
unresolvable numeric algorithm
cryptographic allocation Lanza's and
performance adaptogen workload script
the problem description is to protect
the cryptographic keys using socks in
the cipher mode preventing the cat paws
from penetrating the security container
and accessing the tuna can in this
instance the tunic and holds a to fish
key because block chain here is a
graphical overview I know it's been a
long day I wanted to make it very clear
for you we are demonstrating that the
the cat paws are able to penetrate the
socks layer through the secure container
into the tuna can and obtain the two
fish key material because block chain
again and I will now demonstrate the
heuristic attack that was used in order
to penetrate the secure container with
100% reliability
Falls try and then we have achieved
success so thank you
[Applause]