oh I just want to advertise our winter
school in China but in order to qualify
for winter for rum session talk I would
just start with the attack this is a
real attack we targeted at
cryptocurrency cryptocurrency wallets
which is very convenient to use
especially warm mobile phones actually
there are a couple of security
requirements
it's called trivial like you have to
make good protection of the secret keys
and they must be like a strongly
encrypted and they must be erased out
after use and kind of a typical security
flaws we can exploit such as you know
the the secret keys they are not
properly protected sometimes they are
stored in clear-text
and sometimes they are encrypted that
we've fixed keys that's just hard coded
in your app and sometimes they just an
obfuscated so then but but this kind of
storage storage storage is hard to
explore especially all those mobile
phones nowadays this Android and iOS
they are protected with food the screen
proportion and we can also explore
things from memory because this memory
they are not protected at all we kind
dip achill examples they are code such
as code code Abood attacks and we we
target that top 10 wallet according to
many rankings the name is the name is a
anonymizer but we in cipher the wizard
are Caesar ensure that when when this
you know the memories code when
transformed to the secret skid it just
appeared in the memory in clear text
during the whole lifetime of the app
even when the app is running in the
background or even when we explicitly
invoke the garbage collector this is
because they have somehow they kind of
like
the globe of Rio is out of the reach of
the garbage collector so that is my
attack our attack and the main standing
point is our winter school well we are
together with Professor showing one we
are hosting a winter school in China not
to teach how to break you know
cryptocurrencies but the focus to IBM PC
fhe and the differential privacy and so
on it is the event affiliated with Asia
cryptid this year it's just to write
before a show crypt so you can if you go
to Asia crypt you can make a stopover in
stranger which is just next to Hong Kong
and it is very convenient to reach and
we have sensor has like sweet and as
your airport in the neighborhood and we
have a very fantastic team of lecturers
so you can see most of the faces in the
conference ok and more importantly it's
free the registration is free but you
need to apply and we have also thanks to
that and stipends ok for you to apply if
you interested please go to our website
ok so I hope there some time so you can
take a look that's it thank you very
much
[Applause]