thank you this is George walk with my
colleague daniel ganc add me here
ppattani and Rory Schuster and it
addresses a problem of great importance
for many researchers which is the
following when we have that video
conference with a colleague and they
appear somewhat distracted or disengaged
is that because they are pondering the
open problems that we have posed to them
or because they are browsing the
blockchain now they probably have a
webcam for the for the video conference
but it's pointing away from the screen
they also have a microphone placed in
proximity to the screen which raises the
question can we listen in on their
screen that is are their acoustic side
channels emanated by screens to
investigate this we started by setting
up a simple cover channel detection
methodology we rendered simple zebra
stripes across the screen of various
thickness and we recorded them using a
microphone and we observed that as we
changed the thickness of the zebra
stripes the acoustic signature changes
in the spectra to a spectral line shift
it clearly if different zebras have
different acoustic signatures there is
image dependent leakage you can observe
this leakage on LED and LCD screens for
many manufacturers and of different
models including old ones as well as
fresh ones of Amazon and in all of the
screens we can observe this acoustic van
eck if you will that a reveals the
content of the screens by the movements
of the frequency content you can record
this by many commodity microphones such
as webcams or the Intel or microphones
built into many screens phones and to
jump on the internet-of-things bandwagon
even your favorite digital assistant
smart speaker that would also
conveniently store that captured audio
on the cloud for future reference you
can even measure these signals from afar
say 10 meters away using our favorite
parabolic dish and get the same signals
now what are these signals to dig in
it's most convenient to start by a
synthetic image for example this one a
portraying zebra stripes punctuated by a
black rectangle and if you record using
a microphone a screen as its rendering
this you'll probably see an image
similar to the following where that
punctuation in the middle is clearly
visible within the time trace during a
single rendering of a single frame and
what we are actually observing for this
screen is the line intensity modulated
onto a 32 kilohertz acoustic carrier in
order to exploit this you need to cope
with additional challenges there is
significant frequency drift and time
jitter there is abundant noise and there
is redundancy between frames that we
would like to exploit we cope with this
using custom digital signal processing
algorithms and trace merging piped into
deep learning using a convolutional
neural networks culminating in a
classifier that can tell what your
colleague is up to the optimistic we can
this way distinguish not just the nature
of the activity but also which website
is being browsed between a hundred
websites with excellent accuracy we can
extract text that is rendered on screen
and in case the victim is typing on a
virtual on-screen keyboard we can
extract the keystrokes over all of these
dots goes to show that indeed the
picture is worth a thousand words
because by the time you've spoken to
thousands words we probably detected
which picture you're looking at and four
additional words please see our paper
thank you
[Applause]