hi I'm a darth this is joint work with
around Romer and Mariana I cover this is
not a song it's talking about their
knowledge but building upon previous
talk so their knowledge Brusco seen
enormous decline in recent years mainly
thanks to the blockchain we now have
privacy preserving cryptocurrency smart
contract systems and so on many of them
recently covered in the sink approved
standardization workshop that Mootoo
will be talking about and in the
blockchain scenario you need a
particular kind of zero knowledge proof
ideally it's non interactive proof of
knowledge and especially useful if it's
succinct one so ZK snark but which is
not actually use well the most efficient
ones are based on quadratic arithmetic
programs and they have extremely fast
verification just milliseconds but they
required a common reference string or
using this new terminology from the
workshop a structure different string
and the soundness of the proof system
crucially depends on SRS being correctly
generated and then the private
randomness getting destroyed so who
should do this well you could delegate
to someone whom you trust or you could
use a multi-party computation ceremony
and the best ceremony scale to hundreds
of participants and this is for example
what seekers did but ideally you would
want to use a proof system that doesn't
require a common reference string of Tao
and we have such for example PCP based
systems such as this stark system they
are asymptotically succinct
but generally CAD large constant so the
proofs are much larger in practice if
your statement is sufficiently simple
you could use the non succinct zero
knowledge proof
say bullet proofs are hierarchs or
liquor or zk boo but a statement grows
so there's a verification time and in
blockchain scenario that might be
unacceptable so let's take a look
there's Alex and Steve your favorite
minecraft characters and Alex wants to
send returns
Oh Steve and it includes zero knowledge
proof
so as transaction propagates through the
blockchain sorry through the node
network to be included in the blockchain
it needs to be verified by every single
node
so if verification is slow Steve will
see your transaction after a delay it
might seem like I can use Bill T problem
but it's actually a security issue
because miners if the transaction
verification is too slow after a certain
threshold they'll just stop verifying
them so they'll include transactions in
a book that are in fact invalid and this
has happened before in Bitcoin and
rational miners do this because they get
a head start
why should I verify if most likely is
going to be ok and wherever people will
build upon your block and mine another
invalid block so in this board we
present a system called zero knowledge
sharks succinctly documents of knowledge
which are short proofs that have dual
verification mode you can either verify
them prudently which is linear time
verification just like bulletproof but
no SRS or optimistically which is passed
just as fast as snarks but your lies on
an SRS so in your favorite blockchain
scenario this is as good as snarks
because everyone will just verify
everything optimistically and then
miners during the proof of work will do
the prudent verification this is
incentive compatible note that we did
rely on SRS so what happens if
optimistic verification succeeds but
proven does not
it deals to an immediate detection that
your SRS has been compromised and so you
can go back and retroactively Lee audit
your old proofs and you can recover my
first revoking SRS checking out the old
proofs by during the prudent
verification and after that regenerating
optimistic proof pairs note that if you
just concatenated an Isaac and a snark
you wouldn't get this property
I got five minutes oh I'm sorry
so yeah so in a sense we get the proof
systems that combines both properties of
musics and snarks compromised SRS
doesn't deal to a break in the system
appearances for coming but there is some
local media coverage about charts
already thank you
[Applause]