hi everybody good afternoon and welcome
you're here for a dive dive into
security risk and what I said before
it'll be Paul McKenna I would say that
you know I could make you take risk and
say yes stakeholders on Mars so Who am I
I it was quite interesting when Connor
Wilson just before me mentioned that you
know one of the worst set you know
devices in your home could be set to
boxes I used to work in electronics and
repair set-top boxes I'm as I sometimes
say the poorest camp of Scotty cyber
I've been everywhere don't quite a lot
of staff in academia work from all major
banks I inspired the crypto professor to
do crypto I worked with Jamie Graves who
is now running zone folks and some most
recent things I also helped to ensure
the security of the core components of
the arc recorder which is if you're
interested in some distributed stuff so
been there done that I don't have any
t-shirts most of the companies only
CableCards Pollack only thought I do
understand the O'Day chart I do a lot of
technical things I love talking about it
but guess what not everybody likes
talking about it and often things that
we care about you know as a tech
security forum I leave it behind
somebody puts them somewhere on
additional bit of the document so so
what people actually care about is X
examine that will you left with so if
you want to get something that's where
you need to get it so just to make sure
I'm going to be talking about some
things that have happened in the past
and if you recognize the company I'm
talking about it's because you right
there so don't share it's all gonna be
fine so what is the problem today in
security I into few talks today already
I had some messages that was talking
about breaches Facebook doesn't care
those people don't care it just business
doesn't care that much and
how do we make them hair a little bit
about so imagine you've got the pen test
results are out now you've got the
recommendation you need to get a new
piece of kit into your organization or
somebody is going to take it over you
you know you just get it into your mind
if we found that piece of teeth it could
be a flux capacitor by the way you did
not wanna get out alive so what are you
going to do how you gonna get it from
your stakeholders are you going to do
nothing you know add it to annual budget
unlikely it's usually too small to
actually run the costs for the year you
can wait for a nice project to come
along and ask them or you can still
two-tone him from Lydians and sell it on
I often use that in the past I basically
waited for a big enough project to come
along whenever they would go into the
transformation cycle eventually they
would have hit one of the security gates
and I would be like you know guys if
you're not doing if you're not going to
do that you can go ahead you can deliver
your project the best I got out of it I
actually managed to get a tactical sim
installed for 1.2 million pounds in one
of the bank's I'm quite glad in that but
it's not things I'm proud of because at
the same time I'm the blocker I'm a
security guy saying guys you not gonna
go past planning or you know they're
gonna get to the execution if you don't
invest 1.2 million right now towards the
end of your project I'm the bad guy I'm
dead you know it feels bad and you can't
really oversell so it would be nice if
obviously stake holders will get us near
that when we talk strategy no division
what we want to do with the company but
they don't do it often security is the
thing that is at the back so and it
I get few examples in the past as well
so some stories I remember at one stage
one of the stakeholders in the bank
actually didn't come to us somebody just
send us a little email saying guys that
area in the bank is doing something
risky you know go inspect it and by the
way when I take advantage in any bank I
work in most of the vines in Scotland so
when when somebody say that area is
doing something risky we call and speak
to them is like yeah don't worry it's
we're not changing anything so basically
when clients have problems to get online
this phone has happened they want to get
the statement or something or account
balance we just say you know you could
do it all online you can I take you
through the process so they take all the
security details on at all they asked
people what password would you like the
tip it over that form doesn't matter the
Crawleys get recorded and then they say
to the customer you can use it now
online banking so yeah I had a problem
talking to the stakeholders and telling
them guys there's something wrong about
it so it turns out our common sense is
not the common sense that the business
stakeholder said how can we fix it if we
don't have a common sense that maybe
there is something else we've got in
common so you know business like to talk
about money customer satisfaction press
releases and some other flash you know
some nice pictures maybe feelings of
people say sales pitches security on the
other hand every cut some nice talk we
talk about secured by design as clearly
injection password complexity great it's
nice is I like that chat sky stand get
it you know and then we've got some flat
as well we've got my spy charts of our
dashboards on our new scene actually has
knobbly pie chart if you want to see
those holida one thing we actually had
in common is risk you know business guys
talk about risk every day at least
monthly they need to look at the finance
and credit risk and they'll have also
mandatory eristic plenty of ways to
worry about so I learned a popping that
language and
we talked about this but when we talk
about it we want to stop people taking
risks when they talk about risk they
want to take risk that's how you make
money in a business you don't make money
by sitting at home and being wrapping
yourself in a you know in a doobie and
hoping everything gonna be good that's
not how you make money as a business you
go out there take a risk to be the first
in the market or something else whatever
your domain is and that's how you make
money so how do we go about fixing there
is a disconnect about how we talk it we
even talking about the same thing but we
do things in brain perspective a
different perspective so where I want to
tell you or take you today is how myself
a risk-averse person from a cave diver
and relate it to a lot of things we do
in security so we can imagine going
diving is actually great sport for me I
can't do meditation I just you know
tried I failed
that's my meditation you know like I can
go there with a bunch of friends go
under the water listen to myself
breathing in and out looking to the
world around these visitor there and
relax nobody can call me nobody can talk
to me anyway that is a good app okay
down it's fine
it's it's nice and relaxing sport but
there are some risks especially if you
can't escape that
so actually this is quite a treat ix
visibility dive into it was quite a nice
and relaxing experience Amy as well if
you get Custer public already that's how
I used to get there but I now enjoyed so
what is it that we're not when most
people see something like that
careful risk us what security guys now
say to the business like careful risk
don't go there
something bad can happen I see a nice
repressed recreational area and that's
that's what's behind that fence there is
a huge quarry flooded nobody died before
me and my body
that's what if I'd nice quiet nobody's
there anyway so how do we get people to
see that at different side and because
I'm now talking to the security proud
I'm taking this view that security maybe
follow rather than the business and I
think we can meet in the middle so first
of all how risky is it you find out that
if somebody's cave trained it's you know
one out of three hundred thousand dives
end up being a fatality or causing a
fatality normal diving one out of two
hundred thousand dives somebody dies if
you run a marathon is one out of 100,000
to you guys if you run a marathon I
salute you it's a risky business
it is so don't think that K diabetes
heart is not insulted you can join us
and obviously driving is far more
dangers and and the like the one that
they like in the bottom right is
actually hard something at least wrong
about these sharks people are scared of
sharks but actually you're more likely
to die of flu or stroke or cancer than
I'm tiny risk of being bitten by a shark
so think about it so if we get
statistics wrong and if we get
perception of the risk wrong in our
heads is it that we only get it about
other things maybe when we talk about
work your man's better among three
security guys and girls we cannot have
to be better in each one so in 2019 what
was the most likely I'll having malware
and I don't want you to shout to raise
your hand or anything let's do it the
mentally stylist into yourself one of
those answers okay I hope some of you
were surprised because that's the point
of it most people are now talking about
office there is it's fair of you know
office Kyle palace carrying malware yes
there may be a newer wave they are in
the news but actually javascript files
always carried malware and they still
carry malware and they still majorly t
of malware so maybe some other
statistics you may have been involved in
one of those ransomware incident how
long will it last you've detected that
also incidents of heart you've got a
ransom on your screen how long it
usually takes a company to recover again
think the answer to yourself you know
you've got backups you've got everything
how long it will take you to recover on
average is seven point three days and
it's usually cost the company about
sixty four sixty five thousand dollars
these are the stats from a company
called cold where an extra body quite
like their statistics and Pat one
they've got they say that malware or
ransomware got so bad indeed that now
you've got ninety five chance of
recovering your files if you pay them in
the past I would never advise people to
pay I sit on my bicycle to pay but 95
percent chance of recovering your files
if you pay
it's pretty good software okay so the
protection of risk is all over the place
you know people are scared of terrorist
attack but the risk is actually finding
no as the on the bottom is actual reason
pop is how people are worried about it
everybody talks about you know terrorist
attacks plane crashes actually you are
more of a risk of you know if you're
having a glass of wine a day that's more
likely to be a cause of your death
rather than the tolerance attack so
here's another one for you have you
heard in the last three months that most
of the attacks on organizational most of
the malware into the organization is
carried by the email is coming to me no
thanks that's a start actually all over
the place ninety pounds ninety percent
of everything is carried by email no
this was a Verizon stack the statistics
about AP key had nothing to do with
malware but people that sell ELT tools
and other tools are now using it to
advertise and saying come on get our
tools everything is coming through email
it still Remote Desktop Protocol that
gets people will be surprised 2018-19 so
tune your perception of risk know what's
around you and then get back to you know
white cave diving is not so dangerous
you know we still haven't seen the data
is it is it dangerous is not dangerous
how did it got to that point and command
all had a nice thing is you know
actually you really look at the data and
you shouldn't get any theories about it
so in 70s it was a very risky sport many
people died actually
no 35 people per year would die cave
diving and then something happened
science like that would be put up in
Mexico and Florida to warn people about
danger and also put trainings about and
the reason was because somebody Dom
accident analysis we found out that most
people that died were actually it could
be family so it could be just
recreational divers
the 70s just q-bag real good quite cheap
so they all create go and dive they
would start diving into a nice little
stream it's open water diving so you can
surface anytime you want and get nice
breath of air and then they would go a
little bit in the caves because they
right next to the streams that was the
right came back on next week and I go a
bit deeper Purple's like it's it's an
easy in cave diving come on it's not
scary at all
it a bit deeper deeper every week and
you know they'll get overconfident
actually I died because of something
they would get to the point where where
as our businesses they would you know
you speak to the business and say why
should I do something that you tell me
about I've been operating for the past
three years nothing has happened and
it's the same kind of you know reactions
so how was it keeps they it was a proper
accident analysis done people started to
care about the people
our in a straining state of mind
somebody going diving skills and learn
from the mistakes every time you go into
the cave but now you look at the den is
like it's pretty much like any framework
for trying to defend yourself this one
is the oldest identified protect detect
respond and recover if you've got a
problem if you want to defend yourself
against something going wrong you can
use one of many methodologies but as
long as you go and stick to it to define
so when you defend yourself try to work
these phases identify what could go
wrong for take years of against detect
when something starts to go wrong
respond in recover so what how does it
translate to things but then do it to
proper level well somebody may die at
the end of it maybe the company is the
company gotta die so what kills a crate
diver out of those four other confidence
that is most likely to kill them as I
said before you know other people that
type you will notice that that's a graph
showing how many people had cave diving
qualification hundred and forty three of
them you can have any
having qualifications the people that
actually bothered and done some training
very pretty right not that many open
died but I want you to go further
whenever you're trying to say to
somebody what's gonna happen what is the
wrong thing that are going to happen to
your company or a business or your
colleagues at work or the customers I
want you to go further and think know
what's there you know obviously when we
talk about loss of visibility that can
cause an accident and tango meant yes I
can die because of it after maybe half
an hour but then panic the game but when
I'm diving what's gonna kill me the lack
of air or water in my lungs and the same
with the company they not gonna die
because of a data breach and I've seen
you've seen some examples this morning
from from other people solving how many
breaches Facebook went through and other
organizations went through and they
still alive define so what kills a
company so you probably heard about it
in 2007 17 masks
one of the biggest shipment company
actually the biggest shipping company in
the world was hit by no petia and you
know after that incident they had to
attach about 4,000 servers 45,000 pcs
had to be redone they've been done for
ten days nothing operated so all those
ships were out and see waiting to vote
reports because they couldn't unload
everything was on phase with the ships
they couldn't unload the cargo because
the system wasn't telling people where
to put the cargo the tracks would
actually queue up outside the ports and
block the major highways everybody was
aware of they couldn't do anything about
it
so no but so what happened to masks we
had some people today saying all the
surprise may drop yes it will drop for a
very short while it not going to drop
for long nurse doesn't day the vertical
line there is a day when the actual
initiative is no Patea they're in
similar time that they had in 2000
seeing they've got now between 2018-19 I
don't see that much offense taking diet
because of it mess will continue to
operate they will be fine but if you
would say to mare skies you know you
could save yourself 300 million by not
connecting one of your machines to the
network the machine will be using the
software from the Train that's gonna get
automatically passed by whoever know
somebody you don't trust they'll
probably say yes don't put that machine
on a network maybe pay 400 pounds or 200
pounds to get it secured so talk about
risk can breach analytical that wasn't a
nice one as well they waiting at which
they were the bridge we probably heard
about them they actually if we look at
breaks it or Donald Trump winning the
election they probably had something to
do with it just because they manipulated
people's mind in Facebook and other
sources they died they've been outed
last last year Channel Paul ran a
documentary about them that company is
no longer around
not because of a breach no law but
because they ran out of money they run
out of money depending himself from the
press and also their servers were taken
by the IC also they couldn't operate if
they would have more money he would
continue to operate it was another
element there as well
companies like Trump which channel it
can depend on somebody that he supplier
like Facebook with data we cut them away
from that supplier they're dependent so
if you are a bank for example and you
have millions of customers and you don't
have one single supplier that can take
you down what happens if you blow the
bridge no different a supervisor
surprise may drop for five days they
will cost you but not that much there
was another case of rock you rock she
was a brilliant one and I hope you
actually know about them so if you give
to any password cracking lectures or
anything like that you may have heard
about rocky they were the original
password log I've got outed on the
internet before 2009 everybody thought
that people were quite clever with their
passwords they actually had proper
random
passports but you know one hacker with a
clue minimum is is is I he he was able
to execute an SQL injection on their
website and be able to get all the
password data from the website and what
was nice he kind of made it public that
you know rocky is not safe so we rock
you said all week now patch our systems
everything inspiring people don't panic
but they they weren't honest with people
so you know the attacker can default you
know they need to do something about it
so we thought what best you can do he
actually took 32 million passwords and
add them to the internet with no
username so the security industry learn
a lot from it they actually if you know
about people using password one two
three four or something is because of
that breach they were the first one that
got beat and what what happened to them
that happened 2009 2010 they were still
operating they like had to fire about
half of their staff but up until I think
last month they were still operating
taking died that organization did not
die so if you're going and saying to
your stakeholders come on if you don't
patch the system they're going to be
huge massive data breach and your top
even as with all your customers that's
probably not exactly true you need to be
specific if you are telling your people
that and you need to know what your
company is dependent on so rock in the
game they were depending on Facebook
Facebook could hand down the top and
MySpace they could turn down the top any
time and that's what happened that's why
they actually had to hire a couple named
Stan so what gives companies do not pass
their order to close reading bad press
or a breach but it's different for
everybody we need to understand the
business you're helping
don't just tell them it's a bridge
what's gonna kill you this means you
don't understand the business we don't
understand the risk it means you don't
know how the people you work and will
make money okay so identify know your
business what does it need to survive
and then protect yourself you know in
cave diving we we know you can I have to
having two bottles of air if if any no I
can easily die because I ran off out of
air I can only keep my breath for 30
seconds
I sent inspired myself shot another in
into a deep mind now how do I get out
alive if something happens I need to
have a backup so we always carry two
bottles of air into two separate
regulators if we need to separate the
bottles we've got the 9-volt at the back
which we can just turn down shut down
and had two distinct systems if I go to
a type okay I've got another system
where I keep the bottles on the side I
can take them both off put them in front
of me and be okay I'm never going to be
seen to go past many obstacles but still
a slim as I can get to an obstacle and
sometimes the best kit you can get is
not a diving Keith I think that's a
lifesaver one of the minds we explore we
need to walk about quarter of a mile so
I think that's the best kit we ever
bought in the or bike or port that gets
us to the place and don't get to the
place out of breath but what I want you
to think about is you know when you
trying to protect yourself and now you
know what can kill you get the right
tools for the job
and surely you know that at least one or
two stories of what people buy when they
even money or when they told that
something needs to be changed one of
them you know I remember an organization
that was told you need to get
correlation between password checkouts
and what is a privilege activity and
they went through looking to few
different seen tools and at the end of
it they come out with two and that was
ages ago was about eight ten years ago
they come out with curators plan problem
his plan was it didn't have a security
label back in the day and also the sales
guy from the states didn't want to
travel to UK because it's a smash a
small island you know it was a small
market for them
curator should not do correlation at all
but the salesgirl yeah they were happy
to travel it's free travel come on is a
eight hours in they can help you to that
organization obviously the time that was
a bank they went for curator and that's
where I brought my first score or
checked my first correlation rules in
peril outside of the symptom because the
only way you could do correlation was to
take the logs out of the symbol for the
night
when two different patches compare them
in parallel put it back into the seam
tool and see the exceptions the next
morning and you think to yourself how
much money doesn't waste every day how
much life you're wasting because you got
the wrong tool for a job and your
security if you get something the wrong
be brave enough to say that or think
about the strategy how you're going to
get better so things like that I'm sure
you've got plenty of those horror
stories from your organization's I work
with you before and I know few of those
horror stories so get the right tools
for the job
and then we took detect that something
is getting wrong you know so if you
think about diving accident actually
diving at it then often starts at home
all on the journey to your dive site it
does not start even down in the cave it
starts with maybe your mindset maybe
something happened on the way maybe it's
just not your day one of the cases there
was a guy who was on the boat in Scots
law one of the beautiful areas up in
Scotland and you know he had a little
fall on the board obviously we've got
like 40 kilos of equipment on our backs
so he got up shake himself is like it's
a patient to the skipper and Pines
keeper and skipper thought she looks all
right let him dive he went died down he
was planning a deep dive 260 metres he
never surfaced and it was because of
that little ball that he had exactly
happened to his arm he couldn't operate
things that he should be able to operate
and actually skipper would go to jail if
not for the fact he did not organize the
trip he was just helping some buddies go
on the boat
so think about rally detect those little
signals telling me that something may go
wrong and how do you filter them that
you also don't waste time and look at
too much noise
Tesco bank was an interesting case in
2016 I'm sure that we've heard about
them they're spent on banks like them as
well so they're not my target in here
but if you think about them they had a
breach they somebody worked out how to
do the silly vehicles on their cards and
you know they only lost two points two
million pounds in fraud at that bridge
so they could compensate all the clients
but obviously that was pretty pretty
uncomfortable situations for the client
to find out they'd be losing money and
somebody being deterred in their
accounts so actually they've been fined
sixteen million pounds for that event
and when you read the accident analysis
it turns out that the fraud guys knew on
Friday evening that something is going
wrong and they keep emailing that little
inbox saying we think something is going
wrong you should look into it second
line please look into it and guess what
second line was a way for the weekend
take in check the email somebody did not
check the process and for 21 hours
nobody actually started responding to
the event just 21 hours before somebody
done a change to prevent a fraud from
the time they actually detected and I'm
sure that they've detected at these few
hours you know more after the fraud
started happening so get those signals
early teach people to be open and honest
in diving if I could apart feeling that
about today you know I make a driven 300
miles I'll make it paid if you have the
powers to get onto a boat but if I say
guys I'm not diving today nobody gonna
question and the same in your
organization if somebody sticks their
hands up and say guys think something's
wrong here go investigate check it and
if it's nothing to beat and tell them
okay good thank you for telling us this
is not big because of that that and Dad
so next time you call something like
that think about those things if you
think you're still worried come back to
us so get those everyone
so don't ignore the little things and
then how do you train to respond in
dieting on the left-hand side that's how
you learn to scuba dive and do your mass
clearing you're on the bottom of the
pool
got two hands on your mask and you're
trying to blow in the mask to actually
get the F the water out of your mask
when you take diving on the left-hand
side we need to think about things
you've got a helmet you've got a line if
you lose the line and you can see you're
not going to know which way to go where
it's out of the cave so you need to grab
it you need to get the mask out with
your wife and swap it for another one
because your mask is obviously broken
and and you turn and you are suspended
in water you can't run on the bottom
because the seal just gonna cover things
so think about how we train when we do
Tyburn stance all you desktop best
exercises we go and meet people and they
talk how well they're prepared they we
told them about that exercise amount
I've had so obviously they don't they
homework but at least they've Secretary
done their homework and they've got all
the documents ready for the desktop
exercise one nice things that I i I've
seen before one of the consultants I
worked with before his way of checking
whether component can pick itself up and
whether the crisis team is up to his
scratch he waits for a planned fire
drill and after the pilot will teach up
shut up some soldiers of the crisis
management even say ok guys andhere's
that's you whatever you brought with you
we're taking a cue after and you now
recopied the company it's much harder to
do it and then that reminds me another
client that when I went there and done
an inspection whether they actually
prepared for any kind of physical crisis
they say don't worry about it every one
of our employees has a laptop if
something happens they can take those
laptops home we check we've got enough
licenses for them to connect remotely
they can do everything remotely ok so we
turn up a dog is at 6 a.m. the next
morning
what did we find laptops every single
desk how are you going to recover from a
burning building if your workstations
and how people connect remotely to your
work are on desks and people don't have
them it's not a strategy so train as it
is real life have fun talking about it
are you capable of responding 24/7 trust
add to one stage last year I learned I'm
not I went to Gaza to do my you know one
of my tape training septum few now and
on the first day of the course I had my
mask pulled off me and that's the first
time I think I felt like I may actually
die doing I felt like I'm being
waterboarded so that the thing about
trying to clear your mask especially
when somebody pulled off is that yeah
you can had water getting into your nose
and stuff like that if you had been on a
flight the previous night you only got
to your hotel at 3 a.m. in the morning
and européenne all are all born in
trainings other things didn't have lunch
and then you end up in water and in a
risky scenario I actually had to stop
that exercise and say guys no that's me
today or for this one put my start back
on but I was down on the bottom of the
cave and just say not no more today and
if you think about your responders you
know after I read some LinkedIn statuses
and is like all guys it's so hard being
a security guys we've been here or 5:00
a.m. or maybe 6 applaud it's so late and
we're still working and that's when
you're not being attacked and you
telling the word u.s. security board
somewhere out there wherever you are and
you're not hurt on a normal day do an
easy target
just somebody knocks you off a little
bit you don't have any strength to
defend yourself a normal shock analyst
can have a analyze something for about 5
to 6 hours there were studies done Matt
after that they either need to go home
get their pizza I've had a walk or
something like that so you are not able
to be ready 24/7 prepare your team's for
it an average person works 40 hours a
week Katie our team is organized around
it
okay yeah free time supplies timelines
lives timelines and statistics we talk
about statistics before so when you
trying to recover for magnitude and when
you're trying to do anything try to get
the right benchmarks I've been to so
many clients that say all we lose we
look at industry data the industry data
is telling us that and we also talk to
other people and they told us that
something like that is happening in
their environments and then I go to the
man cave so what is happening in your
company where is your data where is your
attack data where is the data that tells
me how many times you can breach how
many records you lost how many much
money your company lost at the back of
it it doesn't matter that you lost
you know maybe hundred records if you
lost hundred records in 2018 I want to
know what was the impact on that
organization I want to know what you've
done with that whether you learn
anything but keep it as a data point
somewhere and so many people try to look
outside the resolution at least half of
the world is inside your own
organizations analyzing what you got so
to summarize all that these are the
points that I covered it would be far
too easy that I just left it at that
you know it's yeah analyze the problems
you've got think how your company can
die and get start from there but that's
easy said how do we go about it some
lessons are quite old to be honest on
the left one of the best cave diving
groups ever Britain was beaten with 70s
40 years ago
feel as bad as them on the right a book
that was written in or release in 1936
and if you're a consultant I advise you
read I've been told about this book
eleven years ago I had not read it I
thought oh it's about cheating people no
it's not about cheating people it's
about how to be nice and understand
other people's perspectives and get to
understand them and help them so if you
try to help somebody with a security
guide consulting speaking to people I
will read it for the right reason just
because you want to understand other
people and the way they see the world so
and also we don't defensive side we are
not attacking anybody we not a business
trying to do something the reason that
myth that you need a strong leader
everywhere you need strong leader to
take you to the moon let's say you need
strong leader to be on the offensive
side to attack some money only defensive
side as I said before one person can
only cover you for 40 hours a week we
want a strong team of people helping
each other talking to each other if
you've got risks function near company
that audit function your company and
your security person don't go to the
business without speaking with those
guys if you go to the business and say
we need to do that
the risk person sells non-oil you surely
can't do that and the audit has a third
perspective and you expect the business
to be the responsible adult even that
they don't have a clue about security
you're doing it wrong go and speak to
everybody you can and go and build a
herd you know the team of people that
like to have fun but actually like to do
something interesting
[Music]
we need to get better and better
so in here it's me with a blindfold
trying to get myself out of a cave I
didn't know I get lost I need to find
the positions I aim
I can't just try to navigate it and wing
it because I'm a believer in a cave so I
need to ignore position I mean so you
practice harder and harder every time
you do something and you know at this
time I was going to tell you about the
final exercise I've been doing these two
people are applying for they're trying
to get out of the cave because we
simulate zero is that maybe there I'm
now running out of air I mean the head
means I don't have any more air we need
to find to get air from that guy and get
out I was going to say that if you
practice I'd let the crowd of people
like minded and that's why we have fun
with them insecurity in other things
you can do amazing stuff life actually
is better than that me planning it do
you remember the typo is getting stuck
in a cave last year there's 12 typos in
the code called stuck in the head and
one one guy that came to the rescue was
false those drawers Bradley
and that guy last week last Tuesday
never returned from the I was with the
bodies exploring some new caves they
came out he wasn't there we called 9-1-1
the cave rescue team came bound his
bodies couldn't get him they were
exhausted they didn't have air they were
and sitting up to go back in the cold
night one man and waited for them to
arrive 24 hours later those guys you
know are extracting the papers cooking
saying you know we know Josh if he got
into troubles he would try to get to the
safest place is in thyroid 24 hours in a
cave there is a place where he could
potentially have survived for 24 hours
but it's through some narrow and
dangerous passage and you know the
rescuers went into the cave at six eight
six o'clock in the afternoon 50 minutes
later that guy came out himself they
just kept in there he came out and just
asked for pizza and thank everybody
involved next day he was back in the
cave and it's because he practiced these
10,000 hours and harder than hard and
hard and environments he wasn't easy on
himself and he was having fun while he
was doing it it's not about being tough
on yourself if you're not having fun
what you're doing change jobs I really
advise it find the place where you enjoy
what you're doing
so get out to some ground things daily
you will that came strong but you can
help you recover from them that things
that are interesting and build ahead and
remember it's not about a leader when
you depend about building a strong team
that biggest top of the leader is to
find the right people for the team
so thanks very much now started an
initiative called cyber escapes together
I haven't started I'm not helping some
guys doing
that they started it I think is a great
initiative we couldn't go with that
forward
it's called cyber escapes we will get
like-minded people together to have some
fun explosive to it'll melt people sides
not just pen test not just crypto but
also some analyzing of data and actually
speaking to people as well you want to
link in with me
speaking of petaca that's my name proper
name call me ZB and that's my Twitter
handle so that's me thanks very much