em so we we've lost a few along the way
today but thank you all coming along and
just got a few wrap-up things one thank
you to everyone he went to chat to the
sponsors like I say they they do make
this happen so a thanks to the sponsors
we've still got a couple left
you know packing up their context
JPMorgan PwC pentest partners and
tenable basically paid for today papers
of any your catering and so on three of
the sponsors paid for some other bits
and pieces so the badges that you have
all made by the car hacking village guys
so mentor net built those if you're
interested they can turn into an obd2
scanner for your car and then if you
spoke to this stuff online so if your
than that you can find out how to do it
the components are relatively cheap
there's this online instruction so they
can talk to your car your car can talk
to it you can make your car turn into a
brick and never drive again if you're
interested I love people were set at a
lot picking village all day brilliant
you know that's always a good fun thing
to do you keep speaking to them if
you're interested there's a lot of stuff
they do up and down the country and
globally
they're really good ones huge thank you
to our speakers you know again without
them the day is kind of pointless so a
lot of us traveled fairly far it's been
good having them in here we've had some
excellent talks a huge thank you to the
guys in red t-shirts because because you
know they've kind of helped out all day
to make sure this works and broadly
speaking it has there's been your glitch
along the way and we've got it sorted so
thank you guys for giving up your entire
day for no money and only a very small
amount of boots which is which is pretty
small the after party for those of you
who are gonna be taking part in the
capture the flag you want to get across
to the venue by six ish so that you can
get checked in and so did for everybody
else we want to go there after party
turn up there from about 7:00 you're
still getting it's just you wouldn't be
part of the competition which is fine
next year we're aiming to be back in
Glasgow so we'll keep alternating the
only other thing to say is we need to
get yanked appear reasonably quickly the
guys in the venue you're going to set up
for tomorrow's event that they've got
going
so what it suggests is if you've got
chats if you can head out and in fact
wandering up towards the venue on
Chambers Street is probably a good idea
if you wanted to go for drinks and so on
but if you can leave reasonably fast
we're going to be tidying up behind you
so that would help beside a lot aside
from that just thank you to everybody
for making the day go well and hopefully
avoid a good