to talk about the top 10 web hacking
techniques a 2014
everyone a
I mean you've seen a version of this
talk before thought they were
producers you don't know you were
articles
so a because you don't know either bus
we
a matter hinton and the newseum Michael
yeah we're good I'm so a matter it soon
I'm
directors your service is over whitehat
security
I'm Jonathan I'm a manager for the
research center
my head up are you operations in the UK
shorter flights
yes more lively is underway so because
you haven't seen this before
on inaudible clicker thing you know
you're so
good just in with taxes you pay homage
to you
I just a crazy amount of wave
application research that goes on
throughout the year just turned you know
squishy 21 talk
most things better on our on our list
are have their own hour-long talk a
is a new in this room that has something
on this list you know about between us
to use
some other people on this list there
from you so weapon or no
article what is your name you don't know
on this list for something
work about years for
you know doctor a we've been doing this
every year for about
a nine years or so so on this is the
kennedy
away where a for
and for to
how this works me take submissions from
the community
for you know best new research
techniques
year right opening wat
I'm here you know anywhere from you
alone your last year
130 see total submissions
and what happens then is there's a
Nouveau
back a narrows that down to top 50
and we take top 50 I love three experts
like Troy
was just duty you know his honor here
and
panel expert now is that 15 down to list
top ten Alps resort in tone
right so we can see if I whose names
have
attack whether techniques a
for use in we cease we've heard taking
over there
things lot every year with you know he
pours
him crime
I am in last year mutation XSS a
takeover top slot for by merrier talk
later today
K yes access their
top spot again but three top five worst
on corruption-related so people still
really like incursion
I so without further ado I guess
make things up it
same here
on better okay cool
better sorry a
to a no further ado I guess right here's
the
the the top 10 if this year creditors
purchase King again
right helping any research surprise that
sharply take number one heroes
a it was probably the most echo chamber
escaping
web ap thing to happen in the last
decade
right I you know you know it's bad when
like your parents are calling you and
saying hey should I be worried about
this I saw it on the news right that's a
matter you know okay
something serious going on right and so
based on a review is
we have nowhere near enough time in 45
years
talk about I'll tell if these so we're
going to try to give you the
right just a fly through love I 10 36
and they're kinda deep dive into you
top 5 will be more pressure cool so
starting the return we have
covert timing channels now cover time
channels essentially a side-channel
attack
or a timing attack where the measuring
up how long it takes in the process
instructions
may provide what issues are within
privileged information this particular
research
I was covering various issue to be cash
others the time that was required to
infer
data were either cash non-cash so they
look at the last modified in the tag
response headers request headers
denounces
online if one fights and stuff on
modified since this magic non-merch
and a strange on one heavy math going on
here but they made our top 10 list
that was actually the interesting thing
about number 10 those the first time we
ever saw someone campaign to try to get
onto
are but unless they actually put on
slide deck on slide scared said
this is why you should vote for us to do
without them once they get to work
together
so I number nine this ones kinda
interesting case it was
you know the distribute down service
isn't exactly new technique prep but the
avenue of attack was certainly unique I
this researcher actually was able to put
the
the DoS attack with in facebook notes
like the Notes application part
Facebook there a largely should be get
flood so the dust jacket actually
originating from facebook da cops those
pretty interesting
number eight we have a remote code
execution for strikes to you
as a nice dress is your day resulting in
the manipulation of the class loader
and it being able to like this with
public execution
so what you do is you would pass the
class to class loader commands
as a parameter to add on action resource
and then
pretty much it would run whatever could
you want to so
funny thing about this is that the
original six was to you
cinderblock class to class loader over
you can convert that to you
bracket notation easily bypass the first
one to fix that
and then again they weren't checking
case sensitivity
so class be da class later portion can
be lowered his ERA Perkasie
so once again the lebanese back open
back up again um
eventually this text and read at the
bottom is what needed to be added to the
exclude grams portion stress to you
in order to you to sleep excitability
this guy got
I think three total CDs are able to get
to see the
every time they fixed it but not good
enough for many resubmit it was a new CV
any reason that it got a new CD the
three CDs in the same bug repellents
that was pretty cool
arts number seven Google to factor of
bypass this one was kinda just
this this was another unique when the
middle is this yours is an attribute it
to anyone
actual researcher at this is Anonymous
hacker rate but this one again made the
made the news in time and I we you know
we decided to
to still let a qualified to be on the
list and I'm glad we did because I got
voted
you know pretty high up as this was just
an overall
the man we saw these two factor of
bypasses more
I you know this SJ uptick in the past
year
specifically targeting people like
journalists who were starting to use to
factor of which is of course
a great thing right you know finally our
we're getting journalists to
used you for dropping their social media
accounts things like that but we also
saw them get
you know bit pretty hard if they were
able to bypass and
the one that actually the post that
stirred up a bunch in
had an article in Wired knows her stuff
but was the reason that made the list
was
on the bypass is actually through the
cell phone
carrier providers they're actually
social engineer your call the cell phone
provider
and social engineer their way into you I
adding a
call forwarding and text forwarding
number to the account and so
I if they were using tax sms-based to
factor of
and there were some sort of SMS
forwarding going on they were able to
to steal the token bypassed so
number six attacking people against one
click this is essentially
a just a qualified ceaser and I'm really
happy to sit on it is the first time
that a bug bounty one single but money
is made our list
typically the new hacking methodologies
but the songs it's really cool
because I'm basically we got Charlie
found here is that when making a
authenticated request to pay pal and
stripping the
such an credentials or a authentication
tokens
you be redirected to a warning page okay
now
Cesar protection was in place for this
particular app however they're not
regenerating
Cesar tokens so what you had it once you
have it for that particular user
we found is that if you put in a victims
email address
so you have a nude pic and email address
the targeted attack any false password
submit the form in the response the
ceasar token that was generated was not
associated to that particular account
so what you have that one token then
everything within the constraints at
Caesars are applicable in this changes
along with same token because the app
was not regenerating it
um this is because the person I've ever
seen a way for you to like
the session to the this is our cooking
was tied with your account with
YOURUSERNAME
for some reason the reasons think um
and they ordered him a ten thousand
dollar
by many for the some really busy but
many make this top 10 list about
Benihana myself so
pierce the sky yeah that that's user
doing what you do absolutely anything to
let people carry itself
research project okay number five really
get to the
detect here I so as did anyone here but
this one didn't see this talk
the last year this misfortune cookie
research
to some because research this is
probably my favorite wanna last so
given no its not number one this is this
was close to my heart so
I these researchers were able to
to I actually attacked residential
gateway routers
a with a single HTTP request and the way
they went about his recall if you're
interested I'm gonna give you a rundown
if you're interested go watch the full
talking about the best talk but I saw
last year
on up here did sorry so
the just a little bit background what
you need to know to actually understand
this attack
these are things that I don't really
have a full grasp on I also have you
heard in this city are 69
this was new to me yeah it's new to most
to do to you few
okay so I what this is this came out
this
the this is the protocol misused or
abused you know they're
a which it came out in 2004
and and really what this I is is the
I is also known as the CPE way and
management protocol
right so CPE is consumer premises
equipment right so this is how
your Internet Service Providers are I
accessing your home routers and doing
something right ever call your ISP
and say hey something's not working at
all so in a sense answer to reset
Odin you know it power cycles your
device at home
this is the protocols being used their
right so these researchers with that
said hey that seems
it seems pretty powerful read the
there's a lot of power
going on with the ice the hazards
control your device in your per
Prem right so what's going on here and
so what is going on is there's
this auto configuration server as ACS
server
that the ice teas used to have some
semblance a
you know do authentication meaning you
know the ISP knows that you're actually
the consumer that started talking to
consumer knows that
you're actually I speeders trying to
talk to you in there some yes a
back-and-forth communication there
on but like I said this was written in
2004 and
this protocol actually just uses I so
RTC
which is just acceleration EP ratso
a you know this is when hackers dream
rate okay cool so to see a chippy
it's got control over the home router I
okay and
this ACS's the all powerful device that
we're going to worry about right so
a look at this said that's a single
point of failure I'm going to focus on
listed do my research track so it did a
little digging
and the notice that this protocol uses
port a
7547 an do is more digging
and I looking at research from I think
this is University of Michigan
when they scan the entire internet this
port is actually the second most common
port open on the entire
entered besides course eighty rate and
so
you know cases widely prevalent there's
no single point of failure again this
the stream just keep getting better
I so that this was the
this was a scan about 2.8 1,000,000
devices is this an okay peace
extrapolate this over crossed
you know this number for consumers is
correct for the entire internet I have
the actually didn't have to assume
because rapid7 actually did a scan the
entire internet
I later after they started the research
and the numbers actually worse than this
is 1.18 percent
so 46 million I had two devices
at this port open okay so what's on the
sport was running on a sport
so this is a breakdown a the technology
running on this open port that is open
on you know 1.18 percent of the entire
internet
I and so again as as researchers were
you noted on
yet big choke up I over there I
rampaging
so fifty percent love these open ports
were running Ron Peters
I've done a little bit deeper said okay
what
versions a rampage or are there what you
know what kinda person to this code do I
need to act on an ordered if I want to
take advantage
summers of our her death at ninety the
plus per se above the ROM pager
versions that are out there for all
running the same version and want to get
away
year that version was written don't
wanna
no Thad be a dispirited 1980
a know is actually two doesn't even a
so their really up to date version of
the software was roughly seven versions
behind
am's you know ninety-eight percent
back 52 percent love one
percent in June percentages backs up to
ten devices
a running the same version that's old
version
love rounded so it's gonna operated rats
that's kinda the breakdown of
what's going on why we care so a
this from pager version you on router
firmware
I these researchers the Sighthill expose
the stuff this specific version is it
everywhere
I you pretty quickly they were able to
cross the router
right page with Sony should be headed by
using the added the Authorization header
I near Cooper quick guide issues new
browner and 600 ace
and
in their router crashed the problem was
that there was no debug interface
for this router whatsoever so they can
really get a core dump in
kinda you do all the cool things this
area figure out what can overflow
situation they had
right but offers you familiar with this
kind of research this is the
bit ago was notable there unprotected
stream copy
a surged that their for a quick so
on this is I this is brother cause
partners talk
%uh these guys gave I'm since there was
no debugger available
that they couldn't get the cord open
couldn't figure out what they did to
crash the router
they actually opened up the router and
soldered into the motherboard and then
wrote their own debugger
which is the most accurate thing I've
ever heard a
which is awesome and then a on to make
even more awesome than a bit short on
freebie Power Ranger fairness I a bit
support document their record stands for
but it is called the answer
a so this is what they're the open their
debugger
once they crashed the router is what it
looked like and here you can see
instruction pointer up
top and be really okay when it's over at
the instruction pointer it is nasty
sectors router
I problem was this wasn't reliably
a exploded all over the internet because
even though it was the same Bergeron P
do so prevalent
a the memory stacks depending on which
firmware
was using which devices using I was a
lil bit different so you can reliably
exploit this
you know this exact point memory that
you would need so they had to take a
little bit further
I well run Peter happens to use cookies
a
near for infinite valuable reasons
pro so but the the way that there there
could be either way it out
a is is pretty interesting so they have
a pre allocated
you know namespace it's really just c0
c1 c2
whatever and that array is actually
pretty allocated memory
snow across devices they don't need to
worry about the different memories to
is this this terrific is reallocated to
know exactly where it goes
I in the infinite wisdom
around pager the the corner memory that
was
what was used was just strip the sea
of Albuquerque it's certainly a $50,000
that was the border 0
right cool I so that made it into the z4
these ghost few to just the you know
rights in which is confusing
completely just remote code execution
always right
so your speech on the bottom with just a
benign example
rights if you just change the name to
the beach is Ian and whatever you want
the instruction pointer to be
on better start report urges change in
happened to you
oh my god the tax right to substitute
past few when you're trying to be a few
something
an average is redirect the browser to
you this
you know the slash whatever it so this
was the only
and start reporter that actually put in
their talk
I think because the other ones are too
scary I'll
on stage they didn't show the actual
array of cookies to be used
but I just with setting it was three
cookies
there ever completely bypass
authentication the router
could flash the firmware if they wanted
to do whatever the heck they wanna
rights
so again this is from residential
gateway routers this owned
all the computers behind a you know the
tire neighborhood
I think their ways 189 countries in some
countries over half
the IP addresses were gonna put the
Bears so it was not a small bug
I'll and this is usually the slide rice
A
and here's the world warm and fuzzy part
of why shouldn't be worried but this one
I don't have a warm and fuzzy I'm sorry
I were fuzzy for this room is you can
if you're using a mobile device you can
flasher firmware frightened people in
this room probably can't figure out how
to flash the firmware
but a don't give you know ground on my
phone number when you tried ur
water three flashing her firmware or and
I'm not to hold my breath for my ISP
updates any of their advice is that they
have throughout a
your residence where is this was kinda
scary but this geyser
maintaining a list
viable devices there for want to check
it out
okay it's moving on before we have the
Rosetta flashtool
this mean a lot headlines last year is
anyone familiar with this money chance
her to present a flush
couple people school is he in the room
yeah it is
good fantastic so he's got a much more
in-depth talk about this I believe that
today yes a deadly got into the deep
dive we're not gonna do it just as much
a skimming over it
a.m. congrat yeah that being said
a so what this is the tool that he
created to convert to binary swift into
a non alphanumeric swift they can then
be executed on a target them inside
using Jason P so
two things that are there will have with
no interruptions
yet the I as you have some binders worth
every instance like minor garbage before
and
is tall essentially users have been
going to you act as a result is some to
translate that information into
readable alphanumeric text is awesome to
the jason B
so many hackers and I'm like I can
around the Zags on the response came
back with a call back
yes was it all over the place so Jason
px thats X
that accepts a call that parameter a
value berkes
it is the largest cities even underscore
any period so although there's a little
bit but
in the collision place you can't as a
binary and but because I was looking at
work
but if we take this with file and
converted to you just alphanumeric ce
with those allowed character sets we can
foresee some P to execute the Swiss as a
toasted on a target domain
now just a couple sites for using this
or are using this
Google Yahoo LinkedIn and Twitter get
your
and was a Google it's not like some
third-party acquisitions
acquire two months ago its dub dub dub
Dubble accounts like Google Maps I cool
like all the duties of
so here we have just
brief overview again love the research
is going to later arms a minor breakdown
among us with better
now here we've gotten impressed with the
liberal press and hold him a compressed
worse
for the purpose of this research we're
just gonna purpose per are focus on the
New Zealand compressor
is due to the fact that he was able to
brute force the other 30 to check some
into the data the verify the integrity
that
you love data section the almost over
the magic by to you the term which
version is
then version following and then breakup
a
depending on which typeof congressional
no russian issues after that
so result of what has been used and that
I could make you took encoders
in order to map non-oil bites to you
about it because we have a lot more
in the character set binary trash if you
will
then just other numerics with a special
characters so
not I'm going all the talking with you
will he doesn't
sadly but the Waste King dollar girl
characters for the first few bites here
as well as the other thing to check some
is cannibals in the matter he does it
ties into you
1530 yeah with a again
this is the pic on to be generated so
just small ActionScript right there left
this is how would convert into bombing
of an American version
and then you can exploit that put into
this right here
comes with bosnian bedded on an attacker
control domain
using the content-type content type
forcing object tag so you can see the
rainfall mobile doc on
in the attribute value for data and then
down there the bottom
in the preamble use for flashvars we
have people will say the words i cant
use the chase on the call back
as well as attacker host are supplied
resource if you will to log data the
money trail through it
now medications for us
one you could just not used it will be
at all or sandbox that particular
information of
on to the weekend with headers a we can
take on the disposition
attachment file name: which is going to
then don't know that's what phone
surrender at
under in the browser you can also change
X button type options
know stuff or at rather because then I'm
as long as the response center doesn't
come back with a shockwave flash
you're looking to go after changes on
application
a JavaScript then it's not going to fire
as belted swift also
the quick-fix if you will it's just sad
the block comments section daniel green
text
from the call back images on is what
Google's would get a Twitter all they
were doing to you
remediate this very simply so if you're
actually I can around the scene is now
in a comic responses
then that's basically what's coming from
it's a defense to reserve
attack is that in your that still your
Twitter via
slash thirst for success but for
Southern Miss Twitter bio
for for a while yeah China's
its that's fair there okay cool
so yeah we we flew through the actresses
here
you can SC that occurred the bladder so
okay number three we have put also this
was the
the year the branded vulnerability rate
if your gonna believe in the marketing
team then
sucks for you here's these guys did and
so they got on the news
a so everyone heard %uh pool right and
there is on the brutal and there is
likely to bleed or something like that
there's all sorts appears as a verse
that bike
you know just kept rearing its ugly
brutal head a
but its kinda go into what made pool
I what it was right why is everyone so
scared so for
you know we we had to leave the slide
and you know usually we give this talk
to you
you know not necessarily a full app sec
drought-stricken after you know
here what's SSL ratso a cell's magic
and a your attic somewhere
for the road switches it with a key
where's Troy base64 encryptor 2003
another area and the
the USA for tax record that somebody
cracker
the survey 64 attendance record it so
okay XO
I your just quick rundown vivo version
addresses also
the mobile version has a cell for pool
was a SSL version
3 I'll play my favorite game talk what
year did so.
3 about anyone forget
where is it well you know what up the
Niners yeah
moves closer your I he was 96 98
writer came in a long time ago right I
till
TLS replaced it in in the nineties and
anti lost 1.2
came out he doesn t retrieving dealers
1.2 is stills
you real ratso a servers and three as
the problem on a version that
a is going on so ready to be a history
lesson on how that how that works right
so so you have some issue P request
thread
that sensor data the first thing that
happens SLP three is there is going to
be a Mac added to the end that perhaps
so this is just the
to
as make sure the sensor data and hoping
tamper-proof
it's basically checks on for for this I
for tax rate is an actress and check out
the request fails
and it's letting you know that was
tampered with right
and then the after the Mac it's added we
have some padding to get at it so
pat is gonna vary in size depending on
what I prescription you're using if
you're using
%ah wasn't DES is any bid it's gonna be
a month will be bitten
Eske sixteen-bit so
I yeah because patting on here pat is
important for
for this tax cut away going through this
so with the
last character patty is actually the
magic won writes the last character
outing with that does actually tell you
the sizeof the paddock rights that's
gonna say okay how far back
do I need to go on depicting this to get
the Mac Mini validate Mac in the
negative sense
be right so this whole pay I with the
padding the Mac said today to get sick
repeated
in Sobe three using the second block
chaining other
a which also was prepared for the ball
by which one was a primer
Easter them Prime Minister whatever
I so this was this yeah this is also
available
are afraid so there's one in many ways
or so outside watching works is easy I
think this whole blood
to break it up into you two groups and
going to %um
exclusive for them all it online right
to this is the encryption work this way
de Kirchner works that way I missus
history lesson sorry yes right so a if
the
decryption work backwards number that a
that that important characters that last
one tell you how long the padding is
tell you how far you need to go back
knowledge Mac that's important in this
attack
because I back failing and actually
dropping the request is what helps the
attacker
iterative talent is going to be able to
I
the stealing actual sensor data raped
so if say yes attacker man middling you
I N
you're on SLV free connection with the
attackers going to do
gonna take some wanna the CBC blocks
from the sensitive data so some early on
CBC block to copy it and pasted over
the and up at so
as we remember about that last character
being important
is going over right that last pair so
most the time what's gonna happen here
is that this request is going to drop
right back the overriding
adding that means that the length
characters wrong and you go back to the
Mac
I the Mac check fails and then the
connection
just drops right by about one in every
two hundred and fifty six times
I just kinda looks out stars align
and the length is right and we're all
good
connection is fine right so
if the attacker erase the same with Mike
JavaScript or something
you know just a ton of these requests
and I
keeps just copying pasting is over what
this allows them to do
is each time that they get that right
they know that that last character
they know that last character is as part
of that CBC block which is in cryptic
said today
right and so if they keep doing this
10,000 times
they're going to be able to get a few
characters I sensitive data
right so everyone said okay well what's
you know what's the worry just don't let
someone do couple thousand question
even then it's just a few characters at
a time what's the what's the problem
right
well the session cookies are and always
that long
right so that's the kind of thing to
worry about and they're also
predictably located you know early in
the sensitive data rates may know where
that is
so being apart a session token was you
know
feasible us this is the kind of thing
that we were we were
you know word about terrorist attack
I'll so
the fix is a pretty pretty simple and
kinda silly to say this conference so
I it's just don't use the you know one
of the oldest versions as a sell out
there
I just you're completely disable that of
course they're gonna lose some
Explorer 6 users to your website so
I personally say sorry bike I figured
out
I or a yeah a
if you are absolutely forced to use you
know to leave SSL version 3 enable their
website
I due to some customer base somewhere
being unable to upgrade their browsers I
you can
you can know disable the CBC a outer
them and use a different one
which will leave you vulnerable to other
things but we'll fix brutal a
and yeah that's contributed once I know
to the sun's kinda funny
because a in October last year Microsoft
submit a patch to you I sexism actually
allow you to enable TLS version 1.0 on
it
be sought to go into like all your
kitchen settings to specifically enable
it
and users are using a 6-2 prickly don't
even care whether it's important to use
a particular virginity loss just
if you're if you're using a6 you know
where the settings are
herbert a good the number two
we're moving on to shell-shocked Wilson
is best or so lucky said use the euro
branded phone abilities
on in shock came out for a couple weeks
afterwards everyone thought that you
know it's kind it was gonna take over
and this is how I like
the AI apocalypse come two starts behind
a turtle apocalypse
yet so it's extremely extremely easy to
exploit
its like on a scale of one to 10 10
being the easiest it's a 10
on he's to exploit the severity of it is
also a 10 because
from a good execution one can argue that
exploiting this is probably easier to do
than explaining it to someone
it's that that awesome from a single
request
single and I think request over the web
remotely your
reported back with a shell which as we
all know it's game over so
just going to a quick example when it
first came out around a raw a
gray gotta follow on Twitter he did a
lot to be done is it seems that came out
it does open source talk of mask which
people may or may not use for
your force purposes insulated air was
select a target IP range
to scan the internet with our weather
reports and
in his user-agent: cookies hose refer
headers on request
hatter's he just admitted in object
reference we're going to you later
and in a pink a minute to King back to
him so would you expect to see
if you scan the internet with all this
information and the shell-shocked by was
active
we're gonna call home he gonna pin you
back
now although that's not really hacked if
you will
I mean yeah it is but we believe that
this is the right thing in back and this
is from a quick a quick scan
like this could probably happen with the
first 30 seconds scare how are you
following me on Twitter how many people
saw this happen
life just a few you sure you got a good
100 new this is the I gotta follow this
is
this was within hours hoof shots are
coming out
right so this was kinda oh crap that's
real where
with a lot of things pain is sir so
others nothing to troubling about the
skin pingback: an open the question
why did the serving us back and how was
the ping command actually executed
now again look as real as emblem I can
go to
to detail into it back in a time before
we had pretty user interfaces everything
was done by the Commission
you know it allows us to do you ask
questions like what's going on in Crete
files list contents to the processes
delete everything on my hard drive just
I'm sure in just like the characters
with because you know everyone stories
um this is where the shot budgets the
vulnerability lies in being able to
arbitrarily defined environment variable
which specifies function definition
spaces like me into action
what's gonna happen here is that after
that last
curly brace on me and bass is going to
continue executing code as if it were
syntax
not strict now in the sense that the web
bash is extremely widely used about 50
percent I love
servers what times at this time or
Apache an Apache will process CGI
scripts
CDS get a process in bash so just making
a request to it and it's analyzing
you know the referrer header or the
user-agent if your injection is in one
of those places
coding execute just by making requested
so now the next question is
a him how you know season runs
destruction exact exactly that
we know the tricks metaphysically typing
the command you've got programs
ABCDE any that are all talking smaller
programs
FGH I et cetera because we do as
developers you
Center rewriting new programs you use
was already out there likable person
file
I'm not going to write the pressures of
unease autographed or something sorry
like that
a lot of these use the bash shell to
talk to each other
in the background now
this that the purpose of this is that
it's not limited just web servers
you know into things devices anything
that's running the best sellers can be
vulnerable to this
if you have an autonomous wifi-enabled
dog feeder at home
it can be part of the dash or best or
about it
few of or like all those who serve for
life exactly what that something all
these on my computer was Muslim a
processing batch much is extremely low
extremely old it's widely used its well
adopted
away reply whatever game
when I'll oh yeah I hollow shell shocked
but around
that 25 years this month for pool 25
years rate so
I we can actually the the other five are
not so sorry we can actually go and and
and look at that thread
where the the researcher like disclosed
a and he here here's a really quite
grasp the seriousness
vignette is gonna says hey I think I
found something in him
think it's been around a really long
time
and the yeah understatement and the
security of the decade rate
also might want my new favorite t-shirt
is my user agent is in this bitch also
exploit that actually patches
shell-shocked
those as the because that's what I saw
okay run the command but
the patches itself to be the best were
matter the
would be awesome to see select whoever
finds an extra good execution
it's very legal with the paths there's
but
Infinite PC maker okay cool so that's
also extremely easy to exploit
extremely easy to implement and cause a
lot of problems in the game
summit in a number one as I just
pursuant to is hardly
another brain affordability another game
over we thought the world was going to
end
table on couple weeks go by in obviously
the world's leader
no hardly does little bit different come
it does share seriousness with
shell-shocked in
helps appearance its are really easy to
exploit not as easy as shocked it just
looks good getting a bit better
what's going on here is in the open as a
sole
protocol there is a model called
heartbeat the architects engine
and with the heartbeat extension does is
it stops you from having have multiple
simultaneous Steelers connections
going up same time because once you make
a request to a server over SSL
the person happens until a singer she
Asian face you know the exchange keys
they
talk to each other and a there's a lot
of overhead by having multiple tillis
sections ones like a packet drops
at Sarah and will get lighter in a
moment
so disrespectful background use internet
gossip the six
a again but this time but same time shot
came out but have the servers up there
where
Apache with engine exploding on the rise
now merger
active sites skin like %uh this is
Microsoft I a server was a third miscues
but these Microsoft s channel
implementation
up in a soul which is not normal her
bleed and doesn't mean that if you're
using a server that everything's gonna
be fine because you could still be using
like an engine EXR it's a proxy load
balancer
between we had a ton of our client a
review worldwide at those risk and
website abilities are it so we
you know we were letting customers know
about this whole body and
a tournament he said wall no thats you
know that's
are load balancer that's not us can you
get this off my report
you know we have like an order coming in
like no
we care for their comfort for it but I
don't know call more times to your load
what the company I don't that's my
remediation guidance red
so here's the problem you know a little
bit just
introductory static analysis with Linus
and it's funny this
I believe this push this commit happened
like at eleven o'clock on New Year's
for like 2012 service models probably
interested in
like leaving going to drink or something
with so yeah Justin secure
memory allocation here payload was
padding is taken from using but
no bounce checks the restraints so we
have user input making it directly into
the batter
now with this does is this makes the
size the heartbeat response control
a bird's at 64 kilobytes of memory now
so again what happened sir would like an
emblem a ramble about earlier
the First Nation make your website over
HTTPS a TLS handshake
negotiations is going to occur they're
going to negotiate keys are you say hey
I'm client on the server how you Dewin
them jealous connections made now if you
have like
dropped packet or a little lag or you
close your browser
tab for some reason really my cup a new
tell us connection is going to be made
you can have multiple he is happening at
the same time so that does that creates
a lot of overhead
what overhead its computationally
expensive so the heartbeat
extension was made now with the
heartbeat and as with much little
overhead
much less overhead basic will you know
details connections to life
so you can have your quest response
comes back recibe la response comes back
rather
yes you know the clan still there keep
the law such an act now
the heart be requesting to contain some
work was there we've got a payload
and then decides that the these are all
both user controlled values
for an attacker to exploit this the
request is crafted the contains a little
bit the data
the payload inside the request which we
would craft to be arbitrarily large
because given special values through
that one but a similar bill
now there is only sending one bite and
actual information:
we're gonna say the size 65536
its someone going to anything this
request no circus side
was gonna happen server memory is that
this information is going to be cached
and then you see the in black there P
which is the only one bite that I sent
and the rest that random data is
something within the memory bounds but
64 kilobytes when the keepalive response
occurs
the payload that same size along with
whatever's memories can be returned back
and that's it that's all Hartley was
you can do this by sending an ominous Rd
request you don't have to be
authenticated
not be logged in the server just has to
be running the ball mobile version
have open SSL and I forget which side it
was but someone ran a contest as soon as
came out because
of taking off in its a patch and the
contest was like show us our
as Okies and I forget who got it but
and when to come in like 45 hours it was
still billions on request
it was a limit on request because you
can get a random arbitrary peace memory
here
and that can contain all kinds of stuff
it can contain user-submitted
data now the tokens cookies passwords
credit card information
anything that unlike up a normal post
request could be cash in memory
and because this can take some random
data into something request over and
over again
you get back to 64 kilobytes with
information and then just like a police
pieced them all together
more importantly you can get the keys to
encrypt and decrypt traffic from the
server so if you happen to be
logging information you can go back and
then use those keys to do
the crypt it perfect for secrecy is not
enabled no other is protection baked and
SSL not everyone is
and that's it those are hardly so
the you know what I'm before we get to
are lessons later the hell you know
harpley also the reason is number one is
that
it you know it's now the barometer right
it's like
the it is it as bad as sharply right we
just saw something come out yesterday
I'm what was the worst thing ruthlessly
years ago
logjam to watch it now but need your
small
newtie Les Paul and and the broader is
wallace's Bazaar blue
pratt was like what all the the
reporters are asking for but that's of
course
of course I will make them run the other
really scary thing is completely
untraceable
if you if you got attacked great so he
said her resume compromise in
and you know assume your SSL keyser were
stolen if you were available to any
point
and then redo them in how many people do
we think that that
right so a yeah I'm gonna go with not
that many
okay show I like the little less than
where I so encryption is king
a that's kinda what I said at the
beginning and I saying that the end here
you know even though was in the top back
last year you know it's it's it's just
widely respected research the a lot of
times encryption research things like
crime in Beeston
you know we saw the bulldozers on the
past take
a very serious level have knowledge
about encryption
right like you know Year's Eve a you
most the
the researchers from University of
London from PhD candidates right so
all the community just wildly Respir
respecting corruption research into
makes makes the list every year
your prices more more important I these
days as we see all sorts of crazy
government things going on writer
creativity is also something that's
really
really highly respected right so for
anybody who saw this talk
last year was one more creative bug you
ever saw was a pixel perfect timing bird
on was using so many scene 05
video being SPG attacked you
completely bypass same origin policy
greater
right so really creative stuff in and
this year we we we see it once again
which is you know things like
shell-shocked better up to twenty-five
years
so much looked at something that's been
around a long and is used in a way
was must be used to it so shocked
twenty-five years heart bleed was an
implementation are from two years ago
a slow version three years 1998
it's down to attack us to love on from
1998 software so
so that you know if this takes
creativity isn't a book smarts the
stakes looking at something with
you've been on your nose for a really
long time and figure out how to
you know completely on the Internet with
their
and then yeah just overall webster to
prevails look at this conference are
those movies conferences
absecon you have secure say they're just
grown every year whatever you do see
any sort of security news escape the
echo chamber
security and get on till like actual
your news web sites like see a real
quick that
it's always website of its always like
someone got back to a sequel injection
somebody
you know got back to be awesome website
some social media
account got popped in the stock market
dropped immediately your support that is
ridiculous rate it
all web security right so I you guys are
the right conference to learn about I'll
learn a lot about this stuff so is right
bank are
panel experts Troy is here gotta
buy him a beer and just banks to anyone
if any viewer
have submitted anything when we do hope
in this community
aggravation every search in any devoted
to narrow down top 15 thank you guys I
now you as well herded I'm holding you
all to it next year
to submit and growth I just think the
the researchers to
a you know just continue to do mind
blowing stuff
I like our Jason P friend over here I
good check out later and other
researchers the rest the day this this
you know it's the rich we're all here so
bass test
your time QNX run a little late so will
be around the cover sexy day so
to strike down dip