us
think everyone and thank you for joining
me this morning
in the next 45 minutes
I will talk a little bit about and sum
up the No Jia
node.js vulnerability basically a check
mark
and the City of check marks a check
marks reduce orkut analysis
to find on abilities in your code part
of the research is actually looking for
von abilities or other research papers
is
so we can introduce them into our
product and in this presentation we
would like to share with you some of the
interesting aspect love
node.js security which I hope you will
find also
as interesting as I did a for those of
you who were at my
my previous presentations you you may
know that the relief
I'm a great fan of live demos they
really hate to be the recordings at the
downside
love live demos is that they might break
in real time so
bear with me if something like that
happens so that gender for today's
presentation
is as follows: first double will
describe a little be the architectural
node.js
they believe that since you're sitting
in that room most if you are already
familiar with that
but just to make sure we're all on the
same page I will describe a little bit
how no GS
and works behind the scenes its it will
be from short we will describe some of
the denial of services
that and attacks that can be
exploited for node.js we'll talk a
little bit about
the crypto grew fueled with them with
the node.js the Jason
part of node.js Jason is really
fundamental within OJ's
but it brings a whole set of my ability
with we'll be talking about
regular expression in our service and
finally about and I'll describe
trace least throating hijacking which is
very interesting topic in my mind
so very briefly both know Jess
Architektur
so no G et node.js isn't event driven
single-threaded and non-blocking i/o
which is built on top of chrome
from %um projects v8 engine what does it
mean
event-driven so I like for example this
is the code
BC the code let me just turn it off
yeah
okay so that's the code and that
so for example the this is the code that
to find if the specific follow is larger
than 1 megabyte
inside so I like other languages like
dot net and Java where you do
find file and if size greater than one
megabyte do something
in that case actually working with
called back
recall the filesystem exist function we
send this task
for different thread in with all the
system once you find if the file exists
call or call back function okay the one
that appears
writing year once you've found the file
a
give me this time the statistics of that
file once again the statistics
call back my call back function so it's
not
a leaner execution but rather a lot of
call back back and forth looking at the
at the architecture basically there is
an event queue
each event all the events are cute in a
single
cue and it's important that single cue
Thursday event loop
that the grub each day a single event
from the queue
and executed in on a single thread just
a single thread
in case the action
and izzle is an is denial action
action that takes a lot of time but not
from the CPU but
other devices the action is
sent to a different thread so for
example in this is Tim wants to read if
I'll
doesn't happen on the main thread
because it will block all other
activities it is sent to a different
I O thread a so this concept mean that
there is a single thread
which is very sensitive because once
this thread is running
nothing health gonna happen in this
thread basically dispatcher's request
the oh I obon request to other
and
other threads okay and want me these
threats complete
the trigger and a call back function the
push it into the event queue
so in due time it will also get executed
and so the fact that no GST
event even driven single-threaded it
means that on the one hand
the benefit is there is no context
switching a single thread
no context switching works very very
fast this secure doesn't have to wait
for an i/o action to complete
just send the style action to a
different thread
and then starts doing the next action so
it works well for i/o intensive
applications and web app
it doesn't work well for CPU intensive
applications so if you have a CPU
intensive application I just doesn't
work well
will see that in a moment and so let's
take a look on this
am kind of I CPU intensive code
this code looks for the sum all the
numbers between one to p for example if
you want to find the sum up the numbers
one and
plus two plus three plus 4.5 there is a
No
J supplication which that the following
other see this can improve but they just
want to show
something that is CPU intensive so let
me long to that
just to mean sea consider look at so if
people's five we get 15 if we do 10 we
get 55
okay that's easy know what we gonna do
is the following
a blessed system K
123 123 a
and they will also show you the task
manager over here
okay and so what I'm gonna do
I will send the request to compute the
numbers between one and 100 million
it is this very CPU intensive activity
and during that time no GS
will persist no other requests besides
this
the current one so let me hit enter okay
let me just another 0 here okay as you
can
might be able to see the known taking
25 percent of my CPU they have I have
four cores and 50 runs
single threaded on a single core so
basically takes the entire
25 percent particular out is the low to
take
let me run that okay
and during the time another user wants
to come the summer between
one in 100 latte but the
other user doesn't get talked
too slow okay so
the the user doesn't get any response
until the first threat finishes
okay so one user wanted to come the
number two in one in one
hundred-million it takes a lot of time
during that time
know or the user is able to get any
other a response from the server
this shows you how easily and
Dino loves it no jess is vulnerable to
denial-of-service
okay assuming that one user is able to
do a CPU intensive
action on that server no other users are
able to get
any response from that server make sense
ok
no unlike other platform
dotnet who's lost it on I a fine job
with that you don't cut
node.js doesn't have any running web
server
the web server is no jst self when
you're right you're up no justification
you are responsible for handling all the
request get
and post getting the data and and
combining it together
there is no am web server who manages
that in all that happens within the very
same
thread on your application as he said
single-threaded applications
so there is no real suppression between
the web service thing
port and the logical part all run in the
same thread
know obviously their third party
companies which
dude that job for you combining request
go to a getting poked
and but still and
conceptually the all-around within the
same thread as yours
so if you want to write to a web
application
you don't only concentrate on your
business logic but whether you have to
manage
all be heavy lifting glove getting
information from
from the server this is a kind of an
example where you feel the system
to start with anyone for 3000
and greatest server each day in
each time you get a data packet you have
to combine it with the previous packet
so there's a lot of work being done
within your
thread now let's see how it is related
and once we get this architecture let me
show you this example
what's the problem with the following
code in here missus
real code from commercial application
what might be the problem in that code
md5 is
okay that's one and
one alright so
math.random is really week okay
it is considered the default random with
the node.js is considered as as as
fairly
and so in that case whenever a new user
register to the system
his password her password is computed
based on the math random
than it being hatched using md5 and that
would be the default password of that
User
so as I said the eighth
pure in G said the random number
generator is known to be weak I actually
there's a research
from a meet client at the midline wrote
I think in nineteen
in 20 2009 a hoe to break your engine
google has somewhat improved
that algorithm and but feel the very
same structure remains it
whenever you start having some random
numbers for civil you get to see in
and and then the field is used to create
it privately a private data member Colts
take action to date a member state one
state event whenever you ask for the
next no
random number two things happened for
stubble you derive the first random
number
from the state and then you compute the
next eight
based on the previous one okay so you
get this year this it is used to compute
the first
state variables these variables are you
to compute random 0
and state one state one is used to
compute run the one
in state to so that hoe a you get the
chain
random numbers you and so as we said
Karen G
is weak to me that the
we were able to show that given 3 run
don't said the random
numbers were able to and for what was
the state variable used to compute the
third value
and what does it mean once we get state
three what can we do from here
think that you can predict the future
numbers probably we can also produce
know what were the previous random
numbers
maybe from other users but for now we're
complete predict the future
the problem is the first we need to
reverse
the MD 5 numbers okay so there's a
random number under
is a number between 0 21 including 0 not
including 1
but then we run and if I went over that
number
we need to break md5 I do you suggest we
do that
a dictionary attack
and but in that case not that kind of
addiction everywhere user chooses
password it's a random so did sorry
to okay surrendered run rainbow table
or for those viewers from your are you'd
least
I'll various and values and their
md5 computation these tables are indexed
fairly well so if you got the md5 all
you have to find his
the end if and the five entries and go
back to the
a
and original value the problem is that
only available rainbow people that
iPhone are
focused forwards passwords so usually
there were created for by alpha numeric
values a through said
8039 and up to eight nine ten characters
in that case the source for md5
is actually afloat number 80 dot and
then fairly large number
about 15 16 D gets and they confine any
rainbow table that focuses on that so I
had to create such a rainbow table in
Asia and show how weak it can be used
that's the actual source code I'll
the random and within v8 so as you can
see here state 0
is used to compute the next eight and
then to return the the actual value
a there are some magic numbers in here
like 18,000 than 36,000
and then there's the 14 beating here in
eighteen beating here
a Google changes these values
fairly often and this means that the
algorithm
used to hack the random needs to be
changed accordingly
it's not pretty straightforward it but
that's the current version
and node.js using okay and so given
three consecutive random number three
the values of state your own state when
can be inferred has of future values can
be known in advance
back in webbrowser in chrome
each tab runs in a different process
different process
means that the private data members I'll
random
are different between each tab so they
did that if you have a tad
singleton your application and you
compute random numbers you can tell what
r
what's the next state 20 on your tab but
you can tell anything about what would
be the state's
other types okay so that kind of
protection that's why Google
doesn't consider and one of the reasons
that Google doesn't consider
a defend the there appear in GV week as
a real problem
because it's problem coffin with being
the specific session with them
the specific dad that being said
in node.js all users
a running within the same process the
running within the same process
there should ensure the very same state
this means that one user
can get three random values get the
state and then
and hacker can know in advance what
would be the next to run duvalier's
for other users in you think that system
make sense so we will
demonstrate that and I'm so the steps
need to be taken for civil hecker
would ask and written what I'm sorry
getting back to the source code from the
application that we saw
where we get the the random and then we
compute md5 right much
right so we will register three times as
as a fake user
we will get the fake passports or
the real password the run-pass the
register user one
get the password register fake user to
get the password
register your the 3 get the password
know what would be over in
next step not
right away we so we what we got our
three consecutive
md5 over random numbers so what would be
our next step
okay at the end up so we think the
password
will send them to Rainbow
table and left the room with table what
the plain text for
value okay so we will get the clear
random okay some
got us with one graphically random for
two rundown
and then the third one having these
3 randoms we will send a flower magic
float service which will get us
our the future password of the user so
let's see how it's going
now as I said at the beginning it eases
the live demo
each step takes about thirty-seconds
forty-five seconds
which is kind of an eternity in terms of
there
presentation so please bear with me so
okay so
see it's a very secure site there's a
lot so your face okay
air so let's producers as letter just as
fake user one
and pictures the 1password it okay so
that's
md5 ok up with that not the typical see
that
so that's the first md5 that we got
let's register as fake user to
to get the next password what we got
here and then the third
password now that we got that
okay so we've got three
md5 random passwords now let's get to
our hacking
part I'll and here will type
the end the fight that we got the actual
and rainbow table is hosted on Amazon
on one of our servers its roughly 200
Jacobite in size
that's why it's not posted them on my
laptop and
and it's not very well index that's why
takes about 30 seconds to get the clear
value of the
above that number it it was a bit tricky
to commit to get this rainbow table
because
and if you look at the code that you got
from Google basically
you get an in you you unsigned int
which is fairly large up to for for
billion and then it is divided by MaxEnt
to get and values between 0 to 1 okay
so you get a UN and you divided by
Maxine to get a fairly
a small number now it différents
platforms give different results for
example dot net is limited to 10
last a 22 for Team dig dig its after the
doctor
and were with no jst about 6-10 be gates
so if your computer then the md5 with
different platform we just get different
all yours so thats the first clear
number
for the first passport okay three
billion
that would be the let's complete
the next and if I
any questions or for
will wait patiently yet
good
how to generate secure random with known
yeah
there are some a require there are some
modules which do
proper random generator I mean proper
exhibits
no the OPP said Oh but some of them are
able to get
say values either from network traffic
or from your mouse movement
try to get some noisy hand to get the
entropy for
for for your under numbers
okay didn't get the name of that s
JCL
up
and
were soon to be
I'm sorry
both 24 hours on Amazon
and three large something because
we have two computed for basically we
have to to go through
II from 12 for billion in for each one
of them divided by Maxim didn't complete
the md5
I'm sorry
I thought it would be faster but
well didn't do the hard my myself okay
good so we got the third number so we
have here the three
clear text versions of the random
and now we will run the a raking
run Dawn Part once again also should
take about
less hopefully less than a minute and
and what we expected as a result is
first the next
random number cleartext number followed
by
being hopefully next password generated
by the system
well this is running and let me load
that screen through Internet Explorer
just to show that
it's really server-side to nothing is on
the client
would other plans from other places
working
cruncher numbers
and know the next question usually in
being gassed is ho the hacker know the
username
above the you there so we know the next
password but we don't have access to the
user name
and that's a valid question so because
these are forums you can look for
other users in this forum or if the user
name
is kinda consecutive number you can get
that from there
I didn't it really depends on how so
all
and what system you using but they just
wanted to focus on the password part 2
this system tells us that the next
password
to be generated is the following
okay seem to be short yes answer
would be the following
okay so it it will be the CE six
handed by Dez 622 so let's
crossing fingers really user one
and email whatever
with register and the password is
okay you can see it in your see
is six ended by d60 yet ended by
the sixty-two me the cato
just community will see that in
okay CC the password in here okay
next topic
a is a little bit ok with projection
and in node.js that's really interesting
Mongo DB
unlike other databases is considered as
the No SQL database
okay so it there are no tables and
records rather than
there are collections and documents and
all the information is stored as a Jason
the next part they will show you
was actually is part over research done
by
with secure if I about the urinal which
is really interesting
they did behind document is that each
record or each document
can be structured differently for
example the first document your
has and I can feel and if want to feel
where the second object had
the data field name and the second field
site so you can serve both of them at
the very same collection
different different data members in
order to retrieve information
you can use the fine methods to get all
the information
or you can express your worry in
adjacent for Mac
for example I want to find all the
elements were there
want to keep youth 15 now an interesting
point
is that the 15 added value can be
replaced with another
Jason object which actually contains an
operator
for example find all the product that
their
want to keep you greater than 25 okay so
instead of the concrete value we act
that we can actually push
Jason object okay and within the code
Jason can be translated like that so we
have an object or orange
and then up to quantity people's 215
database product find
all elements with his qualifiers and
so this is a classical single injection
okay select for for all were and then
concatenate username and password
and to get it fixed with %uh in node.js
all you have to do is to use the
preferred statement name request
where we get the user name from the
request and then to get
get the password from the request and
just pushing
the name into been in the past week to
the correct feel
took it make sense wrong
that know how it should be done okay
let's move how the system basically
if you seen here with two the
querystring
from the URL and we converted to an
object
name and no just actually does very
interesting stuff when
many
parses the URL we will take advantage of
that so
if for example rewrites the URL
equals be with real creating object
per screen with the field a and value is
the
effete converted to Jason we will get
the structure
if you're right a equals be and then see
people's 2d
we should we get the same object data
member a
with the bolivian been data member see
with the value be and that would be the
Jason structure
writing a cosby sepals the and then
again
a people the okay that we actually get
in array okay a week a
an array that contains two elements be
and that and then see
just a document with the and the Justin
Wolfers follow
pain a then in array up values
if you put in america indexer
a at the fifth location we will get the
very same
array with a single value %uh be okay
and the Jason will be translated however
if we use
string as an indexer as you can see here
we use
the letter F the indexer instead of
actually having it set into an array it
will create a sub
object so RJ dot a duck ass people's to
be
and the Jason part is interesting you
get that a
equals to another Jason object with the
PS
and the value of b okay so it actually
creates
sabes element sub Jason element now
I hope it rings a bell but it that
produce like we actually
showed that you can use the greater than
operator so we can take advantage
that in a short while so
let's actually see that in action
so this is a system if I don't know user
and password
ABC year well
sorry that's not correct and then if we
use a demean demean
were able to login we can do the same
from the purse string
so if I try to login as admin admin
that's perfectly fine
but if I try to plug in with different
username and password I'm unable to
login
sis let's assume that we don't know any
valid
the valid credentials we can use at the
user to use the indexer
greater then so we'll use the greater
than
operator greater than a and then the
password greater than a
okay in that case the system will look
for an entry that
a record or document that matches
greater than a
and I was able to login as an admin okay
and then you can iterate through the
different users for example then we can
use
at the pass for greater than you and we
see another user
so we can actually threat to all the
users in the system or to log in as the
admin
without Val without knowing values in a
min password
and questions yep I'm sorry
air
so I'm not sure who found him guilty but
it is very well documented
at the website web secure if I blog okay
and
I'm not sure if they have found it but
it's an amazing
right up I really recommend you read
that who would secure if I blog
really excellent no
wanna the proposed solutions is
to use am the following
okay DB dots user find find a user given
the user name
and then compare the
get retrieve the password and then
compare the password
to the password that is stored in the
database does it solve the problem
wine why not someone said no
why not I inject the username
then we get let me add me then we get
the password
and we compare it with whatever the user
typed at the text box
so what's the problem here
okay so
everything is that we can still inject
something through the username field
looking through the various operators
that can be injected like greater than
in less than
10 operators is read jack's so we can
actually
look for user name that the name matches
a specific project
and then we can use that to do what is
called
regular expression denial of service to
provide a regular expression statement
which is so difficult for the server
side to compute which will consume
well all the CPU during that time and so
thats would be an example that we just
copy pasted
and
are pointed in want to create a reeling
from that
is good
yesterday and I don't really know
just think image is good
talk so the I will put that interfere
just based
crime doesn't like it okay no
it was a hit enter you will figure that
the Mongo DB service
the service who manages the this request
will use
25 percent of the CPU full-court for
about three to four seconds
chrysalis after
you can see them here okay
longer being takes a few seconds
to validate the user name that they just
tight third during that time probably no
other users can get service from the
manga to be
they actually Council after for 5
request and it stop
but basically during these five seconds
no other users could've getting
any response from the Mongo DB service
okay
a so and and that's probably every node
JS application
is available to to that part okay any
request
that you stand to the database where the
bodies come from the user
a might be possible to that it probably
the best solution would be to use while
character whitelisting okay so there is
no reason to use
square brackets in in as an input for
username
and there are some am require
there are some more jobs with node.js
that can be used to automatically
validate
any input for specific format but
unless you use any of these and may
default your no justification
is wonderful any questions for for
a okay no recapping
if you recall the traditional way and no
just doesn't use any traditional web
server
this mean that the actual your code is
running at the same process
think thread the web server the thing
that problems in your code can affect
on the web server itself not
what they plan to present right now is
well I i wouldn't reply I will present
it or not
i think is that we all know that evil is
evil
that fine and I do want to show
something additional that can be done
with the evil we all know there's a
problem
with that just want to open your mind to
a different
attack vector which I really found it
interesting
and so an
what ish 12 plan to show no was taken
from that research and analyses have no
Jeff platform so in what most web
servers
each request found in your child and
with no jacket
single threaded this mean that and would
modification to the system that they're
done by 1 User
will affect all other users
immediately so evil evaluated string:
and in indictment in Java people cannot
control
for example in dotnet evil cannot
control the I yes
okay the ISA the different process and
the dotted application cannot control
the the
web server with node.js know the can
control the web server
so we will show the difference the
demonstration will be shown on
express JS experts gf is in module that
provide
what servicing to node.js and
vision for example if you want to add
page or service called add to your
glorification
recreate what call a routing
okay so that you wrote Inc
for example if you want to access the
server at the add
page then we add in your outcall dad
together with the code writer at the
at the bottom and so it this service
does
just add two numbers for example
I'd the number three to the number eight
and we get the little number
11 does it really badly by using evil
so eveleen the the first that the member
with with the second
remember and combine the two and but
some really interesting stuff and be
done here
so the actual roping is done
it but what they call the the stack
so there is a routing stack which
contains all be
available pages in each one point to
specific function
so we figure that add point function one
remove both to function to
there are some parameters for RESTful
API
we get the ID for the page and we can
use a regular expression
one focus on on that part in here it but
the
I want to focus on the fact that we can
we have and
they wrote to the add method and
or system can access be the tactful
with the clicking here that
we get the police older wrote in to
YouTube or system so we've got an evil
thanks with that an evil a and the evil
code: the truth
posting here is to get the fourth tak
over the rotating over or system so
that's one
so the stock is acceptable in runtime
both to read and to write
so we will replace the existing routing
with anyone
in this real effect all users connecting
to the system
and it looks very weird because
well I'll show you exactly the basically
we've got the ad
the first comment that we will send it
to actually remove that routing from the
system
and we will add a different wrote Inc
with the very same in an ad
but it will point to a different
function function 5
so any any future users going to the add
page will actually see something
different that one the
well what they expected okay
and know it
what it cost a different function on the
same server your function can do
whatever you want
yeah
I guess so what what you gonna do are in
just that
for stubble we don't to go to the route
to and we will remove
in that case the third element which is
our add age
and then we will immediately afterward
push another ad
which will just think to Bollywood and
multiply to
instead o some coming to and
so let me run this code in here so
three-plus
eight equal to 11 okay three-plus 94 the
12 so everything goes
fine no we will hit
that which i think is here remove third
element
and add another one everything looks
fine
and then no a user wants to know how
much it three-plus
ain't and he gets 24 okay
so no any user connecting to the system
will get
will actually use or multiplication
services
they don't bother adding services and so
it
no the funny part is that it seems like
a bug
so you will approach the vendors say
well I see something going wrong
looking good in your node.js source code
you see nothing wrong
and
and if you try to further investigated
upon or refer to the service
everything just a.m. no israel is
completely removed so you have no
tracking the what actually happened
behind the scenes
this attack believe just in memory
doesn't
store itself in on the DS I think we're
toward the end they were clapping any
questions
and
answer so how to protect against
these attacks for the last while so
first people don't use
evoke that's pretty straightforward
that's really bad just wanted to show
what else can be done with that and what
you're welcome to come for both a guest
you
and discussed that I'm sorry
3 commode how how about
strictures movement with node.js I'm not
familiar with that so I don't don't
thank you very much on who