yen thanks very much for getting a bit
sick as it is a
a long way to come from its a did
IQ will be up and running in just a
moment guns
this comes after listening to country
Australia
day what this a one person me
for the letterman each other analysts
say pick Michael this work
served
and Mustang
yet all right thank you very much
everybody for having me here today
there was kay night now I thought a lot
about what to do if it came out because
king that's meant to be sort a real
insight for I like really reflective in
you know looking at the industry in area
interesting things to take away with it
and the more I thought about what we
should do for an iPhone came out the
more I realize that a nap sick it's just
like it's crazy there is so much stuff
going on any time with or something gave
us something else and that's something
else
and on sale this really crazy stuff I
don't know what I should do is actually
turn this into
aquino's just crazy stuff that fifty
different crazy things that they told me
the story that was going on the industry
just on my cat fifty Shades Feb 6 an all
guy 350 different things
I've the next 45 minutes and %uh so that
a story where want to stop
was around to democratize I should have
hacking
know what I mean by this because this is
gonna be interesting thing
so what amazes very easy for anybody to
become a hacker
said he would say this kid lasted five
year old kid
heck he's dead ticks but we know we had
it because the news headlines is he
acted
but what he did with the best thing in
the controller
and manage to circumvent the printer
control so he did actually get a
privilege escalation
which is pretty cool ended up getting
these name up there on the marks of
security recesses page
and you'd be pretty stoked as a Deadman
years on a five-year business security
resisted
can get a bag ban thi is well say
anybody can become hedrick excited easy
loves it he's like a little but many
kidnaper
anybody can become ACA now the
interesting thing is that we've gotta
love tools out there that help people
become pack is very easily
so things like Bishop the Browns a
plugin so all you do is you just browse
around the internet
and it looks for vulnerabilities
likeness configure that mean
open source control systems it just does
it for you browse the net
and says he got it is this cynicism
and it does the heck employees so it's
very easy
to become hecka now if you do actually
wanna start using some intelligence
their letter to Charles A about had it
coming back
very easy to find tutorials with Google
Docs the look the crease during the
URL's
and then you go to the URL when you put
a single quite any get an internal
database exception
and then you go to the URL you copy it
and then you go and pasted
into heavy dews and you on all things
it's easy if you like to become heckling
this tutorials like this
so we make it rightly or wrongly very
accessible for anybody
to become a hacker now
not everybody wants to become hecka
sometimes the one hi rakha
tenants may have very very easy
distinctly higher
this is not the underground in the dot
where where you find
criminal masterminds in the underworld
this season mainstream consumer facing
hack a list of comments a nice
responsive design website
Scott smiling stock photos it's very
easy to go in just hire a hecka
to do you do anyway so much your head
if these guys the hackers are the
customers everybody looks so happy about
the fact that
you can stop a project for free it's
that simple
to become ACA now this has led to a few
other interesting things as well so one
other things
clearly this happened in recent years as
the sector's mode
so we've had activists mode now you may
be like mainly wondering
exactly what is a hack to this because I
see the term a lot and it seems to me a
little different things for different
people
and I really like swift on securities
taken if you don't fall asleep on
security
stop because he'll she'll who had a
is not awesome and I really like this
definition and so to speak to the
opportunism
the packing find some stuff on a will
come up with the reason later on they'll
be something these guys must've done
something wrong
and often that is the case
so we say things like this this is in
Australia few years ago
and its up tripwire passando
whatever the hell they want it to be for
that that I A this is a government
website now there must be something the
government's doing wrong right we'll
find something they've done that we
don't like
and will make it up and as it turns out
this particular site
it was it's hard not to government
website as it wasn't NGO
to support people with disabilities is a
sort a rehabilitation program and
frankly I think she's been a bit condom
she's been a little bit subtle
but this is what often happens right
this is just legitimate
honest business that its online it's
accessible
it's easy I'm never a problem as well
is that when he becomes so easy we see a
lot of stuff like this
so sailor kids and I mean kids but in
the sensible us
from some feel the owner and the Youngs
must be kids that's something the
legally children as well
and they're in there following the
tutorials to use heavy Julie
to whatever the thing at the time I P to
go in on stuff
and that's a real problem as well
if the interesting thing is everytime
atop a court with their moms that's a
look at the court because they too young
dream by freakin cow they literally
still children were
and the problem is I basically in the
criminalizing themselves very early
which is bad news the main used to be
they would have a nap a sprite
defense is doing something i should get
a kick up the ass for but not go to jail
for
and now because the accessibility of
packing
they end up in some serious trouble now
when they do get criminalize we get into
this world is like I now we've actually
got
look criminal hacking going up and will
have problems with criminal hacking is a
East I say
you know anything about the other
criminal pursuits like a break in the
service station or liquor store
I'm I get my head smashed him with a
baseball bat so there's that
but I could get high N and sit at the PC
any forgot my upset after a small
probably remain fairly anonymous
on my being a part of the world rugby on
extradition anyway
do you really wanna export someone from
the Ukraine for
DDoS Inc from nothing happened
such a safe business now the problem is
because it's such a site business and
it's so easy
for anyone to get into is we say love
the source stuff
and this is just the most random
pointless crap
that pops up this is on pace still an
ass load the data for the wells
had and then if you want to get your
data off the internet because apparently
can get out of the internet now
I send BTC so send us because when we
will take your things off the internet
which is of course medical school
doesn't work like that
it also goes to the other extreme this
comedy
opposite implementation with a guy like
a look he's a buncha data
causes a drop box 09 tropical sector
goes on placement
say he is I segmented nearly seven
million Dropbox account we gonna dump
him on pace been
and if you give me the coronal actually
be more counts
so this is kinda the reverse this is we
will put more stuff on the internet
if you give us money now what often
happens is when we see this sorta stuff
it is not of course Dropbox that's been
hacked in Dropbox
sitting up there on the net and when you
correlate these
data against different breaches so using
something like my however I'm kind
system
I'll take an email address from the drop
box at and would you know what we've
also got the snatcher
hack and facebook hack and cause all
this stuff is just replicated data sets
kids
watching kids hang on the pastebin
copying
rate pricing and then going to me
because I nando get your things off the
internet
so criminal activity like this is very
very accessible you gotta wonder how
successful it actually is meant as in
much sleep a bit kinda stuff but
there's a huge amount on the bet fifty
different grasses this address
i've a couple years against different
price so that
is nasty stuff now the other thing we
started saying critically last year
was this nice extortion months in this
one now this was actually physical miles
sent out to legitimate businesses
and now signing effectively look if you
don't give this one because mine
we got a damaged reputation so
we can define in bomb threats benders we
gonna damage or online reputation which
of course is extremely easy to do it
and the worrying thing about it is
assigning
all's not
take is one big point give us one big
point and it all goes away
and one big point is sort of level money
that you don't think too much about if
it's the safety your business
I mean as much as their hassles doing
this is one big point it's not too hard
to pay one big can make the problem go
away
bizarre to me because clearly nothing is
actually happened it's a protection
racket
just extortion reminds me that that
tightening same pulp fiction where they
talking about
the guy walks into the banking rob the
bank with a fine because he said the
little girl at the other end we got
killer if you don't give us the money
nothing's happened could be an empty
threat but this sort of thing happens
and people do pay be calling for
cause that makes a question so what not
criminals
doing with the because his is all have
them get money well it turns out a lot
of them by Brazilian hookers
now when you actually go around owning
raptors and
owning DNS and being able to control
name resolution across
some large number of rafters will you
can gone by Brazilian hookers because
you can start to stand up fishing pages
just about anythin so it does become
very easy
tracks the mount attacks which let's
give them credit for probably a little
bit more sophisticated and the other
ones who sensor for
so this remains a problem
obviously there is a lot of criminal
hacking going on and none of us really
want to see
esta graver malicious online activity
now one other things it does happen with
criminals
online is fortunately they're not all
that bright a lot over
are not all that bright Penn often they
are coming undone pretty spectacular
style as well
so one that was very big news recently
was this guy so this was Russell bit you
may know him is the Dread Pirate Roberts
emails and I him is
the founder and masterminded the soup
ride underground drug market and
russ was clearly having a little it a
troubled connecting through the store in
service with bill
so he wanted to ask a question about his
underground drug market
when he put the question about had i
connect my underground drug market on
Stack Overflow and it was a fairly
specific question
which was later part of the evidence
that got him convicted
any put it on the under an identity
which was stressful but
him inevitably did other things wrong
according to get arrested in is being
convicted he's tens of millions be
callin
confiscated but this is a simple things
ask the questions take a flight
someone on so along similar lines of
this guy
so he's been in the news a lot lately
jihadi John so he's the black who's gone
around chopping people's heads of
for reasons and the interesting thing
about she had John
is everyone's trying to figure out who
he is because he's got this
strong British accent manny's accent
doesn't quite match
the profile of what you'd expect some
jihadist in Syria to have
so try to figure out who is this guy and
what ends up happening is it it turns
out that he had a gun is in web design
say he wants to buy some web design
software so whom he is the interesting
thing
his tears chopping people's heads off he
doesn't want it he goes online any buys
the web design software from his IP
address in Syria
using his British student ID so not so
bright
and that in a way so warms the cockles
behind criminals are screwing up
left runs and I do end up getting caught
and often by frivolous reasons as well
and when it comes to criminals being
court
by frivolous reasons of the crazy things
and particularly fun to this one
you as my sense is a few years ago so
is a guy going around running Texas law
enforcement web sites
now the ban to Texas but I imagine that
they don't have
a lotta sense a humor and getting I and
hi effectiveness
but anyway so he's come up needs to look
at this good idea he's talking to his
missus
is it listed this I'll do this sign in
the newly neither
and take a photo with your eye fine and
it'll be credible piss them off
and a rub it in a movie it will be a lot
of laos
so she's done this with the iPhone
across what happens when you take a
photo with the iPhone
you get metadata except that you get let
long down a bit 7 decimal places
would get attached to the fight and
unfortunately for this bike he decided
not to scrub
the metadata from his photo before
posting in
which did leave them directly
to the lady here which led them directly
to him so good news all round really
further
for the good side there but what's
really interesting with these guys as
well
is attended to this couple and what
strikes me with that
is is they look so normal like they just
normal people that the shop before in
obviously the attitude he had an things
is done probably thought of what we
consider normal
but this is just a normal couple sitting
in the living room somewhere
owning Texas looking for some web-sites
and Saudi aspect that point anyone can
become
in a you can be perfectly normal person
in every other way God
but you're out there any web sites which
course
is pretty alarming now I also got me
thinking
there are so many people who ultimately
turned out to be a bit steep in other
ways
that ass successfully Mansingh these
online attacks so what is going on
and I we actually making it to easy on
the criminals
to be successful and when you have a
look at some other things that we are
building I say we collectively as
builders breakers people involved in
software industry now I like this one
because when you think about it is quite
ingenious analog in he's a high friction
bad usability so that experience in I
gotta remember your credentials in
yeah it's meant to be something that's
long and strong so what these guys are
so what we'll do
is he taking mobile number any put that
in and your password is the last four
digits in the mud on them because that
way you can remember it
now you can never give your mom a fine
up to anybody else anymore
however this is a much nicer
usability experience the charm your
password now we'll ask that this and
this is a minor sort of obscure little
website
but we also have things like this and
this was only from a couple weeks yes is
a better fit major
online betting agency now Betfair were
conscious that
password resets are also better than
anti usability patton their high
friction prices
you know you gotta wait for the mound
the race certain you know this kinda
stuff that makes life hot so they said
he's will do
right what you do easy put in you use
and I'm and you use and your email
address
you putting your best site and then here
is a person
said
but no email confirmation all you have
to do
show that you now an email address and
the best but
now you might think that silly but
there's a twist
there's a British journalist talking to
Betfair on Twitter &
had bets they were basically berating
him has a terrible terrible trade
exchange
which is Emma book at hand what betty
was saying is
yes but you use a name is a secret you
should not be giving you use and I'm
to anybody its effect on a mattress that
scare people send me e-mail I give them
the email address and then they send me
e-mail
and as for the best they being sacred
will I think we all know that
birthdays are by no means a sacred but
this was the implementation that they
did and I thought that this would
probably make life easier
in some way now sometimes
we go even further and I particularly
like implementations like this because
there is an ingenious side to this
mp3 yes this is credentials in
javascript
but there's I'm a post pics on the
server network latency nice ever
overhead
night hashing overhead on the CPU on the
server this
in many ways this actually works very
well yes the credentials have been the
JavaScript but it does work well
and you can almost time to get some guy
was in source code on a look there
it'll be fun and don't worry about that
but this sort of thing
happens and it continues to happen so
when we look at have a stupid criminal
successful
will sometimes we are making a rather
easy now we also do other things like
this so this is a site map
now site map is meant to be a resource
that describes all the other resources
on the site
so you go to the site map in at least
seven things that
and uses kind of our thing on a site
right so you would put
uses in the site map in credentials kind
about an attribute all the entities
which the put in the site map so maybe
it'll make sense in a
in a strange kind white but this was
literally site map
with all the users and all the
credentials in
so again it it does kinda make you
wonder if you don't necessarily have to
be super smart criminal
in order to be successful now having
said that some lease examples I little
bit frivolous
you know this is nuts and I'm sure that
you're probably like me and probably
know the same as before may never see it
again
but stuff that we do continue to see is
stuff like this and everybody will say
what this is
within about two seconds in this room I
suspect this audience knows exactly what
it is
but sale injection and is number one in
the top 10 in 2013 as number one in 2010
and it still
continues to be everywhere and people
saying how is this still thinking how do
we still do this because wasn't this a
remnant
all they wrote a programming language is
now OTA practices and all the things
that we've now learned
we shouldn't do and we don't do this
anymore accept this is from this year
this is Rob Lowe question few months ago
and this guy's written
an article on have to do a password
reset now eventually a password doesn't
reset
my best
maybe some other things to get reset as
well this example also included hey you
connect to the database
under the s I account which is
effectively got two outs and sickle cell
so we writing this stuff now and again I
say we collectively because it is their
industry
so second action continues to be thing
and I guess the concern is probably
still going to be
a thing in the next top 10 and sometime
after that
because we still writing this stuff and
the West thing is why you say these
pricing you read the comments
thank you has been very helpful I've
never gone and done is in my system
because people do go
and copy and paste the text and I bill
based systems in this white
you know what really bugs me wife is is
he just
literally fall into the key to success
with modern web frameworks these days it
is so
had to actually do things badly compared
to how easy it is to do things well
yet we still keep doing this now
sometimes
I'm also wondering in terms of their
uses only making it
too easy for users so even example what
I mean by that
I we make it too easy for them to
implement poor security
FSA guess ruth is ligated
is why do they need your birthdate do we
really need to keep the pitch waiting
sensitive class is a data
because you have a bit that you can look
in the Betfair you know you don't really
wanna be leaking this stuff in places
you have to wait for some reason I want
the best that
a fair enough but the thing that really
struck me
is the advice around the password never
get past the big in the little later
still the big in a small it is not maybe
it's a kid thing in
kids understand it better but keep it
short so
is easy to remember it's a bit hard to
argue with the fact that yes it would be
easy to remember
account to buy that but it's such
conflicting advice to everything else
that we chine tell consumers
and somewhere someone building the way
that put this in
know probably told to make sense but
they let that get through I didn't push
back
and we end up with Lego saying the right
thing to do
and almost even worse that is probably
kids begin with the young keep the
password short this is really not the
only kiko
so stuff like this is happening now
that's very supportive
by a high-level kinda vice let's just
keep it short
it'll be right and other times we get
really oddly specific about what we do
and don't like with passwords
virgin doesn't like mike is Branson says
very happy about this
now for some reason virgin had a whole
list
different words which they wouldn't
allow on the passage near this wasn't so
does
we have a minimum entropy in you've got
to have this many lower case and symbols
and all the other stuff the guys in the
passwords
this was we specifically don't like
waiters
and inevitably it makes you wonder
what I die and I don't mean wankers in
terms of the
you know the individual are that but in
terms of the actual word so what was it
about having that word
that in like because inevitably if
they're worried about offending someone
on the king of spin myself the phone he
is that as my password
so who else is looking at it because it
like it's not like the CPU gets upset
right there is an operator somewhere who
is looking
at the passwords so again really bad
sort of
ought advice and the other thing that we
tend to see a lot when we talk about
bad on security advice is we do struggle
a lot worse
security questions that cost security
questions
meant to be things that only you know
that shouldn't be easily discover
things like
where you went to school probably not
such a good idea at things like what's
the capital California probably not such
a good idea
that is a good
I written by that a question
I so that sorta thing is is oddly
specific and it really it's a pub trivia
questions on security question
but we see that and I think we struggle
up the security questions because
on the one hand we ask very odd
questions like this which anyone should
know
and then on the other hand we can ask
questions like this which nobody has any
idea about what so ever
that's probably not the nineties benazzo
here
but we do these themes
with their security questions and it is
a hard thing to find the right balance
fun something that's not too easily
discoverable but that you can remember
in this unique in all the rest a bit
and I got me wondering if maybe this
comes down to the way with educating
developers
so I we actually not giving developers
the right message
so is the guidance out there that's
making it hard for them
to do the right thing so I looked around
to find a little bit
advice online that teaches people about
application security
I found this one hey whats up YouTube
disconnection hacker 101 in today I'll
be teaching you guys
how to view other computers IP addresses
I we'd is you type in tracer T said base
artists causing chasity in space
now which one is you wanna take the site
yeah you want to view
so you wanna go HTTP cynical size
and no not cynical little dot Diane in
the website cycle she say a Google
group its name want to see how many IP's
are looking at Google right now
and like at this exact moment we're
gonna find how many people are looking
at Google water IP's are
and what your connection speed is here
we go what you don't raise thirty
space and in the website http
that night slashed last website I'm
doing Google
you are going to be that as example and
you internet and here we go
here they come 1234 I
6 Senate eighty
9 10 and hold it
holder alright 10 people are currently
using
a its
I look it's a good thing the kids get
involved right on its
a I decided I ones then going out and
I and using that yeah this is the funny
thing we do get very own advice
and its it's one thing same kids create
videos and again good running for
actually getting out and having
get this thing is got so many views you
wouldn't believe it as a high could hit
chip
many many many millions but they we get
other advice on line for developers
advice around things like let's set an
exercise
and you guys are going to need to
encrypt your credit card metal I want
you to do this
is unlikely to you by 64 bankrupted
because it looks infected at the other
end on an hour to my hits
you look at the airport
to try some I
and it's a real worry because this
is the information that we giving
developers look at the time
that's the info was not %ah so that
Bellamy rape you lynn what that is the
information that they getting online
encryption is hot i mean i think
probably does this the do it caps a
realize how much you probably don't know
about encryption and then when you start
to look at other advice online you
realize how much other people don't know
about encryption as well
so this was a sec I have a question how
do I securely store my password in the
database
that this guy has come up with an
ingenious plan the 20 cities for each
character the past but you get the S key
value and you at five
and thinking essay the cryptid
I could take away five easy easy easy
and you don't have to worry that keys
are any luck on a rubbish that just gets
in the way
there to other responses as well to this
particular question
one of them was again by 64 and the
other one was instead of five
use that same just like twice as strong
and it works because you look at the
output and it just doesn't look like
anything dishonorable now we do learn a
lot
about the white people build systems by
looking at the questions they ask online
and sometimes we r rather poll
it's concerning
because this is telling us the way
people building systems online it's like
example before I said people put code
for the sequence section holes in things
like that online
and then all these people to thank you
thank you thank you thank you because
they've now gone built their systems in
this way
so that's very concerning but i wanna
just beat up on developers
because not always just developers it is
security pros as well
and I think sign the Security Auditor
isn't idiot
asking for the plain text version every
single pass within the system
and a name out with said plaintext
password every time someone changes that
the guy is an idiot oh and any product
case for SSH
so it just gets all those things
Security Auditor
asking questions so we catch spine
developers but I appreciate all site
that security is a complex thing and it
can be very hard for people to get their
head around
and sometimes it's just not clear what
is the difference between wing dings and
PDP
it is it is a complex spice
you can call to get it cuz the wing
things like little airplanes and things
cousin
doesn't look like it's decipher belittle
so I can be confusing
I get that but I don't want to just
focus on
the builders and Iza securing systems
it's not always their fault in the
reality of it is
sometimes we do you just have downright
problems with their uses
they do do bad things said it wasn't
what I got hacked
Twitter hacked some news to muster got
hacked because that's how big the king
became mcdonald's
they decided they didn't like the water
and now they like the Big Mac and it was
all over Twitter
tangentially they actually picked up
thirty thousand followers overnight
after this happened
couple years ago it's a little marketing
ploy name I'm
but the headlines were Twitter was
hacked and every time someone chooses a
crack password all I reuse at all but
put it somewhere
discoverable its Twitter has hacked
now the same thing happened to tv5 monde
in france recently
he has a sameness so hence as well as I
haven't seen this they're interviewing
the reporter
and is going as a we've been hacked in
the that that
and yes I the back we showed a a.m.
up on the board and Hans that probably
would help but
they're not be discussing other people's
passwords and public talks we should do
that later
I so this is the thing happens in the
Saudi guy Kyle okay
alright it's stupid to have it up there
a public message thing seven film crew
and they fill me in
the but it's a one of them it's not like
that sort of thing happens very much
until they do it again
and the next day there
and up on the keyboard we have
credentials again
enhance again so this other stuff
happens
and it is uses making bad decisions but
equally uses get very confusing messages
because they see things like this they
see a QR
SCANA and the Q ask Anna needs access to
calendars context like Asians because a
sec you askin is work right like i three
African address book and look at he
having lunch with
and the real problem for the user
is what's the one thing these assays on
that screen except what what is the
button that is stopping me from doing
the thing that I wanna do what do I need
to press to go on and actually be
productive
and we are building the systems we
collectively
as builders so that a little bit a
responsibility to it
preparation also consumers are getting a
lot of really AWD
mixed messages about security and
consumers now have to decide between
having a nice day my cable with
antivirus protection or not
now we know there's a lot of other
about HDMI cables but this takes it to a
whole nother level
and yeah the you gotta saw the picture
the consumer as well because it you know
the guys in the story is going well this
one's got any rust protection this was
nothing alarming another
and it's got my lower
United's it is made hired on consumers
in order to be able to make the right
decisions
and I had to wonder if maybe one other
things that make me how to consumers
he's the getting very mixed messages
particularly by social media they get
messages
that a counter to the message that we
would really like to give them about
application security
so often it's things like just wanting
to use a strong password
no one is more than twelve characters
from a passer well you can't because
security
make sense that's all the consumer gets
back
so social media in particular
is really bad at giving crazy bus now on
other times we find that consumers a
genuinely trying to do the right thing
they want to use strong passwords they
want to use password matches and
sometimes possibly have to pace the
password into the EBT
but if they did that be up could lose a
security certificate
and they could be brute force attacked
now I'm kinda curious his the hell you
have a brute force attack because your
pricing is like the dis- have all these
people animals just pasting at the same
time
and then at the end the security
certificates is gone
this happens allegedly so social media
is giving some really bad advice
in terms of the reasons why things are
done with application security
but they're also giving bad advice
intend to practice is to help people
should protect
personally identifiable information just
checking to limit the him
you know I'm just some Twitter account
was just replied to you and trust me I
do have the little blue like the thingy
which means I'm fine
just a big titted have but just put it
in a DM and send it to me and then we'll
see
on your Twitter time on your machine in
the clear and also the net with a time
line in the clear and will probably fire
off an email and AM as well
but don't worry stood so device from
social media
is often atrociously bad but at least
you can kind of understand this one
other one myself a few years ago that
I'm social work at take me three is
if anyone knows what this means
this is not my it up I
if you work it out please let me know
now
as much as this is amusing it's very
subtle I level basic stuff just crappy
advice for social media and clearly what
we won
social media manages to do is just take
the discussion of line
he concerned let's maybe not the in the
past said that maybe we have a private
chat about things
good but at the other end of the
spectrum is that governments
and of course we have learned an awful
lot about governments in recent years
we've learned things
that in many ways their worst fears now
many why some other also amazingly cool
and the NSA's toy box did have some
pretty good stuff in it
to things like rights mast which
festival is a tightly orson I'm
its side danes bone this was a white 7 a
VGA cable
they put on a little red line in the
major cable by China right now and
remotely and then I can see
what is on the screen which is
enormously cool it is very very James
monster
and again horseman choosing and I'm what
are the other things that he is really
interesting that we did learn about
government's
was about how effective many the
security controls that we have
good free general access to really a
things like SSL I was so happy when they
found that SSL is missing in Sopot some
Google Network segments that they broke
down so during Americans
we've got this now classic smiley face
on the network segment that has no SSL
because there was so excited about it
because when it's done right SSL works
really well
and this is actually really interesting
for us because we know that we have very
easy access to this
now the problem of course is that SSL
works so well
that some people don't really like it
very much at all now we'll see what
comes out is i cant say
David Cameron all the UK managing
directly bankrupt General Ban SSL in any
sort of
feasible way it's just simply not going
to happen
it works too well its tourist activities
too much across the world for one
government will come on so we gonna
at Doral compromise a and every time I
try to that the past it really hasn't
looked everywhere
so frankly the government stats look
pretty on heat
stan is this interesting thing here is
so you know governments economy to be
sensible right did not mean to the one
he changed things
but then we start thinking about on him
so we see stuff like this
and nobody saw this coming
you know this was the craziest thing and
frankly I still have trouble believing
that this was dprk
and they're just gonna gatien's a place
in skulls and crossbones in the basement
I mean I did base with you but the exit
that's a big point as far as in I'm
to sign and the funny thing is that we
we get used to thinking about
governments as wanting to infiltrates
and be pervasive and persistent and
silent annex will try to have a long
period of time
basically be pretty subtle and what they
do because that is what is most
effective for getting intelligence
it make sense cited just the face
is just a very very odd thing it
interesting thing with signing as well
as that we found
but that did have some serious impacts
in the physical world
so what I mean by that is a biopsy
pulled the maybe they were gonna show
the moving since the couple
they got threats against cinemas even
taking America got pulled from something
as been at it for a decade or something
but now we worried about upsetting the
access available and maybe though
United had to face another corporate
website so it's interesting to see how
abt sick does that to extend into the
physical world
and sometimes we find it's almost like
ep6 not ready for the physical world and
we see things that were probably just
never in anybody's threat model
and I'm well we write about
a government dprk an employee with the
window in it
here this is what comes undone you know
did we ever expected voted up medicine
so that's not think but of course one
other things about the physical world is
very good at circumventing digital
controls
because you can do things like this
it's still too fact there are many still
gonna head
thing yes it is P into a board with all
the our site Aikens all the pins for the
outside taken sitting there behind the
webcam
each might not be publicly accessible
but
here we have and it is sorta this use of
physical world to circumvent digital
controls
now cause there is a lot about sick
happening the physical world and as we
connect more more things and more more
things have microprocessors
we do get worried about some other
testing is going on
so everyone probably saying chris L that
I am
he wants to take off love Chris one guy
I I could have hit bottom
yes I at you nice sitting with the guy
pen testing in a bus at 30,000 feet on
this not so sure about
not a frankly I think Chris ladies on
airplane because he doing some really
interesting stuff but
I just don't really wanna been applying
them it's just interesting also to see
have this is played out because I care
you know we we know these plugins and
devices he's probably got some info
if you read the news in my the plane fly
sideways it
is probably nasa more interested in that
than inside he's actually managed to
make me a Best Buy sideways
and then the whole thing's being blown
up wit he has admitted hijacking a plane
in midday
you know I'm not quite sure that's
exactly what it was but
here we are in things get blown out of
proportion but when we do talk about
connected things in Absecon course the
big thing that everybody's talking about
these days
is I A T so I A T is the new exciting
thing everybody's rushing to connect all
the things because for some reason
you're free does need to talk to your
toaster
and if you can be the first to market
with the toaster fridge bridge for some
reason
you will do very very well so we say
stuff like this this is Lee fix
this is an all the invention so on a
little bit easier however
it pretty cool bad light bulbs that are
connected so you can control the light
bulbs from its not fun
you can change the color in the mood in
the brightness seeking and a discover
mode
you know whatever you wanna do it I
which is kinda cool now let's take
did have a vulnerability last year and
the interesting thing is
as a people say well if my I A T thing
has a vulnerability do I really care
so do I really cares an attack that puts
my light bulbs
in to discover mode maybe not
but when the attack vector was that the
like lives
with leaking the wifi credentials the
network there on now I care
because now my lot holds Arabic the
into my internal network and this is
what people think about with it. it's
not just the device itself is when you
connecting it to
what do you interesting it with Miley
pics came out and said look
you know it's true that we had on
ability however we do not know if anyone
having been on by the light bulbs
which is good news you should all gum
patches like pubs
I had a pets allowed pope
so they are people going to start to
think that had to actually keep the
i-eighty
themes up to date and patched in
securing why is that they never had to
think about before
and it's only getting we did because we
getting more and more
we'd I Etsy stuff so getting stuff for
the connected toilet
this is real is Japanese as are all good
12 things
and this is the companion app and the
companion app lets you control the
toilet
aspects Japanese that actually likes on
explain this to me
because I'm particularly interested in
that middle one which is like a calendar
with him with some kind of event-driven
daughter or something
on it which is not immediately clear but
the thing about it is when you start
connecting a toilet you now have to be
worried about to take pictures on your
toilet
and there has been a security advisory
related to the toilet and this is
enormously worrying because now you can
suffer a backdoor attacked by a toilet a
and that is about the scariest thing I
can leave you with incense this
wonderful industry
thank you very much
exact figures
where we have emerged round was really a
the 10th time for
12 precious nobody wins Best their own
thing that the toilet
good yet
gem ha I i think that as an absolute
it's an impossible thing and I think the
concept that it is either gonna be
secure and fantastic was gonna be
crappers from another a question
things had a good look I might be the
question is can we did better in your
man would not look better
you know do we really need to look into
mobile number for the non meant
units okay that be running a bit late
with Michael he was president from the
best-organized speaker ever met
thank you try on you be able to date on
shots
good you dread and get some real thats
the door