alright
welcome ladies and gentlemen thank you
for joining us liked it
give it thank you to our sponsors for
this track NT objectives that are
sponsored
this room in this track got a great talk
for you now
Linea using interactive static analysis
for early detection have suffered on
abilities
and got bill to you and
june's you from universe if North
Carolina Charlotte
units BTU thank you very much
I the story we're gonna tell thing
the story we're gonna tell is a
essentially doing
interactive static analysis as
developers type
so people are used to using ID's ID clip
sweet I be mixing texier
you get 1 I've results above errors
and we want to do that for us static
analysis findings
software vulnerabilities that
essentially which I do
I think Michael Howard's talk this
lunchtime sort of sets the stage very
well education is a huge issue
people are not train and even if people
are trained the often forget because you
have pressures deadlines
et cetera so I so so what we're trying
to do is to fill that gap
to be very mine for didn't to keep in
the front of people's
consciousness so
so that those without the basic
observation is Chris static and dynamic
analysis tools are
are reactive you you sort of do this
after you have
which some checkpoints oh its you what
you are not fixing the by against you
as you produced 'em you sort of some
distance away
from that and India typically run by
security professionals
saw approaches as I mentioned earlier is
is really push the envelope are
interactivity
along with the construction of the cold
while developers already Cup
hand the therefore by makes initiative
we mean
its develop oriented and we want to keep
developers in the loop
so the advantages a nice proactive
support of developers with your ability
to have detection and prevention
we want to specifically leverage
developers knowledge about application
contest in logic
to drive custom I stated static analysis
got a lot of times
when you static analysis you used used
by security professionals
and they don't really have the
ApplicationContext
so we're trying to use this tool to
bridge the two and we'll show you it a
couple of demos
about that NN in of course the whole
idea is to drive to
fix my own abilities as early as
possible
cuz you know we we heard gene kim's talk
yet
sometimes you don't get around fixing
the stone abilities even if you'd no
exist so other the
there's two kinds O interactive's did
static analysis we
we have a implemented one is up
interactive data flow analysis which
you know everybody is familiar with the
typical kinds of 10 propagation
in an injection attacks Sonova analysis
for food
for detecting ingestion access injection
vulnerabilities
we also are experimenting with
what we call interactive control flow
analysis the idea is
sometimes you have you have security
policies in variance
things like access control policies see
serve protection et cetera
that you wanna make sure that when you
write code you have
have satisfy those policies and they're
very difficult to detect with data flow
analysis they're really control flow
problems
so so we have some ideas on how to deal
with that and I'll show you share that
with you
now I gave a version of this talk
last year a minute Minneapolis at
Absecon USA
a so-so I will spend a few minutes
the next few minutes just sort of give
you a little bit of a rehash of what we
did last year because
someone you may not be may not have been
there
and but we've done a lot of new work
since 10 so we'll show you more
results and and will also show you some
other current research things that that
they were working on right now
so with that I one commercial Nexus I'll
pull type
demo love a project called a side which
stands for
application security in an ideal
environment
and heart of this is an open source OS
project so so you can't go go
a West Poseidon and you find the page
and
so I saw out is i rationale is this is
designed to be used by
developers not to security professionals
we wanna
have the developers be sort of recognize
instead I'll be calling security
problems is seeing Santa when riding
coat thinking about
what sort of problems I should prevent
we should what we want the tour to tell
the developers
here wanna think about that right a
one might buy so by minimizing extreme
bird not developers
and then we also want to again leverage
developers knowledge
in terms of customized security analysis
so with that June is gonna stand show
the live demo of
a power system both the interactive data
flow analysis and data for static
analysis and I'll
come back and talk to you a little bit
more about
that the sum of the theory and the
mining design issue behind it
so so what he's gonna do is gonna show
you
a an example in an in a in a
in Eclipse environment so we have our
plugging running ed aside plugging
running
so as you see that there are two
warnings and these warnings are
generated because you are reading
and trusted aide in this case get
parameter like this this is an adjusted
so if you commented out and I the show
you how its interactive it is
if you commented on the line the one he
goes away
if you I commented it shows up
so this is that the kinda interactive
style they were driving for
so now if you look at if you click on
that Devils icon
it tells you that you in this case it's
it's a it's a
you to input validation for this thing
right and what we have done is we have
put
are the is sappy library underneath so
you know developer can go down this and
shoes
what validation mechanism he or she
wishes to choose a peach you something
say for example c-string and they were
actually generate cut now
some developers I get some developers
were like it so
so this is you know we're not seeing
this is one size fit all but this is
some of the options that you could do
in the next case in this case you know
%uh the request parameter is passed
through an integer
so you know you don't have to worry
about right so now UK you can also
choose to ignore it
hand and this one will go away so the
idea is
you know as you type in a this gets done
yes where
I
its its to what along with the the
workspace
along with the project up
back back back yes yes okay
back not a we also do something with the
dynamic SQL statement so if
if people ever where the use dynamic SQL
statements
we want to miss a this is not something
you should do okay
we want to stop them in sort of very
very
clear terms alright so this is it just a
very quick overview of what interactive
data flow analysis looks like
are so let's look at to the next part
which is the interactive control flow
analysis
and and idea we we propose here is
we call interactive code imitation so
here's an example
where I let's say you you
you you have access some sensitive
database tables like the context is
you have some security you know a
you know application security people or
security lead
therefore project you would say these
tables
are sensitive okay whenever you change
the state of these tables
you need to do to access control when
you do protection of
see surf right and so what we do then
he was used to clear that this is all
policy-driven you can writing rules
it's not hard wired into the code and as
developers write code
that touches these tables we threw up
warning I
we threw up warning at the level of your
entry-level method whether it's a
an action or servlet something that
starts your web transaction
so the reason we throw up that
particular warning
and you go back at flag is because
in this procedure in this function call
if we go Joe into it
it actually Access database
writes a SQL statement so our rules says
if you touch this table
we watching the n.o take for for access
control of cell
so then you have the the warning so if
you click on this
flack we ask you to show us where you
access control logic
not not every sort of piece of code
passes as access control logic
they must be ballin expressions so in
this particular case
you wanna lol you want entertains you go
back and you say okay here is
checking the user session is not now
I am NOT a tad and then there's another
one that the user actually
owns the account me now
so this information again is stored in
the meta data they're basically says
for this particular access control those
these are actually my logic
yet does the access control check now
just to show you
if you just throw some you know like
assignment statement
you tried and noted that you can add a
third statement and because it's not a
bully in
expression aside it's going just ignore
it so it's only looking for
Boolean expressions there are connected
along the execution paths understands
their
the control flow path acts now the
the interesting idea the proposal we
have is you know we
also hurt some speakers talk about code
with you being
this great idea cocoa with you a call
with you is incredibly difficult
one of the reasons is in progress with
difficult is because you are you you
gotta talk to someone is what you
actually did
right so we're trying to do is you know
doesn't solve all the problems
but the the hypothesis is with the to
like this
you could start build some critical and
notations
so that somebody without a head actually
having to talk to
sit down face to face with their
developer I can pull up to code and say
you now uniform I for my organization
when you touch this
piece of data I wanna make sure what
somebody inspected the code
and in the talking actually give you
some some some ideas
yes are
it in our current implementation no
okay but you know there's no reason why
should you could save this with
along with Madina so when you open up
make in ALK refurbished as long as you
are
your workspace is alive yes but if you
kill the app
you kill the workspace week we have you
know is experimental we haven't gotten
to the point if
sort of making that persist yet yet
okay but E their %ah to use UI issues
are
obviously okay but that this is the idea
is you know that this is the proposition
back so so those are the just give you a
a sort of a very quick a taste up what
this interactive static analysis looks
like a let's go back to their
their presentation
that back so again to recruit due to
rehash it is a interactive data phone as
is this policy German take advantage
over
you know essentially popular influences
algorithms
we want to be my an assist developers
fix each team source
for automatic validation and and code
refactoring
and instantly we have to analyse the
code
with the cup control flow analysis we
identify critical sensitive
operational cold and in this is the part
when I mean by leveraging application
context and develop a knowledge
to develop as they are writing code is
he okay where did you do it
we believe that is the hypothesis is
that's the time
the most familiar with the application
context and knowledge they could provide
that information
and when I'll show you is how this kind
of information
can actually be used to do additional
static analysis
things that you couldn't do in typical
static analysis tools
today so I arm
the subscript so
so so so to give you an idea of what
sort of analysis you could do
with this additional information that
you could couldn't easily do with
current static analysis to so so imagine
this example give your country code
example later on
sorry have some kind kinda web entry
right and then it goes to some database
access
any you ask a developer see where is
your access control check see for
example ceaser
protection for that particular update
and then to
this quickly sign on the side is where
the annotation s
and with that information we can run
static analysis by looking at all
possible paths
from all possible where the entry to
that particular
database operation and if we find
there is a path along which there is no
annotation
then that is a possible point for what
for bypassing authentic check like for
access control so
so we actually have found Cole found
those kinds of on ability seeing
in real life called and I'll show you an
example that now that's the kind of
analysis that you
couldn't really do easily with current
static analysis tool because
the transfer of knowledge between your
developers and
you are security cold auditors sort of
the white walls to do that is just
so complex it's just not going to happen
and so now I'm gonna talk to you a
little bit about the valuation this is
great so
you know would research when I T sort of
product so so we have to say you know
how well that works
so we we r we will we wait we the
get a in-depth analysis of an open
source project Apache roll-up
which has about 65,000 lines have Java
code
and it's quite the quite Whiteley you so
if you do know
Google search powered by Lola no public
over million
sites pop-up s actually actively
maintained so
is a reasonably well-maintained open
source project so we did his first we'll
look at the
evaluation up interactive data flow
analysis we take their
Apache roller we benchmarked against
fortify s yet
so we have a John Milton some of you may
know him
is here at the conference is that the
the lead for an abscess a project
and happens to be a former student of
mine so
so I said John hey you know I know you
do a lot of static analysis why don't
you do a benchmark for C span two days
did a professional job of doing static
analysis on
I suppose what he would have done for
for a for commercial job
and then what we did was we we we we we
we ran this
against side and compare our results
against his results wheezing
that as Oracle so we want what we found
was
that aside found were only looking for a
site is only looking for 10 source
obligation kinds of problems
so ninety-two percent of the problems he
found a site also found right
and I'll %uh there are two issues that
not detected by side but mostly those
are
GSP issues we haven't really implemented
GSP detection in our
aside yet there's no reason why we
couldn't it just you know it's a
research prototype
we there some struts fun a
structures yet that again we have not
implement its ok to the ones that that
that's not covered are the ones that
we quit easily extend our our prototype
to deal with we also found some more
things that's what if I didn't recognize
as
as as problems but we found that there
were problems
so so these are problems you're
basically fall into two categories:
one category is I'll
uuuu you use you red untrusted data
but you sort of didn't do anything with
it so fortify says since it doesn't do
anything now have the worst for
a trigger so I'm not gonna worry about
whereas we take the approach
that says if you touch and trusted data
we ask you to validate
right now the philosophy there is
eventually somehow this day to make it
used
to extension it's better to sort of
validated the beginning so those for you
to this can
with there are some some the a
false positive as well so example of
course positive is
you know somebody's weeding in a binary
value and it can only be interpreted as
to enforce
so a so so so so you know that's that's
that's very application-specific and yes
I would be able to tell that so there
are some love
of those kinds of things and out of the
120 at 118
we we recognize we we we classify 24 as
being
up that type know those with it false
positives
we also evaluated interactive control
flow analysis
so what what what what to wear again we
did is again remember
interactive control for an ass is about
annotation so we ran
aside against a
against wrought by the way both the the
this version is the primary by former
student of mine she's just a pet
defender a PhD dissertation so so the so
we we we sort of
took a code we ran it against aside
and a end so we simulated what the
developer would have to go through if
they were writing the code using soft
and we're specifically looking for
ceaser protection so whenever
the the a rolla changes
it stayed at its state you know ads you
know for example
Adam add a blog entry changes its state
we asked where is the ceasar protection
mechanism
okay and sure enough we found 70 days
there were seven for abilities that
started at least
from Laura 31 to roll a 5-1 which is the
current release
that yup they they've done numerous
face lifts in frameworks in all these
jazz/nu I
but those ceaser protection coaches
would have sailed on
so we can test it all the versions in
the middle they all have these problems
we r reported to the robot roll a team
and a fixed it any credit at us for
for finding those bodies series so so
that's what I've
email mine is at least preliminary proof
that if you have something like that
hate you know this is basically
not rocket science race just when you're
writing code did the the toes as he
weighs you see self-protection
in in we we think that you know people
know what what to do but he's pick up
for whatever reason
so here is an example this is an actual
cold so
you as you can see that this on weblog
seve
well web entry this is when rolla
commits to
the web entry to the database and and at
that point we would have
as you see here are with the red flag
was well where's your ceaser protection
and the developer will look at this
incest okay I checked for authentication
but I didn't check for C serve so
hopefully somebody would have thought
about it in
added to the two added the ceasar
protection enough course
we cannot ensure with the added it
correctly or not but
least they have they would have to think
about it
right so so that's a
the quick overview love evaluation you
know how effective it is we have
supplementary data
against he open source project that
seems like it should work
okay we also thought about education is
we
started out with this presentation see
well you know universities
don't teach secure coding the reason is
most faculty like developers
never training secure complete right and
we have security crisis
right we talk about their policies in a
you know access control and all that but
we don't necessary connect this week
called
right and the on and the
so so so the same problem that we have
industry so how about using aside
as an education towards because most are
students
go through the four-year computer
science program will have to use Eclipse
Java
to write their projects and stuff so
that's a hypothesis is why do we just
throw this
in the air and then and see people can
learn
bye bye by using this tool and that we
we we we
got a grant from the National Science
Foundation so we we built
this this evaluation exercise
so what we did was as though we do a
gamble when we do a demo for the
education version now education versions
essentially the same version you saw
but what we did was we had a lot more
explanations
because we thought that you know these
people
would have never heard about secure
programming date you make many of them
have never heard about
SQL injection so so when we throw
warning at these people
we won it sort of explain to them what
the so we wait so this is our first
attempt at
at doing that a few click on this thing
again you see those
I along with the the choices we have we
added that the
the REIT read more button in which case
we
up
we go online
in a week we we sought to explain what
is in Provo
nation you go on and a and the type of
attacks
and we also Linkin whatever appropriate
material from OS website so
so you from there you can have jump off
points 20 s
I
so so so so it is a as an integration
that's cool let's look at it the the
dynamic SQL case I so here's dynamic SQL
statement
you do it we'd noises don't do this but
we also tell people
what they should do so here is a a
page explaining what is SQL injection
and and how to do it right this case use
parameterized
SQL statements we have sample cold
people can look at
so-and-so right so this is the version
we implement it was designed to be used
by students
and so what we did was okay you know we
have to evaluate how effective that is
right so
let's go back to their thing right so
so we did evaluation I we
we just a just before the a this this
this conference so our paper got
accepted so so so feel
much more comfortable talking about it
so we we recorded 20 graduate students
who have no secure programming training
and awe
this they were just fresh master
students
or senior undergraduate students and
they're working on a web based
application project that
that uses no typical stuff SQL you know
is a java-based web application and we
asked them to work in the lab
our machines with with sightings to
offer to
for three hours we give them a little
bit incentives for them to do that
and and we administer its a set of
questions
which are true force questions before
the
start the project right so these are
your typical secure programming kinds
questions
and then we ask them to work three hours
on their project
and the day came by the way this is all
transparent they can save their
project as a WAV file and then go home
and continue work on
on their on the on their laptops so this
is what do we do
and we also do a post a
three-hour test ever was weekend version
of our test
that that very much similar to minimize
quite different set of questions
also true false questions we test them
after they have used to of course
now what you would expect big being true
false questions
you know you get 50 percent chance of
getting like so
indeed before that before they used a
tool the average score is like 53
percept so it's roughly about you know
random but after
they got ten percent increase okay and
we
we ran through your nose status
statistical analysis tools and it shows
it's very sick statistically
significant so the idea is you know just
after using three hours
AP you begin to dry in the concept
input validation are putting coding and
things like that
this is not with anybody teaching them
just by reading the material going to OS
understanding those guys information
another interesting thing is
I remember the SQL statements right
so for all the students know love them
use piercings
they all use Google's we act which
because we week or their
keystrokes using the screen capture
functions will we see them actually goal
go online search and if I guess would be
fine
if I dynamic SQL statements are the cut
and paste they put stuff in there
none of them use pistons but aside ones
that don't do that in years that the
staff
even though you know for for ethical
purposes we have to go through ethical
review boards for human subjects studies
we could not give people extra credit
for doing security right because the
course is not about security you know we
we do in
do not interfere with that the way the
courses taught so so
getting the security right doesn't give
students an extra points
but even in the context of that are
25 percent of the students voluntarily
change the dynamic SQL statements
to prepare it stings right so so that's
that's kinda very heartening
I mean iraqi just so so that students
really care the CD stains is a
you probably have heard about SQL
injection but they don't really don't
know what it is
so the speak understand it's a bad thing
we
what we see is for those 25 percent
students they would actually go onto
Google search find more about how to
write
PSQ still prepared ask you still
statements right
and then sort of adapted in but then got
that's that's that's when interest
so so that's also any cell preliminary
results shows that
if you have something like that and
imagine you can reinforce this
throughout classrooms with professors
hopefully after four years people see
this thing repeatedly
that the no understand little bit about
secure programming when they graduate
saw so so so so that's what I've
concludes my second part of my talk
first part is sorta overviews is a good
demo
second part is evaluation well how well
it works
now I'm gonna move to the third part of
the talk which is some of the the
research issues they're working on
and this is not implemented you know
best stuff is doing in the laboratory
situation
now the current implementation of static
analysis is
even though is interactive from a user's
perspective but we are rebuilding their
the analysis every time somebody it's a
key right which is
you know force for custom project which
is fine you know you know the computers
a fast enough it's not a big problem
but for for larger projects that's
that's obviously not good work
so what we're gonna tried what we're
doing on this actually part of his
PhD dissertation is to look at
multi-threaded
incremental static analysis out with
them so the idea is we take advantage of
the
eclipse architecture actually its
architect it very nicely
that you have a sort of the GATT
to have base and then you have a thread
that
that deals with you I because eclipse
want to make sure that the use our
interaction guess highest priority you
do not want to freeze the user from
doing anything else
I soda the plugin are replicating
separate
threats so so what we want to do is
wonder
take advantage of this architecture by
running our interactive data flow and
control flow analysis
in the background utilizing multi-core
processors
and then the hope the idea is as not
Google next slide
so as so as
developers tight being cold
and they changed the EST we want to be
able to see well has the st. changed in
and build incremental
changes into our control flow diagram
and data flow diagrams
and and then perform our analysis and
get feedback
to that to the developers so so we're
working on this this interactive
version incremental version of their the
out with
I also wanna talk a little bit about the
pass coverage
out with them which I I talk to you a
little bit about which is
in West you have the analysis how do you
take advantage of this information
and find additional phone abilities so
why
so this is this is now with what we call
the the path coverage in the analysis
this is particular asses is again
looking for
invariants you know we assuming that the
user is going to give us
those in the that the developers are
going to give us those in variance
and then I will go is to look at all
possible paths
throughout the execution of the program
see if all the paths are covered
by control by by bowling checks
if they are not if they are not covered
then that
signify some kinda bypass probs so week
what we found this was with a also
reported last year when we were
and OS last year but it was not
implement it was kinda fury
and a so-so over the last
over this past summer he actually
implemented this out so we have a
version of this out with them implement
it already
and again we use rolla as an example
so here's an actual piece of coding
roller that had this phone ability in it
and I and if you go on to their okay so
here is a a
piece of cold where a the the one in the
in in pink at you know process kept
right so this is where you you get the
work to right
and the reason its its its its
diane is because that's where the the
the database gets update
iraq and the and it seems wasn't talking
get CA who is the basic accepted and all
you access control
logic check are in what is
the golden box in the handle the what is
this comp hando
have the %ah get handler right so so so
we we we we
again we simulated what aside would have
done with country with
way with the and notation so we ask you
you say hey
I look at you handle process get which
will
update your database right where you are
access control check
for this particular operation and a and
then you
go through the code and and and and and
this is handy week
a there's a there's a routine called a
authenticate
and then there is a and use can take a
seat down there
it 'cause a causa verified user
towards the end right and then so
so inside verified user you have you the
check abuser
you know user ID and passwords right so
from
from a developer perspective and
rotation is is
fairly simple I've coded to verify user
he wrote two checks check user ID check
password
here's the access control I've done my
job right
but if you go back to the code
because verified user is called inside
this nested
if statement right so if the conditions
underlined in red female
right the user doesn't gets verified
okay and %uh so that's an excess pika
pika so-so
the pass coverage out with will be able
to find that because you've
you annotated user ID and password and
we found these paths
that will bypass you access control we
will fight this as a
as a vulnerability and a and and I i
suppose you can
imagine yet you know in their in in
revising and riding coat
these things things like that could
happen you you take things you put in in
a Reuben
and then and pretty soon you lose track
of which past few you actually did the
check
so so-so we take this issue again some
preliminary prove
that butts like they're out there and I
and II
it and that's really difficult to find
with
you know current static analysis tools
but again by
leveraging the knowledge of the
developer by sort of telling us a little
bit about
the semantics of the code that we will
be able to to find those kinds
is so again this is the
picture a high-level picture
representation of this
so we just went over to our mental
mapping up this against a West top 10 is
OK
what sort of problems we can't deal with
in West up to obviously injection
attacks
we can't deal with with the address this
with interactive data for nasa's
cross-site scripting some parts of and
and directed the
and validated we do rights and forwards
right
I with control flow analysis we can do
but broken authentication
in security iraq object reference to
when you reference an object we can see
well where's your access control check
annotation C serve enhance again some
parts of
and validated redirects informants so
about 60 percent
after the cattle grazing top 10 can be
in some fashion addressed by this
interactive
analysis so again a quick conclusion I
love what we have done is
again the concept of interactive
analysis by pushing it all the way
to the developer cide
and again two kinds over now says data
for analysis which look at
injection attacks the data validation
issues
and control flow which is you know
dealing with the invariance and policies
and we have evaluated with and
a reasonable open source project can we
you know so
serving a proof-of-concept things that
it might work
and we have tested out with their
students and and see that it does have a
fax in terms of
helping them retaining and learn and
retain information
and I so it's your some future work now
obviously you know where we're working
on interactive
out with them so that we want this
incrementally with implemented path
coverage we now we have two
put this together and we have to look at
performance make people
ask you sir how fast it was not okay
my hunch is its its it's gonna be fast
you know we have to have the code to
prove that
a so anyway so I I wanna acknowledge
the National Science Foundation for
funding us this work
fortify for giving us an education
license so that we could do this kind of
stuff
and the my student who is currently a
interning at fortify
for a for implementing the first version
of of the code
and most importantly that all our
papers Sen some of this Co that we feel
relatively stable are all
Roos website in a it is our intention to
you know eventually as we find it things
mature will with this is the place where
all the stuff will be made available to
the community
we love to get your feedback and and and
down the road participation contribution
to go
et cetera site yeah
aversion me that the the dataflow part
is available it's is is
we're getting ready to actually do a
second release
the one that's currently out there is a
older version
what you saw today will be out in Annex
couple weeks we're doing a much more
live study right now so so we have the
company's
worship it out in the next few weeks we
have
really not looked at you know this is
what the this
obviously a lot of you usability issues
organization issues and there's also
technology issues with
with particularly with the way eclipse
handles things
okay so so work very open to that
but but our hour ago frankly is right
now to get the out with them to work and
and get some results are in and we
haven't really gotten to that
I mean a a theoretically there shouldn't
be any problems
right meets just as we see is a matter
of coding
but but but we haven't have happened I
mean whether that's better than
than the alternative we don't know
I think I'll we we we did look at find
bugs
the the differences what we're trying to
do is is really interactive me
find boxes still very much like static
analysis
you can run static analysis for example
you can run fortify
inside and I D right as a plugin so you
write your code you push a button you
get with
in you you look at the results in you
collated
the code and what we're trying to do is
skip that step run a continuously and
have the warnings
be so to present it ride in the context
of the cold
as opposed to having the developing
these two weeks look at the report
I mean so my analogy is when I don't
programming which is like
you know I'm many many years ago longer
than I get
bit that you know I used to have a deck
of cards and store it in and somebody
give the printouts and I
I look at the look at the warnings and
figure out which like me
that's that the mentality of static
analysis today
essentially you read the reports and try
to figure out were China
question closer to the
thank you %ah