okay so i'm colleen shannon from kada
and what I'm going to talk about today
is some analysis that we did of the
December denial of service attack
against schoo so this is not the recent
my doom automated attack from all the
worm infected computers it was just
probably one person or a small number of
persons with a botnet attacking scope
and I'm from kada we do a lot of network
measurement and research that involves
the whole internet and trying to get big
picture views of things so we're not
really interested in one land or what's
going on in just one isp we're going
after the big picture so one of the
projects that i work on I work on
security stuff and we have this thing we
call the network telescope a lot of you
may know by another other names like a
sinkhole or an Internet sink or a black
hole what we call out our network
telescope it's a slash a network fits
globally routed and has almost no
legitimate traffic on it so almost all
the traffic that we get inbound is
anomalous in some way it's someone
misconfigured something it's a worm its
denial of service attack backscatter its
people scanning for hosts to break into
all that kind of stuff it's good for
seeing big events because it samples
about one out of every 256 ipv4
addresses but it doesn't really tell us
about you know one little thing that's
happening in one place it's good for a
kind of big explosion kind of events and
it depends on there for us to see
something with the network telescope it
depends on there being some kind of
random component in the thing that we
see so it's someone just off the top of
their head deciding on a subnet to scan
or it's a worm that spreads by scanning
random ipv4 addresses or its denial of
service tool that just spoofs rad
addresses by picking them orinda so
that's the kind of things that we can
see um so this is how we actually are
able to monitor to now good now serves
attacks that we see a little red things
you see coming in come from the attacker
and the attacker is often way more than
one machine but the TAC packets come
into the victim they have spoof source
IP addresses and the
can't really tell them from any
legitimate addresses or legitimate
traffic that's going on so the victim
responds to all of these addresses and
sends random traffic out onto the
network time people who do not solicit
it so we get a big chunk of that into
our network telescope big monitor
addresses circle you see up there so who
is scope for those who have been under a
rock to the last year so they were
originally Santa Cruz operations a unix
server company and they were bought by
caldera and then they changed their name
back to schoo group and got some IP from
novell so they have this chunk they have
some parts of linux source code that's
been deployed pretty widely but they
think they own the rights to so last
year they sued IBM and they've
threatened to sue a lot of other people
including individual Linux users and
this has made them pretty unpopular um
in fact there o people set of kind of
think that they're hated even more than
Microsoft these days in the open source
community which is quite an
accomplishment so in a little history on
their denial of service attacks because
they aren't real popular they've been
attacked a number of times um may of
2003 they were attacked in August they
were attacked again and there were some
rumors at that time that they were just
faking the attack to cover up some kind
of internal network problem but don't
really know if that's true or not so
then in December on December 10th they
were the target of that's not right it's
a 340 megabit per second syn flood that
incapacitated their web server so they
were being attacked they you know issued
a press release saying hey we're being
attacked and then later on in the day a
blog called Wroclaw posted a report that
scho was not in fact being attacked they
were just making this all up in order to
implicate the open source community and
there was nothing really going on the
next morning we got a call from a
reporter asking us you know was this
true wisco really being attacked because
there were a lot of nurse new stories
being saying they were being attacked
there were a bunch of news stories
saying no they're just making that up
there see how evil they are
and so we went and looked at our data
and found hey they are actually being
attacked after all that same day the syn
flood was expanded to also target their
ftp server in addition to their web
server and we think that might be partly
because in a lot of the comments on the
blog people were using as evidence of
the web server not being down the fact
that they could still get to the ftp
server i don't quite understand how that
works but whatever so then that Saint
later on on the 11th go took themselves
off the net because they'd been working
for two days trying to get their
providers to help them filter traffic
coming in and it wasn't working so there
was no point in just continuing to sink
all this traffic that was coming in so
this is our little graph of the denial
of service attack traffic that was
coming in cisco you'll see the attack
starting and then with a big red line
going up and then you can see kind of
damp down some as they stopped
responding to a lot of traffic and tried
to do their own internal filtering
operations that didn't work very well at
all and then you can see the next day
the ftp attack starts and that actually
completely saturated they have a ds3
which is about a 45,000 what is this
packets per second they can handle going
out and that was about the max of what
they could take so nothing's got kind of
interesting at least for us we published
our little write-up saying yes they were
attacked here's the graph that shows
they were attacked you know we're
observing this anyone who has a big
chunk of address space anywhere could
also observe this if they look for it
and we got to be the source of a lot of
the attack of a lot of the open-source
folks we learned some interesting things
like that all of our work was funded by
scope and that we didn't exist and that
we hadn't existed before the 10 / 10
which was kind of interesting because
both of these things are pretty easy to
you know tell me to tell that they're
not true we publish lela CLE list the
sources are our funding on our website
and Google will tell you that we've been
around for a long time but that's not
I'm nuts not really interesting to
anyone more than us except that we're
kind of the closest thing there is to an
open source community pioneer in the
network community you know we have data
and we try to release it to people we
make open source tools and
visualizations and try to get them out
to people and make them freely available
to
people and try to get people to
cooperate so it's kind of interesting
that they would choose us as a target
and then we got our own boss attack
later on that evening about eleven
o'clock at night and some of the attack
characteristics of the attack against us
a point to maybe the same tools or the
same perpetrator as the schoo attack but
there's no real evidence one way or
another that we can say for sure what
happened so we learned a lot of things
from this attack we learned that
security experts including us need to be
careful what we say to reporters and
other people we don't have that much
information about what's going on we
were getting a lot of calls from
reporters and people saying well schoo
says they're being completely
incapacitated by the syn flood you know
is that bad is that real and we would
say well as soon flood shouldn't be that
bad it means in cookies and a lot of
other things that help you defend
against that have been deployed for a
long time you know they shouldn't be
able to block it so we don't know but it
sounds like you don't know what's going
on and yeah technology does exist to
thwart syn floods but not at 340
megabits per second in a million packets
per second coming in it was a bandwidth
attack and syn packets like anything
else can be used for bandwidth attacks
and we need to remember that also we
learned that it's really no fun to be a
scone Network admit we had a lot easier
time getting their isp to cooperate with
us and our attempts to find out what was
going on than they did let alone trying
to try and get them to actually block
the inbound traffic there is PS won't
admit that they give them connectivity
so they sure weren't about to go out and
corroborate the fact that they were
under attack their CEO was quoting
security experts like us who were saying
that any five-year-old could be stopping
this attack and wanting to know why they
hadn't fixed it yet and their only hope
was upstream ISPs helping them out who
they weren't do a direct customer of and
they're not real popular with ngoc
employees and it said they'd call up and
say you know can you guys please help us
out can you put in some filters you know
help us block this traffic that's coming
into us from your ingress points where
it's you're getting most of it and then
yeah the people would say yeah sure
we'll get right on that and you know
they can almost hear the sounds of quake
in the background so it's not a lot of
fun to be there
but there's a lot that we admit everyone
in the community and the routing
community and ISPs have to learn from
this as well um there's also some things
we need to ponder about for the open
source community which is why did anyone
believe that scho was faking the attack
to begin with I mean that's kind of
ludicrous everyone hates them so it's
not a real big stretch to think that
someone might attack them and it's a
bigger stretch to believe that they
actually paid someone to attack them
because there's no point also it's not
really in the best interest of the open
source community to say thats go faked
the attack even if it was true even if
there was some evidence that it was true
because it just makes open source forks
look open-source folks look like they're
kind of paranoid and on the edge and um
not really trying to be productive which
is the opposite of what's actually going
on and so they take a message for us is
that while many dos attacks are
short-lived pranks the potential for
real physical damage to customers is
great you know you have your new service
and you're ready to roll it out and then
someone attacks your website and you're
gone from the net when you've paid for
advertising or you have a lot of other
things depending on your site being on
and what happened to schoo can happen to
any of your customers you know there if
you're not a fortune attend company and
you're not a 2-1 isp a million packet
per second attack is going to take you
out and if you don't have a lot of money
and a lot of resources to throw it that
you're going to be looking to your ISPs
and other people to try to help you out
and try to mitigate the damage as best
they can so there's also some other
interesting questions that come up like
especially when you're doing dealing
with a company as litigation happiest co
is which is do you have any legal
obligation to block traffic for your own
customers or for the customers of other
ISPs could a court order force you to do
it even if you didn't want to what about
if you know that one of your customers
is being blackmailed and they're being
threatened with a denial of service
attack do you have any obligation to
help them then what happens then what if
you're a small ISP how vulnerable are
you to this and can you offer any
blocking services with your customers be
willing to pay for that you know some
kind of dos attack insurance what kinds
of solutions do you have online or are
you thinking about that could help your
customers when this becomes a larger
problem
and if you're interested in more
information about what I've been talking
about there's some links to our right up
to some work we did showing how you can
use a network telescope or a sinkhole or
a black hole to stop denial-of-service
attacks or to track them and what we do
with our telescope for research and then
probably the most useful thanks you guys
is some practical uses and how to build
your own how to monitor traffic that's
coming into and out of your customers so
you know one of your customers is being
attacked or is the source of an attack
or as spreading a worm or or is
receiving worm traffic and if you're
interested in more about what k2 does
there's also a link to the kata website
there and that's all it's break time