so hi I'm Brent IM hause this is scott
beretsky and so the talking about bgp
negative testing so how do i make this
go page down no alright cool so we've
had code bugs for forever we will
continue to have code bugs even back as
far as 1996 the the best way to find
these bugs though is typically in tests
or the the most convenient places to
find it as in tests you'd rather find it
there than in production and anyway so
that some of ways the reasons you would
want to test for negative bgp conditions
for a multi-vendor so if you have a
cisco and a cisco operability may work
fairly well but if you have a juniper
and cisco say you want to make sure that
the juniper does something the cisco is
going to be able to handle it in a way
that doesn't impact you negatively
excuse me do this
okay hi I'm Scott co-presenting here
with with Brent so negative BGP
conditions that we have observed in
networks are update message errors
something as simple as an error in an
update message error even causing a
crash in a router of course we have BGP
route explosion which can result in out
of memory conditions and that may in
fact cause a router to reboot reboot and
then we've all observed a extensive BGP
processing where we see high CPU
utilization under certain conditions
particularly around BGP session and
route flapping another thing we've seen
is incorrect BGP path selection process
maybe not so much a bug in a vendor's
implementation but just by the fact that
the selection process is now so complex
that whether you have a 10-step process
11 step 12 step 13 step 14 step process
is dependent upon which vendor you have
and which version of software you have
at any given time so you could have
different different routers and in fact
calculating a different path selection
process and then also a hardware problem
that's been observed in routers is stuck
routes where routes don't get cleared
from the ASIC at the interface and the
forwarding table is incorrect so those
are a lot of negative conditions that
occur in a network we want to ensure
that we want to ensure that router is
deployed in a network do not exhibit
catastrophic conditions and even better
are able to handle those conditions
properly so BGP can continue along
happily so to do that we want to do BGP
negative testing negative testing is the
kind of testing in which you ensure that
under
our arid conditions the networking
device does respond properly it's a lot
different from typical testing it's it's
more difficult from functionality test
and conformance testing and even
interoperability testing because
negative testing is really boundless the
amount of error conditions that you can
have with a routing protocol really you
could just continue to list them forever
but in the case of functionality
conformance you of an RFC with a
definitive amount of things that should
go right so negative testing is in fact
more difficult so around this came a
great question as far back as 2008 Ling
list it was entitled BGP testing ? does
anyone have a script or a series thereof
to do large-scale BGP testing I'm
looking for something that will generate
male down several hundred networks or
varying sizes and or fake pairing
relationships with similar purpose and
or do things that don't meet the BGP
protocol standard so Tim Brown I don't
know you but back in two thousand you
showed a lot of vision so where do we go
if we want to do that kind of negative
testing the first place one would look
to is the IETF benchmarking methodology
working group that's the IETF working
group in the operations area that
defines that develop standards for
router and switch testing however the
BMW G really focuses on scaling
forwarding performance and convergence
types issues there's no standardization
of negative testing going on now typical
typical RFC's and works that you'll see
in the BMW g is the afib based router
performance which is our c3222
benchmarking of bgp device convergence
in the control plane which is an
official internet-draft benchmarking
terminology and methodology for IGP data
plane convergence also an official work
item of the BMW g in fact brent and i
are co-authors on that
so there is work being done around
routing protocols testing of it within
the IETF however there is no no work
being done around negative testing so
that's really getting to the to the
purpose of this presentation we wanted
to help define what should be done for
bgp negative tests and given those given
those negative conditions that can occur
in networks and in fact do so starting
with update errors when you do negative
testing with bgp you want to do bad
things with your a.s path list when
you're doing testing you want to create
routing loops in the a s path list you
want to do testing with the maximum a s
path length first determining in fact
what that maximum length is you want to
send update messages with missing
incorrect errored attributes you want to
do this for different types of pairing
sessions ebgp I BGP route reflectors
confederations if you're using those so
you really want to mess around with the
update packet it is possible you may
have a implementation in your network
that does something incorrectly with an
attribute and a neighboring router
doesn't know how to handle that there's
been a known case where that neighboring
router crashes okay so negative tests
like that should be done you want to do
testing in your update message where the
nlr I next hop is incorrect you want to
have the receiving router be the next
top for that nlr I you want the nlr I in
fact to be its own next top and you want
to have of course an unreachable next
top make sure the device under test can
handle all of those negative conditions
and then you also want to do
interoperability with negotiated
capabilities and you want you want
attributes to be in the update message
that should in fact not be there because
they weren't agreed upon in the
negotiation negative testing of BGP
resources I really consider this the
cornerstone of the BGP negative testing
you want to maximize memory utilization
and cpu utilization and see how your BGP
speaking device performs so first
without in memory simulating a BGP route
explosion case in your network
you force that out of memory condition
by advertising nlr eyes until there is
no memory available so you do do need to
observe the memory utilization on the
device and then you want to continue to
advertise so that you go beyond that
point this is a good test because
different implementations handle the out
of memory condition differently there
are implementations that purposely crash
and reboot your router there are
implementations that bring down pairing
sessions from which the most routes are
being learned there are implementations
where it just hits that point of maximum
memory utilization and stops learning
routes period so there are different
ways that different implementations
handle this case none of which is
standardized so you do want to do this-
testing and see how your router handles
us then there's the case of bgp
processing this is where you force high
cpu utilization and see how your router
handles that the two classic cases for
the high cpu utilization to classic test
cases our first one removed that ebgp
pair from what you've learned the most
routes in your fib just take that away
that'll force high cpu utilization that
pair from from whom you've learned say
even as high as a hundred thousand
routes remove it see how your router
handles that case the next one is what i
call the nested convergence event will
you force a convergence event and while
the device is still converging force
another convergence event so on one like
you may bring that link down and on
another interface remove the BGP peering
session so you have these nested
convergence events that will cause a
very high CPU utilization and then
there's the the case of redistributing
BGP into your IGP that's a very good-
case to see how your your router can
handle memory conditions okay so now in
the in the convergence test cases where
you have it's a rather simple setup
straightforward there are a lot of
different conditions for what you want
to do this so you have your device under
test and you have your test equipment
your test equipment Ford's traffic in on
one interface and the dot has device
under test has two interfaces outbound
that are your
options there's the preferred egress
interface and the next best egress
interface you want to cause a
convergence event to occur so that the
traffic coming inbound going outbound
switches from the preferred to the next
best egress interface and you want to
measure the time that this takes to
happen and you want to do it under a
variety of negative conditions because
you will get different results for each
of these conditions there's cases of
link failure where you have local
interface failure neighbor interface
failure even a remote interface failure
layer to failure so your physical link
is still up but you lose PPP Giggy may
go down igp adjacency fail or failure so
you have likely IGP next hops for your
bgp routes and that adjacency goes down
you want to cause route withdrawals to
force the convergence and then do a cost
change for your IGP or even a med change
for your bgp routes to force the
convergence events it really is
important to run through all of these
cases because you can get different
results for each of these cases okay and
then there's BGP functionality there's
the path decision process you want to go
through the process so that you
advertise the same nlr I from multiple
simulated neighbors and force ties so
that you walk through each of the steps
in the process and make sure that each
of those steps is handled correctly then
you also want to do negative testing
with invalid peering you want to ensure
your device will not care when it should
not peer so you want to do incorrect a/s
numbers you want to do md5
authentication and you want to do it
with invalid passwords and keys
different combinations of that make sure
your device does not care okay and then
there's a particular BGP configuration
that really can influence the
performance of your vgp speaking device
the first one is your hello keep a live
timer you can have it set to 30 90
seconds or 60 180 with different
implementations you can really notice mm
difference you
I think what you have is contagious so
different so different implementations
will actually have different performance
especially around the area of CPU
utilization with that hello keep alive
time are being set so you may in fact
want to set it lower to 30 90 from 60 80
and see what the performance it is that
you actually get another configuration
and this one comes more from your test
equipment is the update rate routers are
typically stable learning 2000 nlr eyes
per second however if it gets much
higher than that you can see sessions
start to come down so you want to do
negative testing test equipment now can
even go as high as 5,000 nlr eyes per
second you want to set the test
equipment to that and ensure that you
can handle that case and if you're
getting flooded with too many out nlr
eyes quickly now in combination with
hello keep a lifetime or an update rate
your results for cpu utilization memory
utilization can be impacted by the
number of peers you have established
what types of peers those are the number
of routes you've learned from each pair
and the total number of routes in your
fib so you have your ribs and your FEHB
number of sessions those can also
influence your CPU utilization and
memory utilization so you want to test
with very various scaling to improve
performance with various scaling you
configure peer groups that way you're
sharing memory resources so you want to
do testing with peer groups too in fact
notice the savings that you expect to
get in your router okay so we started to
talk about the test tools test tools for
vgp negative testing really have come a
long way in the last year if there any
test equipment vendors out here I I
personally want to thank you for the
improvements that have been made over
the last year for doing BGP negative
testing you now have the ability to do
ibgp or ebgp capability while
configuring an igp ospf for is is or
even rip if you want on that same test
port and force your BGP routes being
advertised
to use those advertised igp routes is
the next top so you really from your
test equipment can get the relationship
between your bgp and igp on the same
interfaces you have the ability to
configure update rates and timers to
test the various combinations that we
just talked about another nice feature
that a couple of the test equipment
vendors have come up up with is you can
load an external route table for example
show IP bgp i know in fact not showing
vendor favoritism in any way believe me
i know that the cisco show IP IP bgp
format that output is supported by test
equipment where you load a file with
that show IP bgp format of your BGP
route table 120,000 routes those with
are the routes that the BGP session will
use in advertising it's nlr eyes when
emulating the BGP session so that's a
very nice feature so you can do your
testing with the actual route table okay
and also now all the test equipment
vendors are supporting a tickle
scripting of their routing protocols so
you can really do some nice automated
testing of these negative test cases in
fact I'd really like to see the test
equipment vendors come up with a suite
of negative tests so we don't have to go
write our own if we go all go have to go
write our own where we're wasting
resources right if the test equipment
vendors could write it for us and we'll
just go pay some small price for it then
then we'd be willing to would be very
eager to have that all right now and of
course we'd like something can for the
path selection process as well in case
you don't want to go the route of buying
anything there are a couple freeware
tools out there there's the python
routing toolkit from sprint that you can
use to emulate a large BGP topology and
do some negative testing and then
there's BGP sim from Merritt that's now
on sourceforge com so those are a couple
low-cost alternatives you can use for
your bgp negative tested all right so in
summary negative testing is very
critical especially for bgp and we've
seen what's happened in networks under-
conditions so we need to do negative
testing in the lab before deployment
make sure your negative
thing is driving high memory and cpu
utilization and since the the BMW g
really hasn't given us anything to grab
on to as far as negative testing we've
outlined some key areas that where we
should do the negative testing update
message errors route convergence path
selection process appearing errors and
then configuration details as well what
Brent and I would like to do at this
point is we'd like to bring this as a
draft of the BMW G and even though it's
not a negative testings not part of the
Charter we think we think that this is
important enough that maybe does get
looked at since the BMW G is part of the
operations area your your input their
your involvement on all of the BMW G
drafts but would be very much
appreciated ok and then of course for
all this testing that we're doing I
think the test equipment we need to get
it done is there now alright so thank
you and thank you very much any
questions all right ok well you're
coming up I have one have you seen
anybody doing or having the short enough
wit and enough cannabinol fortitude to
actually test live routers in the wild
no and I think that's a good thing hi
I'm just yours hi I'm Tim Brown thanks
for mentioning me and your PO hey nice
to meet you just a just a couple really
quick comments and questions I think
first the challenge is a lot of the
vendors that are out there and a lot of
the operators are out there have written
these in-house tools I get a lot of
private responses when I wrote that post
and I think there's a I think there's a
call for operators to try to release
some of the in-house tools that they
design because it often meets a lot of
these needs that we talked about here at
nog the second thing is I think there's
been a lot of advancement in the open
source routing community quag a zebra
etc and those have been real enablers as
far as you know doing these statistics
and stuff and I mean I think that you
know if any of the folks that are
contributing to those projects are
listening this
statistics ID is really I think one of
the primary things that interest
operators because generally operators
aren't running their networks on PC
routers and things like that but the
statistics side has definitely helped to
to us so yeah absolutely thank you yeah
thanks for the comments if there's
nothing else thank you very much guys