um if you haven't yet and I hope you
have please do fill out your survey and
that's the last time I'll say that until
the spring and thank you for those of
you who did fill it out terremark we owe
you a big one thank you so much this is
a very partial list sir the people we
worked with most closely in the early
months organizing all this where Josh
snow horn sandy Gonzalez levy Lily Nunez
and Laura Hernandez and in the last few
weeks as things began to pick up and
excitement mounted the engineers got
involved but all saints really as one he
is um been sitting at the wireless desk
and back all this time but he's also
been managing much of the network for us
working along with Andy brunette and
Bill Williams bill was with us when we
were here a couple of years ago so we
are grateful to have all of your help
back again as I mentioned our multicast
v6 feed was set up by Florida
International notably Julio abera Ernie
Ruby and eric johnson thanks so much to
these folks and to Chris Guzman and Mike
lahaye who helped us get the equipment
set up at internet too and I I asked
this every time and I know she won't be
here but uh Carol I saw I saw red but
it's not Carol Carol is magnificent at
working with all of you at working with
me and handling all the hotel
arrangements say goodbye to her when you
pass the desk
thank you that I'll tell her that that
means a lot David Gilbertson our lead
engineer on loan from mission at this
time assisted by Dale Fay Larry Blanc
Theresa Raymond is helping out with real
media our real media guru is here this
time as well Jason Russell don khon
helps Carol with everything she does
Betty Burt keeps an eye on all of us as
our information services manager back at
Merrit thank you to all these companies
for the support you provide it means a
lot to Cisco yesterday for feeding his
breakfast quas metric cost metrics today
and force 10 yesterday afternoon
companies who would like to be the sole
participants at a break and be sitting
at a table with a couple of your
engineers with equipment at any of the
meetings let us know we really
appreciate the support and thank you so
much to these companies thanks also to
our beer and gear folks from last night
Duane whistles troops out to wherever we
are from Boulder for all of our meetings
handles lots of stuff for us as you can
see here and I've put up a very subtle
picture of his second book which is like
just out it's um called the definitive
guide to squid its first book was on web
caching that's what Duane started doing
for us up but he just handles all kinds
of other services for us now I'll take
the second bullet here thank you so much
for being here thank you to all the
speakers just we had wonderful speakers
this time if you borrowed a wireless
card remember to return it and we are
eager to clean up so we will have to
clean you up if you are still in here
after a while so goodbye oh now yeah
sign off and yeah we're leaving that
means that you get to sign off now