okay i have 56 slides in 30 minutes so
i'm not going to keep the average okay
i'm going to take you back really about
16 to 20 years there was just too much
foundational stuff between 85 and 90 to
talk about and basically this is what
I've lived in the last 15 to 20 years so
i'm going to give you my humble opinion
of what failed and what succeeded and
tell you where where I believe the ideas
really came from there was a lot of
original ideas and as Scott said this
morning there were a lot of things that
were imitated so will first start with
communication model layer 2 or layer 3
which is the best way to go datagrams
our connections who won which is the
best way to go different forms or modes
of communication like point-to-point
multi-point anycast broadcast and then
what network layers have we've seen in
the last 15 years and there's the
plethora of network layer protocol so to
speak and then we'll go into the routing
protocols specifically and just going to
focus on the unicast protocols because
there was a ton of protocols over the
past 20 years as well if i have time
which i think i won't i could talk about
management and security if i'm certainly
not an expert at that so there's much
more qualified people in the room to
talk about that so might have to skip
the last part layer 2 or layer 3 what's
the communication model in the mid
eighties uh bridging was really the
popular form of doing communication or
building networks transparent bridging
was the ethernet base side of connecting
lands together ethernet lands in
particular and source rob bridging was
used by IBM to connect token rings
together and they were fundamentally
different technologies even though they
both ran at layer 2 at that time the
layer 3 network layer protocols were IP
xns from z rock and
appletalk decnet face floor had been
around for a long time and a lot of
research and science environments and
deck was at that time converting to
decnet phase five novell had IPX and
those were the deployments in pc based
networks land bridge 100 was actually
the first multi port bridge that came
out before that there were bridges but
there were only two port bridges and
they were mostly transparent bridging
type bridges which means if I see a
frame on this interface I examine the
source address and i learned that source
address so if anything's destined to
that address i know to send it here well
if you're going to send something from
this source and you don't know that the
destination lives on there from that
frame then you send it over to the other
one what's really easy was just to porch
go back and forth and it was quite
simple but the land bridge 100 gave you
the multi port bridge works there was
three or more ports which means you
could build much more interesting
topologies layer 2 topologies of course
that was running at 10 megabits per
second because that was the original
speed for ethernet phase 1 of ethernet
however IBM came out with token ring and
it was running at 16 megabytes of people
were interested to get the extra
bandwidth increase but that required
source route bridging where the actual
source host stack would actually find
all the paths from a source to a
destination or from itself to a
destination and to be able to choose
paths so what happened at that point
moving forward his deck started doing a
100 megabit per second lands because
ftdi just started coming out now we were
having these bridges that were actually
now being multimedia bridges do we could
bridge between FDDI and ethernet problem
there was the encapsulation formats
weren't the same so you really had to do
some really funny things and there was
all kinds of not only were the
encapsulation not the same they had
different lengths so you had to worry
about MTU issues going from one media to
the other then vital in took bridging
one one step further and they wanted to
bridge lands across a point-to-point
infrastructure wide area infrastructure
using 56 kilobits and using some
arbitrary topologies
a lot of people in this room know that
loops in a topology and a layer 2
network are extremely dangerous and
layer two frames don't have ttls which
means of packets going Lupe's they
continue to go on loops until you take
something down this is not good moving
into the wide area cascade and for built
frame relay and ATM switches switches
here you got to use that term very
loosely because that's the trendy turned
out for bridges in this talk I'm saying
a bridge is a layer 2 device that looks
at madhatters layer 2 switches or layer
3 switches confuse this matter quite a
bit as well but we're looking at cascade
an ATM or cascading for is doing layer 2
things below the protocols that I
mentioned these bridges were not kind of
nice because they could support anything
that a host would send out you just it's
just the frame it's on Ethernet it's on
token ring or FDDI you just send it
these bridges tried to be multimedia but
it was very difficult on the other hand
Latin netbios which really didn't have a
network layer and no address ability per
se at the network layer were easier to
bridge basically there was just too much
functionality put into bridges and they
were not scaling they were melting down
networks left and right by the way this
talk is a cola has i put in a collection
of badges or buttons that i've
accumulated over the last 20 years so
i'm going to share all the buttons with
you and this is one that i had to keep
because if you if you want to know if
there's any router bigots out there
you're definitely looking at one right
now routers did it exists for a long
time during you know the commercial
success of bridges was continuing in the
mid 80s but routers were we're doing
things at that time BBN built the
original packet switches for military
and lat and National Lab type
applications deck was building decnet
routers and Apple was building routers
to do plug and play in workgroups and
novell and three camera building
protocols operating systems
and networks to do pc lands as i
mentioned at that time the two premiere
router companies were proteon cisco they
started building multi-protocol routers
because they saw that that bridges
weren't able to you know live up to the
task of doing all these different things
so they picked the largest set of
popular protocols and they switched all
those protocols at the network layer but
then against due to the commercial
success and the ease of use of bridges
protein and Cisco as router companies
from their heritage felt that they
needed to do bridging as well and then
you started seeing these devices which
were called hybrid routers or Browder's
which actually did bridging and routing
depending you know you could you could
bridge for lat and you could route for
IP and if you want it to be able to do
concurrent bridging and routing you
could actually do it for the same
protocol so these devices are getting
pretty complex routers were better than
bridges and these sort of attributes
routers dealt with unlike media much
easier don't forget in the mid 80s to
late 80s time frame we not only had a
thur net and token ring an FDDI but we
also had SMS MDS x.25 frame relay ATM
didn't hit the scene yet that you can
see where things are going these were
different media's from the network
layers point of view and of course
routers could deal with arbitrary
topologies you could have lots of loops
lots of cycles in the graph and they
could deal with a much better because
they they did routing and addressing a
much more sophisticated level routers
dealt with inner organizational
connectivity much better from a bridges
point of view of a port on a on my on my
box as a port on my box I don't treat it
or distinguish it differently than any
other port where in it routers can you
can use demarcation points and say this
is a boundary to another organization I
want to do route filtering or I want to
run an interesting protocol bridges were
better than routers in these respects
they could build cheaper price per port
was an order of magnitude cheaper I
don't know why it was that way just
turned out to be that way routers could
have built routers router vendors could
have built routers really cheap but it
just didn't turn out that
way people like Bridget's because they
had little configuration since
everything was done at the mac layer you
didn't have to configure subnets or or
aggregation or anything like that the
MAC addresses were always factory
installed in all the devices and you
would just learn them in during the data
plane and do the right forwarding and a
lot of people thought you had to be a
neck and just I guess the definition of
an expert is if you have to do anything
more than plug the power in you have to
be an expert so a lot more bridge
vendors and router vendors and that and
that caused the price purport to be
driven down even more so so we have
three interesting battles that happen
during this time frame which data link
was going to win is it going to be
Ethernet or token ring and in the wide
area is it going to be ATM or pause you
heard john curran say this morning that
the best way to connect a router to a
network is to connect it directly to the
fiber nothing between the router and the
fiber is the cost most cost efficient
way of doing things so we'll see who won
there and then what device type do you
should use routers or should you use
bridges so the Battle of Ethernet versus
token ring existed for nearly ten years
and it was basically IBM against Dec it
was really cool and there was also these
you know that this public domain set of
people that was running tcp/ip that tend
to like Ethernet as well workstation
vendors the Sun and the SG eyes of the
world adopted Ethernet mostly and of
course the pc vendors the novellas and
the x and s is also adopted Ethernet so
who won is pretty obvious that ethernet
one and Ethernet now they're building
standards to go at 10 gigabits per
second on Ethernet so that's pretty
that's pretty amazing the battle for ATM
vs. paws existed for about five years i
had when i worked at cisco a lot of
people told me that if cisco going to
came out with paws five years earlier
than they did for systems wouldn't exist
i don't know if that's true or not but
that's what people have told me the
promise of ATM to the desktop was way
too ambitious there was just building a
lair to infrastructure across the world
and assuming everybody would have the
same interfaces on all computers and all
devices was just kind of unrealistic but
ATM did make it
to the core it was a it was a nice way
of connecting routers together because
there was a point where ds3 was just not
enough people needed more bandwidth and
OC 3 no c12 was only available via an
ATM interface via force which so that's
why people jumped to the ATM based kors
pause or packet over sonet is basically
just running IP over the sonnet framing
layer and allowed high-speed connections
between routers this was beautiful this
really simplified things was just a data
link with simple hdl-c or PPP
encapsulation and you could run all your
favorite protocols your network layer
protocols over it so who won the battle
pause really won again for simplicity
it's amazing how far the KISS principle
can take you and now the nowadays
there's more chip vendors doing pausing
ATM because they see the current going
in the opposite direction and it is an
amazing today we can use that old
protocol called IP that's been around
since the mid 70s that can run over a
new new layer ones pause layer at 10
gigabits per second in the wide area
network that's quite amazing so what
type of devices should we use routers or
bridges well the old adages bridge where
you can route where you must bridges are
good for workgroups and if you don't
have too many bridge hops you won't get
into trouble because once you have a lot
of redundancy then you have to deal with
spanning tree and if you want to build
an abstraction layer on top of that and
run VLANs you have to run a spanning
tree pervy land bridges are very good as
a core fabric a lot of the i-x es are
basically just switches that connect
routers into it you can't get into
trouble there even though some of the
IHC operators will say that alone is a
challenge don't forget your broadcast
and multicast applications they
basically those sort of applications
will unscaled own ta bilal if you put
them in a bridge Network because packets
are really going everywhere regardless
of all the fancy protocols you put in to
try to help that problem so I'd really
have to change that first quote to say
bridge make use bridges and make them
localize your subnets and route
everywhere else just use them as a
concentration points of hosts and let's
face it switches really got popular
host wanted more than 10 megabits per
second and when you put multiple hosts
on a land on a shared media collisions
would give you effectively thirty
percent of that so by you having a
point-to-point connection which you're
nearby switch gives you a full 10
megabits per second and i think that's a
useful function of a bridge so who won
well I think routers will never lose
they've been around for 25 years if not
longer bridges are commercial success
through this the ethernet ubiquity the
simplicity of Ethernet cause switches to
be used and they're cheap and they're
plug and play and that's still that that
goes along with the KISS principle as
well so the communication model this is
always fun this went on for so many
years datagrams versus connections is it
better to have a connection oriented
network or a packet network or a
connectionless network with less state
there was always these terms about hard
state versus soft state where TCP has
hard state but IP has soft state well on
my point of view me as a software
developer I have to do a Mallick in both
cases so it's pretty hard to me so some
of the connection oriented protocols
were like x.25 SNA ATM frame relay these
were all using connection oriented
protocols or quote hard state below the
network layer and then the various
Network layer protocols like I p x 10's
IPX appletalk decnet all used
connections at the transport layer were
meant to be end to end and not between
devices in a network and the packets
that were sent between the network were
actually datagrams or or connectionless
entities and then each packet would have
its own address ability and you could be
able to rear out faster everything data
grams is you know motherhood and apple
pie OSI wanted to support both types of
models because there was forces from
different parts of the world where CL NS
was the connectionless network service
and cons was the connection oriented
network service the OSI even wanted cons
to work over ethernet and ethernet is
naturally framed or Datagram based and
that adopted i triple e to build 8022 as
a standard
connections well SNA was a proprietary
protocol so one company can control the
technology and they felt that
connections would provide a predictable
quality of service and that's what they
needed for the financial apps that were
running over their protocols x.25 had
had a lot of influence from ccitt where
it was again more phone company
orientation where connections were
important in fact the next 25 a lot of
people would think that x.25 was a
connection-oriented protocol itself well
it was actually a packet layer that
actually built and user connections as
well as building connections between
devices on a network like routers and it
was really the data link that was
underneath it that was providing the
reliability and retransmission and air
control sort of functions and as some
examples of x.25 networks that were
fairly large networks that we're using
internally packet switches that you
didn't see you couldn't see it you
couldn't do the traceroute like scott
said and be able to see the hops inside
of telenet but telling it in time that
were US base x.25 networks transpac was
a large x.25 network in france and data
pack in germany ATM and frame relay like
mines were also from the circuit switch
oriented world and signals and data and
everything had to go over one technology
over the entire Earth and that just
didn't make sense why if I wanted to
talk to somebody on the other side of
the globe why would there have to be 15
concatenated connections across all the
devices between me and that person on
the other side of the world the
connections could run over Datagram
network but it was harder to run
datagrams over a connection-oriented
network and I I've implemented as so
many times but trying to get IP to work
over data links like x.25 like ISDN like
ATM we're getting a firehose worth of
data and you have to open up a VC to be
able to get the packet to the next hop
well what do you do with all those
packets that are coming in do you drop
all of them do you cue the first one DQ
the last one do you cue the most recent
one what do you do these are hard
problems of solving routers so it was
pretty unnatural to have datagrams run
over a connection-oriented network I was
hard to have connections over each media
type known to man some networks
basically are not connection oriented
and it's also hard to do qos on each
media type Ethernet doesn't have a
quality of service so if you're going to
run a connection-oriented service that
provides quality service over something
it doesn't what good is it going to give
you and why do you need reliable
connections on a reliable link it's just
putting too much belt and suspenders and
you're going to have in efficiencies and
slowness the performance of the system
will just go down most data connection
protocols run in data link mode so for
instance if you want to run 8022 over
ethernet even though there is a cons
mode to it everybody uses unnumbered
information frames which may basically
is saying oh yes we can run TCP or UDP
over this particular data link but we'll
just run UDP so hdl-c and PPP right now
run over point-to-point links in a
connectionless mode most of the dynamic
connection mode protocols run in PVC
mode so the firehose problem that I just
mentioned usually doesn't happen because
the pvcs are set up ahead of time your
next hops are known through your routing
protocol and so when you're ready to
forward data the PVC or those that the
infrastructure is there and ready at
your service datagrams well most of the
host based vendor protocols are Datagram
oriented and all those protocols you see
up there are ones that actually send
data grams into the network at the
network layer and the ubiquity of
Ethernet and other Datagram oriented
data looks allowed Datagram Network
layers to run effortlessly over links
and of course this is the data grams and
packet switches require less States well
a routing table versus a socket or
connection identifier is is pretty much
the same so maybe it's a mood argument
or a subtle argument so who won
datagrams vs. connections in my mind it
was the data grams
let's go into communication modes
there's two parte communication which
the most popular form of communication
point-to-point there's one the many many
to many few too many that's all the
multi-point mode and then there's this
closest parte communication let me get
to the closest server also known as any
caste which we've exploited really only
in the last I'd say five to seven years
in IP and trying to formalize it in ipv6
and of course all parte communication is
broadcast how many people in this room
have tried to send a packet to everybody
on the internet and why would you want
to do that and why is that useful so
within a reasonable scope is broadcast
useful so layer two Datagram protocols
could do unicast multicast anycast in
broadcast the land itself worked really
well and it was a really passive type
multi-party communication model because
you would just program your land
controller and then the land controller
would just listen on the wire for those
addresses you didn't have to go tell
somebody you wanted to listen to
something outside the box layer 2
connection protocols could only do
unicast and multicast like ATM could had
some form of doing multi-point VCS but
it was a switch V scene you'd have to
set it up ahead of time but really when
you're running in PVC mode you had to
simulate this multi-point sort of
communication by doing replication over
the same physical link and that was not
good for bandwidth savings so it was
really only the network players that
could really support all these really
different modes in a robust and scalable
way everybody will claim that they
support it but in a robust and scalable
way mostly the network layer protocols
could do it and not all network layer
protocols could do it and if you look at
that list right there x 10's had
point-to-point communication but only
really had linked local broadcast and
deck had point-to-point link local
multicast and link local broadcast an
apple talk was really the only one that
really went to a multihop multicast
early on they had broadcast and
multicast applications because of the
type of applications and the ease of use
they wanted to provide to the user but
when you look at everything
together really IP and ipv6 have all the
communication modes and they've been
studied and experimented and are really
the more robust and scalable way of
going so for most support who won well
like I said appletalk really had the
applications to back the multicast mode
the chooser the directory services print
sharing file sharing all that stuff you
have to give Apple credit that they they
were able to deploy that stuff much
earlier than IP did but I p learned from
that and use those sort of things a lot
of the ideas of DHCP came from Apple
talk on how to do address assignment you
know dhcp does not date back to the mid
70s it's one of the later protocols that
came into the to the internet sweet IP
as a scale billion and has the more
robust network layer support because the
whole world works on IP not just one
vendor and you get the good and the bad
associated with that so I think all
other variants failed and i think ipv6
is trying to have the same promises ipv4
Gabe and that will remain to be seen
with more experimentation and deployment
experience so why so many network layer
protocols well at the time there was
really no rapidly defined standards IBM
was around for a long time and they had
to focus on their applications and they
wanted to control their own destiny so
hence S&A was proprietary Xerox was out
of pretty much at the same time and felt
the same way and they had a lot of
experience building SBP as the transport
and novell was going after a market that
they saw growing pcs were getting cheap
Ethernet swere simple to plug in they
were going after that market they
couldn't wait for the ITF community or
the tcp/ip community to come up with
standards so they went the wrong way and
of course everybody knows that deck was
just been around for a long time and
they had their idea in fact deck had a
lot of good influence into the ITF over
many years or many generations of people
and protocols and of course Apple was
doing the same thing that novell was
doing but they were doing it with their
proprietary gear and they were building
really cool stuff so that's why
everybody was going off their own way
and at the same time there was this
tcp/ip protocols
we that was in the military in research
labs and a lot of the UNIX is
implemented them a lot of the like 4.1
4.2 timeframe of unix PSD had x 10's and
a lot of those implementations were a
lot of a lot of people were
transitioning from an access protocol
stack to IP and work the new workstation
vendors at the time was sun an SGI dance
support for tcp/ip so all the public
domain code was all running over IP and
it was in the small community of
researchers and scientists and that's
how ECPI p started and there were router
vendors back then that we're building
routers for the good of the internet and
not necessarily for their commercial
success even though they all became
fairly successful in their own right BBN
acc bridge proteon cisco are some of the
early pioneers and you know DARPA and
NSF put a lot of funding into this stuff
and that's why I p became the de facto a
lot of people pride themselves on
calling it the de facto standard because
it it just permeates all this real
reality and what's going on and you have
to admit that the internet really didn't
take off until it was embedded in
windows ninety tcp/ip was embedded in
Windows 95 that coupled with the web
becoming popular really made it take off
to the huge masses of people and hence
we have the big commercial Internet as
we know today well what was wrong with
tcp/ip it wasn't an international
standard hmm ISIL was building
full-blown standards not just at the
network layer but all the way up the
stack layer one all the way up to layer
seven are arguably all the way up to
layer eight which is the political layer
the US government proposed gossip which
was a mandate for new contracts we
cannot buy your products unless you have
an OSI stack it doesn't need to be
turned on it doesn't need to be
configured but as long as it's in the
implementation we know someday we can go
to it so deck was a huge supporter of
osai and decadent phase five was a
complete implementation of OSI but what
about the internet applications that
people grew grow to love what did they
could they run over OSI well I mean in
theory they could run over
but since there is a all these other you
know virtual terminal and f tam which
were the equivalents we don't need those
applications because we're just going to
duplicate it on the OSI side hmm so
bottom line it just took so long for
vendors to feel those I products and
there were a lot of people in the ITF
that actually tried to build co NS based
networks and did to a certain extreme we
had a dual stack internet for a long
time in the late 80s Early 90s it was
dual stack for and it was CL NS&I p but
i always remember that the only seal
honest package that were flown around
were ping packets to test the reach
ability so OS I just didn't just didn't
happen and it was really the standard by
the you know build your protocols by
committee sort of way of doing things
and I etfs model was always rough
consensus and working code and you know
a lot of people say well there's pros
and cons on going both ways but when you
when a when the ITF or the Internet
community built a protocol you knew that
it was tested out already and it just
wasn't something on a piece of paper so
that had a lot of merit and that's I
think part of the success of the
Internet so who won which network layer
protocol one it should be obvious the
power of tcp/ip so in the mid-90s IP had
some problems or at least there were
some perceived problems 32-bit addresses
that's not enough address space it's too
hard to reassign dresses to rotting
domains how are you going to be able to
switch from one is pd another are we
going to get vendor lock riding to the
the routing domain multihoming problem
was exploding the routing table size the
sky is following we better do something
right away when was this soo in 95 94 95
96 timeframe well we're still here and
and i think the network is as good as
it's ever gotten I mean what other
network could move around as much spam
as we have how do we solve the ipv4
problem well there was a interesting
committee I think Paul will talk a
little bit about this but there was this
committee called Road routing and
addressing there were a bunch of people
that got together to figure out how to
do some things Ellen that was a
like way of solving the problem and I
pay was a way of putting encapsulation
into an IP and using another level of 32
bit of dressing the same 32-bit
addressing that we do use today but it
was on top of what was going to be in
the users 32-bit headers so that was one
way OSI was also considered as a
replacement to ipv4 again and then those
were the various proposals on their
knees hip hip catnip tuba Nimrod and Big
Ten Big Ten was a was probably the
protocol that had the most could have
had the most success in the shortest
amount of development time basically a
bunch of people got together at I
airport close to o'hare got to get it
together at a hotel close to o'hare
airport just to come up with a scheme
and at that point it was an argument
between variable length addresses in
fixed length addresses so what happened
is sip was a proposal for a bite
addresses and so based on the influence
from Big Ten it was obvious that eight
was too small and variable length wasn't
going to happen so the compromise by
committee was let's have 16 byte
addresses and that's how IP version 6
was born and there was more merchandise
to became available tese actually what
tube stands for his TCP and UDP with
bigger addresses this is a way you could
run all the internet applications and
TCP and UDP over a new network layer and
its associated protocols and that was
going to be seal and ass is to IOUs EST
is and all those protocols and funny
highest I is is a very popular protocol
today what's good about ipv6 well
there's no ad hoc standards anymore a
lot of people said ARP was specified
because the they looked at the C code
and then translated into English those
sort of things aren't happening in ipv6
it's really more of a standard base it's
kind of merging OSI and and and ietf and
using the best of both worlds or the
worst of both both worlds so so it was
designed both by her host and router
vendors and like the ITF way was built
through implementation
okay we're not gonna say what's bad
about IP ipv6 so I'm like severely
behind and everybody wants to hear about
I GPS okay so let's go to routing
protocols real quick now what what about
the plethora of routing protocols did we
have too many that we learn from our
past sins well we started with Ray okay
this is going to be the nutshell of
everything we started with rip and EGP
that defined the IGP EGP split we needed
two protocols one that runs in the
domain one that runs between domains
everybody like trip because it was easy
to understand you could do route
filtering ggp and EGP were the inter a
as protocols that were run in the early
days of the mill net in the ARPANET okay
bgp was a successor of these protocols
okay this was the rip EGP couple they
ran for a long time and a lot of vendors
products Cisco thought that that wasn't
sufficient had to provide a proprietary
solution to it katie was the public
domain version of it proteon came out
with ospf and high etf was working on
bgp who's going to talk about bgp there
was a war between is Dyson ospf bottom
line is enterprise runs almost PF
service providers when I is the ayahs
and I could talk to you in the bar
tonight why that was useful and this was
the first set of vendors that
implemented ospf sues going to talk
about BGP even though ospf ania sites
were becoming deployed the router
vendors believe that there was still a
need for their own protocols and so
Cisco is working on eigrp novell was
working on mlsp but finally what
happened in the late 90s is more I GOP
networks move to ospf and today we can
say we really have three protocols that
are running and they're very mature
implementations from dozens of vendors
and that's all SPF is tyas and bgp
definitely no mention
you did it okay can I do my last slide
so it as a software developer I believe
that the internet is succeeding because
of open-source public domain learning
through experience and evolution and you
just can't live without it anymore
thanks Ben surf