thank you I'm gonna talk today about the
work I did in AT&T during this summer
with a man shake Tim Griffin and
Jennifer Rexford on the interaction of
OSPF and BGP and you're gonna see how
hot potatoes are hitting up our BGP
routing so first of all most people when
they think about BGP they think about
intradomain routing mainly and then talk
about ok routing in southern areas we
think of OSPF is is but in large transit
areas most of the traffic is actually
routed using BGP and IP changed so
things that happen inside the network
can and do have impact in the BGP
decisions so in this work are trying to
understand how these interactions happen
and mainly it happens because of hot
potato routing so let's look at this
simple example of an IP network where we
have routers in San Francisco New York
and Dallas imagine now we have
destination outside so external this
nation to these areas with two equally
good routes that are learned in San
Francisco in New York
and Dallas has to the students of routes
one of cost 9ig because 9 to reach the
destination and the other one with cost
10 so in this case hot potato routing
tells us that Dallas would choose the
exit point with closes IDP distance to
forward traffic to this destination so
imagine that something internal habit of
failure or some plan maintenance or even
traffic engineering that made the cost
from the path to Dallas to San Francisco
to change from 9 to 11 so now in this
example the all the the routes are being
forwarded through San Francisco going to
start using the exit point in New York
and that's what we are calling here a
hot potato change so the BGP routes look
the same
just changed because of the IGP cost in
this example I'm just showing it for one
destination prefix but in a big trans
Network you have it may have thousands
of destinations shifting from Mon egress
point to the other just because of a
small cost change inside the network and
this has consequences for so during this
the time that the traffic shifting you
may have trans routing instability and
the track shift may cause congestion in
in this path which will cause delays and
losses and some of these may be exported
to external bgp to your neighbors and
the reason that there is this
interaction between those two is that
BGP uses IGP information in its decision
process first of all of course has to
check if the next hop is reachable and
it uses AGP then if all the other
attributes look the same so if the
routes are equally good from BGP
standpoint they need to do the hot
potato check so to check if which one
has lowest Deepika and in this work what
we want to understand is so how much
that's the impact of hot potato routing
in a real network so why do we care
about for hot potatoes so first of all
there is a large number of prefix that
can be potentially affected so all
prefix that we learn from peers are
learned in lots of different pops and
may be affected by hot potato and all
motorhome customers so the customers
that pay more also may be affected by
hot potato routing so we want to
understand the impact now and real
networks how often does hot potato
routing causes bgp routes to shift and
when this change happened
how many prefix are impacted what's the
fraction of our BGP table that's
changing because of the this shift and
also what's the delay from an IG P
change to to the time that the BGP
routes a converge so and after
ultimately what we want to do is to try
to avoid routing instability caused by
hot potato so operators should try to
minimize the number of times that the
hot potato chains happen and for the
vendors the messages so how if the hot
potato has to happen so if you have to
change your BGP routes because something
happened inside a network how can you
minimize the impact of that by making
this interaction as smooth as possible
our approach to do that is to we measure
hot potato changes in 18 T's Network so
we collected measurement of both OSPF
and BGP methods in the common backbone
for each in C and we have one OSPF
monitor that collects all the link state
advertisements and a BGP monitor that
has feeds of tables and updates from at
least one router per pop in the common
backbone we process we process these
messages to cluster them in time so that
we can get clear events for both the
west PF and BGP and then we correlate
this these two streams of data so the
idea here is to emulate one operational
router and we can see all the changes
there SPF changes from that router point
of view and also the BGP updates that it
sends here's just an example of how we
do this matching so first we have to
transform the stream of OSPF messages
dialysis into changes with the router
that we are trying to simulate the point
of view of that router so you mentioned
that you have this series of methods
refresh link failures which change
things like that and then we transform
them
- this volatile quantity also refresh
message don't we don't really care about
them so a link failure may cause the
path strong the our point of view to a
lot of the egress points to change costs
may cause some of them to be deleted and
so we just classify that we also look at
the BGP side we get a stream of BGP
updates I'm not going to explain exactly
how I do this if you are interested in
in my webpage you can find some more
detail on that but to classify all the
BGP updates according to how if they
could be caused by an or SPF event or
not in which kind of voice path event
could cause that update and then we
match them in time so in this case I put
an example of this path cost change that
caused a couple of BGP updates to happen
so how much nice now we wanna try to
answer acquired so how how much of this
really happened in the TNT network so we
I'm presenting here some results that I
found for June last year and I am
presenting the results for two routers I
chose one router in a path with rich
peering so where it in C appears with
all the other big guys all the tier ones
and another path with no peering so
there is no no peering that path and we
see the first table it shows the
percentage of updates in a day that was
caused by OSPF and we can see that in a
pop of rich peering it doesn't really
have much OSPF hot potato related
updates and but in the pub with no
peering it varies from of course there
is some days that there is no updates or
caused by hot potato but there are some
days that go up to 46% of the updates in
a day that were caused by hot potato and
you can see the last column of this
table it shows you for the month of June
the percent of drug day is the number of
the
had more than 10% of updates caused by
hot potato and in this for the gnome
peering round to recede that there are
five days so now answer the first
question hot potato
does happen and it can have some impact
but how much is the this impact so now
we have the second table that shows for
one LSA one or SPF let's say what was
the impact that it costs the good news
is so most of the LSA is around 95% for
both routers doesn't cause any impact so
it doesn't impact it doesn't generate
any bgp update but for a small
percentage of the Alice's that do impact
bgp they can have a significant impact
for the router if no peering we thought
we saw a day in which 90 59 percent of
the BGP table change because of one
single event inside the network so we
understand now that this hot potato can
have a significant impact but how long
does it take after the OSPF change
happened for the BGP updates to come out
so we can divide this this delay in
three three different parts first the
router has to learn after the OSPF
converts and OSPF route is installed you
have to you have to revisit your PCP
decision too and see how long does it
take so this depends a lot on
implementation in the router and there
are different ways of doing it so you
can do in a time a timer based so every
X seconds you run a timer that process
that will revisit your decision and then
you can update your BGP routes according
to your OSPF information or it can be
even driven whenever something happens
in OSPF that who is going to be
reflected into a BGP decision
after that so in the case of ATT and
lots of big networks there is an IB GP
hierarchy and you may you may also have
to wait for your rod reflector to tell
you that your of the new route you may
not know of the the route that has the
shortest path from you now and so that's
a something that's an hour delay and all
this this tube first points takes the
delay from whence the OSPF can happen
it's you BGP learns about the change and
then of course if you're changing fifty
nine percent of your routing table it
may take a while to transfer all these
updates until the last up to the updates
gonna come out so let's see now what we
owe first of all so that's one thing
that's very important is so this delay
is a very sensitive both to the router
implementations and the design of your
network and I'm gonna show here one
example that we saw in the eighteen t
network first this graph it shows the
time difference so when I saw the LSA so
the time that I saw the first update I
came for that LSA and in the y-axis see
the fraction of hot potato changes
cumulative fraction and first of all
let's look at the the blue curve we did
some lab experiments with a router and
we we can see that in this case that we
have a uniform distribution in the range
from zero to around 60 seconds which
suggests that this rather had a timer
base implementation to for the OSPF bgp
interaction so in this straight line
just means that the OSPF event can
happen in any time in this range from
zero to sixty and depending when it
happens then it's gonna see a higher or
lower delay up to sixty seconds you can
see that in the than there are two other
lines it's for the operational routers
that we are emulating using the data we
collected and one line is for the month
of june and the other for the month of
September and you can see that it also
has this the 60-second timer of course
the lines not so straight because I just
used I mean the events that happen in
the network and they're not as many
samples as the blue line but you can
also see that there is this part of the
curve there in the end that has a little
bit longer delays and we contractor now
that that's because of the ibgp
hierarchy that we may have to wait for
two runs of the timer for some of these
of these routes now let's look at how
long does it take for transferring all
the multiple prefixes again I'm showing
the time between the LSA and the BGP
update and here I just chose three
sample events that caused lots of
updates and I'm showing on the y-axis
the cumulative number of hot potato
changes and it's just a cumulative
number of updates that that particular
OSPF event caused let's just look at the
red curve because all of them are
similar just different events so we can
still it starts around 25 seconds let's
say and so that means that the BGP
process run at 25 seconds after the OSPF
event happened and then it can take ups
too it took 81 seconds to transfer all
this because this event caused more than
80,000 prefixes to shift and so the
bottom line here is that in the worst
case scenario we can take around 100 120
seconds to revisit your decision and
then you may take 80 seconds more to
transfer all the rods so the last prefix
may take up to three minutes to to get
updated to get installed in the fable
and we didn't even count the time and to
install the new prefix in the feeb and
so what the implications that is have
for in your near for forwarding packets
so first
the FIB is only going to be updated when
both your IDP and your BGP converge so
people talk a lot about the IGP converse
that's important because of course that
has to happen first but if your BGP
didn't converge all the external routes
are didn't convert yet and the second
question we had is do the measurements
we have today to measure the customer
experience and of the network do they
cap to catch these kinds of performance
degradations so first let's look of how
this can impact the forwarding
conversions so imagine now this example
in the in the top where he had routers
r1 and r2 both using the egress points
you're right there and imagine that the
cost to that link changed from 10 to 111
so what's gonna happen is that in the
end both are 1 and our twos are going to
shift to the egress point in the left
but depending on the order that these
the the timer runs the BGP decision is
revisiting each of these routers what
can happen imagine this following
scenario that the hour to revisit this
decision first then it starts using our
1 to forward packets to this particular
destination then our 1 runs but you
don't know how long it's gonna take it
may take up to 60 seconds for a run to
revisit its decision and all this time
the packets to the destination are going
to be caught in a loop between r1 and r2
and now let's see if how can we detect
these loops can you imagine this can we
see if these are actually happening in
the network so today the way that the
measuring of the cosmic experience work
we put some two machines W 1 and W 2
that will try to measure this but this
loop is only happening for this
particular destination so if you probe
from W 1 so W 2 even though you're
probably the same path you're not gonna
catch your traffic it's not going to be
in this loop so now how can you avoid
unnecessary changes of course sometimes
just have to change but can we do
something can we try to avoid it so we
see that router with the router in a pop
with no peer see many more of these
changes in a router and a popovich
peering so how can we play with the
topology to make to avoid this changes
and also can we do maintenance plan
maintenance in a better way that will
not cause these hot potato changes so
first look at this 3 Toyota polities
here you can see that the the topology
so if from Dallas to San Francisco we
have just Karsten and from Dallas to New
York have cost 10 any little change in
your network is likely to make the
shortest path shift and so this is much
more prone to have hot potato changes
whereas the other two so if Dallas is
really close to San Francisco and really
far away from New York there has to be a
big change in the network to Dallas to
shift from one to the other and the same
thing that in the bottom one if you have
multiple paths that are equally good in
terms of IGP distance then it's also
harder for it to change it may be think
of oh of course it's very easy to do
that and the stoy examples but how can I
do that in my network so yeah I don't
have the answer for that yet but it's
just to give you some food for thought
you know your network and you may be
able to so it's just something else that
you should think of when you do your
traffic engineering when you when you're
doing your planning and tools for doing
that yeah of course we have to work on
that and that's something else that we
you can do is if you look at so how can
we if you're doing maintenance so
imagine you have to do maintenance in
the path from New York to San Francisco
and there's just again a tight apology
and now all your traffic is going
through San Francisco and you want to
take out
this link yonder Montanans there so what
can you do so if you if you just put it
to a very high cost all your traffic is
gonna start using the exit point two
dollars and you're gonna have all the
penalty of doing hot potato changes but
if you think of it ahead of time you can
change the cost of that middle link from
10:00 to 4:00 and then you can cause out
your link and all your traffic gonna
still be using the san francisco egress
point of course you have to wait for SPF
to converge in that example but all your
your BGP routes won't change so the
convergences or SPF times seconds
instead of minutes the traffic is much
more predictable faster and again as I
said before you have to judge how much
of you can do in a real network like
that but it's important to have tools
that will predict these kinds of changes
and will give you answers for that
so in conclusion show that hot potato
can have an effect on a large number of
prefixes and it does have higher
conversions delays so for the the
vendors the method here is even driven
implementations of the IGP bgp
interaction will help to minimize some
of the effects of course you still have
to wait for the path vector protocol to
converge on top of the link state but at
least the timer effects going to wait
it's something that amplifies the the
convergence delay and also once you do
your studies you have to look at in a
more network wide effect not only in the
box level because these events they are
very hard to just see how they they
happen in the box level and for the
operators of course you can tune your
timer
you know our network is you know how how
low we can put the timers down I can
tell you what the right values are
and you can try to play with some of the
examples I showed here in how to set up
your weights and to do maintenance in a
way that will avoid hot potato changes
for in our side we are trying to do some
work into quantifying the impact of hot
potato changes in in shifts of traffic
also trying to see if you can catch
these loops in the in the commercial
network to see if it's really happening
and also quantify how much of it is
exported to your neighbors because most
of these updates probably just ibgp
updates and don't go to to the neighbors
but we want to quantify how much of it
is happening so anyone has any questions
hi Rob Rob Renison Laurel networks these
are probably simple and first of all
regarding the the how we would react
yeah we would listen to rib changes and
obviously could be event-driven then
so if BGP I was trying to resolve its
next topic it listens to the IDP change
and would failover and in milliseconds
and then an observation which is the
fact that for some for some failures in
even in the like your first slide the
simplest of case mmm-hmm the only real
way to measure there would be no routing
change because BGP would just resolve
its own next stop failover to fail over
to another link and the only way you
could see any problem there would be by
traffic analysis and scenes of traffic
loss there are BGP changes yeah yeah
what I'm saying is for the for the
simplest of topology with one one router
one speaker advertising next stop self
and he's got two links to go to the one
of them fails he reader he changes his
own his own view of what the next stop
is and there's no impact he doesn't
withdraw the routes he just fixes
hundred thousand prefixes go to a next
hop so in the simple case you're not
going to see problems now obviously in a
real network with a more richly
connected to apology you made any
changes I'm sorry I think so my example
it was not a link it was a path so yeah
that's why I did the cut this squiggly
line because okay yeah but
that's probably cuz I'm getting here
your simple example but in terms of
correlation so an LSA is withdrawn once
again that's that's withdrawn for
finding the next talk I'm a speaker and
I'm advertising next top self and I see
an LSA withdrawn for for how I get to to
my next top what I've learned by ibgp
how do you correlate the LSA for the
prefix that I'm using to forward the
routes with you know the fact that I've
suddenly started with drawing all these
prefixes you know there's a time thing
about oh yeah yeah withdrawn but there's
no you don't I don't announce that what
was in that LSA so when we look at the L
essays and we look at how Dallas isn't
in fact affect the table for that
particular router and we look at the BGP
update and you see what kind of update
it is for which next hop and then we
manage them in time but it firemen helps
in the next stop so then or I'm
withdrawing routes through still it was
difficult to correlate because myself
hasn't changed the LSA was one that I
was using because that was announced by
my ibgp peers know between so we we get
we get so the data we have it so I bgp
data and so we get all this information
it's yeah for the for these routers okay
yeah