so diana has been the council for the
Science and Technology Directorate and
the homeland security projects at DARPA
Park coming to it she was with DARPA and
many of us have been really good friends
of DARPA's in the early years for nine
years where she developed national
expertise and innovated government
contracting she's a graduate of the
University of Colorado and the Thomas
cooley law system she reserved her LM in
intellectual property from George
Washington University which is very
prestigious and has to intellectual
property articles on government and
contracting please welcome her and give
her a good set of attention as you
notice that security thing like our
routes is going up into the right thank
you now I know that most of you the last
thing that she want to listen to is a
lawyer first thing in the morning and
not only a lawyer but a government
lawyer so we'll try to make this as
quick and painless as possible but there
has been a lot of legislation that's
come out in the last few years on
regulating what happens on the internet
and so it's useful to know what that is
so that you know how to answer any calls
that you might get for information or
how to protect yourself now a little bit
of history you all probably know this
better than I do but the internet began
as the ARPANET
in the 1960s and it was intended to be a
government computer system connecting
the east coast and the government on the
east coast with the academic community
on the west coast and its initial
purpose was to be a mechanism for the
government to talk to its individual
parts in the event of a nuclear war and
a breakdown of communications and for
many many years it was just used by
government folks and academics until it
was transferred to NSF in the 1980s
where it took on a whole new life unto
itself and grew exponentially now
because of its academic focus in the
beginning Congress left it alone for
most of its life and it was only when it
became more of a commercial sort of
aspect that Congress started taking a
look at it but as you well know Congress
is slow regulation riders are slow and
the laws did not keep up with the growth
of the internet and it's only in the
last few years that Congress has finally
taken a look and see the aspects of the
internet that they see all need to be
protected as the American people start
to complain about things like privacy so
let's talk a little bit about privacy
because that's where most of these laws
are focused is on protecting personal
privacy information and having come from
DARPA and having come from the home of
the infamous total information awareness
project I know a little bit about
privacy and how the American people feel
about it right now now in response to
concerns about information sharing into
the the continual education of the
American people about how much
information is on the internet about
them if you talk the majority of
Americans they have no idea the kinds of
information that
out there the kinds of things that are
about them on the internet and it's only
recently that they're becoming aware of
this because of the media so Congress
has passed a number of laws in the past
few years designed to protect the
privacy information that's out there and
to protect its cure their dissemination
on the Internet now having said that the
events of September 11th and the need
for the government to combat terrorism
has sort of put a quash on the number of
bills and laws that have been passed in
the last few years but there are still a
few out there that you need to be aware
of first of all a lot of the
organizations in the government are
using their existing laws to combat the
internet for many many years they could
not find the connection between laws
that affected what happened on paper to
what happens in the cyber world and
they're finally starting to come around
to apply some of these older laws to
what happens on the internet for
instance of Federal Trade Commission has
a privacy program that focuses on
ensuring that companies who have web
privacy policies actually follow them
and maintain them and do what they say
they're going to do and so most websites
now and most corporations have internet
privacy policies about how they're going
to collect information how they're going
to use it store it disseminate it and
secure it and the FTC is using its
section five of its of its underlying
Act which prohibits unfair accepted
practices to actually prosecute people
for not following their internal web
policies so if you have one be aware
that they are bringing actions to
enforce these promises in these policy
statements one of the first are one of
the most recent acts to come out is
called the gramm-leach-bliley act or the
financial Modernization Act of nineteen
ninety nine and you'll notice a trend
and several of these axes in response to
a lot of the problems that were having
lately with companies who seem to
inflate their financial standing or
inflate as an eyesore but actually lie
about how much profit they actually make
how much they're actually worth and a
lot of them have come crashing down like
Enron and if
others this one isn't is designed to
protect personal financial information
held by financial institutions now focus
on personal information it doesn't apply
to business information so information
about corporations or individual
companies is not what they're after here
it's personal privacy information you're
going to see that same thread through
all of these and a financial institution
is not just a bank but is also anyone
who offers financial products or
services like loan officers financial
investment insurance brokers and it's
also folks who handle information
generated by these people so it's not
only the financial institution
themselves but those who actually
receive the information from those
institutions for whatever reason and it
requires these financial institutions to
give privacy notices obviously this is
the wave of the future is to put a
privacy notice about how you're going to
collect this information how you're
going to share it now under this act
consumers do have an option to opt out
in other words they can opt out of
having their information shared with
third-parties however there can't do
this if the financial institutions
sharing it with a company that's going
to offer the financial institution
essential services so network services
billing services those sorts of things
or if it's shared with outside service
providers for marketing purposes so you
all need to be aware that if you receive
this sort of non-public information from
a financial institution if you have them
as a client and the consumer couldn't
opt out of providing it to you you can't
use it to sell that information you
can't use it for marketing and if they
could opt out and didn't you must use it
following the same privacy policy as the
financial institution which can put a
burden on you if you have many customers
who are financial institutions with a
bunch of different privacy policies
you're going to have to be aware of what
they are and you're going to have to
follow them as if you were the financial
institution yourself
now sarbanes-oxley is called officially
the public company accounting reform and
investor Protection Act this is covering
auditors financial auditors meant to be
in response to Enron and and all of
those big three auditing firms that had
little troubles about not being totally
honest in their audit capabilities what
its intended to do is actually put
accountability on the management and the
company who have this information and
choose not to protected so it only
covers public companies those who are
registered with the SEC the Securities
Exchange Commission and it requires them
to implement an internal control
framework to control to secure their
information and it requires corporate
management to be aware of the company's
policies into document and audit the
security policies they're now going to
come in and audit you on these they're
going to ask you for documentation to
make sure that everyone is aware of what
the policies are and everybody is
following them one of the older ones but
still one of the important ones because
the health the health community seemed
to take a long time and getting these
sort of things up and running is HIPAA
which is the health insurance
portability and accountability act this
covers federal our excuse me privacy of
personal health information the
government is trying to encourage the
health community to be more efficient
ergo be cheaper not likely but they're
trying in one of the ways that they
think this can happen is by getting rid
of all the paperwork involved with the
health coverage system with health plans
and putting everything on the web making
it all electronic well when you do that
security is of a great issue to most
people because you don't want all your
health information out there for anybody
to see or anybody to take so they've
implemented this act to try and require
health plans health care clearing houses
health care providers to secure the
personal health information of their
clients
particularly if the healthcare
information is transmitted back and
forth through an electronic form
particularly on the web now this privacy
rule protects individually identified
health information so it's only relating
to the people the personal information
of the health care recipient and it's
transmitted by a covered entity now this
includes health care plans health care
clearing houses health care providers
but doesn't necessarily cover any
incidental access that you might have to
the protected information so those of
you who are merely a conduit of this
information would not be covered under
this act but those of you who might hold
it for clients for a particular period
of time or store it would be covered by
this and would have to follow it now
clearly in the 20 minutes that I have
here I can't give you all the details of
all of these acts but what I'm trying to
do is educate you that they are out
there that they will require you to
maintain this information in a certain
way will require you to do a little
research for your clients if you're
going to handle things like financial
information and I would encourage you if
you have this sort of information to
delve a little further into these acts
with your with your legal counsel this
is not an advertisement for lawyers but
they do help sometimes now other laws of
interests that are unrelated to privacy
particularly for isps is one of them is
the Digital Millennium Copyright Act
this one is not particularly new but if
it continues to be litigated because
there's a lot of ambiguity and how these
sorts of things are going to be covered
what this does is places a limitation on
liability for copyright infringement on
online service providers for many years
anyone in the chain of a copyright
infringement could be sued like the
infringer themselves because what you do
when you you pass along that information
is it's just a rolling infringement of
that copyright but because of the nature
of online service providers Congress
finally recognized that they had no
control over the information itself and
often didn't even monitor what it was
but just passed it along as a conduit
and as a service so this act was passed
to protect the
service providers from being included in
any suit for copyright infringement so
it limits liability for acting as a data
conduit particularly off all you do is
transmission routing our connections or
making transient copies to allow a
network to operate so no longer could
you be included in a suit if all you did
was just provide the pipeline for this
information to travel to the ultimate
loser it also limits liability for
system caching for a long time caching
was considered a copy it is a copy which
would subject you to copyright
infringement should someone choose to
sue you because of this act no longer
can you be your liability is limited as
a service provider for caching
particularly system cashing it limits
your liability for infringing material
on websites and other cysts and other
information repositories on your system
places that responsibility back again on
the website provider or the website
drafter and no longer will well bring
you into the suit if you should be just
hosting an infringing website and it
also limits your liability for
hyperlinking or using search engines
that might link you to infringing
materials the mere fact that you provide
a link no longer subjects you to
copyright infringement now unfortunately
what it does do is allow the government
now to serve you with a subpoena to find
the names and the identities of
subscribers who might be engaging in
infringing activities so you will have
to maintain the records of your
subscribers and if should you be served
with a subpoena you're probably going to
have to give it up and so yet again more
need for lawyers another thing to
consider is coppa which is a children
Online Privacy Protection Act I can tell
you that although there hasn't been a
lot of movement in this area this is a
really hot button for Congress's
protecting children on the internet and
so although cope has come under fire
from a lot of different angle
I don't think that that anyone's going
to get away with just freely releasing
children's information so this
particular act is still enforced and
protects the privacy of children under
13 by requiring parental consent for
collection of use of the personal
information of any child and this is
only going to get more stringent because
everyone is concerned about protecting
children from things on the internet
that they shouldn't be seeing in use of
their information so people can contact
them this law in particular applies to
commercial websites and online services
and so you need to be aware that any
time that you're going to be hosting
children's information you're going to
be more scrutinized probably than less
and finally there is the u.s. Patriot
Act which is a very new Act it's still
not sure how it's going to be
implemented it's being litigated in a
number of areas because a lot of the
liberal community is very upset by the
Patriot Act it allows the government to
use many of its existing surveillance
tools that were never applied to the net
before to try and investigate domestic
terrorism related activities how far
this is going to stretch is going to be
anybody's guess I'm sure that over the
course of the next couple years as we
continue the war on terrorism this is
going to be tested over and over again
but it is going to facilitate
information sharing and cooperation
amongst government agencies which has
traditionally has been very poor to try
and find identify and deal with domestic
terrorism related activities
okay does anybody have any questions
so early everyone just can't
don't yes go ahead
how far past nice kick please get up and
use the microphone and all ioe well I
can repeat that one if you want how far
back do you have to record data working
yet yeah which it only goes back to the
passage of the Act it's not before so
it's not grandfather back to things
which you had before that yeah so in
2010 I'm going to have to know what my
users were doing in 1996 well having
said that you know copyright
infringement cases have a statute of
limitations and so they're usually
between two and three years so you're
not going to have to think about it's
not like your taxes where you have to
keep them for seven years it's only for
the life of a copyright infringement
case anyone else
okay thank you very much
hello back there there we go there we go
I think what the question was is if you
are recording let's say the mapping
between IP addresses and customers how
long do you have to keep that
information is there anything in the
statute or is it just keeping it from as
long as operationally required and if
the request for that binding comes in
from law enforcement during the time
you're keeping it you provided but you
have to keep it some extra special time
no there's no limitation in the statute
about how long you have to keep it its
really left up to you how long you feel
the need to protect yourself from any
sort of claim that you might get or
anything to that you might get on our on
our internet we also keep information
about customer help desk I had this
problem I had this problem with my
internet is that privileged information
things we have to worry about or is it
just privileged information about how
much the customer bases as I suppose
if you were to get a subpoena very
little would be considered privileged
oh sorry if you were to be served with a
subpoena very little that you have would
be considered privileged so it might be
privileged to you it might be considered
proprietary to you but it would not be
something that you could withhold
necessarily from a government action
having said that there's a lot of
different ways that you can protect that
information from being released to the
outside world food prot through
protection orders and that sort of thing
and so there are different mechanisms
you can use to protect that information
full release
yes ha we have black men so could you
talk a little bit about what the
penalties or what liability one is
exposed to for failing to maintain
sufficient records a lot of the Internet
service providers maybe not necessarily
the ones in this room but a lot of
Internet service providers don't
maintain records to that degree of
detail and may not maintain them over a
two or three-year period it's quite a
lot of them in fact wouldn't maintain
them beyond two or three days so knowing
whether there's some criminal penalty
for that or knowing whether it's
exposing you to liability in common with
the perpetrator or whatever is being
investigated or whatever would be really
useful I think well in for instance with
a digital millennium copyright act not
maintaining the information will not
necessarily subject you to any criminal
penalties or any additional words what
you're going to have to do is show that
you were following following your
established procedures that you have
been following them that you didn't just
trash a bunch of stuff in anticipation
of having someone come in and talk to
you it will help bolster your case the
mere fact that you didn't maintain the
information doesn't necessarily subject
you to a criminal penalty a lot of these
laws are designed to have you develop a
procedure where there might not have
been one before to explain that
procedure to your customers and then
follow it what's going to get you in
trouble is if you don't have a procedure
a or you have one and you don't follow
it and you suddenly start doing
something different most of these are
not criminal sanctions they are civil
sanctions which cost you money so you
won't go to jail but you'll have to pay
and you will only be one of many that
will be attached to any lawsuit relating
to these sorts of things for the digital
millennium copyright act in particular
one of the main things that you're going
to have to do is show that you fall into
this category of an online service
provider and within the law they
describe what that is
and once you fall into that category a
lot of the requirements and the
responsibilities that you have will be
much lesser and you'll be removed from
consideration in the lawsuit that answer
question moving from consideration in
the lawsuit means that you would not
also be subject to prosecution for
whatever it is that the person who's
originally being investigated is okay so
unfortunately it may be that your this
is the way lawsuits work you're ever you
include everybody that you can in the
lawsuit and then those of you included
in the lawsuit try to try to start
getting yourselves out so that you don't
have to further defend yourself or be
considered as part of the liable group
and so unfortunately require some work
and some maintaining a documentation to
show that you are following the
procedures that you have or you have
maintain that status as an online
service provider and then you can remove
yourself from the soup okay so
discounting for a moment the fact that
this is America and that's our
constitutional right to be sued and
looking at the criminal side of things
what about service providers whose
service is the provision of anonymity
and privacy what are they exposed to
under the set of laws what do you mean
I'm sorry yeah if the service that a
service provider is providing and is the
guarantee of anonymity and privacy to
for instance a user behind a web cache
and the user goes and looks at say child
porn and the services being provided is
a guarantee of anonymity and the service
provider is there established policy
which they are following is to not keep
any records what liability do they incur
in the criminal prosecution left
well teleport ins of that example
because they have no sympathy for you
with child porn so well it's worse case
that is the worst case if you didn't
have the information about who they are
there are ways to track people down and
you will stay longer involved in the
game of having to find these folks not
keeping the information will not keep
get you out of having to defend yourself
and having to provide whatever
information that you have criminally
probably nothing would happen to you
because you are not the actual user or
viewer of the site as just a conduit but
it is likely that she will have to
experience the joy of working with the
Justice Department that much longer if
you don't keep this information so it's
not that you're going to be criminally
or civilly sanctioned but you're going
to have the Justice Department there for
a long long time if you can't offer up
the information that you need to have
them further contact the people who are
the bad actors we'll take that one
question back here and then we'll close
off yeah I just wanted it he mostly said
it but I just want to get clarification
here since you said yourself the Patriot
Act is such a versatile law um I guess
the cost can ride it by the way what I
didn't write it so don't I believe you
so the question is if it is your
explicit policy written down black and
white that you explicitly follow that
you do not keep user usage information
that essentially provides a shield for
the users if you can show hey we don't
keep anything that's up front that's
what we do then there is no liability
under dmca or what have you is that
correct there is no liability for you
however having said that like I said the
Justice Department will likely camp out
with you in an effort to try and hunt
these people down particularly if when
it you're relating to things like child
pornography or terrorism and so what I'm
suggesting to you is that it might be
useful to you to maintain a minimum of
information that you can provide to them
to get you away from you and start
looking at the bad actors and you'll
have to deal with them that much less so
no to thank you okay thank you very much
Dan