my name is Jurgis ganos and Caleb Connor
ok my name is Georgie honest and me page
the student at the University of
California Riverside I'm really excited
to present my work here at nanoha just
hope you know my excitement doesn't mess
up my presentation so today I'm going to
talk about our to nemesis and present
the brief analysis on the Internet
routing registers and on the quality of
the information they contain so
basically the Internet routing registers
where registries were established as I
mean to improve the cooperation between
autonomous systems and the vision was to
have a stable analyzable internet using
the Internet routing registries
basically they allow an autonomous
system to register its policy which
means basically register what they are
named what the neighbors of the ASR and
what they import from their neighbors of
what they export to their neighbors okay
so so so in reality though the irr as
implemented today they just tore these
policies as clear-text ok so in the
registries they are they don't exist any
consistency checks so we don't know
which registries are correct or which
they register with sorry which
registrations are not correct and which
registrations are not fresh and to the
best of our knowledge that does not
exist a tool that are analyzed these
policies so our goal is to provide the
systematic approach and the tool to
analyze this polish and be able to
identify the polish that are correct and
fresh so in order to do this we have two
phases in the first phase we check for
errors in the second phase will check
for freshness using the external source
of source of data like bit soupy routing
tables and that will consist of two
parts we have the backend that we use
the Postgres database to store the
policies and all the analysis and we'll
have a web page from them that you can
use to cure your database and find out
possible errors that we found the IRR
and the results i'm going to present
they are from jun 22 2003 so today they
exist over 50 registers worldwide some
of them are regional like ripe in Europe
are going to be in the America up nick
in bayesian pacific regimes and some of
them are provider based so basically an
AS maintain its own registry in order to
publish its police information and the
information of their customers so the
biggest registry of all is right which
has over 6,300 their autonomous systems
that actually register import and export
filters we have a little bit over 2,000
AES for both ripe a for both array to be
adapting and we just have 1000 a years
is for the rest it's worth noting here
that on average an Aes in ripe registers
1212 neighbors that has links with 12
neighbors while in their ATP they only
register six in a APNIC disaster three
and for the rest of the registers the
average is six of course the important
thing is not how many a yes is the
registered a polish at some point in the
past but how many they maintain their
policy VAR correct and you know up to
date so the first test we can have is
you can check is both pills register
each other so in this simple example
that we have here we have the policy of
phase one so a show on register that has
a link with a is too so what we want to
find out is if there exists if we have a
registration for a link between s1 and
day is to do you have the reverse
direction so does the data is to
register that it has a link with a s1 so
we compute the percentage of their links
that exist in both directions / registry
and we find out that from forty-nine
percent of the links in the right there
exists the reverse direction while for
error to be the percentage solely
fourteen percent for APNIC is even lower
its six percent and for the rest it's
sixteen percent now in the case when
both
directions exist we want to take if the
filters they register is the same so
again in our simple example if a swan
registers that from a astute will report
be dazhe is to register that we will
export where's 1b and again we compute
this / register and we find out that for
I've forty-nine percent of of this case
you know they use the same filter for
array debates forty percent for APNIC
it's 38 and for the rest of them is 56
so the next thing the next thing you
want to do is check the policy of a is
an isolation so is the police has
registered correct in order to do this
you have to match what the AAS imports
and what the a s exports so in this
example here in the small example we
have that this particular a s exports a
B and C so from where does it import
them how doesn't know they say B and say
okay so see originates from within the
AES a comes from the left link becomes
from the right link so basically we want
to compute you know from the low low
level policy won't compute the league
level policy and be able to check if the
policy is complete and also I correct so
the test for consistent that we use are
two we have two different kinds of tests
the first one we call them polish base
test and basically we check the
correctness of the policy and that means
that we want to save in the important
sport are consistent and if the link
level policies metal and then we check
the freshness of the policy and by
freshness and basically we use the BGP
routing tables to check the freshness
and we require that all piece of all
periods of an ASR found in BGP must be
registered in IRR and also the
high-level policy of an aes should be
the same in both BJP NT nayara basically
there are heuristics that can extract
the high level polish from bit soupy
paths and you can do the same thing from
my RR so if in the bits of paths you
have particular areas as your upstream
we expect to find the same thing in IRR
so if any of this test fails then
consider that this
registration is not correct okay so
these are our results so for the
left-hand blood we have the how many the
percentage of the asus that passed the
polish based test so for I do have that
eighty percent of the edge past the
polls based test for a debate
seventy-seven percent for APNIC is
eighty-four percent and for the rest of
seventy-two percent here we note that
there are some requirements for our
approach sugar correctly in most of the
cases the requirements are meant but
there are very few AES is what which in
in which even though they registered
correctly policy we find them as
incorrect now when we also add the BJP
test to check if the policies press the
percentages dropped dramatically okay so
we have thirty four percent of the a sin
right that all so far that also press in
air ADP the percentage solely fifteen
percent its twenty five percent it up
Nick and fourteen percent for the rest
and also remember that our streets our
tests are very strict so if no matter if
na is register one thousand peers if it
misses one feeling the BJP then consider
these to contain not valid policy so
this is a snapshot of our web-based
interface so basically the group or the
RPS cell source code based in the AES
and in the first tab you can see this
you know you can have links for the
source code so you can go and click them
and find out what is the source code
interfacial format the next up the
external warnings are what the AES
registered versus what its neighbors
register so for example if you register
a link that it doesn't exist we put it
there then we have the internal warnings
you export something that we don't know
from where you import it so we also have
it there as a warning and then we have
the link level policy we're basically
will have the full collaboration between
the important the exports so our
conclusions so to the best of our
knowledge this is the first effort to
quantify the consistency of fire are we
find out the drive is the best register
overall with over 2,000
under the yes is passing all the tests
that we have and here you have to say
that you know in their ad for example
and in APNIC their lives the number of
the total number of days that are
registered are less than this number and
a lot of useful information exists in
the registers you are actively seeking
feedback and collaboration from the
industry how can we use our tool to help
the ISPs do you think it's the our tool
is graceful or not and please go and
user and say our tool at the following
location http redoute CS that you see I
de tu port 8080 slash nemesis
unfortunately i'm an Apple user so I
didn't pay attention to the windows
world so if you are using Internet
Explorer and you try to retrieve the
police of an Aes it will generate an
error you so you just have to go back
and boost the button again in order to
get the policy or you can browse the
registers have you been have you had
anyone ask you if they have private data
well if they have private data not in
the public eye are and you would you be
willing to run your tool on their
private yeah of course and also even
though i don't have it my tool online
now so that you can download the time
plan to put it the next few weeks so you
plan to put your tool online and ice
piece could contact you and my talk here
so that people know that the two lowest
i developed and sec to say you know so
here's a free tool guys talk to him he'd
like some feedback if he gives you some
good information it'll help him out in
his studies but again another free tool
that might give you some indication if
you're using an