thank you for being here my name is
Andre boson Oh I'm a security researcher
with 27 years of experience my first
encounter with malware happened in 1992
with the high virus when me and my
friends were infected while playing
pirated videogame Wolfenstein
back then I had no idea what what a
virus was there was no what to enter
antivirus because we had no access to
internet etc so I had to understand what
was happening and code something like
disinfect ER as we used to call it back
then and this was the beginning of an
awesome journey to me in 2000 2010 I
became a consultant for the Romanian
national cyber emergency response team
and at some point someone alerted us on
potential breach but they had no
evidence of the attack and in the ideas
logs or firewall logs but they were
pretty sure there was there was an
incident happening actually one of their
partners caught fraudulent activity
originating from their private VPN
network but on their site nothing
suspicious raised any any alarms so we
started investigating and we observed
that there was no direct service attacks
no spear phishing attacks
but forensic analysis on the memory of
the of the device was revealed to us
that can you guys be a bit quiet in the
back thank you reveal to us that it what
happened was drive-by download aka
watering hole back then I had no idea
what the watering hole was maybe you
guys know what watering hole is but
wikipedia says that watering hole is a
computer attack that
attacks a particular group organization
in the 300 region and the attacker
either guesses or observes which website
the group uses and in facts one or more
of them of these websites with with
malware more than a 70% of the websites
are are vulnerable so it's pretty easy
to an attacker to to find either non
vulnerability or a zero-day
vulnerability that he can exploit in
order to get access on a website on a
legitimate website that he can infect so
basically this is how watering hole
attack loops these are the phases phase
one the the victims are lured
either by a spear fishing or by simply
browsing pool to an infected web site
the victims are fingerprinted based on
their IP address their browser or other
technologies they use and the victims of
interest are selected and redirected to
an exploitation server where they are
attacked based on information previously
great gathered not interesting victims
get access to the legitimate web site
basically this these are the faces of
the watering hole attack phase one
attacker profiles victims and the kind
of website they go to attacker then test
these websites for vulnerabilities when
the attacker finds a website he can
compromise he injects JavaScript or HTML
redirecting the victim to the to the
separate site that hosts exploit code
for the for the chosen vulnerability the
step four is the compromised website is
now waiting to infect the profile victim
with a zero-day exploit just like a lion
waiting waiting at the watering hole we
can see here that the watering hole
attack can happen either to a normal web
site that serves a malicious
advertisement or through a compromised
web site or even through a spammed ring
aka spearfishing the victim accessing
these resources get into a traffic
Direction system that sends him to an
exploitation server kit that in turn
serves either ransomware banking Trojans
malware crypto jackin ransom er etc so
basically the watering hole attack is
considered a very dangerous but not so
common attack but the problem is most
victims don't even notice they have been
attacked as you will see later because
there is no obvious infection vector for
instance with spearfishing you can see
that someone received an email with
direct services attack you can see that
someone attacked a service and left a
signature in the IDS logs or something
like this during forensic investigations
on high-profile networks in in Romania
we found multiple occurrences of
successful watering hole attacks and
most of these victims had
state-of-the-art security solution in
place let's see how watering hole
attacks appear in the news we see that
apparently a Chinese attack group
infected forbes.com
back in November 2015 in a watering hole
attack and they targeted the visitors
working in the financial services or
defense industries if you if you look at
the second paragraph they stated that
the attack exploited to zero day
vulnerabilities one in Microsoft
Internet Explorer and the other one in
Adobe Flash Player and the Adobe fixed
the flow back in December and Microsoft
updated Internet Explorer as part of its
patch tuesday release so basically there
was no signature for the admin guys to
identify that someone was was attacking
their their systems also what's very
very important to notice is the next
paragraph saying that the campaign
lasted only a few days but I
and in Vincey I did not rule out the
possibility of the campaign lasting a
longer period of time they had no idea
to know that another very important
watering hole attack attacked people
working at Facebook Apple Google
Microsoft this happened in 2013 and the
attackers compromised the mobile app
developers forum as you can see Apple
confirmed being hit in the recent
watering hole attacked many watering
holes targets in hacks that netted
Facebook Twitter and Apple and
apparently not only one web app
developers forum was targeted but in
fact two or three others other forums
where we're hosting watering holes and
they say those other watering holes
served almost identical attacks to
employees from a wide range of target
firms across industries including
prominent auto manufacturers in US US
government agencies and even a leading
candy maker so nobody is safe from
watering holes another very interesting
attack happened in 2017 in February
banks 3031 banks in in Poland had been
affected by a watering hole the watering
hole was served from the Polish
Financial Supervision Authority it was a
legitimate website where people working
in the banking industry had to browse on
a daily basis to be on point and to be
up to date with the latest
recommendations and regulations from the
Polish government what's interesting is
the second paragraph saying that as
indicators of compromising the tech were
shared by the affected
other institutions around the world
found that they have been hit as well so
you can assume that a bank can have
state-of-the-art two security products
in place but still they didn't see the
attacks happening until someone else
shared with them the IOC's of a certain
tag this kind of raised some suspicions
why didn't they see that in the in the
in the logs why didn't the ideas raised
any alarms we also see that the watering
hole are a very favorite attack vector
in apt groups they move more recently in
2018 apparently Ocean Lotus had attacked
like 21 25 websites in Southeast Asia
and amongst them the Ministry of Defense
of Cambodia the Ministry of Foreign
Affairs and international cooperation of
Cambodia and several Vietnamese
newspaper and blocked websites as a new
bush the CEO and founder of a security
company in Vincey I said how can we
train employees to be worried of
watering hole sites it doesn't make any
sense and I can just see why some CIA
soles are getting frustrated at least
with spear fishing you can blame the
user even if it's not their fault
with watering hole of text they can only
say I had to go there for work what do
you want me to do and he has a point
he had to do that for his day-to-day
activities I would like to introduce you
to know some case studies case study one
is called the bank in 2017 one Romanian
bank contacted us for investing
investigating suspected bridge basically
one major ATM network identify
suspicious operations originating from
banks private VPN during out-of-work
hours using legitimate credentials those
were legitimate potentials pertained to
a user who was kind of computer
illiterate he had no security training
he had no idea how to hack and the
manager of the bank told me it's
impossible that he attacked those those
people we need to see what what was
going on there in plus the bank recently
acquired the state-of-the-art monitoring
and detection solution from a major
vendor and no suspicious activities were
detected by the by the bank
state-of-the-art intrusion detection
sensors and firewalls within the the
past two months we we asked them to
provide us with the firewall logs for
the past two months and we didn't see
any suspicious any suspicious going on
there
in + latest patches and updates were in
place but forensic analysis on the
computer who generated the suspicious
behavior didn't reveal any direct
service or spear phishing attacks but
the memory of the device held a lot of
evidence pointing to a watering hole
attack so basically you can see here we
dump the memory we simply search through
the the memory with strings for the
string iframe we anonymized
some watering hole sites on there but we
left two others some of them might still
be active but this happened on a single
bank computer so performing further
analysis on on that computer we actually
were able to narrow down the websites he
recently browsed and we started takin a
scan on those websites and we found the
culprit the culprit was a Romanian NGO
dedicated to cyber security in banking
environment
those dudes where mmm posting
recommendations how security operations
managers in banks should implement the
implement best practices so to say so it
was quite visited by your people working
in the bank responsible for security of
the banks and we in fact identified that
certain pages were implanted with
malicious JavaScript they can has found
that the malicious JavaScript was used
to read redirect users to an
exploitation server and the exploitation
server was using flash and PDF zero days
so basically this was the reason why
nothing appeared in the logs and no
suspicions were were raised you see here
on the on the left side of the screen
this is a resurrection script extracted
from the NGO nothing suspicious if you
look with the naked eye nothing
suspicious if you analyze with an
anti-virus but as soon as you perform a
first step of decoding we can see that
actually the JavaScript was referencing
functions through to a vector instead of
directly calling the the functions he
encoded the the the functions name your
in in hex so signature scanning would
identify nothing nothing suspicious
going on there
further the URL string was also encoded
so nothing suspicious when you perform
regular a signature scanning the other
script looked like this which was
basically an evolved executing
this harmless looking thing nothing
suspicious here if you don't know what
you're looking for but if you decode
this it's actually decode to this
JavaScript which you can see actually it
implants in the in the HTML document a
new script with an encoded string as
source for the URL of the redirection
basically the firewalls and the anti
viruses had no chance to identify that
the those scripts were performing
anything illegal in in this case so as I
said certain pages in the website had
separate influence of of these scripts
especially the the pages where they were
posting regularly recommendations and
the best practices for the for the
bank's only pages that were aware of
direct interest to people working in the
security management in the financial
sectors as you saw multi-layer the
encryption was used as protection
against static analysis all those
implants redirected to the same
exploitation server and the server was
was serving the actually PDF and flesh
zero-days that after successful
exploitation would download the
previously unknown carbonic root is
variant carbon arc is a very known cyber
criminal group that is said to have been
floating the financial industry for a
few years for like two billions dollars
or something like this another
interesting case study it was a major
media network in in Romania
we titled this from malware to crypto
checking because as part of our
regular activities we perform regular
they can ask ends on a Romanian top 100
websites and one time one scan revealed
an interesting watering hole attack on a
major and media network this particular
media network totaled almost 30 websites
with 500,000 unique visitors per day
it was huge it's I think is it's the
biggest in Romania and one of their
three load balancers was infected with
watering hole implants what's
interesting though it's the fact that
instead of redirecting users to an
exploitation server the JavaScript would
redirect users to a crypt rejecting
domain so basically something like
200,000 users where mining
cryptocurrencies for attackers every day
and this was very hard to detect because
it didn't happen all the time not all
load balancers were infected
it was like one out of three hits was
mining cryptocurrencies for the for the
attackers also the crypto checking
script was carefully crafted not used
too much CPU power in order to avoid the
detection so usually people detect
crypto jacking because the resources the
CPU etc go go up the roof and they
notice something fishy is going on and
they start investigating further in this
case nothing nothing as such so people
would happily mine cryptocurrencies for
the for the attackers unsuspecting
anything as a side note we concluded
somehow that a recent trend is to
replace the traditional ransomware
attacks with with crypto jacking because
instead of forcing someone to pay you a
certain sum for their
files you can much more easy easy and
have them mine cryptocurrency on your
behalf without their consent this is how
them people checking script would look
as you can see again nothing suspicious
nothing that could raise any suspicions
to an anti-virus product or a firewall
this is the decoded version of the of
the script on the right
still multi multi-layered encryption
nothing suspicious again for the
firewall or the antivirus but still this
this attacked a lot of a lot of users
and nobody noticed that the attack was
was ongoing most common no payload that
be can be served in watering hole
attacks are trojans apt rootkits crypto
jacking ransomware or spyware the
traditional methods that should detect
watering hole attacks our signature
scanning blacklisting of IPS or other
resources static code analysis and
dynamic code analysis why these methods
fail as we have seen previously there
are a lot of high profile networks that
were compromised using watering hole
attacks and as you can imagine these
places had state state-of-the-art
state-of-the-art technology that was
supposed to protect them but the
technology failed so why why these
technologies fail first the code is
obfuscated and the code is totally
devastated only in the browser memory as
you have seen earlier the code doesn't
look suspicious and doesn't perform any
read react doesn't
for many implants until it reaches the
browser's memory so in transit
everything looks fine also another
problem is that the the code is rarely
reused from one watering hole to another
so it's basically impossible to generate
a signature that can be used in multiple
places for instance how is the case with
our traditional viruses like you have
this virus you know that the signature
will catch every infection with with
that virus in this case the code is
rarely used and most of the times looks
different from one infection to another
another problem is that the exploitation
server uses either zero day attacks that
are totally unknown as you have seen
previously in the press exercise I
presented or one day attacks that are
recently published but nobody generated
yet a signature to detect those those
attacks also the domains and IP
addresses at used in in attacks - as a
command and control center etc are
rarely reused they don't get blacklisted
and most of the times they are
legitimate and trustworthy websites that
simply also serve as a command and
control server for the for the attackers
so you cannot blacklist legitimate
domain because this is rather impossible
also what is very debtor and for the
analysts is the fact that only certain
IP addresses are attacked for instance
in the case of the Polish banks they had
the list of the IP addresses used by the
banks they wanted to target and
all the IP addresses who didn't fall in
there in their list we're redirecting to
to the normal website and no attack no
attack happened so if when analyst tried
to understand what what was going on and
he didn't run the analysis from one IP
addresses that was in the target at
least he would practically practically
see nothing weird nothing suspicious and
so only certain browsers and underlying
technologies are attacked so for
instance if they have a zero-day for
internet explorer they will not attack
you if you use Firefox or Chrome for
instance if they have a zero D for
Firefox they will not attack you unless
you are using Firefox so the analyst has
to know from the beginning what kind of
setup he has to make in order to be
attacked so he can trigger and analyze
the attack another big problem is the
fact that the communication with the
command and control server is done using
covered channels for instance as a side
note the carbonic rootkit variant we we
analyzed used to communicate were on
HTTPS with legitimate website and the
exfiltration and communication was done
through base64 hashed
cookies so basically to anyone looking
in the in the logs this would look like
someone was surfing the web or nothing
suspicious was was going on there and so
as I stated previously the command and
control server is not blacklisted
because it can be legitimate website or
a legitimate server that at this point
in time serves as the command and
control server for certain attackers
also during analyzing malicious HTML
implants samples we identified that they
use a lot of tricks and techniques to
identify an instrumentation environment
for instance they have delayed the
execution the script doesn't actually
execute unless a certain amount of time
has passed they look for signs of human
interaction they look for onmouseover or
mouse activity keyboard activity etc
they have techniques to identify virtual
machine detection for instance they
check the window size there are very
rare cases when the analyst actually
changes the the windows size of the
analyzes environment and this is
practically a standard window size for
for all cases and hackers look at this
and they can decide if it's an
instrumentation environment or it's a
it's a real person who accessed and who
is getting infected so a variant would
be dynamic code analysis but the problem
is that dynamic code analysis is very
time consuming and it's time limited you
can only analyze an sample for a certain
amount of time like 2 minutes
but the hackers could make their script
run after 2 minutes so during your
analysis nothing nothing suspicious
nothing nothing raises any alarms so you
say ok it was a false alarm this site is
a perfectly ok but in fact it is not
also dynamic code analysis is
time-consuming and it will require from
a few tens of seconds to a few minutes
for a complete analysis so analyzing a
single simple website would
take ours this is not feasible in a real
environment so as we as we already saw
there are a few phases in a watering
hole attack basically is the
resurrecting phase where users are
selected and fingerprinted based on
technologies they use using the
information gathered in the resurrecting
phase they are served certain exploits
according to the to the technologies
they use and the third phase is the
persistency phase in which the actual
attacker tries to hold the control of
the equipment he he recently owned and
tries to call back home to his command
and control server most technologies
that protect against watering holes
focus on the exploitation phase or the
persistency phase which you can see it's
rather difficult when the attack is
performed using zero days they attempt
to detect exploit signatures blacklisted
IP addresses or suspicious
communications but this protection is
not enough against euro day or one day
attacks or legitimate IP addresses used
as command and control servers or
covered channels as we have seen in the
example with the with the Romanian bank
where legitimate web server was used as
the command and control server and the
exfiltration in communication was
performed through cookie values so we
understood that we had to to come up
with a new approach a different approach
so I started developing the canals in
2016 as a complex passive scanner using
artificial intelligence to classify
malicious HTML elements our focus was
on detecting phase 1 the resurrection
and fingerprinting of users instead of
trying to identify your blacklisted IPS
or exploit signatures etc we developed
Tekken s is a big big big data system
which allows parallel processing in a
big data environment which in turn
allows us to analyze something like 1
million URL addresses in 24 hours which
is basically huge also we introduced a
new a new concept which is a hybrid
between static analysis and dynamic code
analysis which we call contextual
analysis which means basically
understanding the code from its
semantics not running the actual code
and not only looking for certain
patterns in the in that code but
actually trying to find the correlations
and relations between the HTML
instructions or the JavaScript
instructions and see how would those
features those instructions fit into a
malicious behavior or not this approach
allowed us to have no false negatives
basically there isn't there is no
malicious JavaScript that we did not
detect but we had some false positives
like 0 0.001 percent of the websites we
analyzed the where in fact legitimate
scripts looking like malicious ones but
this false positives are used to train
further the artificial intelligence
algorithm so our research we analyzed
over 2000 20,000 malicious HTML elements
and
we identified certain features that are
common amongst all samples those
features are fundamental in order for
the implant to perform and those
features are resurrection you need to
send the users to 12 to the exploitation
server you need to actually implant and
execute that resurrection through some
of keywords or instructions but this
would be very obvious for an admin guy
and you could easily see that someone
implanted an iframe or a meta refresh
tag in his in his website so they had to
obfuscate and conceal the presence of
such keywords or instructions that would
perform the the resurrection also
another feature is that they need to
fingerprint the the target victims they
need to understand what technologies the
victims use in order to redirect them to
the appropriate exploitation server also
as we stated previously they have
instructions that try to detect the
instrumentation environment so basically
knowing these these features we try to
identify the the instructions and the
keywords that would allow an attacker to
to perform these these actions we
identified basically the code constructs
that would perform these these features
and actually as as I was stating earlier
we don't look for certain instructions
but actual code constructions how the
semantics are used and where the
instructions are placed in in the in the
script or HTML page and how that might
affect the
specifics of the of that certain GOM for
instance to perform resurrection the
attacker needs either meta refresh tags
iframes location.href window open
etc to execute the resurrection the
attacker needs instructions such as
document.write Eva etc to perform of
fisk asian the cone is to cycle through
large chunks of data and apply
transformations on the data basically to
conceal the fact that they attack the
attacker the users of a website they
need to encrypt that to decrypt that
they need to have a very large chunk of
so-called trash that would get
transformed in such a way that is easily
interpreted by the JIT of the of the
certain browser so that it totally makes
sense but it doesn't raise any any
suspicions so we we decided to score
large variables or many variables or
large function parameters we score
transformation instructions such as
charcoal death from charcoal unescape
etc but they are this is just an example
there are many more also the score
increases a lot if they are present
inside the inside loops for instance if
there is a cycle that applies
transformations we try to take into
account how how big the the cycle is and
as big the cycle is the highest score it
it gets the score also increases is
there are multiple multiple instances of
transformation instructions for instance
in order to to apply multi layered
encryptions they use certain different
instructions in the in the same code if
we see many transformation instructions
in the same code or many
iteration instructions in the same code
we increase the the scoring also we're
looking for delay the execution
instructions such as I said timeout or
instructions expecting user interactions
such as almost over all mouse click or
on mouse leave these instructions are
very useful for an attacker to identify
if if it's an analyze DCC system or an
actual user who browse the the website
we also score instructions checking for
user agent or other other features that
could give the attacker an idea on what
technologies are used on the under
certain browser and how they can exploit
the user that access the watering hole
so we're checking for instructions that
look for the local IP address either the
internal IP address or the external IP
address there are very many cases when
this is only used to communicate with
the command and control server saying ok
this IP address is of interest or not ok
let it go so we we take that into
account when we analyze the the
JavaScript or the HTML also we're
looking for instructions for instance
looking for the window size as we stated
previously the window size is used to
determine as one factor used to
determine if the analyzes environment is
present or if it's a normal user
browsing the the website also we score
certain other features that we we have
seen in the malicious JavaScript such as
the concatenation
we also score encoding of payloads as we
have seen earlier there was
encoded with hacks etc we also score
white spaces because in malicious
JavaScript there are not so many white
spaces but in legitimate JavaScript
usually there are a lot of white spaces
because this is one of the way the
JavaScript should should look we also
score
the new lines inserted in each
JavaScript also we we score shell code
looking snippet we also can identify
attacks on the Java compiler through
this - this approach and everything gets
compiled in data set with more than 30
features and all these features are
unique to malicious HTML elements there
are cases when legitimate HTML elements
or scripts might use some of these
features but not in the correlations
present in the in the data set for
instance there might be some legitimate
- scripts that perform the affiliation
for instance in the contact pages or
something like this but the length of
the decoded string is not as large in as
it is in in in the case of a watering
hole attack the result of data set is
fed to a random forest classification
algorithm because a random forest uses a
collection of trees with a random
parameter holdout to build models which
in many cases outperformed individual
decision trees this gives us increased
analyzed speed we can analyze like 1
million URLs in the in 24 hours also the
HTML elements like the species by the
artificial intelligence are sent to a
JavaScript instrumentation sandbox
basically the artificial intelligence
act as a filter to distinguish the
potential suspicious elements from been
ignorance so that the actual dynamic
code analysis is performed only on
elements that are showing great signs of
maliciousness and in parallel they are
sent to a JavaScript instrumentation
sandbox which interprets every
instruction and tries to emulate it but
at the same time they are sent to a high
interaction honeypot which executes the
the HTML page or the JavaScript and
looks for changes in the analyzes system
this actually it's possible to integrate
the the results flag by the artificial
intelligence with any online or offline
sandbox or analysis system and HTML
elements flag the suspicious but not
confirmed by the instrumentation sandbox
or honeypot are submitted for manual
analysis by a human analyst so that he
can decide ok this is something actually
weird going on there or no this is a
totally banning let it let it go and as
soon as the false positive is is
detected that false positive is used to
further train the artificial
intelligence algorithm so we started
decadence in 2016 and after two years
that ken has became a startup part of
the orange faboo startup accelerator we
did not foresee that at some point some
someone would be I would show this great
interest to to dakinis but
we have since November 2018 we have had
a lot of requests to use our our
services thank you guys this was my
presentation