today I'm going to talk about practical
uses for memory visualization my name is
Lou frisk and I'm going to I'm going to
start with a short introduction to my
previous work and also some background
then we'll jump straight into what the
PCL each and the memory process
filesystem is then we'll talk about two
different use cases first how I used an
earlier version of the software in order
to find a total meltdown in Windows 7
then we'll have a look how other people
have been using modified versions of my
software in order to do hardware
assisted cheating in games after that
we'll go more in depth we'll have a look
at its capabilities its API the design
and the plug-in functionality try to
presentation I will do demos lots of
demos live demos so let's help
everything is working
my name is Sol frisk I'm working as a
pen tester by day in Stockholm Sweden
and I also try to do some security
research by night I'm the author of the
PCL each direct memory access attack
toolkit which represented almost three
years ago at Def Con I found it's really
low-cost piece of hardware I was able to
do direct memory access DMA over PCI
Express it didn't require any drivers on
the target and with this really low cost
piece of hardware I was able to do well
over 150 megabytes per second reading
the main memory of the target computer
over PCI Express and also Brighton to
the memory unfortunately this piece of
hardware even though it was really fast
and low-cost and it only was able to
access memory below for jig's since it's
only supported 32-bit addressing but at
that point in time that was not really a
big problem since I was able to
successfully attack most major operating
systems anyway
operating systems improved and also the
forging limit was very boring and this
Hardware it became really popular so
it's sold out as well so that's why I
introduced public FPGA based DMA
attacking
at this ECC a little bit over one and a
half years ago and and everything that
I've been doing up until now it's 100%
open-source and everything is available
on my github page but today we'll have a
look at the memory process filesystem
which is a memory analysis tool with a
strong windows focus it allows you to
visualize in memory objects as files and
folders in a file system it comes with a
C and Python API and if I look at its
its multi-threaded its multi-threaded
core together with native C code and
some intelligent parsing in there it's
really fast it also comes with a wide
range of memory acquisition methods not
just the hardware based ones we are
talking about earlier but also software
based ones so let's do our first demo
for today let's mount a memory dump
image created by Matt's awesome
dump it to let's mount it by
double-clicking on it and do some really
easy pointing click memory forensics so
this is a memory dump image it's 32 gigs
big so let's have a look at it let's
analyze it let's double click on it it
says it's mounted and if you click into
the M drive as it's mounted as in the
root folder you see the PMM file which
is basically a copy of the physical
memory it's not really interesting and
if you're mounting a memory dump file as
you do yes I'm doing now but imagine if
you're acquiring memory using the FPGA
hardware for example or acquiring the
remote memory we have a statist
directory which contains various
configuration options and but more
interestingly we do have it the names
folder which contains each process on
the running system as a directory just
click into let's click into the explore
directory and in each process directory
we do
a couple of files that we can have a
look at and they have the base address
of the director table base CR tree and
we have the memory map which is again by
walking the actual page tables that the
CPU uses and this is all done by parsing
physical memory and you also try to
author identify what this memory is if
it's for example here or if it's belongs
to some process Explorer in this case we
also do have files for the entire
virtual memory just open it in your
favorite text editor have a look at it
to search for stuff in the memory or if
you're using FPGA Hardware you can hit
save as well and then you will write to
virtual memory of that process and it
will be reflected down into physical
memory we have a couple of subfolders as
well we have a Python subfolder which
allows any user to code their own Python
plugins quite easily and just drop the
Python plugins in the program folder of
the file system and it will show up in
this case it provides like a small
Python module provides easy access to
the e process structure and in the
kernel and we can just have a look at it
by just clicking on files more
interestingly we do have a modules
subfolder to each process as well and
here you see did all the loaded deals in
the process and you can analyze them
live by just clicking into the subfolder
we can have a look at its exported
functions imported functions here we see
the exported functions where the
function names and the memory address
they're exported at we have a look at
the imported function as well we can
have a look at the sections for example
executable sections text only sections
and things like that but if we wish to
do edits of a section we can also go
into a subfolder
we can open it in the favorite text
editor whatever and have a look at it if
we so should wish so that's a quick look
at it
guests should disable sound here yeah
this wasn't backed by physical memory
but if it's backed by physical memory
you can click into it have a look at it
and we can actually edit the binary data
and we hit save and if you birth left it
down into memory if you're running with
the FPGA devices where we have bright
capabilities so let's continue so doing
analysis with a hardware device it's
really powerful and in this example here
I do have an analysis computer which is
connected over USB 3 on two really big
Xilinx FPGA development board they exist
smaller boards as well as we will see
later on and then you have PCI Express
to the ThinkPad or Express card in this
case in order to read and write memory
of the target system I do in software on
my analysis computer construct a PCI
Express transaction layer packet PCI
Express is a packet based I construct a
memory read packet in this example I've
wrap it in some extra metadata which
allows it me to transmit it over USB 3
on to the FPGA the FPGA then takes the
PCI Express transaction layer packet
unpacks it and put the raw PLP packet on
the piece express of the target system
once the piece Express packet reaches
the route complex of the target system
it sees that it's a read packet memory
read packet so it's reads from the
physical memory of the target system and
responds with a PCI Express transaction
layer packet which it's a completion
packet in this case which contains the
actual data read and it's responds with
it back to the FPGA and the FPGA
forwards its back to the analysis
computer
right thing works pretty much the same
way and this is really powerful so let's
continue to a couple of use cases first
have a look at how I used an early
version of the memory process file
system in order to locate a total
meltdown in Windows 7 it was a local
privilege escalation vulnerability which
allowed any user to escalate the kernel
trivially it allowed Orbiter of physical
memory reads and writes at gigabytes per
second it only affected Windows 7 and
2008 r2 and it was something that was
introduced in the mountain patches from
from January last year but it looked
like it was patched in March last year
yester before I found it and I didn't
see anything in the release notes from
Microsoft nsrc and I thought that was
really strange since they usually do
give some credit to researchers or
anyway I put up a CV at the but they
didn't do this for this one so I wrote
them an email and told them I want to
publish a blog entry about this I found
this really interesting is it ok and
they were like yeah let's check with our
engineering team and they responded the
day afterwards and was like yeah it's
totally ok to publish this blog entry
and in order to make it a little bit
more interesting I decided to publish a
proof-of-concept as well and only
problem was it wasn't fixed and I
released a traveler exploitable kernel
zero-day with the permission of
Microsoft it was actually fixed if you
were running with administrative
privileges or if you were running as
system it was however not fixed if you
were running as a normal low privileged
user and since I ran everything in my
test case as admin elector and Steffes
admin on my test systems and I didn't
spot this one and neither did Microsoft
beforehand anyway really lucky here they
managed to scramble and they came up
with an out-of-band patch for the kernel
itself yes two days after
released my initial blog entry and I
think that's really super fast response
time and for doing stuff in the kernel
so really thank you to Microsoft for
that one but let's do a demo let's show
how I came to find this total melt or
burn ability let's locate it by looking
at the memory map we had a look at while
ago and India will see that the PML for
which is the topmost paging structure in
the page tables it's self referential
entry was mapped straight into user mode
so I should have a vulnerable virtual
machine here so let's start it let's
mount the memory process filesystem I'm
shooting a little bit here today since
I'm using the actual vulnerability to
you if mount the filesystem when I was
researching this I was using the FPGA
hardware but once we have the file
system mounted we can click into some
folder for example a CMV folder and have
a look at this memory map in here it
looks kinda normal identify some heaps
and some binaries and this is how it
should look like so nothing strange here
until I scroll down at the end I see a
lots of addresses starting with 4 FS
here which are read/write/execute
but they are not a supervisor so they
are not colonel here and adversity
starting with lots of apps they're
traditionally reserved for the kernel
itself they don't have to be really
according to Intel and but in Windows
they should be reserved for the kernel
and this is really strange that I see
these memory addresses in my process
memory space there was what is going on
here I was also able to dump memory at
very high speeds
so let's it wrote up the
proof-of-concept I wrote it from my PC
LH program so let's try to dump the
memory of this vulnerable system and
dumping memory it's quite fast I can
dump memory at around a couple of
gigabytes per second here
I was also able to execute the evil
kernel implants and insert them into the
kernel if it's yeah I held execution
here I've inserted my kernel implant in
the kernel just like that so what is
going on here
I mean this clearly shouldn't be the
case and let's have a closer look at it
once when we knew that their file system
mounted here let's go into folder of a
process the CMD and let's have a look at
the two different PML 42 different
topmost page tables since the melton fix
was actually to split the page table
into two one which was the PML four here
and which was reserved for the kernel of
the world after the meltdown fix and one
for the user which was created before a
meltdown fix and let's have a look at
the first one and we talked about this
self referential entry and we have this
memory address here in Windows 7 the
topmost page table has a very special
entry at offset f68 it's this one it's
self referential it actually points to
the page table itself the PML for itself
and the memory manager uses this and I
have 68 it's actually this one and it as
you can see it's in little-endian
so it ends with 67 it ends with 7 and 7
in this case means that it's present
it's active it's vital and it's
accessible from user mode and that
shouldn't be it should only be
accessible from the kernel itself but
this is the current view of things
after a patch it might not be that
catastrophic so let's have a look at the
user page table as well and if we check
the offset at f68 it's self referential
entering this one it also ends with a 7
and this is the issue itself so the
total Meldrum vulnerability was really
one single bit set in error and if you
read Intel manual it clearly states that
use the supervisor if Cyril user mode
accesses are not allowed to this memory
region so it's set to one using old
accesses or allowed exploitation it was
so easy I don't even want to call it an
exploit
it was just a matter of inserting a fake
page table entry at the fixed address is
in already mapped in processed virtual
memory once I inserted this fake page
table entry I could read and write to
the orbiter physical memory that that
page table entry had pointed to another
use case that I didn't expect at all was
cheating in games it turns out that anti
cheating software it's really powerful
pieces of software they detect the most
if not all software based cheats and a
hardware based sheet it should in theory
it should only be seen as a PCI Express
device on the gaming system and you kind
of need to have PCI Express devices in
your gaming systems you need to have a
powerful graphics card and things like
that for example and then you could use
this Hardware device and then ship
member to a remote computer and do the
analysis there and the yeah
and she'd software cannot reach into
that computer you could do things like a
read-only wool hex radar map decloak X
for example and you could do the
analysis on this separate computer chip
to play a location to another computer
for example you can also do writing but
that might be a little bit more easily
detectable if you're tampering with the
in-game internals I first became aware
of this summer last year when it was a
big cheating scandal in the nori
in csgo community it turned out that
their people have been cheating at home
and on lands to where she was okay to
bring your own computer and then a
couple of months later on even a sheet
focused fork of my PCL each software
appeared on github and this is how it
looks like if we look really closely
here we'll see that we have the PCI
Express screamer fpga board inserted in
this gaming computer initially ante
sheets didn't catch this at all and it
was kind of touted as the next
generation of cheating the future of
sheeting but you see yeah which is a
really good anti sheet it didn't take
them that long to catch up and when they
cashed up and they wrote a blog entry
about it on their site geared toward the
gaming community what explained you
might have a DMA device in your computer
and you read the membership to add that
tag PC doing ad analysis there and then
you ship the player location to a phone
for example they claim the prices for
these sheets had been selling in the
range of 1500 to $5,000 and of course
when they started to do detection it was
really simple initially for them to do
it since most people had just been
downloading my initial my default bit
stream of the FPGA and the farmer from
my site and it was some hard-coded
vendor a decent device IDs in there so
if you had them in your gaming system
you're probably she to rights just ban
them and it resulted in a bandwidth
about sheet customers and developers but
now they also claim that they're able to
detect harbor based sheets
even with disguising the sheet as a
legitimate device and they can look into
some other things some other telltale
signs in there and which is quite easily
detectable which is not so easily be
changed by the user or the but
what if it was possible to perfectly
emulate a legit target word
and this is kinda in the last couple of
months already been demonstrated by
researches at Cambridge University in
there thunderclap paper they used a
really expensive hardware set up here
around $4,500 but we're able to emulate
some networking card entirely in
software and I don't know maybe it would
be we will see this in the gaming area
in the future as well but let's continue
with the memory process file system the
memory analysis part and when I was
creating it I wanted to have something
that's really easy for users to use but
it should yet be very powerful I wanted
to create something that was really
modular in design and had plug-in
functionality API is for C was given
since its coded in C and I also want
added Python API since Python is really
popular within the security community
and also in the memory forensics
community and of course performance is
super important when clicking around in
a file system you can't really wait for
1 or 2 minutes for a directory with the
files to render it needs to be pretty
much instant this is what I came up with
and I used a really awesome third-party
product which is called dokkan which is
a user mode file system it takes care of
all the hard part so I don't have to do
it it has a kernel driver for the file
system parsh all I need to do is to
implement some really simple user mode
hoops in the memory process filesystem
executable and this really simple code
box is pretty much it's just a thin wrap
around the main analysis library which
where I do all the memory analysis it's
it's a really big C API it also takes
care of all the memory analysis steps
and it's in here I do the translation
between the physical memory and the
virtual memory for example I need to
know a little bit about different memory
models also have a plug-in manager in
there for
Python and C plugins and if I do use a
Python plug-in I want to call back into
its memory analysis library and I do
that we are the Python API and if you
kill your own Python the applications
you can use this Python API as well and
then I had a separate library for
physical memory analysis and it's the
lead core library which has a really
strong focus on physical memory some
writes that's all it does and this
allows me to separate memory acquisition
from analysis in a really nice way and
it supports a lot of different memory
acquisition methods I do support the
hardware based memory acquisition
methods and then we can do writing to
use memory as well also I do support
live capture of physical memory from a
system either by using pmm or even
better Matt's wish awesome dampe tool
and we might want to analyze memory
dumps as well and then you can do that
by clicking on a file for example a row
member don't file a fulcrum file for
example created with dump it and even
hyper-v save files recently I also got a
really nice contribution from sin active
and if you do have a vulnerable HP ILO
interface you might be able to reflash
that one with a special custom firmware
or even implant DMA backdoor in a live
HP ILO system without refreshing it and
once you do have de air DMA backdoor in
there and it's the BMC of HP servers and
then you can read and write memory from
the host operating system running on
this server using these tools you're
also able to connect to a remote agent a
remote leech agent or a Kerberos secured
mutual authenticated or PC and this
remote agent is pretty much the leech
core library but remotes you can use any
of the above memory acquisition methods
over the network but on that remote
system
the maintenance is library looks
something like this we do have an API on
top in which my memory process file
system is using or your own application
and on the very bottom I do capture
physical memory from the leach core
library but they also have a simple
object manager in there which allows me
to handle some simple objects in this
library and that allows me to in a
really good way have caches for physical
memory and the page tables user in two
different caches and then I have a layer
which translates physical memory in
through virtual memory and I'd need to
have a knowledge of few different memory
models in order to do that and then I
notion of the process object which
contains a memory map object and a
module map object also have a plugin
manager there which allows me to
communicate with external plugins and if
you're capturing live memory bottles I
remember from a live system I reducing
the FPGA or dump it in its live KD mode
I do have a background updater thread in
there as well
in order to update the caches in in the
background and so the user don't have to
wait for the memory capture and of
course I do all the analysis in here as
well so imagine you have an incident
response scenario you might have a
suspicious process on a remote system
and that computer might be quarantine to
a VLAN or something like that and it's
quite cheap often you do have limited
bandwidth and high latency over the
networks corporate network you want to
analyze physical memory maybe and a full
memory dump over the network might be
super slow the solution might be to
retrieve only the memory you actually
need to analyze and analyze it with a
memory process file system or even
better it's possible to run the analysis
on the remote computer by submitting a
small Python script so let's do another
demo let's demo some remote malware
memory analysis I'm going
to analyze live malware memory from a
remotely remote system which has been
infected and we are going to analyze
this memory by just clicking on some
files so this remote system is another
hyper-v machine here so I'm going to
start this leech agent and we do have
this memory address here I'm using dump
it with its live KD mode in order to
capture live physical memory from this
remote system and I'm going to do it in
interactive mode here today and also in
insecure mode since this computer is not
connected to an Active Directory domain
I can't really secure the connection
with Active Directory Kerberos so let's
do it in insecure mode which it
basically allows anyone with network
access to connect so let's initialize
the connection to instrument system we
are going to start the memory process
file system using the dump it device to
capture memory from this remote system
so this memories should be mounted now
especially let's click in to have it
having a look at it can click into the
names folder and I know already know
what the malware is it's an old Citadel
example here can have a look at its
memory map for example and will clearly
see it that you have some
read/write/execute sections with the
malware which is this one but we can
analyze its memory we can open the
virtual memory in hex editor and in the
hex editor I already know what to search
for here so let's search for some known
really good antivirus software here
because this malware is a block list for
antivirus so we can see and this is like
live memory by editing a file live
memory from this remote system cat
shipped and when we are doing this we
are only capturing that piece of memory
and if we were doing this analysis with
the FPGA as well we could even hit sale
here after we change something and the
malware might not even notice since we
are not using an API some that remote
system early so having incident response
there's really big advantages doing
physical memory analysis and you might
already be familiar with Stardust
bi mát if you're not familiar with it
please have a look at it or you might
even use the more traditional approach
with volatility both those tools are
super awesome and the memory process
file system is not truly meant to
replace them it's more meant to act as a
platform to do things with your own
favorite tools it has an okay
performance even a leggy networks and if
you use the agent you can actually do
the remote analysis parch directly on
the remote endpoint which is super nice
since it avoids both latency and
bandwidth and future focus for is to do
even more performance optimizations I do
wish to prioritize things even more in
order to further reduce latency and
having a multi-threaded design is really
awesome here since allows me to do
things like a background process
refreshes and the analysis capabilities
it's a little bit limited at the moment
but I do plan to add more in the soon
future so let's have another look at the
year Python API let's analyze the live
memory from this remote system in Python
by using the API let's locate readwrite
executable sections in the remote memory
switch over to Python here
first I need to import the Python API
can have a look at the functionality
here we have a few functions that we can
call into we're going to initialize this
first we are going to connect to this
remote system and let's connect to it
and if we check the remote system you
see that we connected and we are still
connected with the other connection for
memory process file systems of this
agent support multiple connections to
this remote system and now we are able
to do things like retrieving the pit for
a process name for example the CMD dot
exe is this pit and we can retrieve some
additional information for that process
or for all processes and have a look at
it by pit and here we see things like
the process name we have the address of
the process the pep band a few other
things in here which might be
interesting when we have this
information we can retrieve it for all
processes we can iterate over it and we
get a really nice list of all the
processes in this system we can retrieve
the memory map for a given process and
this is just one entry in the memory map
it would be HUGE if I would print it the
whole one it seems to be a page from the
MTB level which seems to be read execute
here and it's the entity ll here and now
when we do have all this information we
can do code a small Python program and
let's for each process in the system
let's iterate over it and for each
process we are going to retrieve its
physical memory map and let's iterate
over each entry in this memory map to
see if we can find some readwrite
executable entries in there and then
we're going to print it on the screen
and I'm only going to print maximum two
entries on the screen per process just
for show here and now it takes some time
it's a lot of memory
to acquire from the remote system but
it's quite fast anyway and now we went
through all the pages all the payment
structures of all the processes on the
system and it's already finished as you
can see we seem to find some
read/write/execute pages in onedrive
which is pretty normal
we have our trojan executable here and
also have some pages in PowerShell which
is kind of normal as well we can also
retrieve virtual and physical memory by
using the API and then we do it by using
the memory read function and the first
argument is the pit of the process we
wish to retrieve the memory from and but
we can retrieve from physical memory if
you use pit minus one and it looks
something like this but even better we
might be able to do this by analyzing
live memory on the remote system by
submitting a short script or at remote
system and do the analysis on the actual
remote system and then we don't have to
acquire any memory at all and it's
really nice in low bandwidth scenarios
so let's have a look at our small
program here it's pretty much the same
as around before and but now I'm
printing all the entries from the memory
map so let's use the PCL each program
with the agent exit path from program to
submit this small script to remote test
let's still use dump it to do the memory
acquisition I submit the script we wait
for the result it should and we already
have it and all the memory analysis in
this step is been doing it's been done
on the actual remote system and by
analyzing physical memory on that remote
system we are not really relying on any
operating system api's to do this and
this makes it really hard to catch as
well
so the Python API looks something like
this we have memory read functionality a
memory read and write functionality we
can both read physical and virtual
memory and we can retrieve various kinds
of process information listing the pits
for example retrieve which modules which
dll's are in the specific processes and
for the dll's in the each process we can
retrieve exported functions important
functions sections and things like that
and then the whole file system even
though it's not really mounted as a
drive and we still exist in the API
world so we can query the API and read
and write this virtual file still so
when is creating this performance was
super important and I'm really happy to
have completed multi-threading since
it's a huge boon since it allows me to
do a lot of things in the background
which doesn't really affect the user and
I also rely on in-memory caching and
some really intelligent parsing in there
an example of parsing I really want to
avoid scanning large chunks of memory
for known signatures if I can avoid it
because reading a lot of memory is
expensive in terms of performance
one thing I achieve this is when I'm
starting the memory process file system
I need to locate the kernel director
table base which is the base of the
virtual memory paging structures for the
kernel so I can translate physical
memory into virtual memory and the
kernel base itself and it might already
be known to the underlying device if
it's known to the underlying device I
can use that of course then we are done
nothing more like that otherwise I can
check for a memory structure which is
called the low stub it's something that
usually exists at the address 1000 in
physical memory in hex it doesn't have
to but it usually does and especially
with this structure is that that offset
a zero you do have the kernel PML for
the director of table base of the kernel
which then would allow me to translate
virtual memory into physical memory and
then I have a pointer to the base of the
to the entry of the antis colonel at
offset 70 it's not the base so I need to
be scanning back a few pages but it's
not too much memory so it's really quick
and as a last resort I might to go for
scanning as well but it's it takes a
little bit longer time so you want to
avoid it if I can and so let's go on at
the demo let's do some writing to live
memory on another system as well and
let's overwrite memory in the process on
another system so for this part I'm
going to use the vulnerable Windows 7
here and since the total meltdown
vulnerability allows me to do writing to
physical memory as well so let's start
the leach agent and I'm going to start
it interactive and in secure mode here
today and I'm starting the notepad here
with some text as well so let's try to
need to mount this remote so let's mount
the filesystem it's mounted and now we
should be able to click into it and we
can go into the notepad process for
example and in here we do have the
virtual memory but more interestingly we
do think that this text hello up code it
should be somewhere on the heap of the
notepad I would suspect that list and in
the VM the sub directory we have for
each physical memory region we have
enumerated it's as a file as well so it
should be kind of easy to access and is
tagged if we try if we find what the
memories it's also tagged with that so
let's try to do it and let's do it in
Ubuntu
so let's first mount the drive
and then they go into that subdirectory
and let's have a look if you can find
the heap in there it's probably on the
primary heap heap zero and we just have
one memory region for this heap and
let's do some simple let's do a simple
strings on the heap we're going to do
strings and the text in notepad is
stored in little-endian so utf-16 so
let's do search use strings in that mode
and you just grab for hello and we have
the text there
hello up code in this file and this is
memory acquired from this remote system
live now and let's try to change that
text into something else just use our
hex editor to do that and let's search
for that memory so this is the text
hello up code in utf-16 little-endian so
and here we do have some promising text
here so let's try to change that text
into something else
and hit save in our hex editor and the
text didn't change and that's because we
need to just update the frame buffer we
can't click anywhere and the text will
be updated so
[Applause]
thank you
so imagine doing this on another system
using the FPGA hardware for example it
might be useful in some research
scenarios I hope so the memory process
file system it's a work and a lot of
future work it's a work in progress and
a lot of future work remains and one
thing I want to do is quite soon is to
add some page hashing hashing of the
pages which would allow me to I think
reduce add amount of memory capture from
remote systems and also to do things
like low bandwidth cache coherency
updates and I wish to add a lot of
functionality and features quite soon
and additional analysis capabilities
primer ones being support for the
Windows registry and also threading
threads of the target system analyze
those ones and support for non Windows
operating systems
it's certainly possible but it's a lot
of work and that's a little bit more for
in the future and of course additional
memory acquisition methods is always
nice but to sum everything up the memory
process file system it's an easy
pointing click file based memory
analysis tool it comes with an API for C
C++ and Python it has a wide range of
memory acquisition methods not just
Hardware based ones but software based
ones and also this remote agent
it's 100% open source and it's found on
my D tab and thank you very much