this is working
all right so we'll kick off with this
while we meet Eko meet Eko meet Eko it's
like Beetlejuice Beetlejuice beetlejuice
all right so we have to we can we can
make do so we're a few minutes late
starting I had to install an HDMI
adapter and a new driver and reset my
whole system so everything I queued up
to show you I'm now gonna have to open
during the session isn't that fun so i'm
al morton co-chair of the benchmarking
methodology working group and this is
sarah banks co-chair of thank you so
welcome welcome to our our session at
IETF 100 this this this group is we were
overlooked in the mentioning last night
but this group is as old chartered wise
as the THC dynamic host control working
group I think they've met one more time
than BMW G but but they were both
chartered at the same time so so we have
that honor and that's why I didn't want
to miss this one for sure
okay so we've done the introductions
you've all moved relatively close to the
front thank you for doing that and if
you you're not subscribed to the BMW G
mailing list that's how you do it so
unknown
it's now Thursday afternoon you should
have seen this about 40 times but IPR is
important here you have to disclose it I
don't have the most up-to-date slide
unfortunately but there is an update 253
78 I think
that basically changes a few things IPR
wise so please take a look at that
I mean you've you've basically had the
chance to do that and your registration
and everything okay so here's our
proposed agenda we we have a note taker
Sarah it's Neville oh we might very well
yes yes so so welcome to the work group
and your yes okay good thank you
so before we get going here
we circulated the blue sheets and I
think almost everyone has signed it
anyone not signed the blue sheets now
okay
Sarah is gonna monitor Jabbar so if
there's any Jabbar activity we'll pick
it up there we've talked about IPR we
should also mention meet echo we have
one of our presenters Sean woo on on
meet echo there and one other
participant mister ding I think it is
it's a little hard to see for me at
least
so we'll be watching for participants to
queue up and in any case so this is the
agenda will quickly do working group
status and talk about our Charter and
milestones we've got one draft still in
actually two drafts on Sdn controller
performance they're in working group
last call finishing up and one draft
that we've sudo adopted on evpn and Pb
Pb be evpn benchmarking there that's
actually two topics that were combined
and I guess we'll get a status a little
discussion about that
today mostly from us though right the
chairs yes yeah so then we have a series
of new proposals our remote presenter
Sean Wu will be talking about the
network service layer abstract model we
have updates for the back to back frame
of benchmark which is part of RFC 2544
please find and sign the blue sheet sir
thank you and then we'll have a fairly
brief discussion of the updated
benchmarking for modern firewalls kind
of proposal which which really was just
described for the first time on the list
today we known it was coming but it came
a little slower than we thought so at
least we have at least we have something
to what to look at there but then after
looking at these new proposals and
reviewing the old ones briefly we'll
look at the the reach are during text
will consider what would we would might
want to modify additionally and then we
may look at a few milestones if if we've
got the wherewithal to do that and I
actually think Warren will join us today
Sarah our ad advisor you said he had
another meeting but I think that other
meeting was cancelled I think it was DNS
SEC yeah so he even so he may well be
able to join us any any changes or
bashes to the agenda seeing none that's
good sir please please grab the blue
sheet there and sign in you'll see I'm
recruiting blue sheet signers because
we're we're we're late on Thursday
afternoon and that usually that usually
affects attendance the only thing that
will be worse would be to be after lunch
tomorrow I think so in any case I'm
sorry
good question Sarah asks how many
newcomers do we have in the room please
raise your hands why five very good so
what I always say when newcomers join us
and we're and you're very welcome to
join us this is a very easy group to
join if you have a testing background
you'll you'll fit right in here and we
have a supplemental web page which Sarah
was nice enough to restore to the
interwebs which which in a few
paragraphs tells you how to get involved
here very quickly so that's on our you
know our data tracker charter page so
you guys will see at the end we're
talking about proposals and retar during
discussion what that really means is as
we're looking at taking on new work you
guys are joining at a perfect time
because if there's something you guys
are interested in and you wanted to
bring in now is a great time so I
realize you're new or maybe on a
Thursday you're four days into your
first IETF so if you have questions
about that let us know but now please
don't be shy at the end when we get to
that make sure if you have ideas let's
hear about them and Al and I can help
you even after the meeting on what next
steps are and how to bring that work in
and what have you I knew or tend to use
join us please grab the blue sheets er
which is uh and pass it back there
perfect thank you so much okay so on so
other than this about on no bashing of
the agenda seeing none let's move on all
right so here's our quick working group
status folks I'll bet this thing is
supposed to be turned on we went through
we went through a whole I am meeting
and that I mean that's that's gotta be
it right Wow okay
right right
usually you can turn them on so meet
echo meet echo meet echo we we've got a
microphone out and we've got a speaker
monitor which is not turned on they're
supposed to be monitoring audio to pick
this up I mean I mean I mean that we
could do that too but I can't so here's
the quick working group status as I said
we're in group last call is just about
to end for the SDN controller drafts
we're tracking many proposals here's a
list of some of the proposals which
we've just I talked about in the agenda
but we've got more status some really
good news here look at the list of for
RFC's that we've completed in the last
interim period but we've I mean the the
reason we're reach our turing is fairly
obvious we've actually been really
productive in the last couple of years
or so and and and believe me this is a
group that that works long and hard on
its RFC's to push out for like this is
is pretty amazing I can't remember this
ever happening in a long time right
so discussion on the agenda we're gonna
be talking about the Charter we
mentioned that oh and here's the here's
the link to the supplementary BMW G page
I knew it was in here someplace
this is on you know encrypted dotnet and
Sarah was kind enough to provide this
after one of the cable providers
discontinued my residential web pages so
no problem for that here's our current
milestones just one left on the current
Charter and that's that's also a good
state to be and it means that we should
be considering proposals and looking at
retiring so a little bit late with that
one but we're not going to worry about
it not not your fault
so when we when our drafts are reviewed
by other areas and it's a good chance to
mention our our scope and charter here
we do all of our testing in an isolated
test environment packets that we use
frames that we use they all have
addresses in an address space that's
been assigned to the benchmarking
methodology work and what that means is
that if you see these packets on the
live network you can discard them we
don't want our packets to get out and
the live network and we prefer the
testing to be isolated so that's one way
to you know to try to ensure that that
kind of isolation have our own address
space and so forth but the the main
point I'm making here is that what we
want is for the security folks to
understand if they pick our draft up
cold and they haven't read our Charter
they may look at this and scream what do
you mean you're doing you know look at
all this traffic you're sending them to
the network that's got to be some kind
of problem well it really isn't it's not
going into the network it's a laboratory
isolated testified so we we remind them
of that in general and that this should
be part of all our graphs let's see I
think this may be this goes too far here
yeah yeah I think that's let me check
yeah yeah so we'll look at the proposal
summaries
so we we've adopted and in in some way
shape or form this evpn benchmarking
proposal so we've got that all in green
there and you can see the kinds of
things that we evaluate whether there's
a proposal written on you know written
up for it whether it's in the scope of
the Charter we you know we make the call
on that ourselves and then get feedback
from our ad whether there's a draft that
supports the proposal whether we've seen
significant support at meetings and on
the list and whether there's any
dependencies and other notes so
everything here we have covered for that
and we've had the adoption column on the
list and I believe that was successful
and so the last the last thing we need
there is is a version of it that
actually takes on the working group file
name but but that's something where I
won't be working toward okay so it's
there's other proposals here that I'll
just briefly mention this virtual
benchmarking as a service we haven't
seen much on that in a while and we kind
of alerted one of the authors to it and
at the last meeting and he said oh yeah
I'm gonna bring something in well
nothing so that may well be dead the
virtualized platforms testing but this
was discussed quite a bit in Chicago but
we haven't seen any activity on it since
nevertheless we've got a draft dated
this year so I think we'll keep that on
the matrix for a while here for service
function chaining we did see something
on that in July at the last meeting and
for virtualized Network which sort of
went on hiatus for a while and then came
back we've seen a new draft of that in
July but it continues to have the issues
that have been raised on the list and at
meetings and so they they really haven't
solved the problems just by keeping the
draft up to date so that's that's kind
of a liability there I'll mention that
we've got the new proposal from Sean woo
going to talk a little bit later about
the
servus abstract model and then a new
proposal from me
on back-to-back frame benchmarking and
then this other one on modern firewalls
next generation firewalls so but that
came in so late it didn't end up in the
matrix all right so that's what we'll
get to later with the retiring
discussion any questions about the
working group status okay all right so
then let's let's proceed let's proceed
to our I guess the best thing to do is
proceed to our web page here
this is gonna be horrible
Wow okay so which which one would you
like me to bring up that's what I mean
it'sit's meth okay so as al mentioned
the SDN controller draft is in the
hopefully last group last call comments
welcome we were just and I've done and
now I saw feedback from you I think
yesterday where you caught a snafu on
the editing side with a cut-and-paste
error and then an additional comment
that I need to work through with my
co-author so we'll we'll do that and
revise and resubmit but again it is
working for class call you guys are new
so please if you have comments on it now
now is the time now is the only time
you're going to get the comment on that
particular draft we got a dead mic there
as well as alright great where did you
press the button thank you great thank
you thank you any questions on the SDN
controller draft alrighty then we move
on to the EVP n yeah so the author there
is a student Jake ax he's been coming to
the IETF meetings he's based out of
India and couldn't make it to this
meeting this time I don't see him logged
into the meet echo either so he brought
the draft in last meeting there was a
fair amount of I would say spirited
discussion in the room about the
technical and the editorial content of
the draft we do too
quickly I would say we we almost always
ask that we have discussions on the list
but because there's been a huge outreach
I think with the IETF India community
and making sure that folks are
comfortable I did discuss with students
offline and pointed him back to the
minutes from IETF 99 where the content
some technical things for example his
test bed wasn't very clear what he was
testing at all and while he could
verbally or I think he was verbally
trying to explain it the document needs
to typically read if he's not here so
what I've asked him to do as a co-chair
is to go back and review the IETF 99
minutes and addressed the technical
commentary and if you can do that and I
will help him as an edit or as an from
an editorial function I will help him
with the English or just the editing
sometimes doing your first draft can be
daunting so we we are here to help we've
all been in this position but well I
don't know if you ever were I feel like
you might have come in knowing how to do
it all but I certainly did not know how
to do it all when I first joined and I
was a huge help so we're we're here to
help especially when you're new doing it
the first time we realize it can be a
challenge actly Mike my first draft
looked like the dog's dinner I was using
a word template and I ran a special
thing on on the template which you were
supposed to some little script supposed
to fix the carriage return line feeds
into something else and it actually
deleted all the whitespace ran the whole
thing together and I looked at it and
said well I guess there must be some
additional processing at IETF where they
fix it up so I submitted it that way and
and then and then I asked Matt Mathis
about it and and he said oh no they
don't do anything so the first one was a
true nightmare and and it was it didn't
take me too long to ditch the word
template but yeah that's actually a good
advice so anyway I mean but that's an
old story you know like like 19
eight or something don't be ascared of
the word templates as the non engineer
at IETF I know it's not common to say
that out loud but I live and die by the
word template so well it's very good
work
joe-joe touch put that together and I
guess it keeps it up to date so that's
that's great
so from here I'm expecting I will ping
Soudan if you want to assign me that
action after IETF 100 to make sure that
he understands that we've adopted the
draft that we do see the value not to be
discouraged by the amount of feedback
that he got because it was a fair amount
of feedback but I think the draft will
be much better for it and then once that
comes in I'll ask him to post that
explicitly on the BMW G list and if
you're interested if you have experience
here please read the draft and then
likewise I'll preempt al before he gets
to say it when you read somebody else's
draft well the con onus is there that
they'll read yours and that's a good
thing getting multiple eyes on a draft
is a good thing so that's right and
that's how you join the group really is
by reading a few drafts that we're
working on and providing your expertise
in form of comments where's the blue
sheets all the way in the back there's a
there's a blue sheet coming toward you
sir please we sign it thank you great
thank you
alright one further point on this Sarah
and and that is some I seem to remember
that Sue Dean was looking for additional
editor help
I think you've you've volunteered to do
that if there's anyone else who has evpn
expertise we should also consider maybe
another author as well to provide real
the the technical background that might
help out here
yeah I think that's ultimately a
question for sued in because at the end
of the day he needs to either take on
that help but I think the feedback he
got from your colleague they might
forget Jim Utara Jim thank you me too
yeah was very valid I also think it
might not have been received as well but
as long as we captured it and and
someone can implement it with expertise
that that's that's needed then and and
and really now that we've adopted this
as a working group draft we're sort of
in charge of the editor list yeah for
sure so I think doing something that
I've seen us do and BMW g1 drew you even
before I was chair getting that cross
working group feedback it's probably
going to be key here yeah because we
aren't going to get unless we have Jim
in here every single time I think we're
gonna have to take it to the routing
area to get a review oh yeah
which is good so we'll try that as well
or do that early alright so you get some
time to turn around the feedback yeah
yeah that's will will will work this at
a pace that everybody is comfortable
with very good okay so it's fairly easy
to find our drafts on this is the tools
page by the way which I've I mean this
has been around a lot longer than the
data tracker and I'm kind of more
comfortable using this but there there
is of course the the data track of
version of this and you can go there
alright so let's see
where are we in the agenda all right
we're racing along here okay
so Shawn can you hear us
and can we can we get you in the queue
for speaking yes hi okay hear me okay
yes we can hear you perfectly Shawn
that's fantastic great well I didn't
well I'm not no we move us so fast it's
almost my turn yeah yeah well uh I guess
that's a good thing because we lose our
note taker at five o'clock local time oh
goodness
all right so hang on a second here I'm
I'm finding you're finding your slides
on my greatly reduced screen all right
so I've I've got your slides up Shawn I
suppose you've got a remote display
there yes I do great okay well first off
welcome to the working group and and
this is Shawn is yet another new
participant but he's come to join us
with a some knowledge of what we're
doing and also a pretty good proposal in
hand so let's let's have a look what
just happened there no signal okay now
we're back that's obviously pretty
pretty hinky okay
you can go ahead any time Shawn I thank
you hello everyone I'm Sean from the
Juniper Networks I try the previous
authoress Adeem it also from a Draper
and I sure worked with him in the past
on the EDP end as well so let's move on
to the next slide or yet I'm doing it
right I just got to watch out what I
touch here all right thank you so
the network services layer abstract
model is really a reference model there
provide a converse Kelton of how we
would define at the document the
benchmarking methodology based on the EM
data structure so I have read a quite a
few our past our FCS and a draft from
BMW G and the first question is do we
need another modelling or do we need
another methodology in general since we
have already many existing standards out
there so let's take a step back and
consider our traditional methodology you
for the benchmarking I think I'll
mention it before is that we typically
looking at the black box level testing
and we're looking for the external
characteristics of a device or a system
so there's a few challenges as we the
networking technologies have evolved
over the years for example we're looking
at the black network testing instead of
giving testing folks on a single device
or a set of advice in many cases that
the user will be presented it was a
private vertical how do we do it so
we're looking at external
characteristics of a network rather than
a device or set of devices the ear model
has made a significant progress over the
last couple years and the direction of
the year model and what we are doing
here is complement but on two different
directions
what your model has been typically doing
is trying to define almost every aspect
of a technology or protocol how the
controller can use a vendor agnostic way
to configure a device using a setter
the very detailed commands but here the
abstract model is trying to use a
similar scene set of the scene taxes but
I only retain the high level which is
relevant from a service outlook
perspective so that will leave a lot of
details out only folks were the external
characteristics another kind of hub
buzzword is intent-based networking and
I'm not sure how you already are
familiar with the intent based work
networking so traditionally a user
interact with the device via a set of
configuration and the Yamato it's just a
vendor agnostic way to do it but we have
evolved a using the Sdn controller that
it will only require user to provided a
very small subset of within this
necessary intention so that are based on
a lot of the machine learning and
telemetry later the Sdn controller will
automatically provision the servers
using a set of the growing number of the
underlying devices so we no longer have
a static asset of the configuration
instead we were actually benchmarking
the intent rather than a set of the
devices where the concrete configuration
another challenge is the scale and
dimension the unit dimension those
scaling and unit dimensional
benchmarking is often the primary focus
of testing and typically it works great
when is in the unit dimension and the
ones adding the additional dimensions
which the motif services edge in many
different cases we that's where we start
to seeing a problem so when you have the
ability to abstract the
multi-dimensional Network and into a
simpler file model
that we can really test it out in the
lab and finally the converge your
services and there has really blurred
the boundaries between the different
layers today like if we want to send a
layer of free traffic we know not
necessarily require a layer 3
interconnect or layer 3 based the
product comes in many different cases
for example the evpn with type 5 route
it can actually not only exchange the
layer 2 mac database or mac route but
also has agreed to exchange the layer 3
the ipv4 ipv6 routes so the boundary of
related to an array of 3 is kind of
intertwined these days so we're using
this service model we're trying to come
up with separate the underlying
technology and the service profile which
basically is a set of the customer
requirements if I'm a business
perspective so this is why we are trying
to propose a simplified a year model to
for the model network services for the
benchmarking purpose next slide please
so a little bit busy slider here or I
should have a put a box in the middle
this is the count there's a four key
components in this model some of the old
existing that we have been using for
decades some of the top the component is
the relatively new so let's start from
the bottom if you look at in the middle
column so the bottom is the inventory
the inventory refers to a set of the
notes or hardware software resources and
eating a bunch of the connections wide
or Wireless they form a physical
topology that is the underlying hardware
layer that we are dealing with
and moving up a bit I separated the
logical topology from the physical
topology
the reason being eating the same set of
the physical topology in a lot of the
benchmark testing you know we can easily
create the tunnels to form a they're
completely different view of the
topology and you have the a protocol
adjacency where the device is the far
apart from a physical perspective but
they are really next to each other in
the logical perspective we can use some
of the tunnel technology like a V X LAN
and POS tunnels
USPS the gie tunnel that those are the
technology can really change the
perception of the higher application how
they view the underlying physical
topology the service provision which is
the dark blue bars those really the
static configuration of a testbed if
you're looking of the infrastructure
this is the focusing on IGP bgp the MPS
transport and the potentially the
bridging those define a set of the
communication protocols between the
networking devices provide the baseline
connectivity and finally on the top on
the left side that which is a service
layer this is the fund a set of the
ultimately services received by the user
perspective we have the internet
exchanger provider we have a data center
Metro Ethernet and so on forth so on the
left side of the five different layers
those are not new and we have been using
for decades the trying to capture that
eating the image or in a service
provisioning but what's new here is to
use a set of the e/m based data modeling
to describe or document those key
elements and to provide the baseline
support when we if we try to zoom in a
particular service benchmark
so next to our boxes wanted in a dark
green it's a service profile I think a
lot of times that in the game model we
typically define the configuration which
is a static is scale static
configuration the service profile is a
more referring to a setup with a dynamic
elements of the network there's a four
subcategories the traffic emulation
those are not new and typically a test
vendor that will come of the traffic
profile the protocol emanation emulation
to exchange the control Briony of data
with the network and the test what's
news in addition that a to current
subcategory was introduced the one we
have to have a certain set of the SLA or
how to describe the resiliency of a
network using a set of the timers like
how quickly the network will respond to
a failure scenario and finally we need
to a set of other events that we'll need
to define a common event like no link of
failure the control protocol churns and
some of the mobility the mobile could be
a station moving from one location to
another or VM motion that aware we
quickly provisioning a virtual machine
from one data center to another so those
are the four category that we are
looking to define what service provider
so this profile really owned by a
customer versus a service provision is
owned by the provider an ISP or cloud
provider and finally on the top of the
resource utilization the resources
described how much it's basically it's a
health indicator of the network and the
particular provision which is a set of
the static configuration and a
particular
set up with a loader which is described
in the service profile and how busy the
network is do they have enough capacity
to handle additional load of those
things okay
let's move on to next slide but if any
question from the room and feel free to
stop me and definitely want to answer if
we you have acquired doubts or questions
to eat more clarifications so here's the
okay sure thanks Ron okay here's the set
of the design principles that are we
trying to come up with this is service
model
one is we trying to leverage the
existing MO I took a lot of the tools IT
efforts were all daily tracker there are
tons of the efforts ongoing or past
there are 2500 yen related RFC's and
more than a hundred the internet draft
is being actively worked on so we did
not want to reinvent the wheel
we want to take it existing what all the
work has been done in various protocol
areas but that we don't want to take or
that's what we want making sure only
provide a sufficient set of the keywords
to this abstract model but not
exhaustive we will leave a lot of
additives out for example the IP
addressing and roundest Englisher and
those are necessary for a real
production network provisioning but not
needed here we were trying to look at
the aggregator view from a network of
high-level and unnecessary zooming in
down to the device level an additional
set of the rules we had to introduce is
the distribution model we're not trying
to mirror the exact how the network is
operating but instead we're trying to
look for a abstract the distribution
model to use a very few parameters to
model the existing set of the routing
entries or map database or even a
tracker profile and the
service model also need to provide a
view from different perspective the
Cosmo the provider at a manufacturer
they have different folks about how they
need to benchmark for example the
customer is only looking at the network
capability not necessary care about the
underlying technology that they provide
the service profile meaning that I just
want to move the traffic from place a to
place B they don't necessary care about
which we ended up the equipment what
technology use EDP and avi POS they
probably don't care the MVP on or just
vanilla IP multicast those are just a
choice or if I'm going to provide a
perspective it's not necessary from
customer so the service model is really
focusing on the a external
characteristics which is the from a set
of the surface profiles and a finally
not but not least as we want to make
sure those servicemen were calm rated
the new requirements from the vnf
there's a lot of the discussions as al
mentioning the agenda data the sta and
the D the virtualized the platform and
of those in need to be taking into
consideration not only the virtualized
platform but also virtualized network so
ok well let's take a look at an example
in the next slide again there's a lot of
the content data and I'm not sure if you
can see the clearly from the behind so
there's only this is not a complete a
profile it's a subset of the the model
that is it broke into four different
categories on the top the three one is
the service definition here is example
of the layer two services in the middle
is the traffic profiles traffic profiles
are really you can consider it as a
service profile what really the customer
is a program to put a load what kind of
a load that is prolonged to network that
is going to be handled by the underlying
service
and on the right side is the resource
because when we do them benchmarking and
we have to look at the not only the
final throughput but also looking at the
health indication about a network and
again this table is not the black
network black box testing every we will
have to look at the performance in
indication that we're looking at those
KPIs of the devices and on the bottom
the bottom is the resiliency the
residency is really defined a set of the
timers define how quickly the network or
the device will recover function this is
some of the common events for example
the failover in a motor homing scenario
some of the know the link of failures
the ISSC or the in-service software
upgrade and how much time that would be
allowed to the device to recover without
breaking the control sessions so by a
small set of the data we expect the user
or the tester will take the high-level
parameters and generate the
configuration depending on the
underlying device type and all that we
always care about is get a set of the
validation from both the resource it
basically a setter of the KPI and the
performance in the term of the
forwarding or the scale of the control
plane it can handle as well as making
sure they have in demonstrate enough
resiliency and me those threshold for
various types of the events so this is a
there's a lot of work underway to make
that really useful and making it more
complete so that it can be used to
profile various types of networks so I
think that the decision is really hard
when we
trying to distill a large number of the
existing yen data model into a very
small subset and only keeping what's
necessary that's the hardest part of
this proposal okay the expert yeah come
here here's a question Shawn from Al um
it looks like looks like most of the
most of the things we're looking at here
the elements of the yang model so to
speak
many of them are provisioning or
configuration values like for example
we've got the we've got the traffic
profile here which would be it would
both be input to the device under test
but also the input to the traffic
generator to to to use these specific
frame sizes it would be good to
distinguish between what appear to be
the measured values over here on the
right under forwarding as sort of less
about I guess all of these are
potentially measurements here under
resources aren't they yes the the
resources snapshot of the current kind
of load indication and also the final
outcome of the I guess the results of
the test yes good um and it and it's it
may be worthwhile just as a you know as
a quick feedback that occurs to me here
that that we've got we've got these what
we call sort of secondary or auxiliary
metrics like the CPU utilization and the
memory footprint and so forth
those are those are good to know but we
we always set them aside from the
benchmarks that we that we try to
measure the benchmarks of course like
like throughput being the primary things
that we're after
CPU utilization at the measured
throughput is a there's a good thing to
know and probably the kind of
information that will will particularly
want to supplement our benchmarks with
so that we've got a better chance of
improving how our benchmarks are used in
network engineering in the future yeah
absolutely I think there's different
level the importance of the resources
sections and also this is just showing
one snapshot of the steady-state and
also showing we probably will be
interesting hood is a PQ tradition and
utilization in event of those failure
scenarios how the network will respond
because in a like say 10 in 10 based
networking those in tradition will
matter and dynamically change the
configuration and back to the service
provisioning meaning they will
dynamically move the component of a
certain function into different elements
within the network so that's why I think
it becomes more important to over the
time that both the forwarding and the
snapshot of the resource transportation
need to be captured as a single set good
Sean I have a question so I'm not sure
if I'm clear based on what L asked are
there under the resources profile are
you looking to set the values are you
looking to say this is what you would
expect as maximums what is the intent of
the resources configuration here
resource is not a configuration resource
it is a measurement as a snapshot and
but also we can provide some of the
references threshold meaning that
typically under this is scenario that we
expected the device to reach certain
performance so then just to clarify
you're saying that this would be
populated at the end of a test or a test
case run
and it should most of the value there
should be captured and as a result of
the test while but in some cases the
reefs also have a predefined a threshold
that can be a more kind of a
benchmarking a common part for them but
we expect that as the nine rated at 100%
but it may not reach to it but most
likely the original intention yes I do
mention its capture the results not
necessarily prior to the tester it's a
configuration it's more kind of a
dynamic snapshot all right then not to
beat this up so I see under your traffic
mix you're showing sort of classic pics
from 25:44 are you accounting or
allowing for I mix and so you would just
specify your non-standard your I'm
excretion here in some way I guess so
the frame size the traffic or file is a
way to provide a user to either pick a
predefined like RFC year two five four
four and a profile or they can construct
their own distribution based on the real
network measurement to mimic the real
environment here not necessary to tell
which one the user how to what valley it
is it just provided a way that if they
want to have a customized the profile
those are the very they can provide it
and the underlying processor of this
model can generate the real traffic on
the test emulator based on the in
limited instead of the parameter from
the user thank you sure very good okay
all right next slide
moving right along okay so here's a few
use cases that I can think of how we can
if we develop spend time developing
those abstract model how can we use
first of all is to have a formal way to
document in the benchmarking methodology
and the results in a more into exchange
but data form act and once a library of
the source model or network deployment
scenario is been developed or captured
so here's how we can I can see that the
being used first war is an a map between
the real network production network to
the abstract model it can we can have a
set of a tool to discover the existing
network in tradition exist network
baseline and convert those at your
configuration probably is gonna be a
Java set of the data into a simplified
abstract model once we have the model
then we can feed back into the test lab
for the benchmarking for the design
choices and do the F what if scenarios
in a finally we have the test results in
a feedback to the the model to document
and to store the data for the further
analysis and those are results the
results are from those analysis can be
further fed backing to the network to
improve the design to optimize the
resource assignment to those things but
what I here on the lower right corner is
really kind of a nutrition facts for a
network and this is to provide an extra
it's a really hard decision to which
element is more it's important that we
should be included and those in the
network effects sheet I know there's a
lot of data sheets out there typically
that we have follow the the benchmarking
RFC's and we already have a set of those
but I think when we move it on and how
we can define those that
elem information in the yen data model
and provide a more English
interchangeable format so that a user
can use the same set of a syntax that
generate the report they like okay I
think that's premature next slide
so here's next step you know I
definitely need some help from the work
collaboration and provided the import
various type areas especially for the
SDN area how we can make this more
compatible model to work with the
virtualized Network and we need to
validate to the end keywords and making
sure that we have to run the linked for
the year and the created sample detail
the for complete profile for layer 2
network or could be layer 3 it's just
picking a sample and then all these
feedback once we hear more and the world
updated the internet draft that's all I
have thank you well thank you Shawn that
was a great and very interesting
presentation it was our our first
exposure to yang models here in the
benchmarking methodology working group
and I think now we can probably say that
the net confiscation of the IETF is
complete that's the the term that people
are thrown around for how how the reason
that everybody in the IETF seems to be
working on Anna yang model somewhere so
we we have a we have a question at the
microphone and please identify yourself
CERN and escalade Pedro Martinez from
any city and my question is that how do
you think to deal with data and actually
the benchmarking stuff you know you have
some kind of four men smoking you have
you must have some kind of algorithm and
also some data to input in to the to the
protocol or whatever and then some
reference output to compare that where
do you plan to fire
and this data and what in that sense how
do you think that it would be done with
your model
yeah I think the model thanks for the
question by the way and I think a year
definitely right I'll point out the
difference between the model itself and
the data to be captured and how the data
can be used analyzed for the further
improvement of the network or
benchmarking so if I understand your
question correctly is that the how can
the data being used for to reference
maybe
reference the what expectation or how
the data is gonna be huge due to fed
into this model maybe you can elaborate
a little bit sorry no sorry more than
that is which kind of data are you
planning to use are you proposing to use
okay so like the real tracing data from
the network or something
so so it's the question in the context
of this slide here yeah you have in the
law in this slide in the lower left you
have this design immense marketing is
provided to a test lab where there's you
also need some kind of data to input
today to the whatever protocol software
or whatever you are trying to are
testing where is that data coming from I
mean okay yeah so so the question is
that where this data is coming from to
be fed into the test lab so that the
test lab can do their test right now
yeah okay so this is the trying to use a
set of the a subset of the gear model
take it for example layer 3 deep here
layer 3 VPN has so many arguments
it you completely define a layer 3 VPN
offering what this model does is to
extract a subset of the key elements for
example we only tell the test lab I need
have a hundred sites say I did a total
of the hundred thousand routes but not
necessary tell the test lab the which
router has how many routes or which
route I had how many VPN instances what
the data you provide is an aggregated
view so that a test generator will use
this high-level data from basically is
describing a customer requirements for
network and then distributed into the
individual devices based on the
definition if we go back to the one
slide example probably that can be
explained better yeah ok so in this
particular case is that we this model
defines what the key elements is needed
to describe a network sufficient number
of the elements and the the actual value
is not set by this data instead it
should be set by it's a the test
engineer and say hey this is a target I
have a bigger router I need to increase
the number of the global Mac count
instead the model only defines what to
define but it doesn't define the actual
value I'm not sure if that answers your
question answer it if it doesn't define
the actual value I think one of the sort
of core tenants that we have in BMW I
feel like I'm great repeatability if it
doesn't define the actual value then how
if I run the same test ten times in a
row for example how do I know that I've
run the same test ten times in a row or
how do I know I've run the same
with the same input values each time so
that I can compare apples to apples the
results do you see what I mean
well yes but I think the value when we
do a report a test say this is the
describe the profile the profile will
have a list of the elements end of the
value yourself but our proposal here is
just to define the skeleton of the
profile but the tested repeated test it
will have used the set of parameters
there were you the same set up the
number the pass on the test generator so
out of the 10 attempts they will hear
the same number so I think there's a
question is there's a profile contain
the value yes it does
does our proposal define the value it
doesn't our proposals only to find the
key elements and but certainly we can
provide the values but as vadi will
change over the time depending on the
capacity never underlying network can
offer so I don't think I answer your
question maybe so Shawn I think what
you're saying is for the slide that al
has up right now yeah the profile itself
is in essence the methodology you just
happen to provide in the example sample
test data that the tests are filled in
but I think what you're saying is it
would be up to me to take the skeleton
without the values and then as the test
case or the engineer fill in the values
and record exactly what I tested and
then of course I could repeat with those
same values 10 times in a row for
example that's correct yes that's
correct
okay thank you very good good
clarification yeah so um there's no one
else at the microphone well um I think
we've got a a decent idea of what you
plan here Shawn and
I think I think it will be
I've got your next step slide up we
should have the call for collaborators
on the on the mailing list yeah
absolutely and I think looking for
additional help and if anyone is
interested a the really goal is to
provide a simplified thermal profile on
the network so that make our
benchmarking easier anymore
interchangeable right right and and I
encourage you to continue to to flush
this out in terms of the where to
network benchmarking example okay sure
alright anything else folks okay very
good
I think well well thank yes thanks for
your thanks for your your proposal and
your presentation both both very good
and informative here we'll we'll see ya
where the work working group wants to go
okay okay
all right
so
so next on the agenda here is the back
to back frame a benchmark proposal
that's it's obviously going to update
our se
25:44 there's just one section of RFC
25:44 which would be updated here and
[Music]
so here we go um so that so the draft
was prepared and and circulated on the
list made a little announcement of it
and as a as a little background for the
for this proposal RFC 25:44
subspecialize this measurement measures
the back to back frame benchmark that's
what it's called but it requires a
little more really the back to back
frames is more a description of the
methodology than it is what's actually
being measured it's it's defined in RFC
1242 as the longest burst of frames a
device under test can process without
loss and they go on to explain the tests
of this parameter are intended to
determine the extent of data buffering
in the device
so in 25:44 today there is in fact a
very concise objectives expressed a very
concise procedure and also a very
concise reporting for this benchmark
it's about five paragraphs so when when
I when I looked at this testing in the
context of testing these switches in the
OPN of the V switch performance project
we made some measurements of this of
this benchmark and the results are
basically shown in these two links here
to references the reason I included the
links was because in the printout of the
RFC something went wrong with the
formatting and the URLs went away so it
wasn't what wasn't much help
well it was it looked to me like it was
in a place where they would be displayed
but apparently you got to just append it
in the title or something and that makes
it show up in the reference so um so
I've got that straightened out here for
at least for a temporary basis
and as I said we I I circulated and
discussed the are our results from the V
switch performance benchmarking at some
length at the last meeting I'll talk
about that a little bit now but you're
welcome to take a look at the at the
slides which is which are the this first
link and and actually you can see even
more detail spelled out in the this wiki
page where we were working on on lots of
traffic generator testing and
comparisons there but looking at the
back to back frame testing in particular
so when I ran the tests and this is a as
I said this is a test where you've got
the traffic generator sending traffic to
a device under test and it passes
through the device under test so it's
either routed or forwarded or
encapsulated or transcoded or you know
whatever else whatever else the device
under test does to the traffic it does
it and then it passes that traffic back
out the other side for a reception so
the there it had been noted in the past
that the back to back frame benchmark
had some problems with consistency but
we were able to test this over a series
of months and actually over a series of
two different hardware platforms and we
saw a very consistent results of between
the two for fixed frame sizes and it was
it was somewhat variable and a few of
them but we came up with an explanation
for that
but the sort of the surprising results
were for large frame sizes you saw the
range of frame sizes that Sean just
showed us now all the way up to a fairly
high values 64 all the way up to you
know 15 1,500 approximately white frames
but there so the the frame length
reported for a large frame sizes was
unexpectedly long in other words it was
on the order of 30 seconds of storage in
the
under test we knew that wasn't true and
so it required us to investigate that
and the test equipment we were using
didn't report any kind of error when it
when it said I just produced a burst of
30 packets and that's as far as I'm
gonna go and so that's the longest burst
this couldn't handle that's it turns out
that that that that was erroneous data
the the test generator was reporting
I'll explain that a little bit later the
calculation of the extent of buffer time
in the device under test helped explain
the results with all frame sizes it
turns out that some frame sizes like the
the highest frames the device under test
was able to process them at full
back-to-back frame line rate so in fact
while the processing is bleeding off the
buffer as fast as the frames arrive you
don't get the buffering that you're
trying to measure in this test now
that's a problem if you don't report it
that way so that was one of the things
we want to change I think about the
procedure and it was observed that the
actual buffer time and the device under
test could be estimated using the
results of the throughput tests
previously conducted based on RFC 2544
so so that the final conclusion there is
that the throughput test results
actually if they're if they're paired up
with the back-to-back frame tests they
can they can also be used to reduce the
number of frame sizes tested because
only when only or only when we have a
frame size which is faster than the the
device under test can handle do we
generate a queue length and eventually a
tail drop or a queue overflow where the
burst of packets that was submitted
causes some lost and then we can
conclude that the burst was too long so
we have to reduce the burst size and and
then continue with the trials of the
test so you really want to distinguish
those two cases where the
the packets sending rate with extremely
large frames is too slow to create a
queue and and those which will create
loss so we begin by expanding the the
back-to-back frames test method here and
and so we have identified that the 2544
throughput test needs to be a
prerequisite test now absolutely
conducted before him so the test setup
and configuration much math must match
between the two tests the record we're
going to use the same recommended frame
sizes and we must be using the zero loss
condition which is what 2544 mandates or
throughput and then we can reduce the
frame size set for back-to-back if we if
we compare our delivered frames per
second with the theoretical maximum
which is a the green bar here in this
case so on this graph and this comes
from the OPN efi testing we ran tests at
64 byte frames with the open V switch we
saw I guess it was about 24 million
frames per second with a VPP it was a
little bit less in this particular test
but they were both less than the maximum
theoretical throughput so this is a
frame size that we can we can test well
to see if the device under test is going
to be doing it well it's it's certainly
doing some buffering it can't keep up
the device under test can't keep up with
the the maximum throughput at 64 bytes
per second so at 128 it's a little bit
ambiguous it's actually very close to
the maximum theoretical throughput and
we'll actually see that in in the
results but then at 256 or 512 there
there we we get in in in both cases both
for VPP and OBS they lined up exactly
with the maximum theoretical throughput
for frames at the mini minimum inner
frame back gap as
but back-to-back stands for so so what
we can conclude from this graph is that
most of our testing would be conducted
using the 64 and the 128 byte frames and
there's no point really for this
particular configuration to go on and to
do 256 and the higher frame sizes we're
never going to see queuing and so we're
not really going to be able to measure
the buffer size so in the procedure we
would list the frame sizes selected for
the throughput tests they're composed
the tests are composed of repeated
trials for each frame size a trial
requires sending a burst length counting
the fort first line counting the
forwarded frames and the trials seek to
they the trials seek the longest burst
length that can be sent with zero loss
measured or same same number of frames
sent to the same to the number received
and the test outcome is every time it's
the burst length and we are only going
to count the ones where we see zero loss
so the tests are repeated n times and
actually for the after you after you
seeked and found the largest burst that
you can send without loss then you
record that and then you go on and
repeat the searching again and so you do
that end times and the reversed lengths
are then averaged and the average length
from n repeated tests is the benchmark
value so that's a lot more detail than
is currently in RFC 2544 but I think
that that's the that's the set of things
that we are looking for now so for
clarifications so I I grabbed this right
out of the read out of the draft so for
each frame size we're going to calculate
the following
Maree statistics for the back-to-back
frames over the end tests the average is
the benchmark but we're also going to
report the maximum burst length that we
saw in the end trials the minimum and
the standard deviation and further we're
going to calculate the implied device
under test buffer time and the corrected
device under test buffer time as follows
so the the average buffer time is the
average number of back-to-back frames
divided by the theoretical frame rate so
what we've got here is a calculation of
the time that that is represented by the
burst and that time is it turns out it's
both taken up in buffering and frames
that were served by the processing
because the the device is attempting to
keep up with the maximum frame rate but
in the in the in the low packet sizes
it's not able to so what we we calculate
this total time but then we're able to
correct this buffer time by figuring out
the proportion of frames which were in
the burst which will actually served and
processed and and basically sent out of
the device on their test while the burst
was running so in fact you can think of
it as a a buffer which in the in the
implied buffer time it's the it's the
complete burst that buffer is the time
is represented by all the packets sent
in the burst in this corrected buffer
time we we use the maximum theoretical
foot throughput to figure out how many
packets were bled off the buffer before
one packet overflowed and this gives us
an estimate of the the actual buffering
time inside the device
so we would report the results as
follows for a given frame size like 64
frame octets we would report our average
back-to-back frame length at the first
here it's here it's only 26,000 so
that's a good point a problem I'll
probably want to boost that up so that
it matches more the kind of millions of
packets we've seen in typical testing
but so we've got the average at 26,000
we've got the the min and the max and
the standard deviation here reported at
at 25 527 thousand and and 20 packets
and then the corrected buffer time which
is let's see here it looks like that's
about it's small it's a 40 microseconds
yeah so not very much so that would
typically report it in a table like this
and in addition we'd want to report the
the standard the static and
configuration parameters that are
associated with the test so that's the
number of repetitions obviously and the
minimum step size that the device the
tester uses to try to determine the
burst length in other words it may not
be it may not be incrementing the burst
length by one packet that might take a
very long time so that might be
configured at at in a test with where
we're trying to test millions of packets
we might have a step size of a hundred
packets let's say something along those
lines and that would improve our ability
to complete this test quickly so this is
so a lot of this other than the average
this is a lot of new information that
we're requesting now we've we've kept
the traditional average benchmark but
we're asking to add this additional
collateral information please sign the
blue sheet sir you've been here for 10
milliseconds
too late so um so that that'll give you
a feeling for the oh I think I think the
blue sheets are very good thank you
Steve and and welcome to BMW Jane so so
next steps know what as far as I can
tell no one's actually reviewed read and
reviewed the draft yet and that would be
essential before we adopted it I think
you know I I have to hold myself up to
the same standard that anyone else would
as a participant bringing a proposal
here and then so once we get some
readership and review and feedback we we
could possibly consider I guess I didn't
ask the room has anyone read the draft
almost like a real light turn out who
will read the draft yeah whose willing
it was willing to do some do some work
here great that's that's the kind of
commitment we're looking to see so thank
you thank you for that great in fact you
can start reading it now well we I know
I know so what we could we could agree
to create a milestone for this work on
the basis of this description today that
we think this is worthwhile I've
actually proposed one there and then
obviously sometime in the future after
we've done some readership and review
but we'll hold off on asking that today
we'd ask her working group that this
whole list of authors not me and and
actually my my colleagues from OPM if
the vSwitch performance project may may
join me on this author list as well but
but I wrote this in like two days over
the weekend so I did get a chance to ask
them they wanted to join it but in any
case there's no guarantee even if we
take up a milestone there's no guarantee
that this draft would
be the one that satisfies it other ideas
are welcome so that's the way we play
here so Sarah so I ask please that we
read the draft and I think we'll come
back to your suggestions they're out in
London very good i we should ask if
there's any questions or comments in any
case and III want to do that because I I
saw you coming to the mic may ask please
say your name to mask what is the thing
that you are looking to test using this
methodology so when we do these kind of
tests usually we are looking to test
some particular you know component
within the switch architecture such as
queuing such as packet processing such
as buffering after processing or before
purchasing might take away from what you
described is in a way you try to check
what is the capacity to buffer buckets
before hosting events
am I correct or can you I stay right
stay right there there you may have a
follow-up question what what I
anticipate is that I've in my mind and
and the way I described it I modeled
this as as one buffer and one processing
stage that bleeds off the buffer the
reality is there are many more than one
buffer and there are many processing
stages but at least one of them is the
bottleneck so what we might see is the
sum of all buffers up to the up to the
processing bottleneck and and then
queuing beat bleeds up or or grows out
to the ingress interface before that so
my word so you're trying to check how
much buffering can happen before pocket
cross is seeing cause these issues
before the before the limiting packet
processing
that's right thank you for that good
because just as a note usually we use
these type of things also to detect how
much worse absorption in terms of
congestion a buffer can absorb which may
result in you know totally different
results in places within the switches
that they I've been thinking that the
reason to have this correction factor to
actually try to assess the actual buffer
time or space that's available is that
well actually one of the background
things is that you know real traffic
that doesn't necessarily arrive smoothly
or continuously it it arrives in bursts
and it may be valuable to know when a
device that's doing forwarding or
routing when that device pauses for a
moment or two and and and the processing
stops then how much real buffer is
inside that we can count on to be able
to smooth out these bursts I said so so
so that's that's that's I think we're in
sync on that thank you for their yeah
good good okay please yeah um my name is
Juan Gauri from PRI at tree so I asked
you welcome yeah it's um what professor
so my battery's about previous previous
slide I mean the props are so many
metrics there is um so what area six or
seven things but this is currently work
area right are you looking at the oh yes
yeah you're going back to that you're
going back to the Chairman slides do you
want me to put that up so everyone else
can see it here while you're asking the
question okay yeah oh sure sure no
problem
yeah there it is okay
yes please some what about em the
virtualized performing these and I
understand that but what about the
virtual light virtualization platforms
is it is it the scope of each other no
no no it but that's a it's a different
draft that was prepared by Samuel Camus
and Jacob wrap Jacob wrap one that we
discussed in our meeting in Chicago it's
it's it's sort of data center focused
it's a follow on piece of work to the
sort of the physical device data center
benchmarking that we completed just in
the interim period but they they are now
beginning to look at the data center
with virtualized networking as well so
that's the plat work platform that
they're talking about I'm sorry for the
shortness of the name there but but I
can give you a link to that draft if
you're interested in taking a look yes I
make sure that I am interested in just
like xxo packet accelerating technique
such as DP decay
oh yes so I just Kosar to the microphone
there I think otherwise benchmarking
benchmarking mass knowledge about those
happen technologies I just want to
create the new proposal over the next in
this in this working group okay so I
would be very interested in fact I've
been looking at potentially doing
something down this path as well so if
you have that draft as soon as you have
that ready a with my chair hat on I
think we very much encourage that it's
very relevant to what we see in the
industry and and how to benchmark that I
think is a good thing and then with my
chair hat off just as a participant I'm
very excited to read that so if you're
going to take that on thank you we'll
see you in London and please submit
draft before London so we have a chance
to read it and then we we can talk about
it in the next IETF yeah you know I
through email very very good and and be
sure that you take a look at RFC 80204
which is where the the open platform for
NF e V switched project provided some
considerations for doing exactly this
work I mean that's the project that's
the project that also contributed the
test results that we just discussed and
so we've been you know we've been
testing V switches and and and now vite
the cisco VPP virtual packet process are
there as well so there's some
possibilities for you know cross
insemination of ideas and testing in
this virtual switch and DP DK
accelerated space in fact we're
basically testing the plain vanilla OVS
the DP DK accelerated one and VPP and
DPP uses DP DK as well so thanks for
your proposal that's interesting in fact
um in general the RFC 81 72 talks about
considerations for benchmarking in
general in the in this virtual space and
we just we expanded on that here for
virtual switches in this one so that and
that's a another RC that was published
really just before this interim period
so it's it's actually been five very
recent ones that we've completed okay
[Music]
okay so I think now we want to go to its
the the next generation firewalls in
fact that's what we right look at this
yeah this is yeah this is really
annoying oh wait I mean I can get rid of
this at least okay
all right so um I've been asked to
represent this proposal on benchmarking
next-generation firewalls by the the
proponents who happened to be a couple
of a couple of good guys who worked with
us here in in the past
carsten or us and hovel and balla balla
raja both from the european advanced
network test center and they're
currently working with a not profile
not-for-profit initiative called net sec
open informed to innovate network
security test methodologies and they've
been looking at this for quite a while
they want to strongly improve the
applicability and reproducibility and
transparency of benchmarks for next
generation firewalls but also intrusion
detection and prevention systems unified
threat management and and oh I guess
it's and unified threat management
solutions so this is very opportune that
we have such an esteemed security area
colleague here with us as we're
discussing this yes yes he has to wake
up now yes
[Laughter]
so they're currently developing test
terminology and traffic profiles and
they're focusing on the next generation
of firewalls first and and that's the
work that they would like to begin to
contribute here in BMW G so they plan to
put this you know these other things on
the on the back burner for now and see
how it goes with benchmarking
methodology working group but they they
tell me personally that they looked over
many different standards bodies to
consider where to take this work and to
standardize it and they ended up
choosing us for our ability to take up
work quickly here also the you know the
good timing with our charter reach our
during efforts and so forth and and the
fact that you know we have the attention
of the industry here in in having done
this work before RFC 35 11 is our
previous effort in this area so well
they they plan to submit their first
draft sometime next week
and they hope to proceed quickly through
November in December and and so
depending on on how quickly we we want
to review this work we may take up an
interim meeting perhaps in December we
actually tried to have a nighttime
meeting scheduled here when some of the
folks from the US who are part of net
sec open could join us but that didn't
work out it turns out if that's actually
not very easy to do so so we will
investigate the possibility of an
interim meeting it will be a virtual
meeting - to hear more from the net sec
open folks and what they've got here is
a table of contents which mostly is
composed of the scope so it's focused on
test methodology for network security
device benchmarking tests in terms of
performance metrics describes the test
methodology to obtain repeatable results
independently using different vendor
test equipment
by defining the full set of test
configuration parameters this document
will allow users to reproduce network
performance and compare measurements
benchmarking tests focus a set of key
performance indicators we're all
familiar with those devices such as
firewalls next-generation firewalls
intrusion detection and prevention
devices well see this here they seem to
go beyond the next-generation firewall
scope so that's something I would
feedback I mean I think I think they
should probably attack next-generation
firewalls first see how that goes which
is actually what they said in the
message and then worry about this this
other interesting stuff like deep packet
inspection devices web application
firewalls and and so forth but but I
think you know we might consider adding
a sentence in our Charter to be sure
that everyone knows that we're we're
we're willing to take on devices in this
of this ilk if in fact the working group
is so how let me let me ask the room now
that we've described this how is is
there is there any interest in helping
net SEC open here with benchmarking
modern firewalls if so you can sort of
raise your hands okay nobody here today
personally a lot of my work stems from
the company that I work for them we
don't do we don't manufacture modern
firewall those but certainly I think
it's of interest very interest very
relevant excuse me to the industry today
absolutely and and when you when you
look at the fact that in fact RC 3511
was one of the first ones I helped to
finish up as a co-chair and and so
that's a long time ago 20 2003 so yeah a
lot has been learned in the meantime and
if you remember we had Mike Hamilton's
content-aware
work yes yes well he was the original
proposer that's why I always I always
think of it think of him there
but if there but if there's anything we
learned from that work we need to bring
that forward as well to that that's
still relevant of course that that's
been retired for a few years so and then
the rest of this is fairly usual the
test setup testbed calibration that's a
good thing though and reporting and
benchmarking tests and so forth and and
they want to define traffic mixes here
both know the stateful and and stateless
stuff you know that's going to be
interesting but that's that's something
they they feel very strongly about it
has to be reproduced and used by all the
vendors the same mix I think that's if
you wanted an apples to apples
comparison that's the key and I think
it's one of the places where at least
for me you know 25:44 is great but the
average packet size has evolved on the
internet from Warmack started out in
twenty five forty four times so for them
to at least take a stab at defining
traffic mixes that make sense to them so
you can have an apples apples comparison
across vendors isn't that what we all
want yeah well that and and I think we
want to continue with the fixed size
testing as well yes not discount all
right but I think we have that covered
yeah and I've seen a couple of data
sheets recently for devices in the
next-generation firewall class and they
are basically testing whatever they want
at the moment so so that's the I mean
that's that's the goal here is to get
everybody testing the same thing so that
we can have the apples to apples
comparison without the speck mint chip
yeah that's our that's our original goal
okay so any further questions about that
I encourage you to visit the next step
the net sec open site and see what else
they've got going but I think that's a
it's a timely proposal and one we should
consider further especially after we've
seen the first draft of their draft
okay well thanks for participating in
that review and so back to the agenda
so we so we've covered everything here
that we planned today except for the the
sort of the discussion of any new
proposals and the reach are during
discussion so I would like to now open
the microphone to any new proposals that
folks would like to make although we did
hear one along the way and since I don't
see anyone rushing to the microphone I
thought that I would make one myself in
fact during the IRT F open session mr.
Paul Emmerich from a Technical
University of moongeun
talked about the moon gen traffic
generator and also some results that
we've some of us have seen in the
industry where if you use a different
traffic generator and there's quite a
few choices out there today there's the
hardware ones from Lexy Inspiron and of
course several software generator
generators like like moon gen and and
also t-rex which has its own platform
but can be run on on general-purpose
hardware as well and there's a few
others I won't try to mention them all
but the the point is that we should
we've seen some sensitivity of the
results to sensitivity is is to the
generator itself and we suspect that
that's due to the characteristics of the
packet streams that the generators are
in fact generating but they may be
generating bursts when they say that
they're intending to generate a constant
bit rate stream also we might recognize
that more of the traffic in the network
today is bursty than CBR so so maybe of
maybe some of our streams that we
generate should have some burst
characteristics as well but the idea
that that that came to me as as Paul was
making his presentation
showing the the stream generator
characteristics was that if we have
ideal characteristics that we're trying
to match that a measurement of the
stream itself would be very valuable and
we could compare that with a tolerance
template around the let's say the inner
packet arrival times that have been
generated compare that across you know a
stream that's long enough to
characterize a device under test and
then for every generator that we're
considering using in the various
circumstances and so forth take a look
at how well it conforms to this template
of Tolerance kind of as a calibration of
the the generators themselves and I
think that we if we if we wanted to take
up this work that we would need to add
at least one sentence to our Charter to
say that we will also look into this
calibration so what do you think Sara I
think the idea of having a test apology
where your traditional D UT in the
middle is not actually the D UT but
rather the test tool itself is the D UT
is a fantastically wild idea I'm not
entirely sure we'll make friends with
some folks who have visited us in the
past but particularly as we take on
virtual I think as we take on more of
the virtual testing and how do we
particularly with some of the results
that I was presented from the Opie nfe
work that we've done as you start
testing there's a lot of push for not
just physical testers where you have a
Pina convolve but virtual testers where
the traffic stays inside of the virtual
machine and and I know there's a lot of
controversy around that and how do we
make sure it's a blackbox test but the
idea of having the ability to test the
test tools I think is something that
we've
seeing or I've seen as a equipment
manufacturer coming in for my customer
so has anybody else had experience with
this no answers you're gonna be buying
beer tonight at Pecha Kucha just letting
you know so yeah Paulette Mike to Munich
so yes obviously I've had experiences
that since I gave the talk earlier today
and it's really difficult to measure so
this is like everything is moving to
software package you know at us and now
we are seeing that that they are not
accurate but again to validate them
validate the software package generator
is another software tool doesn't really
work because you get the same in your
measurement device the same position
problems as with your generation device
so you then really need hardware to
precisely calibrate it then the next
question is what is an important or
what's the right metric to or what do I
tell events what is even acceptable may
be some small bursts are acceptable
maybe gave even what we want so I don't
have all Anton antis I just did some
work there and it was very very
challenging and also yeah
the results were kind of unexpected I
thought we might find some some small
deviation but then we found that the
latency differs by 400% just because we
changed the birth size was like Oh what
is going on
so could I then I agree I think it's
hard I do think sometimes when we take
on a draft we take it in and it doesn't
have to necessarily publish out so if we
get to the end of the exercise
maybe we decide this is too difficult to
do but at least we tried for me I think
it's valid
I wouldn't mind I had a class today and
couldn't see your presentation and I'm
wondering if I could potentially
convince you if we have time on the
agenda in London
presented here and then we could maybe
ask a second time do we do we want to
contribute or would we want to look into
this sure this sounds like a great idea
thank you
and in fact um I'm sure your slides will
be available in the IRT F open yes they
so we can we can take a look at those
but yes absolutely I think it if we if
we if we can pursue this then that would
be great I'd be very interested in
following up on this as well also yeah
great there I think and I think I think
the minute the minute anyone in the test
generator world gets wind of us thinking
about doing this well will suddenly have
lots of collaboration that's right
something that I wanted to look into as
but I do you have a package analysis I
actually as precise as they came and
this I didn't have any on hand so maybe
that's and so maybe that's it maybe the
first draft that we take on focuses on
hardware and if we can get collaborators
from the other vendors who have
traditionally come in to BMW G I think
this becomes a little easier we can
donate a WebEx and then talk through and
run our tests bring results here that's
really nice um so how I did these tests
another time we used an FPGA but that
was like well it's it's great hardware
but it can be very cumbersome to workers
if you need to change something but at
least you know how to ourselves so you
know it works and and if we have a
actually there's no reason to wait all
the way from London we you've got the
slides and if we have an interim meeting
this could be one of the topics that we
take up sure but but you could still
potentially get a trip to London out of
this that'd be good
so okay well I I'm glad I brought that
one up and it was well timed with Paul's
earlier presentation I think that's
that's a potential thing that we would
want to add at least one sentence in our
draft charter
so there at least there seems to be
interest in it right sir
okay I wonder if I can
I'm just gonna pray oh yeah I've got it
right here alright so I wanted to I
wanted to mention that we've we've got
this we've got this charter that I
shared on the list for discussion Sarah
and I worked on this a bit before it was
republished and this this paragraph here
the scope of BMW G has been extended to
develop methods for virtual network
functions and their unique supporting
infrastructure such as Sdn controllers
and V switches so we're actually where
we had this as a kind of like a bullet
item before for a specific area of work
we've actually completed the
considerations draft which was the first
homework item there and we're just about
to complete the SDN controller stuff and
then and go on and do some other things
so we've got all sorts of things here
mentioned platform capacity and
performance characteristics or virtual
routers firewalls signaling control
gateways other forms of gateways are
included benchmarks will foster
comparison between physical and virtual
network functions and also cover unique
features of the network function
virtualization systems like migration or
life cycle operations and so forth
there's a lot but there's plenty of
things that we we we could be doing
which are not data plane things lots of
stuff so I think just as a note to self
actually I actually think we've got
enough here to support the well maybe
not quite enough here to support the
security related things that came up for
the security and the second was
specifically adding a sentence for the
calibration right devices so make sure
we
mad that him all right what happened
there all right social security devices
and calibration yeah that's a test
release
okay
so the so we'll flush the wording of
those sentences out and circulate it on
the list and then I guess we'll propose
after we've had some some time for a
review and some of the other documents
well will propose milestones related to
evpn and whatever else we decide to to
take up out of the the set of new
proposals we've heard we've heard about
three brand-new proposals today we've
got some other ones which we've shown in
the matrix they're lurking around and
and hopefully the proponents will be
more active and then then we should have
a good set of milestones that we can put
together with our Charter text and go to
the iesg and say please let us continue
as one of the longest-running working
groups in the Haight yet it shouldn't be
too much problem all right so with that
we've got a plan to continue with our
reach are during activities will will
let Warren know about that as soon as we
can and then I think we've now reached
the any other business topic so if you
have questions in general ideas about
benchmarking now's the time to come to
the microphone and talk about it okay
looks like a pretty satisfied group all
right folks
well thank you all for your attendance
and your participation in particular
those who did I think that we were very
glad to have that here today and there
will be even more of us and in future
meetings I can guarantee you that where
we've really started to work out our
details for new things in particular
we'd like to thank Sean Wu who
participated at a very early hour in in
the east coast of North America Thank
You Sean thank you folks and joy
yeah it worked it worked very well and
we're very thankful to meet Eko for that
so thank you
meet Eko guys and and so there we there
we are I think we're done folks so thank
you again and we'll see you in most
likely in a virtual meeting interim
meeting but also for sure in London
thanks again