check-check
there we go all right well welcome to
see Bohr um anybody who is going to
participate you might want to come a
little bit closer to the front so you
don't have to trot up to the microphone
can you hear me through the mic alright
um so I'm Joe Hildebrand and this is
Francesca Palin beany and so here's the
coordinates to participate do we have
any remote participants on jabber
Christian okay all right um if your
remote and you can hear me and you need
something related to the microphone
we've got somebody who will do that for
you prefix your your jabber with em IC :
and he will relay it for you
that'll be Dave Dale are doing that the
etherpad is on here I think that now
this URL should work great all right
please note well hopefully you have seen
this more than once already this week
but they're participating here you have
certain IPR and other requirements too
so bye-bye please read this and
understand it and make sure that you're
following
agenda so this introduction bit we'll
talk about cuddle for a while for about
a half an hour
we'll talk about the status of the
Seaboard draft and then we've got the
oid draft and a techhdarre draft to talk
through and then there's one that I
haven't read and should called time tags
and then we'll wrap up anything else
that people want to put on this list
anything that people think we ought not
talk about great I'm gonna take that as
good then all right so do you want to
talk about status jam you keep talking
just a quick status update since Prague
so CDL was updated after Prague and
Caston and Hank are gonna present some
issues that they would like the working
group to decide on then about the
Seaboard it was recently updated and to
check that you can also check the github
because that's where the latest version
is there is still the implementation
matrix to fill I I have pink the main
list the only one feeling in was Jo so I
think Karsten is gonna is gonna talk
about that a little bit but please come
forward if you have implementations and
please go to the to the wiki and and
filled it in so it's pretty bad if I'm
the only one who's actually done that
work because I haven't done a whole lot
else so there is JavaScript in my notes
Ybor that will generate the HTML output
if you want to use that as a starting
point so it didn't take me that long I
think it took me maybe an hour and a
half including getting all the
formatting
so there are some tests in there that
you can use as you know here are some
inputs and if you can process those
inputs then you're probably in good
shape now I don't implement all the
entire set of extensions and tags so
hopefully you know somebody else will
have implemented things that I haven't
okay about the tax documents so this is
so there are two two drafts and about
tags that are in the Charter and now
so the CDL and see bore our working
group documents right now and the tags
are not yet working group documents so
we need to talk about that and we need
to see what is what's the status for
those and here I just reported what you
can see the data tracker about when
where these documents last update and
then we would like to hear from the
authors about what they think they need
it's still needed to go for adoption and
and/or then working group last call so
for the OID tags there has been no
update since March so this document
probably needs feedback we have asked
for it and we even yeah the past couple
of meetings so talk about that and about
the array tags it was updated after
Prague still needs still need reviews I
was going through the minutes for the
past meetings and noticed noticed that
some people promised reviews last
meeting did not provide maybe forgot so
I'm just gonna remind it here Jim and
Paul promised reviews on this document
it's it's short
it shouldn't you shouldn't take you long
but yeah so we'll talk about this one
too I think that's it from us and I'm
going to start with CTL
[Music]
if I tip over you have to catch me
okay so um what's this no no it actually
works does anybody know how to run this
on you has something to do with it not
being switched on okay so if you can try
switching it out it worked after
switching it on in the car meeting so I
think it really just needs to research
on okay so just reminder of what this
group is about we are supposed to take
our c7 349 to standards level we are
supposed to standardize the standardized
CDL and do a few tag structure nuts so
that's what's currently the Charter and
I run through this in three parts the
first one is about CD DL so I'm not sure
Hank is here because he has a conflict
with net conf so I'm not sure you can
make this meeting and and christophe is
in raven unfortunately so just to remind
people what CDL is about and give a
little bit of a tutorial that is
probably needed to talk about the actual
issue that we should discuss today we
have been using BNF since RFC 40 so that
comes quite well together with being at
ITF 100 this has a
tradition and for about forty years we
have been using a BNF the Augmented BNF
that can hair enstein developed for the
mail every day I think so this is
something we have some experience with
and there are 750 to overseas that
reference the the a B and F standards
RFC so one could say this is a
successful our see it's even more
successful than yang which is currently
referenced by 160 ourseives
there is some tool support it hit the a
B and F form it hasn't taken the world
by storm but there is support we have
our own tools like Bill feni's a bap and
a B and F Gen but also will establish
pathogen rater towards like endler as
supported and it's just normal in the
IDF if you do a text-based protocol you
write in a BNF spec so this is our role
model here we want to be like a BNF and
actually that not only works on on a
high level but also on a technical level
a B&F is composed of productions so you
have something like an address
specification and that is a local part
followed by an ad side @ sign followed
by a domain so what these a B and F
routes do they give names for
sublanguage 'as and then you have two
kinds of composition you can compose by
concatenation like like this does here
from catenate in a local party net sign
in a domain all you can compose by
choice and this nesting structure then
at some point terminates at literals
like the add sign here or we add a B and
F notations for literal so this just
means all ASCII characters between 33
decimal
and 90 Jason okay so this production
based way of constructing languages of
course has been with us in computer
science since the late 50s when John
Becker's invented it for for Fortran and
what we need to do to use the same
technology for Jason and see where our
data structures is to apply it to trees
- trees of data and not to text strings
so given that the data that we are using
are integers text strings binary strings
floating-point and so on we have to add
literals for those primitive types we
not only have text strings we have these
other things as well and we have
conveyed constructors for the to
container types we have in JSON and C
were the V arrays and maps and the whole
thing is inspired by relax ng which was
the the schema language for exam is done
right you probably know another one and
yeah I'm not going to comment on that
one but relax and G has done some some
interesting work here too so in CDL
rural names are types you can write
something like boolean is either a false
or true and then you have a boolean type
followed by the way is also a type which
has just one number the value falls you
could have something like label which is
either a text or an integer this would
be an application specific type or an
integer is actually either an unsigned
integer or a negative integer in C bar
so types are just sets of potential
values and literal is just a very small
type so this little one here is a type
with the one member in it which is the
number one and then there are there are
other ways of writing these types for
instance one two
actually means a type that contains the
numbers one two and three so that's one
part the other part that feels a bit
more like an ABN F grammar is the groups
the groups allow you to write down
sequences of items and these sequences
of items can then be used within arrays
or within maps so the interesting thing
about the group construct is that there
is a single construct for both defining
maps and arrays and of course maps and
arrays are very different maps have a
label the label is ignored when you use
the group within an array and on the
other hand arrays have a sequence which
is ignored within maps so groups are
grammars for key value pairs and keys
and values are types so this is where
the circle closes you compose groups of
types and you compose types if they
contain arrays or maps out of groups so
that's essentially the whole technology
behind CD DL and the result is that you
can write something like this this was
one of the first examples when we read
RFC 1771 we were annoyed that they had
to define a special stylized form of
English to define their JSON data type
which takes I don't know four or five
pages and so this is the technical
content of RFC 7:07 one on one slide so
what we have here is a name for a type
the type is reputation object we have
the map or JSON object braces and then
what's in here is a group which says you
can have the label application with a
value of text
and I'll show you you must have because
there's no question marks there and you
must have labeled reputations which has
an array of zero or more refuge ins in
it and the refuge one is this thing with
some mandatory parts and some optional
parts and a wild-card at the end that is
there to express the extensibility and
that's really the heart is the one thing
we have to talk about so yeah these
groups get names like types get names so
when you look at it CDA documents
superficially you may not always be
aware which name is a group and which
name is a type but generally that that
becomes clear from the context so just
to give an example of why we want to
finish this now there is this draft in
the RFC editor queue which is called
draft IETF enema grasped 15 dot text and
that draft is done and it's just waiting
for for CDH to get published so we we
already have specs out there that have
references to CDL some informative
because they just repeat the
specification and some normative like
the grasp specification and we want to
make sure that we don't destroy this
specification by a changing CDL in in a
major way and there are a few more the
FC SDI was outside the IGF which cannot
be named in this room but you can guess
three letter and longer acronym who that
might be
so yeah we don't want to break it and we
don't want to put in the kitchen thing
but currently is one of the two focuses
is getting the definition of the
semantics of the language unambiguous so
tool vendors come in and say yes we can
implement that
and one new thing which isn't in the
internet draft yet it's in the topic
branch in the github is appendix B that
is called matching and it summarizes the
matching words that are used by CD types
and groups in a short way it essentially
just goes through the ABN F of course CD
DL as if it's a texture language as
defined in a B and F and it goes through
that a B and F and for every CD I
construct that exists it concisely
summarizes the CDR it semantics and what
we need to find out is whether that new
appendix is useful whether it is correct
and whether it is complete so that's
something where where it would be really
useful to get reuse on so if people
think it's useful and I think the
mailing list has had pretty much a
consensus that it is useful we would put
this into the next version of the draft
so that's one area of work the other
area of work is actually making
technical changes and so far the
appetite for that has been limited so
they have been few people who said I
have said we would like to change this
and Dad except for one area and the
problem comes in when you add a wildcard
to some existing map definition that's
why it was discussed under the heading
map validation but it's actually a more
general issue so since this is a
productive language based on the same
concepts as a B and F these two parts of
the group are taken separately they are
not interpreted together they are just
interpreted as they are and the language
is then constructed by taking these two
two parts together like like in a
because now nonfarm you you know so this
has we might have an entry in the map
with a key of four and a value of type
text and we might have any kind of entry
that has an unsigned integer as the key
and any data type because we don't know
yet how we will extend things as a value
so that's generally fine however really
what what like one what one would like
to explain here to express here is that
the fall is taken so we don't really
want that other guy here to say oh by
the way you also can have a key of four
and any value because the the falls
already taken with us now a grammar
mathematician will tell you oh you are
making the grammar context-sensitive and
that's exactly the reason why we haven't
done this yet context-free grammars have
advantages of a context-sensitive
grammars but the discussion on the
mailing list was this is really a
feature we would like to have it would
really be useful if we get an instance
that has a key of four and a value of
floating point would really be good to
have a validator throw an error for that
instead of just accepting it because
it's captured by the wild card now how
do we fix this there is one possible
answer and this is a slide I have used
last time in the list of kitchen things
saying things we might want to add which
is cuts cuts is something that is it was
initially defined by the Prolog
programming language and recently has
become an item of interest for people
who do pause expression grammar pauses
so BNF started out just as a language
for defining things then the theory
was built around that and two theories
emerged one was way too complicated way
too expensive to implement the past
expression grammars so the theory veered
off into LR and pauses and so on but in
the meantime people have started to do a
pause expression grammars again and the
example here is we have a data type a
which is either an ant or a cat or an
egg and the ant is an array with the
first element being ant and the second
being an unsigned integer cat text egg
float no the yes yes
oh yeah this should said okay that were
true then this would be right so sorry
about that
so the reason why we started talking
about cuts in the office team was that
we wanted to have better error messages
because right now when you put this into
the CDL tree it doesn't really have a
good way to tell you what went wrong
it just says this is not an a it is not
going to tell you oh you said and and
after an end you really should have put
an unsigned integer and this is what
these cuts are doing they essentially
committing to a choice that has been
made they are cutting down the rest of
the search tree by saying oh if you
actually saw the word and then really
all the other rules that are in this
choice don't matter because this is the
one you should be choosing so that means
if you get anything but a you ain't
after the end you know this is wrong and
you can say there should be a you end
there so that was the the reason we
wanted to do cuts and that was a good
reason but maybe not good enough for for
putting it in now the interesting thing
is we can use the same construct
to handle the met validation issue by
essentially inserting cuts between the
keys and the values of an item in a
group so this would mean if you match
the number four and you can ignore all
the other alternatives for matching this
particular video pier in the map you are
done and the only value that is allowed
here is X so that's the this button okay
thank you so this is of course a little
bit noisy so this would come with a
proposal to make the existing : shortcut
include that cut so when you say for :
text this means you really mean the for
is taken by this particular production
about this particular part of it so
that's the proposal now this needs to be
fully defined those people who know
about the theory know that when you do a
cut to reach up the tree and you
actually find how far you reach up it
may seem obvious here but in more
complicated examples it has to be fully
defined that's one thing the second
thing we want to do is checking for
breakage that this change makes and the
third thing of course you want to do is
implement it to make sure it works so
this is probably month of work that is
needed to make this happen
can L demand from the floor uh do you
have other proposals or is this the is
this the only one you've got
I don't want to start I da ting if
you've got other things you want to also
suggest instead no this is really the
main part of this segment so I mean if
what you're really trying to do is get
the extensibility bit and you're having
a sort of retrofit this in just for
extensibility like I get the the
the aunt example you've got there but
like do you want the aunt example enough
to make extensibility it seems
relatively complicated from a
theoretical perspective compared to like
the cognitive load associated with this
is relatively high compared to the rest
of the document yeah because we're
leaving the context-free part and
entries I mean but there are other
things you could do to get extensibility
if you just wanted extensibility so for
example at the end of the the end curly
bracket you could put something else at
the end that says by the way this is
extensible in some way like in for
example you could you could have in
parens after it some sort of type
statement that says what you how you're
allowed to extend okay hi Sean Leonard
so uh a couple of proposal I want to
bring but I want to first address this
pretty clearly so I think it's valuable
as discussed on the mailing list to have
some way to either cut or constrain the
type Carson and I actually worked on a
related problem with this in the context
of a B and F and I would like to propose
that we consider an alternative way to
get the same results namely allowing the
broader definition right the mapping
from the broad type to to anything but
then also have this subtype that's more
constrained right so one way to do it is
cuts and that's already been presented
another way to do it would be to have a
constraint notation so that you have you
int maps any write in the map but then
as a subclass or as a constraint of that
it's possible to define specific
instances of the U nth such as for and
then the matching type on essentially
the right hand side and the difference
is that with
a cut as I understand it it's it's a way
to essentially to produce better error
messages right because you you take that
point of the parser of the tree you
output the error message and then you
backup right essentially so then it
doesn't match however another way to
look at it is that the data production
still does match the broader type you
went to any okay but it just doesn't
match the subtype so then a parser on
the fly or during production will know
that it matched the broader type but not
the subtype and then the application can
treat that as either an error or as
something that's potentially recoverable
where the consumer can then just realize
okay we have the broad match but not the
subtype that we were looking for
therefore the data item is in is
deficient basically and get the same
result so do you know that would be
there is another control operator that
is in CD DL now called within or and so
it would behave in a similar way I guess
I can propose another way to look at
this I have a draft in the a B and F
context which is a draft chantek
constrained a B and F which ironically
uses the Hat so it's very similar
notation but the notation would be
something akin to you int map to any and
then hat and then your list of specific
matches such as for : text 3 : whatever
and so forth that could be one we do and
while still keeping it a context-free
grammar that's that's also that you
would wrote the the controller first
yeah you you would write the catch-all
first and then you write the specific
instances that also match the catch-all
so you're constraining the generic
production to these specific instances
of interest and if it doesn't match the
specific instances of interest then
that's a condition that then of course a
program can can process or deal with
that it match the general thing but not
the specific thing so it's in the
catch-all
it would be interesting to see a
proposal right now my cognitive load
gets up because I suddenly have
something in CBD area where the thing
that comes later has a higher priority
than the thing that comes earlier
everything else in CBL is the other way
round but yeah that could be done okay
good so maybe we should work on that
then as we look at alternatives to this
because I do see that there is a use you
know that's broadly applicable to a
variety of users the problem is that
that this type here without the Hat is
not matching so if you subtract this
type from that type then then four
column float is still in my the
parameters right to process this type
and remove the video information and
just keep the key information before you
can construct the the remainder type
that you are subtracting from from the
katralla type right I don't know how to
do that right that makes sense although
if the remainder type also matches all
of the other specific types you can
first match the remainder type which
presumably would also be relatively
cheap relative relative to going through
the list of specific matches and then
going to the specific match the cup is
essentially a way to construct that
remainder type right so we would need it
in that case as well so we can be
willing to write this in a pool request
or something in the github I can yeah I
can try at least that yeah and actually
I want to take this to remind people to
participate in the mailing list because
we've seen very little participation and
the working group seems interested and
active but in the face-to-face but then
I would like to see more discussion in
the main unless then I cannot keep like
for like trying to get people to talk
you need to him so I have I have other
proposals but before I get to those
proposals I'll step to the back
Jim shot the first problem I have with
this is you all sudden became extremely
order dependent which means no bill
radula hi we already are this is a
puzzle expression Grima it does not
matter in the current grammar if I do
the star first or the four first that
that there those would be equivalent in
the grammar this is not true anymore and
even worse than this is you now have the
question of if you have group one which
ends in the star int you int points to
any and then you say and now append
group two to it all of the cuts in group
two won't ever be seen because you'll
hit the star you end yes we cut bit and
that's because of the order dependence a
look so that's the first problem I have
with with all of this
the second problem I have is I don't
understand why this needs to be
expressed in the grammar and cannot be
expressed in semantics this is commonly
done today
for example if you have an email headers
I can't remember for sure but I believe
that they leave part of the grammar says
you can't have two of these that's not
in the grammar that's in the semantics
so I don't see why this can't just be
expressed in semantics rather than the
grammar but actually the the you can't
have two of these semantics of maps also
is expressed in English and not in the
Rima but I'm not and don't know how to
do this I mean if somebody would come up
with a reasonable proposal that actually
works that would be great I think an
edit of this document um first of all if
there are good proposals and it's
basically what you just said so busy
took some of the words
my mouth that can express this as a
control to this type definition very
interested to see your proposals for
that and then coming back to Joe's
comment this is why it looks like this
is about extensibility it isn't it is
about the fact that sometimes we have
the problem that there are more very
defined keys and less defined keys and
maps if it would be about extensibility
we would use the extension points there
are extension points to our choices
there we could use extension points here
we could use as we could you'll end with
an extension point just as you proposed
it is already in CDL but that is not
what this is about this is about effect
that we have sometimes layers that are
less specified than others and those
would be basically gobble up all the
voyage identified Labor's so if this can
be soft Bob via a control and we were
already considering that actually we're
really happy to have a proposal for that
and compare it but after a really long
time of discussions we basically ended
up with making the : they explode
something to you if yeah it sure can you
solve through the control yeah that's
easy yeah hard part is solving it with
the control in such a way that you don't
have to write everything twice yes yes
exactly
so that is that is why we did this
redundant one of the design principle is
less noisy and this is way less noisy
because it's basically looking like
before it just has some added semantics
Jim - okay great sean leonard all right
um I did want to draw the working groups
attention to a couple of other proposals
that have come up with regard to see DDL
and and the grammar specifically the
proposal that I wanted to make or
discuss had to do with regular
expressions so I did bring up on the
list a few months ago the issue that
regular
currently are defined as pcre which is
great because I think pcre is a great
regular expression implementation and
everything else but there isn't a
normative reference in CDL or in
seaboard to that and I think that that
is something that should be addressed in
both documents because both of them do
in fact reference regular expressions
then because of the power that regular
expressions have to identify and
constrain the different data productions
I feel strongly that regular expression
should be first-class syntactic elements
inside of CDL so for example just as you
can do in Perl or in JavaScript the way
you write a regular expression is you do
slash and then the regular session
content and then slash and then usually
if you have a editor that its language
aware it'll color the regular expression
and show you interesting stuff about it
and and so forth so technology is all
there right now though it's defined in a
string and the problem is that when it's
in a string there's a ton of escaping
right of back slashing that you have to
do to make that work so I wanted to
bring that up to make regular
expressions a first-class syntactic
element another advantage of doing it
that way is that then you can add the
flags or the modifiers such as I and X
and so forth on the end of it
yeah because otherwise you essentially
have to construct two strings and then
put them together and then it's it just
doesn't look it it doesn't look good and
that that alone the conciseness will
will help I think a lot with readability
and it'll help identify and catch errors
and such so yeah so that's sort of on
the table Joe Hildebrand from the floor
I like the idea of slashes as a
syntactic element and promoting regular
expressions first class if we think
they're going to be used enough to
warrant that it's a it's a nice
affordance
carpenter user of cedar Dale I think
these are all great ideas Percy DDL
version 2 I would like see detail
version 1 as a normative reference next
week please so I wonder if you could
think about taking that approach yes I
did and then I found this I sympathize
with you wanting to do this but I also
then but you're a co-author on the draft
that's waiting for it right so you see
the point I mean if you can if you can
think about doing this as a version 2
effort that I think that would actually
be probably better for seeded Yale
because it gives it a place in the world
and you can then work on improvements so
the question first it was this point to
the this the carsten were custom
presented proposal and what then was
this a comment to Sean well both of them
really I mean I don't see any of these
of not being backwards compatible with
existing CDLs so it wouldn't invalidate
existing CDL files it would be additions
so as long as it's strictly backwards
compatible I you know I think you
conversion it
any day you want you can say today is
the day we version it and and then put
the next lot round of things in version
2 so it's really a choice when you do
that ok Sean Leonard related to the -
all the things that were just mentioned
is a concern I have with the control
syntax or control operators and how I
think they could be made better both by
the regular expression syntax and
address I think some of these kind of CD
DL v-0 v1 issues so I clearly see the
value of having the control operators
that are currently defined in the draft
right for example the bits the bits is
it it is control operators write bits
regular expression and then size and a
few other things but in some ways
they're too extensive and they're not
powerful enough at base however I've
read a number of CDL specs in drafts and
RFC's or whatever that have floated
around I'm not aware of standards or
specifications out there yet that are
relying on them normatively we're
removing them or taking them out and
tweaking them is going to cause real
interoperability problems one point
about the control operators I want to
point out is the size control operator
so right now with size you can define it
as a single size or you can define a
range I believe right so it can be like
three to 63 bytes in length or whatever
it is so that's fine but I have use
cases where I want to be able to
constrain the size of a string or a byte
string to basically mod to like only
even numbers or only powers of two or
whatever okay just because that's those
are the increments of the data items I
can do well interestingly if I use a
regular expression constraint I can
actually do that very powerfully by just
saying regular expression has multiples
of two right a group of two characters
or bytes and then plus essentially or
multiples of two I can't do that with
size and I think as a result if we adopt
regular expressions in their more
powerful form right with the slash
notation and whatnot we can actually
find that there will be control
operators that may be superfluous so we
don't need them at all and we might want
to you know make all these control
operators simplified and just say just
use regular expressions and here's like
a handful of very powerful ones that
you're going to commonly use for these
sorts of patterns um so with that said
that's kind of another proposal on the
table not to remove the control
operators but to recognize that there
are perhaps more powerful simpler ways
of annotating the same thing and if
people really really want a v-0 or a v1
of CD DL we can consider you know
dealing with the control operator issue
after the publication of that so let me
answer that because it's really
confusing right now ring exposed rings
okay so yeah so I wanted to point out as
well reg axes are for sequences of code
units so you can just have a binary
regular expression that operates on a
tetes from 0 to 255 as opposed to
regular expressions that operate on
Unicode code points from 0 to 10 ffff
yes right no ringer for Strings right my
view actually is that reg X's could be
applied to both byte strings and text
strings and that and that they you know
they just have a different domain in the
case of oxides it's zero to achieve this
and what we have tried to do is not turn
CDL Interpol
so reg X is are there for the few cases
where they actually add something but
they are traditionally not a way in
which we specify the strings in the IDF
now one way to solve this problem would
have been to add a B and F to a CDL and
maybe in C Drive version 2 we will do
that but I think reg X therefore for a
narrow domain and they should stay that
way and I don't know how to do a grandma
that does this such thing so I have to
pass on that okay I guess I would just
say that regular expressions are a part
of C DDL and they're a part of C bore
too because they're in you know RC 70 49
so and a lot of people do in fact use
them so although it's true the ietf has
not defined them that way I'd first
question do you really need I maybe I
should ask the group or you know
whatever have people been using the
control operators to constrain their
specifications
important critical way where it's like
actually normative and have they used
regular expressions in that way as well
because regular sessions do in fact
appear with some frequency in other
specifications users Jim or no too hard
he says um this is Hank as a user and
yes I have used controls from the
working group so I think Shawn had
raised this before in the mailing list
but please take it up again and we will
and users please respond to this email
okay then why why I stepped up to the
mic the first place was that I had a
difficult time to parse the statement
powerful and simple
so my question really is you don't want
to do this now take take this leg out of
vacation and they fix it to the head
even is this useful do people think this
is useful then the next question is the
proposal that Shawn just made about
record then and then we can talk about
is this something to do right now how
long would this take and if this should
be something for next version or not
right so in response to simple and
powerful how can that work right well
there's always a holy grail of computer
science you say something simple and
powerful and then it turns out to be one
or the other or whatever and the answer
is regular expressions are simple when
they're simple and they're powerful when
they're powerful right but they are a
part up to now of CDL and C bore right
the existence of C DDL in its current
draft
form assumes that AC DDL generator or a
parser or validator of some kind that
can form suspect will do something with
the regular expression right so that
basically assumes that pcre is lying
around does that make sense so assuming
that you have this piece of machinery
that's part of C bore because it's in
the the specs right then that's what you
got so you may as well make the most use
of it does that make does that make
sense yeah and one question that I don't
have on the slides that maybe Aleksic
and can answer so PCR II is not defined
in a normative document that we can use
it also is the right spec to reference
here as shown probably correctly as
identified so I'm not sure whether I
want to be a guinea pig for the new
let's reference over source projects
policy of the is G but this is where it
actually would should I need to check
I vaguely remember there was one of the
save documents that has regex extension
so I can find out what it used there so
if you were willing to take a slightly
less powerful version you could
reference one of the ACMA Docs and use
Java the JavaScript version they are
adding look behind and so you could for
example take that that there's some
rather weird Unicode stuff going on with
those so if we can avoid reference that
I'm just saying that they are a there's
there's there are standards Docs to
point you there which is better then not
having something to reference let me try
to find the document and and then we can
have a look whether it's a good example
or you know at least it's an example
yeah and finally my concern with having
accepted the let's assume we exchange
controls in general the powerful and
simple reg X we are talking about a
domain where if we are ever going to do
message validation actually that's
that's kind of kind of true a bunch of
an overhead maybe and that domain so um
I would be very careful about the pole
for stuff and that domain yeah so the
way forward if Alexei finds out we
cannot do this records currently linked
into the document using an extension
point and we can just throw out vague
excerpts out of this current document
finish it and write a second document
that has the regs reference in it and
let that sit in the internet drafts
directory until we find out how to do it
all right we should move on other things
okay yeah i okay that that sounds good I
would just say as I pointed out not just
reg X but all of control operators if
not because they're not useful but
because maybe we don't need them right
now there is no control operator that
it's not used by at least one it's you
know I know you want to stop this but
I'm confused by something it ultimately
the validator I want to be in my
embedded device oh sorry Dave Robin
maker of embedded devices I want to get
a c-more message in I want to be able to
validate it based on some compiler that
looked at the CDL and told my device how
to validate it now if you can say
everything can be replaced by one
gigantic reg X expression then I'm going
to give it to a human to figure out how
to actually write the code to do that
validation because I don't have a reg X
interpreter in the embedded environment
so let's not go overboard and say we
don't need CDD Allah just one big reg X
expression so the the the opt the
constraints are easily turned into
embedded rules don't go crazy with
things that can
per set those constraints those
constraints can be easily turned into
embedded rules next so the CBO
specification itself as you know our job
is to take this to standards level and
there are several things we need to do
and there is a process you find in RFC
64 10 for doing that so those are you
who are not familiar with that process
please have a look yeah we have some 45
implementations so it should not be too
hard to point out to independent
implementations whether they are
interoperable that that's what we need
to find out is as Joyce said we have
fixed the errata while looking at
interval T we can look at whether we
have unused features and as far as I
know we don't have any patent claims
that are known so far so the status of
the document is that they're zero zero
had already fixed the errata and - l1
has reacted to a few comments that have
been made by implementers one is that
the the way the simple types like false
true null and so on
I encoded is said again in another place
so it's harder to miss the way they are
defined we added a changes section maybe
in the next version we will separate
editorial changes fixes and a new
information from each other and the only
real new material is the new section
about SIBO data months and there we
shall quickly talk about that so those
people who have worked with Jason and we
like it however it's not always clear
what the data model actually is that is
being derived from a JSON instance
and if you really paid attention you
could infer the SIBO data model from our
c7 t49 but maybe it's better to actually
make this very explicit so there is a
proposal for a new section 2.5 which is
called generic data model generic
because it's not about a specific data
model a specific application might be
using but it's about the complete set of
instances that can be realized in recibo
and that generic data model comes in two
parts one is the unexpended basic data
model and the other half is the
extension points of course given that
the extension points are therefore
extending zero that data model is not
closed people can come in and define new
parts of that data model but this simple
document already comes with 18
predefined tags and for simple items
falls through now undefined and of
course there are now a couple of dozen
tags defined in an Ayanna registry so
this is probably a useful thing because
the generic data model makes it more
explicit what we actually expect from an
implementer of generic encoders and
decoders because an encoder decoder
translates between the data model and
the serialization and it's not enough to
just specify the serialization if you
expect generic encoders and decoders to
interoperate and an ecosystem of such
generic and coastal decoders makes
interrogatory so much more likely and
also guides the definition of specific
data models because you won't define
data models in such a way that generic
encoders and decoders have problems with
that so this is one edition which could
be called editorial except there there's
also a little bit of text
in there that clarifies some
expectations and the batteries included
aspect of our FC 1749 is not not
appropriate if you need to ship C bar by
ma so sometimes you have to leave out
the batteries and the question is which
batteries do we really want to have
India which of the pre extensions by the
document are really basic and section
two five now clarifies that the three
simple data items false true null do
come in through an extension point but
they are really not an extension they
are part of what is expected to be
provided in a generic encoder and
decoder that still doesn't mean that a
data model that you define using SIBO
has to use them but it means if you
write a generic encoder decoder please
include false true or not and everything
else is truly optional and a matter of
implementation quality so that's a
statement and that's probably a state
where we want to be very clear about in
this working or whether that's what we
expect from generically coders so again
this is a relevant vent for
interoperability because this ecosystem
of generic encoders and decoders helps
gain gaining interoperability but it's
not a 2119 type of must or must not it's
just an expectation and we historically
have had a little bit of a problem in in
the IDF managing these expectations so
it's a little bit of an unusual way of
specifying yes okay
so if you have any comment on that
that would be something that that would
be really useful on the mailing list or
on the microphone but I don't get maybe
it's just a type of Sean Leonard in your
slide it says anything else including
undefined is truly optional but in draft
oh one which is posted undefined is
actually in the third category of it has
to be supported yeah at least that's
what I just chant fix that but so which
one are you proposing because it seems
that posing false true and no just these
three as core elements and everything
including undefined as option okay I
think I think undefined is is useful to
in the prior category that's just my two
cents for I guess there's a difference
between null and undefined especially
when undefined is used for items that
didn't decode properly or whatever you
know it is where as null is like
explicit no I probably have a
recommended set I would give to an
implementer that includes a couple of
those tags and and undefined and a few
more things that they should be doing
but this is trying to say we really
expect people to do the jason-3 false
true and so if people don't other people
in the room have comments right now
otherwise we can move this to the main
list and hopefully get feedback there
okay the the other thing that came up as
you know we have a few implementations
out there last time I looked at it was
45 it's changing every week now and we
haven't got a lot of feedback about
interoperability problems but we do have
one and that is really not a problem in
SIBO it's a problem in the world
we are bridging two which is the base64
world that has had a little bit of an
evolution since base64 was first defined
for mine and we probably haven't been
tracking that evolution very well so we
have four tags defined that have
something to do with basics default two
of them alpha basically for us which is
what you would use today and two of them
are for base64 classic and there is no
known problem with the basics before URL
once but with basic C for classic it's a
little bit more fuzzy and right now we
are very clear in the definition of K 21
that basically for URL is being used
without padding we are not saying that
explicitly for tag 33 so that may be a
problem but then RFC 4646 about that the
basic C for classic tags 22 and 34 they
reference 46 48 but 46 48 only has
essentially decision criteria if you are
using base 64 those are the reasons why
you would might want to use heading and
those are the reasons why you might not
want to use it yeah so what we have to
decide first do we really mean tag 33 to
also be limited to basics before you are
without padding and I'm pretty sure that
we do want to do that but we merge short
make a conscious decision and on the the
base 64 classic side we have to do a few
no-brainers like saying we don't really
expect whitespace in there or we don't
expect line length limitations which
some basics before implementations have
but it's probably not sufficient to just
say anything goes in particular tag 21
and 22
intended to be acted upon by a civil to
jason converter which might be generic
so it has no idea what the application
requirements on that base 64 are so we
have to tell this generic converter what
kind of basics before it's supposed to
generate so the problem is really urgent
for the tag 22 because people cannot
implement this right now without the
knowledge they have to pick a choice and
you shouldn't they implemented big
something and the second thing is yeah
tag 33 and 34 just say Jesus here is a
text string and by the way the semantics
of the text string is a 64 a 64 URL or
basics before classic now this could be
interpreted in a more permissive way
because the tank just provides
information and we could be happy with
that information being it's some kind of
basics to follow we are not going to
tell you which one but then it also is a
little bit harder to do a conversion
conversion through JSON where the JSON
data model on the other side might have
more strict requirements on the base64
so these are two different but
interrelated sets of problems and this
of course should be guided by how a 64
classic and URL are being used in
practice
now basics before URL is almost always
used without heading and remember having
seen once a version with padding but I'm
not even sure that that was standards
compliant so into ability might benefit
from really nailing this one down and on
the basics default side it's pretty much
a bike shed so it's not really possible
to decide this well yeah so we could be
more explicit about tag 33 we could be
fine tag 22 and 34 as with or without
we could also go ahead and define
additional tags base64 classic with
Betty without padding with up to 70
characters per line
probably not and oh by the way there's
also a question that that occasionally
comes out about base-16 so you can write
hex strings in uppercase and lowercase
but that's the side track right now so
my proposal would be to actually read 46
48 which tells us heading was designed
to help with situations in which the
decoder isn't quite sure about what the
length is in C bar we always know the
length so it's really the no padding
case from 46 48 that we have here now
again the J's inside of a potential
automatic conversion might have other
constraints so maybe the JSON side then
next converts into a mind message or
something like that
so this is not not a perfect argument
but it's an argument that might be used
to sort of that bike shed so my proposal
would be to go for no padding with basic
C for classic - but add some language
documentation note that this was only
edit this clarification was only added
now and asking implementers to be
particularly liberal
about what they accept with this room
cares about may 64 Sean Leonard so I
think the core issue here is that you
want different implementations to emit
the same basic the same sequence of
characters right for base64 whether its
upper case lower case padding or
whatever right so first of all our
question is why I mean is there at light
and when I say why I mean is there like
a canonicalization issue where you
really need it that way because
otherwise some digital signature or hash
is not going to compute
a or something like that or what is it
and then the second is there is I'm not
saying we should do this but another
possibility is that you consider all the
different permutations and you just
register lots of hi tag numbers for all
them so I think that that's not a good
idea but that is a way to like deal with
it and we just pick something
arbitrarily for the current ones that we
believe is gonna be the most common take
Taylor
so I'm partly appeared to respond to
Joe's question does anybody care about
base64 in the so ocf is one of the
organizations that has dependencies on
Seaborg right and I just wanted to
report that that ocf you to express
schemas right they use both rommel and
json schema and now moving towards
swagger and both json schema and swagger
have the property of defining a type for
base64 and not defining a type 4 base64
URL and so that means that they use
base64 URL not because they want to even
though they're using super on the wire
but because of other external
dependencies they're using base64 so
yeah and so the implementation they're
using is tiny sea bore and I don't know
what that does but offhand I'm guessing
your proposal would be fine I have to
check with the tiny sea bore author but
yep ocf would care and offhand I'm
guessing your proposal would be fine but
I will have to check that's a very sad
thing that you just reported but the
tiny sea bore offer really laments the
fact that he can't use the base64 URL
buts in the tiny zebra implementation
for ocf because there's no reason other
than the specification language having
to use previously json schema and now
swagger and if we could get both of
those or should say either of those fix
the tiny co-author would be very elated
so Matthew Miller um so for me
the time it's it's base64 URL and not
base64 where it is basics t4 it's
because of trying to interoperate with
existing tools which will spit out
whatever they spit out but the parsing
of that usually they're accepting of
things is usually pretty permissive in
the first place so I think I don't so I
think it's worth moving in that
direction for the the 30x set of tags
just let it let it be pretty flexible
there we're but on the other side just
remove all the white space and the
safest I've seen for that is also make
sure to keep the padding for base64
versus base64 URL it's almost never
padding but what's it's okay to be
permissive on what what we take but on
what you're going to generate just set
some really strong limits this is one
vote for permissive on the the 34 and
defining the 22 Joe Hildebrand so I'm at
all I'm gonna argue for the complete
other side which is to remove all four
of these tags from sea bore because I'd
find them useless you should just use
byte strings so that ship having sailed
I frankly don't care what goes into
these because I think they're useless
yeah sounds good to me
they are register take so they are not
going away but we could take them away
from the standard okay so that's Kirsten
can you start to thread on this one
remaining list and people also those who
have talked here please respond to the
thread and we'll take a quick decision
because it seems like this is just
something that needs to be decided on
and it's not really controversial so Joe
already mentioned that we have to do
work on the implementation matrix
exactly to put a link on your code on
the slide so maybe you can send it again
to the mailing list so right now again
Joe has done his homework
and yeah is anyone in this room who can
do their homework on this Jim can do
that Carsten no sir a season so which
implementation would you do that
homework for okay Peter's Peter however
you yes okay so that that said please do
so I poked myself and let's do we then
we have four so that that's already a
good thing but if we have more that so
just for the record they said that you
could do for tiny people thank you okay
that's all I had on the syllabus
document now the the last set of items
on the agenda is C bar tags very civil
tag documents and again our c70 49
pretty finds 18 tags maybe it's 14 when
we're done today there's stuff in there
but the point is it's it's easy to
register your own sea boat eggs that may
even be too easy at the moment and there
are more than twenty more tags
some of them defined by the IGF for
instance they're cozy and CWT tags but
people have come in and done tags for
Perl support for Haskell support I'm
going to talk about that in a minute
tagged language tag string which is
really an important addition compression
and so on so just as one example what's
going to be completed very soon is the
see what we're talking which is
essentially the the JSON web token
translated to see ball that packages a
claim set into JSON and then you can
apply a Cosi security to that
in various forms so here we have tag 61
assigned already we didn't even have to
do an earlier location for that because
the the registration policy right now is
very liberal and the working last call
for the CEO we're talking completed in
the IGF iceburg group and we'll go into
ITF last card so that's an example for a
tag document that we are doing because
we have a standard that that actually
uses that we also have some other tags
draft that are not necessarily being
motivated by specific standards but are
being motivated by wanting to do a
specification work that references
certain types of data structures so one
of this is the OID draft and at some
point shown it I have to sit down and
see what we actually want to push
through here at the moment and what
maybe should go into a separate a
document but if you have feedback on
that document that would be useful but
I'm not going to talk about it today the
second one is the array tags draft which
has been out for a while and has been
pretty stable for a while that is still
waiting for a working group adoption I
will talk about that in a minute the
third one is the time tag which is off
charter and essentially is is completed
process wise because the IANA has
registered in an FCFS tag for it the
1001 but maybe we actually want to turn
this into an RFC and I'd like to
understand what this working group when
it has completed its current charter
wants to do with us that's the care or
not then we have the the template tag
but that's really something that that is
over in LP when and not year so maybe
this should be any other group of tanks
motivated by standardization activities
and then maybe at some point we may want
to do a useful tags document because
some of those registered
eggs are actually very useful and it
would be good to collect their
specifications into an RFC so people
have an easier way of referencing those
and we don't have down refs for document
that use that and that useful check
document actually could swallow the time
tag as well if we consider that useful
so that's one way of handling this is
about that okay then let's go into the
array tag that is currently in version o
six but they haven't been many technical
changes there have been small editorial
adjustments in the last draft and this
is inspired by JavaScript it defines 24
contiguous tags in the two byte space
and also defines two more tags for other
homogeneous arrays which is useful in a
decoder if you know ahead of time this
array of 4,000 elements you are finding
is actually homogeneous so you can map
it to a whatever genius you have in your
language and a tag for multi-dimensional
array so when you get the the elements
enumerated you know how many columns and
how many rows there are
so I think these are pretty
non-controversial but for those of
course eating up 24 tags is is maybe a
lot and eating them out of the two white
space is maybe even more a lot
we have 232 there are about 20 taken at
this point in time but I mean this is
about the size of the IP protocol number
space so we want to be a little bit
careful about that and we have have had
arguments on both sides one is it would
be a waste of space because arrays can
be large and large arrays obviously are
fine with a three by check and the other
argument is no arrays can also be small
and one of the more
likely usages of this tank is for an RGB
value which is three bytes and yeah then
you'll need attending a three by tagged
to a three byte value that that's maybe
not so bright what we could do is
partition those 24 tags into those that
are somehow big and those that somehow
not so big that's ugly I'd rather spend
those 24 tags at once but even more
importantly I would like to get this out
of the way for some reason they said
this has kept us from adopting this
draft which is weird because we usually
end up droughts before we have solved
all tanking issues with them so let's
get this all over the way Joe Hildebrand
from the floor we this pattern comes up
relatively frequently where somebody has
like one general concept that they want
to put into a tag and then a bunch of
different potential ways it might be
used and one of the ways of dealing with
that is you assign a large number of
these sorts of tags in order to make
that happen it is possible that we could
come up with a pattern for parameterize
tags effectively where you say here is a
tag for a to a to place array where the
first thing in the array is the
parameter and the second thing in the
array is the actual model that the
actual thing that the tag this human for
instance this is exactly that better
yeah exactly and so having that pattern
more so sort of in our pocket and with a
name that we call whatever this you know
parameterised tag for instance would
allow us to shorthand the discussion and
then so my next question here was well
could we do a parameterised tag for this
where we have one tag specified in which
case having one in the one bite range
even might be fine
and then you'd have another bite for the
array so total of two bytes to describe
the whole thing three and then three one
for the yes so a total of three bytes
for this I don't know if that's too many
bytes if that's or is it too complicated
etc I do agree that having these set of
JavaScript types expressible easily in C
world would be nice so okay Sean Leonard
so to continue off of Joe's point
actually the Seaboard tags OID draft
actually discusses that premise of
having stacked or parameterised tags
where you have a tag which is small and
then another identifier next to it which
could be another tag because you can't
in fact stack tags you know on top of
tag or an integer it's worth pointing
out that in C bore a tag is really just
an unsigned integer with major type six
I believe instead of major type zero
otherwise they're like literally the
same and the semantics of course are
that you can put one thing after it
which is the thing that's being also has
a correct correct yeah that's right
that's correct yeah that's the
difference with regard to this
particular thing I think the draft
should be adopted and I think all the
tag draft should be adopted we just get
it over with
I have I think in Prior meetings
Joe expressed let's put it in the three
byte space I basically think for this
block we should just put in three bytes
space and not use the two byte space but
the premise of allocating blocks of tags
to take it or exploit mathematical
properties like the fact that you know
these are interleaved is a good thing
especially because we are trying to
optimize for IOT you know types of
constrained devices where then this can
be part of a jump table effectively
right with one subtract and then
to wherever you need to go with regard
to the bike shed issue of you know three
buy tags to buy tonight if we have if we
literally have an RGB value that's three
bytes we just give it another tag for
heaven's sakes you know like if it's
gonna be an array of lots and lots of
RGB values because it is the contents of
a graphic buffer or whatever from one
computing device to another that's gonna
be a large array so the tags not gonna
contribute to it and if it's just one
just invent some RGB tag you can put
into one byte space so two bytes space
or just just call it a day you know or
or I will point out this is a good point
to point out you don't actually have to
tag anything at all if you're really
super space constrained on the wire or
whatever just don't tag it just have
some huge huge array of integers or
whatever that gets me to the issue of
when should we tag and some of the oid
draft which is admittedly a bit of a
kitchen sink does go into those
philosophical issues right when should
we tag it all the problem with things
prior to C bore like asn.1 which i'm
unfortunately intimately familiar with
is that there are all these options for
tagging you can make tagging explicit
you can make it implicit you can make it
automatic which nobody knows what does
just the parser does whatever right and
you can reassign tags from one universal
class to another so something that's
labeled and a universal integer maybe
it's not an integer maybe it's who knows
whatever the heck it is I think a real
advantage to see bore which is not
mandated by RFC 70 49 but comes out of
it is that we've got this really awesome
large tag space and one registry where
once you register it that's it
for all applications and so I'd like to
propose and volunteer to take some of
the work I've done on this and kind of
develop a philosophy of Seaboard tagging
internet draft that the working group
look at and adopt so we can all say yeah
you know this is how you should use tags
which mostly is use them explicitly
but if your application doesn't need
them just don't use tags at all and be
okay with that and with respect to
that's good because if we agree as a
whole if we're gonna use tags in a
specification it's always everything's
gonna be explicitly tagged necessary it
is it's gonna be great for debugging
right cuz you get a Wireshark trace or
whatever everything is tagged right and
they're not that big just couple of
bytes but you know exactly what it is
it's that weird RGB thing for Commodore
64 or whatever back in the 80s that's
what it is you know exactly what it is
no big deal it's a four byte tag out and
there's a billion other different tags
all right different numbers we're not
running out so that's my proposal Joe
Hildebrand from the floor again I think
that that would be a useful discussion
for us to have and having a draft to
start from i/o wherever Shawn went there
you are he's standing my blind spot now
I'm sitting my blind spot having a draft
to start that discussion I think would
be used so coming back to this like if
so again this is just me speaking as an
individual if you moved all this stuff
into the three bytes space just to get
us to the point where it's adopted and
then we could have a further discussion
that might be the most expedient way
okay to get past this so I don't know if
your from last meeting the point was
many people seven people around seven
people had read the draft and the thing
that was missing was reviews and we had
people volunteer but then no reviews so
we need to get these reviews so on the
philosophical question of whether you
want to have a cake with a parameter
space or use tags with the mathematical
property as an integer I agree was shown
that that's a good pattern to have we
have 18 trillion tags so we can do this
a lot before we run out
in the particular RGB example the tag is
actually useful because you would use
you and eight if you are in the
classical RGB space and you would use
binary sixteen if you're using high
dynamic range so you actually need the
tank to decide which of the two cases
you have good point or at that point
yeah you just you could have two tags at
that point yeah yes yes but why don't we
just provide those 24 for the
applications that beat this kind of
thing and be done with Mike oh he said
heap like one tag you can do
mathematical operations on like jump
tables computation yeah yeah this
computes on tanks but to be able to
compute on text you need several of them
so I like Joe's suggestion for to turn
it into three by tags for a week have it
adopted and then do the the actual
discussion I mean that at least gets us
past this sort of like philosophical
question and like advances us from a
process perspective and allows this this
document that Shawn was talking about to
get written as a way for us to explore
our feelings a little bit so just is
just as another data point there are a
number of ini registration requests
lined up right now that want to go into
this space so the space wouldn't be
available if we go for those
registrations just as a data by
Alexandra here so I really like the idea
about the document that says you know
this is the way we should be you know
creating tags this is in the way we
should be using them so if you go with
this I'll be willing to to review it
Orion objects express some opinion so
thanks if thanks for starting this
and yeah about these tags like I mean
for me a tag is something that like its
attack you don't attach like semantics
on it
it's it's something that says well the
thing that follows is this right so I
really like the idea of being able to do
some mathematical miracles with it and
do some jump tables or something but I'm
not sure if this attaching semantics to
the things it's not violating the idea
about the tag itself like for me a tag
is like it the fact that it's a number
it it's just like an implementational
detail it could have been like a big
string so having these things it could
could work right but you know I I'm not
sure it's it's something we would like
to start doing at some point because
here now we have some you find some neat
thing to do with it and then maybe
tomorrow we find some other new neat
things to do with some new tags so we
say okay we have some other jump so we
have starting code to the tags and and
you know we example with the lgb so what
happens if okay you have you need to
make the distinction between you int and
binary 16 to make sure that your RGB is
in one case or the other case like
dynamic range or non dynamic range so
what happens if your application doesn't
use use tax anymore at some point you
say okay well in some other case you
want to be super efficient so you don't
or we have some parser that says okay
I'm just going to strip tags because you
know it's not this is all you can do and
if we define it this way
then a specific data model can just say
an RGB value as three numbers and and
use one of the tags that is being
defined here I mean they are still in a
table right so you don't have to do the
arithmetic with the tag if you only care
for a few of them
it's just expedient for a generic
encoder and decoder implementation to be
able to use the table so you would say
an RGB value is either a triple of you
and eight-hour trouble of binary 16 and
then your
okay I mean that's a support point from
the one that wasn't but what I say is
that in this case if you remove the tag
then you cannot purse anymore
the you cannot make this distinction
between is it dynamic range or is it
something fixed so just just saying that
that but that that was like a minor
point that the other point was might be
more important that do we want to make
this explicit like mathematical thing on
top of the text Sean Leonard I think the
general design pattern is not specific
to seaboard to tags it's just when you
have when you're computing right you can
have a huge if else sequence of
statements which is not necessarily it
may or may not be parallelizable but if
you can have a large range of contiguous
choices and then perform a single
mathematical operation and jump to the
right place or or you know compute that
then things go a lot faster and can be
done in much less code so it's just like
a general pattern of allocating the same
numbers in the same block that do
similar things for the same reason that
ASCII 0 to 9 just happened to be in the
hex pattern 30 to 39 because if you'd
subtract 48 from them then you actually
have the number in binary it's the same
exact premise okay but we seem to have
consensus on going for 3 by tags for the
next version during the eruption call
and then we complaining loudly to the
mailing list that that should be two by
text not quickly about the time tag just
note now we have finished with the
chartered items and the time tag is
unchartered
thank you yeah I already said that but
it's good to say that again so the the
time tag came up because the the Haskell
program programming language has pretty
much adopted SIBO as their preferred
binary serialization technique and in
Haskell times are based on microseconds
so he needed a way to represent the time
based on time a seconds and the Afghan
people wanted to have tags so they
really can see in the serialized data
this is a time and not just in any array
of data or something like that
so they wrote up a document and I helped
them a little bit with with completing
that and they got FCSS registration now
we could document this tag if we think
it is useful we it's not only useful for
microseconds also be used for
nanoseconds microseconds or milliseconds
so all the cases when you don't want to
do the computation of converting one of
these pairs of seconds and a subunit of
seconds into a single number it's useful
to to have this kind of a check so it's
pretty general in its usage and we could
also go ahead and add more of what what
was in the original proposal for the
time check to it so there's there were
things were things like time zones and
other information that could draw in
there could not so these are all other
ways of taking it forward and I would
just like to know should I talk to the
independent submissions editor tomorrow
and say this becomes an RFC on its own
if yes he will come through the work
group and ask assist the run around
through working group and so the work
will have to have an opinion on that
or should I wait for the work group to
complete its current charter and then
work on making this workgroup document
or including it in a set of useful tags
or but but have the working work on it I
would like the opinion of our ad on this
I think I mostly have an opinion whether
you should complete other work items
before this one but I have I have an
opinion upon whether you should complete
other work items first before accepting
this but other than that you know I
think it's very fair question if you
want to pole hold the room to see how
many people are interested in working on
this which can inform Karstens decision
you know which way to take it okay Sean
Leonard so I think this is fine as a
working group item with Alexie's caveat
that we should work on the first things
first that we are chartered for an
interesting bookkeeping question which I
believe is completely bike shedding is
do you want to allocate a block for
bookkeeping purposes of seaboard tags
just a time stuff so we just say one
thousand one to one eleven hundred or
whatever is all the time tags will ever
need and then somebody we have a block
of free tags for times periods and
intervals of three tags or of like three
okay okay but I'm saying like we know we
just just reserved 300 tags or just say
Oh somebody's coming up with some weird
time format or do we have a block of
tags for Haskell things right so it's
like programming language specific like
all the pearl stuff is in 3000 to 4000
and the Haskell so I'll support that but
I don't know I don't know I can include
something along that in the dock in the
document philosophy of tagging if that's
important to people I just see this as
there's an opportunity to look at what
are the underlying things that motivate
sea bores you know advantages over other
serialization formats and one of those
is efficiency of the encoders and
decoders I believe that's explicitly
mentioned in 1749 as the motivating case
so to the extent that we are trying to
support IOT devices resource constrained
devices
you know devices that want to just
work very fast on data hopefully that
will inform whether we have a large
number of time tags or whatever to make
the encoding and decoding of these
things faster for devices and easier for
devices than and protocols that actually
need to do them so yeah with that said
if we delve any more into time tags I
really want some subject matter expert
on this thing because I'm not an expert
in time we got an NTP working group
there's gotta be some people in there
who know all about this time stuff much
better than me yeah it helped that Joe
touch was writing a document about times
at the time that they dressed this was
discussed so this document contains a
reference to it or touches okay so maybe
we can can take the power of who's
actually interested in working on using
this who will be interested in this
topic here to be clear who wants us to
do after we're done with our chartered
items who wants us to do more work on
time formats including this one perhaps
just time formats in general let's start
with that hands who think we want to
work on that ear Hank you have to raise
a nom if you have one to spare one all
right so that's two people including one
of Hanks eyebrows all right three all
right that's I think useful but not I
mean this is not a this is more of a
strawpoll kind of question not a don't
work on this but I didn't see a large
thundering herd of folk who were
interested in doing more there yes yeah
I think it's sort of an indicative but
it doesn't have to be binding you can
ask the question once you actually do
those other things right but okay do
anything else there all right
all right so let's talk just a little
bit more about CD DL while we've got
everybody here does anybody think that
we ought to do a ton more work on CD DL
before we publish rev 0 any any hands of
people who think that we ought to do add
a bunch more stuff before we publish
there's a quizzical look I see do people
think we ought I'm going to ask the
opposite question do people think that
we're quite pretty close we should go
into polish mode and just get the thing
out the door like raise your hands if
you think we're there alright so I see a
good number of hands for that I see some
people raising two hands
Alexia is going to clarify I'm going to
start applying slight pressure as Area
Director I'm any document that
normatively reference EDD L is not going
to you know it either has to have a
normative reference or it will have a
discussing it so okay that's so I think
we should I do want to point out one of
the other ADEs asked me about using CD
DL for JSON and he hadn't seen appendix
e out of the the current CD DL spec so
alexei if you could just keep your eyes
open for people questioning if they're
allowed to use CD DL for JSON whatever
allowed means there is that appendix in
the current CD DL draft well he does now
because I sent him the link so if
there's anybody else that wants us to do
more work there before we're done enough
and I used air quotes there before we're
done enough for people to use this in
their JSON specs then the iesg should
let us know because if we're going to
move into quick polish and get it out
mode we're not going to add anything
else other than what's in that
in that appendix talking about JSON so
this is a hey if you would mind
mentioning this the rest of the iesg you
see if anybody else has an issue
otherwise we're just gonna plow ahead so
you know no no what I'm saying is that I
think we believe and I'm that Appendix
II is enough to motivate using CD DL for
describing JSON protocols if the iesg
wants something more than that
appendix say something that feels a
little bit more normative or a separate
doc that describes how to do it or
anything like that we would like them to
speak up immediately and give us a
little bit more direction other than
without hearing anything like that we're
going to move ahead
assuming that appendix B is roughly
exactly what's needed okay sorry because
I haven't actually looked at Appendix C
I cannot provide a useful personal
comment and I'm not asking for you to
tell me the answer to this right now I'm
asking if over the course of maybe
tomorrow and yes or at least point
people to it and tell them that that's
what it's going to be unless they tell
us something different okay did there's
already one I receive public that
reference is City dairy for Jason
informatively
- be careful when you give me action
items I give them back alright anybody
have any other concerns like if we're
gonna put CD DL on this short timeframe
which sounds like we really ought to at
this point does anybody else have any
other concerns or potential roadblocks
things that we ought to aggressively
pull out in order to fix things so
they're like the regular expression
thing like I would maybe put that on the
bubble if we don't have a normative
reference to point to for regular
expressions are you are you okay with
that Sean Sean Leonard so yeah so my
whole thing is I don't want us to be
committed to all these bucketload of
features that we may want to change you
know or improve or whatever later on so
I so you know I am resigned to the fact
that we got to publish something right
and we got to keep people's work going
there's no not really question that but
we need also be clear it's version zero
and we're trying to you know add these
useful things I mean all that I dunno
I'm gonna have to basically start that
as soon as we get the first one in the
can
yeah and so like the the mode here
should be if we can't come to consensus
quickly on exactly what it ought to look
like if we don't have a reference for
the thing for whatever reason will rip
the feature out and we'll put it back in
and this right right and yeah like I
said my I have concerns about like I
said the control operators in general
not because they're not useful but
because like is somebody really using
these now and well I know like give us a
few weeks or the virgin ones like give
it all out you know Hank can you quickly
comment with a certain three little is a
ssin would have a problem with ray X
being taking out do that later
yeah so do that on the so all I'm saying
is that if we can't come to consensus on
these things quickly now I'm also now
that we understand sort of what polish
mode would mean I'm also okay with
somebody going up to Mike and saying you
know we're not quite ready for that I'm
not seeing anybody running to the mic
all right so this is just hey we need to
be able to finish okay chabi relay from
kuru Maeda or some variation of that
pronunciation reg X is good at finding
something matches however bad at
detecting something does not match bad
Greg X patterns might lead to a dos
relying on reg x4 validator could be
risky please send that to the list that
is an entire separate discussion one of
the things Shawn that we probably ought
to put in the dock that you proposed is
a talk about how much these sorts of
things should be used for generating
validators at runtime versus being used
as a mechanism of documenting what the
validators ought to do and I know that
that is a place where timbre and
particulars had very strong opinions in
the past and the way that we got to
being able to do some of the CDL workers
was talking about it in terms of
describing what the interoperability
properties should be and not about
generating values right so Joe this is
Sean Leonard so just a question are you
referring to the philosophy of tagging
document that was oh oh okay yeah
because that your comment was addressed
more to CD DL right okay in my mind it
was one big philosophy document okay no
problem yeah cuz I'm I am of the view
opinion that it's more descriptive than
about validation I'm also I recognized
people will wanna validate things but
the point is to describe and we want to
emphasize that and one way to do that is
to kind of put some focus on the fact
that if stuff doesn't if you have data
that doesn't conform
to the CD DL it's not necessarily a
fatal error okay this is not XML land
it's more like markdown land if it
doesn't quite fit that's okay
still work with it that's not the way we
use this use this for defining protocols
and if the protocol is not being
followed
then you have an error all right so
let's not bogged down in that particular
philosophical whole there are different
ways of using app so the sean's way is
also another way of using it all right
let me go back to what I was talking
about with CD DL so let's make sure that
anything that we don't have pretty good
consensus on or anything that we don't
have good references or or anything
that's not done we can start ripping
that stuff out get a version zero out
the door so that other people can refer
to it that should be a pretty high
priority for us over the next several
weeks and I don't see me but this I see
some nodding heads I don't see anybody
shaking their head I don't see anybody
jumping up to the mic all right go ahead
jump up to the right as Dave Robin I was
just gonna say with the exception of reg
X which gets into the whole
philosophical about it what's it used
for it can it be used for generating
validators I think if you take that out
and you look at the rest of it I can
easily make a validator code out of it
it's it's it's fairly strict I mean we
had some matching questions J year that
we talked about but for the most part I
can automate about a validator from that
so I'm just saying that's that's okay
with the Reg X is more of a explaining
to a human to give to my coder to write
some rules and that that breaks
everything all right so let's have let's
finish off that discussion on the
mailing list
thanks about to jump up because he sees
the way the winds blowing in regard to
the three-letter a true man suo reg X is
not by to within as what is within
control within all right well maybe
that's that's
a quick way out of this for the short
term is would be to remove that regex
control does anybody else gonna have
heartburn from that did you say that all
right so we're gonna Val we're going to
talk about that a list see if anybody
has an issue with it that would be a way
for us to move forward get the thing out
the door and we can add regex back in in
version 1 or version 2 or whatever going
to call it all right two minutes just
remind again please participate in no
meaningless SUBSCRIBE and I would be
personally interested to hear about
people that are using CD dl4 CDL and
implementers of C bore so I see a lot of
people here that I I have not seen in
the mailing list talked a lot so please
make sure you're in the main list all
right any last comments is there anybody
that didn't get the blue sheets do we
have the other blue sheet handy can
somebody raise it up for me somewhere
where I can see it thank you all right
thanks everybody that's all yes so
all they have done great it to a comment
hi there was a bit of misunderstanding I
thought you guys did wasn't quite right
a strategic yes because you are updated
the definition and sort of war spirit I
initially thought it was wrong as in
Euro defined linked relations instead of
defining you once but mark explained
that actuates now your but but because
Europe instead of just doing by
reference you if it is a text